<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 19:38:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 is adding a CS:GO-style mode and bringing back loot boxes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/610599/overwatch-2-season-15-16-update-stadium-new-character-freja-loot-boxes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-is-adding-a-cs-go-style-mode-and-bringing-back-loot-boxes.1107168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/610599/overwatch-2-season-15-16-update-stadium-new-character-freja-loot-boxes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Overwatch 2</em> is getting quite the shakeup in 2025 as it faces growing competition from other online shooters. It starts with the season 15 update that’s coming on February 18th that’ll tease a new hero and introduce an in-game Perks system for existing ones, plus the return of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/24/24278781/overwatch-2-season-14-6v6-test">6v6 competitive queues Blizzard tested late last year</a>. There’s also the return of loot boxes and then, in April, a <em>Counterstrike</em>-like mode, two new characters, and a revamped ranked queue that lets you ban heroes and vote on maps.</p><p>Reintroducing loot boxes may be a polarizing move, as games that implement them have received backlash over the years for their predatory nature. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/16/23171133/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-free-to-play">Blizzard removed them from <em>Overwatch</em> a few years ago</a> in favor of an in-game shop when it restructured its monetization model after going free-to-play. The company will responsibly publicize drop rates and is guaranteeing that you’ll receive an item of “Rare” rarity or better in each box, plus a guaranteed “Epic” after opening five and a “Legendary” after opening 20. We’re not sure whether you’ll still be able to purchase cosmetics directly from a rotating in-game shop, but you can earn loot boxes as part of weekly and event rewards, and you can get up to three guaranteed Legendary loot boxes in each seasonal battle pass.</p><p>Stadium is arguably the biggest change announced for <em>Overwatch 2</em> so far. The new gameplay mode is a best-of-seven romp between two teams of five that’s akin to <em>CounterStrike: Go</em> or <em>Valorant</em>. You’ll earn currency each round, with rotating maps and objectives alternating between Control, Clash, and Push.</p><p>The cash goes toward upgrades for your hero that are unique to the mode, whether you’re unlocking an ability or upgrading it with enhanced potency or transformative effects that buff your offense and team utility. You can even choose between first-person or third-person POVs. It’s getting its own ranked queue, too, and launches with 14 heroes to start, with more planned to be added in future updates alongside a steady rollout of new maps.</p><p>Season 16 will also introduce Freja, a high-mobility character who can dash horizontally and jump vertically while wielding a dual-mode crossbow that enables both rapid-fire shooting and precision sniping. You’ll be able to play her for a bit during a trial weekend in Season 15. Blizzard is also teasing a new character for Season 18 named Aqua, appropriately named for his water-based abilities.</p><p>As for the new Perks system, it promises to enhance all of the game’s heroes with two unique upgrades per match. Your first upgrade is a minor one that lets you choose one of two slight boosts, perhaps a slightly stronger passive or a reduced cooldown for a core ability. The second upgrade offers a more substantial play style shift designed to help turn the tides of battle — Torbjorn can choose between a stronger level three turret or the ability to mount it on a wall, for example.</p><p>These drastic changes are almost necessary for any service-based online arena shooter to stand out amidst growing competition, as evidenced by <em>Fortnite</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24315134/fortnite-ballistic-counter-strike-first-person-shooter-fps">recently receiving a similar mode</a> as Epic Games continues experimenting. There are only so many players to go around, after all, especially with newcomer <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337409/marvel-rivals-fantastic-four-season-1-date-trailer">Marvel Rivals</a></em> making a loud and very noticeable Namor-sized splash of late.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch Adds Ability-Altering Perks, Brings Back Loot Boxes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-adds-ability-altering-perks-brings-back-loot-boxes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-adds-ability-altering-perks-brings-back-loot-boxes.1107159/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-adds-ability-altering-perks-brings-back-loot-boxes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Two major changes to Overwatch are coming in Season 15 of the long-running hero shooter from Blizzard: the debut of gameplay perks and the return of loot boxes. Billed as the “boldest gameplay evolution yet,” perks let players level up their hero abilities with new effects mid-match.</p>



<p>Check out the full details on all the <a href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24177197/overwatch-2-spotlight-a-new-era-of-innovation-and-excitement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new changes</a> coming to Overwatch in Season 15 below.</p>



<h2 id="h-overwatch-s-biggest-content-change-arguably-since-the-sequel">Overwatch’s Biggest Content Change Arguably Since the Sequel</h2>



<p>The new perk system allows player to upgrade their hero’s kit during a match by earning level experience. Players can earn level experience by getting kills, dealing damage, and healing. The perks are similar to Reality Augments in Fortnite: when a player unlocks the ability to get a perk, they can use their controls to select one of the two options. If a player switches heroes during a match, their hero level will reset, but they will earn experience faster. Players can equip three perks per match: two Minor perks, and one Major perk.</p>



<p>In addition to the new perks system, Season 15 will re-introduce loot boxes. Players will be able to earn loot boxes from weekly and event rewards, as well as one Legendary loot box from the free battle pass, and two more from the Premium pass. A Rare or better item will drop in every box, an Epic item is guaranteed within five consecutive boxes, and a Legendary it guaranteed within 20 consecutive boxes. If an item you already own is in the box, it will re-roll it with an item of the same rarity.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Season 15: Honor &amp; Glory Official Trailer | Overwatch 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mZR6lbjMFnk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>These two changes are just a portion of the changes promised over the next 2-3 seasons. Other changes include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Competitive rank reset</li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-classic-sees-6v6-matches-return-for-limited-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Permanent Overwatch Classic mode</a>, featuring the GOATS Meta (three tanks, three support)</li>



<li>New hero: Freja, a bounty hunter with a quick-firing crossbow, a quick dash, and an explosive Bola Shot</li>



<li>New cosmetics</li>



<li>Stadium mode: a completely overhauled competitive mode featuring a best-of-seven system, new abilities, first and third person mode, and its own ranked mode. Currently in development, launching in season 16</li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>



<p>Season 15 officially launches on February 18.</p>



<p>Is this massive wave of new content enough to get you to return to Overwatch? Let us know down below and in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1197/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/electronic-arts-almost-owned-cod-blizzard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Electronic Arts almost acquiring Blizzard</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Early Access Launch Times Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-early-access-launch-times-revealed/1100-6529447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-early-access-launch-times-revealed.1107156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-early-access-launch-times-revealed/1100-6529447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529447">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft's next big game, the RPG Avowed from developer Obsidian, launches on February 18. But the Premium Edition unlocks a full five days earlier, beginning February 13.</p><p>Obsidian has now posted the official unlock times for Avowed's early-access period, which begins at 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET on February 13. This works out to 6 PM in London and 7 PM in Paris. For people on the other side of the world, Avowed arrives at 3 AM in Tokyo, 5 AM in Sydney, and 7 AM in Auckland on Friday, February 14. You can see all the unlock times below.</p><h2><strong>Avowed early access unlock times</strong></h2><p><strong>Thursday, February 13</strong></p><ul><li>10 AM PT</li><li>12 PM CT</li><li>1 PM ET</li><li>3 PM BRT</li><li>6 PM GMT</li><li>7 PM CET</li></ul><p><strong>Friday, February 14</strong></p><ul><li>3 AM JST</li><li>5 AM AEDT</li><li>7 AM NZDT</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4442937-screenshot2025-02-12at1.45.56pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4442937" data-ratio="0.55436893203883" data-width="2060" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4442937-screenshot2025-02-12at1.45.56pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4442937"></a><figcaption>Avowed is almost here.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4442937-screenshot2025-02-12at1.45.56pm.png"></figure><p>Avowed is included with Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass, but early access is not. For that, players have to buy the $90 Avowed Premium Edition. Alternatively, Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass members can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-members-can-upgrade-to-avoweds-90-premium-edition-for-a-fraction-of-the-price/1100-6529257/" data-ref-id="1100-6529257">buy an upgrade add-on for $22.50</a> that offers early access and other bonuses.</p><p>Microsoft offers a <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/xbox-game-pass/pc-game-pass/direct?ef_id=_k_CjwKCAiAtYy9BhBcEiwANWQQL060WztejYDT820IxgrLK3sR8Q_jlevGUG8QtksNo3ABpHdap0WtShoCXNYQAvD_BwE_k_&amp;OCID=AIDcmmiixzwwab_SEM__k_CjwKCAiAtYy9BhBcEiwANWQQL060WztejYDT820IxgrLK3sR8Q_jlevGUG8QtksNo3ABpHdap0WtShoCXNYQAvD_BwE_k_&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAtYy9BhBcEiwANWQQL060WztejYDT820IxgrLK3sR8Q_jlevGUG8QtksNo3ABpHdap0WtShoCXNYQAvD_BwE" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14-day PC Game Pass trial for $1</a>, so anyone taking advantage of that offer could play Avowed for only $1. Microsoft is known to remove this special deal ahead of the launch of a high-profile game, but that hasn't happened yet. There is no $1 trial for Game Pass Ultimate, however.</p><p>Avowed is Obsidian's first new release since 2022's Pentiment. It's not Obsidian's only in-development project, either, as the studio is also making <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2/" data-ref-id="5000-533237">The Outer Worlds 2</a>, which is planned for release this year.</p><p>In other news, Avowed's game director has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-is-now-capable-of-running-at-60fps-on-xbox-series-x-will-have-jank-at-launch/1100-6529303/" data-ref-id="1100-6529303">warned fans to expect some "jank" when the game launches.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expelled! is a murderous sequel to Overboard! coming out in March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/expelled-is-a-murderous-sequel-to-overboard-coming-out-in-march/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/expelled-is-a-murderous-sequel-to-overboard-coming-out-in-march.1107120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/12/expelled-is-a-murderous-sequel-to-overboard-coming-out-in-march/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Inkle has just revealed Expelled!, a sequel to their reverse murder mystery <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/overboard">Overboard!</a>, coming to PC, Nintendo Switch and iOS on 12th March.</p>
<p><iframe title="Expelled! Official trailer - release date announcement" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OzUjGieWQIY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Someone has pushed a school prefect out of a window on the top floor of a school, and all fingers at this 1920s boarding school are being pointed right your way. Starring Amelia Tyler (Baldur’s Gate 3) as Verity, you have to find a way to reveal the “truth”, no matter the cost, trying to get away with the deed. Truth be told, I’m jumping to conclusions, considering the plot of Overboard!, so there’s a chance that Verity really didn’t do it – it does look quite 1920s Mean Girls.</p>
<p>You’ll have to get through the school day, talking to other characters, sneaking around and revealing the secrets of student and teachers to use to your advantage. But you’ll have to do your best not to be caught, with a simulated world where other character move and act independently and remember everything they see and hear you do. You’ll have to act fast and be smart to make it through the day without getting expelled.</p>
<p>A play-through will last for around 30-45 minutes, whether you succeed or fail, making this eminently replayable as you make your way through the story.</p>

<p>It’s all in the same vein as Overboard!, a game in which a lady has decided to give her husband the old heave ho, knocking him over the side of a ship and to his demise. She needs to try and get away with it, pinning the blame on one of the five other passengers in order to get the life insurance money – suicide won’t cut it for that!</p>
<p>Overboard was one of the highlights of 2021, building on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/inkle">Inkle’s</a> storytelling pedigree with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/80-days">80 Days</a>, and Expelled! looks like it’s taking that core idea to the next level.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Adds In-Match Perks – ‘The Biggest Gameplay Innovation Since Overwatch Launched in 2016’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-adds-in-match-perks-the-biggest-gameplay-innovation-since-overwatch-launched-in-2016/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-adds-in-match-perks-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98the-biggest-gameplay-innovation-since-overwatch-launched-in-2016%E2%80%99.1107117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-adds-in-match-perks-the-biggest-gameplay-innovation-since-overwatch-launched-in-2016/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Blizzard Entertainment has announced several major changes coming to Overwatch 2 with Season 15, which is due to begin on Tuesday, February 18.</p>
<p>By far the most significant addition, described by the studio as the biggest gameplay innovation since the franchise launch, is in-match Perks. While in a match, players will now level up two times, gaining hero-specific bonuses that are meant to provide greater strategic depth.</p>
<p>With the first level up, the player will get to pick between two minor Perks. For example, with Torbjorn, they can either choose 'Craftsman' (Forge Hammer restores armor health to allies and the turret repair heal is improved by 25%) or 'Fully Loaded' (activating Overload completely refills the Rivet Gun's ammunition). Another example shared is Lucio's 'Bass Blowout', which increases the knockback of his Soundwave skill.</p>
<p>With the second level up, Overwatch 2 will offer a choice between two major Perks. In the case of Torbjorn, you'll be able to pick 'Anchor Bolts' (increasing the throw range of Deploy Turret by 50% and allowing it to be attached to walls and ceilings) or 'Level 3 Turret' (which will transform your turret into level 3 for five seconds when using Overload). With Reaper, the 'Dire Triggers' Perk gives him a Secondary Fire that does decent mid-range damage and is great for getting that last shot on an escaping foe.</p>
<p>Blizzard said that the Perks concept originated in early 2024, though most of the project came together in the last six months. It went through several stages of trial and error; for instance, Perks was initially just a leveling system featuring predetermined upgrades. However, that version of the system lacked player choice, which is what the team focused on adding for the final version.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Perks_Torbjorn_Major-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>Blizzard also shared some of their favorite Perks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Winston's Chain Lightning lets him charge up Secondary Fire to zap multiple enemies near his target.</li>
<li>Hanzo's Scatter Arrows will make for some great multi-kill clips.</li>
<li>With Baptiste's Shoulder Turret, when using Amplification Matrix, the turret comes out to add extra Automated Healing.</li>
<li>Ramattra's Vengeful Vortex enables players to explode Ravenous Vortex in the air and send down any flying enemies.</li>
</ul>
<p>In case you were wondering, these Overwatch 2 in-match Perks will be available in both Competitive and Quick Play modes.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/OVR_PK_S15_GalaxyWeaponSkin_Hanzo_001-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Season 15 will mark the beginning of this year's competitive season for the game, bringing with it a Ranked reset, new competitive Galactic Weapons designed to give players the power of the stars, competitive rank Weapon Charms, and new Player Portraits.</p>
<p>Players will be able to join the new <a href="https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-will-run-two-6v6-tests-in-season-14/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6v6</a> Competitive queue as well as Overwatch Classic: GOATS. Moreover, Loot Boxes are coming back, being available via weekly and event rewards, as well as earning 1 Legendary Loot Box in the Free Battle Pass and an additional 2 Legendary Loot Boxes in the Premium Battle Pass.</p>
<p>The Overwatch 2 team has already shared the official Loot Boxes drop rates in an attempt at transparency:</p>
<table id="table_1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.95"><strong>Loot Boxes</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.93"><strong>Legendary Loot Boxes</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.67">Legendary - 5.10%</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.6">Legendary - 100%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.69">Epic - 21.93%</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.54">Epic - 21.93%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.79">Rare - 96.26%</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.81">Rare - 96.26%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.83">Common - 97.97%</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.81">Common - 97.97%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Moreover, Blizzard said that a Rare or better item is guaranteed to drop in every single box, with an Epic item within five consecutive boxes and a Legendary item within twenty consecutive boxes.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/OW2-Loot-Boxes-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>That's not all Bizzard discussed today. The developers also outlined major additions coming later this year with Season 16, starting with the brand new Stadium game mode. Stadium is meant to be a wholly different way to experience Overwatch 2, starting with the camera, which, for the first time in the franchise, will default to a third-person view (although switchable at any moment to the familiar first-person view). Blizzard says that the new perspective slightly slows down the pace of action while also allowing players to better see the more iconic abilities of their hero.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Stadium_Dva_1p-and-3p-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>Stadium is played 5v5 in a best-of-7 format (with role queue) where players will earn in-game currency each round to purchase and customize abilities. These are powerful upgrades that can alter your character's survivability and damage output and even completely overhaul their skills. Stadium features a redesigned and intuitive user interface and icons, allowing players to seamlessly view, buy and sell mods (which include Items, Hero Items, and Powers), as well as see the builds of your rival team's builds to maximize your strategy from round to round.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Stadium_Armory_Customization_3-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>Stadium also features its own Ranked Mode with multiple divisions, ranks, and unique rewards.<br>
There will be at least 14 core heroes when Stadium launches in Season 16. Over time, Blizzard plans to introduce more heroes, maps, and modes.</p>
<p>Season 16 will bring even more to Overwatch 2, including a brand new Hero called Freya. She's a former search and rescue operative turned bounty hunter, equipped with an explosive crossbow and unique abilities. Her abilities include&nbsp;Take Aim, which can be used to line up the perfect shot and fire a high-speed explosive bolt; Quick Dash, a dodge that also reloads Freya's explosive bolt; and Bola Shot, which grabs enemies. Freya can also use wind updrafts to propel herself into the sky. While she's slated to join the roster in Season 16, players will be able to check her out during a free trial weekend later in Season 15.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/OVR_PK_S15_H43_Freja_002-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Blizzard even teased another character, currently codenamed Aqua. This one is a Chinese hero featuring water-based abilities. He's currently slated to launch in Season 18. Season 16 will also see the arrival of Hero Bans in Competitive Mode. Later in 2025, Blizzard will add a new Map Voting system.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/aqua_concept-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Overall, it seems that the developers have been hard at work revamping Overwatch 2 in various ways. Whether this will be enough to reignite interest in the game remains to be seen.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11 Important Changes Coming To Overwatch 2 To Finally Get It Back On Track]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-showcase-perks-stadium-freja-aqua-season-15-1851761489</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/11-important-changes-coming-to-overwatch-2-to-finally-get-it-back-on-track.1107099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-showcase-perks-stadium-freja-aqua-season-15-1851761489<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="58059c94a78fc11935b03b24aeee8542" data-recommend-id="image://58059c94a78fc11935b03b24aeee8542" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Freja holds her crossbow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Freja holds her crossbow." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="58059c94a78fc11935b03b24aeee8542" data-recommend-id="image://58059c94a78fc11935b03b24aeee8542" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Freja holds her crossbow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Blizzard is bringing some of the most substantial changes to <em>Overwatch 2 </em>that the game has seen since it launched in 2022. In a 30-minute-long Spotlight presentation, the company revealed several changes and new modes, as well as a new hero coming to the hero shooter in 2025. You can watch the full presentation below, or if you just want the highlights, read on.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-recommend-id="image://1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The UI of Orisa picking between two perks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The UI of Orisa picking between two perks." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-recommend-id="image://1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The UI of Orisa picking between two perks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The most important change coming to <em>Overwatch 2 </em>in 2025 is the addition of Perks. This system essentially turns the shooter into a MOBA, allowing you to upgrade your hero throughout a match and fundamentally change their ability sets to cater to your playstyle. This feels like the revival of the planned skill trees that would have given heroes different abilities that riffed on their base ones in a PvE mode that was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-mode-pve-content-release-date-window-1850442457&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-mode-pve-content-release-date-window-1850442457">canceled in 2023</a></span>.</p><p>One example shown was Orisa, who can add a placeable shield similar to the one she had in the original <em>Overwatch </em>to her kit, allowing her to defend herself and allies with a more stationary playstyle. Also shown was the option to upgrade Ana to be able to use her damage-reducing Nano Boost ultimate on herself, giving her a power boost and a degree of survivability she otherwise doesn’t have. This is the biggest fundamental change <em>Overwatch 2 </em>has introduced to its gameplay since the game launched. It’ll be implemented in quickplay and competitive modes in Season 15, beginning on February 18. We’ll have impressions on the site very soon.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0e8c9a9548ebfc570c7602c7b412905f" data-recommend-id="image://0e8c9a9548ebfc570c7602c7b412905f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Hanzo holding a Galactic weapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Hanzo holding a Galactic weapon." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0e8c9a9548ebfc570c7602c7b412905f" data-recommend-id="image://0e8c9a9548ebfc570c7602c7b412905f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Hanzo holding a Galactic weapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Blizzard is adding new rewards to its Competitive mode, including a purple Galactic skin for weapons, and weapon charms that show off your rank. Also coming to Competitive are hero bans in Season 16. Each team will be able to vote for two heroes each match, with the ban applying to both teams. In a future season, you’ll also be able to vote between different maps before a match, but that will be coming sometime after hero bans.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e60ea435c42801bcd772d2784aefd58e" data-recommend-id="image://e60ea435c42801bcd772d2784aefd58e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1915" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An Overwatch loot box." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An Overwatch loot box." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e60ea435c42801bcd772d2784aefd58e" data-recommend-id="image://e60ea435c42801bcd772d2784aefd58e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1915" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An Overwatch loot box." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After years of backlash over Blizzard getting rid of Loot Boxes in favor of expensive cosmetics, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>is bringing them back in Season 15 to give you a random chance to unlock skins and other goodies. These will be found in weekly rewards and the free battle pass track, and the game will note the odds for different cosmetics before you open them.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2c2ddd636bf3e623b5895ded3b939f78" data-recommend-id="image://2c2ddd636bf3e623b5895ded3b939f78" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Hazard, Tracer, Reaper, Mercy, Juno, an Reinhardt charge into battle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Hazard, Tracer, Reaper, Mercy, Juno, an Reinhardt charge into battle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2c2ddd636bf3e623b5895ded3b939f78" data-recommend-id="image://2c2ddd636bf3e623b5895ded3b939f78" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Hazard, Tracer, Reaper, Mercy, Juno, an Reinhardt charge into battle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After recently testing a return to <em>Overwatch</em>’s original 6v6 format, Blizzard is giving it a separate competitive queue in Season 15. This will be an open queue but will have a limit of two tanks per team. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="efe1d40aeb7807f81382f82067f3755d" data-recommend-id="image://efe1d40aeb7807f81382f82067f3755d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Juno, Hazard, and Lucio charge into battle with googly eyes on their face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Juno, Hazard, and Lucio charge into battle with googly eyes on their face." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="efe1d40aeb7807f81382f82067f3755d" data-recommend-id="image://efe1d40aeb7807f81382f82067f3755d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Juno, Hazard, and Lucio charge into battle with googly eyes on their face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In a bold move, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>is adding a new iteration of its nostalgia-driven <em>Overwatch Classic </em>mode that reverts the game to different points in its nearly nine-year lifespan. The next version will spotlight one of the most controversial metas: <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/jeff-kaplan-knows-some-people-will-always-hate-overwatc-1831624036&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/jeff-kaplan-knows-some-people-will-always-hate-overwatc-1831624036">GOATS</a></span>. This three tanks/three supports meta was prominent in 2019 and widely considered one of the lowest-interest compositions to watch and play. Some theorize the reason Blizzard introduced Role Queue was to ensure competitive players can’t run the composition. If you’re feeling nostalgic, the GOATS <em>Overwatch Classic</em> will be available in Season 15.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="dbc67cf2fcba9686f5bf31ebf388f854" data-recommend-id="image://dbc67cf2fcba9686f5bf31ebf388f854" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Freya holds her crossbow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Freya holds her crossbow." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dbc67cf2fcba9686f5bf31ebf388f854" data-recommend-id="image://dbc67cf2fcba9686f5bf31ebf388f854" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Freya holds her crossbow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One of the big headliners of the presentation was Freja. She’s a new damage hero who was a member of the original Overwatch before it was disbanded. Blizzard describes her as a high-skill-ceiling hero due to the precision required to master her kit. She uses a crossbow, is able to leap up high and slow down time with her alternate fire, and has an ultimate that can drag enemies to a central point to rain down damage on them. Freja will join the roster in Season 16.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="6e1422e5c5f2d0602e7ff5ec53744092" data-recommend-id="image://6e1422e5c5f2d0602e7ff5ec53744092" data-format="jpg" data-width="2421" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Concept art of Aqua." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Concept art of Aqua." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6e1422e5c5f2d0602e7ff5ec53744092" data-recommend-id="image://6e1422e5c5f2d0602e7ff5ec53744092" data-format="jpg" data-width="2421" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Concept art of Aqua." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>While we didn’t see the hero following Freja in motion, Blizzard did show concept art of a new character codenamed “Aqua.” This guy is a Chinese “water wielder” who has ”one of the most unique ability sets” in the game. He’ll join the roster in Season 18.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-recommend-id="image://47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-recommend-id="image://47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Stadium is a new mode coming to <em>Overwatch 2</em> that includes Mods, a new mechanic that lets you make incremental upgrades to stats and abilities to create your own build for your character. You’ll build one hero throughout a lengthy match that rapidly swaps between different maps and modes as a best-of-seven game. At the beginning of each round, players are given access to an armory and can spend earned points from the previous round to upgrade their character’s traits and abilities. Some examples given include Reaper being able to fly while in Wraith Form, Soldier: 76’s healing station gaining increased range and delivering a power boost to those in its radius, and Kiriko being able to teleport across the map without having to target an ally to do so. Blizzard describes Stadium as the ultimate “fantasy” of each hero, cranking their ability sets to an absurd level of destruction and chaos. </p><figure id="" data-id="bb9cd7795877aeb50aaf930f115464e7" data-recommend-id="image://bb9cd7795877aeb50aaf930f115464e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="D.Va's mod customization screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="D.Va's mod customization screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bb9cd7795877aeb50aaf930f115464e7" data-recommend-id="image://bb9cd7795877aeb50aaf930f115464e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="D.Va's mod customization screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Another notable aspect of Stadium is that it can be played in either first person or&nbsp;third person. Blizzard says this is to help avoid screen clutter, which is only made worse as abilities become upgraded throughout the match. Stadium will launch with 14 heroes, with the rest of the cast added over time. We’ll have impressions of the mode on the site soon.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="032382fb5e459c1c4f44ffbd0dc2b613" data-recommend-id="image://032382fb5e459c1c4f44ffbd0dc2b613" data-format="jpg" data-width="1870" data-height="1051" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Zenyatta's Mythic skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Zenyatta's Mythic skin." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="032382fb5e459c1c4f44ffbd0dc2b613" data-recommend-id="image://032382fb5e459c1c4f44ffbd0dc2b613" data-format="jpg" data-width="1870" data-height="1051" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Zenyatta's Mythic skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Blizzard ran down the handful of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-mythic-skin-store-prisms-battle-pass-mercy-1851414356&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-mythic-skin-store-prisms-battle-pass-mercy-1851414356">customizable Mythic skins</a></span> coming over the course of the next three seasons. In the Spotlight presentation, we see the Zenyatta skin based on the mythological Chinese creature called the Pixiu in-game; that one’s coming in Season 15. In the following season, Juno will get the Mythic skin as part of a magical girl theme called DokiWatch. Come season 17, D.Va will get a Mythic skin based on the Siberian tiger. Additionally, Widomaker, Mercy, and Reaper will each get a Mythic weapon over the next three seasons. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="93a86865a33cbd489886634ec442df12" data-recommend-id="image://93a86865a33cbd489886634ec442df12" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The members of Le Sserafim wave at the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The members of Le Sserafim wave at the camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="93a86865a33cbd489886634ec442df12" data-recommend-id="image://93a86865a33cbd489886634ec442df12" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The members of Le Sserafim wave at the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>K-Pop group Le Sserafim is returning to the <em>Overwatch 2</em> world. The girl group already collaborated with<em> Overwatch </em>back in 2023 with a limited-time event that included skins, an arcade mode, and a music video featuring Tracer, Sombra, Brigitte, Kiriko, and D.Va. Le Sserafim revealed that new skins based on the group’s aesthetic will come in Season 15.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="bad204a7adeeaceba8ed11a88ed6c9cb" data-recommend-id="image://bad204a7adeeaceba8ed11a88ed6c9cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="One of the new maps coming to Overwatch 2 after Season 19." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="One of the new maps coming to Overwatch 2 after Season 19." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bad204a7adeeaceba8ed11a88ed6c9cb" data-recommend-id="image://bad204a7adeeaceba8ed11a88ed6c9cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="One of the new maps coming to Overwatch 2 after Season 19." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>After a rundown of new Esports formats in the Overwatch Champions Series, game director Aaron Keller threw out a few rapid-fire updates, including announcing map reworks for Ciravasa and New Junk City, as well as more “classic” map reworks. Also coming after Season 19 is a new map based on the Atlantic Archology lab, and one set in Tokyo.</p><hr><p>We were able to get hands-on time with both Perks and the new Stadium mode. Be on the lookout for written thoughts on those very soon.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2's Round-Based Stadium Mode Looks To Reinvent Blizzard's Shooter In A Big Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-2s-round-based-stadium-mode-looks-to-reinvent-blizzards-shooter-in-a-big-way/1100-6529416/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2s-round-based-stadium-mode-looks-to-reinvent-blizzards-shooter-in-a-big-way.1107093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-2s-round-based-stadium-mode-looks-to-reinvent-blizzards-shooter-in-a-big-way/1100-6529416/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529416">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard has big plans for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/overwatch-2/" data-ref-id="5000-504256">Overwatch 2</a> in 2025, and one of them is a new mode that is unlike anything the game has seen before. Called Stadium, the mode is a competitive, round-based, third-person game mode where players upgrade their chosen hero over the course of a match using currency.</p><p dir="ltr">Revealed as part of Blizzard's recent Overwatch 2 Spotlight livestream, Stadium is intended to join Quick Play and Competitive as a new, third pillar of Overwatch 2 when it arrives as part of Season 16 later this year. The mode will only be playable as a ranked game mode with role queue, and matches will play out in a "best of seven" format. Overwatch's normal Control, Push, and Clash game modes will be featured in Stadium, and players will still be using Overwatch's colorful cast of heroes. That, however, is where the Overwatch 2 players may be accustomed to ends and in many ways a whole new game emerges.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442716-overwatch2stadiummodethirdpersonsoldier76.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442716" data-ratio="0.56227201667535" data-width="1919" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442716-overwatch2stadiummodethirdpersonsoldier76.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442716"></a><figcaption>Overwatch 2's Stadium mode will be played from a third-person perspective. </figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442716-overwatch2stadiummodethirdpersonsoldier76.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Stadium will be the first game mode in Overwatch 2 to support a third-person camera, something recent hero shooter <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/marvel-rivals/" data-ref-id="5000-624043">Marvel Rivals</a> has used to great success. Players will, however, have the option to still play in first-person should they choose. The mode will feature a pre-round "buy" phase, where players can spend currency earned each round to purchase ability upgrades and stat-boosting items, MOBA-style. Items can do everything from granting players simple stat boosts like more health and faster movement speed all the way to granting attacks life-stealing or reducing the duration of negative effects.</p><p dir="ltr">Hero abilities can be augmented with currency too, granting them additional effects that can dramatically change the way a hero is played. Players will earn currency by killing enemies and earning assists, as well as a percentage of the damage and healing they do over the course of a round. There will also be a bounty system, where those who take out well-performing players on the enemy team will be rewarded with a currency payout.</p><p dir="ltr">At launch, only 14 heroes in Overwatch 2's roster will be playable in Stadium mode "to ensure balance and competitive play," according to Blizzard. More heroes will be added to the mode over time.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442717-overwatch2stadiumarmory.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442717" data-ratio="0.56227201667535" data-width="1919" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442717-overwatch2stadiumarmory.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442717"></a><figcaption>A look at the pre-round item shop where players can customize their hero with items and abilities.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4442717-overwatch2stadiumarmory.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Based on what Blizzard has described and shown, it sounds as if Overwatch 2 is taking the pre-round buying phases of games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/counter-strike/" data-ref-id="5000-3000">Counter-Strike</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/valorant/" data-ref-id="5000-509039">Valorant</a>, mashing it together with the third-person gameplay and MOBA-inspired item shop seen in Valve's still-in-the-works <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/deadlock/" data-ref-id="5000-639448">Deadlock</a>, and then combining it all with Overwatch to form a new game-within-a-game.</p><p dir="ltr">Whether or not the new mode catches on remains to be seen, but Stadium isn't the only major addition coming to Overwatch 2 in 2025. Blizzard additionally revealed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-2-ditches-loot-boxes-pvp-roadmap-promises-new-heroes-and-maps-regularly/1100-6504688/" data-ref-id="1100-6504688">loot boxes (originally removed when Overwatch went free-to-play</a> and transitioned into Overwatch 2) will be returning as part of Season 15 on February 18. The season will also introduce a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-injects-moba-energy-into-overwatch-2-with-new-perks-system/1100-6529410/" data-ref-id="1100-6529410">new gameplay system in the form of Perks</a>, where players will be able to choose between ability-altering bonuses over the course of a match. New heroes are coming too, with Blizzard giving fans a first look at the crossbow-wielding Freya and the monk-like Aqua.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Shows Off Assassin's Creed Shadows' Enhanced Visuals And Dynamic Seasons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-shows-off-assassins-creed-shadows-enhanced-visuals-and-dynamic-seasons/1100-6529444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-shows-off-assassins-creed-shadows-enhanced-visuals-and-dynamic-seasons.1107090/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-shows-off-assassins-creed-shadows-enhanced-visuals-and-dynamic-seasons/1100-6529444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529444">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-gameplay-and-everything-we-know/1100-6523576/" data-ref-id="1100-6523576">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> is the latest installment in Ubisoft's long-running franchise, and it's going to take full advantage of the capabilities of PCs and modern consoles. In a newly released video, Ubisoft has offered a glimpse of what Shadows has to offer on PC and new-gen systems, including uncapped framerates and some truly breathtaking visuals of the game's recreation of feudal Japan.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xs2w3qSEBCs" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Xs2w3qSEBCs" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Shadows' PC edition will feature an in-game benchmark that can determine the capabilities of the computer it's running on. Low-end and medium-end PC users won't be left out, as the game can be run in either low or high mode. But the more powerful computers will be able to handle ultra mode, which has stunning graphics.</p><p>Among the other features, Shadows includes ray-traced global illumination and reflections, dynamic seasons, and ultra-wide resolution support. However, some of the most fun may come out of the game's destructible environment. The sheer power of the samurai Yasuke can devastate everything around him, and even the ninja known as Naoe can leave a path of destruction in her wake.</p><p>Assassin's Creed creative director Jonathan Dumont recently indicated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-adapt-to-your-favored-main-character/1100-6529423/" data-ref-id="1100-6529423">Shadows will adapt if players favor Yasuke or Naoe</a> over the other, and most of the game's story can be experienced with either character. The game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-gets-censored-in-japan/1100-6529030/" data-ref-id="1100-6529030">Japanese release has been censored by Ubisoft</a> because of the option to dismember enemy characters. But that feature can be turned on or off in other countries. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-accessibility-options-are-the-series-most-robust-yet/1100-6529024/" data-ref-id="1100-6529024">Shadows' also has robust accessibility options</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-release-its-expansion-in-a-much-different-way/1100-6529019/" data-ref-id="1100-6529019">an expansion</a>, which will be a preorder bonus rather than a standard DLC. However, the expansion will also be available for purchase at some point in the future.</p><p>Assassin's Creed Shadows will be released on March 20 on Xbox Series X|S, PS5, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite's new crime season will let you play as a giant pickle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnites-new-crime-season-will-let-you-play-as-a-giant-pickle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnites-new-crime-season-will-let-you-play-as-a-giant-pickle.1107087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnites-new-crime-season-will-let-you-play-as-a-giant-pickle<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-12_SIk4M7T.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> has revealed the theme of its next season, which will launch in just over a week's time, on 21st February.
</p>
<p>
Lawless, as the season is titled, will be the second during the game's Chapter 6 era. Intriguingly, while that began with a distinctly Japanese setting, a first look at next season suggests more of a 'bad bits of LA' vibe.
</p>
<p>
So, what can we see? From a <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1889691128221372868">teaser image</a> posted to social media, there's a broken neon Hotel sign and burning wood in a barrel, and what look like discarded gold bars littering the street following some kind of quick getaway. Fortnite is once again going for a bank vaults and heist theme then, it seems.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_63ZSlWA.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Fortnite Chapter 6 Season 2 teaser image. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Epic Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Wanted posters feature a new version of fan-favourite gold lover Midas, now sporting a mullet, and an anthropomorphic pickle man called "Big Dill". These are almost certainly skins set to feature in the season's new battle pass.
</p>
<p>
Big Dill the pickle man looks to be Fortnite's latest fruity character, in the style of Peely the banana. Eagle-eyed Fortnite fans will have spotted the current battle royale Island's pickle farm growing over the past season from a small farm to a giant factory. Is Big Dill its latest produce?
</p>
<p>
Last month, it was revealed that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/i-cant-believe-this-is-true-but-wickeds-biggest-song-features-a-hidden-fortnite-cameo">hit film Wicked features Fortnite sound effects during a pivotal scene</a>. Work is also continuing on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disney-x-fortnite-collab-moves-into-stable-branch-exactly-a-year-after-disney-invested-15bn-in-epic-games">Epic Games' big new Fortnite Disney offering, which is now mid-development</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Shows Off the Improved Anvil Engine, Shares New Tech Info]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-shows-off-the-improved-anvil-engine-shares-new-tech-info/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-shows-off-the-improved-anvil-engine-shares-new-tech-info.1107063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-shows-off-the-improved-anvil-engine-shares-new-tech-info/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Ubisoft <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xs2w3qSEBCs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> a new Assassin's Creed Shadows video to showcase the improvements of the latest Anvil Engine. This is largely what we covered <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-gamescom-preview-the-most-visually-advanced-assassins-creed-to-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in our Gamescom 2024 article</a> and the recent <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-pc-requirements-revealed-rtx-4090-for-4k60-with-max-ray-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC specs reveal</a>, albeit in a video format.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows features dynamic seasons, environmental destruction, dynamic wind and environmental particles, ray traced global illumination and reflections, and Nanite-like virtualized geometry. On PC, players will enjoy uncapped frame rate, Ultra-wide resolution support, dynamic resolution scaling support, an in-game benchmark tool, high customization for both graphics and gameplay, 'wide support for low and medium end' configurations, as well as all available upscaling and frame generation technologies. Intel XeSS 2 was singled out <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-intel-official-cpu-gpu-partner-assassins-creed-shadows-game-bundle-core-cpus-arc-gpus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">as part of Ubisoft's partnership with Intel for the game</a>, which will be specially optimized for Intel Core Ultra processors.</p>
<p><iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows: PC &amp; New-Gen Features Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xs2w3qSEBCs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Ubisoft also <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/4XbPPtFyQEtIMWrA9xVDmZ/assassins-creed-shadows-tech-qa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">answered</a> several technical questions from Reddit fans:</p>
<ul>
<li>The PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S|X versions of the game will both have a 4K upscaled, 60 FPS Performance Mode. There was no mention of PS5 Pro enhancements.</li>
<li>The Selective ray tracing preset will only apply ray traced effects to the Hideouts rather than the open world.</li>
<li>The new Atmos physics-based weather system lets Ubisoft simulate natural, dynamic cloud formations where transitions between weather states are more fluid. For example, after a storm, clouds dissipate naturally.</li>
<li>The dynamic weather and seasons can affect stealth. When it's raining, the sound covers your footsteps so you can move around without being heard as much. It also changes enemy patrols, as the higher classes will seek shelter from the rain. Seasons have an even greater effect, as some bushes/vegetation simply disappear in the winter months. Agriculture changes with the seasons, creating new hiding places, and snow can slow down Naoe, but not Yasuke. Finally, icicles can fall from roofs, creating noise distractions that enemies can actually hear and react to.</li>
<li>The environmental destructibility has been optimized in the latest Anvil engine by automatically merging objects into a single object as part of the build generation process, which limits CPU processing costs as a single object in the engine represents perhaps a dozen objects in the world. Furthermore, Ubisoft have offset the increased cost in physics simulation by making greater use of the GPU instance renderer, which is the Anvil engine's state-of-the-art system for offloading objects to the GPU for rendering.</li>
<li>On PC, the Field of View (FOV) can be tweaked from 85% to 115%. Motion blur can be toggled on and off.</li>
<li>The game won't be officially compatible with the Steam Deck, since Valve's handheld has lower specs than the minimum requirements.</li>
<li>Assassin's Creed Shadows supports cross-save and cross-progression.</li>
<li>The Ubisoft launcher won't be necessary when purchasing the game on Steam.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ubisoft also released the official macOS specs.</p>
<table id="table_1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.89"><strong>SOFTWARE</strong><br>
<strong>SELECTIVE RAY TRACING</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.96"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.97"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.95"><strong>SELECTIVE RAY TRACING</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.97"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"><strong>STANDARD RAY TRACING</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.97"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.96"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.32"><strong>PRESET</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.9">LOW</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.9">MEDIUM</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.94">HIGH</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.89">LOW</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.93">MEDIUM</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.91">LOW</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.93">MEDIUM</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.95">HIGH</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=96.82"><strong>RESOLUTION / FPS USING DYNAMIC RESOLUTION AND METALFX</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=94.08">720P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=97.09">1080P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=96.66">1440P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=94.91">720P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=98.21">1080P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=94.79">1080P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.01">1440P AT 30 FPS</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.44">1440P AT 30 FPS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.94"><strong>CHIP</strong></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=98.6">M1 MAX</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=98.37">M1 ULTRA</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.44">M2 ULTRA</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.43">M3</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.79">M4</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=88.72">M3 PRO</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=96.89">M4 PRO</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.66">M3 MAX</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.39">M2 PRO</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=97.59">M2 MAX</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=0"></td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.66">M4 MAX</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Pre-orders are open ahead of the new March 20 launch date. Ubisoft has <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-again-to-march-20-while-ubisoft-appoints-advisors-to-review-potential-company-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">delayed the game</a> twice in an attempt to avoid falling into the same trap of Star Wars Outlaws and other less-than-successful games released recently by the publisher.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Launching Perfect Couples Costumes on Valentine’s Day]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-launching-perfect-couples-costumes-on-valentines-day/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-launching-perfect-couples-costumes-on-valentine%E2%80%99s-day.1107057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-launching-perfect-couples-costumes-on-valentines-day/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you’re only going to be married to Marvel Rivals on Valentine’s Day, then the perfect costume bundle will be there for you if no one else will be. The 60th Wedding Anniversary Combo Bundle is releasing on February 14, featuring wedding outfits for both Mister Fantastic and Invisible Woman.</p>



<p>Somewhere, Namor is crying, but you can’t tell because he’s underwater.</p>



<h2 id="h-mister-fantastic-amp-invisible-woman-celebrate-their-anniversary-in-marvel-rivals">Mister Fantastic &amp; Invisible Woman Celebrate Their Anniversary in Marvel Rivals</h2>



<p>Inspired by The Life Fantastic series and the 2005 Wedding Special comic, the new costumes in Marvel Rivals celebrate the 60th wedding anniversary of Mister Fantastic and Invisible Woman. Both members of the Fantastic Four look their best in a stunning tuxedo and gorgeous wedding dress.</p>



<p>According to Marvel Rivals insider Miller Ross, both costumes will be <a href="https://x.com/mmmmmmmmiller/status/1889706032676348258" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">permanent additions</a> to the store. Each outfit can be bought on its own for 2,200 units, and includes the costume, an MVP animation, a nameplate, a spray, and an emote. The bundle that combines both of them is surely the better value, as you get both costumes and all the add-ons for just 2,800 units.</p>



<p>However, players also have the chance to pick up the bundle for free, by playing quickmatch at the same time and on the same server as a popular streamer. Streamers like Nadeshot, Emiru, and TimTheTatman <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/events/20250212/40956_1211432.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">are all participating</a> from February 12 to 13.</p>



<p>In-game purchases like costumes and battle passes have been the focal point of revenue for the free-to-play game. While no official numbers have been released, Chinese outlet Gamelook <a href="http://www.gamelook.com.cn/2025/01/562110/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">estimated</a> back in January that the game has pulled in “around 1 billion Yuan,” or around $136 million USD. This figure can be attributed to its large player base and consumer-friendly seasonal content plan, with developer NetEase <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-to-get-two-heroes-every-3-months/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">committing to the release of two new heroes each month</a>.</p>



<p>Are the Mister Fantastic and Invisible Woman wedding anniversary skins ones you’ll pick up? Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more coverage from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-cancels-mid-season-rank-reset/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NetEase’s decision to cancel mid-season rank resets in Marvel Rivals</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hungry Lamb: Traveling in the Late Ming Dynasty coming to Switch on March 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/the-hungry-lamb-traveling-in-the-late-ming-dynasty-coming-to-switch-on-march-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-hungry-lamb-traveling-in-the-late-ming-dynasty-coming-to-switch-on-march-13.1107051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/the-hungry-lamb-traveling-in-the-late-ming-dynasty-coming-to-switch-on-march-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 2P Games [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/2p-games">2P Games</a> and publisher and developer <a title="Companies > Zerocreation Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zerocreation-games">Zerocreation Games</a> will release <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > The Hungry Lamb: Traveling in the Late Ming Dynasty" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-hungry-lamb-traveling-in-the-late-ming-dynasty">The Hungry Lamb: Traveling in the Late Ming Dynasty</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,630 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on March 13, the companies <a href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000089975" target="_blank">announced</a>. It will support English, Japanese, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-943371"></span></p><p><em>The Hungry Lamb: Traveling in the Late Ming Dynasty</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2593370/The_Hungry_Lamb_Traveling_in_the_Late_Ming_Dynasty/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 22, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2593370/The_Hungry_Lamb_Traveling_in_the_Late_Ming_Dynasty/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Trek across ancient China in a dark, boundary-pushing visual novel inspired by traditional Chinese art with modern animation. Escort four girls to the prosperous city of Luoyang in a branching narrative with themes of revenge, cannibalism, involuntary servitude, and more on a redemptive journey.</p><p><strong>A Collapsing Empire</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>During Chongzhen’s Reign (A.D. 1628-1644), land annexation reached unmitigated extremes, the country faced domestic issues and foreign invasions, coinciding with the catastrophic Little Ice Age. After many years of horrid disasters in succession one after another, the Ming court continued to impose inhumane policies resulting in widespread starvation and leading to the rise of multiple rebellions against the court.</p><p><strong>A Travelling with Desperados</strong></p><p>Liang the bandit, and his companion are commissioned for a job from an unsavory merchant and must escort four girls to a wealthy lord in the city of Luoyang. They must pass through Huazhou, Wenxiang, Shanzhou, and finally reach their destination of Luoyang.</p><p>Liang initially believes that the girls he is escorting will be sold to the wealthy lord as adopted daughters to begin a new life. However, one of the four girls named “Sui” reveals the hidden secret of their journey to Luoyang.</p><p>The lord is a swine demon who has practiced devouring young ladies for over a thousand years. Every year on his birthday, he dispatches human traffickers to abduct girls from Shan in celebration of his special day. Sui’s sister was among the many who have fallen victim to the demon’s appetite.</p><p>Sui is hopeful that Liang will end the escort and join her in assassinating the swine demon to avenge her sister, and those who have perished in recent years. Although Liang wants to believe Sui, there are too many inconsistencies in her story. Throughout the journey, Liang will gather information, unravel the truth, and make his decisions accordingly.</p><p><strong>Lamb that Chooses to Be a Wolf</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Liang</strong> – Play as Liang, the main character and protagonist. His family has run a successful business for years, but Liang never saw himself as his father’s successor. Instead, he would rather travel the world as a hero and visit as many new locations as possible. The day of the Great Tianqi Explosion in 1626, was the day Liang lost everything. After becoming a refugee with nothing left to his name, he turned to a life of <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e. Liang became a bandit and makes a living by killing others for loot.</li><li><strong>Sui</strong> (voiced by Rie Kugimiya in Japanese, Hanser in Chinese) – Sui, a nine-year-old mute born in Luoyang. Her sister was killed by the swine demon that also dwells in Luoyang. To avenge her sister’s death, she intentionally let her self-become abducted to get close to the demon and assassinate him. Some, or all of the above statement is false, part of Sui’s untrustworthy nature.</li><li><strong>Tongue</strong> (voiced by Kazuma Horie in Japanese, Lengquan Yeyue in Chinese) Liang’s partner Tongue, the silver-tongued devil who is motivated by greed. When they work jobs together, Liang executes their target’s lives while Tongue works on securing loot.</li><li><strong>QuiongHua</strong> (voiced by Risa Shimizu in Japanese, Hualing in Chinese) – A girl from an authoritative family that was abducted by human traffickers. It is said to be a distant relative of governor general Yuan.</li><li><strong>Hong’er</strong> (voiced by Hiroko Watanabe in Japanese, Shi Yan in Chinese) – One of the two sisters from Northern Shannxi who was sold by her parents in a year of turmoil. She is full of vigor and an honest person, who cares deeply about her sister.</li><li><strong>Cui’er</strong> (voiced by Yuina Yamada in Japanese, Liu Yilei in Chinese) – One of the two sisters from Northern Shannxi, also sold by her parents. She is charming, pure of heart, and is also very dependent on her older sister.</li><li><strong>Kite</strong> (voiced by Hiroko Watanabe in Japanese, Yu Shan in Chinese) – An old friend of Liang, who owns an inn outside of Haizhou city.</li><li><strong>The Dashing King</strong> (voiced by Kazuma Horie in Japanese, Cheng Zhichao in Chinese) – In the fifth year of Chongzhen (1633), a rebel leader came to Jin from Shan and called himself the “Dashing King.”</li><li><strong>Swine Demon</strong> (voiced by Katsuya Miyamoto in Japanese, Wang Xigua in Chinese) – The swine demon disguised as a wealthy lord that devours young girls on his birthday for thousands of years, according to Sui. He is also the one who has commissioned Liang to escort the four girls to the city of Luoyang.</li></ul><p><strong>Unescapable Karma</strong></p><p>There are a variety of different endings and branch options, but good deeds cannot be rewarded during times of war. Pay for the crimes Liang has committed and suffer the consequences.</p><p>In addition to a rich storyline, our goal is to achieve the highest level of quality in a Chinese visual novel. Implementing a unique combination of traditional Chinese art and animation style, focusing on impasto painting technique. We rigorously follow the clothing, architecture, environment and other elements of the late Ming Dynasty, to bring both the historical atmosphere and visually appealing aesthetic to our audience.</p><p>We also strive to achieve the highest level of authenticity in terms of sound quality. Music and sound effects will be composed by Lin Fangzhou, alongside our producer who will also provide direction and creative input. Leng Quan Ye Yue will lead as the voice recording director, working alongside talents like Hanser, Hua Ling (<a title="Games > Genshin Impact [122 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a>, <a title="Games > Honkai: Star Rail [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a>), and others.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A mystery <a title="Genres > Horror [554 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> story around dark themes.</li><li>features 260,000 words of non-repetitive text and nine different endings, providing players with a high degree of decision making</li><li>Full voice-over lines with a professional cast.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the Chinese culture by immersing yourself in the history, the art, the music &amp; the amazing voice-over acting.</li></ul><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Production Team:</strong> Zerocreation Games</li><li><strong>Producer / Script/ Performance:</strong> Zero</li><li><strong>Character Design</strong> (for main and supporting characters): Hutao-o-Jiazi, Haishen</li><li><strong>Scene Design:</strong> fronzenX</li><li><strong>CG Director:</strong> Pazidinglu、Hutao-o-Jiazi, Huoji</li><li><strong>Character Design</strong> (for NPCs): Ziyinyin</li><li><strong>Diagram Design:</strong> Chazi</li><li><strong>Programming:</strong> Yaoshu</li><li><strong>Script / Performance Assistant:</strong> ice935, Jiuyue</li><li><strong>Art Assistant:</strong> Huoji, Xiaogutou</li><li><strong>Interface Design / Art Promotion:</strong> Xiazhongmao</li><li><strong>Sound Design:</strong> Lin Fangzhou</li><li><strong>Chinese Voice Recording Director:</strong> Lengquan Yeyue</li><li><strong>Chinese Voice Cast:</strong> hanser, Lengquan Yeyue, Hualing, Shi Yan, Liu Yile, Cheng Zhichao, Wang Xigua, Yu Shan, etc.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite May Be Gearing Up For Fast & Furious Season]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-may-be-gearing-up-for-fast-furious-season/1100-6529442/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-may-be-gearing-up-for-fast-furious-season.1107045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-may-be-gearing-up-for-fast-furious-season/1100-6529442/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529442">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There have been some rumblings in the past couple weeks that Fortnite would be collaborating with the Fast &amp; Furious movie franchise in the very near future--and those leaks took on a whole new meaning on Wednesday when we saw the very first teaser image for Chapter 6 Season 2, which showed a new version of Midas wearing Dominic Toretto's signature sleeveless black tee and gold chain--alongside a new season title, Lawless, and the launch date, February 21.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4442845-fortnitec6s2teaser.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442845" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4442845-fortnitec6s2teaser.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442845"></a><figcaption>Fortnite's Lawless season starts very soon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1757/17577455/4442845-fortnitec6s2teaser.jpg"></figure><p>You can see it there just the left of the season title--Midas Toretto right there on a wanted poster. It's an image that puts an entirely new spin on some recent leaks that had seemed pretty run-of-the-mill initially. Specifically, there were two leaks: that Dom's Dodge Charger <a href="https://x.com/SamLeakss/status/1886129604877804000" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">would finally be ported</a> from Rocket League to Fortnite, and that Dominic Toretto (Vin Diesel) and Han Lue (Sung Kang) <a href="https://x.com/Loolo_WRLD/status/1888663806428975496" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">would be getting skins</a>.</p><p>Since two Fast &amp; Furious cars were just brought over from Rocket League in the fall, it wasn't that big a deal to learn that others would follow. Rocket League has released five different Fast &amp; Furious cars over the years, and it only made sense to keep porting them. But the word that we'd be getting skins for Dom and Han made it clear that this stage of the Fast &amp; Furious collab would be a bigger deal--it indicated that Han's Mazda RX-7, also in Rocket League, could arrive imminently as well, for one thing. But now we have to also wonder if we might be getting one of these new character skins in the battle pass.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4442889-dominictorettofortnite.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442889" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1600" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4442889-dominictorettofortnite.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442889"></a><figcaption>Dominic Toretto's signature look.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4442889-dominictorettofortnite.jpg"></figure><p>This first official teaser, now, is only going to ramp up the speculation about whether this means that Chapter 6 Season 2 is an outright Fast &amp; Furious season. It's an exciting prospect for those who enjoy Fortnite's car-based gameplay, but it might inspire fear in the folks who detested last summer's divisive Wrecked season. But since the cars in Fast &amp; Furious are not usually weapon platforms, it's doubtful this car-based season would be quite as ridiculous as that one was.</p><p>Fortnite Chapter 6 Season 2 starts on Friday, February 21, and it's very gradually starting to come into focus as the big day inches closer and closer. We're tracking <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-season-2-start-date-theme-battle-pass-leaks-and-rumors/1100-6529339/" data-ref-id="1100-6529339">all the rumors and leaks about upcoming content in the new season right over here</a>, so you don't have to.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/112115755814061051052?rel=author">Phil Owen</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator's Wallace & Gromit DLC has a release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/powerwash-simulators-wallace-gromit-dlc-has-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulators-wallace-gromit-dlc-has-a-release-date.1107039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/powerwash-simulators-wallace-gromit-dlc-has-a-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-w%26g.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FuturLab/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Wallace &amp; Gromit are trading claymation for spray-mation on 4th March, when the beloved duo gets the muck-blasting <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/powerwash-simulator">PowerWash Simulator</a> treatment in a new paid DLC.
</p>
<p>
PowerWash Simulator's Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack was announced back in January - amid praise for the duo's recent movie release, Vengeance Most Fowl - when a "cracking cleaning adventure" for nozzle-hoisters was teased, spanning 62 West Wallaby Street and beyond.
</p>
<p>
Today's release date announcement - which happens to coincide with Gromit's birthday - doesn't offer much more in the way of specifics, but previous word from developer Futurlab said players would be de-griming locations including "charming British suburbs" and "cheesy celestial bodies." Some of those can be glimpsed in the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoDeGKEbAMQ">release date trailer</a> below.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PowerWash Simulator | Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack Release Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aoDeGKEbAMQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PowerWash Simulator | Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aoDeGKEbAMQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aoDeGKEbAMQ?autoplay=1" title="PowerWash Simulator | Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack Release Date Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoDeGKEbAMQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
FuturLab's Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack brings PowerWash Simulator's paid DLC releases up to six, following on from expansions themed around Shrek, Warhammer 40K, Back to the Future, SpongeBob SquarePants, and Alice in Wonderland.
</p>
<p>
PowerWash Simulator's Wallace &amp; Gromit Special Pack will be available for PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, Switch, and PC when it launches on 4th March. It won't, however, release on Meta Quest following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/powerwash-sim-kills-off-vr-support-in-bid-to-provide-job-security-for-the-team">FuturLab's decision to end support for the VR version</a> in order to provide "job security" for the team.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Considering Allowing Just Two Players]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-considering-allowing-just-two-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-considering-allowing-just-two-players.1107018/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-considering-allowing-just-two-players/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Elden Ring Nightreign <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-solo-or-trio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">isn’t going to launch</a> with the ability to play with just two players. However, that doesn’t mean it’s completely out of the question.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.ungeek.ph/2025/02/elden-ring-nightreign-director-says-they-are-considering-a-two-player-option/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ungeek</a>, Game Director Junya Ishizaki was asked about players who just want to play with one friend. Ishizaki says that, technically, players will be able to do that at launch. However, it’s not done in the traditional since.</p>



<p>Players will be able to queue up into the game with just one other person if they choose. They will then be matched up with a third random person to complete the required trio. So, while you can play with just one friend if you’d like, it won’t be the two-person run that many have asked about. </p>



<p>To that point, Ishizaki says that the team is thinking about it for a future update.</p>







<p>“Regarding having just two players, not three players or solo, it is something we are considering, but it is currently not in the game at the moment,” he said. </p>



<p>Announced at The Game Awards 2024, Elden Ring Nightreign is a standalone spin-off game set in the world of Elden Ring. Players will find themselves on a smaller map based on the region of Limgrave with enemies being randomized for each play.</p>



<p>The game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launches on May 30</a> for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC. </p>



<p>Do you want to see Elden Ring Nightreign to allow runs with just two players?&nbsp;Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">classic Call of Duty game</a>&nbsp;is scheduled to come to Xbox Game Pass in the coming months And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This $190 Elden Ring Nightreign Helmet Probably Won't Protect You, But At Least It Looks Cool]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-190-elden-ring-nightreign-helmet-probably-wont-protect-you-but-at-least-it-looks-cool/1100-6529441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-190-elden-ring-nightreign-helmet-probably-wont-protect-you-but-at-least-it-looks-cool.1107015/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-190-elden-ring-nightreign-helmet-probably-wont-protect-you-but-at-least-it-looks-cool/1100-6529441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529441">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date-trailer-news-everything-we-know/2900-6095/" data-ref-id="2900-6095">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> has an official release date of May 30, and fans looking to splurge on the co-op game can check out a very cool piece of merchandise being released alongside the standard and deluxe versions. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-preorder-guide/1100-6529431/">While there is a $200 collector's edition</a> that comes with extra DLC, art books, and a statue, there's also the <a href="https://store.bandainamcoent.com/elden-ring-nightreign-helmet-of-wylder/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$190 Wylder Helmet replica</a> that you can preorder through the Bandai Store.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4442886-wylder-helm.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442886" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4442886-wylder-helm.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442886"></a><figcaption>This helmet and the stand combined weigh quite a bit as well.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4442886-wylder-helm.jpg"></figure><p>This is described as a 1:1 scale replica of the hero's helmet, and it comes with everything you need to turn it into an attention-grabbing display piece in your home. Will it protect you from the Elden Lords, should they ever pierce the membrane separating our dimensions? Probably not, so you'll want to consider using it only for cosplay purposes. Bandai says only 9,999 of these will be made, and they'll be available starting May 30.</p><p>One thing to also note here is that you're not getting a copy of Elden Ring Nightreign with this replica, but it is a nice addition to your collection if you picked up any of the previously released Malenia and Messmer Elden Ring helmets that Bandai Namco sold for a limited time.</p><p>Elden Ring Nightreign is the latest entry in From Software's critically acclaimed souls-like franchise, following the release of Elden Ring in 2022 and its massive expansion Shadow of the Erdtree in 2024.</p><p>"Elden Ring Nightreign requires you to play a From Software game the wrong way. It asks players to prioritize aggression over stoicism; encourages almost reckless speed over careful strategy; and casts aside meticulous exploration for smash-and-grab expeditions," Tamoor Hussain wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-explores-exciting-and-unexpected-new-ground-for-from-software/1100-6529377/" data-ref-id="1100-6529377">Elden Ring Nightreign preview</a>.</p><p>The game will launch for PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X|S, and Xbox One in May, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-sign-up-for-elden-ring-nightreign-beta-registrations-live-now/1100-6528736/">and an invite-only network test will kick off on February 14</a> and run through February 17.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Has A Secret Ending You Only See If You're The Worst Person Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-has-a-secret-ending-you-only-see-if-youre-the-worst-person-ever/1100-6529439/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-has-a-secret-ending-you-only-see-if-youre-the-worst-person-ever.1107012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-has-a-secret-ending-you-only-see-if-youre-the-worst-person-ever/1100-6529439/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529439">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review-whats-old-is-new-again/1900-6418333/" data-ref-id="1900-6418333">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> lets players act however they want in a massive medieval open world, but like some of its fellow open-ended RPGs, certain actions have consequences. As it turns out, being an absolute menace to society at every chance you get unlocks a secret, morbid ending for protagonist Henry.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action-rpg/think-twice-before-causing-too-much-trouble-in-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-because-henry-can-and-will-get-executed-and-theres-a-heartbreaking-cutscene-for-it/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesRadar</a> spotted an X/Twitter post from a player and YouTuber <a href="https://x.com/NikTekOfficial" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">NikTekOfficial</a> that shows what happens when you "commit multiple crimes" in Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2, and it doesn't end well. This is the final step in the game's crime-and-punishment scale, as it gets more dire each time you're caught--something that NikTek also <a href="https://x.com/NikTekOfficial/status/1887654635319795970" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">covered</a>.</p><p><em>Warning!</em><em> Spoilers for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 below. </em></p><p>Eventually, guards will capture Henry if he gets too out of hand, giving him the option to pay off his sins. There's also the more ballsy route to continue the chaos by fighting his way out of the predicament. If you want to try to pay it off, the amount set is always too high and Henry can only say he can't afford the price. From there, he's thrown in prison awaiting the hangman.</p><p>A nearly two-minute cutscene follows that has Henry getting jeered and spit on by a crowd as he's escorted to the gallows. As the standing stool is kicked from under him, the game over screen reads, "You have been executed for your crimes." What a way to go.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft's Activision Blizzard takeover sparked by both companies failing to buy TikTok, Kotick says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-activision-blizzard-takeover-sparked-by-both-companies-failing-to-buy-tiktok-kotick-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsofts-activision-blizzard-takeover-sparked-by-both-companies-failing-to-buy-tiktok-kotick-says.1107006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-activision-blizzard-takeover-sparked-by-both-companies-failing-to-buy-tiktok-kotick-says<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"If the deal doesn't get done, we should sit down and talk."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_62oDWFG.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision / TikTok / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Former Activision Blizzard boss <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/bobby-kotick">Bobby Kotick</a> has shared the conversation he had with Microsoft boss Satya Nadella that would later lead to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-has-finally-bought-activision-blizzard">Xbox buying the Call of Duty maker for $67.8bn</a>.
</p>
<p>
Speaking on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2urSgcuyyo&amp;ab_channel=KleinerPerkins">Grit podcast</a>, Kotick recalled being involved in discussions around the sale of TikTok during US president Trump's first administration, back in 2020.
</p>
<p>
At the time, Kotick was himself interested in a bid to buy the smartphone social media giant. But, as has been widely reported, Microsoft was the frontrunner.
</p>
<p>
"Trump administration 1, they banned TikTok," Kotick said. "Microsoft was the only bidder. 
</p>
<p>
"I know the founder of ByteDance [Zhang Yiming] pretty well, he's a great guy... So I called Yiming and I said 'would you rather have Microsoft or rather have me?' He said 'I'd probably rather have you'."
</p>
<p>
Seemingly aware that even his pockets weren't big enough to outbid Microsoft, Kotick claims he floated an alternative option - that he and the Xbox owner share ownership of TikTok.
</p>
<p>
"I said it may be tough to pull it all together and I don't know that I have all the resources to do what will need to be done," Kotick continued. "Like, we don't have top secret security clearances with the government, I don't know what the National Security issues are going to be."
</p>
<p>
According to Kotick, Yiming said he should discuss the matter with Microsoft boss Satya Nadella. And it was during that next phone call that the idea of Microsoft buying Activision Blizzard was floated.
</p>
<p>
"So I called Satya and I said 'I don't want to bid against you, it would be great if we were partners in this, I think we're more of a consumer company than you are and I think I know a little bit more about social media than you do. We should do this together'," Kotick said.
</p>
<p>
"[Nadella] said 'look, we're further ahead than you, I don't even know if this deal is going to get done, I don't need a partner in this one'. And [then] he said, 'but if the deal doesn't get done, we should sit down and talk about us buying Activision."
</p>
<p>
And the rest is history: Microsoft did not buy TikTok at the time, but did eventually buy Activision Blizzard, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-activision-blizzard-deal-approved-by-uk-regulators">after a lengthy anti-competition process</a>.
</p>
<p>
Roll forward five years, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-in-talks-to-buy-tiktok-us-president-says">TikTok is once again banned, and Microsoft is once again the frontrunner to purchase it</a>.
</p>
<p>
But has Kotick given up his goal to own a piece of TikTok? When asked, the former CEO suggested he was not able to disclose the current situation: "I can't really talk about it," he concluded.
</p>
<p>
Kotick's wide-ranging interview also includes the eyebrow-raising claim by him that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bobby-kotick-says-activision-blizzard-fake-lawsuits-were-simply-a-union-plan-to-drive-up-membership">the various harassment lawsuits Activision Blizzard faced were "fake" and simply a "plan" to drive up union membership</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation State of Play February 2025 - Ghost of Yotei and Death Stranding 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-state-of-play-live-report-february-2025-ghost-of-yotei-and-death-stranding-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-ghost-of-yotei-and-death-stranding-2.1107003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-state-of-play-live-report-february-2025-ghost-of-yotei-and-death-stranding-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Live from 10pm UK time.</p>

<p><span>
  Live
</span>    </p></div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_t5VLGrW.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer / Sucker Punch</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>What is the state of play? Well, tonight Sony is going to tell us in a PlayStation State of Play broadcast, which begins at a not horrendous time of 10pm UK (5pm ET / 11pm CET). As always, we'll be running a blow-by-blow report here in this article, where you can also watch the stream and chat to us.</p>
<p>What are we likely to see tonight? The show will be 40-minutes long apparently (also not horrendous) and the chances of a Ghost of Yotei showing, and a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2</a> showing, seem high. We haven't seen either for a while and both are expected to release this year.</p>
<p>We're also hoping we might get a look at Bungie's long-in-development Marathon, which is a fitting name, and the much talked about multiplayer component to Horizon. Could we also be in for a glimpse of Insomniac's Wolverine? And what is remake specialist Bluepoint up to? What of the third-party games, too?</p>
<p>Much to wonder about. See you later?</p><figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="State of Play | February 12, 2025 [English]" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vQtPbTOhLEc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>State of Play | February 12, 2025 [English]</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vQtPbTOhLEc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vQtPbTOhLEc?autoplay=1" title="State of Play | February 12, 2025 [English]">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vQtPbTOhLEc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>





  
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>