<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:59:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[July 2025’s PS Plus Monthly Games include Diablo 4, as PS Plus celebrates 15th anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/the-july-2025s-ps-plus-monthly-games-include-diablo-4-celebrates-15th-anniversary/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/july-2025%E2%80%99s-ps-plus-monthly-games-include-diablo-4-as-ps-plus-celebrates-15th-anniversary.1228248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony has revealed the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps-plus">PS Plus</a> monthly games for July 2025, as well as detailing some of what will happen to mark and celebrate the 15th anniversary of the subscription service, which launched in a very different guise all the way back in 2010.</p>
<p>Let’s not mess about, though. PS Plus this month includes Diablo 4, and two other games, which are…</p>


<p><span>What are the PS Plus July 2025 Monthly Games?</span></p>
<p>There’s a solid trio of titles for PS Plus this month, which includes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Diablo IV</strong> | PS5, PS4</li>
<li><strong>King of Fighters XV</strong> | PS5, PS4</li>
<li><strong>Jusant</strong> | PS5</li>
</ul>
<p>Obviously <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/06/08/diablo-iv-review/"><strong>Diablo IV</strong></a> is the headline act here, with Blizzard’s latest action RPG title looking to completely overhaul how it taps into online features, building more of a live game to compliment the moreish loot hunting. There’s been a bunch of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/03/diablo-iv-season-of-loot-reborn-review/">seasons</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/25/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-dlc-review/">expansion</a> content added to the game since launch in 2023, but at the time Gamoc said, “Diablo IV is almost shockingly refined, with an absorbing story and addictive gameplay. The shift to always online and connected play might turn some away, and the level scaling can make combat a little same-y, but on the whole, this is still Diablo at its best. It plays very well, offers tonnes of options for tailoring your character and acquiring that all important hunt for better and better loot will keep you coming back for more.”</p>


<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/02/15/king-of-fighters-xv-15-review/"><strong>King of Fighters XV</strong></a> revived the long-running fighting game series, back in 2022. SNK’s storied series had gone pretty quiet through the previous decade, but came back with a hefty punch. Dom said in our review, “King of Fighters XV marks an excellent return for the series, modernising it at nearly every turn. While we await a story that’ll finally do justice to the characterful roster, it stakes a claim to SNK’s past with an eye firmly on the future.”</p>

<p>Alas, we have no review of Jusant to draw upon, but Don’t Nod’s climbing game was certainly fascinating to see developed and released. It’s both an action-puzzle climbing game where you try to clamber up the side of a huge tower, but it’s also a meditative journey because of this, with secrets from a lost civilisation to uncover.</p>
<h2>What’s happening for the PS Plus 15th Anniversary?</h2>
<p>Sony has pulled together a bunch of new game trials for PS Plus Premium members, some special offers, exclusive Valorant content, and PS Tournaments. Oh, and a free weekend!</p>
<p>Here’s everything that’s happening:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Let’s Wrestle! </strong>– starting today, PS Plus Premium members can jump into a Game Trial of WWE 2K25. Launched in March this year, the latest game in 2K’s incredible wrestling franchise is one of the best yet. So, dive into the action and experience the thrill of playing as your favorite wrestler right now!</li>
<li><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds </strong>– another exciting Game Trial opportunity for PS Plus Premium members. The ultimate hunting experience awaits in Monster Hunter Wilds – available from June 30.</li>
<li><strong>PlayStation Store Exclusive Offer Weekend </strong>– this coming weekend (June 27 – 29), we’ll be offering PlayStation Plus members the opportunity to grab exclusive savings on must-play titles such as Sniper Elite: Resistance, Sid Meier’s Civilization® VII and Star Wars Outlaws.</li>
<li><strong>Valorant PS Plus Pack </strong>– also starting today, all PS Plus members can redeem a Valorant pack at no extra cost which includes: 2x Prelude to Chaos Gun Buddy, 1x Kohaku &amp; Matsuba Player Card, 1x Imperium Spray, 1x Chronovoid Spray, 10x Radianite Points. All items are cosmetic and do not affect gameplay.</li>
<li><strong>PlayStation Tournaments</strong> – starting this Saturday (June 28), we’ll be hosting a special PlayStation Plus 15th Anniversary Cup tournament. Players will get the opportunity to compete in popular titles like EA Sports FC, NBA 2K, UFC, Madden NFL, College Football, Tekken 8, and more for a chance to win prizes including in-game virtual currency, an exclusive PSN avatar, and Sony Pictures Core Movie Credits. Access the Tournament through custom tournament cards or the in-game menu, choose your competition, and prepare to showcase your skills in exciting 1v1 matchups.*</li>
<li><strong>Sony Pictures Core</strong> – From today through August 12, PlayStation Plus Premium members can unlock a 15% discount on up to 2,000 movies store-wide straight from your console across the Sony Pictures Core library**. Please note, movie titles are subject to change without notice and vary by market.</li>
<li><strong>Online Multiplayer Weekend </strong>– we’ll have an Online Multiplayer weekend this Saturday and Sunday (June 28 at 12:01am to June 29 at 11:59pm local time) where all players can join online multiplayer matches with no PlayStation Plus membership required.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Can you still get the June 2025 PS Plus games?</h2>
<p>Yes! You’ve got until Monday 20th June to claim your PS Plus games, which include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>NBA 2K25</strong> | PS5, PS4</li>
<li><strong>Alone in the Dark (2024)</strong> | PS5</li>
<li><strong>Bomb Rush Cyberfunk</strong> | PS5, PS4</li>
<li><strong>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</strong> | PS5, PS4</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/25/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-july-a-big-thank-you-to-players-for-15-wonderful-years/">PS Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/the-july-2025s-ps-plus-monthly-games-include-diablo-4-celebrates-15th-anniversary/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The FTC Will Send More Than $126 Million In Refunds To Players Over Unwanted Fortnite Purchases, Reopens Claims Process For Two More Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks.1228245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The FTC <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2025/06/ftc-sends-126-million-refunds-fortnite-players-who-were-charged-unwanted-items-reopens-claims?utm_source=govdelivery">announced today</a> that it will send refunds to players who made unwanted purchases in Fortnite, with the refunds totaling over $126 million. The agency will also reopen the process for players and their parents or guardians to make claims for further compensation from now until <strong>July 9, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>This latest batch of refunds is a follow-up from the 629,344 refunds issued in <a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-users-refunds-are-being-issued-by-the-ftc-following-settlement-of-fortnite-case/">December 2024</a> over what the FTC described as "<em>deceptive</em>" practices from Epic that led to players making unwanted purchases in the first place.</p>
<p>While the agency disclosed the average refund amount in December to be $114 per person, it does not disclose what the average refund will be this time around, perhaps due to the fact that there's still time for people to submit claims. Beginning today, however, either through PayPal or a check, the FTC will begin delivering <strong>969,173</strong> refunds.</p>
<p>If you selected to receive a check on your claim form, the FTC recommends you cash it within 90 days. PayPal recipients should redeem their refund within 30 days.</p>
<p>Including today's batch of refunds, the FTC has now provided players with more than <strong>$200 million</strong> as part of the FTC's punitive action against Epic Games.</p>
<p>This claims process began in <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/09/ftc-announces-claims-process-fortnite-players-who-were-charged-unwanted-items">September 2023</a> and is part of the $245 million Epic was fined for its practices regarding microtransactions in Fortnite. The first claims process lasted from September 2023 to January 2024, though if you missed that window, you now have an extra two weeks to get your cut of the refunds from Epic Games.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-ftc-will-send-more-than-126-million-in-refunds-to-players-over-unwanted-fortnite-purchases-reopens-claims-process-for-two-more-weeks/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy is in control]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/691964/remedy-entertainment-profile-alan-wake-control-fbc-firebreak</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-is-in-control.1228242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>In the quiet city of Espoo, a short drive west from Helsinki in Finland, is an unassuming building that’s home to one of the most confounding studios in games. Remedy Entertainment is known for getting <em>weird</em>. It started with the meta horror of <em>Alan Wake</em>, and has since expanded with <em>Control</em>, a game that turns a bureaucratic government office into a sinister and unsettling battleground. Their worlds merge the surreal and the mundane — which is not a bad description of Remedy itself. </p><p>On the day I visited, the studio’s energy was relaxed and subdued — in true Finnish style, there are even multiple onsite saunas — and frankly a little boring, especially for a creative team known for the likes of the mind-bending <a href="https://control.fandom.com/wiki/Ashtray_Maze">Ashtray Maze</a> or “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uxs_HYw_mLk">Old Gods of Asgard</a>” musical. But that contrast is also one of the keys to Remedy’s recent success.</p><p>In the wake of the covid-19 pandemic, the video game industry has experienced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276700/netflix-gaming-studio-closure-blue">studio closures</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/22/24349728/gdc-state-of-the-industry-survey-2025-results">persistent layoffs</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/685322/how-ea-killed-the-dragon-age">corporate meddling</a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/29/24282900/sony-shutting-down-concord-firewalk-studios">ill-fated games that were canceled soon after launch</a>. Exceptions like Remedy have been rare. Over the past decade, the studio has been implementing a plan to help it compete with bigger, better-funded developers and publishers, steadily inching its way from a work-for-hire studio to one in charge of its own destiny. As the industry has shifted toward live-service hits like <em>Fortnite</em> and blockbusters like <em>Grand Theft Auto</em>, Remedy has taken big swings with ambitious and delightfully strange narrative titles.</p><p>Now it’s trying to expand even further with its first multiplayer — and self-published — game in <em>FBC: Firebreak</em>. The stakes are high: it’s the perfect example of Remedy’s new way of working and a proof of concept for its larger, more expansive future. It’s also a strange experience, marrying the surreal tone of <em>Control</em> with co-op play that bucks the latest online gaming trends. But to hear it from the Finnish developer, it only gets to take swings like <em>Firebreak</em> because it nailed all of the boring stuff first.</p><p>“We are this building,” explains creative director Mikael Kasurinen. “This is it; this is us. We aren’t owned by anybody else, and I think that realization brings that culture of taking more responsibility. There is nothing above us that will save the day if things go wrong. It’s all on us.”</p><p>This wasn’t the case for much of the studio’s existence. Founded in 1995, Remedy’s first release was a combat racing game called <em>Death Rally</em>. A few years later, the studio garnered widespread acclaim with 2001’s <em>Max Payne</em>, a hard-boiled noir with action ripped out of a John Woo movie. After a sequel, Remedy expanded in new directions with the survival horror game <em>Alan Wake</em> and sci-fi game / TV show hybrid <em>Quantum Break</em>.</p><p>Despite its modest success, though, the studio found itself stuck in a cycle of working from game to game. It didn’t own any of its creations — instead, they were the property of publishers like Rockstar and Microsoft — and, with the exception of the rapid 18-month development of <em>Max Payne 2</em>, Remedy was only putting out new games every five years or so. That half-decade cycle meant that if any game failed, so did the company.</p><p>This put Remedy in a precarious position, and it’s something Tero Virtala realized right away when he took over as CEO in 2016. “At that point Remedy had been around for 20 years, and succeeded in relation to many criteria,” Virtala says. That included releasing several hit games and steadily growing in headcount. But Virtala says that “it didn’t feel like enough” to have such a talented team and only release one game every four or five years. While it’s typical for games to take years to build, only having one project at a time left the studio vulnerable in case any of them flopped.</p><p>Virtala helped spearhead a new path for Remedy’s future built on two pillars: One was becoming a multi-project studio, so that it was less dependent on any single game. Second, Remedy also wanted ownership of its original creations and to eventually become its own publisher.</p><div><p>“It’s important to understand enough of the business, even though I don’t love it.”</p></div><p>A major part of making this work was ensuring that everyone in the studio bought in and understood the plan, not just management. It sounds like a controversial idea and runs counter to the way the industry typically works: whereas most studios operate with clear lines dividing creative and business, Virtala believed that empowering developers to understand the business side meant they’d be better able to make the right decisions on the creative end.</p><p>“People are smart,” Virtala says of his employees, “and they are mature enough to understand that if you want to make creative, ambitious games, it’s not possible unless you have the financial basis, unless you are aligned with the technology, unless you have the people and the production plans are in order. We try to provide the teams with as much information as possible. And then the teams are in the best place to try to figure out what is the best creative path within these constraints.”</p><p>And it seems that the creative side has bought in. Sam Lake has been with Remedy for nearly its entire 30-year existence, starting out as a writer on <em>Death Rally</em>. (He’s also the face of the original Max Payne — <a href="https://www.vg247.com/alan-wake-2-director-sam-lake-may-regret-using-likeness-in-max-payne">literally</a>.) He now serves as creative director and is the lead writer behind all of Remedy’s major franchises. “It’s important to understand enough of the business, even though I don’t love it,” Lake says. “When you’re creating a game concept, there are a lot of decisions being made, and the more you understand about what these decisions affect, the better you are prepared to choose wisely.”</p><p>The real turning point came with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/26/20832997/control-review-creators-thriller-ps4-xbox-pc">the launch of <em>Control</em> in 2019</a>, the first game released under Virtala’s leadership. While the idea for the story and world had been kicking around in Lake’s head for some time, the actual development happened as Virtala was implementing broader studio changes. He pushed for more efficient processes and timelines, hoping to make games faster without sacrificing the quality level Remedy had become known for.</p><p>“Those three years were transformative for Remedy,” Kasurinen says. He notes that this new development style meant planning much more in advance on <em>Control</em>, and viewing limitations around budgets and timelines as creative challenges “that forced us to reinvent many things in a good way.” When it came out, <em>Control</em> exemplified exactly what the studio wanted to be: it was developed in a comparatively brisk three years, was a brand-new property that the studio would (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/28/24085807/remedy-is-now-in-control">eventually</a>) own outright, and was in development alongside another project in collaboration with Korean publisher Smilegate. Creatively, it also allowed the team to attempt a new kind of open-ended action game and it opened up new directions for the future.</p><div><p><em>Control</em>’s success allowed this plan to continue. Since then, Remedy has steadily expanded. <em>Control</em> was followed by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23934662/alan-wake-2-review-ps5-xbox-pc">a long-awaited sequel to <em>Alan Wake</em></a>, and the studio has grown to 380 people. It currently has four projects in development: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/19/24300511/control-2-action-rpg">a sequel to <em>Control</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/6/23013920/max-payne-1-2-remakes-remedy-rockstar-take-two">remakes of the <em>Max Payne</em> games</a>, an unannounced title, and its first multiplayer game, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/665752/fbc-firebreak-preview-interview-remedy-control-ps5-xbox">the recently launched <em>Control</em> spinoff <em>FBC: Firebreak</em></a>. With the exception of <em>Max Payne</em>, which is being published by Rockstar, all of its in-development games are self-published.</p></div><p>Remedy now also <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2019/07/01/1876391/0/en/REMEDY-ENTERTAINMENT-PLC-Remedy-records-2-5-million-euros-of-one-time-royalty-income-from-previously-released-games.html">holds the publishing rights for <em>Alan Wake</em></a> (the sequel was originally published by Epic Games), and has created its own connected universe, which unites the worlds of <em>Alan Wake</em> and <em>Control</em>. In 2024 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/29/24231469/control-sequel-movie-tv-remedy-annapurna">it partnered with Annapurna Pictures</a> to potentially expand this even further through film and TV adaptations. Branching out into new genres and mediums is a further attempt to grow Remedy’s capabilities — and to better insulate itself from the volatile whims of the games industry.</p><p>Getting to this moment required some structural changes. Remedy now has multiple development teams, with staff shifting between them as needed, and it also has a unique setup with two creative directors in Lake and Kasurinen. Lake says that both of them want to be hands-on when they’re leading a new game, and so having two people in the role allows the creative side to always be involved in larger studio decisions, even in the midst of an intense development process.</p><p>“When I was deep into <em>Alan Wake 2</em>, I wasn’t a part of attending weekly management meetings,” Lake says. “I just needed to focus on [the game]. But it’s really important that we have the creative side represented on the company level. So this arrangement gives us flexibility. We can represent each other.”</p><p>Even still, the transition wasn’t always smooth. As Remedy attempted to grow into a multi-project studio, not all of its expansion attempts worked out. First, the studio partnered with Smilegate on a new iteration of the popular military shooter <em>Crossfire</em>. The idea was that Smilegate would make the multiplayer portion of the game, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21334562/crossfirex-remedy-trailer-xbox-one-series-x-smilegate-fps">while Remedy would craft a single-player story mode</a>, giving the studio a chance to make its first first-person shooter. But <em>CrossfireX</em> was poorly received upon release in 2022 — campaign mode included — and shut down a year later.</p><div><p>Remedy also attempted to get into the world of free-to-play games through a partnership with Tencent, but the title — known as Project Vanguard — <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-remedy-entertainment-plans-to-reboot-codename-vanguard-to-a-premium-game-with-a-strong-cooperative-multiplayer-component/">eventually shifted to a premium release</a>, before finally being <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-codename-kestrel-cancelled-as-remedy-focuses-on-existing-franchises/">canceled before it was ever shown to the public</a>.</p></div><p>Virtala says that these setbacks were largely a result of pushing too far too fast. And in the case of Vanguard, the failure helped the studio realize that four games at a time was the sweet spot for what the company could manage. “We started to feel that we had a bit too many projects for our size of organization,” he explains. “We saw that if we had a bit more focus, it would help our other projects to succeed.”</p><p>But those failures don’t mean Remedy is done trying new things. In fact, the studio’s first fully self-published game, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/665752/fbc-firebreak-preview-interview-remedy-control-ps5-xbox"><em>FBC: Firebreak</em></a>, is also one of its most surprising releases. It’s a multiplayer shooter, which might sound like an odd release from a studio known for single-player narratives. But as the studio looked to expand, multiplayer was one of the key areas the team wanted to explore.</p><div><p>“We want to explore ways of building new types of experiences.”</p></div><p><em>Firebreak</em> is a relative baby step in that direction. It’s connected to a popular game the studio owns, and it was built by a small internal team. While regular updates are planned — <a href="https://x.com/ControlRemedy/status/1932800170850152957">including “major” releases in the fall and winter</a> — <em>Firebreak</em> isn’t a live-service game on par with <em>Fortnite </em>or <em>Call of Duty</em>, designed to keep players coming back with ongoing events and daily activities. It’s a paid game <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/horror/remedy-director-says-that-fbc-firebreak-respects-player-time-instead-of-relying-on-fomo-which-has-infected-modern-games/">meant explicitly to “respect the player’s time.”</a> It’s also a way for the studio to expand its capabilities without stretching the team too far.</p><p>“We want to explore ways of building new types of experiences,” says Mike Kayatta, game director on <em>Firebreak</em>. “I like to think that we know what we’re doing when it comes to these large, single-player story-driven games. This is how the studio built its reputation and what it’s good at. When you’re faced with saying, ‘Hey, we need to diversify the types of experiences we’re making,’ do you really just want to just make five more of these linear, story-driven games?”</p><p>So far, <em>Firebreak</em>’s release hasn’t gone exactly to plan. It was greeted with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/689333/fbc-firebreak-review-xbox-ps5-steam">mixed reviews from critics and players</a>, many of whom complained that, while it maintains some of the weird and unsettling tone as <em>Control</em>, it’s held back by repetitive gameplay and a lack of Remedy-style narrative flourishes. But the studio seems intent on fixing things, recently posting an extensive list of <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/2272540/announcements/detail/536605349656920273">patch notes</a> and other upcoming changes that cover everything from the onboarding experience to the UI. “Several things have gone well,” <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/2272540/announcements/detail/536605349656920275">the studio wrote</a>. “Clearly, not everything has.”</p><p>The success of a game like <em>Firebreak </em>is still critical for Remedy even under its multi-project structure. It’s a complex plan that has kept Virtala very busy over the last 10 years. In fact, when I spoke to him in an empty conference room at Remedy’s office, he was delayed because he had to prepare for the studio’s most recent financial report the next day. “Every single game is highly important for us,” Virtala says. “There is no question that we are not fully insulated. But we are less dependent on any single game than we used to be.”</p><div><p>This feeling is only strengthened by the current realities of the gaming industry. It’s a space where even <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675923/black-panther-cancelled-cliffhanger-studios-shut-down-ea">a well-funded EA studio can’t get a Black Panther game made</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/29/24282900/sony-shutting-down-concord-firewalk-studios">a Sony-backed multiplayer shooter in development for eight years, <em>Concord</em>, is quickly shuttered</a>, and the likes of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/22/24276700/netflix-gaming-studio-closure-blue">Netflix</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686351/amazon-games-christoph-hartmann-twitch-luna-new-world">Amazon</a> are struggling to make headway despite huge investments. Remedy is currently in a good place, with a growing back catalog and multiple games in development, and while it has grown, it’s still a fraction of the size of most other studios making big-budget games, which often have headcounts in the thousands. </p></div><p>While the last decade has been a big shift at Remedy, Lake describes his time at the studio as being filled with constant change, as the company steadily grew in terms of both staff and the scale of its projects. Even still, he believes that the current incarnation of the studio might be ideal for this multi-project structure, and says that he “would be surprised” if Remedy continued to grow significantly over the next few years. While many large studios are seemingly focused on perpetual growth, the team at Remedy is happy to be sustainable.</p><p>“There were a couple of false starts trying to get there, but now it feels very much like we’re settled,” says Lake. “This is what Remedy is now.”</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/691964/remedy-entertainment-profile-alan-wake-control-fbc-firebreak]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Is The Most Devastating Way I've Ever Seen A Show Announce It Was Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/tiny-chef-nickelodeon-canceled-season-3-kristen-bell-1851785074</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-is-the-most-devastating-way-ive-ever-seen-a-show-announce-it-was-canceled.1228236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="a709c966c72abd2587c16e206dceb78c" data-recommend-id="image://a709c966c72abd2587c16e206dceb78c" data-format="png" data-width="1178" data-height="663" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Tiny Chef cries. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Tiny Chef cries. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Tiny Chef / YouTube</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a709c966c72abd2587c16e206dceb78c" data-recommend-id="image://a709c966c72abd2587c16e206dceb78c" data-format="png" data-width="1178" data-height="663" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Tiny Chef cries. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The first time I heard RuPaul’s voice introduce the <em>Tiny Chef</em> cooking show, starring a Gumbi-like green fur-ball that slobbers over his words like a St. Bernard chewing baseballs, I knew it was going to be something special. Less than three years and 41 episodes later it’s been unexpectedly canceled by Nickelodeon, and one of the most emotionally gut-punching viral pieces of animation I’ve ever seen is not how I expected to find out. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197586" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Disney+ Pulls The Abyss Over Controversial Rat Scene — Again" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="128" data-playlist="197586,197585,197583" data-current="197586"><div><p>Disney+ Pulls The Abyss Over Controversial Rat Scene — Again</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23107.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I know <em>Tiny Chef</em> mostly through my kids who watch older episodes streaming online. A riff on both cooking shows and late night talk show hosts, it’s a bit like foodie’s equivalent of<em> Reading Rainbow </em>presented in a stop-motion style with a Wes Anderson-like sensibility. It educates kids on the basics of how the food they put in their bodies is grown and prepared. Maybe they learn a greater appreciation for cooking. At the very least they aren’t rotting their brains on algorithmic YouTube garbage. </p><p>So like most people, including those who watch <em>Tiny Chef</em>, I stumbled upon its cancellation announcement completely by accident when a now-viral short of the titular character getting the bad news directly from the execs at Nickelodeon popped into one of my social feeds. “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o2uQbr3f_-I&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o2uQbr3f_-I" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tiny Chef needs your help</a></span>,” reads the title of a YouTube video uploaded on June 24. In it, Tiny Chef is humming to himself and dusting his room when the news gets broken to him that the show is finished. “But I have ideas that will blow your mind,” he adorably lisps into the phone. <br></p><p>Instead of getting angry and blowing up he finally says, “I understand,” and tries to go back to cleaning before breaking down and sitting on his bed with his head in his hands. It’s crushing. “That little attempt to straighten himself out and then get back to what he was doing only to immediately break down...that’s REAL grief right there,” reads one of the top YouTube comments. “I didn’t know about this show until 10 minutes ago,” reads another. “But the depiction of the chef trying to be strong while this clearly gets to him is something I can relate to a lot and that clearly the creators understand very well.”</p><p>“<em>Tiny Chef</em> and the team need your help now more than ever!” reads a call for donations on the show’s website. “Many of you have said that you would die for <em>Tiny Chef</em>, we don’t need all that (!!!) but we do need crowd funding to keep going.” The creators have asked people to subscribe to the YouTube channel as well. It’s unclear at this point if the plan is to keep producing new episodes independently or try to demonstrate enough support so that one of the streaming services orders new episodes. </p><p>The show was created by animator Rachel Larsen, co-creators Adam Reid and Ozlem Akturk, and counts Kristen Bell of <em>Veronica Mars</em> fame as one of its producers and most frequent guest star. It’s the kind of kids’ programming that seems like a perfect fit for Disney or Apple. Brian Grazer and Ron Howard’s Imagine Entertainment took an equity stake in <em>Tiny Chef</em> back in 2019, so I’m sure it will find its feet. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/tiny-chef-nickelodeon-canceled-season-3-kristen-bell-1851785074]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can You Solo Dune: Awakening?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-multiplayer-1000-solaris-pvp-pve-hagga-1851784965</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/can-you-solo-dune-awakening.1228230/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Can you imagine wandering the world of Arrakis on your own? It’s a daunting prospect, considering the size of the sandworms below and the spaceships above all vying for your head. Thankfully, <em>Dune: Awakening</em> offers options. You’ll always play on a server with other people, but how social you want to be is completely up to you. From one solo player to another, multiplayer isn’t all that scary. Here’s how it works in <em>Dune Awakening</em>!</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196307" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode " data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="657" data-playlist="196307,196909,195891" data-current="196307"><div><p>10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode </p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21857.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h849378"><a id=""></a>How multiplayer works in <em>Dune Awakening</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="ebbdbcf5aca6c002448360b14ae83e2c" data-recommend-id="image://ebbdbcf5aca6c002448360b14ae83e2c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A player satanding in front of a sandworm." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A player satanding in front of a sandworm." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Funcom / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ebbdbcf5aca6c002448360b14ae83e2c" data-recommend-id="image://ebbdbcf5aca6c002448360b14ae83e2c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A player satanding in front of a sandworm." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>When you first start your journey in <em>Dune: Awakening</em>, you’re thrust into a smaller zone that’s more story-centric, allowing you to grasp the ropes of desert survival without worrying about the greater overarching war ongoing across Arrakis: the war for spice. You’ll find yourself traversing Hagga Basin, a mostly PvE zone filled with quests, events, and opportunities to learn the game’s mechanics, combat, and crafting.</p><p>It can take some folks approximately 50 hours to fully prep for the game’s endgame, known as the Deep Desert, though some take up to 100 hours to reach this point by playing slowly. What is the Deep Desert in <em>Dune: Awakening</em>? It’s the ultimate battleground. Here, you’ll battle with 300 other players, fighting for spice and politics far above your station.</p><p>But worry not, the Deep Desert also features a PvE zone, should you rather avoid open combat with other players!</p><h2 id="h849379"><a id=""></a>How to play with friends in <em>Dune Awakening</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="ce6826bd566af634de914c46d9ad5416" data-recommend-id="image://ce6826bd566af634de914c46d9ad5416" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The guild screen in Dune Awakening." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The guild screen in Dune Awakening." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Funcom / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ce6826bd566af634de914c46d9ad5416" data-recommend-id="image://ce6826bd566af634de914c46d9ad5416" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The guild screen in Dune Awakening." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Everything is better with friends, right? Sure, some of those things are better left unsaid, but we’re talking about playing <em>Dune Awakening</em> multiplayer, of course. You have options here, including joining a guild, partying up with others, and spending a bit of real-world money to host a private server with just you and your buddies.</p><p>To play with your pals:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Open your map, then select the social menu from the bottom of the HUD.</li><li>Check the players tab to see active players in the server, or search for your friend’s name manually, before sending out a friend request.</li><li>Select your prospect once they add you, then hit invite to party.</li></ul><p>Alternatively, your friend can invite you, which causes a pop-up to appear on your HUD. If you hit ‘Enter’ when it appears, you’ll join their group, so long as there’s room. Only four players can play in a group.</p><p>You can also form a guild for 1,000 Solaris—<em>Dune Awakening</em>’s in-game currency—and amass a small army of players for when you reach the Deep Desert. Sure, it’s expensive and you could use that money for better gear and other investments, but think about all the fun you’ll have with your buddies!</p><hr><p><em>Dune Awakening</em> launches on June 10th on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Windows PCs.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-multiplayer-1000-solaris-pvp-pve-hagga-1851784965]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil's Raccoon City: A Complete History - From Sleepy Town to Zombie Nightmare]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-you-need-to-know-about-resident-evils-raccoon-city</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evils-raccoon-city-a-complete-history-from-sleepy-town-to-zombie-nightmare.1228215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Survival horror is finally coming home. Raccoon City is the setting for the classic Resident Evil games, its awesome remakes, and some surprisingly relevant spinoffs. As far as iconic locations in zombie fiction go, Raccoon City easily hangs in the hallowed company of holy horror spaces like the Monroeville Mall and the Winchester pub.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as it seemed that Resident Evil had definitively closed the book on RC, Capcom announced a return to the ruins of Raccoon City for the ninth main entry in its seminal survival horror series. For longtime fans, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> feels like it could be a joyous reunion...</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But life in Raccoon City can be… complicated. Infrequent visitors might find themselves asking questions like “Where am I?” “What the heck happened here?” "Does the world know about the miraculous healing powers of colored herbs?" and “Why do I have to put jewels in a statue when I go to the DMV?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s why we’ve assembled this ultimate field guide to Raccoon City. We’ll explore RC’s behind-the-scenes history, discuss everything that went down in the games, unpack the town’s enduring appeal, and solve a few mysteries along the way. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Why “Raccoon City?”</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Introduced in the opening seconds of the original <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil">Resident Evil</a>, or “Bio Hazard” in Japan, “Raccoon City” had an important role to play in establishing the series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Resident Evil’s predecessor, the Japan-only Famicom game Sweet Home, took place in a haunted mansion in the Japanese countryside. Producer Tokuro Fujiwara wanted to remake the 8-bit cult classic for a new generation of consoles, but Capcom no longer had the rights to the film from which Sweet Home was adapted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So Fujiwara and director Shinji Mikami reworked the concept to center around zombies instead of haunted paintings, envisioning the game as an interactive horror movie, complete with a haunting score, cinematic pre-rendered backgrounds, and jump scares a-plenty. Instead of taking inspiration from supernatural, psychological J-horror such as Sweet Home, the developers instead looked toward the West.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/rc-new-1-1750851537527.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The terrifying streets of Raccoon City in Resident Evil 3. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Resident Evil clearly owes a massive debt to George A. Romero, the godfather of the zombie genre who shot his movies in the small cities surrounding Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Setting the game in a fictional Anytown, U.S.A. allowed Capcom to capture the vibe of classics like Dawn of the Dead and create inroads to a Western audience more effectively than any live-action FMV sequence with cheesy American actors</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Early drafts of Bio Hazard had the action taking place in a town called “Harnbee,” located in either New Jersey or Arkansas. Capcom ultimately decided to name the city after an animal, which isn’t strange by itself, as the fine folks from Buffalo, New York or Dinosaur, Colorado will tell you. Still, adorable trash pandas seem like an odd choice for spine-chilling survival horror.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One longstanding theory is that Capcom was referencing the species of “raccoon dog” called tanuki, which Western gamers might be familiar with from its presence in Japanese folklore and pop culture. These cute little guys look a lot like raccoons, save for some slight anatomical differences, and they’ve quite frequently appeared in video games. So could “Raccoon City” just be a localized version of “Tanuki Town?” It’s not likely. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For one thing, tanuki aren’t even raccoons at all as far as taxonomy is concerned. More importantly, the original Bio Hazard refers to its setting as “Rakūn Shiti,” using the English transliteration of “raccoon” as opposed to “tanuki” or “araiguma,” the Japanese word for the actual species. With Raccoon City, Capcom is very specifically referring to the North American mammals. But why?</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/rc-new-2-1750851561728.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The skyline of Raccoon City. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Raccoons aren’t native to Japan, but in the ‘70s, a popular anime called Rascal the Raccoon led to tons of Japanese people importing the little critters to keep as pets. This was not a good idea, as anyone who has to deal with these feral, garbage eating creatures can tell you, and today, raccoons are classified as an “invasive alien species” that causes millions of dollars in damages to crops and wildlife all throughout Japan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Were the mindless swarms of flesh-devouring zombies that infest “Raccoon City” inspired by these destructive varmints? Could it be a commentary on America’s less-than-stellar reputation on the global stage, or at least the behavior of its most obnoxious tourists? It’s certainly possible, but it’s unlikely that a game that’s such a loving homage to American horror films would make that kind of dig. The real answer is probably more simple: the mansion is in a forest, Raccoons live in the forest, hence “Raccoon Forest,” which in turn gave the city its name.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the end, Capcom wanted to make a zombie game set in the U.S. and came up with a plausible-sounding place for it to happen. There’s no hidden meaning or dark secret lurking at the heart of Raccoon City… At least, behind the scenes. Within the world of Resident Evil, there’s a lot going on beneath the surface.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Raccoon Rising</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Nestled in the Arklay mountains, bordered by the sprawling Raccoon Forest to the north, was a small midwestern town called Raccoon City. Founded in the 1800s, RC was largely unremarkable until the end of the swinging ‘60s, when its struggling economy was revitalized by a corporate benefactor that would one day bring about its total destruction.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 1968, three best buds with a crazy dream got together to form the Umbrella Corporation. The plan? To create a superior breed of humans through twisted science. While none of the deeply unpleasant men who founded Umbrella had any deep ties to Raccoon City, Oswald E. Spencer just so happened to have some valuable real estate that would be perfect for their evil ambitions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A few years earlier, in 1962, Sir Spencer commissioned a famous New York architect named George Trevor to build his dream home in Arklay County. Situated above a sprawling limestone cavern large enough to host a secret underground laboratory, the mansion was to be a recreation of Spencer’s childhood estate back in England… with a few twists.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/spencer-mansion-new-1750851611668.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The lobby of the creepy Spencer Mansion. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Trevor made his name designing intricate buildings with traps, secret passageways, and tricksy puzzles–  the kinds of gimmicks that make lunatics like Spencer (and strategy guide writers) squeal. As the mansion neared completion in 1967, Spencer grew more paranoid, as evil masterminds tend to do. He was convinced that Trevor would reveal his secrets, so he convinced the architect to bring his family to Raccoon City and conspired to wipe them all out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer infected Trevor’s wife Jessica and daughter Lisa with the Progenitor Virus, precursor to the T-virus, the manmade zombie plague that would later doom Raccoon City. Jessica died, and was entombed beneath the mansion. Lisa survived, but mutated into a shambling, nigh-unkillable monstrosity. Umbrella kept Lisa prisoner for 28 years, experimenting on her to produce even deadlier concoctions like the G-virus. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for old George Trevor himself, he wound up trapped in a labyrinth of his own making. According to his diary, while searching for his family he actually forgot the solutions to the puzzles he created, which is relatable if nothing else. Unable to juggle all the crests, keys, and cranks that unlocked the Spencer Mansion, Trevor died of thirst and starvation deep within the bowels of his final masterpiece.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With those loose ends somewhat messily tied up, Umbrella was free to continue with its mad science, thriving within a blissfully unaware Raccoon City. The town was growing rapidly, and the jobs provided by Umbrella paid for some much-needed infrastructure. Founded in 1969, the Raccoon Police Department eventually purchased a palatial art museum to convert into its headquarters at the urging of future chief (and madman) Brian Irons. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/lisa-trev-2-1750851671953.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Lisa Trevor. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now safe under the watchful eye of a deranged serial killer, the growing population soon enjoyed the benefits of a zoo and its adorable mascot, Mr. Raccoon, a kick-ass public transit system, a training school for gifted youngsters, a university, a bustling downtown shopping district, and at least one pro football team. Give it up for your Raccoon City… Sharks? RC also hosted a thriving media industry that somehow sustained eight newspapers and a TV news network, all cut down in their prime twenty years before the pivot to video.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Umbrella kept the city’s economic blood pumping with its legit industries above ground, but the real money came from the top secret research it conducted under Raccoon City’s nose. The eugenicist vision of Spencer and the founders was largely replaced with the extremely lucrative industry of creating bio-organic weapons (B.O.W.s) for the highest bidder. Deadly as they are, the Hunters, Lickers, and Chimera Umbrella churned out by the truckload were merely the beta versions of its ultimate creation, the mighty Tyrant.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the early ‘90s, Umbrella cemented its hold on Raccoon City by pouring tons of money into a revitalization project called “Bright Raccoon 21.” It built hospitals and orphanages, renovated the landmark clock tower, and recruited a special ops police unit called S.T.A.R.S. in 1996. It also took the opportunity to construct not one but two secret NEST facilities underground, where scientist William Birkin was hard at work on the G-virus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Umbrella owned the mayor, the police department, and employed 40% of the city’s 100,000 citizens. It had infected Raccoon City like one of its patented viruses, transforming the rust-belt industrial town into a bustling metropolis under the iron grip of Umbrella.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This didn’t last very long. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Raccoon City Destruction Incident</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The situation began spiraling out of Umbrella’s control in early 1998, when strange occurrences around Raccoon City started drawing unwanted attention. Strange dogs with wet, decaying flesh were spotted in the woods, and a series of grisly murders seemingly committed by cannibals had residents spooked about a possible death cult lurking in the forest.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The heat made Umbrella nervous, so it called upon its intelligence agent extraordinaire, Albert Wesker. As the company man in charge of S.T.A.R.S., he was to lead the unit on a sham investigation to clean up the mess and retrieve precious combat data, the single most valuable commodity in the Resident Evil universe. Wesker, magnificent bastard that he is, was plotting to ditch Umbrella at the first opportunity, but he complied with his orders.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the 23rd of July, 1998, the S.T.A.R.S. Bravo Team helicopter crashed in the forest, courtesy of Wesker’s sabotage. The man in the shades personally led Alpha team on a so-called rescue mission that trapped them in the iconic foyer of the Spencer Mansion. As the events of Resident Evil 1 play out, S.T.A.R.S. members Chris Redfield and Jill Valentine battle through zombies and B.O.W.s, discover the hidden lab beyond the manor walls, and learn of Umbrella’s role in the slaughter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As Bravo Team rookie Rebecca Chambers discovered in the extremely mid prequel, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-zero">Resident Evil 0</a>, the Mansion outbreak was the work of Umbrella co-founder James Marcus, or rather, a mutated leech posing as the murdered magnate. She reunites with Jill and Chris, only to be betrayed by Wesker, who unleashes Umbrella’s apex weapon on his former comrades. Wesker is seemingly skewered by the Tyrant, which is destroyed by a deus ex rocket launcher courtesy of cowardly pilot Brad “Chickenheart” Vickers, as the surviving S.T.A.R.S. members (and a chemically-enhanced Wesker) escape the exploding facility.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/final-resi-2-1750851849011.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Rebecca Chambers and Chris Redfield battle Umbrella's Tyrant. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Umbrella immediately went to work covering its tracks, hushing up any media murmurs and bribing Chief Irons to discredit and disband S.T.A.R.S. The corporation’s containment efforts were about as successful outside of the lab as in it, and the walls were closing in. Sightings of monsters in the Arklay region continued, growing ever closer to the town as summer turned to fall. William Birkin had seen enough.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The man behind the mutagenic G-virus was preparing to hand over his research to the U.S. government, in exchange for a clean slate and protection for himself, his wife Annette and daughter Sherry. Umbrella caught wind of his intentions and dispatched a spec-ops task force to NEST on September 22nd. In the ensuing firefight, Birkin injected himself with his G-virus, transforming into a body horror monstrosity and releasing T-virus samples among the city’s rats and into the water supply. Raccoon City would be overrun within days.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The military descended on the city in a failed attempt to contain the disease, while Umbrella dispatched its own private mercenary group, the UBCS, to contain the situation. Umbrella also made the most of the opportunity to test new B.O.W.s, airdropping a Nemesis pursuer and handful of Tyrants into the chaos to dispatch unwanted survivors, recapture the G-virus, and explore their combat capabilities in a disaster scenario of its own design.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">By the 28th of September, the RPD had fallen and the army had all but abandoned Raccoon City. Those who remained alive did whatever they could to survive the outbreak, often in episodic scenarios perfectly suited for online co-op sessions. On the 29th, a rookie cop with heartthrob hair arrived in Raccoon City, late for his first day on the job and somehow unaware of the destruction that lurked within. Welcome to Resident Evil 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Leon Kennedy linked up with Claire Redfield, a young woman searching for her brother Chris, who was off in Europe doing his own research on Umbrella. Together, the two sought refuge in the zombie-infested RPD, evading “Mr. X” and a mutated William Birkin with help from Ada Wong, an agent working for Umbrella’s unnamed corporate rival. Together, they storm the NEST, rescue Birkin’s daughter Sherry, witness Ada’s apparent demise, defeat their tormentors, and haul ass out of the self-destructing facility on a speeding train.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/final-resi-remake-2-1750851911598.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Leon holds his ground against the mutated William Birkin in the NEST. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-3">Resident Evil 3</a> revealed that Jill Valentine was trapped in town while all this was going down, her last escape halted by the relentless Nemesis, programmed to murder any remaining S.T.A.R.S. members. Jill teams up with Carlos Oliveira and his ragtag group of UBCS spooks to infiltrate the secondary NEST facility and find a vaccine. The Nemesis is destroyed, along with any potential T-virus cure, and Jill and Carlos flee the city shortly before its destruction.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On October 1, the U.S. government decided to wash its hands of Raccoon City by wiping it off the map. The President ordered the launch of an experimental thermobaric missile to destroy the town, any evidence of the outbreak, and every living and unliving creature still inside. When the dust settled, all that remained of Raccoon City was a smoldering crater.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Umbrella’s role in the disaster was exposed by journalist Alyssa Ashcroft, a survivor who revealed the existence of B.O.W.s to the world. The U.S. President resigned in disgrace, but the government managed to keep its dealings with Umbrella under wraps. Facing prosecutions, lawsuits, and dwindling sales following the death of 100,000 people, the Umbrella corporation shriveled and died, leaving Raccoon City as its final, shameful legacy.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Uncanny City</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The few brief mentions of Raccoon City in Resi 1 sparked our imaginations, and RE 2 made them a reality. While the sequel largely took place inside the ornate RPD building, RE 2 begins with a bang, throwing Leon and Claire into the burning streets of Raccoon City proper and daring them to survive the horror. Clambering up fire escapes and sprinting past zombie-filled basketball courts was such a mind-blowing expansion of scope in 1998 that we didn’t really notice that Raccoon City doesn’t make any sense. At least, not for an American city.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The pre-rendered backgrounds of the original Resi 2 and 3 are chock-full of narrow, winding streets and mazes of tiny alleys that lead to dead ends, none of which are really representative of a bustling mid-sized midwestern metro. In fact, Raccoon City as originally envisioned feels a lot like the commercial area of a Japanese city– Shinjuku draped in grimy Western set dressing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Most Japanese game devs in the ‘90s weren’t given the budget to fly across the Pacific to do in-depth research on cities in the United States– Konami famously used the Arnold Schwarzenegger family comedy Kindergarten Cop as its primary reference when conceiving the streets of Silent Hill. RC isn’t supposed to be an accurate U.S. city, it’s an imaginary version of one cooked up via Capcom’s cultural osmosis, based on its impressions of American culture from afar– it’s no coincidence that RE 2’s only accessible building outside of the RPD is Gun Shop Kendo. The result is a Raccoon City that feels familiar enough to Western audiences with a subtle undercurrent that something is wrong, the uncanny valley effect played out in environmental design. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/rc-old-2-1750851940796.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The streets of Raccoon City in the original PS1 version of RE2. Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This sensation diminished as the series evolved beyond pre-rendered backgrounds, with the multiplayer-focused Outbreak games returning to a fully polygonal RC. The somewhat forgotten spinoff has been thrust into the spotlight with the reveal that Resident Evil Requiem will star Grace Ashcroft, daughter of reporter Alyssa Ashcroft who was a prominent playable character in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-outbreak">Outbreak</a>. It’s a series worth revisiting even without the ability to play online, in large part because of how it expands Raccoon City. Survivors explore bars, hotels, apartment buildings, a zoo, and even Raccoon University campus, fleshing RC into a more fully realized space while maintaining the gritty, pre-HD vibe.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The advent of the Resident Evil remakes gave Capcom the opportunity to update Raccoon City for a new generation. The impressive RE Engine provided realistic, high fidelity graphics, but it feels like something was lost in translation. While the city more closely resembles a thriving midwestern tourist destination, with towering skyscrapers and a more sensible urban layout, it sacrifices the otherworldly aesthetic of the original games. It feels less like a waking nightmare and more like an actual place– even though a real-life Raccoon City is rather implausible. Umbrella funding aside, the sheer amount of amenities and infrastructure built to serve such a small population would probably raise some suspicious eyebrows and definitely jack up the rent prices. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And even if it could exist in our world, that begs our final question: where is Raccoon City supposed to be? Capcom has never definitively stated its location, and the most specific the canonical series ever got was in the intro to the Resident Evil 3 remake. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The (fantastic) tie-in novels by S.D. Perry explicitly placed the city in rural Pennsylvania, as did the screenplay for George Romero’s legendary unproduced Resident Evil adaptation. The Paul W.S. Anderson movies kept things vague, with some clues that Raccoon City is either near Allentown, PA or somewhere in Michigan, but most of the action was filmed in Toronto, Canada. The ill-fated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/resident-evil-welcome-to-raccoon-city">Welcome to Raccoon City</a> film was similarly shot in Ontario, but it too declined to name the state it stood in for.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/ashcroft-1750852007189.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">RE Requiem lead character Grace Ashcroft is the daughter of Alyssa, a character from RE Outbreak. Image credit: Capcom </figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Countless fan theories have emerged throughout the decades, using every snippet of lore and a whole lot of logical leaps in an attempt to deduce the location of Raccoon City. Plausible arguments exist for Colorado, South Dakota, and even Cleveland, Ohio, but the prevailing hypothesis is that Raccoon is a stand in for Springfield, Missouri. There aren’t many mountains in the midwest, after all, but the foggy Arklay hills could be interpreted as Missouri’s Ozark region. Springfield also happens to be situated above massive limestone caverns with plenty of room for growing young B.O.W.s.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are a few holes in this hypothesis, like the fact that Leon and Claire emerge from Raccoon City into a sprawling desert that is far removed from any geographic feature of the Show-Me State. The truth is, we probably were never supposed to know exactly where Raccoon City is– and maybe that’s what makes it so creepy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Raccoon City could be the growing town up the road where a soulless corporation just built a new billion-dollar data center. It could be the quaint hamlet up by the woods that hosts a mysterious old house that’s rumored to be haunted. It could be your city, that one day you might have to escape in a desperate dash for survival. For nearly 30 years, Raccoon City has played host to countless mysteries and unanswered questions, some of which may finally be revealed in Requiem. But one thing has never been in doubt: Raccoon City is a scary place to be.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-you-need-to-know-about-resident-evils-raccoon-city]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rift of the NecroDancer DLC ‘hololive Music Pack’ now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/rift-of-the-necrodancer-dlc-hololive-music-pack-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rift-of-the-necrodancer-dlc-%E2%80%98hololive-music-pack%E2%80%99-now-available.1228209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Brace Yourself Games [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/brace-yourself-games">Brace Yourself Games</a>, in cooperation with COVER Corporation, has released <em><a title="Games > Rift of the NecroDancer [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rift-of-the-necrodancer">Rift of the NecroDancer</a></em> downloadable content “hololive Music Pack.” <span id="more-976068"></span></p><p>The “hololive Music Pack” Consists of the following content:</p><ul><li>“REFLECT” by Gawr Gura (free to download)</li><li>“BIBBIDIBA” by Hoshimachi Suisei</li><li>“Ahoy!! Warera Houshou Kaizoku Dan☆” by Houshou Marine</li><li>“Play Dice!” by Hakos Baelz</li><li>“Carbonated Love” by IRyS</li></ul><p>Each song can be purchased individually for $1.99.</p><p><em>Rift of the NecroDancer</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,577 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2073250/Rift_of_the_NecroDancer/" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/rift-of-the-necrodancer/june-25-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>DLC “hololive Music Pack” Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Rift of the NecroDancer - DLC &quot;hololive Music Pack&quot; Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tiwh3rZkNcs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_976069"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/rift-of-the-necrodancer-dlc-hololive-music-pack-now-available]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld X Terraria Crossover Update Is Out Now, Game Discounted Significantly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-x-terraria-crossover-update-is-out-now-game-discounted-significantly/1100-6532715/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-x-terraria-crossover-update-is-out-now-game-discounted-significantly.1228200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532715">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/palworld/" data-ref-id="5000-532768">Palworld</a>'s latest major update is live, featuring a crossover with Terraria. Tides of Terraria brings several new features and mechanics to the game. Palworld is also on sale for various platforms, making this a great time for new players to jump in.</p><p dir="ltr">Palworld: Tides of Terraria is packed with new content. The game adds a fishing mechanic, and players can now craft fishing rods and bait to catch all-new Pal types. The map continues to expand with three more island types to explore: Tropical, Iceberg, and Shipwreck.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1798027684" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466150,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Palworld%20%C3%97%20Terraria%20%7C%20Tides%20of%20Terraria%20Major%20Update%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:85,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/palworld-terraria-tides-of-terraria-major-update-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6466150\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466150\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466150\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466150\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466150&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466150,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532715&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;palworld&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,macintosh,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;pocket-pair-inc&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;palworld&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;palworld&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466150},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466150\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4521385-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/teSTCtzn.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1750860480,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="teSTCtzn" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Palworld × Terraria | Tides of Terraria Major Update Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">As for the Terraria-specific content, players can tackle the game's Moon Lord as Palworld's latest raid boss. Terraria's Eye of Cthulhu is featured in the promotional art for the update, and this looks to be a Pal-type monster that players can fight and potentially catch. Six new weapons and seven armor pieces from Terraria have been added as well.</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, the update includes the addition of treasure maps, a new NPC mission system, more Pal skills, and several new items to craft for bases. There are also bug fixes and quality-of-life improvements.</p><p dir="ltr">For those who have not experienced Palworld yet, this is a great time to jump into the game and explore the Tides of Terraria update. Palworld is currently on sale for 25% off its full price on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1623730/Palworld/" rel="nofollow ">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/palworld-game-preview/9nkv34xdw014">Xbox</a>, and the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/palworld/">PlayStation Store</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-x-terraria-crossover-update-is-out-now-game-discounted-significantly/1100-6532715/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox launches a branded Meta Quest 3S headset]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xbox-launches-a-branded-meta-quest-3s-headset</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-launches-a-branded-meta-quest-3s-headset.1228197/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft has collaborated with Meta to release a branded headset: The Meta Quest 3S Xbox Edition.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Announced yesterday, the company shared details about the bundle via </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/06/24/meta-quest-3s-xbox-edition/">Xbox Wire</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The limited edition package is available for $399.99 USD and includes the 128GB version of the headset, a Meta Quest Elite Strap, an Xbox controller, and three months of Meta Horizon+ and Xbox Game Pass Ultimate.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to the company, the selling point is the Xbox Cloud Gaming app, which started its beta on December 13, 2023. The app allows you to stream any compatible Xbox game, either from Game Pass or your own library, directly to the headset.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The headset is available via the Meta store, as well as Best Buy in the US, and both Argos and EE in the UK, all in "extremely" limited quantities.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"With cloud gaming and the launch of the Meta Quest 3S Xbox Edition bundle, there have never been more ways to play with Xbox," reads the Xbox Wire post. "Whether you prefer to jump into action on a console, stream to your TV or phone, or immerse yourself in the world of VR, Xbox has you covered across more devices than ever before."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At the beginning of the month, Microsoft </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-first-xbox-handhelds-have-finally-arrived">announced</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> two Xbox branded handhelds that have been developed in collaboration with Asus, taking the form of the ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/genai-animation-startup-motorica-raises-5-8-million-investment" target="_self" data-discover="true">GenAI animation startup Motorica raises $5.8 million investment</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unlike the Meta collaboration, the existing ROG Ally models feature some external and internal tweaks that go beyond just matching Xbox's color palette. This includes a dedicated Xbox button that will grant access to chat, apps, and settings through a Game Bar overlay, a modified version of Windows 11, and more.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="More layoffs at Xbox on the horizon">More layoffs at Xbox on the horizon</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news of the collaboration with Meta came on the same day that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-24/microsoft-plans-major-job-cuts-at-xbox-gaming-division?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc1MDc3Mjc0NiwiZXhwIjoxNzUxMzc3NTQ2LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTWUQ0VkxEV1JHRzAwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.iMkVuxzB6m6hT_Rpwa-NQCTCvDapSt1DaRfpnGaqUSw&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall">Bloomberg reported</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that managers within Xbox are expecting "substantial cuts" to be made across Xbox. The company-wide reorganization will reportedly take place next week.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company has done three waves of layoffs in the past year, affecting </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-microsoft-follows-activision-blizzard-merger-with-1-900-layoffs">1,900 people</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in January 2024, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-microsoft-is-planning-another-round-of-major-xbox-layoffs">650</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in September, and an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-conducts-small-layoffs-across-various-divisions">unspecified number</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in January 2025. It also shuttered </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-closes-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-alpha-dog-studios">internal studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which included Arkane Austin, Alpha Dog Games, and Tango Gameworks. The latter was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/krafton-acquires-tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-franchise-from-microsoft">acquired</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by Krafton later in the year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As for Meta, the company reportedly laid off </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-meta-has-laid-off-over-100-reality-labs-employees">over 100 employees</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> across its Reality Labs division back in April of this year. During an earnings call at the end of the last quarter, investors asked the company if there is "light at the end of the tunnel" for the division after it reported $4.2 billion in operating losses during the first quarter of the fiscal year, totaling $17.7 billion during the 2024 fiscal year. Revenue was also on the decline due to lower sales of Meta Quest hardware.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mindseye-developer-build-a-rocket-boy-confirms-layoffs" target="_self" data-discover="true">MindsEye developer Build a Rocket Boy confirms layoffs</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xbox-launches-a-branded-meta-quest-3s-headset]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony really won't be putting new first party games on PlayStation Plus day one any time soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-really-wont-be-putting-new-first-party-games-on-playstation-plus-day-one-any-time-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-really-wont-be-putting-new-first-party-games-on-playstation-plus-day-one-any-time-soon.1228194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Current strategy "working really well".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sony is sticking to its guns, and won't be releasing its first party games day one on its PlayStation Plus subscription service.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/playstation-plus-15th-anniversary-interview-ghost-of-tsushima">GameFile</a>, vice president of global services at PlayStation Nick Maguire said the company was "not looking to put games in day and date" on PS Plus, and will instead stick with its current way of doing things.</p>
<p>This is, of course, very different from Xbox, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">often puts big first party releases such as Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> and many more on Game Pass from the get go.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FBC: Firebreak Preview - How Does It Play And Is It Good?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUcZW6m4iA0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FBC: Firebreak Preview - How Does It Play And Is It Good?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUcZW6m4iA0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rUcZW6m4iA0?autoplay=1" title="FBC: Firebreak Preview - How Does It Play And Is It Good?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>FBC: Firebreak Preview - How Does It Play And Is It Good? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rUcZW6m4iA0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Sony, meanwhile, has added some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/blue-prince-review">third party games like the excellent Blue Prince</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stray-launches-next-month-included-in-pricier-playstation-plus-tiers-on-day-one">Stray to PS Plus on the same day as their initial launch</a>.  But the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-plus-games-list-premium-extra-this-month-6300">likes of God of War Ragnarök and Horizon Forbidden West</a> - both from Sony's first party studios - weren't added to the service until around a year after their initial release.</p>
<p>"Our strategy of finding four or five independent day-and-date titles - and using that to complement our strategy of bringing games in when they're 12, 18 months old or older - that balance for us is working really well across the platform," Maguire continued, before adding:</p>
<p>"If there were six or seven great opportunities, then we would go for them as well."</p>
<p>When asked if the company had considered the benefit of putting its own first party live-service titles on PS Plus, with Concord -  the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-exclusive-pvp-shooter-concord-is-firewalk-studios-first-game">debut game from Sony's FireWalk Studios</a>, which was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/concord-pulled-from-sale-as-sony-admits-our-initial-launch-didnt-land">taken offline just two weeks after its PS5 and PC debut</a> - being used as an example, Maguire declined to give a specific comment. The Sony exec did say, however, that PS Plus has "proven itself to be a great way to introduce new players to franchises" when they arrive on the service.</p>
<p>"There's always going to be a moment for any game where there's the right time for it to go into Plus, when it's ready to reach a wider audience or… to find new fans or new parts of our platform that it hasn't already reached," Maguire said.</p>
<p>This month, Remedy's multiplayer Control spin-off <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/herere-your-playstation-plus-extra-and-premium-games-for-june">FBC: Firebreak was available to all those on PlayStation Plus' Extra and Premium tiers</a> day one. However, even when included on a subscription service, some live-service games still flop. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>'s Foamstars, for example, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/foamstars-season-pass-ends-with-ironically-titled-party-goes-on">failed to set the world alight despite being part of the PS Plus catalogue</a>.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Would Concord have faired better if it had released on PS Plus?  | <span>Image credit: <cite>Sony Interactive Entertainment</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Today's comments echo what the exec stated back in 2023, when <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-still-wont-be-putting-new-games-on-playstation-plus-day-one-says-exec">Maguire said putting games on to Sony's subscription service "a bit later in the life cycle" is working for the company</a>. Therefore, this will "continue to be [its] strategy moving forward," Maguire said at the time.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, meanwhile, Sony president Hideaki Nishino stated the company is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-will-continue-to-add-more-value-to-ps-plus-says-company-president-but-it-may-come-with-price-changes-too">open to adjusting the price of PlayStation Plus in the future</a>, as it aims to "maximise profitability".</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-really-wont-be-putting-new-first-party-games-on-playstation-plus-day-one-any-time-soon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II Enhanced PS5 release date set for August]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-enhanced-ps5-release-date-set-for-august/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/senua%E2%80%99s-saga-hellblade-ii-enhanced-ps5-release-date-set-for-august.1228191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II has a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a> release date on 12th August, Ninja Theory and Xbox have confirmed. This enhanced release of the game is also coming as a free update to the game on Xbox Series X|S and PC at the same time.</p>
<p><iframe title="Senua's Saga: Hellblade II Enhanced - Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bOSjv1Nb1-E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>So, how is it enhanced? Ninja Theory has outlined the new features that are coming to the game:</p>
<p>New features and upgrades included in the Enhanced release include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Performance Mode</strong> – Where the original release was optimized for 30fps to deliver an immersive, cinematic experience, the Enhanced update will include a ‘Performance Mode’ to optimize for 60fps. On PC, the game will offer a “Very High’ preset to push fidelity even further based on personal hardware.</li>
<li><strong>Dark Rot Mode</strong> – The Dark Rot from <em>Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice</em> has returned and offers an additional challenge for Senua in this optional game mode. The Dark Rot will grow each time you fail, and if it reaches Senua’s head, her quest is over and all progress will be lost.</li>
<li><strong>Enhanced Photo Mode</strong> – the Enhanced update will include an expanded and improved toolset, including a new ‘Motion’ tab for custom cinematic video capture.</li>
<li><strong>Developer Commentary –</strong> for those interested in the craft and creative decisions behind <em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II</em>, the Enhanced update includes over four hours of developer commentary from a variety of voices involved in the making of the game.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s not explained here if or how the game will take advantage of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a>, but we’d anticipate that there’s at least a resolution boost to the Performance Mode.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/08/24/microsoft-explain-why-they-bought-ninja-theory/">Microsoft’s acquisition of Ninja Theory in 2018</a> came off the back of the success of Hellblade. The studio had struggled to find stability for quite some time, despite critically acclaimed games like Heavenly Sword, Enslaved: Odyssey to the West and DmC: Devil May Cry. The first Hellblade was an experiment in small budget game development at AAA quality, and it was a major hit for the studio. It was also a PlayStation 4 console exclusive at its original 2017 launch before being ported to Xbox and Switch in subsequent years. That Microsoft’s acquisition meant that the sequel would be Xbox exclusive was unpopular with PlayStation gamers, to say the least. But Microsoft’s current cross-platform strategy is at least breaking down this barrier for one of the most visually stunning games of last year.</p>
<p>Playing the game last year, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/21/senuas-saga-hellblade-2-review/">we said</a>, “Just like its forbear, Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II is an oppressive, powerful and haunting example of the power of video games, and one that sets its own parameters for what a digital experience can be. It is a game that must be experienced, not least because, there’s nothing else quite like it.”</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-enhanced-ps5-release-date-set-for-august/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stalker 2 Update 1.5 Brings Huge A-Life Changes, New Threats, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-2-update-15-a-life-new-threats</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-update-1-5-brings-huge-a-life-changes-new-threats-and-more.1228188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GSC Game World has released&nbsp;<em>Stalker 2&nbsp;</em>Update 1.5, which brings yet more improvements to the game's much-talked-about A-Life system, as well as new threats to face and more.</p>

<p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-2-patch-14" rel="nofollow">May's Update 1.4</a>, Update 1.5's main feature is a big boost to the A-Life AI system, which, I think it's fair to say, was released in a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-2-a-life-20-gsc-game-world" rel="nofollow">fairly incomplete state</a> when the game launched in November.</p>

<p>Per the official <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1643320/view/525346350588494399" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">patch notes</a>, the A-Life system now means "life in the Zone is now simulated for all characters, not just those in the player's view". This means characters will continue to pursue their goals and live their lives away from what you're seeing, and there are other A-Life changes intended to make the game's AI more immersive as well.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/stalker-2-update-1.5-a-life-pointing.jpg?itok=CmT3ExGY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/stalker-2-update-1.5-a-life-pointing.jpg?itok=K51wC2rH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Stalker 2</em>'s characters should act a little more believably now.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as the new A-Life system, you can also look forward to a new hazard in the form of the Water Electric Tornado, and as the name suggests, you're not going to have a good time if you encounter it.</p>

<p>Of course, the new update also brings a ton of bug fixes and balance tweaks with it, so you might want to head back into the Zone if you've been having trouble with glitches. There's obviously no guarantee your particular issue (or "anomaly", hem hem) will have been fixed, but it's worth a go, eh?</p>

<p>If you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Stalker 2</em>, it's the long-awaited sequel to 2007's&nbsp;<em>Stalker: Shadow of Chornobyl&nbsp;</em>(which was recently renamed to reflect the Ukrainian spelling of the city upon the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-legends-of-zone-enhanced-edition-release-date" rel="nofollow">release of the remastered version</a>).</p>

<p>Like the original, the game will have you exploring the Chornobyl Exclusion Zone in search of artifacts, and you'll meet a full cast of characters, who have now been even further enhanced by the A-Life system.</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Stalker 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1643320/STALKER_2_Heart_of_Chornobyl/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/stalker-2" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. No mention of a PS5 version has been made yet, but given the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-ps5-release-date-enhancements" rel="nofollow">friendliness</a> with which Xbox has been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced" rel="nofollow">approaching</a> PlayStation in recent months, I wouldn't be surprised if a release is on the cards for the future.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-2-update-15-a-life-new-threats]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening's first major patch has entered public testing, so you can give some Deep Desert PvE a go]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakenings-first-major-patch-has-entered-public-testing-so-you-can-give-some-deep-desert-pve-a-go</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakenings-first-major-patch-has-entered-public-testing-so-you-can-give-some-deep-desert-pve-a-go.1228185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And possibly get attacked by a lingering sandworm</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Funcom</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A work-in-progress version of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dune-awakening">Dune: Awakening</a>'s first big post-release patch is now testable on Steam, so you can hop in and check out the changes Funcom's making early doors before it rolls out for everyone in a few weeks.</p>
<p>A bunch of the changes the game's devs teased or confirmed during <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-will-get-a-big-update-in-early-july-and-funcom-have-a-three-pronged-plan-to-improve-deep-desert-pvp">their recent AMA </a>and letter to players haven't found their way into the patch, or at least this early version. Though, you'll at least be able to try out PvE in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-how-to-enter-deep-desert">the Deep Desert</a>, something folks have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakenings-deep-desert-is-getting-partial-warfare-pve-areas-so-you-can-gather-endgame-resources-without-being-pvped-to-death">demanded en-masse</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Alongside pointing folks to the freshly launch Dune: Awakening Public Test Client on Steam, where you can now test out patch 1.1.10.0, Funcom have released <a href="https://duneawakening.com/news/announcing-public-test-client/">the notes</a> outlining what's in it.</p>
<p>Among the highlights is the news that "the PvE area near the shield wall has been expanded to cover row A, B, C, D and half of E within the Deep Desert." So, you'll be able to check out some Deep Desert PvE, which folks had been calling for to avoid being forced into PvP during Awakening's endgame, when you're hunting for the best gear and resources.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Sleepers, we have news!</p><p>Patch 1.1.10.0 is now live on the new Public Test Client. Be among the first to experience the changes, and help us hunt down technical issues.</p><p>🔽 Read more about the Public Test Client and get the patch notes here: <a href="https://t.co/b504leiKl6">https://t.co/b504leiKl6</a> <a href="https://t.co/TZn6ntZrHy">pic.twitter.com/TZn6ntZrHy</a></p></div>— Dune: Awakening (@DuneAwakening) <a href="https://twitter.com/DuneAwakening/status/1937873638130139219?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>I have noticed a few folks on the social arguing that this PvE expansion is too big an adjustment - we'll have to see what the consensus is. Outside of that, Funcom have "reduced the frequency of Harkonnen attacks on certain Atreides bases (and vice versa) in Hagga Basin", set up the main menu's play now button to filter out private servers, and made sure "sandworms now linger for a bit around spicefields that have been recently harvested from".</p>
<p>Meanwhile, you can now use, claim and list items straight to and from the inventory of your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-how-to-get-ornithopter">Ornithopter</a> in the exchange. There are a bunch of handy minor tweaks to everything from base building to vehicles, combat and the UI. However, if you're hungry for the big PvP changes that the devs have teased, adjustments to the Landsraad, or just the ability to deposit all of your stuff at once, you'll have to keep waiting.</p>
<p>In the meantime, why not <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-enthralled-by-dune-awakenings-in-game-radio-drama-and-bad-sitcoms">listen to the radio</a> and read our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakening-review">DA review</a>?</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dune-awakenings-first-major-patch-has-entered-public-testing-so-you-can-give-some-deep-desert-pve-a-go]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hell Yes Another Excellent Climbing Game]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/peak-climbing-impressions-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hell-yes-another-excellent-climbing-game.1228176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I love a rock climbing game, despite the fact that I have hardly climbed at all since moving back to New York. Every climbing game seems to have its own unique take on the sport, from <a href="https://aftermath.site/new-heights-climbing-impressions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hyper-realistic</a> to <a href="https://aftermath.site/i-would-live-in-this-climbing-game" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fantastical</a>, from <a href="https://aftermath.site/indie-game-jusant-gets-rock-climbing-right" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">enjoying the view</a> to <a href="https://aftermath.site/cairn-demo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">focusing on what’s under your hands and feet</a>. The take of recent indie game <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3527290/PEAK/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Peak</em></a> leans toward both fantasy and simplicity, doing away with the affectations of other climbing games to make things both easier and more difficult.</p><p>It’s pretty clear to me that <em>Peak</em> wants to be played co-op, and honestly I might have given up on my solo session if <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/budget-steam-smash-hit-peak-is-my-new-gaming-obsession" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eurogamer</a> hadn't praised playing it alone. The game opens with your plane crashing on a mysterious island, where you have to climb from a beach to a plume of smoke at the top of a mountain. With friends, I could see this being a hilarious or back-stabbing adventure; alone, I at first found it a bit challenging to make progress while managing my character’s weight and stamina. Without a friend to boost or pull me up a lengthy rock face, or companions to spread the weight of gear around with, I had to spend a lot of time circling the mountain looking for short climbs. But eventually I got the hang of it, making it to the top of the mountain and opening up new, more challenging areas to scale.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="PEAK Trailer: OUT NOW!" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jrlUVhLBjG0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>Peak</em> has its own approach to climbing mechanics. Instead of looking for handholds or routes, you can basically climb anything simply by pressing a button to attach to it. This relative ease is made complicated by your stamina bar, which, unlike other climbing games that use stamina as one of several meters, is the entire deciding factor in how far you can climb. You have just the one bar, and then things take chunks out of it: how much stuff is in your backpack, being hungry, getting injured. Each of these is represented by its own color and symbol, making it easy to understand why your whole stamina bar isn’t available.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Aggro Crab/Landfall: The meter in the bottom left shows the impact of certain conditions on your stamina</figcaption></figure><p>Less easy is what you’re supposed to do about it, which is where a lot of the fun of <em>Peak</em> comes in. Dealing with hunger is particularly complex; in addition to packaged food you can find in suitcases scattered around the world, there’s also edible plants and fruits. They’ll all address your hunger, but they have hidden effects too. In my time with the game, desperate for food so I could regain stamina and make progress, I made my situation worse by carrying heavy coconut halves, or poisoned myself with mysterious berries. Other foods have positive effects; if you’re encountering something for the first time, there’s no way to know what it will do except try it out.</p><p>There’s also plenty of environmental hazards: In the first level, I regularly slipped on jellyfish if I wasn’t careful to scoot around them. In the second mountain, a jungle slope replete with rain and thorny vines, I wandered into…<em>something</em>: my screen went purple and my poison meter shot up, and of course I tumbled to my death. The mountains change on regular intervals, so while enough play will probably undo the mystery of these hazards, there’s still new things to discover and overcome.</p><p>All of this means that, alone, I frequently felt like I couldn’t make any progress when situations had taken too much out of my stamina and there was no one to help me address it. On the standard difficulty there’s also a time limit, enforced by rising fog, though you can lower the difficulty to turn it off. But once I accepted that I couldn’t make the long climbs of other games and had to get a bit more creative, <em>Peak</em>’s solo gameplay opened up to me. It became less about brute forcing my way up as quickly as possible and more about exploring and learning the land, strategically choosing my path to make little pieces of progress. And, the higher I got, the more tense things got: the riskier climbs and jumps felt, the more stressful deciding whether to eat a new food became. Every pathway and item required a careful balancing of risk versus reward, while the game’s straightforward mechanic and bright colors kept things feeling more goofy than grim.</p><p>I’m enjoying <em>Peak</em> on my own, though I’d love to try it out with friends. <em>Peak </em>started life as a game jam game between developers <a href="https://aftermath.site/the-crab-has-a-gun" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aggro Crab</a> and Landfall, and has gone on to sell <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/im-gonna-crash-out-new-climbing-game-peak-has-sold-1-million-copies-in-less-than-a-week-outperforming-its-developers-most-popular-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one million copies</a> in its first week, which means probably someone I know owns it and can be convinced to listen to me wax poetic about climbing while we fling and drop each other to our dooms.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/lies-of-p-overture-review"><h3>Lies Of P: Overture Is The Best Parts Of The Game Executed With Confidence</h3></a><p>Lies of P: Overture proves the success of the first game was no fluke, and establishes a bold house style.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/adventure-gamers-online-casino-gambling-website-sale-parasite-seo"><h3>Adventure Games, Poker And Casinos Do Not ‘Overlap’, You Weirdos</h3></a><p>No normal person could type 'Recognizing the growing convergence between gaming and gambling'</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/peak-climbing-impressions-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dbrand Responds To Switch 2 Owners Experiencing Joy-Con 2 Issues With Its Killswitch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dbrand-responds-to-switch-2-owners-experiencing-joy-con-2-issues-with-its-killswitch/1100-6532709/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dbrand-responds-to-switch-2-owners-experiencing-joy-con-2-issues-with-its-killswitch.1228164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532709">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Switch 2 owners who purchased Dbrand's Killswitch have been reporting that their Joy-Con 2s detach from the console relatively easily once their controllers have been wrapped in the protective cover. Several users have claimed that the magnetic connection is weakened by the Killswitch case, but Dbrand is preparing to address this as it says anyone suffering from the "manufacturing tolerance issue" can reach out to the company and get a free set of replacement Joy-Con 2 Grips.</p><p>Dbrand originally acknowledged this issue <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1lhvtyw/killswitch_joycon_detachment_update/" rel="nofollow ">in a Reddit post that wasn't too well-received</a>, as it acknowledged an air gap that's crucial in creating resistance between console and controller was filled when the Killswitch was added. Because the lip on the Killswitch eliminated the buffer that was designed to absorb movement between the console and controller--which is needed to create a fulcrum point when you remove the Joy-Con 2s--several users had begun reporting that their console detached from the controllers far too easily.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1101379628" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466121,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20Console%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:904,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-console-review\/2300-6466121\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466121&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466121,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532709&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466121},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466121\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1565\/15650751\/4513820-site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/htxhuu6a.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1749856800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="htxhuu6a" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 Console Review</p>
      </div>
<p>"When holding the Switch 2 in a specific way, detachment between the Joy-Con 2s and [the] remainder of the console can occur," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1ljlhwy/joycon_detachment_update_part_2_were_fixing_it/" rel="nofollow ">Dbrand explained</a>. "Some experience this issue. Some do not. This discrepancy is due to a manufacturing tolerance issue on the retaining lip that keeps the Joy-Con Grip attached to the Joy-Con. Anyone who suffers from the manufacturing tolerance issue can reach out and we'll get them better Joy-Con Grips in July. One nuanced point that got a bit lost in the prior update was that there <em>is</em> an alternative to the retaining lip. It's been tested and is already in-market on a few Switch 2 cases. It's adhesive. The problem with adhesive is that, given enough time or the wrong kind of stress, it will ultimately fail."</p><p>In our own testing, we did manage to replicate the issue with the Killswitch that several Switch 2 owners have experienced. The catch here is that this did require us to have our Switch 2 held at very specific angles to properly replicate, and we needed to apply some considerable force to the console as well.</p><p>While this appears to be an issue that some people are experiencing, the updated version will still be worth grabbing, as the Killswitch does offer some of the best ergonomic support, thanks to its design when compared to competitors like Satisfye and JSAUX. The Killswitch offers ridges for your fingers to rest in, resulting in a comfortable and natural grip.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dbrands-nintendo-switch-2-killswitch-grip-is-up-for-preorder/1100-6532032/" data-ref-id="1100-6532032">Check out our previous story on the Killswitch</a> for more details about the grip, including the unique dock adapter, optional travel cover, and bundle options.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dbrand-responds-to-switch-2-owners-experiencing-joy-con-2-issues-with-its-killswitch/1100-6532709/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Survival Kids on Switch 2 is Unity's only in-house game (for now)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/why-survival-kids-on-switch-2-is-unity-s-only-in-house-game-for-now-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-survival-kids-on-switch-2-is-unitys-only-in-house-game-for-now.1228158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">New platforms like the Nintendo Switch 2 are a siren call for many developers—and being selected by Nintendo to create a launch-exclusive title can be a huge boon for a game studio. So developers may have been surprised to see one of the few platform-exclusive titles at launch was a game called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/survival-kids-switch-2/">Survival Kids</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It's published by Konami, but was developed entirely in-house by engine and in-app advertising company Unity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Given Unity's prior aversion to developing games with its own engine (a practice sometimes called "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/14/business/dogfooding.html">dogfooding</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">"), it was surprising to see the company land in such a prominent position. But as producer Andy Dennison explained to Game Developer, this doesn't mean Unity is all-in on internal game development. The team cooked up </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to achieve two major goals: first, to make a game fully "end-to-end" with Unity to help Dennison's team with its main task: parachuting in to help Unity developers solve engine-specific technical problems.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">And second: to prepare Unity—and everyone who uses it—for the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="From ">From <span>Gigaya</span> to <span>Survival Kids</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unity nearly began making games with its own software in 2022 with the game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://unity.com/blog/games/introducing-unitys-latest-sample-game-gigaya">Gigaya</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which was meant to be a "sample" game and a commercial product. But just two months after the game was announced, it reportedly laid off </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/unity-is-reportedly-laying-off-hundreds-of-employees">the bulk of the development team</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and canceled the project.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/nintendo-switch-2-shows-nintendo-s-strategy-for-a-social-future" target="_self" data-discover="true">Nintendo Switch 2 shows Nintendo's strategy for an online social future</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the same year, Unity was quietly ramping up a division called "Unity Studio Productions" in the United Kingdom. Its first employee was Dennison, who leads the studio, primarily helping developers "behind the scenes" optimizing Unity. "You don't often hear about the work we do," he admitted in a recent chat with Game Developer, saying that the team's projects can range from short-term engagements like high-level performance profiling to larger long-term projects like porting or moving codebases from one engine over into Unity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dennison said that these smaller projects taught Unity plenty of lessons that could be used to improve the engine. "But they're always relatively narrow windows into [game] development," he explained. "You might only be looking at a specific problem or platform." That drove Unity to resurrect the idea of making a game entirely in-engine from end-to-end.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It was in late 2022 that Dennison and his colleagues connected with Konami at Gamescom in Cologne, Germany, striking it up with Konami Europe exec Richard Jones. There the two teams hit it off, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> entered development in March 2023.</span></p><p>Image via Unity/Konami.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With a slew of Leamington Spa-area developers on the team (many veterans of Codemasters, Playground Games, and Rare), Dennison said the company was able to ship </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a relatively quick two-year period. With neither Konami or Unity relying on the game's success to prop up their financials, Dennison said the Studio Productions team could focus on "replicating what many of our customers go through."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"They're building games with [schedules], with scope they have to think very carefully about, and a team they have to manage and look after," he observed. "I think that replication of our customers' day-to-day, and how they operate their businesses, was important as well."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's why he's glad the studio made what he called a "larger" game—not a platformer or mobile game Unity is more broadly used for. It also made Unity Studio Productions one of the first teams to get a look at two key Switch 2 features: GameShare and GameChat.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Survival Kids"><span>Survival Kids</span> is optimized for GameShare and GameChat</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Nintendo Switch 2 isn't a console with major new gameplay features like the Wii, Wii U, or the Switch. Its primary advancements come in the form of modest </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/nintendo-switch-2s-dlss-support-to-be-a-big-part-of-future-nintendo-games">internal hardware upgrades and AI upscaling</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/design-opportunities-for-devs-from-our-time-trying-out-the-nintendo-switch-2">a Joy-Con mouse mode</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/nintendo-switch-2-shows-nintendo-s-strategy-for-a-social-future">a slew of social features</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> marking Nintendo's first major foray into the world of online multiplayer games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dennison said Unity learned about the social features after work started on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but "the stars aligned" and the game became a strong testbed for two key features: GameShare and GameChat. Dennison was particularly proud of the work on GameShare, which allows one player to invite other Switch and Switch 2 users to their game session without installing additional software. "It's essentially an extension of split-screen technology," he explained. When players use GameShare with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, their device renders a separate in-game camera for each player and streams it out to other Switch devices. Unity had already been developing two-player split screen for local play, but found it could push and optimize the engine to support up to three players over GameShare.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We worked really closely with the platform team, who didn't have another test case for that at this stage because it's so new."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This also made </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> a test for how game designers can think about games players might want to play together over GameChat—the video/audio chatroom system built into the Switch 2. It's not as straightforward as just making a good multiplayer game. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/extended-reality/owlchemy-labs-dimensional-double-shift-shows-what-s-next-for-vr-development">Developers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> we've chatted with in 2025 have spoken about how "presence" and spaces where players can relax and form their own kind of play are part of an emerging trend particularly popular with younger audiences.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Dennison, once Nintendo explained how the Switch 2 would handle the chat components of the game, his team doubled down on the "emote system" as a tool for in-game socialization and cooperation. Players can tap an "emote" button to auto-play a "smart emote" that aligns to what they're mostly likely trying to communicate, or use a wheel-like interface to pick specific emotes like planting a flag. This emote makes a flag emoji pop up on the other players' screens, pointing them in the direction of their teammate.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Focusing on emotes puts Unity in the same camp as Riot Games, which is counting on them to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/how-riot-games-is-preparing-for-the-next-generation-of-players">boost the socialization</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> aspect of its upcoming tag-team fighting game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>2XKO</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dennison previously worked at Rare on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sea of Thieves</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, so he's familiar with this kind of play. He still thinks the industry is only "scratching the surface" of this genre. "It's really encouraging communal play. I think there's another 20 years of innovation in that space, for sure."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Just don't expect Unity Studio Productions to be the one doing that innovating. Dennison made clear that his team's first priority is "doing everything we can internally to make sure what we build is production-verified." It's the company's policy to make sure the engine is ready day zero for the launch of new platforms like the Switch 2, and in this case, making an original game was a great method for hitting that goal. It's not the team's primary focus now that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Survival Kids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is out the door.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But it could be again—under the right circumstances. "We would love to find the right opportunity to partner with someone again and the right "story" internally about the technology we're going to push on that next product," Dennison said. "I would certainly love to explore that—what opportunities are there for us?"</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div data-testid="contributor-summary-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Follow Bryant Francis, Senior Editor, on </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me">Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> or </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryant-francis-99898b29">LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/why-survival-kids-on-switch-2-is-unity-s-only-in-house-game-for-now-]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two worlds collide at last as Palworld: Tides of Terraria launches today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-worlds-collide-at-last-as-palworld-tides-of-terraria-launches-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-worlds-collide-at-last-as-palworld-tides-of-terraria-launches-today.1228155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Two pals, together at last.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Pocketpair</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-beginner-tips-tricks-9409">Palworld</a>: Tides of Terraria is out now, an expansion blending the third-person survival game and the popular sandbox.</p>
<p>Tides of Terraria adds fishing, salvaging, three new islands, missions, and the Pal Trust system to Palworld, the latter allowing you to build bonds with your gaggle of cute comrades.</p>
<p>On top of all this, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/terraria">Terraria</a>-themed enemies and weapons have been added to properly combine the two games.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PALWORLD Early Access Review: Is It Worth It?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FmZl10Mlc7I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PALWORLD Early Access Review: Is It Worth It?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FmZl10Mlc7I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FmZl10Mlc7I?autoplay=1" title="PALWORLD Early Access Review: Is It Worth It?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Check out our video review of Palworld here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmZl10Mlc7I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>You can expect new building types too, allowing you to better improve your base. There's also an overhauled enemy base system, allowing foes you find out in the wilds to construct their own fortifications much like you do. The full list of changes and additions<a href="https://x.com/Palworld_EN/status/1937709560053285318"> can be found here</a>.</p>
<p>Palworld took the world by storm last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-passes-5m-copies-sold-in-three-days">selling five million copies in three days</a>. The game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-is-officially-out-today-on-playstation">later came to PlayStation</a>, but not before its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-sues-palworld-developer-for-infringement-of-multiple-patents">developer was sued by Nintendo for copyright infringement</a>. Pocketpair <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-developer-says-pokemon-lawsuit-will-prompt-more-disappointing-changes-as-it-continues-to-dispute-claims">described this development as disappointing</a>, removing some features as a result, though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-mod-restores-gliding-feature-pulled-amid-nintendo-lawsuit">gliding was reintroduced thanks to fan mods</a> earlier this year.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-developer-being-sued-by-nintendo-says-switch-2-port-still-possible">a Nintendo Switch 2 port of Palworld is still on the cards</a>, according to Pocketpair. As for right now, this Terraria crossover could very well lead to a new wave of interested players. After all, Terraria is no slouch itself, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/terraria-has-sold-more-than-35-million-copies">selling more than 35m copies as of 2021</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-worlds-collide-at-last-as-palworld-tides-of-terraria-launches-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari's Badass 'Fatal Run' Revival Nails A Fall 2025 Release Window]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/ataris-badass-fatal-run-revival-nails-a-fall-2025-release-window</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ataris-badass-fatal-run-revival-nails-a-fall-2025-release-window.1228152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Fasten your seatbelt</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Atari has announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fatal_run_2089">Fatal Run 2089</a>, the upcoming racing revival for the Switch, will launch in Fall 2025.</p>
<p>The accompanying gameplay trailer gives us a fresh look at the new post-apocalyptic racer from developer MNSTR Studio, and we have to say, it's looking pretty decent so far. There's definitely a pretty heavy <strong>Mad Max</strong> vibe to the whole thing, and the brief snippets of dialogue sequences give us a good taste of the story.</p>
<p>We have to admit though, looking at the key features below, 20 levels doesn't really sound like a lot on paper. We might have to get a bit more context as to how long each one lasts and whether it's somewhat comparable to a proper race course you might see in a Mario Kart game, for example.</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-2" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>824k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>Hopefully we'll get a couple more good glimpses at the game ahead of its launch later this year, but we're certainly intrigued, at least.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- 20 levels across four landscapes with branching paths, hidden shortcuts, and explosive set pieces</p>
<p>- Four larger-than-life boss fights that will each provide a unique challenge to players</p>
<p>- Classic arcade progression challenges you to beat the clock, or ARC decay, or it’s back to the start</p>
<p>- 63 different enhancements that can be dropped or appear in shops and 27 randomized add variety and unpredictability to each run</p>
<p>- 4 co-pilots with different skills and personalities add extra character to your adventure and ways to shape your playstyle</p>
<p>- Tailor your approach to one of seven vehicles with distinct performance characteristics: weave in and out of danger with a light ride or barrel through enemies with a heavy one. But you can only choose one car per run, no mid-trip switching.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>What do you make of this one so far? Interested in grabbing a copy? Share your thoughts in the usual place.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/ataris-badass-fatal-run-revival-nails-a-fall-2025-release-window]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rematch Suprasses 1 Million Units Sold And 3 Million Unique Players]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rematch-suprasses-1-million-units-sold-and-3-million-unique-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rematch-suprasses-1-million-units-sold-and-3-million-unique-players.1228149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Sloclap's new football game, Rematch, has surpassed 3 million unique players and 1 million copies sold, the studio has <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/playrematch.com/post/3lseohvckdc2a">announced</a>.</p>
<p>It's a big milestone for the studio and a strong follow-up from its previous martial arts hit, Sifu, and seemingly a clear sign that being available on Xbox Game Pass at launch was a major boon for the multiplayer game.</p>
<p>Rematch officially launched for everyone on June 19, and just in its first 24 hours, was able to hit <a href="https://wccftech.com/sloclap-pushes-hotfix-for-rematch-network-stability-issues-as-rematch-hits-1-million-unique-players-in-first-24hrs/">1 million unique players</a> jumping onto the pitch, whether they bought the game or played it through Game Pass.</p>
<p>Now, less than a week from its official launch, and a week from its early access release for those who paid for the deluxe edition, it's tripled that number of players and still managed to hit a strong sales milestone.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ivx73oyahbwxlsm3yspl5jxe/app.bsky.feed.post/3lseohvckdc2a" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreidvoyjxlkjdfbfv5exlp4pcg27aif6ns45mek4bz3f73gamodfqpu">
<p>Rematch has officially reached 3M unique players!For those keeping score, that's- 11.8M matches played- 55.6M goals scored- 33.5M assists- 69.1M savesThis is just the beginning.Thank you for being with us, in and out of the pitch!#rematch</p>
<p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ivx73oyahbwxlsm3yspl5jxe?ref_src=embed">Rematch (@playrematch.com)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ivx73oyahbwxlsm3yspl5jxe/post/3lseohvckdc2a?ref_src=embed">2025-06-24T18:00:48.389Z</a></p></blockquote>

<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/rematch-review-an-excellent-football-game-thats-been-tackled-at-the-knees/">I reviewed Rematch for Wccftech</a>, and was happy to be able to report that none of the issues I have with the game come from the core gameplay. It's a very tightly-made game, which makes it all the more unfortunate that there are so many issues around the core gameplay in how it's all structured that bring the experience down. Issues like poor menu design, slow-progression, and the misclassification of actions while in games, like how a goalie punching the ball away from a shot on net instead of catching it is counted as an interception, instead of a save.</p>
<p>Still, none of these issues are worth stopping you checking it out, as many of them can thankfully be patched out, along with all the bugs that myself and 3 million other players have had to endure. And, not to beat a dead horse with regarding the launch discourse around the game, but if you're playing Rematch, for the love of all that is good in football, please learn to pass.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/rematch-suprasses-1-million-units-sold-and-3-million-unique-players/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There’s a desktop-grade Nvidia RTX 5050 after all, and it’s out next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-desktop-grade-nvidia-rtx-5050-after-all-and-its-out-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there%E2%80%99s-a-desktop-grade-nvidia-rtx-5050-after-all-and-it%E2%80%99s-out-next-month.1228143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I’d give it a fifty-fifty chance</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nvidia</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yesterday’s launch of the Nvidia GeForce RTX 5050 laptop GPU was quiet, yet nonetheless featured a surprise: there’s also a <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-gb/geforce/news/rtx-5050-desktop-gpu-and-laptops/">desktop version of the RTX 5050</a>, set to release (exclusively in third-party garb – there’s no Founders Edition) in "the second half" of July. Quite the turnaround for the non-laptop XX50 lineage, which was widely assumed extinguished following 2022’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3050-review">RTX 3050</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The RTX 5050 will replace the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5060-review">RTX 5060</a> as the cheapest of Nvidia's current-gen desktop GPUs, starting at $249. Budget buyers will need to make do with 8GB of last-gen GDDR6 VRAM, however, as well as a lighter smattering of CUDA cores: 2,560 to the RTX 5060’s 3,840. There’s obviously no desktop <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-year-on-the-rtx-4050s-appeal-has-grown-but-better-laptop-gpus-loom">RTX 4050</a> to compare these specs to, though next to the RTX 3050, it does offer more memory bandwidth even if the total gigabyte count remains the same. Presumably there are also performance advantages, especially where ray tracing is concerned, that the RTX 5050 can glean from its updated Blackwell architecture.</p>
<p>'Course, while the RTX 5050 might make for a decent upgrade for current 3050 owners – especially those interested in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nvidia-dlss-4-explained">DLSS 4</a> and frame generation – its $249 price tag does keep it nervily close to the $300 RTX 5060. Which, even with its driver issues, really isn’t a bad 1080p card itself, so we’ll have to see what the 5050 can do to coexist with its more core-rich, wider-bandwidth big brother.</p>
<p>I’ll admit, there’s a not-small part of me that hopes it can. We can raise eyebrows at the specifications and make "Fnar fnar new GTX 1030" jokes until our typing fingers are worn down to stumps, but there genuinely are vast numbers of PC players who are happy with below-max quality 1080p yet can’t reliably stretch to mid-rangers like the XX60 series. People, in other words, who haven’t been adequately served by the GPU market in years. Arguably since even before the RTX 3050, what with that GPU launching during the dark times of COVID-compounded shortages and price gouging.</p>
<p>Will the RTX 5050 fill that gap? I won’t know until I’ve tested one out. But I’d rather it ends up as a failed attempt, than a repeat of the RTX 40 series' failing to try at all.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-desktop-grade-nvidia-rtx-5050-after-all-and-its-out-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Final Fantastic Four: First Steps Trailer Has Me Questioning The Whole Thing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-last-trailer-mcu-marvel-1851785068</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-final-fantastic-four-first-steps-trailer-has-me-questioning-the-whole-thing.1228131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="c7ee022d5a39ead812d9f5c30f3d4b4c" data-recommend-id="image://c7ee022d5a39ead812d9f5c30f3d4b4c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Fantastic Four pose for a family photo." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Fantastic Four pose for a family photo." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c7ee022d5a39ead812d9f5c30f3d4b4c" data-recommend-id="image://c7ee022d5a39ead812d9f5c30f3d4b4c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Fantastic Four pose for a family photo." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-trailer-movie-marvel-1851754637&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-trailer-movie-marvel-1851754637"><em>Fantastic Four: First Steps</em></a></span><em> </em>is finally bringing the first family to the Marvel Cinematic Universe next month, and after several trailers I’m starting to wonder how much we’ll actually see Reed Richards (Pedro Pascal) stretching his limbs as Mr. Fantastic. Each glimpse we get of him using his powers appears to be from one of two scenes in the movie. This final trailer shows him just a little more, but I still want to see that stretchy king smack someone around with long, flailing limbs. I hope the fact that Marvel has kept it under wraps in the trailers isn’t indicative of him not being in the action as much.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197556" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="GTA 6 Trailer 2: 13 Details You Might Have Missed" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="210" data-playlist="197556,197583,197586" data-current="197556"><div><p>GTA 6 Trailer 2: 13 Details You Might Have Missed</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197556/197556_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197556/197556_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197556/197556_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23080.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The final trailer for <em>First Steps </em>doesn’t really tell us much that we didn’t already know. Galactus is coming and the Silver Surfer is here to foreshadow his arrival. We still don’t see more than the planet-eating invader’s foot in this trailer, and at this point, I guess we won’t get a really good look at him until the film premieres on July 25. These trailers have shown a lot of the same stuff each time—this latest trailer perhaps showing even less than previously—and the most charitable read I can give is to assume that Marvel is keeping this movie’s secrets close to its chest. The Fantastic Four’s debut is a big deal for the MCU, and maybe you don’t want to spoil every surprise and cool sequence, but in doing so it’s kept me from finding anything to latch onto. How many different times can I hear Invisible Woman say that they’ll handle this apocalyptic moment as a family? <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-trailer-silver-surfer-mcu-1851776570&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-trailer-silver-surfer-mcu-1851776570">Julia Garner still looks pretty sick as the Silver Surfer, though</a></span>.</p><p>Check out the full trailer below:</p><p><em>Fantastic Four: First Steps </em>is the first film in the MCU’s Phase Six, and then the movies will take a break for a bit until the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-secret-wars-delay-gta-6-1851782163&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-secret-wars-delay-gta-6-1851782163">recently delayed <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em></a></span> premieres on December 18.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-last-trailer-mcu-marvel-1851785068]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story: Time Stranger introduces new Digimon enhancement systems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/digimon-story-time-stranger-introduces-new-digimon-enhancement-systems</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-introduces-new-digimon-enhancement-systems.1228128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Here are the details, via Bandai Namco lead producer Ryosuke Hara on <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/25/digimon-story-time-stranger-introducing-new-digimon-enhancement-systems/" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a>:</p><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</em> is a monster-raising <a title="Genres > RPG [17,389 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> that combines a rich narrative centered on the bond between humans and Digimon, a deeply strategic turn-based battle system, and extensive Digimon collection, training, and customization mechanics. Players take on the role of an agent from the secret organization ADAMAS, which specializes in investigating supernatural phenomena. Your mission will take you across both the human world and the Digital World: Iliad—and beyond the boundaries of time itself.</p><p>The game is developed by Media.Vision, the team behind the fan-favorite <em>Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth</em>. Building on that experience, we’ve introduced new systems and immersive ways to express the game’s world, story, and characters to create a special experience for longtime fans and those just discovering Digimon games alike.</p><p><strong>What is a Digimon?</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]--><br><video id="video-976054-1" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/Q3o218u.mp4?_=1"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/Q3o218u.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/Q3o218u.mp4</a></video></p><p>In this title, Digimon are electronic lifeforms that possess characteristics of both organic matter and electric signals. Early on, players will take on their first hostile Digimon encounter with their choice of a Digimon provided by ADAMAS. Defeat each Digimon type often enough to create an instance of it in a process known as Conversion. You can collect and train over 450 Digimon, each with unique traits and non-linear evolution paths.</p><p><strong>Attributes and Elements: How to Beat the Odds</strong></p><p>The turn-based battle system is built around the interaction of Digimon Attributes and Element. Their interactions create a battle environment where deeper strategies can emerge.</p><ul><li>Attribute: Vaccine, Virus, Data, Free, Variable, and others (seven total)</li><li>Element: Fire, Water, Plant, and others (11 total)</li></ul><p>Virus-type Digimon are weak to Vaccine-type, which are weak to Data-type. The other Attributes have their own strengths and weaknesses. Separately, each Digimon has resistances and weaknesses to the Elements.</p><p>For example, if your opponent is a Virus-type, attacking with a Vaccine-type Digimon will grant a +100% damage bonus. Additionally, using Water-type skills against them if they’re weak to water will further increase the damage multiplier! The reverse is also true—if both attribute and element matchups are unfavorable, the damage dealt will be significantly reduced.</p><p>Gain the battle advantage by obtaining a variety of Digimon through both converting Digimon and by Digivolving them. As digital beings, Digivolution is not linear—meeting certain conditions will unlock multiple evolution paths, and Digimon can even be De-digivolved to a younger form, allowing for flexible training strategies.</p><p><strong>Digimon <a title="Series > Persona [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>lities: Daring or Adoring?</strong></p><p>One of the new systems introduced in Time Stranger is Personalities. Each Digimon has one of 16 personality types, which influence stat growth, skill acquisition, and even digivolution conditions.</p><p>For example, a Digimon with a Daring personality will see higher growth in Attack and Defense, making it more suited for physical offense.</p><p><video id="video-976054-2" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/1iA99n8.mp4?_=2"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/1iA99n8.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/1iA99n8.mp4</a></video></p><p>They can also learn personality-linked skills that enhance combat capabilities. While a Digimon’s personality is initially determined when it is converted, it can be changed later through communication and training using special items in the Digifarm.</p><p>That means you can have two of the same Digimon that may perform differently based on their Personalities.</p><p><strong>Agent Skills: Lend a Helping Hand</strong></p><p>Another new system is Agent Skills, which represents the player’s own abilities as an ADAMAS agent. By completing missions, players earn points that can be used to unlock various effects—such as enhancing Digimon with specific personalities, increasing experience gain, or easing digivolution requirements. These skills allow for even more depth in how you prepare for battles.</p><p><video id="video-976054-3" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/ScVgZkG.mp4?_=3"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/ScVgZkG.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/ScVgZkG.mp4</a></video></p><p>Agents also have unique abilities known as Cross Arts—powerful techniques that fuse the player’s Digivice with a Digimon’s power during battles. Cross Arts can significantly influence combat with support effects like stat boosts or follow-up attacks.</p><p>As your Digimon train and evolve, you will also experience your own growth, indicated by Agent Rank. This directly affects your Digimon’s strength.</p><p><video id="video-976054-4" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/MwzN5Uf.mp4?_=4"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/MwzN5Uf.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/MwzN5Uf.mp4</a></video></p><p>We encourage players to take on missions proactively, raise their rank, and experience the sense of unity that comes from fighting alongside their Digimon teammates.</p><p><video id="video-976054-5" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://i.imgur.com/Us7gsQr.mp4?_=5"><a href="https://i.imgur.com/Us7gsQr.mp4">https://i.imgur.com/Us7gsQr.mp4</a></video></p><p>As you can see, Attributes, Elements, and Digivolving—along with the new Digimon Personalities and Agent Skills—all work together to add strategic depth to this unique battle system. Every fight is an opportunity to understand the strengths and weaknesses of Digimon and an opportunity to build a roster of Digimon ready for any scenario.</p></div><p>Watch a short video summary of the new information below.</p></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/digimon-story-time-stranger-introduces-new-digimon-enhancement-systems]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date Everything Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/date-everything-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/date-everything-review.1228113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Have you ever wanted to have a relationship with your toilet? No? Me neither. It sounds far too much like a euphemism to describe the morning after eating a particularly heinous kebab. Still, it’s definitely a question developer Sassy Chaps have asked themselves, and in response, they’ve created the sandbox dating simulator Date Everything, a narrative text-based adventure in which you can date, well, everything.</p>
<p><iframe title="Date Everything | Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dlxxzmOXRf0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As we all know, AI is coming for our jobs. But for the protagonist of Date Everything, AI has already arrived. In a humorous – yet scarily believable – opening, our hapless lead has just got a new working at home job for a massive tech firm, only to instantly lose it again when they are promptly fired. It’s not all bad though, as they soon receive a mysterious parcel from another ex-employee.</p>


<p>This gift turns out to be a pair of near-magical glasses, named Date-viators – that turn every object in the house – well, around a hundred of them anyway – into sentient and eminently dateable entities. What follows is a very loose and delightfully daft conspiratorial narrative, which is nothing more than an excuse for the hilarity of trying to woo your boiler.</p>
<p>Characterisation here is over the top and completely charming, with gorgeous comic-book-like artwork bringing humanised curtains, shelves, and gym equipment to life. Each day you mooch around your house, using the handful of charges your glasses possess to chat to your furniture, before you head to bed – which you can also date – to allow your mystical specs to recharge.</p>


<p>Exploration takes place from a 3D first-person view, and it’s here that Date Everything is at it’s weakest. The frame rate on Switch during these first-person sections frankly sucks, with obnoxious controls that make even navigating around a kitchenette a ridiculous chore. It’s almost as if First-Person games were never a thing, with controls that haven’t been refined over decades of gameplay. However, put up with these clunky moments and you’ll find a lot to enjoy in Date Everything.</p>
<p>The script is razor sharp; sardonic, silly, often laugh-out-load hilarious and occasionally rather touching. As you chat to your household objects each day, you’ll learn more about them and their relationships with their fellow tables, TVs and tennis racquets. Often, you’ll have feuds to resolve by playing peacemaker, with the ultimate aim to bring harmony to your home, rather than to get intimate with your lamp – though both are possible. Voice acting is top-notch, with a who’s who of vocal talent from across the videogame industry.</p>

<p>My personal highlights include the Thor-like Gym-equipment called Kristof, the insecure office supplies named Penelope who just wants to be noticed and used again, and Rebel the… erm… bad ass rubber duck who hangs out in the bathroom. Sassy Chaps clearly take great pleasure in skewering modern culture, but they’re definitely equal opportunity mockers, with Microtransactions being lampooned with the money-obsessed and brilliantly named Michael Transaction. You can even date their own Deluxe Edition of the game, Lucinda, to hilarious effect.</p>
<p>It’s just enormous fun talking to these wonderfully conceived characters and undertaking their simple quests, and in doing so unlocking further characters to talk too. There’s no prescriptive order to chat to your objects either, you’re free to talk to, or not talk to, whoever you want. Whilst extended sessions with the game can reveal the limitations of the gameplay – which amounts to little more than reading and selecting the occasional response, let’s face it – in short bursts Date Everything is a sumptuous treat.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/25/date-everything-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>