<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 20:06:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drunkards, Druggies, & Delinquents Pre-Orders Now Open]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/drunkards-druggies-delinquents-pre-orders-now-open</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/drunkards-druggies-delinquents-pre-orders-now-open.1167273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/drunkards-druggies-delinquents-pre-orders-now-open<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Pre-orders are now live for <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1183ce14-1675-44b1-af00-4d7855d7f06c" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/chris-prynoski-talks-drunkards-druggies-and-delinquents-how-420-joke-became" rel="nofollow"><em>Drunkards, Druggies, &amp; Delinquents</em></a>. This light RPG experience is the tabletop game debut for Titmouse, the animation studio behind many beloved mature animated shows spanning both character dramas and crass comedies.</p>



<p>In an official press release, Titmouse announced pre-orders went live for <em>Drunkards, Druggies, &amp; Delinquents</em> as part of the company celebrating their 25th anniversary. Copies of the game will begin shipping in late August ahead of a Fall 2025 retail release.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/drunkards-druggies-delinquents-box-artwork.jpg?itok=MFEHnCka 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/drunkards-druggies-delinquents-box-artwork.jpg?itok=rrkF4i18 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The game was originally pitched as an April Fools Day gag, but became a passion project for Titmouse starting in 2023. The lead creators are company Founder Chris Prynoski and Chief Creative Officer Antonio Canobbio. The game is designed for 3-8 adult players and a single game can last roughly 1-3 hours.</p>

<p><em>Drunkards, Druggies, &amp; Delinquents</em> is a blend of a light TTRPG, fantasy quest, party game, and collaborative trainwreck. Players take on the roles of unpredictable anti-heroes taking on increasingly absurd quests, leading to wild improvisation and escalating hilarity. The character classes include the Beerbarian, Weed Wraith, the Whiskey Wizard, and the Druid of the Flower.</p>

<p>The focus of the game isn't on strategy or victory, but on improv. Yes, you can get equipment for your character, and you do roll dice to resolve challenges. The twist is that if your character gets hurt, you have to drink or partake in whatever substance you have on hand. If you want a cleaner experience, these explicit prompts can be swapped out for drinking soda or doing dares.</p>

<p>This explicit style of game is in keeping with Titmouse's body of work. They are an award-winning animation studio whose work includes Mike Judge's <em>Beavis &amp; Butthead</em>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/star-trek-lower-decks-buffer-time-card-game-about-doing-starfleet-menial-tasks" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Star Trek: Lower Decks</em></a>, Adult Swim's <em>The Venture Bros</em>, and Critical Role's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/legend-of-vox-machina-season-4-confirmed-by-critical-role-and-prime-video-ahead-of-s3" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>The Legend of Vox Machina</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A pair of Armored Core games are being freed from their 2000s Japanese mobile phone prison with upcoming PC ports]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-pair-of-armored-core-games-are-being-freed-from-their-2000s-japanese-mobile-phone-prison-with-an-upcoming-pc-port</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-pair-of-armored-core-games-are-being-freed-from-their-2000s-japanese-mobile-phone-prison-with-upcoming-pc-ports.1167270/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-pair-of-armored-core-games-are-being-freed-from-their-2000s-japanese-mobile-phone-prison-with-an-upcoming-pc-port<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>And a couple of Shin Megami Tensei games to boot, too</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/armored-core-mobile-mission.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>G-Mode/ FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/armored-core-vi-fires-of-rubicon">Armored</a> Core is a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/fromsoftware">FromSoftware</a> series that absolutely rips, and has done since its debut way back on the PS1. Technically us PC players only recently were graced with the ability to play something from the series with the release of Armored Core 6, but soon we'll have a couple more to mess around with. The only caveat is that it would be helpful if you could speak Japanese, as they're not getting an English language release.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
You see, back in the early 2000s, Japan had some pretty advanced phones, some of which had cameras built in, internet access, GPS, and yes, even games. Some of them had whole ports of classic Final Fantasys, and there's even a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-vii">Final Fantasy 7</a> spinoff that's exclusive to one of these phones (which is, legally speaking, unplayable to this day despite supposedly being canon). Amongst the numerous other series that got early mobile spinoffs - I'm talking <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-hearts">Kingdom Hearts</a>, Monster Hunter, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/katamari-damacy">Katamari Damacy</a>, Persona - Armored Core also received a few entries too.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="【新作発表】G-MODEアーカイブス5周年記念生放送【じもチューブ第8回】" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/akg38-Vu0Hg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>【新作発表】G-MODEアーカイブス5周年記念生放送【じもチューブ第8回】</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/akg38-Vu0Hg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/akg38-Vu0Hg?autoplay=1" title="【新作発表】G-MODEアーカイブス5周年記念生放送【じもチューブ第8回】">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=akg38-Vu0Hg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
And, as announced by developer G-Mode, Armored Core Mobile Mission and its sequel Mobile Mission 2 are coming to Steam. The first one's actually due out soon, on April 30th, and you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3633410/GMODE_ARMORED_CORE_MOBILE_MISSION/">wishlist it on Steam</a>, but the second one doesn't have a release date just yet. Mobile mission is a top down shooter, but you can still customise your mech, and the second one actually lets you walk around its levels too. Honestly, really impressive stuff for the time.
</p>
<p>
Not only that, there's a couple of Shin Megami Tensei ports on the way too, if <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPGs</a> are more your thing. The first of them, Tokyo Requiem, was a completely original game for Japanese phones, whereas <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/20xx">20XX</a> was a prequel to Shin Megami Tensei 2. Neither have release dates just yet, but the latter is available to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3652460/GMODE_20XX/">wishlist on Steam</a> too.
</p>
<p>
Again, none of this will be playable in English, but I really love the work that G-Mode is putting into these releases. Their whole shtick is porting old Japanese phone games, not an easy feat given that some of them were exclusive to certain networks, so I'm chuffed to see them playable on modern hardware. Good motivation to finally start those Japanese lessons I reckon!

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demonschool launches this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/demonschool-launches-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demonschool-launches-this-summer.1167258/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/demonschool-launches-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New trailer introduces minigames.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>School life <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [412 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">strategy RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Demonschool [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demonschool">Demonschool</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,070 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,922 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,975 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,928 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1900250/Demonschool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://necrosoftgames.itch.io/demonschool" target="_blank" rel="noopener">itch.io</a> this summer, publisher <a title="Companies > Ysbryd Games [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ysbryd-games">Ysbryd Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Necrosoft Games [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/necrosoft-games">Necrosoft Games</a> announced. <span id="more-959418"></span></p><p>A new trailer was also released, introducing minigames like <a title="Genres > Cooking [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking</a>, fishing, singing karaoke, lifting weights, <a title="Genres > Racing [243 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> beetles, and island hangouts.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Ysbryd Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Demonschool</em> is a new-style tactics <a title="Genres > RPG [17,167 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> where motion equals <a title="Genres > Action [2,672 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>. Defeat big weirdos in between the human and demon worlds as Faye and her misfit companions, while navigating university life on a mysterious island.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Tactics</strong> – Rewind any action during the planning phase and create combos to dispatch your foes.</li><li><strong>Story</strong> – A light <a title="Genres > Horror [595 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> narrative told through huge avatars with side quests aplenty.</li><li><strong>Schedule</strong> – Plan your school schedule to level your characters and build their skills.</li><li><strong>Friendship</strong> – 15 characters with whom to build relationships.</li></ul><p><strong>Battle System Basics</strong></p><ul><li>Units interact contextually with their environment. Enemies will be struck, objects moved, or the character will simply dash.</li><li>Plan movements at your leisure, and execute them all at once. You can also rewind actions during the planning phase.</li><li>Buffing friendlies and debuffing enemies compounds damage output. Note the damage numbers!</li><li>Combos do big damage and produce unique elemental attacks, which you can use to exploit enemy weaknesses.</li></ul><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Faye</strong> – Last in line of the final demon hunting family on the planet Earth. Loves to punch up, cares about everybody.</li><li><strong>Destin</strong> – A pugilist through and through. A good guy who believes in you to his detriment.</li><li><strong>Namako</strong> – Photography nerd who keeps everything packed down in a tight little knot in her stomach ’til she explodes.</li><li><strong>Knute</strong> – Pragmatic media enthusiast who always sees all the angles. Trying to be more positive these days.</li></ul><p><strong>World</strong></p><p>Explore a mysterious island that reveals its mysteries morning, noon, and night, day by day, week by week, across a university semester. Plan your team’s schedule to enhance their skills and gain new abilities. Gain new teammates and enhance their relationships depending on who you choose to pursue.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Minigames Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Demonschool - Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbiJTs1h8kY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Painkiller ‘Weapons’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/painkiller-weapons-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/painkiller-%E2%80%98weapons%E2%80%99-trailer.1167255/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/painkiller-weapons-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Introducing the Electrodiver, Stakegun, SMG, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 3D Realms [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive/3d-realms">3D Realms</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Anshar Studios [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/anshar-studios">Anshar Studios</a> have released a new trailer for <em><a title="Games > Painkiller (2025) [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/painkiller-2025">Painkiller</a></em>, the upcoming reimagining of the classic <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> franchise. <span id="more-959427"></span></p><p>Here are the latest details:</p><blockquote><p>In <em>Painkiller</em>, you’ll unleash hell with seven bonebreaking, flesh-ripping weapons. Each weapon offers primary and alternative fire modes, elemental effects such as fire, ice, electro, and kinetic, and are upgradable with different abilities to provide unique bonus effects:</p><ul><li><strong>Electrodriver</strong> – Barrage enemies with rapid-firing shurikens that bounce off hard surfaces.</li><li><strong>Stakegun</strong> – Hurls high-damage stakes that can impale foes from long range.</li><li><strong>SMG</strong> – Unleashes loads of ammo in short, rapid-fire bursts.</li><li><strong>Handcannon</strong> – Decimate enemies from long range with deadly precision.</li><li><strong>Shotgun</strong> – Spits destructive pellets at short range that can damage and stagger multiple foes.</li><li><strong>Rocket Launcher</strong> – Discharges a rocket projectile with a devastating blast radius that can stagger even heavy enemies.</li></ul><p>The titular Painkiller, a versatile weapon with a brutal melee attack that hooks onto enemies and shreds them to pieces while refilling your ammo<br>Welcome to Purgatory! You’ve been sentenced for your transgressions against Heaven, but the Voice of the Creator is giving you one chance to redeem yourself. Blast through hordes of demons in brutal, fast-paced combat with an array of infernal weapons. Battle across gruesome gothic environments to stop the fallen angel Azazel’s invasion of Earth and earn your salvation—solo or in online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">co-op</a> for up to three players.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Purgatory Is Your Playground</strong> – Jump, hook and dash across vast, spine-chilling biomes while fighting nightmarish enemies in bloody, fast-paced combat with a host of new and classic <em>Painkiller</em> weapons.</li><li><strong>Grotesque Terrors Await</strong> – Challenge a variety of horrifying foes, from hordes of demons to titanic terrors like the monstrous children of Azazel – the Nephilim.</li><li><strong>Unleash the Pain</strong> – Use tarot cards to upgrade your abilities, rank up to expand your arsenal, and team up with other players to obliterate all foes.</li><li><strong>Choose Your Character Wisely</strong> – Play as one of four distinctive characters – Ink, Void, Sol and Roch – with unique perks to boost your energy, health, power and damage.</li><li><strong>Three-Player Online Cooperative and Solo <a title="Genres > Action [2,672 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong> – Play online with up to two friends or offline with bots, exploring diverse locations, uncovering secrets and facing off against terrifying enemies.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Painkiller</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,070 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,928 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2300120/Painkiller/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this fall.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Weapons Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Painkiller - Weapons Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2J41CouSSWU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello Kitty Island Adventure's Fruitful Friendship Update Gives The Game A Medieval Spin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin/1100-6530949/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin.1167249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin/1100-6530949/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530949">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hello-kitty-island-adventure/">Hello Kitty Island Adventure</a>'s latest seasonal content drop--the Fruitful Friendship update--is available now on Apple Arcade.</p><p dir="ltr">Starting on April 18, players can join Kitty White, Kuromi, My Melody, and the rest of the Sanrio crew in the Imagination Celebration, a medieval-themed limited-time event complete with princess dresses, suits of armor, wizard robes, and castle-worthy furniture. Players must help Hello Kitty &amp; Co. collect Mystic Stones to restore magic to the Kingdom of Friendship. The Imagination Celebration Event ends on May 22.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mthep19u6aw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mthep19u6aw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">But the Fruitful Friendship update has plenty more in store. It also includes a new feature in which players help Keroppi plant and maintain an orchard located on City Town's rooftops, allowing players to grow 13 new fruits. These new fruits can then be used to concoct new types of Fruit Sandos in the Imagination Cafe.</p><p dir="ltr">The update also includes a City Town newcomer and new visitor quests. Players can help decorate a cabin to serve as a home for Retsuko's new friend, Puko, and new quests for pre-existing City Town visitors have also been added.</p><p dir="ltr">Lastly, Fruitful Friendship is introducing a number of player-requested quality-of-life improvements, like a map to help players navigate City Town's Sewers and an updated tool wheel.</p><p>But even more seasonal content is on the way, according to developer Sunblink Entertainment, which directed players to "prepare for an <em>egg-cellent</em> island takeover of an iconic Sanrio pal." The developer added that "Players can look forward to exciting content update coming soon."</p><p>Hello Kitty Island Adventure is available to play via Apple Arcade, PC (via Steam), and Nintendo Switch.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World features missions for the first time in 20 years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/mario-kart-world-features-missions-for-the-first-time-in-20-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-features-missions-for-the-first-time-in-20-years.1167237/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/mario-kart-world-features-missions-for-the-first-time-in-20-years<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will feature missions for the first time in 20 years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As part of today‛s </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mq4uCJDwO9U">Mario Kart World Direct</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Nintendo showed an in-depth overview of Free Roam mode, which allows players to explore the map in its entirety, seemingly without barriers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During this exploratory phase outside of races, players can bump onto P Switches, objects that start missions. The examples shown included collecting eight blue coins on an obstacle course under 24 seconds, and a race where golden armadillos are blocking the track.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart DS</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> first introduced Mission Mode in 2005. The feature offered players a reprieve from competitive races with multiple objectives and boss fights.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, missions aren‛t part of a separate mode, but rather integrated in the open world segment. The trailer noted there are "hundreds of P Switches" across the world, their purpose being to “hone your driving ability outside of races” by completing the missions. There are also collectibles to find, and players can use Photo Mode to take pictures.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Cruising together">Cruising together</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other players can join a session in Free Roam. While this is meant to serve as a hub to kickstart races together, it‛s possible to tag along to explore the map. Game Developer senior editor Bryant Francis noted that it will be interesting if these missions are structured around </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/nintendo-switch-2-shows-nintendo-s-strategy-for-a-social-future">social play with friends</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> versus linear progression.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/design-opportunities-for-devs-from-our-time-trying-out-the-nintendo-switch-2" target="_self" data-discover="true">The Nintendo Switch 2's mouse mode opens amazing doors for devs</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Based on the examples shown, it could go either way. Considering that Nintendo is pushing the communal online aspect around the Switch 2 with the inclusion of GameChat for video calls during game sessions, as well as its own camera, it wouldn't be surprising if some objectives overlapped with other players.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is set to release as a Switch 2 launch title, which is estimated for June 5. Pre-orders are currently unavailable in the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-scraps-switch-2-pre-orders-in-the-u-s-over-trump-tariffs">U.S.</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-are-delayed-in-canada-as-well">Canada</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> over the Trump administration tariffs. In China, Nintendo is reportedly </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-nintendo-is-delaying-switch-2-pre-orders-in-china-due-to-government-regulations">delaying the console indefinitely</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to asses demand levels in the highly regulated local market. The company has yet to address the pre-orders publicly, although the U.S. tariff pause, announced last week, could provide the company time to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/u-s-tariff-pause-could-give-nintendo-time-to-amass-a-switch-2-stockpile">amass a Switch 2 stockpile</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Has A New Battle Royale Game In Development Inspired By Apex Legends – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-has-a-new-battle-royale-game-in-development-inspired-by-apex-legends-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-has-a-new-battle-royale-game-in-development-inspired-by-apex-legends-%E2%80%93-rumor.1167216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-has-a-new-battle-royale-game-in-development-inspired-by-apex-legends-rumor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to a report from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-ubisoft-is-developing-a-new-battle-royale-heavily-inspired-by-apex-legends/">Insider-Gaming</a>, Ubisoft has another live service game in development following its shutdown of XDefiant, which will be gone forever this coming <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisofts-xdefiant-will-be-closing-down-for-good-in-june-2025/">June 2025</a>.</p>
<p>The report claims that this game will be a battle royale and is currently in development under the codename "Scout. "One of Insider-Gaming's sources says that "<em>I think the goal is to capitalize on the player count of Apex dropping and them [Ubisoft higher-ups] thinking there's room in the market for another hero Battle Royale.</em>"</p>
<p>This, of course, isn't Ubisoft's first crack at adding another successful live service title to its portfolio. Rainbow Six is arguably the most significant live service success it has, but that's still a paid title, and not a free-to-play game. Ubisoft's track record is very different in terms of its free-to-play successes.</p>
<p>Out of its current free-to-play offerings, it is easy to imagine that Brawlhalla is the most successful, though Ubisoft's longest-running free-to-play game is the PC-only MMO sandbox Growtopia. Last year's summer release, Battle Core Arena, Rocksmith+, Roller Champions, Trackmania, and Rabbids Coding are also listed on <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-ca/games/free">Ubisoft's website</a> as part of its free-to-play lineup. If these games are doing amazingly well for Ubisoft, the company certainly isn't discussing those successes.</p>
<p>Of course, XDefiant used to be on that list, but it was long removed after last year's closing announcements. <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/hyper-scape/">Hyper Scape</a> is another free-to-play title that, just like XDefiant, didn't last. Right now, it's difficult to see whatever this project Scout ends up becoming, having a different fate than either XDefiant or Hyper Scape.</p>
<p>Battle royales are also not the new, exciting genre they once were in the free-to-play, live service world. Sure, the biggest ones are still very popular. No one is dethroning Fortnite, Call of Duty: Warzone, or PUBG anytime soon. If anything, you could argue that XDefiant's attempt at bringing back an old-school flavor of multiplayer was what had a better shot at breaking through the live service ceiling.</p>
<p>If Ubisoft had let the game run for at least a calendar year and supported it differently, XDefiant might have ended up on the rise after the drop-off from its launch success. If this rumored project makes it to PCs and consoles, we'll see if Ubisoft is willing to give it that chance.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost Records: Bloom & Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-playstation-1851776660</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-is-short-shocking-and-strangely-satisfying.1167210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-playstation-1851776660<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="styled-global-nav"><div><a href="https://kotaku.com/" title="Kotaku" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Logo click&quot;,&quot;Kotaku&quot;]]"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="212" height="39" aria-label="Kotaku logo" viewBox="0 0 212 39"><path fill="#FBC000" fill-rule="evenodd" d="M191.72 5.28l1.2 17.98-8.58.16-1-18.37-6.51-.17.94 21.03c.13 3 2.28 5.38 4.77 5.29l12.99-.49c2.3-.09 3.97-2.48 3.75-5.33l-1.5-19.93-6.06-.17zm13.1 1.62c-.2-2.61-1.88-4.8-3.78-4.88l-1.74-.07.64 9.67 5.22.08-.34-4.8zm6.8 0c-.23-2.61-1.9-4.8-3.77-4.87l-1.71-.08.72 9.67 5.14.08-.39-4.8zm-60.2-3l.2 28.27 2.58-.1c2.85-.1 5.1-2.76 5.04-5.92L158.9 4.1l-7.46-.2zm7.83 10.72l8.01.04c2.62.01 3.8 1.18 4.79 3.02l9.66 20.68c-1.07 1.4-7.06.8-9.53-4.74l-5.12-11.27-.45.01-.4.01c-2.76.04-7.05-2.58-6.96-7.74zM143.39 4.23l-12.1-.33c-5.75-.15-7.27 4.83-6.34 8.06l15.81.14-.1 12.1-10.89.2.05-2.14 3.2-.04c5.72-.08 7.1-4.77 6.17-7.94h-.04l.02-.01-11.92-.05c-3.09-.01-5.72 2.61-5.84 5.9l-.04 1.05-.22 6.04c-.13 3.39 2.39 6.06 5.57 5.94l16.55-.63c2.91-.1 5.24-2.8 5.23-5.97l-.05-16.77c-.02-3-2.26-5.47-5.06-5.55zm-39.82 24.5a5.95 5.95 0 0 0 6.33 6.37l3.32-.12 1.08-21.27-9.75-.06-.98 15.08zm13.46-17.03c6.17.05 7.73-5 6.8-8.21l-20.86-.56c-6.64-.18-7.88 5.14-6.96 8.58l21.02.19zM88.76 2.5l-19.43-.54c-7.58-.21-10.1 5.6-9.22 9.38l24.53.23-1.25 14-14.16.27 1.45-12.99-10.9-.07-2.09 16.38c-.5 3.95 2.53 7.07 6.71 6.9l21.57-.8a7.76 7.76 0 0 0 7.31-6.98L94.75 8.9a5.98 5.98 0 0 0-5.99-6.4zm-69.34-.55L12.7 38.02l4.22-.16c4.65-.18 8.92-3.63 9.6-7.67l4.74-27.9-11.84-.34zm11.06 12.68l13.02.05c4.23.02 5.87 1.5 7.02 3.81l8.1 19.65c-2.05 1.8-11.6 1.18-14.3-5.88l-2.96-7.84h-.73l-.63.01c-4.52.06-10.9-3.25-9.52-9.8zM15.7 12.67l1.9-10.51-6.57-.2C1.9 1.7-.63 8.26.12 12.53l15.58.16zm22.73 1.96l16.8-3.68c3.16-1.93 4.51-8.9 2.3-10.95l-16.3 3.95c-2.77 1.5-5.95 5.86-2.8 10.68zm124.62 0l8.93-4.84c3.1-2.63 3.97-6.97 1.32-9.79l-9.64 6.05c-3.44 2.32-2.92 5.76-.61 8.58z"></path></svg></a><p>Gaming Reviews, News, Tips and More.</p></div><nav><ul><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;home&quot;]]" data-key="home" href="https://kotaku.com/"><span>Home</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;latest&quot;]]" data-key="latest" href="https://kotaku.com/latest"><span>Latest</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/entertainment&quot;]]" data-index="1" href="https://kotaku.com/entertainment"><span>Entertainment</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/reviews&quot;]]" data-index="2" href="https://kotaku.com/reviews"><span>Reviews</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/culture/news&quot;]]" data-index="3" href="https://kotaku.com/culture/news"><span>News</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/game-tips&quot;]]" data-index="4" href="https://kotaku.com/game-tips"><span>Tips &amp; Guides</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games&quot;]]" data-index="5" href="https://kotaku.com/games"><span>Games</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;Nav Editions&quot;]]" data-key="editions" href="https://kotaku.com/"><span><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="18" height="18" aria-label="Globe icon" viewBox="0 0 18 18"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M9 1a8 8 0 1 1 0 16A8 8 0 0 1 9 1zM6.11 13.13l-.1.02c.42.66.98 1.3 1.7 2.02l.79.77V12.9c-.89.02-1.67.09-2.39.22zm3.4-.23l-.01 3.04.78-.77A11.2 11.2 0 0 0 12 13.12a15.7 15.7 0 0 0-2.5-.22zM5 13.4l-.12.03c-.34.11-.66.24-.97.38a7 7 0 0 0 2.85 1.83A11.04 11.04 0 0 1 5 13.4zm8.03-.04l-.07.13a11.2 11.2 0 0 1-1.72 2.15 6.99 6.99 0 0 0 2.89-1.86c-.35-.17-.72-.3-1.1-.42zM4 9.4H2A6.96 6.96 0 0 0 3.26 13l-.2.1a8.7 8.7 0 0 1 1.5-.62A8.86 8.86 0 0 1 4 9.4zm11.98 0h-2a8.92 8.92 0 0 1-.53 3.04c.46.14.9.31 1.3.52A6.94 6.94 0 0 0 16 9.4zm-7.49 0H5c.04 1.12.2 2.01.54 2.82a16 16 0 0 1 2.96-.31V9.4zm4.5 0H9.5v2.5h.06c1.1.02 2.06.11 2.92.29.32-.8.48-1.69.51-2.79zM3.37 4.83l-.06.07a7.1 7.1 0 0 0-1.3 3.5h2c.04-1.21.24-2.19.64-3.08a7.9 7.9 0 0 1-1.28-.5zm2.27.74v.02c-.4.8-.59 1.69-.64 2.8h3.5V5.87c-1.06-.02-2-.12-2.85-.29zm6.72.03l-.16.03c-.9.16-1.91.24-3.08.24h.37V8.4h3.49a7.1 7.1 0 0 0-.62-2.8zm2.28-.74l-.28.13c-.32.14-.66.27-1.01.37.38.88.58 1.84.63 3.04h1.98a6.96 6.96 0 0 0-1.32-3.54zM9.5 2.14v2.73c.87-.02 1.64-.08 2.33-.19a11.9 11.9 0 0 0-1.47-1.7l-.86-.84zm-1 0l-.14.14-.72.7c-.6.6-1.07 1.13-1.45 1.67.7.12 1.45.19 2.3.21l.01-2.72zm2.61.18l.18.18c.66.68 1.18 1.3 1.59 1.96.38-.1.75-.24 1.1-.39a7 7 0 0 0-2.87-1.75zm-4.22 0l-.19.07a7 7 0 0 0-2.64 1.65c.34.15.7.28 1.08.38.44-.7 1.02-1.36 1.75-2.1z"></path></svg></span>Editions</span><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="18" height="18" aria-label="ChevronDown icon" viewBox="0 0 18 18"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M3.87 6.16a.5.5 0 0 0-.74.68l5.5 6c.2.21.54.21.74 0l5.5-6a.5.5 0 1 0-.74-.68L9 11.76l-5.13-5.6z"></path></svg></span></a><div><ul><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;Edition Dropdown&quot;,&quot;es.kotaku.com&quot;]]" data-index="es" href="https://es.kotaku.com/">Español</a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;Edition Dropdown&quot;,&quot;de.kotaku.com&quot;]]" data-index="de" href="https://de.kotaku.com/">Deutsch</a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag click&quot;,&quot;Edition Dropdown&quot;,&quot;fr.kotaku.com&quot;]]" data-index="fr" href="https://fr.kotaku.com/">Français</a></li></ul></div></li></ul></nav><div><div><a href="https://kotaku.com/" title="Kotaku" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;,&quot;Logo click&quot;,&quot;Kotaku&quot;]]"></a></div><div><div><p>Discover</p><ul><li><a data-key="home" href="https://kotaku.com/"><span>Home</span></a></li><li><a data-key="latest" href="https://kotaku.com/latest"><span>Latest</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag Click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/entertainment&quot;,{&quot;metric20&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/entertainment"><span>Entertainment</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag Click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/reviews&quot;,{&quot;metric20&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/reviews"><span>Reviews</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag Click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/culture/news&quot;,{&quot;metric20&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/culture/news"><span>News</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag Click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/game-tips&quot;,{&quot;metric20&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/game-tips"><span>Tips &amp; Guides</span></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Vertical/Tag Click&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games&quot;,{&quot;metric20&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games"><span>Games</span></a></li></ul><p>Editions</p><div><p><a href="https://es.kotaku.com/" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;, &quot;Editions click&quot;, &quot;es.kotaku.com&quot;]]"><span><span><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="12" fill="white"></circle><path d="M11.3438 15.7734V17H6.40625V15.7734H11.3438ZM6.66406 5.625V17H5.22656V5.625H6.66406ZM10.6797 10.5156V11.7422H6.40625V10.5156H10.6797ZM11.2656 5.625V6.85938H6.40625V5.625H11.2656ZM18.6562 14.125C18.6562 13.8594 18.625 13.625 18.5625 13.4219C18.5 13.2135 18.3906 13.026 18.2344 12.8594C18.0781 12.6927 17.8594 12.5339 17.5781 12.3828C17.2969 12.2318 16.9401 12.0781 16.5078 11.9219C16.0391 11.7552 15.6146 11.5703 15.2344 11.3672C14.8542 11.1589 14.5286 10.9219 14.2578 10.6562C13.9922 10.3906 13.7865 10.0859 13.6406 9.74219C13.4948 9.39844 13.4219 9.00521 13.4219 8.5625C13.4219 8.11979 13.4974 7.71094 13.6484 7.33594C13.8047 6.96094 14.0234 6.63542 14.3047 6.35938C14.5911 6.07812 14.9349 5.85938 15.3359 5.70312C15.737 5.54688 16.1849 5.46875 16.6797 5.46875C17.4193 5.46875 18.0417 5.63281 18.5469 5.96094C19.0573 6.28385 19.4427 6.70833 19.7031 7.23438C19.9635 7.75521 20.0938 8.3125 20.0938 8.90625H18.6562C18.6562 8.47917 18.5859 8.10156 18.4453 7.77344C18.3099 7.4401 18.0964 7.17969 17.8047 6.99219C17.5182 6.79948 17.1432 6.70312 16.6797 6.70312C16.263 6.70312 15.9193 6.78385 15.6484 6.94531C15.3828 7.10677 15.1849 7.32552 15.0547 7.60156C14.9297 7.8776 14.8672 8.19271 14.8672 8.54688C14.8672 8.78646 14.9089 9.00521 14.9922 9.20312C15.0755 9.39583 15.2031 9.57552 15.375 9.74219C15.5521 9.90885 15.7708 10.0625 16.0312 10.2031C16.2969 10.3438 16.6094 10.4792 16.9688 10.6094C17.526 10.7917 18.0026 10.9948 18.3984 11.2188C18.7943 11.4427 19.1172 11.6953 19.3672 11.9766C19.6172 12.2526 19.7995 12.5677 19.9141 12.9219C20.0339 13.2708 20.0938 13.6667 20.0938 14.1094C20.0938 14.5729 20.0156 14.9922 19.8594 15.3672C19.7083 15.7422 19.487 16.0625 19.1953 16.3281C18.9036 16.5938 18.5521 16.7995 18.1406 16.9453C17.7292 17.0859 17.2656 17.1562 16.75 17.1562C16.3021 17.1562 15.862 17.0833 15.4297 16.9375C15.0026 16.7917 14.6146 16.5729 14.2656 16.2812C13.9167 15.9896 13.638 15.6302 13.4297 15.2031C13.2214 14.7708 13.1172 14.2708 13.1172 13.7031H14.5547C14.5547 14.0938 14.612 14.4297 14.7266 14.7109C14.8411 14.987 15 15.2161 15.2031 15.3984C15.4062 15.5807 15.638 15.7161 15.8984 15.8047C16.1641 15.888 16.4479 15.9297 16.75 15.9297C17.1667 15.9297 17.5156 15.8568 17.7969 15.7109C18.0833 15.5651 18.2969 15.3568 18.4375 15.0859C18.5833 14.8151 18.6562 14.4948 18.6562 14.125Z" fill="#222222"></path></svg></span></span><span>Español</span></a><a href="https://de.kotaku.com/" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;, &quot;Editions click&quot;, &quot;de.kotaku.com&quot;]]"><span><span><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="12" fill="white"></circle><path d="M6.80469 17H4.86719L4.88281 15.7734H6.80469C7.48698 15.7734 8.04167 15.6432 8.46875 15.3828C8.89583 15.1172 9.21094 14.7266 9.41406 14.2109C9.61719 13.6901 9.71875 13.0469 9.71875 12.2812V10.3359C9.71875 9.73177 9.66146 9.21094 9.54688 8.77344C9.43229 8.33594 9.26042 7.97656 9.03125 7.69531C8.80208 7.41406 8.51302 7.20573 8.16406 7.07031C7.8151 6.92969 7.40625 6.85938 6.9375 6.85938H4.82812V5.625H6.9375C7.57812 5.625 8.15625 5.72656 8.67188 5.92969C9.1875 6.1276 9.63021 6.42708 10 6.82812C10.3698 7.22396 10.651 7.71615 10.8438 8.30469C11.0417 8.89323 11.1406 9.57552 11.1406 10.3516V12.2812C11.1406 13.0573 11.0417 13.7396 10.8438 14.3281C10.651 14.9167 10.3672 15.4089 9.99219 15.8047C9.61719 16.2005 9.16146 16.5 8.625 16.7031C8.09375 16.901 7.48698 17 6.80469 17ZM5.66406 5.625V17H4.22656V5.625H5.66406ZM19.9844 15.7734V17H15.0469V15.7734H19.9844ZM15.3047 5.625V17H13.8672V5.625H15.3047ZM19.3203 10.5156V11.7422H15.0469V10.5156H19.3203ZM19.9062 5.625V6.85938H15.0469V5.625H19.9062Z" fill="#222222"></path></svg></span></span><span>Deutsch</span></a><a href="https://fr.kotaku.com/" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;, &quot;Editions click&quot;, &quot;fr.kotaku.com&quot;]]"><span><span><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="12" fill="white"></circle><path d="M6.66406 5.625V17H5.22656V5.625H6.66406ZM10.5 10.7422V11.9766H6.39062V10.7422H10.5ZM11.1484 5.625V6.85938H6.39062V5.625H11.1484ZM13.4375 5.625H16.6172C17.3568 5.625 17.9766 5.75521 18.4766 6.01562C18.9818 6.27604 19.362 6.66146 19.6172 7.17188C19.8776 7.67708 20.0078 8.29948 20.0078 9.03906C20.0078 9.5599 19.9219 10.0365 19.75 10.4688C19.5781 10.8958 19.3281 11.2604 19 11.5625C18.6719 11.8594 18.2734 12.0807 17.8047 12.2266L17.4141 12.3906H14.5781L14.5625 11.1641H16.6016C17.0391 11.1641 17.4036 11.0703 17.6953 10.8828C17.987 10.6901 18.2057 10.4323 18.3516 10.1094C18.4974 9.78646 18.5703 9.42969 18.5703 9.03906C18.5703 8.60156 18.5052 8.21875 18.375 7.89062C18.2448 7.5625 18.0365 7.3099 17.75 7.13281C17.4688 6.95052 17.0911 6.85938 16.6172 6.85938H14.875V17H13.4375V5.625ZM18.8984 17L16.6328 11.8438L18.125 11.8359L20.4375 16.9062V17H18.8984Z" fill="#222222"></path></svg></span></span><span>Français</span></a></p></div><p>More</p><div><p><span><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 70 70"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M34.4 0a20.3 20.3 0 1 0 0 40.7 20.3 20.3 0 0 0 0-40.7Zm0 32a11.7 11.7 0 1 1 0-23.4 11.7 11.7 0 0 1 0 23.5Z" clip-rule="evenodd"></path><mask id="a" fill="#fff"><path d="M5.4 77.4c-2.9 0-5.2-2.3-4.8-5a34.4 34.4 0 0 1 68 0c.5 2.7-1.8 5-4.7 5-2.8 0-5-2.3-5.7-5a24.1 24.1 0 0 0-47.2 0c-.6 2.7-2.8 5-5.6 5Z"></path></mask><path stroke="#000" stroke-width="8.6" d="M5.4 77.4c-2.9 0-5.2-2.3-4.8-5a34.4 34.4 0 0 1 68 0c.5 2.7-1.8 5-4.7 5-2.8 0-5-2.3-5.7-5a24.1 24.1 0 0 0-47.2 0c-.6 2.7-2.8 5-5.6 5Z" mask="url(#a)"></path></svg></span></span><span>Log In / Sign Up</span></p></div><div><p><a href="mailto:tips@kotaku.com" target="_self" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;, &quot;Tips button click&quot;]]"><span><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="18" height="18" aria-label="Pencil icon" viewBox="0 0 18 18"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M14.7 1.39l1.91 1.92c.52.51.52 1.35 0 1.87l-9.77 9.8c-.1.1-.32.2-2.02 1.02l-.03.02a567.4 567.4 0 0 1-1.92.9c-.16.08-.31.09-.76.08a17.86 17.86 0 0 1-.57-.02.5.5 0 0 1-.47-.41 4.45 4.45 0 0 1-.07-.7c0-.28.02-.5.11-.7a546.56 546.56 0 0 1 .91-1.92l.02-.03c.81-1.71.92-1.93 1.02-2.03l9.77-9.8a1.32 1.32 0 0 1 1.87 0zm-3.74 3.28l-7.2 7.22c.06-.05-.15.37-.2.48l-.62 1.28-.01.03a569.36 569.36 0 0 0-.91 1.91A2.8 2.8 0 0 0 2 16h.12c.14.01.38 0 .31.03a542.86 542.86 0 0 0 1.92-.9l.03-.02 1.27-.62c.11-.05.52-.26.47-.2l7.2-7.23-2.37-2.38zm2.58-2.58l-1.87 1.87 2.37 2.38 1.87-1.87a.33.33 0 0 0 0-.46L13.99 2.1a.32.32 0 0 0-.45 0z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Send us a Tip!</span></a><a href="https://kotaku.com/newsletter" target="_blank" data-ga="[[&quot;Sub navigation&quot;, &quot;Subscribe button click&quot;]]"><span><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="18" height="18" aria-label="Mail icon" viewBox="0 0 18 18"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M14.5 3A2.5 2.5 0 0 1 17 5.5v7a2.5 2.5 0 0 1-2.5 2.5h-11A2.5 2.5 0 0 1 1 12.5v-7A2.5 2.5 0 0 1 3.5 3h11zM2 5.5v7c0 .83.67 1.5 1.5 1.5h11c.83 0 1.5-.67 1.5-1.5v-7l-.03-.3-6.34 5.67a.5.5 0 0 1-.38.13.5.5 0 0 1-.38-.13l-6.7-6-.02-.02c-.1.2-.15.41-.15.64zM14.5 4h-11c-.24 0-.45.05-.65.14l6.4 5.73 6.19-5.54c-.26-.2-.58-.33-.93-.33z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Subscribe</span></a></p></div><p>Extra</p><div><p><a href="https://kotaku.com/about">About</a></p></div><div><p><a href="https://g-omedia.com/" target="_blank">Advertising</a><a href="https://g-omedia.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank">Privacy</a><a href="https://gomedia.applytojob.com/apply" target="_blank">Jobs</a><a href="https://g-omedia.com/terms-of-service/" target="_blank">Terms of Use</a></p></div></div><div><p>Explore our other sites</p></div><div><ul><li><a href="https://kotaku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span></span></a></li><li><a href="https://theroot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span></span></a></li></ul></div><div><ul><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Social button click&quot;,&quot;facebook&quot;,{&quot;metric21&quot;:1}]]" href="https://facebook.com/kotaku" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Social button click&quot;,&quot;twitter&quot;,{&quot;metric21&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/kotaku" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Social button click&quot;,&quot;instagram&quot;,{&quot;metric21&quot;:1}]]" href="https://instagram.com/kotakudotcom" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Social button click&quot;,&quot;youtube&quot;,{&quot;metric21&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/KotakuNYC" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></li><li><a data-ga="[[&quot;Network navigation&quot;,&quot;Social button click&quot;,&quot;rss&quot;,{&quot;metric21&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/rss" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></li></ul></div><p><span>© 2025 G/O Media</span></p></div></div><p>We may earn a commission from links on this page</p></div><div><div poster="https://no.kinja-img.com/image/upload/c_fill,h_542,pg_1,q_60,w_965/dac832869bfdcf7c187465ecb655944a.png"><div data-video-id="197527" data-monetizable="true" data-position="featured" data-video-title="Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="169" data-playlist="197527" data-current="197527" id="197527"><div><p>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" playsinline="" poster="https://no.kinja-img.com/image/upload/c_fill,h_542,pg_1,q_60,w_965/197xrjaz7466rpng.png" data-poster="https://no.kinja-img.com/image/upload/c_fill,h_542,pg_1,q_60,w_965/dac832869bfdcf7c187465ecb655944a.png" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23057.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><div><div><p>Share <span><svg width="16px" height="16px" viewBox="0 0 16 16" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g id="Permalink" stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g id="Permalink-Video-" transform="translate(-478.000000, -897.000000)" fill="#CCCCCC"><g id="Group" transform="translate(477.000000, 896.000000)"></g></g></g></svg></span></p></div><div><div><p>Subtitles</p></div><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div></div></div></div><div><header></header><div><p>The <em>Life Is Strange</em> team’s latest supernatural teen drama probably didn’t need to be two parts, but its conclusion was worth the wait</p></div><div><div><p><time datetime="2025-04-17T14:39:00-04:00"><span>Published</span>an hour ago</time></p><div></div></div><div><p>We may earn a commission from links on this page</p><!-- --><p>.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div id="playlist-carousel-container" data-playlists="[{&quot;id&quot;:&quot;mostPopularPlaylist&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Most Popular&quot;,&quot;videos&quot;:[&quot;196646&quot;,&quot;196790&quot;,&quot;196742&quot;,&quot;196626&quot;,&quot;196539&quot;,&quot;196406&quot;,&quot;196411&quot;,&quot;196848&quot;,&quot;196470&quot;,&quot;196766&quot;,&quot;196452&quot;,&quot;196860&quot;,&quot;196805&quot;,&quot;196599&quot;,&quot;196394&quot;,&quot;196880&quot;]},{&quot;id&quot;:&quot;latestPlaylist&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Latest Videos&quot;,&quot;videos&quot;:[&quot;197527&quot;,&quot;197525&quot;,&quot;197298&quot;,&quot;197284&quot;,&quot;197260&quot;,&quot;197209&quot;,&quot;196923&quot;,&quot;196922&quot;,&quot;196917&quot;,&quot;196915&quot;,&quot;196918&quot;,&quot;196909&quot;,&quot;196907&quot;,&quot;196903&quot;,&quot;196888&quot;,&quot;196884&quot;]},{&quot;id&quot;:&quot;3323&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Commentary&quot;,&quot;videos&quot;:[&quot;196923&quot;,&quot;196918&quot;,&quot;196888&quot;,&quot;196880&quot;,&quot;196848&quot;,&quot;196843&quot;,&quot;196842&quot;,&quot;196840&quot;,&quot;196805&quot;,&quot;196773&quot;,&quot;196766&quot;,&quot;196626&quot;,&quot;196566&quot;,&quot;196406&quot;,&quot;196251&quot;,&quot;196231&quot;,&quot;196213&quot;,&quot;196187&quot;,&quot;196181&quot;,&quot;196115&quot;,&quot;196049&quot;,&quot;195928&quot;]},{&quot;id&quot;:&quot;76&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Anime&quot;,&quot;videos&quot;:[&quot;195369&quot;,&quot;195064&quot;,&quot;194972&quot;,&quot;194741&quot;,&quot;194664&quot;,&quot;194600&quot;,&quot;194547&quot;,&quot;194480&quot;,&quot;194449&quot;,&quot;194448&quot;,&quot;194445&quot;,&quot;194444&quot;,&quot;194389&quot;]}]"><div><p>Video Program Guide</p><div><p><a href="#playlist-mostPopularPlaylist">Most Popular</a><a href="#playlist-latestPlaylist">Latest Videos</a><a href="#playlist-3323">Commentary</a><a href="#playlist-76">Anime</a></p></div></div><div><p><h3 id="playlist-mostPopularPlaylist">Most Popular</h3></p><section aria-label="carousel-slider" role="region" tabindex="0"><p>Slide 1 of 16</p><div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 1 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 0&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-mystic-spearhand-strider-class-capcom-1851321764&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-mystic-spearhand-strider-class-capcom-1851321764"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:17</p></div><h4><i>Dragon’s Dogma 2</i>’s New Class Is A Twirling Death Machine</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 2 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 1&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-martin-ulrika-npc-murder-capcom-1851395318&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-martin-ulrika-npc-murder-capcom-1851395318"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:22</p></div><h4>Why Everybody Hates This <i>Dragon's Dogma 2</i> NPC</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 3 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 2&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-dragonsplague-pawn-contagion-capcom-1851369870&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-dragonsplague-pawn-contagion-capcom-1851369870"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>04:14</p></div><h4>What Is Dragonsplague? <i>Dragon’s Dogma 2</i>’s Devastating Contagion Explained</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 4 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 3&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/unicorn-overlord-vanillaware-vibe-rankings-switch-demo-1851313835&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/unicorn-overlord-vanillaware-vibe-rankings-switch-demo-1851313835"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>04:31</p></div><h4>Who Is The Best Hang In <i>Unicorn Overlord</i>? A Scientific Ranking</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 5 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 4&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lysfanga-quantic-dream-sand-door-studio-hades-pc-1851264639&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lysfanga-quantic-dream-sand-door-studio-hades-pc-1851264639"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>04:38</p></div><h4>This Innovative <i>Hades</i>-Like Feels Built For Speedrunners</h4></div></a></div></div></section></div><div><p><h3 id="playlist-latestPlaylist">Latest Videos</h3></p><section aria-label="carousel-slider" role="region" tabindex="0"><p>Slide 1 of 16</p><div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 1 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 0&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-playstation-1851776660&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-playstation-1851776660"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:49</p></div><h4><i>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage </i>Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 2 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 1&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/erenshor-mmorpg-fun-single-player-game-1851776472&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/erenshor-mmorpg-fun-single-player-game-1851776472"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:22</p></div><h4><i>Erenshor</i> Turns The MMO Experience Into A Surprisingly Fun Single-Player Game</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 3 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 2&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/live-forever-in-the-universe-of-new-world-aeternum-1851669193&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/live-forever-in-the-universe-of-new-world-aeternum-1851669193"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>01:48</p></div><h4>Live Forever in the Universe of <em>New World: Aeternum</em></h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 4 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 3&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/kevin-smith-sneaking-into-movies-mallrats-1851664302&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/kevin-smith-sneaking-into-movies-mallrats-1851664302"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>10:43</p></div><h4>Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, <i>Mallrats</i>, And More</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 5 of 16" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 4&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/agatha-all-along-sasheer-zamata-star-trek-snl-1851652795&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/agatha-all-along-sasheer-zamata-star-trek-snl-1851652795"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>05:48</p></div><h4>Agatha All Along Star Sasheer Zamata On Witchcraft And Star Trek</h4></div></a></div></div></section></div><div><p><h3 id="playlist-3323">Commentary</h3></p><section aria-label="carousel-slider" role="region" tabindex="0"><p>Slide 1 of 22</p><div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 1 of 22" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 0&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/spyro-the-dragon-4-in-development-toys-for-bob-1851459412&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/spyro-the-dragon-4-in-development-toys-for-bob-1851459412"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>05:55</p></div><h4>Kotaku’s Hopes For <i>Spyro The Dragon</i>’s (Reported) Comeback</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 2 of 22" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 1&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sucker-for-love-date-to-die-for-pc-dating-sim-akabaka-1851449456&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sucker-for-love-date-to-die-for-pc-dating-sim-akabaka-1851449456"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>01:58</p></div><h4>Why You'll Fall In Love With This Indie Horror Romance Mashup</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 3 of 22" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 2&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/harold-halibut-slow-bros-xbox-game-pass-playstation-pc-1851432593&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/harold-halibut-slow-bros-xbox-game-pass-playstation-pc-1851432593"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>01:54</p></div><h4>Why This Claymation Indie Game Is Like An Aquarium</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 4 of 22" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 3&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-10-wrecking-ball-rework-mythic-shop-1851423207&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-season-10-wrecking-ball-rework-mythic-shop-1851423207"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>03:38</p></div><h4>Ranking <i>Overwatch 2</i> Season 10's Biggest Changes</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 5 of 22" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 4&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/windblown-gameplay-trailer-motion-twin-dead-cells-hades-1851416683&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/windblown-gameplay-trailer-motion-twin-dead-cells-hades-1851416683"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>01:08</p></div><h4>This Roguelite Is Giving <i>Hades</i> Meets <i>Dead Cells</i></h4></div></a></div></div></section></div><div><p><h3 id="playlist-76">Anime</h3></p><section aria-label="carousel-slider" role="region" tabindex="0"><p>Slide 1 of 13</p><div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 1 of 13" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 0&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/one-piece-netflix-live-action-trailer-easter-eggs-1850687453&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/one-piece-netflix-live-action-trailer-easter-eggs-1850687453"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>01:58</p></div><h4>Netflix's <i>One Piece</i> Live-Action Trailer Has A Treasure Trove Of Anime Easter Eggs</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 2 of 13" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 1&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/anime-dads-fathers-day-whitebeard-piccolo-loid-forger-1850557083&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/anime-dads-fathers-day-whitebeard-piccolo-loid-forger-1850557083"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:49</p></div><h4>The Four Best Anime Dads</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 3 of 13" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 2&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/birdie-wing-golf-girls-story-anime-crunchyroll-1850529104&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/birdie-wing-golf-girls-story-anime-crunchyroll-1850529104"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:15</p></div><h4>This Lesbian Mafia Anime Might Actually Make You Want To Play Golf</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 4 of 13" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 3&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/crunchyroll-my-love-story-with-yamada-kun-at-lv999-1850450924&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/crunchyroll-my-love-story-with-yamada-kun-at-lv999-1850450924"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:19</p></div><h4>An Anime That Might Make You Put Your Minecraft Bed Next To Someone</h4></div></a></div><div aria-hidden="false" tabindex="-1" aria-label="slide 5 of 13" role="group" inert="true"><a data-ga="[[&quot;Video Player Interaction&quot;,&quot;Carousel click - position 4&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/kotatsu-anime-corner-heavenly-delusion-hulu-disney-1850428741&quot;]]" href="https://kotaku.com/kotatsu-anime-corner-heavenly-delusion-hulu-disney-1850428741"><div><div><div><div><p>Now playing</p></div></div><p>02:42</p></div><h4>Hulu's New Anime Is <i>The Last of Us</i> Meets <i>The Promised Neverland</i></h4></div></a></div></div></section></div></div></div></div><div><p><small>Advertisement</small></p></div><div><p><small>Advertisement</small></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snowbreak: Containment Zone Update Adds New Events and Gameplay Enhancements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/snowbreak-containment-zone-update-adds-new-events-and-gameplay-enhancements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/snowbreak-containment-zone-update-adds-new-events-and-gameplay-enhancements.1167201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/snowbreak-containment-zone-update-adds-new-events-and-gameplay-enhancements<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The free-to-play 3D waifu sci-fi RPG shooter Snowbreak: Containment Zone just dropped its latest update, and it adds lots of new content. There are new characters, skins, gameplay modes, and even more on the horizon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re not familiar with Snowbreak, it’s a third-person RPG shooter on PC and mobile that takes place in a world where giant beings known as Titans suddenly appear in heavily populated areas. They cause untold destruction and leave a toxic substance known as Titagen in their wake. Leaders joined together to form the Heimdall Force, a paramilitary unit whose mission is to fight back against these Titans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You play as the Adjutant of the Heimdall Force, and your job is to recruit and lead a squad of female super soldiers. Known as Manifestations, these soldiers awakened to their powers after the first arrival of the Titans, and the strongest among them are even able to use Titagen in combat without the ill effects normally associated with it.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/fight-1744401193210.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The story is told in chapters, with each chapter further broken down into stages. In each combat stage, you form a squad of three characters, each of whom have their own unique skills. You only control one character on the battlefield at a time, and using their skills drains energy, which slowly refills over time. So you need to strategically swap between each of your characters to make the best use of their abilities without fully draining their energy. As you progress, you can build relationships with members of your squad by giving them gifts or deploying them in combat. As their affinity for you grows, you’ll get to know them better.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest update adds a new story scenario called Abyssal Dawn, which will have you investigating an incident with the two characters who are also new additions in the update: Nerida and Nita - Pulse.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/nerida-1744401232522.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Nerida is self-demanding, often solitary, and can be stern with others but not to you. She likes sweet snacks, plushies, and ancient marine life models, and she’s obsessed with deep-sea documentaries and jellyfish care. She’s equipped with a Chaos-type assault rifle, and her role is the primary damage dealer of your squad. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">She excels with both single-target and area-of-effect attacks and can build up the Internal Injury effect on enemies with both her Standard Skill and Ultimate, which summons a jellyfish that provides AoE damage buffs and stays on the field even if you switch to another character. You can then switch back to her to use her Standard Skill, which deals big burst damage by consuming the Internal Injury effect you’ve built up.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/nita-pulse-1744401268347.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Nita - Pulse is casual yet perceptive, driven by money but protective of the vulnerable. While she’s on the battlefield, she keeps her eyes peeled for items of value and likes to pocket them, like Titagen objects. She wields a Thermal-type shotgun and brings a new QTE combat mechanic with her. Successfully chain QTE inputs together during her Standard Skill to deal increased damage, and if you fully complete the chain, she unleashes a final powerful strike.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nita - Pulse is free to acquire for all players, available now by completing the Pulse Puzzles event. She’ll also be available for free as a login reward during the Nita’s Invitation event that starts May 1. If you participate in that event, you’ll also be able to earn Nita’s fully modified exclusive weapon, maxed Auctus Drive (her version of a Manifestation), and signature fixed-talent Logistics squad. So in one event, you can max out her full build at no cost.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/nitas-invitation-event-1744401305118.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re wondering what the Pulse Puzzles event is, that’s another new addition with the latest update. As the name implies, it’ll have you solve puzzles across various parts of the game. It’s a chance to relax and better understand Nita, and it will be permanently available, so you can do it at your own pace. To get to know Nita even more, there’s also a new interactable scene with her called Grove of Secrets that’s available from now until May 29.<br>
</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/nita-sylvan-spirit-1744401345665.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Nita - Pulse and Nerida were both introduced alongside additional skins. Nita’s transforms her into a white-haired forest nymph, and Nerida’s features interchangeable parts, including footwear and stockings, similar to the customization options available for Vidya. But they’re not the only ones getting new looks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The update added new outfits for Katya, Fenny, and Bubu. Katya was introduced a year ago and is known for her unique appearance and characteristics. Fenny has been in the game since launch and become a fan favorite, and Bubu is a character from last year’s traditional-themed event.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/katya-1744401375399.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also a new hide-and-seek gameplay mode called Let’s Go, Heimdall! for 15 players at a time, where three seekers try to find 12 hiders. On the horizon is the much-anticipated Emotional Purge mode, which adds cover-based shooting gameplay. It’ll first be available on April 28 and will be further refined in future updates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And in addition to her new costume, Bubu is also getting a new dorm room at your home base. That also adds new interactable furniture in the form of her Tranquil Desk Set.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/11/tranquil-desk-set-1744401487995.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Those are the highlights of this update, but there’s even more that’s been added. You’ll just have to play it to see it all. Snowbreak: Containment Zone is available to download for free right now on Steam, iOS, and Android, and it’s cross-platform, so your progress is shared across all platforms. To learn more about the game, characters, and world, check out <a href="https://snowbreak.go.link/j7m9u" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">the official website</a> or join the community on <a href="https://x.com/SnowbreakEN" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Twitter</u></a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/@SnowbreakEN" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Facebook</u></a>, or <a href="https://discord.com/invite/snowbreak" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Discord</u></a>.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready or Not coming to PS5, Xbox Series this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/ready-or-not-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ready-or-not-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-this-summer.1167198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/ready-or-not-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Tactical first-person shooter makes the jump to console.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > VOID Interactive [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/void-interactive">VOID Interactive</a> will release tactical <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Ready or Not [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ready-or-not">Ready or Not</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,070 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> this summer, the developer announced. <span id="more-959111"></span></p><p><em>Ready or Not</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1144200/Ready_or_Not/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on December 17, 2021, followed by a full release on December 13, 2023. The PC version will also be made available via <a title="Companies > Epic Games [349 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store and Microsoft Store alongside the console release.</p><p>The console versions will be available both physically and digitally in the following editions:</p><ul><li><strong>Standard Edition</strong> ($49.99 / £44.99 / €49.99)<ul><li>Base game</li></ul></li><li><strong>Day One Edition</strong> ($49.99 / £44.99 / €49.99)<!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Base game</li><li>Pre-order bonuses:<ul><li>M32A1 Grenade Launcher</li><li>MK-V Pistol</li><li>590M Shotgun</li><li>These items will be updated for free to PC owners of the game</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> ($69.99 / €69.99 / £59.99)<ul><li>Base game</li><li>Downloadable content:<ul><li>“Home Invasion” – available separately for $9.99 / £7.99 / €9.99</li><li>“Dark Waters” – available separately for $9.99 / £7.99 / €9.99</li><li>Unannounced Downloadable Content #3</li></ul></li><li>Pre-order bonuses<ul><li>M32A1 Grenade Launcher</li><li>MK-V Pistol</li><li>590M Shotgun</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>Here is an overview of the game, via VOID Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Console players enter the world of Los Sueños. The surge of <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e across the greater Los Sueños metropolitan area has severely depleted LSPD resources, threatening to overwhelm the department’s ability to maintain order. In response to the growing threats facing residents, LSPD is mobilizing its Special Weapons and Tactics (SWAT) teams to respond to high-threat scenarios, including active bomb threats, barricaded suspects and high-risk hostage situations to minimize police casualties.</p><p>Timed to the console launch, VOID Interactive is releasing ‘Storiesfrom Los Sueños’ free DLC in the form of two new single-player or online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> missions.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>20 single-player or online cooperative missions with up to five players.</li><li>Two new missions as part of the Stories from Los Suenos free downloadable content update.<ul><li>PC players will have access to the new missions in a free update day-and-date with console launch.</li></ul></li><li>Two downloadable contents that introduce six additional levels, and in Dark Waters DLC the UH-60 support Helicopter.</li><li>Dozens of options to customize a player’s entire SWAT team including armor, weapons, apparel, and more.</li><li>Immersive tactical gameplay, full flexibility of approach, and authentic equipment that SWAT teams utilize in the field.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ready or Not – Console Reveal Trailer (PS5/Xbox Series X)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jW3zr1Jn5bM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9th Dawn Remake coming to PS5, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch on April 24, iOS and Android on May 1]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/9th-dawn-remake-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-april-24-ios-and-android-on-may-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/9th-dawn-remake-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-april-24-ios-and-android-on-may-1.1167195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/9th-dawn-remake-coming-to-ps5-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-april-24-ios-and-android-on-may-1<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Open-world RPG currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Valorware [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/valorware">Valorware</a> will release <a title="Genres > Open-World [611 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [17,167 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> remake <em><a title="Games > 9th Dawn Remake [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/9th-dawn-remake">9th Dawn Remake</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,290 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,922 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,975 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on April 24, followed by iOS and Android on May 1, the developer announced. <span id="more-958982"></span></p><p><em>9th Dawn Remake</em> for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1550180/9th_Dawn_Remake/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 25, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Valorware:</p><blockquote><p><strong>More Than a New Coat of Paint</strong></p><p>Like the original title, <em>9th Dawn Remake</em> is a truly massive open world RPG—where dedicated (and curious!) players can spend over 200 hours completing the main and side quests, collecting rare loot, and raising monster pets. Bursting at the seams with dungeon-crawling hijinks, <em>9th Dawn Re</em>make lovingly riffs on the original <em>9th Dawn</em> game—evamping the combat and streamlining quests to deliver a novel, exhilarating <em>9th Dawn</em> experience. <em>9th Dawn Remake</em> has also been localized into French, Spanish, German, Korean, Japanese, Simplified Chinese, and Brazilian Portuguese!</p><p><strong>New Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>New 2.5D graphics.</li><li>Completely remade dungeons with bigger maps.</li><li>Sprites cleaned and reworked with improved animation.</li><li>Rewritten story and quests.</li><li>Online and two-player local <a title="Genres > Co-Op [253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play.</li><li>Combat replaced with more fluid, <a title="Genres > Action [2,672 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>-based gameplay.</li><li>First-person mode added.</li><li>Two big mini-games included: Fishing Survivors, a bullet-heaven fishing game—and Deck Rock, a deck-building card game.</li></ul><p>In the comedic fishing mini-game Fishing Survivors, the amount of fish players defeat directly affects the fishing yield – making for a fun time with the fishies. Fishing Survivors also features a number of different missions that are locked behind overworld map exploration – along with a couple of extra worm warriors to unlock.</p><p>Players can also enjoy Deck Rock—a deck-building card mini-game that was inspired by <em><a title="Games > Slay the Spire [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slay-the-spire">Slay the Spire</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Roguebook [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/roguebook">Roguebook</a></em>. Taking control of medieval paper champions, players are tasked with beating game dungeons using the maps found in the main campaign. This turn-based <a title="Genres > Strategy [237 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> provides countless hours of fun while players unlock all cards, level up paper champions, and complete dungeons.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>sive Open World</strong> – Explore more than 45 new hand-crafted dungeon—each brimming with deadly creatures and loot.</li><li><strong>Design Your Build</strong> – Unlock spells and abilities, assign attribute points, and upgrade your equipment.</li><li><strong>Raise Monster Pets</strong> – Hatch friendly creatures from eggs and raise them into powerful allies.</li><li><strong>Side <a title="Platforms > Quest [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s</strong> – Aid the villages of Montelorne by partaking in a range of side quests.</li><li><strong>Loot and Prizes</strong> – Collect a vast amount of loot and fill your collecting journals for rewards.</li><li><strong>Craft the Best</strong> – Forge weapons, brew potions, and upgrade your weapons to become a champion!</li><li><strong>Fishing Survivors Mini-Game</strong> – Take control of powerful worm warriors and survive deadly waves of enemy fish.</li><li><strong>Deck Rock Mini-Game</strong> – Collect maps, level up your card champions, and create an epic deck.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles and <a title="Platforms > Mobile [2,801 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">Mobile</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="9th Dawn Remake - Console and Mobile Release Dates??" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZaZIGK_T360?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Consoles Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="9th Dawn Remake - Console Launch Trailer - Coming 24th April 2025!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JX9fUVyqzns?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Mobile Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="9th Dawn Remake - Mobile Trailer - Coming May 1st!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1CymGiKLLB8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords Of The Fallen 2.0 Update Gets A Surprise Friend Pass Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature/1100-6530947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature.1167192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature/1100-6530947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530947">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>CI Games has revealed Lords of the Fallen version 2.0 and it comes with plenty of surprising features, including shared progress co-op saving and a Friend Pass. However, the Steam release has been delayed.</p><p>Co-op was one of Lords of the Fallen's standout features, but now the update lets both players save all main story progress. There are some caveats, though. Both players need to be on the same "New Game" and must have defeated a similar number of bosses. They will retain all loot and 100% vigor.</p><p>There's also a new Friend Pass that lets players invite another person even if they don't own the game. The invited friend gets to keep all loot and character classes.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2jQ3S2JzA9s" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2jQ3S2JzA9s" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The new update adds a dedicated jump button and a refined lock-on function, as well as an overhauled character creator. The animations should look smoother and as a result, weapons and evasions should feel more responsive. The user interface has also been cleaned up, and the Umbral Lamp now can guide players to the next destination.</p><p>In a now-deleted <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1501750/view/527592442371768492" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam blog post</a>, CI Games apparently stated that the <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-out-now-with-enhanced-combatmovement-and-free-friends-pass" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam release is seeing a small delay due to a technical issue</a>, but the 2.0 update should be live on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and the Epic Games Store.</p><p>In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/lords-of-the-fallen-review-dark-slog/1900-6418133/" data-ref-id="1900-6418133">Lords of the Fallen review</a>, we said, "While Lords of the Fallen has all the right Souls-like elements, its disjointed pacing and painful checkpoint system make much of the game a slow and frustrating march."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A retro hardware maker willing to pay Trump’s tariffs is suspending US shipments anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/651007/retrotink-us-shipments-suspended-trump-tariffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-retro-hardware-maker-willing-to-pay-trump%E2%80%99s-tariffs-is-suspending-us-shipments-anyway.1167153/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/651007/retrotink-us-shipments-suspended-trump-tariffs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>RetroTINK, a company that sells hardware for playing retro consoles on modern screens, says it will be temporarily suspending US shipments — even though the company wants to pre-pay President Donald Trump’s tariffs, <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/04/us-retrotink-shipments-are-being-temporarily-suspended">as reported by <em>Time Extension</em></a>.</p><p>The company is suspending shipments “due to lack of guidance on how tariffs will be collected starting May 2nd,” RetroTINK’s Mike Chi <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/retrotink.com/post/3lmsr6nja6k2x">says on Bluesky</a>. “Without proper procedures in place, the risk of delays and lost packages is simply too high.” The company will resume shipments “as soon as we understand how to pre-pay tariffs on behalf of the customer,” he says.</p><p>In a post <a href="https://www.retrotink.com/blog/tariff-update-last-call-for-us-orders">on its website</a>, the company says that “we have not received guidance from the government on how US shipments will be processed.” April 23rd will be the last day to make non-expedited orders and April 28th will be the last day to make expedited orders for US-bound shipments.</p><p>Chi also <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/retrotink.com/post/3lmsr6njf2t2x">says that</a> the company expects that the situation “will be resolved eventually – but it is impossible to say when or how.”</p><p>President Donald Trump announced wide-ranging tariffs <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642240/trump-tariffs-imports-apple-manufacturing">on April 2nd</a>, and while he lowered them to 10 percent for many countries shortly after they went into effect <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/646029/trump-announces-a-90-day-pause-on-tariffs-outside-of-china">a week later</a>, the US currently has <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/646604/trump-tariffs-reciprocal-pause-canada-mexico-china-de-minimis">a 145 percent tariff</a> in place on goods imported from China.</p><p>RetroTINK isn’t the only small business in games dealing with issues created by the tariffs. Fangamer, for example, is <a href="https://www.fangamer.com/collections/pizza-tower/products/pizza-tower-game-collectors-edition-nintendo-switch">delaying preorders</a> of the <em>Pizza Tower Collector’s Edition</em> because of “new tariffs targeting manufacturing in China that have made it impossible for us to estimate the CE’s final price.”</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playdate’s second season of games starts in May]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/648193/playdate-season-2-games-price-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playdate%E2%80%99s-second-season-of-games-starts-in-may.1167150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/648193/playdate-season-2-games-price-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>One of the new titles comes from the studio behind FTL and Into the Breach.</p></div></div><div><div><p>One of the new titles comes from the studio behind FTL and Into the Breach.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-04-17T17:20:00+00:00">Apr 17, 2025, 5:20 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo: Vjeran Pavic / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Playdate is about to get a big batch of new games. Today, Panic confirmed the first details of the handheld’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24284707/playdate-season-2-release-date">upcoming season 2</a>, which will include 12 new games and run from May 29th to July 3rd, with two titles releasing each week. The full season will cost $39.</p><p>When the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23025390/playdate-handheld-portable-gaming-console-review">Playdate first launched back in 2022</a>, it similarly came with a number of games from notable developers that released over time. The idea was that every Playdate owner would receive these mystery games at the same time as they launched weekly throughout the season, but ensuing shipping delays put a wrench in that plan. Panic says that with this second season it “hopes to deliver on that original idea,” while adding that the season will also include “a must see surprise for all those who want something… a little different.”</p><p>In addition to the date and price of season 2, Panic also revealed four of the games that will be featured. They include:</p><div><ul><li><span><em><a href="https://play.date/games/fulcrum-defender/">Fulcrum Defender</a></em>, a “crank-powered, arcade action game” from Subset Games, the studio behind strategy classics <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/26/17053172/into-the-breach-review-pc-steam-ftl">Into the Breach</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/3/5577792/best-new-apps-ftl-for-ipad">FTL: Faster Than Light</a></em>.</span></li></ul></div><div><ul><li><span><em>Taria &amp; Como,</em> a “physics-based puzzle platformer where movement is built around swinging instead of jumping,” from Popseed Studio Inc and JuVee Productions.</span></li><li><span>A classic-style point-and-click adventure from Pixel Ghost called <em>Shadowgate PD</em>.</span></li><li><span>And <em>Dig! Dig! Dino!</em> from Dom 2D and Fáyer, which is about, well, digging dino bones.</span></li></ul></div><p>Panic also announced a new yellow case for the handheld, which is available to order today for $34.</p></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2: The Best Perk Choices For Support Heroes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-support-perk-mercy-kiriko-juno-zenyatta-lucio-1851776618</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-the-best-perk-choices-for-support-heroes.1167141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-support-perk-mercy-kiriko-juno-zenyatta-lucio-1851776618<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-recommend-id="image://d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-recommend-id="image://d71c6b2b7bb8f01c866b31093c36e9e7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ana swings her sleep dart gun behind her during a highlight intro." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As exciting as the return of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971">Loot Boxes</a></span> is, the biggest change for <em>Overwatch 2</em> is season 15’s perk system. Whether they’re small tweaks for healing or new mobility options, healers need to choose the right upgrades. To make that a bit easier, we’ve narrowed down the best perk choices for each Support hero so you can keep your team alive.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,196049" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><ol data-type="List" data-style="Number"><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#ana&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#ana">Ana</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#baptiste&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#baptiste">Baptiste</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#brigitte&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#brigitte">Brigitte</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#illari&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#illari">Illari</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#juno&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#juno">Juno</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#kiriko&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#kiriko">Kirko</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#lifeweaver&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#lifeweaver">Lifeweaver</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#lucio&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#lucio">Lucio</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#mercy&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#mercy">Mercy</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#moira&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#moira">Moira</a></span></li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#zenyatta&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#zenyatta">Zenyatta</a></span></li></ol><hr><h2 id="h64896"><a id="ana"></a>Ana</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Biotic Bounce</strong> buffs Ana’s Biotic Grenade so that it will still explode on contact, but then also bounce and cause a second explosion. It’s perfect for healing/dealing more damage or potentially making up for a terrible throw.</li><li><strong>Shrike</strong> provides an amazing buff to Nano Boost - Ana receives the effects as well when she uses it. Two nano-boosted players can change the tide of a battle far better than one.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64897"><a id="baptiste"></a>Baptiste</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>I recommend choosing the <strong>Field Medicine</strong> perk simply because it comes into play more often than the other choice. It upgrades Baptiste’s Immortality Field to heal nearby allies with 80 health and himself with 40 health when the object is destroyed.</li><li>The <strong>Rocket Boots</strong> perk allows for a horizontal dash during an Exo Boots jump. This is the better option because the other perk hampers his healing capabilities. Also, more mobility is always cool.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64898"><a id="brigitte"></a>Brigitte</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Morale Boost</strong> extends the length of a Whip Shot-triggered Inspire by three seconds. It’s a bit situational, but it almost doubles the amount of time Inspire usually lasts.</li><li><strong>Quick Fix</strong> upgrades Brigitte’s Repair Packs to be more effective for critical health allies, giving them another 35 instant health. Receiving 60 instant health is a lot better than 25.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64899"><a id="illari"></a>Illari</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Rapid Construction</strong> helps Illari heal allies more often by accelerating Healing Pylon build time by 300% and reducing its cooldown by 1.5 seconds. </li><li><strong>Solar Power</strong> brings a bit of Moira into Illari’s toolkit, making it so that a fully charged Solar Rifle hit will replenish 12.5% solar energy, up to an overfill amount of 50%.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64900"><a id="juno"></a>Juno</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Every Support hero’s goal is to provide more healing, which is why <strong>Familiar Vitals</strong> is the best minor perk for Juno. Pulsar Torpedoes lock onto allies 35% faster with it.</li><li><strong>Master Blaster</strong> upgrades her Mediblaster primary fire to crit enemies. With how great her healing already is, increasing her damage output is the next priority.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64901"><a id="kiriko"></a>Kiriko</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Urgent Care</strong> is a great perk to ensure you quickly heal those who need it. Choosing this will increase Healing Ofuda speed by 50% when seeking an ally in critical health. </li><li>Protection Suzu is already helpful for keeping your teammates alive, but the <strong>Foxtrot</strong> perk will make their escape more likely by providing a 40% movement speed bonus for two seconds.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64902"><a id="lifeweaver"></a>Lifeweaver</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Life Cycle</strong> is the more useful perk due to how much healing it provides. Not only does it constantly regenerate 10 health per second for Lifeweaver, but it also drops a 250 health healing seed when he dies.</li><li>While extra damage is nice, <strong>Lifeweaving</strong> will usually be the preferred major perk choice. It adds an extra 20 healing to a Healing Blossom projectile if used within three seconds after a Rejuvenating Dash.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64903"><a id="lucio"></a>Lucio</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Groovin’</strong> regenerates four ammo per second while wall riding, which is a no-brainer pick because you’ll be doing that a lot anyway.</li><li>Buffing your Crossfade music choice with Amp It Up is a common ability usage. The <strong>Noise Violation</strong> perk adds another buff by increasing Crossfade’s range by 150% so that you can reach more teammates.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64904"><a id="mercy"></a>Mercy</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Angelic Recovery</strong> provides you with 15 health every second your Caduceus Staff is attached to a full health ally. This will typically be the better choice since you’ll spend more time pocketing someone or healing nearby allies than needing to fly across a map.</li><li><strong>Chain Boost</strong> upgrades your damage amplification beam to tether toward a second ally. This is perfect whether you’re trying to take an objective or hold one down.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64905"><a id="moira"></a>Moira</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>The <strong>Vanish</strong> perk increases Fade’s duration by 0.5 seconds. That doesn’t sound like much, but the extra time gives plenty more leeway for repositioning.</li><li>Biotic Orb can be a finicky ability, especially since it recovers health over time. The <strong>Ethical Nourishment</strong> major perk tweaks the ability so that the first 50 healing is instant for any ally that comes into contact with it.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="h64906"><a id="zenyatta"></a>Zenyatta</h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Zenyatta has always lacked mobility, which is why <strong>Ascendance</strong> is an amazing perk. It allows him to hover for three seconds if you hold after a double jump.</li><li><strong>Duality</strong> brings both sides of Zenyatta’s gameplay together, healing Orb of Harmony targets with 20% of his damage dealt to Orb of Discord targets.</li></ul><hr><p><br>While the above perks will be the most consistently helpful, every perk is pretty practical depending on your match. I suggest keeping an open mind with these buffs and messing around with them in quick play. If you also dabble in other character classes, we’ve got you covered with the best <em>Overwatch 2</em> perks for both the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tanks-best-perks-dva-doomfist-hazard-orisa-1851771469&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tanks-best-perks-dva-doomfist-hazard-orisa-1851771469">tank heroes</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-dps-widowmaker-tracer-hanzo-cassidy-1851776302&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-dps-widowmaker-tracer-hanzo-cassidy-1851776302">damage heroes</a></span>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda Fans Are Worried Tears of the Kingdom's Switch 2 Version Won't Support Cloud Saves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves.1167135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The cloud situation is a bit foggy.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 is set to get special enhanced versions of several Switch 1 games, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>. A newly spotted disclaimer has fans worrying some games, or at least one game, won't support Nintendo's cloud save functionality as they'd hope.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the last day or so, users have been noticing that Nintendo's pages for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787249.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tears of the Kingdom</a>'s Switch 2 edition carries the following disclaimer: "Please note: this software does not support the Nintendo Switch Online paid membership’s Save Data Cloud backup feature."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Per <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-switch-2-editions-of-the-legend-of-zelda-botw-totk-do-not-support-cloud-saves-saves-can-still-be-transferred-however.1166340/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ResetEra</a>, the page for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Breath-of-the-Wild-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787250.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Switch 2 Edition</a> also apparently carried this disclaimer at one point, as did <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/Super-Mario-Party-Jamboree-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-Jamboree-TV-2785806.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</a>. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Though it's since disappeared from those pages, the Tears of the Kingdom still has the disclaimer as of this writing. The Japanese page though, per <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-edition-zelda-games-wont-support-cloud-saves-to-backup-your-data" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> via machine translation, does not carry the same disclaimer; only the US and EU pages seem to be showing it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has reached out to Nintendo for clarification on the matter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If this holds true, this could create some confusing scenarios for players. Nintendo's cloud save option for NSO members is handy, for one. It makes carrying games across systems, or juggling storage space for games without losing your saved progress, a little less stres-inducing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Actually importing a save file from the original Switch to the Switch 2 Edition of Tears of the Kingdom does seem to still work. The Nintendo page noted an additional save slot for the Switch 2 Edition, where one can start a brand-new journey or "continue a previous one with your existing save data." Nintendo does note that save data created in the second save data slot cannot be trasnferred to the Nintendo Switch 1 version of Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a confusing situation that can possibly lead to some stress, as players would likely not want to lose a save file they've dumped many, many hours into when upgrading versions. Hopefully, this gets cleared up soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 Edition does have a few reasons for prospective Switch 2 owners to upgrade, including the Zelda Notes app, which comes packed with helpful guiding content, lore, and even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-zelda-ports-will-let-players-repair-equipment-with-the-zelda-notes-app-if-theyre-lucky">some potential equipment repair options</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Is Crossing Over With Dark Fantasy Manga Series Berserk For Its First IP Collab]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab.1167126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530944">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4's</a> first external IP crossover event is coming, and it's with none other than the dark fantasy masterpiece, Berserk.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard hasn't gone into too much detail on what all the crossover will entail, so far only tweeting out a short animated teaser showing a Brand of Sacrifice-marked Barbarian outfitted with Berserk's iconic Berserker armor and Dragonslayer sword. Considering the teaser doesn't say Diablo 4 specifically (and lists iOS and Android), it looks like the event will come to both Diablo 4 and the free-to-play <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-immortal/" data-ref-id="5000-489022">Diablo Immortal</a>. No other details, including dates for the event or what all it will entail, have been officially announced.</p><p dir="ltr">For those not in the know, Berserk, by the late author Kentaro Miura, is considered a seminal work in the manga space. Not for the faint of heart, it tells the tale of the mercenary known as Guts and his quest to survive a punishing dark fantasy world. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-creator-kentaro-miura-has-passed-away/1100-6491749/" data-ref-id="1100-6491749">Miura passed away in 2021</a>, leaving the longrunning manga unfinished, though <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-manga-to-continue-in-2022/1100-6504227/" data-ref-id="1100-6504227">new chapters created by Miura's friend Kouji Mori</a>, alongside Miura's various assistants and apprentices, have slowly been released since Miura's death.</p><p dir="ltr">The manga's influence, from its dark fantasy themes to its iconic suits of armor and weapons, can be seen everywhere. Anytime a character uses a comically oversized sword, Berserk is likely the inspiration, and games like From Software's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dark-souls/" data-ref-id="5000-83346">Dark Souls</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/elden-ring/" data-ref-id="5000-497664">Elden Ring</a> haven't shied away from wearing their Berserk influences for all to see.</p><p dir="ltr">While Berserk is the first external IP to be featured in Diablo (with another IP crossover slated for later this year, according to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-2025-roadmap-highlights-new-crossovers-endgame-updates/1100-6530666/" data-ref-id="1100-6530666">Diablo 4's 2025 roadmap</a>), both Diablo 4 and Diablo Immortal did crossover with another Blizzard IP, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>, last year. That crossover was to celebrate World of Warcraft's 20th anniversary, and saw a number of pricey WoW-themed armor sets and cosmetics inspired by some of the game's iconic characters like Sylvanas Windrunner and The Lich King added to Diablo 4's premium shop. Various cosmetics and WoW-themed items also appeared in Blizzard's Diablo mobile game.</p><p dir="ltr">The Berserk crossover will be coming as part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-8-is-all-about-bosses-and-its-bringing-back-a-fan-favorite/1100-6530012/" data-ref-id="1100-6530012">Diablo 4 Season 8, which will overhaul the game's endgame bosses</a> and see the return of a fan-favorite from Diablo 3, Belial. Diablo 4 Season 8 begins April 29.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New DLC Gets Price Cut Before Release Due To "Events Happening In The World"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world.1167123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530941">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockfish Games has announced that it's dropping the price of its upcoming DLC expansion for Everspace 2 ahead of its May 12 release due to "events happening in the world."</p><p>The expansion, Wrath of the Ancients, was originally going to cost $30. However, Rockfish Games reduced the price to $25. The studio also recently reduced the price of Everspace 2's first expansion, Titans, from $15 to $12.</p><p>Rockfish Games clarified that even though the price for Wrath of the Ancients has been lowered, no content has been cut from it. It contains new stories, side quests, enemies, and a new playable Wraith ship.</p><p>"As an independent studio, we are lucky to be in a position to be able to do this based on the support of an amazing community," Rockfish Games said in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1128920/view/524214742651240614?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam blog post</a>. "If you were genuinely looking forward to giving us that little bit extra, thank you! We will have a new artbook and soundtrack gathering together content from our DLCs available when Wrath of the Ancients launches that you can put that money towards instead."</p><p>The studio didn't specify "events happening in the world," but acknowledged the rising costs of everything and feelings of uncertainty. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-prices-have-increased-in-some-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530829/" data-ref-id="1100-6530829">PS5 console</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-plus-prices-have-increased-in-certain-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530919/" data-ref-id="1100-6530919">PS Plus prices</a> have increased, and certain games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-defends-mario-kart-worlds-80-price-tag/1100-6530643/" data-ref-id="1100-6530643">Mario Kart World are now $80</a>. It's also possible that Rockfish Games is referring to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/esa-says-tariffs-will-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-entire-gaming-industry-not-just-nintendo/1100-6530636/" data-ref-id="1100-6530636">Trump tariffs that are impacting the video game industry</a>.</p><p>Everspace 2 is an open-world space shooter that follows Adam, a clone pilot who aims to escape the Demilitarized Zone of Cluster 34. It features a robust single-player campaign, plenty of side missions, loot, and additional challenges to partake it in. Everspace 2 is available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>