<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 19:34:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Annapurna’s 2025 lineup of indie games is full of tea and T-poses]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/618431/annapurna-interactive-2025-games-showcase</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/annapurna%E2%80%99s-2025-lineup-of-indie-games-is-full-of-tea-and-t-poses.1117632/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/618431/annapurna-interactive-2025-games-showcase<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Annapurna Interactive is hosting its first showcase of the year, and it’s an important one. Last year, Annapurna Interactive’s entire staff <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2024/9/12/24243317/annapurna-interactive-staff-reportedly-resigns">resigned en masse</a> after negotiations to spin off the respected indie game publisher into its own independent entity broke down. Since then, those employees have formed their own company and even have a new crop of games to manage since it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/7/24338274/annapurna-interactive-new-company-take-two-private-division">took over publishing duties for Take-Two’s former indie label Private Division</a>. But where does that leave Annapurna?</p><p>After the resignations, the company issued a statement assuring players that its games would still be published as normal. With this showcase (which you can watch in full <a href="https://youtu.be/5XTSFLFV7e8?si=mTgy-svDE5xaefi4">here</a>), we will get more details on what to expect from Annapurna in the first half of 2025. </p><div><p id="to-a-t"><h2><em>To a T</em></h2></p></div><p><em>To a T </em>is the latest release from <em>Katamari Damacy</em> creator <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/17/21025916/keita-takahashi-interview-wattam-katamari">Keita Takahashi</a>, and damn, if it ain’t adorable <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/16/21021203/wattam-review-ps4-pc-katamari">like most of his games</a>. The game tells the story of Teen, a young person with a… we’ll say “unique” posture, and it’s up to you to help them navigate the challenges that come with being born stuck in a permanent “T” pose. For the showcase, <em>To a T </em>got a special music video a la “<a href="https://youtu.be/sQTk4eK2fP4?si=cBFDxOYSEBkOFSN5">It’s Bugsnax!</a>” featuring the vocal stylings of <em>Steven Universe</em> creator Rebecca Sugar. <em>To a T</em> launches on May 28th on Xbox, PS5, and PC, and a demo is available now on Steam.</p><div><p id="morsels"><h2><em>Morsels</em></h2></p></div><p><a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1719040%2FMorsels%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Morsels</em></a> is a creature collector roguelite with a creepy / cute grossout vibe. Use your powers of transformation to turn into the right monster for the job and battle against evil cat creatures. (Finally, some cozy <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/7/18/23220428/stray-video-game-review-ps4-ps5-steam">cat</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/14/23999288/neko-atsume-purrfect-kitty-collector-meta-quests-trailer-release-date">game</a> counterprogramming!) No release date on <em>Morsels</em> yet, but expect it to launch sometime in 2025 on PC and Nintendo Switch.</p><div><p id="wheel-world"><h2><em>Wheel World</em></h2></p></div><p>There’s something about the kinds of presentations that give a glimpse into the people and lives that make these games that really endears me to both the studio and the game. I’m not a bike person, but after seeing the behind-the-scenes presentation for <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1497460%2FWheel_World%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Wheel World</em></a>, I want to be. <em>Wheel World</em> is an open-world magical cycling adventure where you can ride, race, customize your bike, and ultimately save the world. It launches summer 2025, but you can check out the demo now during Steam’s Next Fest.</p><div><p id="faraway"><h2><em>Faraway</em></h2></p></div><p>According to its one-man development team, <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F2831000%2FFaraway%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Faraway</em></a> can be played with just one hand. In it, you play as a shooting star destined to flicker out but that keeps itself shining brightly by traveling the stars and making constellations. The game consists of a “story” mode that procedurally generates in response to players’ actions and skill levels. There’s also a puzzle mode designed to challenge players in their journey across the stars. Try out <em>Faraway</em> during Steam’s Next Fest or wait for the game’s release on PC later this year.</p><div><p id="geometric-interactive"><h2>Geometric Interactive</h2></p></div><p>Geometric, developer of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23939189/october-2023-games-hidden-gem-cocoon-subpar-pool-jusant">phenomenal puzzle platformer <em>Cocoon</em></a>, is back with some lo-fi vibes to carry orbs to. The studio is working with iam8bit to release a collector’s edition of the game as well as <em>Cocoon</em>’s soundtrack on vinyl. The studio also teased that it’s working on a completely new game but, of course, didn’t share any details yet. </p><div><p id="lushfoil-photography-sim"><h2><em>Lushfoil Photography Sim</em></h2></p></div><p>As the name suggests, <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1749860%2FLushfoil_Photography_Sim%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Lushfoil</em></a> is all about taking pictures using true-to-life photography techniques. Explore different locations around the world, including the torii gates of Kyoto, Japan, the lush forests of Italy, and even the mountainous Annapurna region in Nepal. Each location is rendered in stunning detail and features photography objectives and collectible cameras that’ll encourage players to strive for the perfect shot. <em>Lushfoil</em> has a demo available on Steam and is slated to launch on April 15th, 2025, on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC.</p><div><p id="wanderstop"><h2><em>Wanderstop</em></h2></p></div><p><a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1299460%2FWanderstop%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Wanderstop</em></a> is a cozy adventure sim all about tea and navigating difficult life changes, but mostly about tea. Collect ingredients for tea, brew it in an elaborate contraption that looks more like a mad scientist chemistry kit, and thwart the designs of an apparently nefarious bird. <em>Wanderstop</em> is the first game from Ivy Road and is set to launch on Steam and PS5 on March 11th.</p><div><p id="skin-deep"><h2><em>Skin Deep</em></h2></p></div><p><a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F301280%2FSkin_Deep%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Skin Deep</em></a> has one hell of a pitch. According to the developers at Blendo Games, the game is essentially “<em>Die Hard</em> with more comedy.” You play as Nina Pasadena, a legendary assassin turned “insurance commando” tasked with saving a starship from a space pirate invasion using whatever tools and weapons she can scrounge along the way. Based on the trailer, <em>Skin Deep </em>feels like a cross between <em>Hitman</em> and <em><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/07/24/skibidi-toilet-movie-tv-franchise-youtube-michael-bay/">Skibidi Toilet</a>, </em>which, honestly, sounds like a neat vibe. You can test that vibe for yourself in the demo or wait for the game’s launch on April 30th.</p><div><p id="sayonara-wild-hearts"><h2><em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em></h2></p></div><p><em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em> was one of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/25/20882183/sayonara-wild-hearts-interview-switch-ps4-apple-arcade-simogo">breakout hits of 2019</a>, and it’s back with next-gen updates and a brand-new game mode exclusively for PS5. Remix Arcade allows players to chase high scores in infinitely replayable, progressively faster, and more difficult sound bites with no loading. <em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em> on PS5 is out now and available as a free upgrade if you have the PS4 version.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Is No Longer Rated 18+ In Europe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/balatro-18-pegi-rating-wrong-changed-12-esrb-europe-1851766176</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-is-no-longer-rated-18-in-europe.1117620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/balatro-18-pegi-rating-wrong-changed-12-esrb-europe-1851766176<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/balatro-poker-roguelike-worth-it-is-it-good-review-pc-1851283124&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/balatro-poker-roguelike-worth-it-is-it-good-review-pc-1851283124">Indie superhit <em>Balatro</em></a></span><em> </em>no longer has the same Pan European Game Information (PEGI) rating as <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> in Europe. Last year the card game received the adult PEGI 18+ rating due to its poker gameplay and rules. But thanks to a successful appeal, <em>Balatro’s </em>rating has been lowered to PEGI 12+. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Balatro</em>, which launched a year ago last week, has been a huge hit across the globe. The roguelike card game  tasks players with putting together high-scoring poker hands using luck, skill, and powerful joker cards that act like supernatural wildcards. <em>Balatro</em>—available now on consoles, PC, and mobile devices—isn’t a game about gambling and doesn’t include any violence or real money transactions. That didn’t stop PEGI from randomly, with no warning, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/balatro-nintendo-switch-eshop-removed-gambling-1851301756?_gl=1*iow2wp*_ga*MzE4MTUxNzQ2LjE3NDA0MTE5MzE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDQyMjE1OC4zLjAuMTc0MDQyMjE1OC42MC4wLjA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/balatro-nintendo-switch-eshop-removed-gambling-1851301756?_gl=1*iow2wp*_ga*MzE4MTUxNzQ2LjE3NDA0MTE5MzE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDQyMjE1OC4zLjAuMTc0MDQyMjE1OC42MC4wLjA.">raising the game’s rating from 3+ to 18+,</a></span> however. The American equivalent would essentially be the ESRB  changing a game’s rating from E to M. Now, finally, PEGI has realized how silly it was to rate <em>Balatro </em>18+. </p><p>On February 24, Balatro creator and developer LocalThunk confirmed that after his publisher had appealed to PEGI, <em>Balatro’s </em>rating had been lowered from the adults only 18+ to the more sensible 12+, which is similar to an ESRB T rating. </p><p>“This is a good step from PEGI - bringing nuance to their ratings criteria that used to be 18+ or nothing. I hope this change will allow developers to create without being unfairly punished,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/LocalThunk/status/1894076713522384943&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/LocalThunk/status/1894076713522384943" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted LocalThunk</a></span>. </p><p>Over on the PEGI website, the group confirmed it had lowered <em>Balatro</em>’s rating as well as the rating of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/balatro-luck-landlord-google-play-store-gambling-mobile-1851731303&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/balatro-luck-landlord-google-play-store-gambling-mobile-1851731303"><em>Luck Be A Landord</em></a></span><em>—</em>a game that featured slot machines and directly inspired <em>Balatro</em>—for similar reasons. </p><p>“The Complaints Board concluded that, although [<em>Balatro</em>] explains the various hands of poker, the roguelike deck-building game contained mitigating fantastical elements that warranted a PEGI 12 rating,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://pegi.info/news/pegi-complaints-board-amends-classifications-balatro-and-luck-be-landlord-pegi-12&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://pegi.info/news/pegi-complaints-board-amends-classifications-balatro-and-luck-be-landlord-pegi-12" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said the board on the PEGI website.</a></span> </p><p>PEGI further explained that <em>Luck Be a Landord</em>’s rating change from 18+ to 12+ was because “the same arguments as above applied: although the game features a slot machine mechanic, there were no specific transferable gambling skills.”</p><p>The PEGI rule that any game that teaches or glamorizes simulated gambling will result in an automatic 18+ rating isn’t going away. However, the board says that it will provide 12+ ratings to games, like <em>Balatro</em>, that don’t simulate gambling in a casino or betting hall. </p><p>“PEGI acknowledges the finding of the Complaints Board appeals panel in regards to amending the classifications of these games,” said the board. </p><p>“The PEGI system continuously evolves in line with cultural expectations and the guidance of independent experts who support our assessment process. PEGI strives to apply ratings criteria fairly, consistently, and transparently to ensure that audiences understand the type of content that is present in games.”</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TRON: Catalyst launches June 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/tron-catalyst-launches-june-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tron-catalyst-launches-june-17.1117614/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/tron-catalyst-launches-june-17<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Story-driven isometric action adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Story-driven isometric <a title="Genres > Action [2,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,069 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > TRON: Catalyst [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tron-catalyst">TRON: Catalyst</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,905 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,685 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3025590/TRON_Catalyst/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on June 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Big Fan Games [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital/big-fan-games">Big Fan Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Bithell Games [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bithell-games">Bithell Games</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3025590/view/543349971553880398" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-946205"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Big Fan Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>TRON: Catalyst</em> pulls you back into the world of <em>Disney’s TRON</em> to battle multiple opposing factions in the latest imaginative story from Bithell Games (<em>Thomas Was Alone</em>, <em>Subsurface Circular</em>, <em><a title="Games > TRON: Identity [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tron-identity">TRON: Identity</a></em>). <em>TRON: Catalyst</em> is an all-new story-driven, isometric action adventure game, set in the immersive and diverse locations of the Arq Grid introduced in <em>TRON: Identity</em>.</p><p>Play as Exo, a highly resilient and resourceful program wielding an unexpected power known as the Glitch, gaining strength and abilities which the overlords of the Arq Grid’s crumbling society seek to bring under control. Ride Light Cycles, engage in Identity Disc combat, and more as you’re relentlessly pursued through the city and beyond by Conn, a malevolent program with an agenda of his own, while uncovering more about the glitches that threaten the stability of this world.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Dynamic Combat System</strong> – Battle a legion of fearsome enemy programs in melee and ranged combat, both on-foot and while riding a Light Cycle. <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter advanced techniques like parrying and Disc kicks to gain the upper hand, while exploring the Arq Grid and collecting Data Shards to upgrade your code base with new abilities.</li><li><strong>Immersive New Story</strong> – Dive into an original <em>TRON</em> storyline. Meet the programs of the Arq Grid, uncover their secrets and fight to survive in a chase across the city and outlands. Playing as Exo, a courier working in this grid’s capital city, your life is turned upside down when a mysterious package explodes, granting you powers beyond any program’s normal function. With the Arq Grid’s ruthless ‘peacekeepers’ in hot pursuit, you’ll unlock the mysteries of this grid, and learn what kind of hero it needs you to become.</li><li><strong>Exploit The Glitch</strong> – The Arq Grid is losing stability. Glitches roll back the clock, catching the world in a series of system level time loops… and only you can see them. Utilize Exo’s unique ability to uncover secret areas and shortcuts, and influence the factions jostling for control over the Arq Grid.</li><li><strong>Authentic World of <em>TRON</em></strong> – Explore the neon-lit streets of the Arq Grid on foot or Light Cycle, and navigate your way through the intriguing—often dangerous—characters that inhabit this high-stakes world. Travel through a diverse Grid filled with intriguing stories within a budding revolution all set to an immersive soundtrack from composer Dan Le Sac (<em>TRON: Identity</em>). If you’re a fan of <em>Disney’s TRON</em>, get ready to step into the universe you love like never before. If you’re new to this story, prepare for a thrilling adventure.</li></ul><p>Now… finish the game.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="TRON: Catalyst Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AQQEnuaNhdw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jump Ship launches in Early Access this summer for Xbox Series, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/jump-ship-launches-in-early-access-this-summer-for-xbox-series-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jump-ship-launches-in-early-access-this-summer-for-xbox-series-pc.1117608/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/jump-ship-launches-in-early-access-this-summer-for-xbox-series-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Mission-based cooperative first-person shooter from former Hazelight, Mojang, and Coffee Stain Studios developers.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Mission-based <a title="Genres > Co-Op [234 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,607 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Jump Ship" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/jump-ship">Jump Ship</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam this summer, publisher <a title="Companies > Coffee Stain Publishing [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/coffee-stain-publishing">Coffee Stain Publishing</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Keepsake Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/keepsake-games">Keepsake Games</a> announced. Sign-ups for the closed beta test are available <a href="https://jumpshipgame.com/" target="_blank">here</a>. <span id="more-946239"></span></p><p>“Our goal was to create a game that balances the fun and immersion of space exploration,” said Keepsake Games CEO Daniel Kaplan in a press release. “Coming from <a title="Companies > Hazelight [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hazelight">Hazelight</a>, Mojang, and Coffee Stain, we understand how to make a great co-op game, and we’ve reached a point where player input is vital in order for us to make <em>Jump Ship</em> as good as it can be. That’s why we’re releasing into Early Access this summer—to work directly with our players, listen to their feedback, and combine it with our vision.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Coffee Stain Publishing:</p><blockquote><p><em>Jump Ship</em> is a mission based co-op FPS in which players can transition seamlessly from crewing their very own space ship to on-foot exploration and space walks. The goal of each mission is to survive with the crew’s ship intact and make the next jump, picking up valuable resources, blueprints and weapons along the way. While one crewmate is piloting the ship, another might be putting out fires or fixing radiation leaks on the deck, while the rest of the group boards enemy vessels or battle through volatile space stations to make off with precious supplies.</p><p>In <em>Jump Ship</em>, the galaxy is filled with handcrafted celestial settings, from vast asteroid rings dominating the horizon to distant, luminescent nebulas radiating kaleidoscopic light. The scenery changes with each jump, as players go from boarding and pillaging a rival corvette-class ship to salvaging shipwrecks floating in vacuum or exploring an abandoned research facility.</p><p>However, deep space hides many other, more celestial threats, as solar flares and meteor showers regularly threaten to end players’ spacefaring journeys in an instant.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new set of trailers below.</p><h2><span>Beta Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Jump Ship - Beta Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BKs5vBNaT-U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Gameplay Moments</span></h2><p><iframe title="Jump Ship - Gameplay Moments" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vFaIpLGmBdA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Is Now On Game Pass With New Fallout And Assassin's Creed Collaborations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-now-on-game-pass-with-new-fallout-and-assassins-creed-collaborations/1100-6529681/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-is-now-on-game-pass-with-new-fallout-and-assassins-creed-collaborations.1117602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-now-on-game-pass-with-new-fallout-and-assassins-creed-collaborations/1100-6529681/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529681">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>LocalThunk has revealed that Balatro is now on Game Pass for Xbox and PC, along with the fourth Friends of Jimbo pack. This pack includes collaborations with Fallout, Assassin's Creed, and more.</p><p>Friends of Jimbo packs are free updates that allow players to change the face cards of any or all suits in the deck. These have no impact on gameplay. In this most recent pack, the eight new crossovers are: Dead by Daylight, Civilization VII, Critical Role, Assassin's Creed, Fallout, Bugsnax, Slay the Princess, and Rust.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xn4ft9u924I" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Xn4ft9u924I" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Previous Friends of Jimbo packs included crossovers with Cyberpunk 2077, Warframe, and Stardew Valley. Balatro's inclusion onto  Game Pass is a surprise, as Microsoft already revealed the rest of the games that'll <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/game-pass-is-getting-three-more-games-in-february-2025/2900-6268/" data-ref-id="2900-6268">join this month</a>, including Watch Dogs Legion, EA Sports F1 24, and Warhammer 40k: Rogue Trader.</p><p>Balatro recently got its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatros-confusing-rating-finally-changed-leads-to-europe-changing-how-it-rates-gambling-games/1100-6529673/" data-ref-id="1100-6529673">European classification changed from PEGI 18 to PEGI 12</a> due to an appeal from the game's publisher. PEGI concluded that even though Balatro taught poker hands, its more fantastical and mystical elements mitigated the gambling aspects.</p><p>Balatro is one of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamespots-10-best-games-of-2024/2900-6045/" data-ref-id="2900-6045">GameSpot's best games of 2024</a>, and it has received numerous awards and nominations at shows like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/28th-annual-dice-awards-nominees-revealed/2900-6116/" data-ref-id="2900-6116">2025 DICE Awards</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/game-developers-choice-awards-2025-nominees-revealed/2900-6173/" data-ref-id="2900-6173">Game Developers Choice Awards</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/new-york-game-awards-2025-all-nominees/2900-6106/" data-ref-id="2900-6106">New York Game Awards 2025</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2024-winners-revealed/2900-5956/" data-ref-id="2900-5956">The Game Awards 2024</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise! Balatro has shadow dropped on Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/surprise-balatro-has-shadow-dropped-on-game-pass</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surprise-balatro-has-shadow-dropped-on-game-pass.1117596/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/surprise-balatro-has-shadow-dropped-on-game-pass<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>With collabs from Assassin's Creed and more.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_YmHi8jS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Balatro / Xbox / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Balatro, the highly-acclaimed card-based roguelike from developer Local Thunk, is now available via Xbox Game Pass. It arrives alongside a new bit of free DLC featuring collaobrations from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dead-by-daylight">Dead by Daylight</a>, Civilization 7, Fallout, and more.
</p>
<p>
As announced during Microsoft's latest ID@Xbox showcase, Balatro can be enjoyed by Game Pass subscribers right now - and its arrival brings a fresh set of cosmetic card skins featuring fan-favourite characters from across a range of titles.
</p>
<p>
Friends of Jimbo Pack 4, as the DLC is known, has more of a blockbuster focus compared to Balatro's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatros-back-with-another-collaboration-card-pack-featuring-the-likes-of-cyberpunk-2077-and-stardew-valley">previous, predominantly indie-themed collaborations</a>. Now, players can adorn the back of their decks with the likes of Vault Boy from the Fallout series, Assassin's Creed's Ezio Auditore da Firenze, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bugsnax">Bugsnax</a> protagonist The Journalist, and Dead by Daylight's The Hillbilly.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0G24sFdbXws?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0G24sFdbXws?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0G24sFdbXws?autoplay=1" title="Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) | Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Balatro - Friends of Jimbo 4 trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0G24sFdbXws" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Other games represented in Friends of Jimbo Pack 4 include <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>, Rust, and Slay the Princess. Critical Role's Percival Fredrickstein von Musel Klossowski de Rolo III is in there too. And if that appeals, the DLC is available right now on all platforms.
</p>
<p>
Balatro first launched on Xbox alongside versions for PC, PlayStation and Nintendo Switch a year ago. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-out-on-mobile-later-this-month">smartphone edition for iPhone and Android devices</a> followed last September. 
</p>
<p>
It's fair to say Balatro has been a smash hit, with more than five million copies sold of its roguish poker-inspired cardplay, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/meeting-the-people-of-pegi-talking-age-ratings-gambling-and-why-their-famous-voice-only-got-200">despite its controversial 18+ age rating</a> - which is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-wins-formal-appeal-to-reclassify-poker-game-as-pegi-12">finally getting overturned in the EU</a>, and replaced by a PEGI 12 rating instead. 
</p>
<p>
Since its release, Balatro has added further cards via updates that have included crossovers with major gaming franchises such as The Witcher, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/among-us">Among Us</a> and Vampire Survivor. 
</p>
<p>
Here on Eurogamer, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-50-best-games-of-2024-ranked">Balatro was one of our favourite games of 2024</a>. "It's a work of marvellous depth and winning simplicity, and rightly one of the best and most memorable games you'll play this year," our Katharine wrote.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remembering Viktor Antonov, Beloved Artist Behind Half-Life 2 And Dishonored]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/viktor-antonov-half-life-2-dishonored-artist-obituary-1851765954</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remembering-viktor-antonov-beloved-artist-behind-half-life-2-and-dishonored.1117572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/viktor-antonov-half-life-2-dishonored-artist-obituary-1851765954<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It was announced earlier this week that video game artist Viktor Antonov had died at the unreasonably young age of 52. With stints working at big-name studios like Valve and Arkane, Antonov’s work was a key part of some of the most loved games of all time. It was his unmistakable style that defined <em>Half-Life 2</em>'s City 17 and <em>Dishonored</em>’s Dunwall, two of the most distinctive and unforgettable locations in game history. We spoke to people who knew and loved him to learn more about Antonov and his work.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Beginning on memorable games like 1997's <em>Redneck Rampage</em> and 1999's infamous <em>Kingpin: Life of Crime</em>, Viktor Antonov had quickly formed a partnership with fellow game artist Aaron Barber. Barber was hired by Valve, working on 2001's original <em>Half-Life</em>, and Viktor soon followed. <strong>Marc Laidlaw</strong>, the legendary writer behind the <em>Half-Life</em> franchise, told me that once both had been hired and <em>Half-Life 2 </em>development had begun, the two “started in right away.”</p><p>Laidlaw had a vision for City 17, but found it hard to properly articulate. Thankfully, Antonov was there. “Viktor was very thorough in trying to understand what we were after, and once he saw the situation, he set about correcting it,” says Laidlaw. “The game was in need of correctives, and strong visual unity, and Viktor provided that, going between the daily practical ‘Yes but how do I actually build it?’ needs of level designers and my vague, atmospheric, ‘It should sorta feel like’ suggestions.”</p><figure id="" data-id="175956a1b2f23e54dd3b40c2ca817945" data-recommend-id="image://175956a1b2f23e54dd3b40c2ca817945" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A strider stalks the player in City 17." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A strider stalks the player in City 17." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="175956a1b2f23e54dd3b40c2ca817945" data-recommend-id="image://175956a1b2f23e54dd3b40c2ca817945" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A strider stalks the player in City 17." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>“I was really smitten with [the stop-motion animation duo] the Brothers Quay,” Laidlaw told <em>Kotaku</em>, “so in my mind we were chasing a shadowy surreal kind of European style, but meanwhile I grew up in Southern California and have never been to Europe, so it could only ever be stylized and abstract, and hard to communicate in terms of spaces designed for combat.” But Viktor, born in Bulgaria, then living in France, Switzerland, Los Angeles and eventually Seattle, had a novel perspective, and more than simply for geography. Laidlaw continued, “Viktor bridged those worlds—between literary abstraction and concrete level design, between general themes and specific architecture.”</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>We would talk and then he would go off and talk to the artists and designers and slowly a world we could all agree on emerged, full of promise, full of specificity, realistic in some senses but also unique to our game.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Laura Dubuk</strong> was a young art student, and working at Valve was her first professional job. Viktor Antonov would be her mentor at the studio, leaving an indelible mark on her career. “For me personally,” Dubuk told me, “he got across how much work and skill it would take to succeed in the video game industry, and how to do it properly. Thankfully he gave me clear direction and led me to learn the fundamentals so I could begin my journey.”</p><p>Dubuk continued, “Viktor was a truly unique, unforgettable person. He cared deeply about his friends, and wanted to make sure they were all cared for properly, and going about their lives well and with intention. He was an incredibly observant person which gave him an amazing sense of humor, and was an extremely engaging conversationalist. He was intensely curious and went to the absolute depth of every topic that captured his attention. It goes without saying this curiosity and passion was infectious.”</p><hr><p>After many years with Valve, Viktor Antonov moved to Arkane Studios, the developer behind <em>Dishonored </em>and <em>Prey</em>, and it was the former where Antonov had the most distinct influence. Marc Laidlaw noted the impact of his move. “I think you can see that when Viktor went off and designed worlds with Arkane, the similarities between <em>Half-Life 2</em> and <em>Dishonored</em> show that there was a distinctive Viktor Antonov style that kind of transcended both games and belonged to his original sensibility.”</p><p><strong>Raphaël Colantonio</strong>, the founder and former president of Arkane Studios, shared the sentiment. “He and Arkane bonded over the shared passion for creating worlds,” Colantonio told me, “free from corporate and commercial influences: we were both idealists, we wanted to do pure art. That sincerity and uncompromised mindset was deeply ingrained in Arkane in general.”</p><p>“Viktor was one of those people that you instantly know are one in a billion,” Colantonio said. “I could talk about him for hours. We were extremely lucky to cross paths with him on his way out from Valve.”</p><figure id="" data-id="622cba1237bea65bb85d66f8adcaf29a" data-recommend-id="image://622cba1237bea65bb85d66f8adcaf29a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1981" data-height="1114" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The grim vision of Dunwall in Dishonored, seen from a boat." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The grim vision of Dunwall in Dishonored, seen from a boat." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arkane / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="622cba1237bea65bb85d66f8adcaf29a" data-recommend-id="image://622cba1237bea65bb85d66f8adcaf29a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1981" data-height="1114" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The grim vision of Dunwall in Dishonored, seen from a boat." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Colantonio recalls how Antonov played such a crucial role in designing the look and feel of the game’s central city, Dunwall. “Viktor leveled up Arkane’s art department. He worked closely with [art director] Sébastien Mitton to restructure and change our processes and together they built a world-class team of artists that could rival any top team in the world.”</p><p><strong>Harvey Smith</strong>, who headed up Arkane Austin, added his memories of Viktor. “An absolute titan like Viktor Antonov working with the already-stacked Arkane art team, led by the incredibly talented Sebastian Mitton and Jean-Luc Monnet, was one of those thunderbolt moments that keeps reverberating forever, across the lives of all the people who worked on or played the <em>Dishonored</em> games. I will always be moved and humbled by what that visual design group created.”</p><p>That sense of  impact was also brought up by Marc Laidlaw, who sees Antonov’s influence in similarly game-changing ways. “Viktor at that point in time not only benefited the games he worked on, but the industry as a whole,” said Laidlaw, “helping it step away from the wearisome influences of <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Blade Runner</em> and <em>Alien</em>. I think we agreed that the visual vocabulary of the game industry needed to be drastically expanded, especially when it came to science fiction and fantasy. So if future games end up looking a bit like City 17 or Dunwall instead of Giger or Syd Mead, we will have Viktor to thank.”</p><hr><p>Beyond Viktor Antonov’s influence on games and game design, he was also a man people simply loved. Everyone I spoke to was effusive with praise for his decency, passion and warmth.</p><p>“Viktor was a force of nature,” said Harvey Smith. “Simultaneously the storm and the rock you cling to. He educated those around him about art, design, and beauty with every breath, even when talking about brutal systems of oppression, like the security systems in <em>Dishonored</em>; perpetually relevant subject matter, it seems. His insights, his powerful presence, and his devastating dry wit will be missed.”</p><p>“Viktor was extremely intelligent, articulate, always surprising with shocking yet accurate remarks about world building,” Raphaël Colantonio recalled. “People respected him and were often intimidated because of his serious demeanor (though he was secretly extremely funny). We became good friends, we traveled together a lot. No-one could tie up or control Viktor, but when I left Arkane to start Wolfeye Studios, he consulted for our projects, like in the good old times. I miss him, I miss his funny wit.”</p><p>Lovely guy,” said former Valve developer <strong>Chet Faliszek</strong>, “and being super Frenchy, he was a fun breath of fresh air at Valve.”</p><p>“Losing Viktor is a big loss because I know he still had a lot to offer,” Dubuk said, “but again he contributed so much in his life to games and film during his years, and I know we are all grateful for him.”</p><p>Marc Laidlaw recalled their shared love of literature, how “a recurrent conversation of ours concerned Nikolai Gogol.” He explained, “Viktor urged me repeatedly to read The Nose and The Overcoat, two of his favorite stories. I can no longer remember his point—probably he was just trying to expand my own vocabulary for literary surrealism. After retirement, I finally got a complete Gogol collection and read through it, with special attention to Viktor’s favorites.”</p><p>“One last memory,” added Marc Laidlaw. “My youngest daughter was obsessed with Paris after watching the Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen movie, <em>Passport to Paris</em>. On one of his trips to France, Viktor returned with a souvenir model of the Eiffel Tour just for her.”</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Arrives on Game Pass with Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-game-pass-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-arrives-on-game-pass-with-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4.1117566/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-game-pass-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Everybody’s favourite poker-based deck builder, Balatro, is now available on Xbox Game Pass, along with the latest Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) expansion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Announced during the ID@Xbox event, Balatro revealed their latest expansion, Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4). The new expansion will feature popular gaming franchises, including Bugsnax, Assassin’s Creed, Slay the Princess, Fallout, Critical Role, Rust, Dead by Daylight and Sid Meier’s Civilization VII. Within the Friends of Jimbo Pack 4 reveal trailer, the developers had tucked away an even more exciting announcement: Balatro is now available on Xbox Game Pass.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Balatro’s Friends of Jimbo Pack 4 expansion will include <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2379780/Balatro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">new cosmetic card skins</a> for beloved characters from these popular franchises, including “Vault Boy, Ezio Auditore da Firenze, Percival Fredrickstein von Musel Klossowski de Rolo III and more.” The update is available now on PC, Consoles, and mobile.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Balatro was released a year ago, and since then, it has gathered massive appreciation from critics and the general community. Within that time, the game has sold over <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-has-announced-its-sold-5-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">5 million units</a>, which is nothing short of commendable for an indie title. The game also won its appeal <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-luck-be-a-landlord-win-pegi-ratings-appeals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">against PEGI ratings today</a>, and Balatro will now be rated PEGI 12, compared to the previous PEGI 18 rating.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0G24sFdbXws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, check out the Balatro <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-trophy-guide-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophy Guide</a>, which thoroughly explains how to complete LocalThunk’s roguelike card game. Also, here’s how to unlock <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-throwback-joker-balatro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Throwback Joker</a> in Balatro. Are you going to play Balatro through Xbox Game Pass, and what are your thoughts on the Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) announcement).&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/idxbox-showcase-february-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">&nbsp;everything announced at ID@Xbox</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[33 Immortals launches in Early Access on March 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/33-immortals-launches-in-early-access-on-march-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/33-immortals-launches-in-early-access-on-march-18.1117563/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/33-immortals-launches-in-early-access-on-march-18<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Cooperative roguelike action game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Cooperative <a title="Genres > Roguelike [299 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > 33 Immortals [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/33-immortals">33 Immortals</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/33-immortals-9873a2" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/33-immortals/9p8lr42ptrgj" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on March 18, developer <a title="Companies > Thunder Lotus Games [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thunder-lotus-games">Thunder Lotus Games</a> announced. It will also be available via Game Pass. <span id="more-945521"></span></p><p>“The release of <em>33 Immortals</em> will mark a monumental milestone for Thunder Lotus,” said <em>33 Immortals</em> creative director Stephan Logier. “We’re proud to finally be able to deliver a genuinely unique co-op experience. We look forward to seeing how players will tackle the challenges of facing God’s wrath together.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Thunder Lotus Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>33 Immortals</em> is an ambitious 33-player action-roguelike that invites players to “face the wrath of God” in a “lean, mean distillation of the MMO raid experience.”</p><p>In <em>33 Immortals</em>, players are damned souls, rebelling against God’s final judgment. The game’s quick and seamless matchmaking launches 33 players into punchy <a title="Genres > Co-Op [234 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> roguelike raids, in a radically streamlined re-imagining of the massively <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [448 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> online experience Thunder Lotus has dubbed “pick-up and raid.” Players optimize their builds to match their playstyle, mixing and matching weapons, perks, and persistent upgrades to steadily improve their rebellion’s odds of withstanding the wrath of God. Above all, <em>33 Immortals</em> actively encourages players to collaborate throughout the runs, to ensure that the largest and strongest group possible survives the enemy hordes, and prevails in the showstopping boss fights.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>33 Immortals</em> is the debut online multiplayer title for Thunder Lotus, the studio best known for immersive single player experiences like the two million unit-selling <em>Spiritfarer</em>. To meet the unique challenges of its first foray into online games, Thunder Lotus expanded its operations to two parallel development teams, with the <em>33 Immortals</em> development team being made up of industry veterans well-versed in online multiplayer.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>33-player cooperative combat against hordes of enemies and massive bosses.</li><li>Instant “pick-up and raid” matchmaking gets you straight into the action.</li><li>Ultra-fast runs through a streamlined distillation of the massively multiplayer online raid experience.</li><li>Randomized foes, challenges, and rewards ensure no roguelike run is ever the same.</li><li>An epic arsenal of weapons empowered by sins and virtues, each with their own unique combat style.</li><li>Hundreds of upgrade combinations and character builds.</li><li>Customize your character with a wide variety of cosmetics.</li><li>Beautiful hand­-drawn art and animation.</li><li>A richly textured world inspired by Dante’s <em>Divine Comedy</em>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="33 Immortals - Release Date Trailer (ESRB)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rV5kEt8Sr7Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro ‘Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4)’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/balatro-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-%E2%80%98friends-of-jimbo-pack-4-%E2%80%99-update-now-available.1117557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/balatro-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4-update-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Collaborations with Assassin's Creed, Fallout, Rust, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Playstack [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playstack">Playstack</a> and developer <a title="Companies > LocalThunk [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/localthunk">LocalThunk</a> have released a free update for <em><a title="Games > Balatro [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/balatro">Balatro</a></em> titled “Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4),” which features collaborations with <em><a title="Series > Assassin's Creed [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/assassins-creed">Assassin’s Creed</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Bugsnax [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bugsnax">Bugsnax</a></em>, <em>Critical Role</em>, <em>Dead by Daylight</em>, <em>Fallout</em> (Vault-Tec),<em>Rust</em>, <em><a title="Games > Sid Meier's Civilization VII [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Sid Meier’s Civilization VII</a></em>, <em>Slay the Princess</em>. <em>Balatro</em> is also now available via Game Pass. <span id="more-945943"></span></p><p><em>Balatro</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,905 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,741 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,685 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [22,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2379780/Balatro/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, iOS, and Android.</p><p>Watch the update launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>“Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4)” Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Balatro - Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0G24sFdbXws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DON’T NOD and Tiny Bull Studios announce top-down action RPG The Lonesome Guild for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dont-nod-and-tiny-bull-studios-announce-top-down-action-rpg-the-lonesome-guild-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/don%E2%80%99t-nod-and-tiny-bull-studios-announce-top-down-action-rpg-the-lonesome-guild-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1117551/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dont-nod-and-tiny-bull-studios-announce-top-down-action-rpg-the-lonesome-guild-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out this fall.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > DON'T NOD [117 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dont-nod">DON’T NOD</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tiny Bull Studios [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tiny-bull-studios">Tiny Bull Studios</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > The Lonesome Guild" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-lonesome-guild">The Lonesome Guild</a></em>, a single-player top-down <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,508 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,905 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1486450/The_Lonesome_Guild/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this fall. <span id="more-946188"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via DON’T NOD:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In a world consumed by loneliness, only friendship can save the day. Lead a quirky cast in this colorful single-player action RPG full of heart, battles, and bonds that change everything.</p><p>The world might be lonely, but you don’t have to be.</p><p><strong>A Tale of Togetherness in a World Apart</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>The Lonesome Guild</em> is a single-player top-down action RPG all about togetherness. Embark on a heroic <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,069 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> as Ghost, a spirit who wakes to find they hold no memories.</p><p>The world has become shrouded by loneliness and the mist just keeps spreading, corrupting everyone in its path. Now it’s up to you to get the band back together… even if they’re meeting for the first time.</p><p><strong>Six Misfits, One Goal</strong></p><p>The ragtag group of unlikely friends you’ll recruit each will bring their own story, quirks, motives, and abilities.</p><p>Switch seamlessly between the six of them during exploration and combat to navigate <a title="Games > Ete [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ete">Ete</a>re, solve puzzles, and defeat enemies!</p><p><strong>Bond and Battle</strong></p><p>Relationships are the heart and soul of <em>The Lonesome Guild</em>—it’s a party, literally. As your friendship grows, so does your power with new abilities and combos.</p><p>A party can only be strong if each member is strong too—unravel your new friends’ stories and help them find peace.</p><p>Unlock side quests, new abilities, and heartfelt chats by the campfire. Together, we’re unstoppable!</p><p><strong>Fights That Keep You on Your Toes</strong></p><p>Three difficulty levels, a roster of cool abilities, one very powerful Ghost power.</p><p>Test your might in intense battles where you can switch between characters whenever you fancy and ambush enemies with clever combos.</p><p>Build your dream team and fight your way through Etere.</p><p><strong>A World Worth Fighting for</strong></p><p>Etere is full of charm and secrets, mystery and treasures to uncover.</p><p>From unearthing old secrets in the ruins to gathering round campfires in the forest, there’s always something new around the corner in <em>The Lonesome Guild</em>.</p><p>Solve puzzles, explore vibrant landscapes, and find shiny things as you restore balance and hope to the world.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Lonesome Guild | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dQWc-2nEqNE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Warzone Leak Suggests Controversial POI Could Return With Verdansk]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-leak-suggests-controversial-poi-could-return-with-verdansk/1100-6529679/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-warzone-leak-suggests-controversial-poi-could-return-with-verdansk.1117548/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-leak-suggests-controversial-poi-could-return-with-verdansk/1100-6529679/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529679">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Last year, Activision confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Call of Duty: Warzone</a>'s original Verdansk map would return to the free-to-play battle royale in 2025, but the publisher still hasn't provided further details for the map's release. Now, new leaks have surfaced to suggest a more "OG" version of Verdansk, detailing some of the map's main points of interest.</p><p dir="ltr">According to known Call of Duty insider "<a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1893792956227698707" rel="nofollow ">The Ghost of Hope</a>," Verdansk will return with the launch of Season 3. The leaks also suggest that the map will be very similar to the original version that launched back in March of 2020, but the insider does detail a few minor differences.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1893792956227698707" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">EXCLUSIVE Details on the return of Verdansk:<br>- Will launch with Season 3 of BO6<br>- It is pretty much the OG March 2020 version<br>- Train Station interior will be closed<br>- Interior of Stadium will be open BUT roof will be closed<br>- The Train returns<br>- No fast travel subway system <a href="https://t.co/69aAy79RLS" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/69aAy79RLS</a></p>  — Hope (@TheGhostOfHope) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1893792956227698707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 23, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">One of the most notable details mentioned is that Verdansk will keep the Stadium point of interest with the roof intact. This might be a controversial map decision for Verdansk's return, as the original Stadium could often be a frustrating location to traverse. The building was usually plagued with rooftop campers, and it was also a massive structure to try and maneuver around while running from the gas.</p><p dir="ltr">However, Ghost of Hope does suggest that the interior of Stadium will be open this time, so hopefully players can use interior passages to better escape the area during a circle collapse. It's also worth noting that a post-launch update for Modern Warfare and Warzone included a Verdansk event that blew the top off Stadium to make the point of interest more viable. So, it's possible further map changes could arrive sometime after the return of Verdansk.</p><p dir="ltr">The insider claims that the train is returning with Verdansk, which was a feature that was not part of the original map design. The Train Station point of interest is also mentioned to be included on the map, but the station's interior will be closed off. A fast-travel subway system was added to Verdansk in a later season, but Ghost of Hope says this isn't planned for the map's return.</p><p dir="ltr">While all leaks should be taken with a grain of salt, it's worth mentioning that known Call of Duty dataminer <a href="https://x.com/realityuk_/status/1892643037462835327" rel="nofollow ">RealityUK</a> also claims that Verdansk references are now showing in the game files following the Season 2 Reloaded update.</p><p dir="ltr">If true, players won't have long to wait before the fan-favorite Verdansk returns. Based on the days left in the Season 2 battle pass, the Season 3 update should arrive to Black Ops 6 and Warzone around March 20. Until then, players can expect a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-adds-tmnt-event-plus-splinter-included-in-paid-pass/2900-6270/#3" data-ref-id="2900-6270">TMNT-themed limited-time event</a> on February 27, and the Clover Craze event arrives on March 13 for early Saint Patrick's Day celebrations.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mecha BREAK Open Beta Mashmak Hands-On Preview – Extracted Core]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mecha-break-open-beta-mashmak-pc-hands-on-preview-extracted-core/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mecha-break-open-beta-mashmak-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-extracted-core.1117521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/mecha-break-open-beta-mashmak-pc-hands-on-preview-extracted-core/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Mecha BREAK developer Amazing Seasun Games recently invited Wccftech and a handful of other gaming outlets to their main offices in California to go hands-on with the latest PC build of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2452280/Mecha_BREAK/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mecha BREAK</a>. In this session, we were able to sample a taste of the three core modes.</p>
<p>For those who haven’t kept up with the media blitz of reveal trailers and mode announcements, <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-demo-first-time-in-actual-game-ai-powered-interactions-mecha-break/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mecha BREAK</a> is, at its core, a hero shooter with gigantic mechs. Players assume control of one of 13 mechs available across a variety of roles, including your typical short-range bruisers, long-range snipers, and healing/support mechs. Each mech comes with a radically different kit in terms of weapons and active/passive abilities that all run on their own timers that should feel instantly familiar to anyone that might have dabbled in Marvel Rivals or Overwatch over the past few years. What sets Mecha BREAK apart from the other hero shooters on the market is a fast-paced dash and evade gameplay that evokes strong feelings of taking your favorite Mobile Suit and giving them the mobility kit of Jehuty from Zone of the Enders. Sure, you could play Mecha Break as a slow and deliberate tank class if that’s more your style, or you could take the role of Vic Viper and play the Falcon and transform between mech and fighter plane at will.</p>
<p>The game's core mode focuses on the 6-vs-6 team gameplay across a variety of familiar match types, each with Amazing Seasun Games’ take on the formula. You have your standard team deathmatch modes and Headquarters-style capture and hold base defense as well as a transport mode that can only be described as pushing the payload. Depending on the mechs that you’ve unlocked/purchased, your mileage may vary depending on your performance in each mode. If Tricera is one of your first mechs unlocked, this walking fortress might be the perfect addition to guard the payload to its final destination.</p>
<p>My playstyle in most hero shooters leans towards playing more of the support/healing role, and I first tried Lumine and their twin pistol combat kit meant that I could either deal damage or swap to a healing mode to support my teammates, making this mech feel like a direct analog to Overwatch’s Moira. However, it wasn’t until I picked up the heavy sniper Aquila that I got a proper feel for how damage and harassment are meant to work in Mecha BREAK. Giving a sniper the ability to automatically lock on up to six enemies at a time and unload your entire sniper clip at once was too good to pass up, even if the damage inflicted was usually minimal, depending on how shielded the enemies were.</p>
<p>The different types of shielding and health are something I haven’t quite fully grasped in Mecha BREAK, despite how simple they are on the surface. Each mech comes with a passive shield called Fluid Armor that’s meant to sustain most types of damage; once it’s been drained or overloaded, then any damage taken is converted to direct HP damage. On top of that, each mech has its own variety of defensive stats to protect against energy, melee, ballistic and blast weapon types. For Aquila, all of that mech’s damage is done via energy weapons. I found out quite early on that, despite that massive sniper rifle Aquila carries, it doesn’t really do enough damage to be the AWP-wielder I wanted it to be. Instead, he’s more of a poke/harass type, meant to chip away at enemies from afar while the more melee or close-ranged focused attackers go in for the kill.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Evacuate-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>

<p>The real star of the show that Amazing Seasun Games invited us out to play was their new extraction mode, Mashmak. This loot-and-scoot PvPvE mode is all about airdropping onto a massive 16x16 km map, scouting for resources, taking out rival squads and NPC bosses, and making it out alive with whatever you can carry with you. Despite having a large map, the actual gameplay is limited to up to ten squads of three players, with empty spots filled by NPCs. To force players to keep moving and not camp out in one remote corner of the map, extraction points slowly start to appear at the ten-minute mark with more dropping every five minutes; once one has been used, it’s gone for good for the rest of that match. Not only do players have to contend with enemy players potentially camping these extraction points out, but there’s a constantly shrinking field of engagement as Corite Pulse Storms slowly engulf the battlefield. This field can disable weapon lock-ons and also inflict a constant drain on both mech health and fluid armor.</p>
<p>While players are limited to bringing one of their unlocked mechs to battle, that doesn’t mean it’s the only tool available to them. Players can call in a variety of airdrops, from rocket beacons to extract some of your earned loot, repair beacons to heal up the entire squad, and a survival beacon that each player comes automatically equipped with that can call a downed squad member back to the fight on a five-minute cooldown.</p>
<p>There’s another beacon that became my favorite part of Mashmak: the weapon airdrop. Players can select a completely different secondary weapon to bring to the fight and call at will. Playing a sniper that has some serious close-range deficiencies? Equip a lance and unleash your inner Panther. Unlike the main multiplayer modes where weapons are all recharge-based, both main and subweapons in Mashmak all run off of ammo that will need to be collected from enemy drops or loot crates.</p>
<p>In its current state, Mashmak’s NPCs are brain-dead if you can engage them from afar like Aquila. Because of this, I spent a good majority of my matches clearing out enemy fodder units from afar so that my teammates could rush in without fear of being shot by turrets. When it came time to face an actual player squad, Aquila felt underwhelming and my main source of damage came from a twin pair of rocket launchers that I picked up from one of those weapon airdrops. I could go either way with the current state of NPCs in Mecha BREAK’s Mashmak. It’s fun for a short while that Mashmak is largely a shooting gallery for enemies that don’t have much bite, but at the same time, there is rarely a sense of danger from rushing headfirst into a base due to the game's mobility and fluid armor mechanics, at least until you come across a rival squad or one of Mashmak’s gigantic bosses.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mecha BREAK Mashmak Press Preview Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vQmJtKbBtFI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A successful extraction in Mashmak usually rewarded me with new research unlocks for different gear that I could bring into the next match or call in via airdrop, including high-mobility gliders that can give some of your slower attackers like Stego an unfair advantage when it comes to chasing down and harassing enemy squads.</p>
<p><a href="https://mechabreak.seasungames.com/">Mecha BREAK</a> is currently on track for a Spring 2025 release on PC (Steam and Xbox App) along with an exclusive console launch on Xbox Series S|X. PlayStation 5 has also been confirmed for a release later in 2025.</p>
<p><em>[Editor’s Note: Amazing Seasun Games and their PR agency provided hotel and travel accommodation to attend this event.]</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apocalyptic Deckbuilder As We Descend Gets March Early Access Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/as-we-descend-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apocalyptic-deckbuilder-as-we-descend-gets-march-early-access-release-date.1117515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/as-we-descend-early-access-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Box Dragon and publisher Coffee Stain have announced the release date for apocalyptic roguelike deckbuilder&nbsp;<em>As We Descend</em>, which is launching into Early Access next month.</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>As We Descend&nbsp;</em>will land on PC via Steam Early Access on March 27th, and since we're at the start of the latest Steam Next Fest event right now, you can try the game out for free on that same platform if you like.</p>

<p>In&nbsp;<em>As We Descend</em>, you'll be thrust "into an apocalyptic future to shape the fate of a submerging civilization at the end of the world". It'll be your job to oversee "a city on the edge of extinction" while also sending expeditions beyond the city's walls to see what lies in wait for you.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/as-we-descend-early-access-release-date-cards.jpg?itok=ZgghQKEo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/as-we-descend-early-access-release-date-cards.jpg?itok=27euRW1z 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>As We Descend&nbsp;</em>brings apocalyptic roguelike deckbuilding to Steam Early Access in March.</figcaption></figure><p>You'll be gathering resources to keep your city alive, all while navigating "feudal politics" and building relationships with those around you in order to compel them to your cause.</p>

<p>Beyond the city management aspect of&nbsp;<em>As We Descend</em>, it'll also offer "challenging card-based combat" for which you can recruit "a variety of squads with unique card sets and abilities", allowing for a number of different combinations and strategies.</p>

<p>Combat revolves around two different zones: the Guard Zone and the Support Zone. Switching your forces between both zones will allow you to dodge monster attacks and set up your defenses.</p>




<p>As you'd probably expect from a roguelike, death won't be the end in&nbsp;<em>As We Descend</em>, either. As the Steam page notes, failure will arm you with "new secrets", allowing you to "begin the next journey with new knowledge and tools".</p>

<p><em>As We Descend&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1769830/As_We_Descend/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a> on March 27th. The demo is live right now, and you can check it out until March 3rd, so make sure to give it a look if you're a fan of card battlers like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/slay-spire" rel="nofollow">Slay the Spire</a>&nbsp;</em>or city-builders like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/frostpunk" rel="nofollow"><em>Frostpunk</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro’s PEGI 18 rating in Europe has been changed following appeal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/618342/balatro-pegi-rating-appeal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro%E2%80%99s-pegi-18-rating-in-europe-has-been-changed-following-appeal.1117512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/618342/balatro-pegi-rating-appeal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Balatro</em>, the hit roguelike with poker imagery and poker hands but no actual gambling, no longer has a PEGI 18 rating in Europe following an appeal, <a href="https://pegi.info/news/pegi-complaints-board-amends-classifications-balatro-and-luck-be-landlord-pegi-12">PEGI announced today</a>.</p><p>LocalThunk, the creator of <em>Balatro</em>, has publicly <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/18/24324626/balatro-localthunk-18-plus-rating-europe-pegi">shared his frustrations the rating</a> — the game was originally given a PEGI 3 rating, but it was bumped to PEGI 18 shortly after its launch in February 2024 because of the game “contains prominent gambling imagery and material that instructs about gambling,” as explained <a href="https://x.com/PlaystackGames/status/1763614758043795909">by publisher Playstack</a>.</p><p>Now, <em>Balatro</em> will have a PEGI 12 rating following an appeal submitted by Sold Out Sales &amp; Marketing, which rebranded to Fireshine Games <a href="https://fireshinegames.co.uk/sold-out-sales-and-marketing-have-rebranded-as-fireshine-games/">in 2022</a> and publishes <em>Balatro’s</em> physical edition. “The Complaints Board concluded that, although the game explains the various hands of poker, the roguelike deck-building game contained mitigating fantastical elements that warranted a PEGI 12 rating,” PEGI says.</p><p>PEGI is also changing the PEGI 18 rating for <em>Luck Be A Landlord</em>, a roguelike with slot machine mechanics but similarly has no real-world gambling, to PEGI 12 an appeal submitted by Fangamer. “The Complaints Board reasoned that the same arguments as above applied: although the game features a slot machine mechanic, there were no specific transferable gambling skills and the game can therefore be rated PEGI 12.”</p><p>PEGI is going to make more classification criteria to address games with gambling imagery but that may not need the PEGI 18 rating. “At this moment, any teaching or glamorisation of simulated gambling automatically leads to a PEGI 18 rating,” PEGI says. “On the basis of these appeals, the PEGI Experts Group will develop a more granular set of classification criteria to handle gambling themes and the simulation, teaching and glamorisation of gambling in different age categories, which will now include 12 but also keep 18 as an age category for games that simulate gambling typically played in casinos and betting halls.</p><div><p>“This is a good step from PEGI”</p></div><p>“After an appeal from my publisher, Balatro has been reclassified by PEGI from 18 plus to 12 plus,” LocalThunk says <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/localthunk.bsky.social/post/3liwvjvlt622y">in a post on Bluesky</a>. “This is a good step from PEGI — bringing nuance to their ratings criteria that used to be 18 plus or nothing. I hope this change will allow developers to create without being unfairly punished.”</p><p>“Playstack is pleased to confirm the PEGI Complaints Board’s decision to reclassify Balatro to a PEGI 12 rating, following appeals from Playstack and our physical distributor, Fireshine Games,” Playstack communications director Wout van Halderen says in a statement to <em>The Verge</em>. “We applaud the PEGI Experts Group on their commitment to develop a more granular set of classification criteria as indie games continue to stretch into new ideas and concepts. We believe it is a sign of a healthy classification board that it evolves in line with cultural expectations and continue to ensure that audiences understand the type of content present in games.”</p><p>“I’m happy that PEGI finally made the right call here and lowered <em>Luck be a Landlord’s</em> age rating,” says Dan DiIorio, the solo game developer at TrampolineTales, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/trampolinetales.com/post/3liww64yvhc2a">in a post on Bluesky</a>. “I just hope that this sets a standard and other games are treated the same way <em>Balatro</em> and <em>Luck be a Landlord</em> were. Now give games with loot boxes (actual gambling) higher age ratings!”</p><p><em><strong>Update, February 24th</strong>: Added statements from LocalThunk, TrampolineTales’ Dan DiIorio, and a revised statement from Playstack.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s you versus yourself in the demo for roguelite clone-hunter DoubleWe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-you-versus-yourself-in-the-demo-for-roguelite-clone-hunter-doublewe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-you-versus-yourself-in-the-demo-for-roguelite-clone-hunter-doublewe.1117506/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/its-you-versus-yourself-in-the-demo-for-roguelite-clone-hunter-doublewe<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>This town ain’t big enough for the both of me</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/DoubleWe-Wishlisted.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/NightByte Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            
<p>I adore the premise of DoubleWe: you’re given a randomised appearance, dumped in a cramped sci-fi shithole full of dodgy-looking NPCs, and forced to find kill your identical clone before he can emerge from the crowd and shank you first. There’s a demo for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/event-brands/steam-next-fest">Steam Next Fest</a>, and it’s provoked in me some of the most pulse-quickening paranoia since the days of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dayz">DayZ</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>ID’ing the clone is, despite the ruffian density, usually the easy part. You have a mirror on you at all times, and the Evil You typically prefers to bide their time and blend in instead of rushing straight for the kill, so you have a few moments to memorise your doppelganger. Still, that window is better spent scrounging up a flimsy knife or one-shot pistol from weapon stashes. Rather than wrapping you in a comfort blanket of justifiable self-defence violence, however, arming yourself only serves to up the tension further.</p>
<p>Opening the stashes is agonisingly slow – my very first death came when the clone took advantage of my apparent difficulties with operating a briefcase – and the weapons themselves force you into close-range, all-or-nothing confrontations with an opponent who’s far less likely to miss their swing. Add in the general unease of how readily the clustered NPCs will stop to stare at you, plus the knowledge that DoubleWe’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelite</a> structure means failure will send you back to the start of a chapter, and each round becomes a deliciously mistrustful slice of shortform suspense. Even taking the time to stalk your own stalker at the beginning doesn’t help much, as stopping to grab a weapon is more than enough time for them to melt back into the throng, or to lurk behind the corners of a chokepoint. I ain’t walking though that doorway, man. The other me might be in there.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/DoubleWe-demo-crowd.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/NightByte Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That’s just the earliest encounters, too. After a few successful slayings, any hopes of settling down into more relaxed clone deathmatches are dashed by devious raisings of the stakes. First, officers are introduced to baton you senseless if they see you gearing up an attack, forcing you to either strike more swiftly or coax your pursuer into a quieter corner. Then, an anonymous assassin is dispatched to actively hunt you from the start, laying on even more pressure (and, if you decide to fight back, depleting your weapon uses) while forcing you to scan every single one of these blockheaded creeps for a telltale blade. I remain both intrigued and perturbed by the more overtly horror-flavoured antagonist variants that the final game will feature, including clones that explode into raging, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil-4-remake">Resident Evil 4</a>-style meat yuccas, though such monstrosities would be in keeping with DoubleWe’s taste for escalating threats.</p>
<p>I only rarely enjoy being scared in games, but I do crave a more sustained, eerie flavour of tension – it’s what made creeping through Chernogorsk, praying its snipers were watching elsewhere, such an electric thrill. DoubleWe manages to recreate and intensify that feeling in compact, minute-and-a-half bursts, and I’d dearly like to string myself out on more of them.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Promise Mascot Agency has a solution for the open world genre's most heinous crime]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-solution-for-the-open-world-genres-most-heinous-crime</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-solution-for-the-open-world-genres-most-heinous-crime.1117503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/promise-mascot-agency-has-a-solution-for-the-open-world-genres-most-heinous-crime<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/promise-mascot-agency-pink.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Kaizen Game Works</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585830/Promise_Mascot_Agency/">The demo</a> for Kaizen's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/promise-mascot-agency">Promise Mascot Agency</a> throws a lot of ideas you, but at its heart, it's just a game about being a good boss.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Stripped back, it's part <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> driving game, part business management. You pull up in the cursed town of Kaso-Machi, a broke yakuza with a sentient severed digit hanging out in the back of your grimy pickup truck.</p>
<p>You're here to make scratch helping the locals, so you'll need to recruit mascot creatures to hire out for jobs. They're a hopeless bunch, possessing all the neurotic animism you'd expect from distinctly 21st century yōkai. You're soon negotiating salaries and benefits with a giant block of perpetually weeping tofu. Then, enlisting the help of a traffic safety superhero to help out when jobs go south.</p>
<p>The tofu gets stuck in a door on their first job. To help out on the next, I pack them a lunch comprising a wilted hamburger from a vending machine. The tutorial missions dry up, so I open the map. It takes a moment to realise what I'm looking at. Or, rather, what I'm not.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Promise Mascot Agency Demo Trailer!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lHfm3II7U9A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Promise Mascot Agency Demo Trailer!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lHfm3II7U9A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lHfm3II7U9A?autoplay=1" title="Promise Mascot Agency Demo Trailer!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lHfm3II7U9A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Not a nagging map marker in sight, despite a menu telling me there are several tasks available. Promise Mascot Agency will only mark the activities available on your map if you explicity tell it to. You ask Pinky for hint, and choose the type of activity you fancy, whether that's recruiting new mascots, finding new jobs, or hiring more heroes. Once you ask - and only then - the game adds a pin showing where to find that type of task.</p>
<p>This is - if I'm using my academic ludology terms correctly - the good shit. An adrenaline shot for decision paralysis. A Marie Kondolance for our era's inescapable hellscape of cluttered landscapes. I have stared deep into the skittish eyes of the chattering mind monkey and sealed his lips together with Gorilla Glue, but not before <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tall/comments/1dlwkv3/til_heightmogging/">heightmogging</a> him with the gorilla on the label. Thank you, Promise Mascot Agency.</p>
<p>There's plenty more to love here. The town is run down and dusky, but the landscape flows in such a way that you can see the streetlights shoal together from a distance. Driving in from the outskirts feels like it does when you catch a taxi in from an airport; the rising swell of life and lights and noise despite a ghostly ambience. Dreamy, dark pop slows to a warped cassette crawl when you pause. I collect floating coins that each tell tiny stories with their confirmation pop ups. A wallet containing a shopping list with nothing crossed off. A thousand yen note used a bookmark. When I crash the car my <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-use-a-ps5-dualsense-controller-on-pc">DualSense</a> speaker starts yelling a cartoonish, clattering racket at me.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/promise-mascot-agency-town.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Kaizen Game Works/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A pack of ghostly foxes escape from a mechanic's garage while I'm chatting to him. I chase them for truck upgrades. The first gives me a cannon that lets me shoot Pinky at the remaining foxes. You can't leave your truck, which is tiny bit awkward in certain spots, but you can bunny hop and boost over difficult terrain. Your truck is invulnerable and I wholly believe the game wants you to drive like an idiot.</p>
<p>I think the tofu crying all the time is a reference to how irritating it is to drain tofu so you can grill it properly, although its mainly used here to humiliate the poor creature. Alongside the exploration, social, and management aspects, the other part of Promise Mascot Agency is card battles that take place when your mascots run into trouble on their jobs. They look like this:</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/promise-mascot-agency-door-battle.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Kaizen Game Works/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The demo is unfortunately timed, and I didn't get much of a chance to see how much depth the card game has, but the basic idea is that you use the cards of the heroes you've recruited to damage whatever obstacle you're up against like a boss battle. Run out of actions before you win, and you lose. It's perhaps the game's weakest aspect but again, I barely scratched the surface. Still, what's here is just as beautifully odd and oddly beautiful as you'd expect from Kaizen. It's due out this year, and I will make that tofu smile if it kills me.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Revolution Starts Now In Star Wars Andor's Explosive Season 2 Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-disney-death-star-trailer-s2-1851766160</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-revolution-starts-now-in-star-wars-andors-explosive-season-2-trailer.1117491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-disney-death-star-trailer-s2-1851766160<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="e57d5c9793140035d254fd7e482a4619" data-recommend-id="image://e57d5c9793140035d254fd7e482a4619" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Andor walks away as an explosive goes off. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Andor walks away as an explosive goes off. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e57d5c9793140035d254fd7e482a4619" data-recommend-id="image://e57d5c9793140035d254fd7e482a4619" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Andor walks away as an explosive goes off. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The best <em>Star Wars</em> TV show ever <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/andor-season-2-disney-plus-trailer-alien-earth-1851695650&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/andor-season-2-disney-plus-trailer-alien-earth-1851695650">returns in just a few months</a></span> and Disney has released a new teaser to celebrate. The <em>Andor </em>season 2 trailer shows that the rebellion is taking shape with more galaxy-spanning guerrilla warfare and the construction of the Death Star nearing completion. Also Diego Luna’s titular freedom fighter Cassian Andor briefly looking like the Count of Monte Cristo. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193897" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="418" data-playlist="193897,194499,196842" data-current="193897"><div><p>10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19360.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-release-date-disney-streaming-1851694453&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-andor-season-2-release-date-disney-streaming-1851694453"><em>Andor </em>season 2 starts streaming on Disney+ on April 22</a></span>, kicking off the beginning of the end for the most critically acclaimed bit of <em>Star Wars </em>media produced in the sci-fi franchise’s modern streaming era. The 12 episodes will be released in batches of three per week, breaking the final season into four chapters covering events spread across five years.</p><p> The show’s conclusion will lead directly into the events of <em>Star Wars: Rogue One</em> and the original trilogy, meaning prepare for some gnarly time jumps. But all you really need to know about the show is that it somehow both felt like prestige TV and authentically <em>Star Wars</em>. Here’s the new trailer:</p><p>“We’re in a war,” Cassian says at the beginning. “You want to fight? Or you wanna win?” The ominous advice suggests season 2 will ramp up the “ends justify the means” tension that took shape in season 1 as Cassian and company expand the scope of their insurrection against the empire to new fronts, from backroad trade routes to going undercover in the halls of political power. </p><p> “One of the great thrills of making <em>Andor </em>is the scale of the story and the number of characters we’re able to meet—ordinary people, Imperial overlords, passionate revolutionaries,” creator and showrunner&nbsp;Tony Gilroy <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/andor-season-2-teaser-trailer/#:~:text=The%20final%20season%20will%20unfold,subsequent%20chapters%20debuting%20each%20week.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/andor-season-2-teaser-trailer/#:~:text=The%20final%20season%20will%20unfold,subsequent%20chapters%20debuting%20each%20week." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote in an announcement today</a></span>. “They are real people making epic decisions, all of them staring down questions with terrifying consequences. Cassian’s journey is the soul and spine of our story, but it’s the choir that makes the show. I’m so excited for audiences to see where we go in Season 2.” </p><p>We also catch a harried Forest Whitaker returning as the battle-hardened Saw Gerrera trying to inspire new recruits, as well as Ben Mendelsohn showing up as weapons research director Orson Krennic, who’s overseeing the construction of the Death Star. Plus there’s a good number of things going “kaboom” and “pew-pew” across various elaborate and realistic-looking settings. It all looks quite expensive! Hopefully Gilroy and the rest of the creative and production teams can bring <em>Andor</em> in for the landing it deserves. And then we can all be sad that nothing <em>that</em> good might be made again in the <em>Star Wars</em> universe for quite some time...or ever. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ID@Xbox Showcase February 2025: Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/idxbox-showcase-february-2025-everything-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/id-xbox-showcase-february-2025-everything-announced.1117488/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/idxbox-showcase-february-2025-everything-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-92249">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>On Monday, February 24, Xbox held its ID@Xbox showcase for February 2025 in partnership with IGN. The show featured 21 upcoming Indie games that are either releasing soon or in active development. The showcase include new reveals, release date announcements, gameplay trailers, and more.</p>



<p>Games featured in this year’s show include 33 Immortals, Revenge of the Savage Planet, a new Tron game, Lies of P, Balatro, and Descenders Next. </p>



<p>You can check out everything that was announced during the event below. Be sure to let us know your thoughts on the showcase in the comments or join the discussion further in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming Forums</a>. It’s worth noting that everything is in the order it was shown. </p>



<h6>READ MORE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-interview-mecha-break-creator/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW: Mecha BREAK Creator Has Planned 3 Seasons Worth of New Mechs</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-everything-announced-at-id-xbox-showcase-for-february-2025">Everything Announced At ID@Xbox Showcase For February 2025</h2>



<p><strong>Revenge of the Savage Planet — Release Date</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Revenge of the Savage Planet - Official Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VzIwBczEdO8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Jump Ship</strong> <strong>– Early Access</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Jump Ship - Official Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/51LynAGQbHI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Echo Weaver </strong></p>



<figure><p>
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WTeFgJJQ6Jg
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault - Game Pass Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7mFHewrlgig?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Blue Prince</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Blue Prince Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Goj5usM4tGM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Outbound</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Outbound - Official Gameplay Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7pFcV-7cD3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Herdling</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Herdling - Official Gameplay Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/17kGVeGsHg8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Wax Heads</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Wax Heads - Official Gameplay Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FOacQhVbZKo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>The Lonesome Guild</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="The Lonesome Guild | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dQWc-2nEqNE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Buckshot Roulette</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Buckshot Roulette – Coming Soon to XBOX GamePass" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GiCH_b6LqdU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Hotel Barcelona</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="HOTEL BARCELONA Xbox Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zlwvY3Yw85U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Balatro (<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-game-pass-friends-of-jimbo-pack-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FULL STORY</a>)</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Balatro: Friends of Jimbo (Pack 4) - Official Reveal Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3tUJdI3AO9I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Rock Beasts</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="RockBeasts - Official Announcement Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sL25NjOVf7w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Ratatan</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Ratatan - Official Gameplay Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/63RmA6SOS-M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Tempopo</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Tempopo - Official Release Date Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WvuVEpT4870?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Woodo</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Woodo - Official Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gVb0BptxN6w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>TANUKI Pon’s Summer</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="TANUKI Pon's Summer – Arriving to XBOX Game Pass" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1jTyDuxVr-E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Descenders Next</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Descenders Next - Official Release Date Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fmOIBfu7eaI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Tron Catalyst</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="TRON: Catalyst - Official Release Date Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KWLBH5UK7A8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>33 Immortals</strong> <strong>(<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/33-immortals-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FULL STORY</a>)</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="33 Immortals - Official Early Access Release Date Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K0a_w1bk_uU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p><strong>Lies of P: Overture</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Lies of P: Overture - Official DLC Trailer | ID@Xbox" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C23aZR6Gr6g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-luck-be-a-landlord-win-pegi-ratings-appeals/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-luck-be-a-landlord-win-pegi-ratings-appeals/">Balatro, Luck Be A Landlord Win PEGI Ratings Appeals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Both Balatro and Luck Be A Landlord have won their PEGI rating appeals, bringing their PEGI rating to a lower level.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-ceo-says-company-will-train-new-ai-on-a-catalog-of-games/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-ceo-says-company-will-train-new-ai-on-a-catalog-of-games/">Microsoft CEO Says Company Will Train New AI On A “Catalog Of Games”</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella says that the company will begin training its new AI on a “catalog of games” with hopes of it playing them.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-players-want-to-filter-out-games-that-use-generative-ai/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-players-want-to-filter-out-games-that-use-generative-ai/">Steam Players Want To Filter Out Games That Use Generative AI</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Steam players have taken to the suggestion box requesting the ability to filter out video games made using generative AI.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-gameplay-leaked/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-gameplay-leaked/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Gameplay is Being Leaked Online as Early Copies Are Already in Players Hands</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Early physical copies of Assassin’s Creed Shadows have already found their way in players hands, resulting in early gameplay of the game being streamed and uploaded online.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW: Mecha BREAK Creator Has Planned 3 Seasons Worth of New Mechs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-interview-mecha-break-creator/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-interview-mecha-break-creator-has-planned-3-seasons-worth-of-new-mechs.1117485/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-interview-mecha-break-creator/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Mecha BREAK, a mecha-based third-person shooter from Amazing Seasun Games, is quickly picking up momentum during its Steam open beta. The game that features both 6v6 objective-based multiplayer matches and a PvPvE mode that combines extraction shooter with battle royale <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mecha-break-beta-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached 317,000 concurrent players during its first day</a>.</p>



<p>Just days before the start of the open beta, Insider Gaming was invited alongside other media to the developer’s North American office in Irvine, California. During the event, we got to try out the game’s tutorial, its 6v6 mode, and couple matches of the PvPvE mode, Mashmak.</p>



<p>We also got the chance to sit down with the company’s CEO and Mecha BREAK’s creator, Kris Kwok, to talk about the game’s audience, his unique approach to player feedback, and new content fans can expect over the next couple months. During the interview and during Kris’s earlier presentations, one thing became very clear: this is the game he’s always wanted to make.</p>



<h2 id="h-mecha-break-creator-kris-kwok-says-all-the-mecha-s-are-his-children">Mecha BREAK Creator Kris Kwok Says All The Mecha’s Are His “Children”</h2>



<p><em>The following interview has been edited slightly for clarity and length.</em></p>



<p><strong>IG: You said you’ve always wanted to make a mecha game. What challenges have arisen in trying to make a game that appeals to both mecha fans and the more general gaming audience?</strong></p>



<p>There’s two sides: I have an emotional drive to make this game, and a [more] rational side. At the very beginning, rationally speaking, we weren’t that confident about reaching out to non-mecha fans. Earlier on [around 2021], we were only aiming at the 6v6 mode, but what surprised us and gave us a confidence boost was that in China, which isn’t known as the capital of mecha fans, we still got about a million views within three days on one platform. The reason we’re so confident in the project is that the more we do, the more positive feedback we get.</p>



<p>On the emotional side of things, no matter how good the FPS you make [is], the main vehicle of expression is the person. You’re shooting as a human. So a lot of games, despite other features, kind of feel repetitive. So in this project, what we’re seeking is a novel experience: operating as a mecha to gain that differential from traditional shooter games.</p>



<p>We’re not aiming at a wider audience [by including an extraction shooter]. We would like to bring the experience of operating a mecha to people who like mecha and who like extraction shooters. We’re still serving the core audience of mecha fans first. So we’re doing what we’re good at, which is making the mecha gameplay good. If both [mecha and non-mecha] fans really like it, they’ll naturally introduce it to other people via word-of-mouth.</p>



<p><strong>IG: Mecha BREAK has undergone years of various testing periods. What piece of player feedback from those tests most heavily influenced the current state of the game?</strong></p>



<p>Technically speaking, if the world is behind in the sense that everybody’s running [with] a horse carriage, then they wouldn’t advise you to invent a car yet. They don’t know what they want. So, despite what [players] say, I’d much rather spend time watching <em>how </em>they play. I spent a lot of time watching players’ livestreams and replays. I’m almost addicted to people playing the games I’ve created. A lot of problems were discovered just by watching those replays. In general, players are adequate in providing bug feedback and accessibility feedback, [but] in terms of big visionary direction, they’re just not equipped.</p>



<p>At the beginning we only had 3v3 and 6v6, and could have gone into official launch last year. During a trip to Japan, I realized in the 3v3 and 6v6 matches that players tend not to communicate with each other. And every time they died they got really frustrated. That opens a space that the Japanese players really wanted: a PvE area where they can either solo it or play with a couple friends casually. That’s how we arrived at the decision to make Mashmak. Originally it was teams of six broken down into sub-squads of two or three, but they would get lost in the map very quickly. And with a team of six it’s even harder to coordinate. That’s why I emphasize observation over verbal feedback.</p>



<p><strong>IG: When you first play the tutorial, it almost feels like it’s setting up the story for a single player campaign? Was that something you ever considered for Mecha BREAK?</strong></p>



<div><p>“We don’t have any official plan to implement a campaign mode, yet. And we are probably not going to go into the traditional linear narration. Instead, most stories are told from fragmentary sources: you go into the Hangar, you interact with the NPCs and the world environment, learn about the lore, and you’ll get to do missions as special characters.</p><p><strong>IG: We were told you put hundreds of hours of playtime into each mecha. Which one is your favorite?</strong></p></div>



<p>Being not only the producer, but the designer of all the weapon and skill sets and ability designs of all the mechas: they are my children. So I can’t pick a favorite. It wouldn’t be fair. The best answer I can give you right now is who I play with more at any given time: whichever one is the weakest [at the time], that’s who I play the most.</p>



<p><strong>IG: How many more mechas do you have in the works? What’s the eventual roster size you want to see?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>During the initial rollout, we’re going to have 13 playable mechas, there are six other ones that are completely finished and ready to ship, and three more that are a work in progress. The rollout frequency will be about three mechs per season, so we’ve got the first three seasons reserved already. It’s hard to say how many in total the roster will be, but honestly, once you have more and more they’re likely going to have functional overlaps. But I’ll try my very best to provide different expressions, visually, control-wise, and mobility-wise.</p>



<p>Are you one of the thousands playing Mecha BREAK during the open beta? Let us know in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-multiplayer-skyrim-before-reboot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how close Avowed came to being a “multiplayer Skyrim.”</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Dev Successfully Appeals PEGI 18 Rating Over Simulated Gambling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/balatro-dev-successfully-appeals-pegi-18-rating-over-simulated-gambling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-dev-successfully-appeals-pegi-18-rating-over-simulated-gambling.1117482/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/balatro-dev-successfully-appeals-pegi-18-rating-over-simulated-gambling<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Thank those "mitigating fantastical elements".</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Last year, the publisher and developer of popular card game Balatro found themselves in an unusual argument with a ratings board after Balatro received an 18+ rating. But today, Balatro successfully won that appeal in Europe, earning itself a PEGI 12 rating and a lot more visibility on digital storefronts as a result.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This all started in March of 2024, shortly after the release of Balatro, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/balatro-devs-argue-poker-roguelike-does-not-encourage-gambling-as-it-vanishes-from-some-stores">players noticing the game missing from certain digital storefronts overseas</a> seemingly due to an unexpected change in its age rating post-launch. Per a post at the time by publisher Playstack, it received this rating  “due to a mistaken belief that the game ‘contains prominent gambling imagery and material that instructs about gambling.’” The PEGI 18 rating covers "depiction of gross violence, apparently motiveless killing, or violence towards defenceless characters. The glamorisation of the use of illegal drugs and of the simulation of gambling, and explicit sexual activity should also fall into this age category," per the PEGI website.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In December, the PEGI ratings board <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/roguelike/pegi-digs-its-heels-in-over-balatros-18-rating-according-to-its-disappointed-dev-blaming-eu-laws-blaming-storefronts-waiting-for-the-future/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dug in on the 18+ rating</a>, despite Balatro not involving any actual gambling. At the time, developer LocalThunk called out PEGI for inconsistencies, pointing out that games like EA Sports FC (with heavy microtransactions and randomized elements) had a 3+ rating.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But today, the PEGI ratings board announced it has releneted and reduced the age rating of Balatro from PEGI 18 to PEGI 12 after a successful appeal. "The Complaints Board concluded that, although the game explains the various hands of poker, the roguelike deck-building game contained mitigating fantastical elements that warranted a PEGI 12 rating," <a href="https://pegi.info/news/pegi-complaints-board-amends-classifications-balatro-and-luck-be-landlord-pegi-12" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reads the announcement on the PEGI website</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Update 10:15am PT: </strong>Following this news, LocalThunk shared the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/localthunk.bsky.social/post/3liwvjvlt622y" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">following statement on Bluesky</a>: "After an appeal from my publisher, Balatro has been reclassified by PEGI from 18+ to 12+. This is a good step from PEGI - bringing nuance to their ratings criteria that used to be 18+ or nothing. I hope this change will allow developers to create without being unfairly punished."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Original story continues below:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the same decision, PEGI also changed the PEGI 18 rating for the game Luck Be a Landlord to PEGI 12 for the same reasons - it has a slot machine mechanic, but it's a roguelike deck builder and there are no "specific transferable gambling skills" involved.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Going forward, PEGI will reconsider how it evaluates simulated gambling. As the board states:</p><blockquote>At this moment, any teaching or glamorisation of simulated gambling automatically leads to a PEGI 18 rating. On the basis of these appeals, the PEGI Experts Group will develop a more granular set of classification criteria to handle gambling themes and the simulation, teaching and glamorisation of gambling in different age categories, which will now include 12 but also keep 18 as an age category for games that simulate gambling typically played in casinos and betting halls.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Balatro is currently available on all major platforms, though in the 35 regions that use PEGI ratings, it was often not immediately visible on digital storefronts due to the PEGI 18 rating. This seems likely to change in light of the recent decision. In the United States, Balatro is rated E for Everyone 10+ by the ESRB.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>