<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 11:29:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New open world action-RPG Silver Palace is about playing detective and curb-stomping demons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-open-world-action-rpg-silver-palace-is-about-playing-detective-and-curb-stomping-demons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-open-world-action-rpg-silver-palace-is-about-playing-detective-and-curb-stomping-demons.1187739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-open-world-action-rpg-silver-palace-is-about-playing-detective-and-curb-stomping-demons<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I don't remember Baker Street having this many harpies</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Elementa</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I have a narcissistic recurring daydream that consists of teleporting historical celebrities into the present so that I can show them bits of 21st century technology and absolutely blow their tiny, primordial minds.</p>
<p>"This deceptively pocket-sized contraption is a trillion times more powerful than your silly adding machines," I would tell Charles Babbage, brandishing my smashed Google Pixel phone. "Did the Wright Flyer have wifi?" I would ask Wilbur and Orville, pushing their faces against the window of a 747. "Put this in your pipe and smoke it," I would tell Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, menacing him with the trailer for Silver Palace, a new open world action-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> from Chinese developers Silver Studio and publishers Elementa, which is notionally set in a Victorian metropolis.</p><!--more-->
<p>Silver Palace's Victorian metropolis has red phoneboxes, elegantly appointed trams, top hats, clocktowers, detectives and ballgowns. I imagine Sir Arthur Conan Doyle could just about keep pace with all that, though he might object to the plunging necklines and the overall loudness of the colour scheme.</p>
<p>But then I would show him the angel-winged anime girls, the power-drifting panther steeds, the neck-snapping finishers, the real-time character-swapping, the demons pretending to people who must be exposed using magic profiling functionality. "Why don't your Sherlock Holmes stories have glide mechanics?" I would sternly enquire of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, as he curled up sobbing into his hands.</p>
<p>Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's one psychic defence would be to point out that his Sherlock Holmes stories don't contain any gacha mechanics, this being a curse peculiar to our so-called modern age. Fine, Doyle, I'll let you have that one. It's not clear what Silver Palace's gacha elements involve, but here's 11 minutes of gameplay overview to give you a sense of the whole.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Silver Palace Gameplay Showcase" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EIUa74hDJiQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Silver Palace Gameplay Showcase</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EIUa74hDJiQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EIUa74hDJiQ?autoplay=1" title="Silver Palace Gameplay Showcase">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EIUa74hDJiQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Some press release blurb to finish: Silver Palace is the tale of Silvernia, a city powered by the "revolutionary element" of Silverium. You are a Detective who must delve into a shady world of corporate monopolies, underground syndicates, and hidden monsters. It runs on Unreal Engine 5, and will be free-to-play.  There's no release date as yet.</p>
<p>I can take or leave the overclocked character designs but I do like the looks of that urban backdrop. Hopefully the open world element is pronounced enough to allow for a Crackdown-style collectathon. Also please may I have some kind of Watson, Silver Studio? Is that catgirl maid the equivalent of Watson in Silver Palace, and if so, can you please make her as creepy as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-you-played-sherlock-holmes-the-awakened-2007">Creepy Watson</a> in Frogwares' games?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerA OPS V3 Pro Wireless Controller Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review.1187727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/powera-ops-v3-pro-wireless-controller-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>PowerA are asking a very specific question with the OPS V3 Pro Wireless Controller – how much RGB is too much RGB? That is, admittedly, a flippant introduction to a controller that sits at the top end of PowerA’s lineup, boasting wireless and wired play for PC and cloud gaming, Hall Effect sensors, mechanical switches, six additional inputs and a magnetic charging base, but when you turn it on, you’ll find that you’re holding one of the brightest, most colourful controllers. Ever.</p>
<p><iframe title="PowerA OPS v3 Pro Wireless Controller for PC and Cloud Gaming with Lumectra" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YauMt7AqZo0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>I’m going to deal with the RGB first, as it is genuinely the overarching first impression that this controller gives. Branded with their in-house Lumectra lighting, an RGB strip runs around the perimeter of the OPS, while there’s further RGB lighting around the analogue sticks, the D-pad and each of the four main face buttons. Personally, I think it looks pretty great, though the width of the lighting around each button feels a little bit too wide. Whatever the case, this is a controller that you won’t miss, and especially not in a darkened room.</p>


<p>There is thankfully a lighting button on the back of the controller that lets you turn the effects on and off, as well as tinker with the colourways and lighting, but this is not the most intuitive implementation I’ve ever seen. Part of that is due to the multiple zones of lighting, with several different areas that you can alter, and even when you know what buttons you’re supposed to press, it’s overly fussy to remember it all. That said, you can create some spectacular effects, with each area blending into the next and giving you lots of different combinations. I opted for blue and yellow, and every time I turned it on I was left impressed by the overall look.</p>
<p>Well, I did until the OPS V3 ‘forgot’ my settings, defaulting to pure green a couple of times during my review period. You can fix it using the manual controls, but I imagine there is a point where you will give up and stop readjusting it, even if it doesn’t match your mouse and keyboard anymore.</p>


<p>Beyond the eye-catching lighting effects, the OPS V3 Pro belongs to the school of official Xbox controllers, with the overarching form being nigh-on identical to Microsoft’s timeless creation, and with its two Hall Effect sticks laid out asymmetrically. They feel great in use – taut and precise – and rather than offer the option of different height caps, you can twist each stick into a higher or lower position, giving you extra precision when you want it, and the ability to quickly make adjustments.</p>
<p>The OPS V3 Pro is constructed from solid-feeling black plastic, with texturised grips built into the bottom of each grip. They feel tactile, and grippy, but I did notice an alarming amount of dust and grime building up in them in only a short amount of time. You can clean it easily with a damp cloth, without causing any damage to the internals, but it’s a strange phenomenon that I’ve not seen happen so readily with other controllers. If dust and grime gives you the ick, maybe steer clear.</p>
<p>The stars of the OPS V3 are the mechanical face buttons, shoulder buttons and D-pad. They feel and sound stunning to use, giving you such an immediate response that you can’t help but be delighted with them. I’ve been playing a heap of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/08/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-review/">Revenge of the Savage Planet</a> with this gamepad, and all of the platforming and alien combat felt spectacularly tuned in. Returning to Overwatch 2 also showed that the OPS V3 has some competitive chops, and I never once felt that a death was the result of my equipment, rather that it was helping me to get the drop on unsuspecting foes.</p>
<p>That’s helped by the OPS V3’s copious amount of additional inputs. Besides the expected, Xbox-esque main controls, there are six programmable buttons to aid you in whatever fight you’re involved in. Four of them sit in the expected places beneath your fingers as you grip the controller, and they’re of a good size and substantial activation to balance ease of use while avoiding accidental presses.</p>

<p>They’re joined by the unusual placement of two further buttons on the top of the controller, alongside the triggers and beneath the extended reach of the shoulder buttons. Once you’re used to them being there, I actually found these to be the most intuitive and easiest of the extra inputs to use, and thanks to the Program button on the rear of the controller you can change them – and any of the other additional buttons – up at a moment’s notice.</p>
<p>My one disappointment with all of these is that they lack the same mechanical switches found in the main buttons. It makes them feel like a downgrade, though I expect that fewer people use these extra buttons compared to the central inputs, and it’s part of PowerA’s attempts to keep the controller’s price down.</p>
<p>The final, and perhaps key, inclusion is trigger lockouts. In my opinion, all controllers need these, and PowerA have opted for a stepped setup that lets you choose from three different trigger input lengths. Once again, they don’t have mechanical activations at the end as we’ve seen with the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/gamesir-cyclone-2-controller-review/">Gamesir Cyclone</a>, but they’re certainly swift enough, aided no doubt by the magnetic Hall Effect sensors running the show.</p>
<p>The OPS V3 has three different connection modes, with the wired or RF receiver options for PC and Bluetooth for mobile platforms. It’s a real shame that the OPS V3 isn’t certified for Nintendo Switch as well, limiting it compared to some of its key rivals, and also because it’s a well-made, enjoyable controller to use.</p>

<p>The OPS V3 also includes a charging station with a USB-A socket for the RF dongle to sit in. I love this sort of functionality, and anything that makes it easy to keep your peripherals charged is a clear win. However, it’s so small and light, that it just comes away with the controller, and you have to yank it off each time. It’s hardly a problem, but compared to the Gamesir Super Nova or Cyclone, it’s a far more workmanlike solution rather than something to display your fancy new controller.</p>
<p>At £99.99, the OPS V3 straddles the line between affordability and becoming a true premium option, and with its wealth of extra inputs and cool lighting it’ll be a great choice for many players. That said, its feature set puts it in direct competition with Gamesir’s Super Nova and Cyclone, both of which offer more value for money, a better stand, and are overall more comfortable to use.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve are expanding the Steam Deck Verified system to cover future SteamOS devices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-are-expanding-the-steam-deck-verified-system-to-cover-future-steamos-devices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-are-expanding-the-steam-deck-verified-system-to-cover-future-steamos-devices.1187724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-are-expanding-the-steam-deck-verified-system-to-cover-future-steamos-devices<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Starting with the Lenovo Legion Go S</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Lenovo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a> owners will be familiar with the practice of peering into a new game’s Steam store page and hoping, begging, praying to whatever god is yet to abandon this cruel joke of a reality that it has a little green tick mark on it. This is, of course, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview">Steam Deck Verified programme</a>, wherein Valve gives good behaviour stickers to games that function fully on their handheld PC.</p>
<p>Soon, this system – so often a source of relief and disappointment – will be expanded, with a view to rating games for compatibility with SteamOS as a whole. As the <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/532097310616717411">announcement post</a> explains, that’s because the first non-Steam Deck SteamOS handheld, a new version of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/behold-the-lenovo-legion-go-s-the-steamos-handheld-pc-that-isnt-a-steam-deck">Lenovo Legion Go S</a>, is launching soon, with the possibility of more in the future.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Valve’s compatibility testing staff presumably can’t try out every game on every possible SteamOS device, no matter how many wheeled desks they can roll into the office, as it's an open-source operating system that could feasibly run on any desktop or laptop. But they can, and apparently will, use data gleaned from their existing Steam Deck Verified testing to determine whether a game has or avoids problems with the OS in particular, subsequently rating it as either SteamOS Compatible or SteamOS Unsupported. With a nice blue tick for the former, aww. As with the current system’s Verified/Playable/Unsupported ratings, these will appear on store game pages and in the Steam libraries of anyone playing on a non-Steam Deck SteamOS PC.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Lenovo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"We expect over 18,000 titles on Steam to be marked SteamOS Compatible out of the gate," sayeth the post. While these specific new categories don’t take framerate performance or control input functionality into account, as the Steam Deck ratings do, they should at least let you know if certain games are literal non-starters. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> seems due a SteamOS Unsupported tag, for instance, after it <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-have-killed-apex-legends-steam-deck-support-in-the-name-of-anti-cheat">binned Linux support last year</a>.</p>
<p>I haven’t tried the Legion Go S yet, and our adoptive cousins at <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lenovo-legion-go-s-review">Ian Games Network</a> weren’t especially impressed with the Windows edition. But the current state of play among portable PCs definitely has SteamOS above Windows 11 as the more usable, comfortable, lightweight, and stable OS. One that’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-and-use-lutris-on-the-steam-deck">surprisingly</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-epic-games-launcher-on-steam-deck">capable</a> of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-minecraft-on-steam-deck">running</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-battlenet-on-steam-deck">non-Steam</a> games, too. As such, I’ll happily get on board with anything that both makes SteamOS patronship slightly easier and might encourage future handheld manufacturers to switch over. Valve expect as much, writing that "the only other officially supported device running SteamOS is Lenovo Legion Go S, but we see this expanding to more devices in the future."</p>
<p>Exciting times, then, if the concept of the Steam Deck has caught your eye but you’d rather wait and see what other hardware makers can do with a baggable form factor <em>and</em> Valve’s own OS. All that being said, one new, lower-spec handheld does not a sea change make, and the recently leaked <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/here-are-some-leaked-images-of-an-xbox-branded-handheld-and-the-asus-rog-ally-2">Asus ROG Ally 2</a> looks to remain so tied up in Microsoft’s ecosystem that there’s a separate Xbox-branded version of it. Bet it doesn’t have tiny colourful ticks, mind.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade PC Release Date, Features, New Boss Fight, and 25 New Outfits Revealed by Leaked Sony Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-pc-release-date-features-new-boss-fight-and-25-new-outfits-revealed-by-leaked-sony-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blade-pc-release-date-features-new-boss-fight-and-25-new-outfits-revealed-by-leaked-sony-trailer.1187718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-pc-release-date-features-new-boss-fight-and-25-new-outfits-revealed-by-leaked-sony-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The PC version of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stellar-blade">Stellar Blade</a> launches via Steam on June 11 along a raft of PC-specific features, a trailer leaked by Sony itself has revealed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The trailer, published by Sony Interactive Entertainment on the PlayStation YouTube channel before it was removed, also revealed a Complete Edition of Shift Up’s popular PS5 action game. As you’d expect, the internet captured the trailer, which we expect will be released officially soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Complete Edition includes the base game and all the DLC released so far for both PS5 and PC. The news comes over a year after Stellar Blade’s successful April 2024 launch on PS5.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Stellar Blade has all the features you’d expect on PC, including AI upscaling via Nvidia DLSS 4 and AMD FSR 3, an unlocked framerate, Japanese and Chinese voiceover, ultrawide display support, higher resolution environment textures, and DualSense support for haptic feedback and trigger effects.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, the trailer reveals a new boss battle vs Mann, Leader of the Sentinels, and 25 new costumes, which we presume will also be made available on PS5. Players have also noticed that, at the end of the trailer, Eve lets go of a memory stick — a sequence that isn't in the base game. Some are now speculating Stellar Blade is set for a new ending or maybe even DLC.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/13/qua2wq8-1747125726116.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The trailer reveals the Stellar Blade Complete Edition, coming to PC and PS5.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Stellar Blade was a big hit for Korean developer Shift Up, bringing in $43 million in royalties in its last financial year. It expects the PC version to outsell the PS5 version, which sold more than 1 million copies in two months. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-developer-shift-up-considering-a-sequel"><u>Shift Up has said it's considering making another game in the franchise</u></a>, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Stellar Blade sees players take on the role of Eve as she battles against unknown invaders to reclaim Earth in fast paced action role-playing game combat. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-review"><u>It earned a 7/10 in IGN's review</u></a> and proved popular otherwise, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-exclusive-stellar-blade-sells-1-million-copies"><u>quickly selling a million copies</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Stellar Blade is great in all of the most important ways for an action game, but dull characters, a lackluster story, and several frustrating elements of its RPG mechanics prevent it from soaring along with the best of the genre," we said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 sales forecast not affected by production or tariffs, Nintendo reiterates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-sales-forecast-not-affected-by-production-or-tariffs-nintendo-reiterates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-sales-forecast-not-affected-by-production-or-tariffs-nintendo-reiterates.1187712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-sales-forecast-not-affected-by-production-or-tariffs-nintendo-reiterates<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>But price adjustments will be considered.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a> production capacity and US tariffs didn't factor into sales predictions Nintendo said, as its forecasts were criticised by investors for being conservative.</p>
<p>Following its latest financial report where Nintendo predicted <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-predicts-switch-2-will-outsell-its-predecessor-at-launch-despite-demand-exceeding-expectations">Switch 2 sales would slightly outsell its predecessor</a>, multiple investors probed the company on why it hadn't estimated higher sales during a <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250509e.pdf">Q&amp;A</a>.</p>
<p>"We are forecasting Nintendo Switch 2 hardware sales of 15m units for this fiscal year," said Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa. "We set this figure with the aim of reaching the same level of sales we achieved with Nintendo Switch in the roughly 10-month period between its launch in March 2017 and December that year."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The "limits of our hardware production capacity were not a factor" in setting the sales volume forecast, he continued, and "the tariff situation in the US or a possibility of a recession did not affect our sales volume forecast either".</p>
<p>"Our first goal is to get off to the same start we did with Nintendo Switch, and we are working to strengthen our production capacity so we can respond flexibly to demand," said Furukawa.</p>
<p>In a follow-up question, the president continued: "We recognise the positive feedback from the Nintendo Switch 2 Experience events and the situation with applications for randomly selected drawings for pre-orders on My Nintendo Store in Japan. But the Nintendo Switch 2 hardware is priced relatively high compared to Nintendo Switch, so even if there is momentum around the launch, we know it will not be easy to keep that momentum going over the long term through the holiday season and beyond.</p>
<p>"We have been working to ramp up Nintendo Switch 2 hardware production since even before we held the Nintendo Switch 2 Experience events and began My Nintendo Store applications. Our sales volume forecast was not determined based on any limit to production capacity."</p>
<p>Demand for the Switch 2 in Japan in particular has far exceeded expectations - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-admits-switch-2-demand-far-exceeds-expectations-in-japan-as-company-president-offers-stark-warning-over-stock">Furukawa previously warned of stock issues</a>.</p>
<p>Nintendo predicted 45m sales of software in its financial report, but Furukawa noted this figure does not include <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> units bundled with the console. Including these units, software sales are expected to surpass the 52m units sold for the original Switch. This is partly due to the "more robust lineup" at launch than the previous console.</p>
<p>Further, Furukawa stated the forecast was calculated maintaining current US tariff rates throughout the fiscal year. This has, however, resulted in a "negative impact of several tens of billions of yen at the profit level". The Switch 2 hardware also has a lower profit margin compared to the original Switch.</p>
<p>Should tariffs change, the company will consider price adjustments accordingly.</p>
<p>"Our basic policy is that for any country or region, if tariffs are imposed, we recognise them as a part of the cost and incorporate them into the price," said Furukawa. "However, this year marks our first new dedicated video game system launch in eight years, so given our unique situation, our priority is to maintain the momentum of our platforms, which is extremely important for our dedicated video game platform business, and to rapidly expand the install base of our new hardware. Consequently, if the assumptions on tariffs change, we will consider what kind of price adjustments would be appropriate, taking into account various factors such as the market conditions."</p>
<p>Furukawa's comments <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-says-tariffs-werent-factored-into-switch-2-price-but-its-something-were-going-to-have-to-address">echo those of Nintendo of America boss Doug Bowser</a>, who admitted tariffs were "something we're going to have to address".</p>
<p>Later, Furukawa also commented on the increased price of hardware and software compared to the previous console.</p>
<p>"When determining hardware prices, we consider not only the manufacturing cost, but also various factors such as consumers' impression of the price, the vast differences in exchange rates compared to the Nintendo Switch launch, and the market conditions in each region," said Furukawa.</p>
<p>"For software, in addition to the same factors, we also take into account rises in costs, due to aspects such as increased game file size and extended development periods, when determining price.</p>
<p>"Going forward, we will continue to consider appropriate prices for each title when it comes to software prices. Hardware involves special factors such as tariffs, and we will take into account factors like those we have just described, while conducting careful and repeated deliberations when determining price."</p>
<p>Bowser previously stated the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-responds-to-mario-kart-world-bumper-7580-cost">higher price tag for Mario Kart World was an example of "variable pricing"</a> and was not establishing a more expensive "benchmark".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy is holding an FBC: Firebreak technical test this weekend – sign ups now open]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-sign-ups-now-open/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-%E2%80%93-sign-ups-now-open.1187703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/remedy-is-holding-an-fbc-firebreak-technical-test-this-weekend-sign-ups-now-open/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Remedy Entertainment has announced an <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a> Closed Technical Test for this coming weekend, bringing the public in to stress test and play the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/control">Control</a> co-op shooter spin-off.</p>
<p>Available across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC with cross-play enabled, the FBC: Firebreak Closed Technical Test will run from May 15th, 6AM PDT/9AM EDT/2PM BST/4PM EEST, until May 19th, 1:59PM PDT/4:59PM EDT/9:59PM BST/11:59PM EEST.</p>


<p>You can <a href="https://firebreak.firstlook.gg/signup/tech-test-may-2025">sign up to take part here</a>.</p>
<p>However, it should be noted that this is a closed test and Remedy are not allowing public sharing of impressions, screenshots, videos or live streaming. Discussions will be limited to an area of the official Discord server.</p>
<p>The technical test will help Remedy smooth out kinks in the matchmaking and balance for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/fbc-firebreak-release-date-confirmed-for-june/">the game’s full launch next month</a>. Aiming to get as large an intake of invited participants as possible, the tech test will have two of the Jobs in the game,&nbsp;Paper Chase and Ground Control, and access to three of the kits with all equipment unlocked – Garden Gnome, Teapot, and Piggybank – and three of the guns.</p>

<p>For PC players, the system requirements that Remedy are pushing at this time are:</p>
<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10 64-bit</li>
<li>Processor: Ryzen 7 3700X or equivalent</li>
<li>Memory: 16GB RAM</li>
<li>Graphics: GeForce RTX 2080 Ti</li>
</ul>
<p>For more details, Remedy has shared <a href="https://firebreak.firstlook.gg/static/faq">a closed technical test FAQ</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a> is launching on 17th June, dropping onto PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam and Epic at that time. It will also be available day one via PC Game Pass, Game Pass Ultimate, and the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog (Extra and Premium).</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2272540/eventcomments/597400564876236928?snr=1_5_9_">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City Remastered in UE5 Gets Surprise Launch Today; Frogwares Promises Big Things for the Franchise]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-surprise-launch-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-remastered-in-ue5-gets-surprise-launch-today-frogwares-promises-big-things-for-the-franchise.1187700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-surprise-launch-today/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ukrainian game developer Frogwares&nbsp;<span>surprised its fans today with the sudden launch of&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-unreal-engine-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Sinking City Remastered</a> on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. Even better, the game is free for owners of the original, and newcomers can purchase it at a 50% discount price ($24.99 on console, $19.99 on PC) for a few days.</span></p>
<p>This remaster leverages Unreal Engine 5 technology to improve the original game's visuals in various ways, as you can see in the trailer below. There are even some gameplay tweaks. Here's the complete list of improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li><span>The game is fully relit in Unreal Engine 5</span></li>
<li><span>Enhanced locations with additional levels of detail and objects</span></li>
<li><span>4K textures and improved reflections</span></li>
<li><span>Photo Mode</span></li>
<li><span>Support for DLSS, FSR, and TSR upscaling</span></li>
<li><span>Various gameplay adjustments, certain accessibility features, and more</span></li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Sergiy Oganesyan, Publishing Director at Frogwares, teased 'big things' for the franchise:</p>
<p><em>We plan to do big things with The Sinking City IP, starting with the sequel and then beyond. So, after our rather well-known struggles with the original, it feels amazing to have this positive moment be part of the game’s twisted history and for us to be the ones to fully decide it. Making it free to all our existing fans is our way of giving back to them for having supported us all this time through thick and thin.</em></p>
<p>Less than two months ago, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-qa-frogwares-on-renewed-combat-focus-ue5-switch-and-continued-war-impact/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> an exclusive interview with Sergiy Oganesyan on The Sinking City 2. The sequel was funded through Kickstarter with $627K in pledges, which was 450% of the minimum target set by Frogwares. As a reminder, The Sinking City 2 will be a full-fledged survival horror game with greater emphasis on combat. However, Frogwares plans to maintain the investigation mechanics as an optional bonus feature that will make life in the game easier for those who choose to engage with it.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City Remastered gets a surprise launch with a 50% discount on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch-with-a-50-discount-on-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch-with-a-50-discount-on-steam.1187697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch-with-a-50-discount-on-steam<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Surprise tentacles are without a doubt the worst kind of tentacles, except in a couple of very specific cases. Fried squid at a pot luck? Sure. Come in, my friend. Benevolent kraken helping you out of an aquatic pickle by lifting you safely to shore? Thank you, Kraken. I will fry you last. Frogwares surprise launching a remaster of Lovecraftian <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-adventure-games">adventure game</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-sinking-city">The Sinking City</a> with a free upgrade to existing owners and a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/750130/The_Sinking_City_Remastered/">50% discount on Steam</a> for everyone else? I'll fry you second to last, Frogwares. Find a comparison trailer below.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Sinking City Remastered - Official Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3CpG0rMZqg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Sinking City Remastered - Official Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3CpG0rMZqg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o3CpG0rMZqg?autoplay=1" title="The Sinking City Remastered - Official Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3CpG0rMZqg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Originally made in Unreal Engine 4, the remaster has been built in UE5, with a few quality-of-life features bundled in. Read them why don't you:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Game fully relit in Unreal Engine 5</li>
<li>Enhanced locations with additional levels of detail and objects</li>
<li>4K textures and improved reflections</li>
<li>Photo Mode</li>
<li>Support for DLSS, FSR and TSR upscaling</li>
<li>Various gameplay adjustments, certain accessibility features and more</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Originally released in 2019, Frogwares gained <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frogwares-regain-control-of-the-sinking-city-but-all-old-saves-will-break-soon">full publishing rights to The Sinking City</a> last year following a legal battle with Nacon over royalties and funding, including allegations that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sinking-city-devs-claim-publisher-pirated-the-game-to-release-it-on-steam">Nacon had pirated the game</a>. Frogwares are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frogwares-reveal-wet-survival-horror-sequel-the-sinking-city-2-taking-the-dev-in-a-newer-direction-in-2025">now working on a sequel</a>, which is slated for release sometime this year.</p>
<p>Alice Bell (RPS in peace) wasn't convinced by The Sinking City's take on Lovecraft or clumsy racism allegories <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sinking-city-review-pc">in her review</a>, but thought the game worked well enough otherwise, calling it "a slightly janky, slightly grindy detective game that does some interesting things in a very atmospheric depiction of a profoundly depressed town".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade PC will release on 11th June, according to leaked trailer montage of technical improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellar-blade-pc-will-release-on-11th-june-according-to-leaked-trailer-montage-of-technical-improvements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blade-pc-will-release-on-11th-june-according-to-leaked-trailer-montage-of-technical-improvements.1187685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellar-blade-pc-will-release-on-11th-june-according-to-leaked-trailer-montage-of-technical-improvements<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation Publishing LLC</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stellar-blade">Stellar Blade</a> - the apparently very good third-person action extravaganza with a heroine who definitely only dresses like that because she's comfortable with her sexuality and besides, bunny girl outfits are lightweight and tactically efficient - will launch on 11th June, according to a new trailer. PlayStation appear to have posted the trailer early in a classic case of marketing butterfingers. They've now removed the video, but somebody from Reddit has <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/stellarblade/comments/1kkza3w/someone_made_an_oopsie_pc_trailer_june_11th/">preserved and uploaded it</a> as an everlasting monument to Sony's shame.</p> <!--more-->
<p>The video walks us through a few of the PC version's new bells, whistles and features, including AI frame generation, higher resolutions, a bunch of bonus outfits, Japanese and Chinese voiceovers, a new boss fight, and ultrawide display support for players who are secretly owls with the ability to rotate their head almost 360 degrees. It all seems very swish. I like the spangly blocking effects.</p>
<p>The PC version of Stellar Blade was confirmed in February, at which time <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jiggle-powered-apparently-decent-action-game-stellar-blade-confirmed-for-pc-release-in-june">I wrote a little about the console version's popularity/infamy among internet sexists</a>. To recap: this is very much an experience for people who like looking at shiny bottoms and wobbling chests. It also sounds like an accomplished graduate of Combo, Parry And Fishing Minigame University that deserves a lot of the praise it has received. Ah, history abhors a paradox.</p>
<p>I don't, personally, object to anybody wanting to look at a shiny bottom, providing their enthusiasm for shiny bottoms doesn't metastasise into e.g. the argument that Western civilisation is doomed thanks to a chronic dearth of bikini armour in Assassin's Creed. Anyway, we'll possibly have something less slapdash to say on the subject in June.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City Remastered is available right now!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now.1187667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/13/the-sinking-city-remastered-is-available-right-now/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Sinking City Remastered has been given a surprise launch by Frogwares, who have made the game available today for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/31/the-sinking-city-remastered-announced/">The Sinking City Remastered&nbsp;</a>was announced at the end of March, along with confirmation that owners of the original release for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S would get this upgrade for free.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>”We plan to do big things with The Sinking City IP, starting with the sequel and then beyond. So, after our rather well-known struggles with the original, it feels amazing to have this positive moment be part of the game’s twisted history and for us to be the ones to fully decide it. Making it free to all our existing fans is our way of giving back to them for having supported us all this time through thick and thin.</em>”, said Sergiy Oganesyan, Publishing Director at Frogwares.</p>
<p>The Sinking City Remastered sees the original game remade in Unreal Engine 5, adding enhanced details to environments and objects. The game has 4K textures and an added photo mode so you can zoom in and check the details for yourself. There is also support f<span>or DLSS, FSR and TSR upscaling, as well as new accessibility options.</span></p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/06/27/the-sinking-city-review/">The Sinking City Review</a></h2>
<p>In our The Sinking City review, Steve said,<em>&nbsp;“The Sinking City promises a nightmarish journey through a Lovecraftian townscape filled with monsters and threatening cults, but too often falls into a loop of forced combat and resource hunting. The investigative parts are excellent, and this is probably the best Lovecrat adaptation since Call of Cthulu: Dark Corners of the Earth, but it still never really lives up to its potential. Close, but no Shoggoth.”</em></p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/03/06/the-sinking-city-2-has-gone-full-on-horror-coming-out-in-2025/">The Sinking City 2</a> was announced last year with a release window of 2025, with some funding coming from a Kickstarter. The final amount raised in the Kickstarter was 553,100 euros, way above the target of 100,000 euros.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silver Palace Is a New Victorian-Inspired F2P Open World Gacha Game Powered by UE5]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/silver-palace-is-a-new-victorian-inspired-f2p-open-world-gacha-game-powered-by-ue5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silver-palace-is-a-new-victorian-inspired-f2p-open-world-gacha-game-powered-by-ue5.1187664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/silver-palace-is-a-new-victorian-inspired-f2p-open-world-gacha-game-powered-by-ue5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Silver Studio and Elementa have unveiled a new free-to-play open world gacha game called Silver Palace. Powered by Unreal Engine 5, the game features a rather refreshing Victorian era-inspired setting, albeit still with the anime-like art style we've previously seen in games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/genshin-impact-will-soon-require-age-verification-in-the-united-states/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genshin Impact</a>. The game is being developed for PC, console, and mobile devices, and the combination of the reveal trailer and 10-plus-minute-long gameplay showcase has already shown quite a bit.</p>
<p><iframe title="Silver Palace Trailer | The Golden Age of Detectives" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ELC4r7fbKEQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Additionally, Silver Studio also shared a detailed overview of the features and content:</p>
<p><em>Silver Palace is a brand-new ARPG set in a prosperous metropolis with a Victorian aesthetic. It features an engaging story, a delicate art style, distinctive characters, and a dynamic, action-oriented combat system. Players will play the role of a “Detective” and embark on an adventure with a diverse group of partners to defeat the unknown enemies and unravel the mysteries in Silvernia, an industrialized metropolis built on the power of Silverium.</em></p>
<p><em>The discovery of Silverium was the key to Silvernia’s industrialization. This revolutionary element transformed technology and daily life beyond imagination, attracting numerous residents and fostering innovation. The city became a hub of miracles, driven by the massive industrialization and monetization of Silverlum under the city’s administration.</em></p>
<p><em>In Silver Palace, players assume the role of a “Detective” tasked with investigating crimes and uncovering hidden truths. As various factions—from corporate monopolies and underground syndicates to royal affiliates and cults – vie for control of Silverium, tensions rise across the city.</em></p>
<p><em>Players can switch between characters in real time to unleash powerful skills and chain QTE combos. As they explore the city’s sprawling environments, they’ll dive into the scenes of crime, hunt for clues in the shadow, battle their enemies and in the process reveal more of the stories of Silvernia.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Silver Palace Gameplay Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EIUa74hDJiQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Pre-registration for PC and mobile devices (which will likely launch before consoles, as usual with these games) can be submitted <a href="https://silverpalace.elementagames.com/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the official game website</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Communists attacked the Wild West" for booze in shooter RPG Chambers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers.1187661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/communists-attacked-the-wild-west-for-booze-in-shooter-rpg-chambers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Mr. Pink/JFJ</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> cup likely runneth over this month with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a> (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-the-dark-ages-review">unless you've got good taste</a>. Nah, I'm just messing. It's alright) but if you'd like a top up, spare a thought for the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2437570/Chambers/">early access release</a> of "comedic RPG shooter" <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chambers">Chambers</a>. It's from Mr. Pink and JFJ, the former of which made Golden Light, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-worlds-most-disgusting-fps-golden-light-is-free-for-the-next-hour-only">which Edwin called "the world's most disgusting FPS"</a>. Have you the read the Maw? Do you know how much it takes to disgust Edwin? Here's a little looksee.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Chambers Early Access Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Chambers Early Access Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iovhzY955zM?autoplay=1" title="Chambers Early Access Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iovhzY955zM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Not a shield in sight. Just old time, good time, down home rocket communists riding flying machines made of revolver parts, cannibalism, and a "hookshot-hat". Bafflingly, the trailer does not show the hookshot-hat, but I respect the restraint.</p>
<p>The west has been torn apart by the great War For Booze, and your once-idyllic family life has been shattered. So, you hop on your horse and set off to do some gun violence at communists over a series of open sandbox levels. Here are some features:</p>
<p>(Also, here's a grammar question for you, the discerning nitpicker. I always want write to "here's some features" but that's technically not correct because there's multiple features, but "here are some features" just feels so unnecessarily drawn out I want to expire and crumble into dust before I reach the end of the sentence. It's a bloody conundrum, it is! Little insight into the tortuous struggle I experience in the daily process of sausage making, there.)</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Story driven adventure set in open sandbox-like levels.</li>
<li>Dynamic slapstick combat.</li>
<li>Equipment system with upgradeable weapons and clothing.</li>
<li>Trading and cooking systems.</li>
<li>First person rolling, bullet catching, kicking, hookshot-hat, cannibalism, drinking booze and puking.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>The description of "dynamic slapstick combat" puts me in mind of Blendo Games' recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skin-deep">Skin Deep</a>. I read something the other day about how one of the purposes of narrative design is to make the things you do in games seem less weird and stupid, but I'm a supporter of leaning into the opposite. I'm also reading Blood Meridian for the first time at the moment, and feel this would make an incredibly incongruent but just similar enough companion piece to make both experiences much stupider.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City Remastered now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-sinking-city-remastered-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-remastered-now-available.1187652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-sinking-city-remastered-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A surprise release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Open-world detective thriller <em><a title="Games > The Sinking City Remastered [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-sinking-city-remastered">The Sinking City Remastered</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,455 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,187 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,117 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, developer <a title="Companies > Frogwares [36 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/frogwares">Frogwares</a> announced. It is a free upgrade to all existing owners of <em>The Sinking City</em> on those platforms. <span id="more-964691"></span></p><p>“We plan to do big things with <em>The Sinking City</em> [intellectual property], starting with the sequel and then beyond,” said Frogwares publishing director Sergiy Oganesyan in a press release. “So, after our rather well-known struggles with the original, it feels amazing to have this positive moment be part of the game’s twisted history and for us to be the ones to fully decide it. Making it free to all our existing fans is our way of giving back to them for having supported us all this time through thick and thin.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Frogwares:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Originally released in June 2019 and developed on Unreal Engine 4, the upcoming remaster is being built in Unreal Engine 5 and promises an upgraded visual experience alongside some requested quality-of-life features. The core additions to the remaster include:</p><ul><li>Game fully relit in Unreal Engine 5.</li><li><a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d locations with additional levels of detail and objects.</li><li>4K textures and improved reflections.</li><li>Addition of a Photo Mode.</li><li>Support for DLSS, FSR, and TSR upscaling.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Sinking City Remastered - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agkU47W0ZyI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spooky detective spruce-up The Sinking City Remastered gets a surprise launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/spooky-detective-spruce-up-the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spooky-detective-spruce-up-the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch.1187646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/spooky-detective-spruce-up-the-sinking-city-remastered-gets-a-surprise-launch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>And a free upgrade for existing players.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Frogwares</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sinking-city">The Sinking City</a> Remastered - the Unreal Engine 5 spruce-up of developer Frogwares' 2019 Lovecraft-inspired detective adventure - has slithered out of its tenebrous seclusion sooner than expected, and is available now for PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X/S.
</p>
<p>
For the uninitiated, The Sinking City tells the story of troubled private investigator Charles Reed as he travels to the supernaturally flooded city of Oakmont, Massachusetts, in search of a way to quell his hellish visions. There's a bit of gunplay as the cosmic horror begins to take hold, but mostly it's a game of exploration and investigation, playing out across a series of open-ended cases and the titular open world.
</p>
<p>
All that's true of The Sinking City Remastered, of course, but Frogwares is also promising an "upgraded visual experience alongside some requested quality-of-life features". There's talk of enhanced and fully relit locations with additional levels of detail and objects, for instance, alongside 4K textures, improved reflections, "various" gameplay adjustments, and new accessibility features. There's also a photo mode and, on PC at least, support for the likes of DLSS, FSR and TSR upscaling.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NEoQxVMzBEg?autoplay=1" title="The Sinking City Remastered - Comparison &amp; Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Sinking City Remastered comparison trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NEoQxVMzBEg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
To mark The Sinking City Remastered's arrival, Frogwares has released a new trailer showcasing some of the differences between the 2019 original and its new Unreal Engine 5 update. And if that's got you in the mood for some eldritch adventuring, The Sinking City Remastered gets its digital release today on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/750130/The_Sinking_City_Remastered/">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP5205-PPSA01772_00-TSCUA00000000004">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-gb/games/store/the-sinking-city-remastered/9p3xq5qwlfjj">Xbox Series X/S</a> - and it'll be available as a free upgrade for all existing owners.
</p>
<p>
Frogwares' remaster comes ahead of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sinking-city-2">The Sinking City 2</a>, which was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sinking-city-2-gets-first-gameplay-trailer-smashes-crowdfunding-goal-in-less-than-a-day">successfully crowdfunded on Kickstarter</a> earlier this year. The sequel is again set in 1920s America, but this time sees players exploring the flooded streets and crumbling buildings of Arkham in an survival horror-style adventure said to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sinking-city-2-will-pivot-to-a-horror-focus">shift away from the deduction focus of its predecessor</a> in favour of combat and exploration.
</p>
<p>
All this activity follows Frogwares' <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/frogwares-now-sole-publisher-of-the-sinking-city-following-dispute-with-nacon">lengthy dispute with publisher Nacon</a> over the rights to the original The Sinking City. Since a resolution was last year, the studio has taken over as The Sinking City's publisher, updated the Steam build, and released new DLC. The Ukrainian studio also found time to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/frogwares-remaking-sherlock-holmes-and-cthulhu-crossover-the-awakened">crowdfund and release 2023's Sherlock Holmes: The Awakened</a>, as it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sherlock-holmes-developer-frogwares-shares-update-on-life-in-ukraine-amid-ongoing-war-with-russia">continued to adjust to life during Russia's ongoing invasion</a>.
</p>
<p>
"We plan to do big things with The Sinking City IP, starting with the sequel and then beyond," Frogwares publishing director Sergiy Oganesyan wrote in a statement accompanying today's remaster news. "So, after our rather well-known struggles with the original, it feels amazing to have this positive moment be part of the game's twisted history and for us to be the ones to fully decide it. Making it free to all our existing fans is our way of giving back to them for having supported us all this time through thick and thin."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon renews Fallout for third season, six months before second arrives]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-renews-fallout-for-third-season-six-months-before-second-arrives</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-renews-fallout-for-third-season-six-months-before-second-arrives.1187643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-renews-fallout-for-third-season-six-months-before-second-arrives<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The Fallout TV series has already been renewed for a third season on Amazon Prime.
</p>
<p>
That's despite the show's second season still being months away - and indeed, we now know Fallout's next batch of episodes will debut in December 2025.
</p>
<p>
More than 100 million people have watched Fallout's first season to date, Amazon has revealed (thanks, <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/fallout-renewed-season-3-release-date-season-2-1236394393/">Variety</a>), making it one of the streamer's top three launches ever.
</p>
<p>
Amazon is now moving quickly to make more of the show, and begin teasing its second batch of episodes with another longing look at the Las Vegas skyline at the end of the below trailer.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout Season 2 Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout Season 2 Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" title="Fallout Season 2 Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Fallout season two teaser.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tu5EN8V35JM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
This video, released for Amazon's Upfront event, sees a pre-Ghoul Walton Goggins getting pitched advertising campaigns for various products (it's a humorous nod to Upfront itself, where Amazon seeks marketing pitches from brands). And yes - that is Amy Acker, AKA Fred from Angel! More of her character please.
</p>
<p>"We are absolutely thrilled that our global Prime Video customers will be able to delve deeper into the wonderfully surreal and captivating world of Fallout," said Amazon TV boss Vernon Sanders paying tribute to the show's writing and production teams. "Together with our amazing partners at Bethesda Games and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bethesda">Bethesda Softworks</a>, we are delighted to announce a third season of Fallout, well ahead of the much-anticipated debut of season two."</p>
<p>Over the weekend, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-show-could-run-for-five-six-seasons-says-actor">Fallout actor Aaron Moten revealed that he expected the show to run for "five, six" seasons</a> in total.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout TV Series Renewed for Third Season; Second Season Gets December Release Window and First New Vegas Teaser]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-series-renewed-for-third-season-second-season-gets-december-release-window-and-first-teaser/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-tv-series-renewed-for-third-season-second-season-gets-december-release-window-and-first-new-vegas-teaser.1187634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-series-renewed-for-third-season-second-season-gets-december-release-window-and-first-teaser/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Just yesterday, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-tv-show-could-run-for-5-6-seasons-says-lead-cast-member/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that lead cast actor Aaron Moten expects the Amazon Prime Video Fallout TV series to last five or six seasons, based on conversations with the showrunners. A few hours later, Amazon officially renewed the show for a third season, while also announcing that the second season will air on Prime Video this December.</p>
<p>Vernon Sanders, global head of television at Amazon MGM Studios, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>We are absolutely thrilled that our global Prime Video customers will be able to delve deeper into the wonderfully surreal and captivating world of Fallout. Jonah Nolan, Lisa Joy, Geneva Robertson-Dworet, and Graham Wagner have done an exceptional job bringing this beloved video game franchise to vivid life on Prime Video. Together with our amazing partners at Bethesda Games and Bethesda Softworks, we are delighted to announce a third season of Fallout, well ahead of the much-anticipated debut of Season Two.</em></p>
<p>Fallout TV series executive producers Jonathan Nolan and Lisa Joy stated:</p>
<p><em>The holidays came a little early this year – we are thrilled to be ending the world all over again for a third season of Fallout. On behalf of our brilliant cast and crew, our showrunners Geneva and Graham, and our partners at Bethesda, we’re grateful to our incredible collaborators at Amazon MGM Studios and to the amazing fans as we continue our adventures in the wasteland together.</em></p>
<p>Showrunners Geneva Robertson-Dworet and Graham Wagner added:</p>
<p><em>We’re so grateful to have survived the apocalypse for another season! Thanks to the incredible team — our whole cast and crew, Kilter, and Amazon.</em></p>
<p>The news came at Amazon Prime Video's Upfront presentation, which was held yesterday at New York’s Beacon Theater. As befitting such an announcement, we also got a season two teaser that you can see below, providing us with the first look at New Vegas in the Fallout TV series.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout Season 2 Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As a reminder, the Fallout TV series takes place around fifteen years after the events seen in Fallout: New Vegas, and the showrunners have already clarified that fans of the game will see a much-changed location. Still, there's little doubt that the debut of season two will once again see the fan-favorite game skyrocket up the most-played charts.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 doesn't require reflexes, says player who beat the game without dodges or parries]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries.1187631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-doesnt-require-reflexes-says-player-who-beat-the-game-without-dodges-or-parries<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Despite the hype, this is not Elden Ring."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Kepler Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yes, yes, I'm opting for the scoundrel's gambit and reporting on a Reddit post. Of a self-imposed challenge run, no less! But I <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">adored the bejeezus</a> out of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, and figured this was worth sharing in case it convinces a couple of you to give it a go. Redditor HunterIV4 has <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/expedition33/comments/1ki94qi/can_you_beat_the_game_without_dodging_yes_part_2/">chronicled their journey</a> to beat the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> without dodging, parrying, or even using the powerful gradient parries, in a bid to show that Sekiro reflexes aren't as crucial to success as they might seem. Thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/clair-obscur-player-tanks-their-way-through-the-entire-game-without-dodging-or-parrying-to-prove-a-point-you-can-finish-it-without-gamer-reflexes/">cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wWGIakhqr5g?autoplay=1" title="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Official Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wWGIakhqr5g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Tackling the game's story mode, HunterIV4 took the approach of bumping up their party's health as much as possible. It sounds like they had a fairly easy time through the game's first act, although they had to focus more heavily on effective builds for the latter portion. Personally, I enjoyed the buildcraft in Clair Obscur so much it's been a little disheartening to see it overshadowed by the Sekiro comparisons and what not. I do think this is partially a quirk of the design, since you can technically make the character building meaningless by just getting very good at button pressing. Still: good to hear that it does have the capacity to play like a more traditional turn-base 'em up.</p>
<p>HunterIV4 ended the second of their two posts with screenshots of both final bosses beaten with zero parries or  dodges. "Don't let concerns about a 'hardcore' experience prevent you from playing this awesome game and experiencing the story first-hand," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/expedition33/comments/1kfc7mz/no_dodgeparry_an_experiment_and_what_to_do_if_you/">they wrote</a>. "Despite the hype, this is not <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>."</p>
<p>Granted, this doesn't sound like the best way to experience the game - Act I took them much longer that they'd have like, apparently. But, hopefully it's tempted a few more of you to join the cult of Esquie's magnificent ass. The time of the airship is over, now is the age of the dump truck.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade out on PC next month, according to leaked trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-out-on-pc-next-month-according-to-leaked-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blade-out-on-pc-next-month-according-to-leaked-trailer.1187625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-out-on-pc-next-month-according-to-leaked-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-guides-tips-tricks-9430">Stellar Blade</a> will release on PC next month, according to a trailer posted too early on the PlayStation YouTube channel and since removed.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-gets-confirmed-pc-release-and-goddess-of-victory-nikke-dlc">PC version of the action game was announced back in February</a> but without a full date. Now we know it will launch on 11th June across Steam and the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p>The PC version will come with a number of extras, including an unlocked framerate, higher resolution environment textures, DLSS 4 and FSR 3, ultrawide monitor support, and more.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Stellar Blade x Goddess of Victory - Nikke DLC Trailer | PS5 and PC Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2uKLuMd4S4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Stellar Blade x Goddess of Victory - Nikke DLC Trailer | PS5 and PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2uKLuMd4S4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A2uKLuMd4S4?autoplay=1" title="Stellar Blade x Goddess of Victory - Nikke DLC Trailer | PS5 and PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Stellar Blade x Goddess of Victory - Nikke DLC Trailer | PS5 and PC Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A2uKLuMd4S4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, there will be a new boss fight against cyber warrior Mann, as well as 25 new costumes for protagonist Eve.</p>
<p>Additional content from the console release will likely be included, like the NieR: Automata DLC and photo mode.</p>
<p>More DLC based on Shift Up's other big franchise Goddess of Victory: Nikke is also set to arrive on console alongside the PC release (and presumably on PC too), though it's not part of the leaked trailer - but is in the trailer above.</p>
<p>Shift Up stated in a financial report from February it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blades-pc-sales-expected-to-exceed-console-says-shift-up">expects the PC version to exceed console sales</a>.</p>
<p>"In the AAA game market, PC devices have a higher market share than consoles, so we expect the performance of the PC version to exceed that of the console version," the company said. "We are particularly observing trends such as the significant expansion of the single-player action game market in the Asian gaming industry."</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-stellar-blade-on-ps5-pro-a-simple-but-hugely-effective-upgrade">game received a PS5 Pro patch</a> in time for the new console's release, which Digital Foundry described as a "hugely effective upgrade". Soon we'll be able to see how the PC version compares.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>