<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 14:44:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Real-Time Combat Mod Now Allows Party To Get Involved]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-real-time-combat-mod-now-allows-party-to-get-involved/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-real-time-combat-mod-now-allows-party-to-get-involved.994377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-real-time-combat-mod-now-allows-party-to-get-involved/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Since the release of Patch 7 for Baldur's Gate 3, the modding scene has been inundated with new projects, as Patch 7 saw the release of the official modding toolkit. As previously covered, one particular modder named <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@tinybike" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tinybike</a> is working on turning the combat into <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-modder-working-on-real-time-combat-mod/">real-time combat</a>. Originally, they shared a video of how their progress was coming along, and it only showed the main character facing off against an enemy with no sort of party in sight.</p>
<p>There have been many new mods released for Baldur's Gate 3, as well as many being showcased as they are in production. This includes mods such as making new maps, and taking players to lands such as Avernus. This particular mod has been in production since the toolkit came out, and tinybike has released a new YouTube video that shows off the mod in detail, and how the mod has evolved since last time.</p>
<p><iframe title="Real time combat test 3 - companions &amp; timers (Baldur's Gate 3)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C0FBQknd0mU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In the description of the one-minute video, TinyBike stated that this was a "very rough draft" and started testing out the companion and ally AI battles in a new campaign on Balanced difficulty. While they've said that this is a rough draft, it still seems rather detailed and actually allows cutscenes to happen without the possibility of imminent death while you're trying to have a conversation. However, the video does take place on the Nautiloid, which doesn't exactly harbor a ton of danger. In the video, the combat is incredibly fast-paced and chaotic, with enemies dying quickly.</p>
<p>"Many people have commented that combat seems really imbalanced, which is 100% true," they stated in a previous test video also posted on their YouTube. Even in the latest test video, this also seems to be true, as combat seems to be swayed in your team's favor. In a previous test video, tinybike commented, saying, "The main challenge right now is that the built-in BG3 combat AI is only accessible during turn-based combat. Just to test things out, I'm using some simple handrolled 'AI' logic, but I suspect this won't work well for more complicated encounters."</p>
<p>The beginning combats are relatively simple to some of the ones that players encounter later on, where it's possible to end up in combat with up to twenty enemies at once. Of course, it only gets harder once you change the difficulty, which would most likely add some extra complications to coding a project as big as this. The project is progressing nicely, but features like multiple attacks, stealth, and initiative all need to be added to this mod.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors Studio Poncle Moves Into Publishing]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-survivors-studio-poncle-publishing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-studio-poncle-moves-into-publishing.994374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-survivors-studio-poncle-publishing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Vampire Survivors&nbsp;</em>developer Poncle has announced that it's opening a publishing wing, but it sounds like the indie studio doesn't want to do things the way most traditional publishers do.</p>
<p>Speaking at an investor and publisher event in Liverpool in the UK yesterday (<a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/vampire-survivor-developer-poncle-opens-publishing-arm" rel="noopener" target="_blank">via GamesIndustry.biz</a>), Poncle says that although it's moving into publishing, it doesn't "want IP" in the same way most publishers do.</p>
<p>Instead, Poncle wants to allow developers to "make their games", with the emphasis on "their"; the studio says it wants, in GI.biz writer Vikki Blake's words, to "work more as a label or fund" rather than as a publisher in the traditional sense.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/poncle-vampire-survivors-publisher-gameplay.jpg?itok=UVYz61Sp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/poncle-vampire-survivors-publisher-gameplay.jpg?itok=CiIn3jRt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Vampire Survivors&nbsp;</em>dev Poncle is branching out into publishing.</figcaption></figure><p>Poncle says it's looking for games made with "sincerity, passion, and depth", according to the GI.biz report. It'll offer those games support for funding, platforms, localization, and more, as well as development advice.</p>
<p>Additionally, Poncle wants to offer its signings marketing support, helping them to create what Poncle says will be "replayable, affordable, and fun" games, akin to the philosophy that birthed&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>.</p>
<p>However, Poncle also says it doesn't want to sign <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathfinder-gallowspire-survivors-10-release-date">"Survivor-like" games</a>; that's one of the studio's "insta-nos", so if you've got a&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>-<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/temtem-swarm-announced-mashing-together-pokemon-like-creatures-and-survivors-style">esque game</a> to pitch, you might want to look elsewhere.</p>
<p>The newly-minted publisher's other major no-nos include Web3 games, as well as anything that uses generative AI and any kind of free-to-play mobile game. It sounds like Poncle's publishing heart is very much in the right place.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/soulstone-survivors-gameplay.jpg?itok=l75cprht 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/soulstone-survivors-gameplay.jpg?itok=AxQaScjW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Got a&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>-style game to pitch? Don't pitch it to Poncle's new publishing wing.</figcaption></figure><p>Poncle has yet to announce what its first major publishing project will be, but in the meantime,&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors&nbsp;</em>is still very much firing on all cylinders.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://x.com/poncle_vampire/status/1838926583823831488" rel="noopener" target="_blank">major update "that no-one knows about" for the game</a> is in the works, and&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors&nbsp;</em>is also getting the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/vampire-survivors-getting-animated-tv-show" rel="noopener" target="_blank">animated series treatment</a>, although I'm not entirely sure how production company Story Kitchen is going to handle this one. We'll have to wait and see, I suppose.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K: Space Marine 2 Update Fixes Its Most Annoying Mission]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-patch-3-0-chaos-arena-1851659411</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-update-fixes-its-most-annoying-mission.994368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-patch-3-0-chaos-arena-1851659411<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Warhammer 4o,000: Space Marine 2</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/space-marine-2-warhammer-40k-review-how-long-review-ps5-1851639029&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/space-marine-2-warhammer-40k-review-how-long-review-ps5-1851639029">is full of high points</a></span>, but one of the lowest comes very early on. The end of the Operation I: Skyfire mission has you defending artillery cannons against swarms of Gargoyles, and it can be a real pain in the ass. The sci-fi shooter’s latest update should change that. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197260" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Agatha All Along Star Sasheer Zamata On Witchcraft And Star Trek" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="348" data-playlist="197260,197209,196923" data-current="197260"><div><p>Agatha All Along Star Sasheer Zamata On Witchcraft And Star Trek</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197260/197260_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197260/197260_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197260/197260_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197260/197260_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22805.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The mission takes you from trench warfare against the Tyranids on the surface of Kadaku up through a sprawling megastructure until you’re on the roof, repelling aerial attacks to secure the planet’s last line of defense. It’s a great introduction to the flow of the game and a spectacular reveal once you reach the skies and see them flooded with the Gargoyle brood. </p><p>But then you’re tasked with defending four of the targeting beacons from multiple swarms and a ground assault while your brothers in arms stare at their space marine  boots. It’s an unexpected difficulty spike in a game that’s mostly about the simple joys of carving up mob after mob of brutal alien hordes, at least if you’re playing solo with AI-controlled allies. </p><p>Fortunately, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2183900/view/4696781406109497749&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2183900/view/4696781406109497749" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Space Marine 2</em>'s Patch 3.0</a></span>, released on September 26, addresses this as well as a bunch of other things in the game. In addition to the PVP Sparring Arena, private matchmaking, and ultrawide support on PC, the update tinkers a lot with the AI bots that accompany you during the campaign in single-player. The biggest change is that your space marine brothers will more aggressively aid your during fights without stealing too much glory for themselves:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Various inhibiting restrictions were lifted, allowing bots to be more helpful and effective, while still not beating the game for the player</li><li>Bots will now help focus-firing zoanthropes when the player attacks them.</li><li>Heavily eased restrictions on bots finishing of enemies instead of leaving them for the player, to reduce annoyance.</li><li><strong>Bots are now allowed to help with Gargoyle objectives</strong></li><li>Fixed a variety of bugs related to bots getting stuck</li><li>Fixed a bug where bots can run out of ammo on weapons without a magazine</li></ul></blockquote><p>While this has consequences for the entire campaign, the developers at Saber Interactive specifically call out the Gargoyle objectives. Previously, the AI bots would follow you around and hang back even when the health bar on one of the towers was plunging to zero. Now, they’ll actually join in the fight, similar to if you were playing with real humans. It’s also interesting to see the restriction “heavily eased” on bots finishing off enemies. Brutal finishers are a way to quickly restore your character’s shield in the middle of a tense fight. I’ll be curious to see if that becomes harder with the renewed bloodlust of the bots. </p><p>The rest of the patch deals primarily with bugs and map fixes. It also improves the customization options for dressing up your marine. Operations Mode spawns for Chaos enemies have been nerfed a lot as well, though elsewhere, enemies like the Hive Tyrant have been made more difficult in the regular campaign. A lot more content is on the way for<em> Space Marine 2</em>,<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;http:// https://kotaku.com/space-marine-2-faq-pvp-spawns-servers-veteran-co-op-1851652630&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http:// https://kotaku.com/space-marine-2-faq-pvp-spawns-servers-veteran-co-op-1851652630" target="_blank"> including new classes</a></span>, but for now this looks like a nice set of tweaks.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy Entertainment Gets €15 Million Loan From Tencent]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-gets-e15-million-loan-from-tencent/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-entertainment-gets-%E2%82%AC15-million-loan-from-tencent.994365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-gets-e15-million-loan-from-tencent/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Remedy Entertainment, the developers behind Control and Alana Wake, have entered a loan agreement with Tencent for €15 million ($16.76 million). </p>



<p>The announcement comes <a href="https://news.cision.com/remedy-entertainment-oyj/r/inside-information--remedy-enters-into-a-eur-15-million-convertible-loan-agreement-with-tencent,c4043667" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via press release</a> from Remedy on Friday morning. It’s a move that Remedy CEO Tero Virtala says allows the company to move forward with development of games as well as self-publish future titles.</p>



<h6 id="h-related-remedy-partners-with-annapurna-to-bring-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television">RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-partner-annapurna-control-alan-wake/">Remedy Partners With Annapurna To Bring Control and Alan Wake To Film and Television</a></h6>



<p>“Part of Remedy’s long-term strategy has been to strengthen our position in the value chain, to have more control over how our games are commercialized, and to grow our share of the value these games can create,” he said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“As we move towards self-publishing, this financing will support us in developing and fully realizing the potential of the games we have in development and successfully carrying out the commercial activities of our next self-published games. Tencent’s investment demonstrates strong confidence in Remedy’s long-term vision and strategy.”</p>



<p>Remedy currently has a number of games in development, including Control 2 and Control spin-off game Project Condor. The studio is also working on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/control-2-is-now-playable-as-max-payne-1-2-remake-enters-full-production/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Max Payne 1 &amp; 2 remake</a> that is in full production.</p>



<p>The convertible loan agreement carries an 8% annual non-cash interest rate that will convert at €27.2($30.40) per share. The price will allow the loan to be converted up to 811,100 new Remedy shares. That represents roughly 5.98% of all shares in the company.</p>



<p>Tencent currently owns 15% of Remedy.</p>



<p>What do you think of Remedy getting a loan from Tencent? Let us know in the comments below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about Blizzard, once again, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-starcraft-shooter-in-development-at-blizzard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working on a StarCraft shooter</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Warzone Fans Up in Arms Over Playlist Consolidation Ahead of Black Ops 6 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-fans-up-in-arms-over-playlist-consolidation-ahead-of-black-ops-6-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-warzone-fans-up-in-arms-over-playlist-consolidation-ahead-of-black-ops-6-launch.994362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-fans-up-in-arms-over-playlist-consolidation-ahead-of-black-ops-6-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Activision has been accused of “butchering” the playlists available for battle royale Warzone after developer Raven Software announced a consolidation ahead of the release of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a>.</p><p>Warzone typically rotates different modes, squad sizes, and even maps every week, much to the annoyance of some fans who just want to play the battle royale in their favorite way, or with a specific number of friends.</p><p>With Black Ops 6’s release just a few weeks away, <a href="https://x.com/RavenSoftware/status/1839349500017861077" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raven announced</a> it’s making “preparations” for the future of Warzone. As part of that, has consolidated the current playlist selection into the following:</p><p> • Battle Royale Solos &amp; Quads</p><p> • Resurgence Duos &amp; Quads</p><p>Plunder, Bootcamp, and active Limited-Time Modes will remain available, and Trios will continue to be available via Ranked Play, with the current season ending on Thursday, October 17.</p><p>However, it’s what Warzone has lost, rather than what it now has, that has sparked a backlash from fans, with Duos and Trios no longer available in Battle Royale mode, and Solos and Trios unavailable in Resurgence.</p><p>This means that from now until at least the launch of Black Ops 6 on October 25, Urikztsan (the current Battle Royale map) only supports Solos, Quads, and Plunder Quads, and Resurgence has a Duos and Quads map rotation, with Trios available in Ranked Play only via Rebirth Island (by far the smallest map in the game).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>It’s fair to say this announcement has sparked a backlash from Warzone’s hardcore community. “This might be one of the worst decisions I’ve ever seen,” said YouTuber Westie. “You’re essentially sunsetting core branches of your game and giving no real explanation at the time the change is being made.</p><p>“Some added context/information would be wonderful.”</p><p>Here’s some more reaction:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">There is no Way hahahahah</p>— James - JGOD (@JGODYT) <a href="https://twitter.com/JGODYT/status/1839350258339631537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Black Ops 6 isn’t even out you don’t have to butcher the playlists till it drops lil bro🙏😭</p>— HunterTV☄️ (@itsHunterTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/itsHunterTV/status/1839350382679773642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just say you dont want us to play Warzone till BO6 drops… this is hilarious</p>— Chris (@STYLERZ97) <a href="https://twitter.com/STYLERZ97/status/1839358649078362262?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I’m 100% positive people would rather wait 5 minutes to get into a trios or duos than be forced to play quads man down or with randoms. Worst decision I’ve ever seen. Sheesh.</p>— Ral (@Rallied) <a href="https://twitter.com/Rallied/status/1839360922349097070?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">RIP to the social media guy posting this who had zero influence over this decision 😭 <a href="https://t.co/KwmvHqz3gd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/KwmvHqz3gd</a></p>— Isaac (@IceManIsaac) <a href="https://twitter.com/IceManIsaac/status/1839354342027211162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Raven has yet to offer an explanation for its decision, but some are speculating it has to do with a need to maintain fast-filling lobbies amid a perceived shrinking playerbase. Players are also wondering why Raven namechecked the release of Black Ops 6 in its announcement — Warzone is set to incorporate the upcoming shooter’s mechanics, weapons, and gear into the game, but there’s no explanation for why this would require a playlist consolidation.</p><p>For now, Warzone players have no choice but to play with this new, consolidated playlist offering, or, as some are threatening, quit until their favorite ways to play return.</p><p>Last month, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/verdansk-is-finally-returning-to-call-of-duty-warzone-and-fans-are-delighted">Activision announced that Warzone is bringing back the map that started it all, Verdansk, in spring 2025</a>. Verdansk is the most beloved map in Warzone’s four-year history, and it returns to the battle royale complete with iconic points of interest such as Stadium, the Train Station, and Superstore. Fans are now hoping their favorite playlists will be available in time for Verdansk’s release.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI LIMIT limited-time demo launches October 14]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/ai-limit-limited-time-demo-launches-october-14</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-limit-limited-time-demo-launches-october-14.994359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/ai-limit-limited-time-demo-launches-october-14<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play through the entire first level of the game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > CE-Asia [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ce-asia">CE-Asia</a> and developer <a title="Companies > SenseGames [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sensegames">SenseGames</a> will release a limited-time demo for <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,354 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > AI LIMIT [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ai-limit">AI LIMIT</a></em> from <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241014T1700" rel="noopener" target="_blank">October 14 at 10:00 a.m. PT / 1:00 p.m. ET</a> to <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241021T1700" rel="noopener" target="_blank">October 21 at 10:00 a.m. PT / 1:00 p.m. ET</a>, the companies announced. <span id="more-918210"></span></p><p>The demo, available as part of Steam Next Fest: October 2024 Edition, will feaure the entire first level of the game, “Sewer Town Southwest,” which will take approximately two hours to complete. Gameplay includes enemy, elite, and boss battles, and the level will provide a battleground for players to learn how to master spells and spell frames, and discover weapons and other equipment.</p><p>Users who clear the level will receive a special reward in the form of an additional, secret, unlockable level featuring a new boss and combat system not featured in the “Sewer Town Southwest” demo.</p><p><em>AI LIMIT</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2407270/AI_LIMIT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2024.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Xenoverse 2 DLC ‘Future Saga Chapter 2’ teaser trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/dragon-ball-xenoverse-2-dlc-future-saga-chapter-2-teaser-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-xenoverse-2-dlc-%E2%80%98future-saga-chapter-2%E2%80%99-teaser-trailer.994356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/dragon-ball-xenoverse-2-dlc-future-saga-chapter-2-teaser-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,572 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Dimps Corporation [279 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dimps">Dimps</a> have released the teaser trailer for <em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball Xenoverse 2 [116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-xenoverse-2">Dragon Ball Xenoverse 2</a></em> downloadable content “Future Saga Chapter 2.” The second of four planned chapters is coming soon. <span id="more-918357"></span></p><p><em>Dragon Ball Xenoverse 2</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,520 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/454650/DRAGON_BALL_XENOVERSE_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, and will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,157 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> on May 24.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>DLC “Future Saga Chapter 2” Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="DRAGON BALL Xenoverse 2 - FUTURE SAGA Chapter 2 Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6ZlYHW58tBs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="ドラゴンボール ゼノバース2 - FUTURE SAGA Chapter 2 ティザーPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IjVleRhk3e4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anime-inspired arcade space combat game Rogue Flight announced for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/anime-inspired-arcade-space-combat-game-rogue-flight-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anime-inspired-arcade-space-combat-game-rogue-flight-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc.994353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/anime-inspired-arcade-space-combat-game-rogue-flight-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Perp Games [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/perp-games">Perp Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Truant Pixel [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/truant-pixel">Truant Pixel</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Rogue Flight" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rogue-flight">Rogue Flight</a></em>, an <a title="Genres > Arcade [62 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> space combat game inspired by 80s and 90s anime. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,157 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2784620/ROGUE_FLIGHT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in late 2024. <span id="more-918367"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Perp Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Rogue Flight</em> is a breathtaking arcade space combat game inspired by the landmark style of 80s and 90s prestige anime. Traverse the Sol system and join a flight force voiced by a veteran cast, featuring Japanese talent from <em>Sailor Moon</em>, <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em>, <em>Gundam</em>, <em>Naruto</em>, and <em>One Piece</em>, and English voice talent featured in <em>Overwatch</em>, <em>Fallout 76</em>, <em>League of Legends</em>, and <em><a title="Games > Marvel's Avengers [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marvels-avengers">Marvel’s Avengers</a></em>. Jump into true stylish arcade <a title="Genres > Action [2,204 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> with a huge host of spacecraft upgrades, game modes, and multiple narrative paths.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>It’s been three years since the world burned. It was ARGUS; the interstellar watchman system given control of the Solar Defense Force.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In a secret facility deep beneath the surface of the Earth, the last vestiges of humanity prepare to launch a daring counterattack.</p><p>Take control of an advanced light space fighter and face hordes of enemies in a last-ditch effort to destroy ARGUS and restore peace to the Sol system.</p></blockquote><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Featuring a retro 80s to 90s analogue video art style inspired by the golden age of prestige anime.</li><li>Stylish high-speed arcade action set across nine unique stages spanning the Sol system.</li><li>Utilize incredible aerial acrobatic maneuvers coupled with a dizzying array of weapon types.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a branching narrative path with multiple endings.</li><li>Choose from standard arcade and unlockable <a title="Genres > Roguelite [192 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite game</a> modes which offer greater risks and even greater rewards.</li><li><a title="Series > Persona [87 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>lize your aircraft from over 100 unlockable liveries, as well as 24 badges with multiple color and style combinations.</li><li>Customize your loadout from over 40 unlockable aero designs and 40 unlockable weapons from multiple classes with upgradable attributes.</li><li>Featuring an original soundtrack featuring renowned video game sound design duo Fat Bard, additional music by Rinn, and an original opening theme with stunning vocals by J-Pop artist Itoki Hana.</li><li>Fully voiced in English and Japanese by veteran casts, including English talent from <em>Fallout 76</em>, <em>Overwatch</em>, <em>League of Legends</em>, and <em>Marvel’s Avengers</em>, and Japanese talent from <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em>, <em>Gundam</em>, <em>Sailor Moon</em>, <em>Naruto</em>, and One Piece.</li><li>Unlockable extras, accolades and more.</li><li>Multiple difficulty levels for every player skill.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/rogue-flight/september-27-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Rogue Flight - Coming Late 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IX_GefjbJbE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save Big On Monster Hunter Art And Design Books At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon/1100-6526755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon.994347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon/1100-6526755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526755">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Excited for Monster Hunter Wilds? Then you'll probably enjoy this Monster Hunter art book that's available for a big discount at Amazon. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1974711099?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter: World - Official Complete Works</a> is a 560-page paperback book packed art, development materials, and even commentary from the game's producers. It's normally $50, but you can get it for just $28.73.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374601-mhworld.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374601" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374601-mhworld.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374601"></a><figcaption>Monster Hunter: World - Official Complete Works</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374601-mhworld.jpg"></figure><p>Monster Hunter has seen several other art books over the years, including the Monster Hunter Illustrations line. There are three hardcover books in the series and you can pick up the first book for $35 (was $45) <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMonster-Hunter-Illustrations-Hardcover-9781772940855%2F710464577%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsave-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon%2F1100-6526755%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">at Walmart</a>. Monster Hunter Illustrations 2 is available for $41.25 (was $55) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Monster-Hunter-Illustrations-2-Capcom/dp/1772940860?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Monster-Hunter-Illustrations-2-Capcom/dp/1772940860?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>. Unfortunately, the third book in the collection is sold out, but as a backup pick, the Japanese book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/404733345X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">New Continental Sketch Tour - Monster Hunter: World Editor's Journal</a> is available for $23 at Amazon.</p><h2>Monster Hunter Illustrations</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374602-mhillustrations.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374602" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374602-mhillustrations.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374602"></a><figcaption>Monster Hunter Illustrations series</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374602-mhillustrations.jpg"></figure><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMonster-Hunter-Illustrations-Hardcover-9781772940855%2F710464577%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsave-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon%2F1100-6526755%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Illustrations</a> -- $35 (<del>$45</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Monster-Hunter-Illustrations-2-Capcom/dp/1772940860?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Illustrations 2</a> -- $41.25 (<del>$55</del>) | Also at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMonster-Hunter-Illustrations-2-Hardcover-9781772940862%2F317403320%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsave-big-on-monster-hunter-art-and-design-books-at-amazon%2F1100-6526755%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1772941352?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Illustrations 3</a> (sold out)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/404733345X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">New Continental Sketch Tour - Monster Hunter: World Editor's Journal</a> -- $23 (Japan import)</li></ul><hr><h2 dir="ltr">Monster Hunter Figure Preorders</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374600-figures.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374600" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374600-figures.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4374600"></a><figcaption>Kaiyodo Revoltech Monster Hunter Figures</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4374600-figures.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">If you're looking for even more Monster Hunter merch, there is a new line of Kaiyodo Revoltech figures based on various popular armor and weapon sets from the series, including <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DG9V76FY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Rathalos</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C56XVJMH?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Zinogre</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CJY1C141?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lunagaron</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CD7K1N12?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Malzeno</a>. Each figure costs $100 and is available for preorder at Amazon.</p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C56XVJMH?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaiyodo Revoltech Monster Hunter Zinogre Armor figure</a> -- $100 | Preorder, releases March 5, 2025</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DG9V76FY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaiyodo Revoltech Monster Hunter Rathalos Armor figure</a> -- $100 | Preorder, releases March 5, 2025</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CJY1C141?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaiyodo Revoltech Monster Hunter Lunagaron Armor figure</a> -- $100 | Preorder, releases March 5, 2025</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CD7K1N12?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaiyodo Revoltech Monster Hunter Malzeno Armor figure</a> -- $100 | Preorder, releases March 5, 2025</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Speaking of preorders, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-preorder-release-date-bonuses-editions/1100-6526687/" data-ref-id="1100-6526687">Monster Hunter Wilds now is available for preorder</a> ahead of its launch on February 28, 2025. Physical edition preorders are available for PS5 and Xbox Series X, including a limited steelbook edition.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-mario-red-nintendo-switch-oled-is-back-in-stock-with-a-big-discount-at-amazon/1100-6526568/">Super Mario-Themed Nintendo Switch OLED Drops To Best Price Yet At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avatar-the-last-airbender-now-has-a-deckbuilding-card-game/1100-6526544/">Avatar: The Last Airbender Now Has A Deckbuilding Card Game</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/stanley-kubrick-the-shining-compendium-stephen-king-adaptation-preorder-guide/1100-6526309/">The Shining Compendium Box Set Is A Staggeringly Ambitious Examination Of Kubrick's Horror Classic</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/walmart-exclusive-lego-batman-bundle-comes-with-three-sets-for-only-50/1100-6526223/">Walmart-Exclusive Lego Batman Bundle Comes With Three Sets For Only $50</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-popular-pokemon-labyrinth-board-game-is-getting-a-glow-in-the-dark-edition/1100-6526286/">The Popular Pokemon Labyrinth Board Game Is Getting A Glow-In-The-Dark Edition</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cult-of-the-lamb-the-first-verse-graphic-novel-is-up-for-preorder-at-amazon/1100-6526253/">Cult Of The Lamb: The First Verse Graphic Novel Is Up For Preorder At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/trigun-manga-preorders-amazon/1100-6523338/">Save Big On Trigun Deluxe Edition Manga Ahead Of Next Week's Release</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-nightmare-before-christmas-manga-is-returning-to-haunt-the-winter-holidays/1100-6526230/">The Nightmare Before Christmas Manga Is Returning To Haunt The Winter Holidays</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526681&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-free-games-for-october-2024\/1100-6526681\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526684&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/my-time-with-the-ps5-pro-reaffirmed-i-shouldnt-spend-700-right-now-my-base-ps5-is-still-enough\/1100-6526684\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526658&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meet-your-new-voice-assistant-jack-skellington-the-amazon-echo-dot\/1100-6526658\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526714&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/blizzard-co-founder-founder-left-because-he-was-tired-of-fighting-bobby-kotick-report\/1100-6526714\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526662&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/stellarblade-sues-over-stellar-blade\/1100-6526662\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526734&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dualsense-30th-anniversary-edition-is-selling-out-fast-at-major-retailers\/1100-6526734\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526741&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-exclusives-get-huge-limited-time-discounts-including-zelda-and-mario-games\/1100-6526741\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526682&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/two-new-fighters-join-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-shredders-revenge\/1100-6526682\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526690&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-horizon-zero-dawn-tallneck-set-restocked-before-lego-horizon-adventures\/1100-6526690\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526611&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tales-of-the-shire-will-let-you-hang-out-with-hobbits-this-march\/1100-6526611\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526700&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-pro-dev-discusses-who-its-for-and-the-hefty-700-price-point\/1100-6526700\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526633&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-state-of-play-coming-this-week-report-says\/1100-6526633\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526725&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-the-game-pass-titles-announced-at-xbox-tgs-2024-starcraft-remastered-legend-of-mana-and-more\/1100-6526725\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526688&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/stellar-blade-is-getting-a-nier-automata-crossover-dlc\/1100-6526688\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526733&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/former-playstation-boss-has-a-message-for-ghost-of-yotei-haters\/1100-6526733\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526729&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sold-out-ps5-pro-bundles-are-already-up-on-ebay-and-scalpers-want-to-sell-them-for-thousands\/1100-6526729\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526639&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/thunderbolts-poster-gives-the-sentry-six-fingers-on-one-hand\/1100-6526639\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526687&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-preorder-release-date-bonuses-editions\/1100-6526687\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526728&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-trailer-has-everything-but-a-release-date\/1100-6526728\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blasphemous' first chapter of The Pentient One coming to mobile next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/blasphemous-first-chapter-of-the-pentient-one-coming-to-mobile-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blasphemous-first-chapter-of-the-pentient-one-coming-to-mobile-next-year.994344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/blasphemous-first-chapter-of-the-pentient-one-coming-to-mobile-next-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>I curse you forever in name. I bless you forever in death.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-09-27-at-15.16.42.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Game Kitchen</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The first chapter of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/blasphemous">Blasphemous</a>' The Pentient One - which recently marked its fifth anniversary - is now available to pre-order on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/blasphemous/id6499431452">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.thegamekitchen.blasphemousmobile">Android</a> for £8 ($8).</p>
<p>The mobile port - set to release on 24th February 2025 - includes the base game along with all DLC "day one", "delivering the complete experience right at your fingertips".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Blasphemous - Mobile Announcement &amp; Pre-Order/Registration Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G-Jx9jttgCg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Blasphemous - Mobile Announcement &amp; Pre-Order/Registration Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G-Jx9jttgCg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/G-Jx9jttgCg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Blasphemous - Mobile Announcement &amp; Pre-Order/Registration Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-Jx9jttgCg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Players will get to explore a non-linear world, fearsome enemies, deadly traps, new combos and special moves, and brutal combat as you fight to "release the power of Mea Culpa, a sword born from guilt itself, to slaughter your foes".</p>
<p>You'll also get to customise your build with a range of relics, rosary beads, and sword hearts that give you new abilities and boosts.</p>
<p>"The Miracle be praised!" the team teased on social media. "Your prayers have been answered: Blasphemous arrives on iOS &amp; Android mobile devices.</p>
<p>"After years of fan requests, you'll soon be able to carry the dark and brutal world of Cvstodia in your pocket! Get ready to embrace the Penance wherever you go!"</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>The Miracle be praised!</p><p>Your prayers have been answered: Blasphemous arrives on iOS &amp; Android mobile devices. After years of fan requests, you'll soon be able to carry the dark and brutal world of Cvstodia in your pocket!</p><p>Get ready to embrace the Penance wherever you go! <a href="https://t.co/znGmEBsjmg">pic.twitter.com/znGmEBsjmg</a></p></div>— Blasphemous (@BlasphemousGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlasphemousGame/status/1839356987168989383?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 26, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>In related Blasmphemous news, we recently learned <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/blasphemous-2s-mea-culpa-expansion-and-big-free-content-update-arrive-this-october">Blasphemous 2's paid Mea Culpa expansion</a>, and an accompanying free update, will arrive for all platforms on 31st October.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atelier-resleriana-red-alchemist-and-white-guardian</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-announced.994329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/atelier-resleriana-red-alchemist-and-white-guardian<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Koei Tecmo has announced&nbsp;<em>Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian</em>, a followup to this year's&nbsp;<em>Atelier Resleriana: Forgotten Alchemy and the Polar Night Liberator</em>.</p>
<p>According to Koei Tecmo, the new game will be "a new adventure from the world of&nbsp;<em>Atelier Resleriana</em>", but it'll feature "new protagonists and an original story", so don't expect to follow up with the characters from the previous game.</p>
<p>All we know about&nbsp;<em>The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian&nbsp;</em>so far is that it's currently in development for PC, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch (sorry once again, Xbox users), and that it's intended to launch next year.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-path.jpg?itok=V_03tia3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-path.jpg?itok=oqgzv6fG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian&nbsp;</em>sure looks like an&nbsp;<em>Atelier&nbsp;</em>game.</figcaption></figure><p>For what it's worth, though, the teaser trailer for&nbsp;<em>Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian&nbsp;</em>sure makes it look like an&nbsp;<em>Atelier&nbsp;</em>game.</p>
<p>It's got all the idyllic locations, mysterious-looking caverns, and wide, sweeping expanses you'd expect from the series, plus plenty of cozy-looking villages.</p>
<p>The new protagonists look like they fit the bill, too; there's a studious-looking anime boy who wears glasses, and a girl with cat ears who looks like she's going to take the role of&nbsp;<em>Atelier</em>'s familiar sassy protagonists.</p>
<p>You can check out the teaser reveal trailer for&nbsp;<em>The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian&nbsp;</em>right here. It doesn't give too much away, but we're not expecting the game until next year, so that makes sense.</p>

<p>Koei Tecmo says this game will "build on the experiences of the&nbsp;<em>Atelier&nbsp;</em>series while also evolving", and also that it'll be "completely offline", so you won't need an online connection to play it.</p>
<p>It's not yet clear whether the game will be a free-to-play title with microtransactions <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/free-to-play-all-star-jrpg-atelier-resleriana-announced-for-west-by-koei-tecmo">like its predecessor</a>, but given that it's totally offline, it sounds like it'll be a premium JRPG instead. Let's hope so!</p>
<p><em>Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist and the White Guardian&nbsp;</em>arrives on PC, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch sometime in 2025. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age Fans Are Concerned About How Few Choices Carry Over To The Veilguard]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-choices-import-morrigan-inquisitor-1851659355</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-fans-are-concerned-about-how-few-choices-carry-over-to-the-veilguard.994320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-choices-import-morrigan-inquisitor-1851659355<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On September 25, BioWare revealed the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-choices-character-creator-import-1851643966&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-choices-character-creator-import-1851643966">choices that will carry over</a></span> from previous <em>Dragon Age </em>RPGs in the upcoming fourth game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-preview-bioware-rook-solas-rpg-1851648350&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-preview-bioware-rook-solas-rpg-1851648350"><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em></a></span>. For the past decade and a half, the studio has largely positioned itself as, above all, a maker of games in which choices matter, and that’s extended across multiple series. Both <em>Dragon Age </em>and its space opera franchise, <em>Mass Effect</em>,<em> </em>have given players universe-bending choices that have carried over between games through save data transfers and external apps that let you craft your world state. In <em>The Veilguard</em>, however, only three decisions from previous games will carry over, and that has fans concerned about the sequel’s handling of continuity.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,195150,196773" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>[spoilers for <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em> follow]</p><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In <em>The Veilguard</em>, players will import three decisions during the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-character-creator-hair-body-types-1851651794&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-character-creator-hair-body-types-1851651794">character creation phase</a></span>. In this menu, you’ll have the chance to create your version of the Inquisitor, the protagonist of 2014’s <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em>. Then you’ll be able to make three key decisions (or report which decisions you made in these situations when playing <em>Inquisition</em>) that will be reflected in the story: who did the Inquisitor romance, did they disband or maintain the titular organization, and are they still friends with Solas, the party-member-turned-antagonist of <em>The Veilguard</em>? Given Solas and the Inquisitor’s past relationship, these will obviously play key parts in how that character reacts to events in <em>The Veilguard</em>, as you won’t be controlling them this time around. But given how many big events have happened throughout three previous games, fans are wondering just how much, if any, impact their previous decisions will have on the story.<br></p><p>In an interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/how-dragon-age-the-veilguard-grapples-with-the-series-wildly-expansive-lore-and-your-choices-in-it&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-dragon-age-the-veilguard-grapples-with-the-series-wildly-expansive-lore-and-your-choices-in-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span>, <em>Veilguard</em> creative director John Epler explained that the trimming down of imported choices was partially because the fourth game takes place in a distant region of its universe. <em>The Veilguard </em>is set in northern Thedas, whereas previous games were in the south. So maybe it doesn’t matter whether you ended up with the traditionalist Cassandra or the more progressive Leliana as the church’s leader at the end of <em>Inquisition</em>, because that’s all happening elsewhere.</p><p>On its face, I buy that explanation for why a large swath of choices from previous games are seemingly not brought up in <em>The Veilguard</em>. If BioWare doesn’t bring up these choices in any dialogue or codex entry, does it really matter what, specifically, is going on elsewhere in the world? This approach worked for <em>Mass Effect: Andromeda</em>, which was set in a different galaxy from its predecessors, allowing it to carefully write around which of the galaxy-changing choices you made at the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-3-ending-shepard-catalyst-crucible-choice-1851313435&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-3-ending-shepard-catalyst-crucible-choice-1851313435">end of <em>Mass Effect 3</em></a></span>. What I and several other fans are left wondering is how this will affect returning characters in <em>The Veilguard</em>.</p><p>There are two major figures in this discussion: The Inquisitor and Morrigan, a party member from the original <em>Dragon Age: Origins</em> and a major supporting character in <em>Inquisition</em>. Both characters have been confirmed to return in <em>The Veilguard</em> and both were part of one of the biggest decisions in <em>Inquisition</em>. Near the end of the game, there is a questline in which either the Inquisitor or Morrigan drinks from the Well of Sorrows. This magical well is said to house elven knowledge, but it will come at a price. Regardless of which of the two of you drinks from the well, one of you is forever tied to Mythal, an elven goddess who has possessed Flemeth, Morrigan’s mother.</p><p>Flemeth is seemingly killed and absorbed by Solas at the end of <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em> and the decade-long theory has been that Solas may have some kind of magical control of either the Inquisitor or Morrigan after being revealed as a traitor at the end of the game. Now, without the ability to import this decision into <em>The Veilguard</em>, fans worry it might be going absolutely nowhere, which is strange for a game that centers on Solas and the elven gods. The lack of choices that specifically refer to Morrigan is also strange considering she may have a son depending on if the player romanced her in <em>Origins</em> or conducted a ritual to conceive a child in the endgame. In any case, the inability to import any choices pertaining to her has taken fans by surprise.</p><p>The Inquisitor, meanwhile, is one of the biggest question marks leading up to<em> The Veilguard</em>. BioWare has confirmed the character will appear in the game (I may have spent a good 30 minutes trying to recreate mine in the character creator when I <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-preview-bioware-rook-solas-rpg-1851648350&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-preview-bioware-rook-solas-rpg-1851648350">played the game earlier this month</a></span>), but has been tight-lipped on what their deal is this time around. But the fact that you only answer three questions about their journey has fans concerned about both the substance of their role in <em>The Veilguard</em> and whether it’s possible for the game to represent all the variations of the hero players have made over the years.</p><p>That’s a tall order, of course. But it understandably matters to players, given that the conflict between the Inquisitor and Solas is one of the most personal in the series. (I’d even argue that they should have still been the protagonist of the game in which you face him, but I digress.) Now, we’ll be meeting a version of our old hero entirely defined by BioWare’s writing team with very little input on our part. If the only questions about them we’re allowed to answer are “Who did they romance?” and “Are they still friends with Solas?” that doesn’t leave a lot of room for nuance. There’s a question now of whether players who weren’t especially invested in Solas are going to get a character who’s a little too different from their own Inquisitor for their comfort level.</p><p>But even if you don’t put the Inquisitor and Morrigan under a microscope, it is questionable that the only choices that seem to have any impact on <em>The Veilguard </em>come from <em>Inquisition</em>. This may make sense in context of the full game, but it does feel diametrically opposed to a series that once let you use an app to import every decision from earlier games, big and small, into <em>Inquisition</em>.</p><p>Though a lot of fans are understandably concerned, others have been more understanding, saying that <em>The Veilguard</em> should focus more on new relationships and choices as they pertain to new protagonist Rook rather than being overly referential. Others are taking the wait-and-see approach, hoping that once the game is actually out these decisions will make better sense in context or that those choices will come up in another <em>Dragon Age </em>project down the line.</p><p>Epler explains that, in selecting which choices <em>The Veilguard </em>would import, the team wanted to pick details that could result in more than just a cameo and some altered dialogue. I could see things like the status of the Inquisition and the Inquisitor’s relationship to Solas having major ramifications, but like many others, I am surprised that some very significant choices aren’t going to be brought up in a game <em>about</em> those related characters and factions. What I played of <em>The Veilguard </em>felt like it had a lot of strong connective tissue between the games of old even without explicitly referencing my choices, but I never met Morrigan or the Inquisitor in my demo. I don’t know how I’ll feel about their roles when all is said and done. We’ll see how it all pans out when <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard </em>launches on October 31.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dynasty Warriors: Origins unveils new gameplay details at TGS 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/dynasty-warriors-origins-unveils-new-gameplay-details-at-tgs-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dynasty-warriors-origins-unveils-new-gameplay-details-at-tgs-2024.994311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/dynasty-warriors-origins-unveils-new-gameplay-details-at-tgs-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Fight alongside and against Ancient China’s most feared warriors.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Omega Force [1,236 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/omega-force">Omega Force</a> have released new information and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Dynasty Warriors: Origins [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a></em> introducing new gameplay details following its Tokyo Game Show 2024 live stream. <span id="more-918291"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p>From the “Yellow Turban Rebellion” to the climax of the “Battle of Chibi,” the story of <em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em> will transport players to the heart of an ancient China in turmoil. Through the eyes of a nameless hero, players will have to make choices in order to restore peace and shape history to their own experience.</p><p>Travelling across the world map as they embark on their epic journey, players can suppress rebellions or choose to rescue government forces during “Missions,” overcome “Skirmishes,” and visit various locations where they will be able to buy weapons. Throughout their quest, players will also encounter a variety of characters familiar to the <em>Dynasty Warriors</em> franchise, such as Cao Cao and Liu Bei. Depending on the bond forged, these characters can become travelling companions, or an enemy.</p><p>Battles in <em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em> will require players to be more strategic than ever before. A variety of “Tactics” can be used to command their allies and coordinate forces. By gathering a large number of soldiers under their command, fans will also be able to form a “Large Force” which they can lead by deploying “Grand Tactics” maneuvers. This will allow players to radically change the course of a battle. However, users will need to keep an eye on their opponents, who will also be able to form a “Large Force” and will try to deploy their own “Grand Tactics” to win.</p><p>In one-versus-1,000 combat, players will have to master and alternate between swift and powerful attacks that can break an opponent’s guard. Repeated attacks will increase the protagonist’s “Bravery”, enabling them to use powerful and unique attacks called “Arts.” These “Arts” will be unique to each weapon, so it will be crucial for players to master the various arsenal at their disposal, allowing the protagonist to gain “Rank” and thus improving their skills.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Not only will players have to master the protagonist’s various attacks if they want to emerge victorious on the battlefield, but they will also have to strengthen their defense. By blocking enemy attacks at the right moment, they can unleash a powerful riposte, “Parry,” which creates a breach in the enemy’s defense. Some attacks cannot be blocked, so players will have to dodge them before counterattacking.</p><p>Finally, players will sometimes encounter powerful officers protected by an energy called “Resolution.” Players will have to work on reducing this “Resolution” to weaken them before they can launch a powerful “Assault” attack which can sometimes be the decisive coup de grace.</p></blockquote><p><em>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,157 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2384580/DYNASTY_WARRIORS_ORIGINS/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on January 17, 2025.</p><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="//">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>“Ask the Producer Sho!” Live Stream Archive</span></h2><p>(From 3:19:22 to 4:07:28.)</p><p><iframe title="コーエーテクモLIVE! in TGS2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cj3NIx8hEN0?start=11962&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_918292"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Deadlock Update Lets Players Turn Cheaters Into Frogs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-deadlock-update-lets-players-turn-cheaters-into-frogs/1100-6526756/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-deadlock-update-lets-players-turn-cheaters-into-frogs.994308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-deadlock-update-lets-players-turn-cheaters-into-frogs/1100-6526756/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526756">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Valve's new hero shooter, Deadlock, hasn't even officially launched yet, but cheaters are already becoming a problem. The game is currently in the midst of a closed beta, meaning players can only access the game via an invite from another player. But that hasn't stopped the game from gaining <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valves-new-game-hasnt-been-announced-already-has-almost-17000-concurrent-players/1100-6525718/" data-ref-id="1100-6525718">massive popularity</a>, and as is the case with many online shooters, more players means more cheaters.</p><p>Naturally, Valve is handling the influx of aim-bots and other instances of cheating the way any reasonable developer would: by turning the offending players into frogs.</p><p>"When a user is detected as cheating, during the game session the opponents will be given a choice between banning the user immediately and ending the match or turning the cheater into a frog for the rest of the game and then banning them afterwards," the Deadlock developer known as Yoshi shared in <a href="https://forums.playdeadlock.com/threads/09-26-2024-update.33015/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a forum post outlining a recent game update</a>. "The system is set to conservative detection levels as we work on a v2 anti-cheat system that is more extensive. We will turn on the banning of users in a couple of days after the update is out. When a match is ended this way, the results will not count for other players."</p><p>The frogs in question are essentially defenseless, unable to do damage or use the abilities of the character they were playing prior to being frog-ified. Non-cheaters can easily kill a frog, or simply choose to let it leap around the arena for the rest of the match.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valve-finally-acknowledges-deadlock-a-new-game-people-have-been-playing-for-months/1100-6526115/" data-ref-id="1100-6526115">Deadlock was officially announced</a> in late August, when Valve uploaded an announcement trailer and lifted the NDAs signed by streamers and other playtesters. The game's official release date has yet to be announced, but one thing is certain: No fairytale princesses will ever plant a kiss on any of Deadlock's frogs, especially given their history of cheating.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Version 5.1 Launches in October, New Info Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-51-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-version-5-1-launches-in-october-new-info-revealed.994290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-51-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.1 release date, as well as what kind of content you can expect from the update when it arrives.</p>
<p>Version 5.1, which is titled "The Rainbow Destined to Burn", launches across all platforms on which&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>is available on October 9th. It follows on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-version-50-release-date">August's Version 5.0</a>, which brought the nation of Natlan with it, as well as a number of other new features.</p>
<p>This update isn't quite as major as the last one, but it does continue the Natlan storyline, asking you to help rescue the nation from "destruction and the looming threat of the Abyss". We've all been there.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.1-release-date-xilonen.jpg?itok=MD4aLmiL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/genshin-impact-version-5.1-release-date-xilonen.jpg?itok=6IjFgdQd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>New character Xilonen joins the roster in&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.1.</figcaption></figure><p>As you'd expect from&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>, a new character is also joining the roster in Version 5.1 in the form of Xilonen, a skilled smith who also happens to be a five-star sword-wielding Geo fighter.</p>
<p>She can debuff enemies, heal her teammates, and deal area-of-effect damage to enemies, making her a versatile (if somewhat tricky to get to grips with) character for your team.</p>
<p>Xilonen will be available as part of the first half of Version 5.1's Event Wishes, alongside a rerun of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/genshin-impact-showcases-new-5-star-geo-character-chiori">Chiori</a>. The second half will bring reruns of Nahida and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/genshin-impact-hu-tao-build-guide">Hu Tao</a>.</p>
<p>Version 5.1 also introduces the Sabzeruz Festival in Sumeru, where you'll get the chance to take part in a number of minigames and extra activities for the chance to claim some rewards, including an opportunity to recruit Candace.</p>

<p>Of course, HoYoverse has also released a number of codes to help you grab some free goodies, as is customary when it comes to&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>update announcements. Here are today's codes!</p>
<ul><li>XSME6NV4GX2Z: 100 Primogems, 10 Mystic Enhancement Ore</li>
<li>KALF66CLGXKM: 100 Primogems, 5 Hero's Wit</li>
<li>PT5WP6D5GXJ9: 100 Primogems, 50,000 Mora</li>
</ul><p><em>Genshin Impact&nbsp;</em>Version 5.1 launches across <a href="https://genshin.hoyoverse.com/en/home" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC, PlayStation, and mobile devices</a> on October 9th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cheaters in Deadlock Can Now be Turned Into a Frog Mid-Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/deadlock-frog-cheaters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cheaters-in-deadlock-can-now-be-turned-into-a-frog-mid-game.994284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/deadlock-frog-cheaters/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-58882">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>A new patch update in Deadlock has announced that cheaters in the can can now be turned into a frog before being banned.</p>



<p>The new update came from the Deadlock patch notes, which reveals that Valve has added an initial anti-cheat detection system into the game. “When a user is detected as cheating, during the game session the opponents will be given a choice between banning the user immediately and ending the match or turning the cheater into a frog for the rest of the game and then banning them afterwards.”</p>



<p>Valve describes the new system as its first step in being able to detect cheaters and is “set to conservative detection levels” while the team work on a v2 anti-cheat system. One of the biggest questions here though is, will we still be able to turn cheaters into a frog in the new system?</p>



<p>Despite Valve saying that the update will roll out in a couple of days, one X user (formerly Twitter) <a href="https://x.com/poggu__/status/1839438568110031076" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">@poggu__</a> has been able to snap some footage of what it will look like:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Deadlock is still in its ‘early access’ stage but has already seen an all-time peak of 171,000 players on Steam, with a daily concurrent peak of around 100,000 as of late.</p>



<p>As of the time of writing, Valve is yet to officially announce its full release date, but assumptions are that it’s likely to be sometime in 2025.</p>



<p>What do you think of Deadlock? And what do you think of the new anti-cheat system that’s been implemented to turn cheaters into a frog? Let us know in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/forums/deadlock.17/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-invictus-will-be-a-fall-guys-like-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-invictus-will-be-a-fall-guys-like-game/">Assassin’s Creed Invictus Will Be A Fall Guys-Like Game</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new leak gives plenty of new details surround the in-development Assassin’s Creed Invictus, and Insider Gaming can confirm many of them.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-day-before-devs-return-fntastic-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-day-before-devs-return-fntastic-2/">The Day Before Devs Return With ‘Fntastic 2.0’ and a New Kickstarter Campaign</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fntastic is back with a new mission, a fresh Kickstarter campaign, and a promise of honesty and integrity – but where’s The Day Before 2?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/strategy-game-songs-of-conquest-coming-to-mobile/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/strategy-game-songs-of-conquest-coming-to-mobile/">Strategy Game Songs of Conquest Coming To Mobile</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developer Lavapotion has announced that its turn-based fantasy strategy game Songs of Conquest is coming to mobile on both iOS and Android.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-season-2-trailer-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-season-2-trailer-2/">New Trailer For Last of Us Season 2 Released by HBO</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>To celebrate Last of Us Day, HBO and Naughty Dog have released a new and detailed trailer for the second season of the live-action show.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme announced for PS5, PS4, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc.994281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme-announced-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in early 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Team NINJA [633 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/team-ninja">Team NINJA</a> have announced “immersive <a title="Genres > Romance Visual Novel [58 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/romance-visual-novel">romance adventure game</a>” <em><a title="Games > Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme">Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme</a></em>. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3155730/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > DMM Games [74 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dmm-games">DMM Games</a> Player in early 2025 in Japan and Asia with English language support. <span id="more-918175"></span></p><p><em>Venus Vacation PRISM: DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme</em> is a first-person <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,787 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> in which you can romance six of the girls from <em>DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme Venus Vacation</em>, including Misaki (voiced by Minami Tsuda) and five others to be revealed in succession beginning October 7.</p><p>Get the first details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>On this island, the moment of love.</p><p>The first ever full-fledged romance game in the <em>DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme</em> series, offering romantic encounters with six cute, charming girls!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> True Romance and a Thrilling Sense of Closeness!</strong></p><p>As the boss on the Venus Islands, where summer is everlasting, you will interact with the girls you encounter there. Your story with the girls will unfold based on the choices you make, resulting in a variety of outcomes. The heart-fluttering sensation caused by casual gestures, the thrill felt as you draw closer to your love interest, the worry about which girl to choose… Are you ready to experience true romance on the islands of everlasting summer?</p><p><strong>Make Memories of Special Dates in a World Just for the Two of You!</strong></p><p>Having multiple interactions with each of the girls will sometimes get you invited on dates. Gorgeous, vivid visuals and fully-voiced animations will make each date an enjoyable experience, as if the two of you are in your own world. The smiling face of a carefree girl, her profile as she watches the ocean waves in the evening, her eyes as she looks shyly up at you—each of these random moments can be photographed by you during your dates! Remember to keep your absolute favorite photograph as a memento of your date.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/venus-vacation-prism-dead-or-alive-xtreme/september-27-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website here: <a href="https://www.gamecity.com.tw/venusvacation/prism/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">English</a> / <a href="https://www.gamecity.ne.jp/venusvacation/prism/jp/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Venus Vacation PRISM - DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0PtARxmJ-Rg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『Venus Vacation PRISM - DEAD OR ALIVE Xtreme -』ティザートレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BVqtf2Tyjus?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_918200"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spirit Mancer launches November 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/spirit-mancer-launches-november-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spirit-mancer-launches-november-7.994275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/spirit-mancer-launches-november-7<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC demo now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Hack-and-slash and <a title="Genres > Deckbuilder [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/deckbuilder">deckbuilder</a> hybrid game <em><a title="Games > Spirit Mancer [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/spirit-mancer">Spirit Mancer</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2172580/Spirit_Mancer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on November 7, publisher <a title="Companies > Dear Villagers [82 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plug-in-digital/dear-villagers">Dear Villagers</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sunny Syrup Studio [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sunny-syrup-studio">Sunny Syrup Studio</a> announced. A demo is available now for PC. <span id="more-918220"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Dear Villagers:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Spirit Mancer</em> is a 2D hack-and-slash adventure with deckbuilding mechanics. Inspired by classics like <em>Mega Man 5</em>, <em>JoJo’s Bizarre <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,787 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></em>, and the first <em><a title="Series > Pokemon [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/pokemon">Pokemon</a></em> adventure, players are in the role of a modern-day demon hunter, they can go alone or also can join forces with a friend in local couch <a title="Genres > Co-Op [203 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> mode. Slash, shoot, and break hordes of demons from Ars Goetia and stop the evil queen with the power of the Spirit Mancer. Capture their spirits and summon them out into battle in the beautiful yet dangerous world of Inferno!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Hack-and-Slash [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/hack-and-slash">Hack-and-Slash</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,204 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Combines With Deckbuilding Elements</strong> – With a skill base card, you can summon demons to do your bidding and help you during combat.</li><li><strong>Local Cooperative Play Support</strong> – Like in the old <a title="Genres > Arcade [62 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> times, join forces with a friend and jump together for an epic battle into a colorful and vibrant inferno.</li><li><strong>Over 50 Unique Enemies You Can Fight and Capture</strong> – Huge variety of unique monsters and demons that you can fight and capture.</li><li><strong>Summon Captured Enemies to Battle as Spirit Cards</strong> – Capture any demons into spirit cards then summon them out into battle as your friends.</li><li><strong>Deckbuilding With Over 100 Spirit Cards</strong> – Build your deck with demon spirits that you want in your pocket.</li><li><strong>Over 40 Guns and Weapons to Be Used</strong> – Blast any foes with a large variety of weapons.</li><li><strong>Over Eight Levels for You to Explore</strong> – Beautiful beach, Volcanic fortress, Lush forest, and more adventure a huge fantasy world of inferno with over 20 biomes to explore.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SPIRIT MANCER - Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tQgrihwd4oI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve croaks down on Deadlock cheaters by letting you turn them into frogs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-croaks-down-on-deadlock-cheaters-by-letting-you-turn-them-into-frogs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-croaks-down-on-deadlock-cheaters-by-letting-you-turn-them-into-frogs.994269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-croaks-down-on-deadlock-cheaters-by-letting-you-turn-them-into-frogs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Valve has released a patch for its-still-in-works hero-shooter Deadlock, which includes a rather brilliant anti-cheat measure.</p>
<p>The new <a href="https://forums.playdeadlock.com/threads/09-26-2024-update.33015/">patch notes</a> cover a pretty extensive list of tweaks and adjustments, as well as the introduction of a new hero called Mirage. But, the highlight by far is that aforementioned anti-cheat measure.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qb7vhF2ELZg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you were feeling a little froggy-headed this morning, I am sure this particular patch note will make you hoppier.</p>
<p>You see, now when a player is rumbled for cheating in Deadlock, their opponents will be given the option ban them immediately, or... turn the wrong-doer into a frog for the rest of the match. And then, when the match is over and the frog has finished hopping all over the place, the cheater will still get banned. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ban-cheater-or-turn-into-frog-buttons-from-a-deadlock-cartoon.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Which button would you choose?  | <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure><p>

"The system is set to conservative detection levels as we work on a v2 anti-cheat system that is more extensive," Valve wrote in the patch notes. "We will turn on the banning of users in a couple of days after the update is out. When a match is ended this way, the results will not count for other players."

</p><p>I promise this isn't all croak and mirrors. You can see just how Deadlock's current anti-cheat measure looks in action via the post below. Sorry, pal, but that's no glitch. Be gone!</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>After an extended period of silence despite <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/now-theres-leaked-footage-of-valves-new-game-deadlock">a wave of leaks</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-hero-shooter-deadlock-still-hasnt-been-announced-but-had-16k-steam-concurrent-players-this-weekend">high-levels of player numbers which were available to the public</a>, Valve officially <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-finally-admits-deadlock-exists">revealed in Deadlock a very un-fanfare-y way</a> back in August.</p>
<p>Since then, a Valve developer has given us all an extra peek at a prototype of Deadlock, which showed a rudimentary urban area, complete with placeholder assets such as those of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/deadlock-prototype-had-half-life-2s-antlions-marching-along-beside-you">Half-Life 2's alien insectoid creatures, Antlions</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dustborn Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/27/dustborn-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dustborn-review.994227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/27/dustborn-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Dustborn is a unique little game. It’s a narrative heavy road trip with audio-based superpowers, combat with a throwable baseball bat that can be recalled Mjollnir-style, and some light ghostbusting. It’s an eclectic mix of ideas that might seem difficult to balance.</p>
<p><iframe title="DUSTBORN | LAUNCH TRAILER" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TiBhYBG6bEE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The highlight here is definitely the story and the characters. Set in the pseudo-dystopian hellscape known as America – an alternate history one, I mean, that’s now called the American Republic. You play as a woman called Pax who is tasked with delivering a package to Nova Scotia and has a small team to help her out. Pax and two of this team are Anomals – individuals with superpowers stemming from a mysterious cataclysmic event – and are planning to use this trip to Nova Scotia to escape their lives to a country more accepting of them. So in order to smuggle themselves and the mysterious package across the country, they start a band and go on tour. It’s the perfect cover…. band.</p>


<p>The characters and their dialogue is phenomenal throughout, and there’s absolutely tonnes of it. Most of the time, the game plays like a Telltale adventure or, more fittingly as it’s published by Quantic Dream, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/05/24/detroit-become-human-review/">Detroit: Become Human</a>, just without the silly quicktime events for opening doors and stuff. You’ll be having a lot of conversations, walking around an location for some light puzzling or adventuring, sending one of your crew in to pick a lock or just knock a door down, and so on. I absolutely love this part of the game, I found myself quickly becoming attached to the characters thanks in no small part by the excellent voice acting, which is handy when you can’t skip a single line of dialogue.</p>


<p>What’s also superb is the attention to detail, sometimes to a fault. Dustborn keeps tracks of an awful lot of things you say or do and often brings it up later. At one point, Sai was having a bit of an episode in a bathroom and I was trying to convince her to come out so we could continue. Having exhausted all of my non-magic options, I tried to give her some beef jerky I’d picked up earlier – something that would definitely have worked in a LucasArts point &amp; click – and boy, was she offended.&nbsp;Later I offered it to her again when she was a little more calm, and she actually commented “is this what you tried to give to me earlier? I’m not a dog, Pax!” which really made me laugh.</p>
<p>There’s a lot of little elements like this that make everyone feel more convincing as characters. One quirk that doesn’t, though, is when you can check in with everyone at the end of the day, butting into the conversations they were having between themselves. Those chats then pause and resume after you’re done with an “as I was saying” type line. After a while, I found it ruined my immersion to hear that after a serious conversation.</p>
<p>Dustborn isn’t exactly subtle with its themes or intentions. From “Anomals” sounding almost exactly like “a-normals” to the “ghosts” which are actually echoes of misinformation that turn people into hateful and paranoid people, it’s all very much on the nose and outside of the accurate statement “misinformation makes people bad,” it doesn’t really say any more than that. Even the people that’s aimed at would agree, but just argue they’re not the ones who are misinformed. Some of these ideas don’t play out to satisfying conclusions, the game establishing a few interesting topics and then leaving them behind as you move onto the next one. It would have been great to tie them back together more cohesively.</p>

<p>While the characters and story are the main focus of the game, there’s a few other genres thrown in alongside. The occasional combat sequences play like a ropey arena brawler. It’s a bit too imprecise and chaotic feeling, but it’s also too easy and gets repetitive despite having some fun abilities, like Pax’s voice turning enemies on each other or convincing them they’re on fire. You can skip some of these encounters… but a one-off instance where I was able to sneak past a gang of bikers broke down when one of the other crew members failed to follow me to the bus, forcing me to fight anyway. Another one-off flashback took the form of turn-based RPG combat, which is rough but deep enough to be satisfying for its brief appearance.</p>
<p>Then there’s the music. You’re in a band, so you need to “write” some songs that you can perform whilst on tour. There’s a rhythm mini-game for both writing and playing the songs, not too dissimilar to Guitar Hero, but while some of these original songs are catchy in places, I wouldn’t expect them to end up in your daily playlist. The rhythm game itself is also just serviceable, button prompts flying in from all sides of the screen in a way that can make the timing more difficult to judge than it should be.</p>

<p>Variety is nice, but all these elements undercut the game’s focus and pacing. You can have a road trip across America smuggling a mysterious package that deals with weighty topics like discrimination and misinformation, but when the main story is combined with long conversations on other topics, it can feel disjointed. Add to that the funny subversions and absurdities between the serious stuff, and there’s a bit of tonal whiplash.&nbsp;It builds toward an ending that leaves a few too many threads without a satisfying resolution.</p>
<p>The presentation on the whole looks good, with pleasing character designs and models and a good art direction, but with environments that often feel a bit sparse and bare.</p>
<p>Now this all sounds like doom and gloom, but it really isn’t. I really enjoyed Dustborn. Mechanically, it doesn’t quite hit the targets perfectly, but I’m a sucker for a character driven story and the characters here are remarkably well realised, which is more than enough to keep me going through some mediocre gameplay and unrealised potential. The world might be a touch heavy handed in how it’s set up, but I think that we can collectively agree that the time for subtlety has passed when people are unironically cheering on Homelander whilst watching The Boys.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Day Before Developer Fntastic Is Once Again Asking for Your Money]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/day-before-developer-fntastic-returning</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-day-before-developer-fntastic-is-once-again-asking-for-your-money.994224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/day-before-developer-fntastic-returning<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Fntastic, whose name you might remember from the disaster that was&nbsp;<em>The Day Before</em>, is once again asking for your money, this time in the form of a Kickstarter campaign to revive the studio and help it make its latest game.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/FntasticHQ/status/1839404741841047686" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a message on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Fntastic implores those who "helped us create Fntastic through Kickstarter" to pledge their "help again to bring Fntastic back".</p>
<p>The studio has <a href="https://www.fntastic.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">created a new official website</a> to herald its return, and it comes complete with a step-by-step plan explaining how you can help Fntastic if you want to, as well as a "Fntastic 2.0" outline in which the studio details how it's going to do things better this time around.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fntastic-the-day-before-return-escape-factory.jpg?itok=tgOZpuhA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fntastic-the-day-before-return-escape-factory.jpg?itok=aSgVG07o 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>The Day Before&nbsp;</em>developer Fntastic is working on a new game, and it wants your help.</figcaption></figure><p>In its <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/66cf2872c641a645890f1c5d/t/66e3f77eace4a55f13841699/1726216072958/Fntastic-2-0.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">plan for recovery</a>, Fntastic pledges to run its business on the three core principles of "honesty", "transparency", and "professionalism", pledging to build trust within its community, actively engage with said community via social media, and end the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/day-before-devs-ask-for-volunteers-to-help-finish-their-game">practice of relying on "volunteers"</a>.</p>
<p>The studio says its new mission is to deliver "high-quality gaming experiences, combining innovation, creativity, integrity, and transparency". One rather wonders why that wasn't the plan to start with, but hey.</p>
<p>As well as its plan, Fntastic has also released <a href="https://www.fntastic.com/faq" rel="noopener" target="_blank">an FAQ</a> anticipating some of the questions people might have about its return. The studio says that after its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/day-before-developer-shuts-down-as-controversial-game-flops">initial closure</a>, its staffers "reflected on our past mistakes and initiated significant internal changes".</p>
<p>Fntastic's return this time around hinges on a game called&nbsp;<em>Escape Factory</em>, which looks to be a sort of multiplayer&nbsp;<em>Fall Guys</em>-esque platformer with "physics-based challenges". It looks like the studio's Kickstarter campaign covers both the game's development and the company's return.</p>

<p>In case you need a reminder, Fntastic is the company that created&nbsp;<em>The Day Before</em>, a zombie survival game with a marketing campaign Fntastic itself describes as "embellished" (which is certainly one way to put it).</p>
<p>On release, the game was quickly and widely panned for its lack of similarity to the game trailers and marketing hype promised it would be, and just a few weeks after its launch,&nbsp;<em>The Day Before&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/day-before-will-completely-shut-down-in-janhuary-as-steam-will-refund-all-players">shut down for good</a>, with Fntastic refunding everyone who bought it.</p>
<p>Fntastic may want everyone reading its new plan to think it's turned over a new leaf, but back in January this year, the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fntastic-the-day-before-social-media">blamed what it called a "hate campaign"</a> for&nbsp;<em>The Day Before</em>'s failure.</p>
<p>In the aforementioned FAQ, Fntastic admits that its team "still consists of the same people who created all of our previous games". Despite pledging not to use volunteers, the studio also says that "some team members are helping out on a goodwill basis".</p>
<p>I'll leave it to you to decide whether or not bringing back Fntastic is a good idea, but if you want to, you can support the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/fntasticgames/escape-factory/description" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Escape Factory&nbsp;</em>Kickstarter campaign here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact version 5.1 update ‘The Rainbow Destined to Burn’ launches October 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/genshin-impact-version-5-1-update-the-rainbow-destined-to-burn-launches-october-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-version-5-1-update-%E2%80%98the-rainbow-destined-to-burn%E2%80%99-launches-october-9.994215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/genshin-impact-version-5-1-update-the-rainbow-destined-to-burn-launches-october-9<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Storyline progression, Xilonen, Nahida's birthday, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The version 5.1 update for <em><a title="Games > Genshin Impact [118 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a></em>, dubbed “The Rainbow Destined to Burn,” will launch on October 9, developer <a title="Companies > miHoYo [174 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> announced. <span id="more-918151"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via miHoYo:</p><blockquote><p>The main storyline will continue in the newly unveiled region of Natlan, where Xilonen will join as a master forger and a dependable ally in combat and exploration. Meanwhile, Sumeru will celebrate the return of the Sabzeruz Festival, filled with joy, festivities, and a special birthday surprise for Nahida.</p><p>Following the previous Archon Quest, Natlan is in urgent need of help to save herself from destruction and the looming threat of the Abyss. While players and Xilonen work together to forge an Ancient Name for the Traveler, Citlali, a member of the Masters of the Night-Wind, will finally appear to lend a hand. Meanwhile, her fellow tribe member, Ororon, is devising a secret plan. Players’ efforts to rescue Natlan will be rewarded, as they can claim an additional 500 Primogems by completing the two new acts of the Archon Quest in Version 5.1. Additionally, up to 400 Primogems can be obtained by completing specific World Quests and gaining Natlan Exploration Progress.</p><p>Xilonen, renowned for crafting legendary items like the Pyro Archon’s sunglasses, is not only a talented smith but also an agile and reliable warrior. Unlike traditional climbers, this five-star Geo Sword wielder can skate effortlessly and execute agile leaps along cliff walls. In combat, Xilonen demonstrates versatile support skills by reducing enemies’ Elemental RES or healing her teammates, thanks to her unique combat equipment: Samplers. All three Samplers initially record Geo Source Samples, which Xilonen can instantly activate using her Elemental Skill to reduce enemies’ Geo Elemental RES while enhancing her Normal and Plunging Attack DMG. When she teams up with Hydro, Pyro, Cryo, or Electro characters, the Source Samples will undergo Elemental Conversion and change colors, but they can only be activated after maxing out her Nightsoul Points through Normal Attacks, allowing her to reduce the corresponding Elemental RES of enemies. If at least two Source Samples change color, Xilonen can activate them more rapidly, shifting her Elemental Burst from dealing Geo AoE DMG to healing nearby active teammates. Additionally, she can help the team regain a certain amount of Phlogiston by triggering a Nightsoul Transmission.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_918152"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>In the Version 5.1 Event Wishes, Xilonen will feature in the first half alongside the rerun of Chiori, while the second half brings back Nahida and Hu Tao. As more allies join the team, Natlan introduces a new Enemy Boss: the “Secret Source Constructor,” an ancient construction machine with a lethal nature that awaits challengers in a long-forgotten cave.</p><p>Back in Sumeru, the streets come alive with joyful rhythms during the Sabzeruz Festival, honoring the birthday of Lesser Lord Kusanali. This year, players will reunite with Dehya, Tighnari, and Collei to prepare a heartwarming birthday surprise for Nahida, taking on the special role of Knight of Flowers to escort her carriage through the festival parade. In Port Ormos, the festivities feature a series of mini-games, including “Rocking Carriage,” where players control a carriage to collect flowers and dodge obstacles; “Interreflection of Reality and Dreams,” which challenges players to spot anomalies in the dream world; and a combat challenge where participants fight as the Knight of Flowers. By earning enough Festive Fervor through these activities, players can claim various rewards, including a chance to recruit Candace for free.</p><p>Version 5.1 also introduces several quality-of-life improvements for the Spiral Abyss, character ascension, Artifacts, and Echo Cosmetics. In the Spiral Abyss, a new skip feature allows players to bypass Floor 9 if they achieved full stars on Floor 11 in the previous update. Similarly, players who completed Floor 12 with full stars can skip both Floors 9 and 10. Character ascension has become more intuitive, with inventory updates displaying the quantities of craftable materials. A new formula filter at the Crafting Bench will also simplify crafting management. Additionally, in the character Artifact interface, Artifact Set filters and affix sorting preferences for individual slots will now be saved, eliminating the need to reset them after each session. Lastly, Zhongli and Keqing’s Echoes can now be obtained by completing new Envisaged Echoes challenges introduced in the latest update.</p></blockquote><p><em>Genshin Impact</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://ys-api-os.mihoyo.com/event/download_porter/link/ys_global/genshinimpactpc/default" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">client</a> and <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/genshin-impact" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/genshin-impact/id1517783697" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.miHoYo.GenshinImpact" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Play</a>. An Xbox Series version is due out on November 20. A Switch version is also planned.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/genshin-impact/september-27-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Version 5.1 Update Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Version 5.1 &quot;The Rainbow Destined to Burn&quot; Trailer | Genshin Impact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yJ-tllvBvmI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【原神】Ver.5.1公式PV「燃ゆる運命の虹光」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_DqVC77tmrc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="원신 | 5.1 버전 PV: 「타오를 운명의 무지개」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0o27pHWAHyg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》5.1版本PV：「命定将焚的虹光」 #原神 #版本PV #命定将焚的虹光 #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bKRci4cTgB8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>4th Anniversary Theme Song: “Passing Memories”</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="4th Anniversary Theme Song: &quot;Passing Memories&quot; - Faouzia | Genshin Impact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j3661mhHfvY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【原神】4周年記念テーマソング『記憶の旅』 / HOYO-MiX feat.中島美嘉" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yCc0bpbsPgo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신 | 4주년 테마곡 〈Passing Memories〉【Faouzia】" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k0p97Ce_DCk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》四周年主题曲《经过》 【张杰】 #四周年主题曲 #经过 #张杰 #原神 #GenshinImpact #HoYoverse #Genshin4You" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BDZZso6kJ0k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 5.1 Events Overview</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Version 5.1 &quot;The Rainbow Destined to Burn&quot; Events Overview | Genshin Impact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lW0ey8UH0Os?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【原神】Ver.5.1「燃ゆる運命の虹光」イベントまとめ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c2MzOTe-Y7Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="〈원신〉 5.1 버전 「타오를 운명의 무지개」 이벤트 총정리" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0-Vdh7bbYPc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》5.1版本「命定将焚的虹光」活动汇总 #原神 #版本預告 #納塔 #命定將焚的虹光 #GenshinImpact #Natlan" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HZq3eVAf_ag?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 5.1 Update Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Genshin Impact Version 5.1 Special Program #NewVersion #SpecialProgram #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l-MzF9Pmq-o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Ver.5.1「燃ゆる運命の虹光」予告番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1jAIqsSg7C0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신｜5.1 버전 특별 방송" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sDk9YGLnTHY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist & the White Guardian announced for PS5, PS4, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-the-white-guardian-announced-for-ps5-ps4-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-the-white-guardian-announced-for-ps5-ps4-switch-and-pc.994212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-the-white-guardian-announced-for-ps5-ps4-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A "completely offline" title set in the world of the mobile game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gust [794 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/gust">Gust</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist &amp; the White Guardian [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-the-white-guardian">Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist &amp; the White Guardian</a></em>, a “completely offline” and original story in the world of <em><a title="Games > Atelier Resleriana: Forgotten Alchemy and the Polar Night Liberator [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/atelier-resleriana-forgotten-alchemy-and-the-polar-night-liberator">Atelier Resleriana: Forgotten Alchemy and the Polar Night Liberator</a></em>, coming to <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,350 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2025. <span id="more-918165"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Koei Tecmo:</p><blockquote><p>A new <a title="Genres > RPG [16,671 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> from the <em>Atelier</em> series.</p><p>A new <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,787 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with new protagonists and an original story in the world of <em>Atelier Resleriana: Forgotten Alchemy and the Polar Night Liberator</em> is coming to consoles and PC as a “completely offline” title. </p><p>Building on the experiences of the <em>Atelier</em> series while also evolving, we invite you to look forward to another story of Resleriana.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://atelier.games/resleriana_rw/us/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist &amp; the White Guardian - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZQXqnr0maj4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『紅の錬金術士と白の守護者 ～レスレリアーナのアトリエ～』ティザートレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gmgMn8k-NXE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy enters into €15 million loan agreement with Tencent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/remedy-enters-into-15-million-loan-agreement-with-tencent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-enters-into-%E2%82%AC15-million-loan-agreement-with-tencent.994209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/remedy-enters-into-15-million-loan-agreement-with-tencent<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Alan Wake and Control developer Remedy has entered into a €15 million ($16.7 million) convertible loan agreement with Tencent.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Remedy said the loan will carry an 8 percent annual non-cash interest rate and has a fixed conversion rate of €27.2 per share.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Studio CEO Tero Virtala said the move will strengthen Remedy's position in the value chain and give the company more control over how its projects are commercialized.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As we move towards self-publishing, this financing will support us in developing and fully realizing the potential of the games we have in development and successfully carrying out the commercial activities of our next self-published games," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://news.cision.com/remedy-entertainment-oyj/r/inside-information--remedy-enters-into-a-eur-15-million-convertible-loan-agreement-with-tencent,c4043667">he added in a press release</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "Tencent’s investment demonstrates strong confidence in Remedy's long-term vision and strategy."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tencent currently </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-moves-forward-on-projects-as-tencent-s-ownership-grows">holds a 15 percent stake in Remedy</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and first invested in the company back in 2021.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Remedy's business partners">Remedy's business partners</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Chinese conglomerate isn't Remedy's only partner. Earlier this year, the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-and-annapurna-enter-strategic-agreement-on-control-2-and-transmedia-push">struck a deal with Annapurna Pictures</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/all-of-annapurna-interactive-has-resigned">not to be confused with embattled publisher Annapurna Interactive</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) to secure financing for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In exchange, Annapurna nabbed the transmedia rights to both Control and Alan Wake.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discussing that deal, Virtala again suggested it would enable Remedy to move into self-publishing while expanding its franchises into other mediums.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Remedy has multiple projects in development including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and a multiplayer Control spin-off codenamed Project Condor. The latter is currently in full production, while the former is at the "production readiness" stage.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Finnish studio is also remaking the first two entries in the Max Payne franchise with Rockstar Games.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LG and Razer made an ultra-responsive Bluetooth controller for cloud gaming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/27/24255778/lg-razer-ultra-low-latency-bluetooth-ull-gaming-controller</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lg-and-razer-made-an-ultra-responsive-bluetooth-controller-for-cloud-gaming.994191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/27/24255778/lg-razer-ultra-low-latency-bluetooth-ull-gaming-controller<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>LG has teamed up with Razer and MediaTek to develop <a href="https://www.lgnewsroom.com/2024/09/lg-teams-up-with-razer-and-mediatek-to-present-first-ever-bluetooth-ultra-low-latency-technology/">a new Bluetooth gaming controller</a> that could greatly reduce the input lag for cloud-based gaming. According to LG, it’s the first controller to utilize Ultra-Low Latency (ULL) Bluetooth technology — an <a href="https://www.bluetooth.com/specifications/specifications-in-development/#:~:text=Ultra%20Low%20Latency%20HID">in-development standard</a> that aims to make wireless controllers as responsive as their wired counterparts.</p><p>The BT ULL-enabled controller was compared against a “standard controller” at&nbsp;LG’s webOS Summit event on Friday. “The demonstration highlighted the superior responsiveness, reduced input lag and control precision of the BT ULL technology across various cloud-based games, including FPS, fighting and racing titles,” LG said in its newsroom post.</p><div><figcaption><em>There’s no close-up shot of the new controller, but the design may be subject to change before it officially launches.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: LG</cite></p></div><p>Input lag on Bluetooth controllers can vary by model and environmental factors, but anything below 10–20 milliseconds is preferred. Wired controllers typically have a lower input latency, which makes them appealing to competitive gamers. Razer’s new ULL Bluetooth gaming controller was supposedly demonstrated with a “game-changing 1ms input lag.”</p><p>Google once tried to solve controller input latency issues with its Stadia service, enabling the controller to connect directly over Wi-Fi to Google’s data centers. This allowed Google to avoid the added Bluetooth latency. After Google <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/29/23378713/google-stadia-shutting-down-game-streaming-january-2023">shuttered its Stadia service</a> last year, the company released an update to enable <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23559284/google-stadia-controller-bluetooth-mode-how-to">Bluetooth on its Stadia controllers</a> for use on PCs, Macs, phones, and other devices.</p><p>Bluetooth ULL support is being built into select LG 120Hz OLED and Mini LED TVs that use MediaTek’s MT7921 WiFi chipset, which are scheduled to launch in 2025. LG is also planning to introduce a certification for third-party ULL-supported controllers to ensure they “work seamlessly with LG webOS smart TVs,” with Razer being the first company to qualify.</p><p>There’s no price, release date, or even an official name associated with the new Razer controller yet, so it may take some time before it’s available for consumers to buy. We could get some additional details on both the controller and LG’s ULL-supported TVs at 2024’s CES, which is taking place January 7th–10th.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>