<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:44:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-newscast-playstation-upsets-vr-fans-not-e3-june-hype-cycle-1-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/with-the-death-of-keystone-will-xbox-give-up-its-streaming-console-plans-forever.913485/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-newscast-playstation-upsets-vr-fans-not-e3-june-hype-cycle-1-1<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Or is cloud gaming an inevitable future?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xbox-keystone-patent-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft/USPTO</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
This week on the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/newscast">Eurogamer Newscast</a>, we discuss the cancelled Xbox project Keystone: Microsoft's plans to launch a relatively cheap streaming console.
</p>
<p>Keystone popped up yesterday in an old patent which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-what-xboxs-ill-fated-cloud-gaming-console-might-have-looked-like-according-to-newly-surfaced-patent">detailed the prospective hardware in fresh detail</a>, though we have of course seen it in the wild before - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fans-think-phil-spencers-shelf-is-teasing-the-xbox-game-pass-streaming-box">on Xbox boss Phil Spencer's shelf</a>. Spencer has addressed Keystone's cancellation, and blamed it being shelved (literally) on Microsoft not being able to make it a cheap enough proposition.</p>
<p>But does the end of Keystone mean Microsoft is abandoning its cloud gaming plans entirely? No, of course not - and Xbox Cloud Gaming remains. And in the future, as internet speeds improve and streaming games becomes more common, could we see Keystone Version 2? Joining me this week are Eurogamer's Ed Nightingale and Victoria Kennedy to discuss.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<figure><div data-domain="playlist.megaphone.fm"><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p></div><figcaption>Prefer to listen elsewhere? Find us on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/podcast/the-new-eurogamer-podcast/id1590860415">iTunes</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/search/eurogamer">Google Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Podcast/B08K5WQN99">Audible</a> and <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/6pnWMEcUH3zZ65tiMJBZEF">Spotify</a>.</figcaption></figure>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD FSR 3.1 Was Just Added to All Nixxes Ports, From Marvel’s Spider-Man Remastered to Ghost of Tsushima: Director’s Cut]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-3-1-was-just-added-to-all-nixxes-ports-from-marvels-spider-man-remastered-to-ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd-fsr-3-1-was-just-added-to-all-nixxes-ports-from-marvel%E2%80%99s-spider-man-remastered-to-ghost-of-tsushima-director%E2%80%99s-cut.913482/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-3-1-was-just-added-to-all-nixxes-ports-from-marvels-spider-man-remastered-to-ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Just a few minutes ago, Nixxes (which was <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-acquires-nixxes-playstation-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Sony</a> to work on its PlayStation to PC ports) confirmed the addition of AMD FSR 3.1 to several games, including <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-remastered-pc-is-a-solid-debut-for-nixxes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvel's Spider-Man Remastered</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-miles-morales-pc-is-another-great-port-by-sony/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-pc-not-polished/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-forbidden-west-is-another-solid-pc-port-from-nixxes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horizon Forbidden West Complete Edition</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-dlss-upscaling-fsr-3-frame-gen-simultaneous/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut</a>.</p>
<p>Here's the message posted by Nixxes about the new feature:</p>
<p><em>We have been working closely with AMD to incorporate FSR 3.1. This performance-enhancing technology can be used with recent graphics cards from AMD, Intel and NVIDIA.</em></p>
<p><em>AMD FSR 3.1 includes frame generation and offers improved FSR upscaling quality. It also allows you to use AMD FSR frame generation in combination with any upscaling technology available in the game for your graphics card.</em></p>
<p><em>AMD FSR 3.1 also includes a Native AA option that applies high quality anti-aliasing without upscaling, for improved image quality. To enable this option, set Upscaling Method to Off and select AMD FSR 3 Native AA from the anti-aliasing options. This setting can be used in combination with or without frame generation.</em></p>
<p>Each game may also have received other unique minor changes/additions beyond AMD FSR 3.1. For example, Marvel's Spider-Man Remastered, Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales, and Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart (all games originally made by Insomniac) also updated Intel XeSS to version 1.3 with XeSS Native AA option and introduced the ability to start the game with a controller from the launcher. The two Marvel's Spider-Man also got general stability improvements. For Ratchet &amp; Clank, Nixxes fixed an issue where shooting surfaces would not show bullet hole decals.</p>
<p>For Sucker Punch's Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut, Nixxes fixed an issue with the HDR Max Luminance slider that caused it to cap at 1000 nits and improved the Legends co-op multiplayer matchmaking. Out of all the games listed above, Horizon Forbidden West Complete Edition got the most changes, including some performance improvements and brand-new settings.</p>
<ul>
<li>Added a Cinematic Face Detail option in the Graphics menu.</li>
<li>Added a Stylized Mouse Cursor option in the Mouse &amp; Keyboard menu.</li>
<li>Added an Output Mode option in the Audio menu.</li>
<li>Various optimizations and performance improvements.</li>
<li>Improved audio for Logitech G HUB Surround Sound users.</li>
<li>Ammo Crafting is now remappable on Mouse &amp; Keyboard.</li>
<li>When using a Nintendo Switch Pro controller, buttons are now working and show as intended.</li>
<li>Buttons are now working as intended when using Nintendo Button layout on Steam Deck.</li>
<li>The Toggle Vista Prompt now works correctly when using Mouse &amp; Keyboard controls.</li>
<li>Various user interface fixes.</li>
</ul>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow of the Erdtree Has Sold 5 Million Units in 3 Days]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-sold-5-million-units-in-3-days/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-sold-5-million-units-in-3-days.913479/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-has-sold-5-million-units-in-3-days/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, publisher Bandai Namco and developer FromSoftware proudly <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1806326803276906929" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that the Elden Ring expansion Shadow of the Erdtree has sold five million copies in its first three days of release. That's an excellent result, to say the least. As a reminder, the base game had sold <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-has-sold-over-20-million-units-in-its-first-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20 million units in its first year</a> and 25 million units as of this month.</p>
<p>Despite the <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-steam-user-reviews-are-mixed-citing-excessive-difficulty-and-performance-issues/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mixed Steam user reviews</a>, which bemoaned performance issues and excessive difficulty, the overall response of the community on the first and only DLC for 2022's Game of the Year has been excellent. Shadow of the Erdtree also got fantastic scores, including from Wccftech's Francesco De Meo, who <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">awarded the expansion a 10/10</a>:</p>
<p><em>It did not take long to get back into the engaging adventuring loop of the Elden Ring experience, searching for map fragments to get a better look at the map, placing markers where points of interest are seemingly located, and getting amazed by beautiful vistas, immense castles, and sprawling haunting forests, unaware of the dangers that lurked inside of them. With open-world fatigue setting in earlier this year due to the many open-world games released in 2024—like Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Rise of the Ronin, and the PC versions of Horizon Forbidden West and Ghost of Tsushima—Shadow of the Erdtree's open-world design stands out as a testament to how the Elden Ring experience still surpasses anything else on the market. As such, I believe a perfect score is justified, even with the evident lack of significant innovation and some technical hiccups.</em></p>
<p>FromSoftware is also still working on improving the expansion post-launch. A calibration update was just <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-balance-gets-tweaked-with-update-1-12-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a>, and the developers have also confirmed more Shadow of the Erdtree balance tweaks and bug fixes are on the way for a future update. We'll let you know once it goes live, of course.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox games will soon be playable via your Amazon Fire TV Stick]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24187316/xbox-amazon-fire-tv-partnership</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-games-will-soon-be-playable-via-your-amazon-fire-tv-stick.913476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24187316/xbox-amazon-fire-tv-partnership<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="dDz8g1">Microsoft and Amazon have <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/xbox-gaming-on-amazon-fire-tv" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/xbox-gaming-on-amazon-fire-tv?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">announced</a> a cloud gaming partnership starting in July that lets users with select Amazon Fire TV Sticks play Xbox games without a console. Instead, users can download the Xbox app on their Fire TV device, log in to their Microsoft account, and start playing right away — all without an Xbox console being necessary.</p>
<p id="c4UhI5">If you don’t own an Amazon Fire TV Stick, rest assured it’s cheaper than an Xbox would be, although there is a bit of spending involved in this setup. For the whole situation to work, you’ll need to own or acquire either a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/firetvstick4kmax" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/firetvstick4kmax?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Fire TV Stick 4K Max</a> or a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/firetvstick4k" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/firetvstick4k?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23951357__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Fire TV Stick 4K</a>. You’ll also need a subscription to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/deals/23759446/xbox-pc-game-pass-ultimate-subscribe-price-perks">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a>, as well as a compatible Bluetooth controller (like an Xbox wireless controller or Xbox adaptive controller, or a PlayStation DualSense or DualShock 4 controller).</p>
<p id="Fftke1">There are some extremely graphically intensive games on Game Pass at the moment, such as <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24120021/hellblade-2-senuas-saga-preview-ninja-theory-unreal-engine-5"><em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em></a>, as well as technological heavy-hitters like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23852522/starfield-review-xbox-series-x-pc-exclusive-bethesda-microsoft"><em>Starfield</em></a>. The Amazon Fire TV stick uses cloud streaming to make it possible for people to play these games without running them directly off of console hardware. This brings us to the final line item you’ll need in order to take full advantage of this: <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/10/14/21499262/cloud-gaming-setup-internet-router-how-to">decent internet</a>. </p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Bounty Hunter Is Being Remastered And Adding Boba Fett]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-remake-boba-fett-jango-1851564002</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-bounty-hunter-is-being-remastered-and-adding-boba-fett.913473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-remake-boba-fett-jango-1851564002<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A remastered and improved version of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/star-wars-bounty-hunter&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/star-wars-bounty-hunter"><em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunte</em></a></span><em>r</em>, originally released over 20 years ago, is set to launch in August across consoles and PC. And this new version will finally let players unlock Boba Fett, something teased in the original release but never actually offered. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193897" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="418" data-playlist="193897,194499,196842" data-current="193897"><div><p>10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19360.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Developed and published by Lucasarts in 2002, <em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter </em>is set before the events of the prequel film <em>Attack of the Clones</em> and stars Jango Fett—clone daddy of Boba Fett—as he takes on a dangerous job to eliminate a Dark Jedi. Along the way, players can capture other bounties while partaking in third-person combat and light platforming. And soon, you’ll be able to play (or replay) this fan-favorite <em>Star Wars </em>game via a fancy remaster.</p><p>On June 27, Lucasfilm announced that <em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter </em>is being remastered by Aspyr. The remastered <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars:_Bounty_Hunter&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars:_Bounty_Hunter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bounty Hunter</em></a></span> is set to arrive on PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, Switch, and PC on August 1. It will cost $20. Here’s the first trailer for this new version of <em>Bounty Hunter.</em></p><p>This remaster of the game will feature improved textures, a new dynamic lighting system, and it even adds a flashlight to Jango Fett’s arsenal of tools and weapons. That flashlight will help in some areas of the game that are really dark. Back in the day players complained about the lack of a flashlight, so 22 years later, Aspyr is finally fixing this problem. </p><p>The bigger and more exciting news is that this new remaster finally makes good on an Easter egg left in the original game’s files. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/jango-fett-returns-in-enhanced-star-wars-bounty-hunter-coming-to-ps5-august-1/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/jango-fett-returns-in-enhanced-star-wars-bounty-hunter-coming-to-ps5-august-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As mentioned in a PlayStation blog post about the remaster</a></span>, in <em>Bounty Hunter </em>there was a low-res texture that contained a secret message: “Cash in all the bounties to play as Boba.” This wasn’t a feature in the OG game. However, in the remaster, after completing the game, players will be able to replay <em>Bounty Hunter</em> as Boba Fett. </p><p>Does it make any sense within the narrative of this game? Nope! But who cares, it’s cool! Plus, it’s probably the closest thing we’ll get to a proper Boba Fett game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-1313-boba-fett-lucasarts-lucasfilm-gameplay-f-1848434419&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-1313-boba-fett-lucasarts-lucasfilm-gameplay-f-1848434419">especially after <em>Star Wars: 1313 </em>was canned</a></span>. </p><p>The remastered <em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter </em>lands on Xbox, PlayStation, Switch, and PC on August 1. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord early access beta set for July 12 to 14, open beta set for July 18 to 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/concord-early-access-beta-set-for-july-12-to-14-open-beta-set-for-july-18-to-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-early-access-beta-set-for-july-12-to-14-open-beta-set-for-july-18-to-21.913470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/concord-early-access-beta-set-for-july-12-to-14-open-beta-set-for-july-18-to-21<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play as all 16 Freeguners.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Firewalk Studios [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment/firewalk-studios">Firewalk Studios</a> will host an early access beta for <em><a title="Games > Concord [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/concord">Concord</a></em> from July 12 to 14, followed by an open beta from July 18 to 21, the companies <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/27/concord-beta-dates-announced-beta-early-access-launching-july-12/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-895643"></span></p><p>The early access beta will only be available for users who pre-order <em>Concord</em>. All users who pre-order the game will receive five codes for the early access beta—one for you, and four to distribute amongst friends.</p><p>The open beta will be available for all players.</p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Play the Full 16 Freegunner Roster</strong></p><p>You won’t have to wait until launch to find your favorite Freegunner(s). During the <em>Concord</em> beta weekends, you’ll be able to play as all 16 of the Freegunners that will be available at launch. Whether you like to run and gun, lock down an area, lay down fire from afar, or back up your team, there are Freegunners for players of a wide range of playstyles and skill levels.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>From familiar faces like Haymar, Vale, Lennox, 1-0FF, and Star Child from the reveal trailer to other members of the Northstar crew, like It-Z, Teo, Bazz, and more, you’ll get to experiment and learn how each character brings distinct strategic abilities, traversal and gunplay feel, and, most of all, your own personality to the battlefield.</p><p><strong>Explore (and Battle Across) Multiple Planets and Modes</strong></p><p>Throughout both <em>Concord</em> beta weekends, you’ll be able to visit and battle across multiple worlds and maps in the Concord Galaxy.</p><p>During the <em>Concord</em> beta early access weekend, you’ll have a chance to play on four maps:</p><ul><li><strong>Freewater</strong> – Set in a fortified outpost on the sun-scorched planet of Glance, Freewater features intersecting perimeter lanes and a large central courtyard in the middle of the map that serves as a prime convergence point and inspires intense combat engagements.</li><li><strong>Water Hazard</strong> – On the stormy water-covered planet of Leviathan, a massive, armored eel, known as a Morack, has been caught and is being harvested on a large floating fishing rig. Players will fight across the platform and within the jaws of the Morack in a primary harvesting site.</li><li><strong>Star Chamber</strong> – Located atop the tallest mountain on the planet Gloom sits an ancient observatory with narrow corridors and a meteorite at the center, which creates great opportunities for team fights and one-on-one battles.</li><li><strong>Shock Risk</strong> – Located beneath a massive conductive kite in the sky that harvests lightning on the planet Leviathan, Shock Risk features multiple unique arenas for battling with rival crews with pathways that converge on a large center tower.</li></ul><p>During the open beta weekend, a new world and fifth map will be introduced: Bone Mines on the planet Akkar.</p><ul><li><strong>Bone Mines</strong> – The remains of massive vastadons on the tropical planet Akkar have become the site of a lucrative Guild mining operation, where you will fight through the excavated bones and mining caverns in a mix of close-quarters and mid-range combat.</li></ul><p>The <em>Concord</em> beta will also have multiple modes to fit your mood, whether it’s to jump in for a quick match after work or to team up with friends for more coordinated and competitive play.</p><p>The <em>Concord</em> early access beta weekend will launch with three modes:</p><ul><li><strong>Trophy Hunt</strong> – A respawn-based mode where you fight to take down members of the rival crew and collect their bounty cards to earn points for your team. The first team to reach the target score before time runs out wins the match.</li><li><strong>Cargo Run</strong> – A no-respawn mode where teams compete to retrieve the Blue Buddy robotic package delivery system, plant it at one of the zones, and defend it from the rival crew to win.</li><li><strong>Clash Point</strong> – A round-based, no-respawn game mode where teams compete to control a single capture zone at a central location on the map.</li></ul><p>Then, during the open beta weekend, you’ll be able to try out a new mode: Area Control.</p><ul><li><strong>Area Control</strong> – A respawn mode where teams compete to control multiple capture and control zones around the map. Control two or more zones to increase your team’s score and reach the point threshold to win.</li></ul><p><strong>Witness the Beginning of the Northstar Crew’s Story</strong></p><p>Alongside familiarizing yourself with the Northstar crew through gameplay, you’ll also be able to see the beginning of their story. When you play the beta, you’ll be welcomed with the very first of our cinematic vignettes—brief cinematics that, when <em>Concord</em> launches, will premiere every week in game. When the beta early access launches and then when the open beta starts, we’ll introduce new cinematic vignettes in-game to give you a small glimpse into how the Northstar crew’s stories will unfold each week.</p></blockquote><p><em>Concord</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2443720/Concord/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/concord/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on August 23.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Didn't Care About Concord Until I Played It]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/i-didnt-care-about-concord-until-i-played-it/1100-6524530/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-didnt-care-about-concord-until-i-played-it.913467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/i-didnt-care-about-concord-until-i-played-it/1100-6524530/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Fire Walk With Me</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>I don’t envy the developers behind Concord. The hero shooter subgenre is a difficult space to break into, and cultivating a dedicated playerbase is even tougher. After seeing Concord’s gameplay reveal last month and its lukewarm response, I would have told you Firewalk Studios’ debut title would likely fall flat on its face.</p><p dir="ltr">However, after spending a few hours with Concord earlier this month, it’s clear that PlayStation and Firewalk Studios have built a solid foundation for its sci-fi multiplayer shooter. Mechanically, Concord sits somewhere between Overwatch and Valorant. Gun combat plays a big role in the moment-to-moment gameplay, but fast reaction times and pinpoint accuracy aren’t the be-all end-all of firefights. Each hero, or Freegunner as they are called, boasts a unique primary weapon, a distinct movement style, and two primary abilities. The lengthy time to kill lets all these different abilities shine without undermining the tight and responsive gunplay. Success requires good team composition, an understanding of each character’s abilities, and a bit of raw skill.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325525-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_42_02.still006.png" data-ref-id="1300-4325525" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325525-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_42_02.still006.png" data-ref-id="1300-4325525"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325525-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_42_02.still006.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">While most Freegunners still fit into a traditional role--such as a support or tank--they feel a bit more flexible than their Overwatch counterparts. You'd think Star Child, the blue and red behemoth with a large health pool, would be the ideal tank. But thanks to his well-rounded kit--including a primary ability that essentially turns him into a wrecking ball that charges across the battlefield--and his shotgun that doubles as an axe, he can fit into an offensive DPS role with hit-and-run tactics. In the back half of one game, I racked up a half dozen kills by outflanking the enemy team.</p><p dir="ltr">All 10 of the Freegunner’s I tested out felt deadly in their own way, while still playing towards specific roles. Vale is a sniper equipped with a bolt-action sniper rifle, a pistol, proximity mines, and an enhanced vertical leap. She thrives at range where she can pick off weakened enemies, but thanks to her trip mines, she can also control the flow of the battlefield. All three maps I played consisted of three interconnected lanes, and while a couple trip mines carefully placed along one of these corridors likely won’t stop an enemy team, they are sure to slow them down.</p><p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, Lennox is Concord’s Cole Cassidy, formerly McCree. Armed with a six shooter, explosive throwing knives, and a self-heal ability, Lennox feels like your standard high-skill DPS character. Lining up headshots is key, and activating his abilities at the right time can get you out of some sticky situations. Lennox captures that high risk, high reward playstyle. His self-heal makes him viable for lone wolf tactics, and if you can consistently land headshots, most enemies won’t last long.</p><p dir="ltr">My favorite Freegunner was Haymar, a crossbow wielding spellcaster that can hover around the map. Her Flameshot Bow fires an incendiary bolt that can deal significant damage on direct hits. Her abilities consist of a blinding flash that disorients enemies and a wall of fire that can create chokepoints. Flying around combat zones essentially flash banging enemies and laying down walls of fire while teammates cleaned up the stragglers was a blast.</p><p dir="ltr">Freegunners and their abilities aren’t set in stone, either. Firewalk Studios hopes to keep combat fresh with something called Combat Traits. Each Freegunner has a set of Combat Traits that act as perks. For example, Lennox had one that let him automatically reload when he dodged. This felt a little unbalanced in a PvP setting--especially when the main drawback of revolver is its slow reload speed--but it definitely has me curious how these Combat Traits could affect a Freegunner and their role within the team.</p><blockquote><p>Firewalk Studios has opted to lean into that asymmetry of its characters.</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">Flexible Freegunner roles and Combat Traits feed into Concord’s asymmetric combat. Each Freegunner has their own set of strengths and weaknesses thanks to their varied health pools, weapons, and abilities. This means some heroes may pair well with each other while others don’t. For example, there’s a support character named Daw who can put down AOE heal stations and force fields that block all incoming and outgoing fire. Daw is great for holding down objectives and keeping Star Child covered at long range. However, my team quickly learned that Daw’s force field ability could negatively impact all of our medium to long range heroes at crucial moments. Jabali on the other hand can heal teammates with a bit more precision thanks to his healing orbs, similar to Zenyatta’s Orbs of Harmony from Overwatch. Seeing how all these different Freegunners could compliment each other and counter the other team’s makes firefights feel dynamic and unpredictable.</p><p dir="ltr">Firewalk Studios has opted to lean into that asymmetry of its characters. While this will undoubtedly make specific matchups difficult, this imbalance forces you to work as a team, and use your character’s entire kit. Of course, the Firewalk Studios team will be monitoring balance once the game ends up in players hands, but according to Claude Jerome, the lead gameplay designer, that asymmetry is crucial to Concord’s heroes.</p><p dir="ltr">This asymmetry is not reflected in Concord's game modes and map design. I had the chance to check out three different game types: Trophy Hunt which is basically Kill Confirmed from Call of Duty, and Cargo Run and Clash Point which are round base modes with no respawn. As someone who’s played over 500 hours of Rainbow Six: Siege, Cargo Run and Clash Point were the highlights for me. The limited respawn and objective based gameplay required a level of coordination that you don’t always get in team deathmatch style modes. Unlike Siege and Valorant, Concord’s symmetrical maps meant that both teams were at an even playing field at the start of each round. This makes it easier to focus on team composition relative to your team rather than your starting location.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325531-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_53_48.still007.png" data-ref-id="1300-4325531" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325531-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_53_48.still007.png" data-ref-id="1300-4325531"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325531-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_53_48.still007.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325526-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_31_37.still005.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325527-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_10_17.still004.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325528-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_03_32.still003.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325529-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_33_49.still002.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325530-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_30_41.still001.png" data-ref-id="1300-4325526,1300-4325527,1300-4325528,1300-4325529,1300-4325530" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1512/15120939/4325526-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_31_37.still005.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1512/15120939/4325527-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_10_17.still004.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1512/15120939/4325528-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_03_32.still003.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1512/15120939/4325529-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_33_49.still002.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1512/15120939/4325530-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_30_41.still001.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325526-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_31_37.still005.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325527-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_10_17.still004.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325528-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_02_03_32.still003.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325529-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_33_49.still002.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4325530-01_concord_trophyhunt_ps5_vale%28sniper%29_teo%28soldier%29_loss.00_01_30_41.still001.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Concord’s mechanics may tread a lot of familiar ground within the hero shooter genre, but the way Firewalk Studios’ heroes, maps, and game modes compliment each other feels fresh. Each Freegunner has just enough flexibility to break out of their role if they need to, the simplistic arena-style maps prioritize smart ability usage over intimate map knowledge, and the game modes are just complicated enough to encourage teamwork. I’m curious to see if and how Concord holds up with more maps, characters, and game modes in the mix.</p><p dir="ltr">While I was impressed by the combat, I’m not entirely sold on the universe and the story Concord hopes to tell. Freegunner’s are outlaws that speed around the galaxy looking for adventure. Each week, Firewalk Studios will release a two minute vignette that plays when you boot up the game. These vignettes will shape an ongoing narrative that players will experience together.</p><p dir="ltr">Before my hands-on session, the studio showed us the first one, and its tone gave off a we-have-Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-at-home sort of vibe. Maybe it could build to something more interesting, or maybe I’ve just grown tired of that Marvel-esque tone, but it didn’t do much for me in the moment. I also wonder how Concord plans to onboard new players if they’ve missed the first few weeks of the story. According to the devs, they will make all those vignettes available on YouTube, but I can’t imagine players will actively seek those out.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Monkey Ball Player Plays Super Monkey Ball With Monkey In Ball]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-monkey-ball-player-plays-super-monkey-ball-with-monkey-in-ball/1100-6524559/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-monkey-ball-player-plays-super-monkey-ball-with-monkey-in-ball.913464/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-monkey-ball-player-plays-super-monkey-ball-with-monkey-in-ball/1100-6524559/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524559">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There are many wacky video game controllers out there, but it's fair to say that Dr. Tom Tilley has designed an unprecedented way to play Super Monkey Ball. In a viral internet video, Tilley shows off a DIY controller that's perfect for the game: a physical monkey in a ball that rotates like a trackball to handle the in-game simian.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gIlI3aXOIXA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gIlI3aXOIXA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Tilley showed off some aspects of the build in the video. It shares its basic design with a soccer-ball controller that the hacker built for use with Katamari Damacy. The sensor appears to be an upside-down ball mouse that's held in place with plastic balls (seemingly from old deodorant sticks) and mounted on a cardboard rack. Perhaps the most impressive aspect of the design is Tilley's 3D-printed model of Super Monkey Ball's cute mascot AiAI, who looks remarkably on-point.</p><p>Reached via email, Tilley explained the inspiration for the controller. "We lived in Thailand for about 10 years and while we were there I played an obscure Japanese arcade game called Armadillo Racing from 1992. The game cabinets have a trackball that you use to steer your armadillo and I thought it would be fun to try and recreate the experience."</p><p>"When I put some video up online people suggested trying it with Katamari Damacy and Super Monkey Ball and it felt very intuitive playing these games. When I was editing a thumbnail to go up on YouTube with some video playing Super Monkey Ball I photoshopped AiAI in a ball in place of the actual soccer ball and I think that was the genesis of going, "'Maybe I could use this with an actual monkey ball.'"</p><p>Tilley also explained some aspects of its creation: "The ball sits on top of an optical mouse to detect the mouse movement but there's still some variation in height as you roll the ball so the mouse tracking would be intermittent. To compensate, another deodorant roller is glued onto the mouse and the ball sits on top of this roller. As the soccer ball moves it turns the deodorant ball underneath the ball and the mouse sees it moving just as if you were moving the mouse over a surface."</p><p dir="ltr">In a <a href="https://x.com/DrTomTilley/status/1805843351217819935" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">follow-up post</a> on social media, Tilley said some upgrades are planned: "The legs are hinged and I've added some mount points where AiAi's knees should be," Tilley clarified to GameSpot. "I'm hoping to add a trailing wheel with a crank that will push the legs backwards and forwards as the ball rolls to make it look like AiAI is running inside the ball." We'll keep an eye out to see if Tilley can pull it off. The latest entry in the Super Monkey Ball series, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble/" data-ref-id="5000-618874">Banana Rumble</a>, released on Switch earlier in June.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Cloud Gaming coming to Amazon Fire TV in select markets]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-amazon-fire-tv-in-select-markets</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-amazon-fire-tv-in-select-markets.913458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-cloud-gaming-coming-to-amazon-fire-tv-in-select-markets<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Partnership begins next month, enables players in 25 countries to stream games via their Fire TV Stick</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Microsoft and Amazon are partnering to bring Xbox Cloud Gaming to more devices: specifically, the latest models of Amazon's Fire TV Stick.</p>
<p>The Xbox firm announced in a <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/06/27/xbox-cloud-gaming-amazon-fire-tv/">blog post</a> that the Xbox app will be made available on Fire TV in 2 selected markets from next month, enabling anyone with an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate membership to access the cloud gaming titles in Microsoft's library.</p>
<p>To begin with, the app will be limited to two devices: Fire TV Stick 4K and Fire TV Stick 4K Max, which were both released last year. These retail for $49.99 and $59.99 respectively, with Microsoft positioning this as a more affordable way to get into Xbox gaming.</p>
<p>Players will need a compatible Bluetooth-enabled wireless controller (which, as <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/xbox-gaming-on-amazon-fire-tv">Amazon's blog post</a> confirms, includes PlayStation's DualShock 4 and DualSense controllers) to access these titles.</p>
<p>While an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate membership is needed for the full library of titles, the Xbox app will give non-members the opportunity to play Fortnite.</p>
<p>The partnership is the latest in Microsoft's efforts to bring Game Pass via cloud gaming to more devices, following a <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-tv-key-to-taking-cloud-gaming-mainstream">similar partnership with Samsung</a> and its Smart TVs.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree sales top 5 million in three days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-sales-top-5-million-in-three-days</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-sales-top-5-million-in-three-days.913455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-sales-top-5-million-in-three-days<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Within its first three days of release, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">topped 5 million copies in sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">FromSoftware's one and only expansion for its 2022 hit started off strong, with the milestone deemed the result of "tremendous support from players all over the world, to whom we express our heartfelt gratitude."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"To the many who tread the path left by Kindly Miquella, we extend our heartfelt gratitude," it </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1806326803276906929">added</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">base version released two years ago, it sold </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-has-sold-12-million-copies-worldwide">12 million copies</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> within a month. With critical acclaim and strong word of mouth, it's gone on to net </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/elden-ring-tops-25-million-in-players-and-sales-ahead-of-expansion-launch">25 million copies and players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and was a big driver for Bandai Namco's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-posts-third-quarter-slump-despite-early-tekken-8-success">2022-2023</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> fiscal year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The expansion met similar acclaim, and further shows how much FromSoftware's profile has grown in the past 15 years.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Where does ">Where does <span>Elden Ring </span>go from here?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ahead of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Erdtree's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">release, game director </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hidetaka-miyazaki-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-interview">Hidetaka Miyazaki</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> indicated there was a possibility for more </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">in the future. He confirmed there were no plans for a second expansion or sequel, but kept the door open for something down the line.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Whatever form that takes, phones may be a part of those plans. Earlier this year, it was reported that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/mobile/report-tencent-wants-to-replicate-genshin-impact-success-with-mobile-version-of-elden-ring">Tencent</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was developing a mobile spinoff, but it's unclear where it stands now as the tech giant is looking to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-tencent-pivoting-from-licensed-games-to-own-works">distance itself</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from licensed titles.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">More recently, Miyazaki said he would be open to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">getting a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-movie-there-is-interest-dev-says/1100-6524511/">movie adaptation</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but such a project would need a "very strong partner" to tackle those efforts.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Checking Out Concord, PlayStation's Upcoming 5v5 Hero Shooter | New Gameplay Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/ngt/2024/06/27/checking-out-concord-playstations-upcoming-5v5-hero-shooter-new-gameplay-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/checking-out-concord-playstations-upcoming-5v5-hero-shooter-new-gameplay-today.913452/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/ngt/2024/06/27/checking-out-concord-playstations-upcoming-5v5-hero-shooter-new-gameplay-today<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>We got our first big look at Concord, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/state-of-play/2024/05/30/playstation-reveals-first-look-at-concords-5v5-fps-gameplay-out-this">PlayStation's upcoming 5v5 multiplayer hero shooter</a>, during a State of Play last month. And last week, we traveled to California to go hands-on with the game. <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2024/06/26/concord-feels-like-destiny-meets-overwatch">You can read&nbsp;<em>Game Informer's</em>&nbsp;full Concord preview thoughts here</a>, but in short: it feels great and we're excited to play more.&nbsp;</p>

<p>We have a lot of questions remaining about the game's progression, seasonal content, narrative emphasis, and more, but if the handful of hours we've played of Concord are any indication, developer Firewalk Studios has, at the very least, created a fun and great-feeling shooter. In today's New Gameplay Today, host Wesley LeBlanc talks about his visit to PlayStation's HQ to play the game with Kyle Hilliard and how he felt after checking out 10 of the game's 16 heroes and three of its gameplay modes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;<strong>Check it out for yourself in the Concord NGT below</strong>:&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XvpLE2j8ElU" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Head to&nbsp;<em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/gameinformer" target="_blank">YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for more previews, reviews, and discussions of new and upcoming games. Watch other episodes of&nbsp;<em>New Gameplay Today</em>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/ngt" target="_blank">right here.</a></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Bounty Hunter Remaster Brings Back Jango Fett in August]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-august</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-brings-back-jango-fett-in-august.913410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-august<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Aspyr has announced a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>remaster, bringing the 2002 original to PC and consoles complete with a visual overhaul and gameplay improvements.</p>
<p>According to a press release,&nbsp;<em>Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>will arrive on PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch on August 1st, and it'll sport improved environment textures and new dynamic lighting. It'll also allow you to use a flashlight to navigate dark areas.</p>
<p>What's more, if you manage to complete the game's campaign, you'll unlock a Boba Fett skin, allowing you to play through the entirety of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>as another of the most notorious bounty hunters in the galaxy.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-cutscene.jpg?itok=1VChhaPI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-bounty-hunter-remaster-cutscene.jpg?itok=XoaPH8WH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>is getting a remaster.</figcaption></figure><p>Aspyr, the studio handling the&nbsp;<em>Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>remaster, is well-known for its work remastering older games, and occasionally, that reputation isn't exactly a positive one.</p>
<p>In&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>terms, you might recognize Aspyr's name from the recent&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Battlefront Classic Collection</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-update-1">drew fan ire</a> for <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-aspyr-response">network connection issues</a>, the presence of bugs and issues that weren't problems in the original games, and more.</p>
<p>The studio was also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/jason-schreier-confirms-kotor-remake-done-by-aspyr-media">the original developer</a> on the long-awaited&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/star-wars-knight-of-old-republic-remake-kotor-remake"><em>Knights of the Old Republic&nbsp;</em>remake</a>, although development on that project was apparently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/theres-new-knights-of-old-republic-studio-taking-reins">taken over by Saber Interactive in August 2022</a>.</p>
<p>Outside the galaxies of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>, Aspyr has ported a number of other games to modern systems, the most recent of which being&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/tomb-raider-1-3-remastered"><em>Tomb Raider I-III Remastered</em></a>.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter</em>, it's a 2002 shooter originally developed and published by LucasArts.</p>
<p>The game sees bounty hunter Jango Fett hired by a Sith Lord to take down a Dark Jedi. Along the way, he becomes embroiled in a criminal conspiracy, because hey, what else is a Fett to do?</p>
<p>The remaster of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter&nbsp;</em>launches across PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch on August 1st. Watch this space for more info.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Albatroz is a Latin American backpacking RPG with glorious views in which you search for a walking mountain]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/albatroz-is-a-latin-american-backpacking-rpg-with-glorious-views-in-which-you-search-for-a-walking-mountain</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/albatroz-is-a-latin-american-backpacking-rpg-with-glorious-views-in-which-you-search-for-a-walking-mountain.913407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/albatroz-is-a-latin-american-backpacking-rpg-with-glorious-views-in-which-you-search-for-a-walking-mountain<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>(and also, your missing brother)</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_hAvsnxp.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>SOEDESCO</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/albatroz">Albatroz</a> is a "backpacking adventure <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>" that takes place in The Forbidden Lands, a photogenic wilderness "where two worlds converge". You are jaded city worker Isla, and you are here to search for your missing brother, who was himself searching for the mystical mountain of Albatroz - locally known as "the walking mountain", for reasons that you will never guess. There's no combat, and no enemies that I can see - instead, you'll occupy yourself with equipment management, repairing your dinky car, and improving your hiking skills using points earned by doing favours for villagers along the way.</p><!--more-->
<p>This, truly, is a combination of elements precision-tooled to entice the long-haul <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> fan burned out on the likes of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a>. It's a game of verdant valleys and big skies, whose otherworldly elements are kept in check by the practicalities of travel and survival. It's on show at Gamescom Latam 2024 at the São Paulo Expo centre - the first Latin American edition of Gamescom - and they've released a new trailer below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Albatroz | Gamescom Latam 2024 trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KR8FecuUvaQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Albatroz | Gamescom Latam 2024 trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KR8FecuUvaQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KR8FecuUvaQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KR8FecuUvaQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Speaking as somebody who can't finish a workday without wanting to hurry Bilbo Baggins-style out the door and straight into the nearest moderately-sized national park, I am dead keen on the "backpacking RPG" getup. I am considerably less keen on the game's being presented as a big vibrant metaphor for wrestling with loss and the process of self-discovery.</p>
<p>The trailer dialogue is so on the nose it gives me a nosebleed, and well, when is heading off into the wilderness <em>not</em> some variation on the act of letting go in order to find yourself? I'm probably being very condescending and unkind to developers Among Giants, here. I'm sure the sentiments are heartfelt. But I'm fervently hoping the full version involves much less poignant self-reflection and philosophising, and a lot more silent hiking and beholding.</p>
<p>The writing isn't all monuments to mortality. There are those villages, each of which has its history and spread of personalities. Providing these trips into town are appropriately spread out, I can imagine them being a nice change from the isolation of hiking - it depends how "vast" the environments are in practice. As for the survival elements, you can pass out if you run out of supplies, but it doesn't look like you'll be limping back to town with broken ankles and a case of dysentry. This feels much closer to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/brothers-a-tale-of-two-sons">Brothers: A Tale Of Two Sons</a> than The Revenant.</p>
<p>Albatroz is out this year. There's a demo on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2171880/Albatroz/">Steam</a>, which I'll be trying out later, unless I do succumb to the call of the open road, in which case I'll probably get as far as the local Dominos before heading back home to watch House Of The Dragon. If you enjoy going for long walks but would prefer a bit more friction, why not go for a stroll in Sons Of The Forest? Alice O (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pretty-walking-simulator-sons-of-the-forest-offers-peaceful-seclusion">says it's lovely in there</a> and she has yet to lie to my face.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree reaches 5M players in first week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24187358/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-copies-sold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-reaches-5m-players-in-first-week.913404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24187358/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-copies-sold<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="jCH23B"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24180518/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-review-dlc-fromsoftware"><em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a> sold 5 million units in its first three days of availability, publisher Bandai Namco announced Thursday, an impressive figure that equates to about one-fifth of the original game’s overall fanbase. </p>
<p id="YUp9Tc">Bandai Namco and developer FromSoftware announced in June, nine days ahead of the DLC’s launch, that <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1800890964925366476"><em>Elden Ring</em> had sold 25 million copies</a> since its release in February 2022. (It was the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23070948/elden-ring-sales-chart-npd-call-of-duty-best-sellers">bestselling game in the U.S. that year</a>, according to analysts.)</p>
<p id="3ZSoqi">That some 20% of all <em>Elden Ring</em> players have jumped into the notoriously difficult DLC is impressive, especially when you factor in the completion rate of the feats required to even access <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>. Two weeks prior to the DLC’s launch, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24176047/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-preparation-achievements-completed">more than half of all <em>Elden Ring</em> players across multiple platforms hadn’t defeated the two bosses</a> — <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-guide-walkthrough/22993446/radahn-location-general-starscourge">Starscourge Radahn</a> and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-guide-walkthrough/24087922/mohg-how-to-beat-boss-strategy">Mogh, Lord of Blood</a> — required to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24087766/how-to-access-dlc-start-location-requirements">access the <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> map</a>.</p>
<p id="wDdokG">Even today, more than 20% of <em>Elden Ring</em> players haven’t accomplished the most basic of feats: reaching the Roundtable Hold, where many of the game’s NPCs reside.</p>
<p id="icqjKG">Completion rates for felling Starscourge Radahn and Mogh, Lord of Blood have gone up since then, but, in some cases, only by a fraction of percentage points. It appears that the most dedicated <em>Elden Ring</em> players are the ones continuing into <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, which isn’t much of a surprise. But that stick-to-itiveness hasn’t prevented some players from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24186312/elden-ring-dlc-shadow-erdtree-difficulty-too-hard-git-gud">complaining that the DLC is unfairly hard</a>.</p>
<p id="ERQdww"><em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</em>’s early success only serves to reinforce what FromSoftware has already said: that <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22980899/elden-ring-new-franchise-fromsoftware">Elden Ring is a new franchise</a> for the developer that it hopes to “[expand] beyond the realm of games.”</p>
<p id="p72EeD"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> is available on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Windows PC, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X. If you’re struggling, check out Polygon’s extensive <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide"><em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree </em>guides</a> to finding the all-important <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24178006/scadutree-fragment-locations-all-where-to-find-sote-dlc">Scadutree Fragments</a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24183189/dlc-remembrance-all-rewards-how-to-get-sote">boss Remembrances</a>, and the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24180256/all-new-dlc-weapon-locations">weapons</a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24180257/all-spell-locations">spells</a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24177999/talisman-locations-all-dlc-sote">talismans</a>, and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-guide/24180255/all-new-dlc-armor-set-locations">armor</a> you’ll need to make the <em>Elden Ring</em> DLC slightly easier.</p>

  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where To Find Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree's Horned Warrior’s Sword]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-horned-warriors-sword-guide-1851563857</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-find-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-horned-warrior%E2%80%99s-sword.913401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-horned-warriors-sword-guide-1851563857<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="08c9dc3df2134292c55d387531b7c3d7" data-recommend-id="image://08c9dc3df2134292c55d387531b7c3d7" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Our bear-clad hero holds the extra-pointy Horned Warrior Sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Our bear-clad hero holds the extra-pointy Horned Warrior Sword." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="08c9dc3df2134292c55d387531b7c3d7" data-recommend-id="image://08c9dc3df2134292c55d387531b7c3d7" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Our bear-clad hero holds the extra-pointy Horned Warrior Sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The Horned Warrior’s Sword is a Curved Sword you can only discover in <em>Elden Ring</em>’s <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> expansion. If your build combines a bit of Strength or Dexterity with Faith, this could be a solid weapon to wield against your enemies. Its unique Ash of War makes it particularly fun in combat, and it automatically comes with two swords if you prefer dual-wielding.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Here’s what you need to know about the Horned Warrior’s Sword and where to find it.</p><h2 id="h230"><a id=""></a><strong>Horned Warrior’s Sword stats and features</strong></h2><p>The Horned Warrior’s Sword has a weight of 5.0 and requires the following stats to wield:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>STR - 11</li><li>DEX - 14</li><li>FAI - 14</li></ul><p>The weapon comes equipped with Ash of War: Horn Calling. This Ash of War invokes tangled horns on the sword’s blade before slamming it into the ground. The slam produces piercing horns that damage foes in a small AOE in front of you, making this good for letting groups of smaller baddies know when you’ve had enough of their crap.</p><p>The Horned Warrior’s Sword can be upgraded to +10 with Somber Smithing Stones.</p><h2 id="h231"><a id=""></a><strong>Horned Warrior’s Sword item description</strong></h2><p>The Horned Warrior’s Sword’s item description reads:</p><p>“Curved sword of the horned warriors, keepers of the tower.</p><p>The ornamental tangled horns allow the blade to serve as a medium for horn-calling.”</p><h2 id="h232"><a id=""></a><strong>Where to find the Horned Warrior’s Sword</strong></h2><p>You can farm the Horned Warrior’s Sword from any Horned Warrior in the Belurat Town Settlement legacy dungeon or elsewhere in the game. There’s one just up the stairs by the Small Private Altar Site of Grace (accessed along the main path) that makes for especially efficient farming.</p><p>However, you can get a guaranteed drop of the Horned Warrior’s Sword by defeating a specific Horned Warrior in the swamp area of the Belurat Town Settlement legacy dungeon. You’ll find him standing on a piece of dry land in the northwestern section of the swamp.</p><figure id="" data-id="04547642d922e565df3e96f0799005ed" data-recommend-id="image://04547642d922e565df3e96f0799005ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Horned Warrior’s Sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Horned Warrior’s Sword." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="04547642d922e565df3e96f0799005ed" data-recommend-id="image://04547642d922e565df3e96f0799005ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Horned Warrior’s Sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This dual-wielding enemy isn’t any stronger than any other Horned Warrior you’ve encountered in your adventure thus far, so just play smart and try to stay out of the poison as best you can. Once you take him down, you’ll earn a guaranteed Horned Warrior’s Sword as a reward.<br></p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Country's Controversial $60 Price Tag Makes Metroid Prime Feel Like A Steal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/donkey-kong-returns-hd-metroid-prime-remaster-price-1851563971</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-countrys-controversial-60-price-tag-makes-metroid-prime-feel-like-a-steal.913398/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/donkey-kong-returns-hd-metroid-prime-remaster-price-1851563971<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em> is an enhanced version of the 2o10 Wii game coming to Switch in 2025, and fans can’t believe Nintendo is charging $60 for it. The price was revealed in the new eShop listing and makes last year’s <em>Metroid Prime</em> Remaster look like an incredible deal by comparison. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196230" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="217" data-playlist="196230,196470,196307" data-current="196230"><div><p>This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21779.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Revealed in the big June Nintendo Direct, <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em> ports the platforming franchise’s 2010 revival to a modern platform with higher resolution graphics and, based on the trailer footage, some notable visual improvements to level backgrounds that give them more detail and depth. It also comes with the additional levels added to the previous 3DS port of the game, as well as a mode that scales down the difficulty. It’s a great game in a beloved franchise that deserved a comeback. But $60?</p><p>Some Switch owners on social media immediately scoffed at the price. Many shared screenshots of an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://hard-drive.net/hd/video-games/nintendo-holds-12-hour-meeting-to-decide-if-company-can-survive-selling-donkey-kong-country-tropical-freeze-for-less-than-60/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://hard-drive.net/hd/video-games/nintendo-holds-12-hour-meeting-to-decide-if-company-can-survive-selling-donkey-kong-country-tropical-freeze-for-less-than-60/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">old <em>Hard Drive</em> parody</a></span> titled “Nintendo Holds 12 Hour Meeting to Decide if Company Can Survive Selling ‘Donkey Kong Country: Tropical Freeze’ for Less Than $60.” Fans on Reddit <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1dpf4m2/donkey_kong_country_returns_hd_is_priced_at_60_usd/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1dpf4m2/donkey_kong_country_returns_hd_is_priced_at_60_usd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">were also flummoxed</a></span>. “I don’t understand why Nintendo gets away with this,” wrote one user. “If Ubisoft or EA pulled this type of stuff, you’d see dozens of boycott posts a day.”</p><p>You can see the logic in the company’s thinking. Since the sequel,<em> Tropical Freeze</em>, was priced at $60, doing the same for <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em> helps signal that it’s a similar value proposition, and deserves the same premium. On the other hand, <em>Tropical Freeze </em>was a Wii U port that added more to the previous version. It was also arguably a better game. </p><p>You can see a lot of examples of Nintendo experimenting with variable pricing for its back catalog. <em>Mario vs. Donkey Kong </em>was a remake of a Game Boy Advance Game and it was only $50. <em>Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp</em> was $60 but it included visual overhauls of two games. And then there was <em>Metroid Prime Remastered</em>, an immaculate re-rendering of the GameCube classic that was only $40. </p><p>That’s the one that has people scratching their heads the most in comparison to <em>Returns HD</em>. Does Nintendo just have less faith in the <em>Metroid</em> brand or did it just want to see what would happen if it sold <em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em>’s predecessor at a much more aggressive price? <em>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</em>, another remaster of a GameCube game, was $60 after all. Such is the power of the mustachioed plumber, even when he’s a 2D cutout. Then again, the <em>Super Mario</em> <em>3D All-Stars</em>, a collection containing <em>Super Mario 64, Sunshine, </em>and <em>Galaxy</em>, was $60 for three games. Who can know the mind of Nintendo? Not me. </p><p>It’s hard to get too mad at the company for trying to preserve the value of its back catalog, even if I’ll stick to my 3DS copy of the game at that price. But what it does do is make the anomaly of <em>Metroid Prime</em> feel like even more of a steal. The game’s even on sale right now for just $34 on the eShop. Hopefully, some potential <em>Metroid Prime 2</em> and <em>3 </em>remasters keep the trend going. Maybe they’ll even get bundled for $60 for both. A Nintendo fan can dream. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Miyazaki Says Finishing His Elden Ring Playthrough Was Difficult: "I Absolutely Suck At Video Games"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/miyazaki-says-finishing-his-elden-ring-playthrough-was-difficult-i-absolutely-suck-at-video-games/1100-6524564/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/miyazaki-says-finishing-his-elden-ring-playthrough-was-difficult-i-absolutely-suck-at-video-games.913395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/miyazaki-says-finishing-his-elden-ring-playthrough-was-difficult-i-absolutely-suck-at-video-games/1100-6524564/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524564">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's no secret that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/elden-ring/">Elden Ring</a>--like many From Software games--is quite challenging. But new players aren't the only ones having trouble mastering the game's intimidating combat system. From Software president and Elden Ring director Hidetaka Miyazaki struggles with the game's difficulty, too.</p><p dir="ltr">Miyazaki recently revealed that while he's very hands-on in terms of playing his games while they're being developed, he tends not to play his games after release.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1133914218" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464417,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Elden%20Ring%3A%20Shadow%20Of%20The%20Erdtree%20DLC%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:659,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review\/2300-6464417\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464417\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464417\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464417\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464417&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464417,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6524564&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;elden-ring&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,pc,playstation-4,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;bandai-namco-games,from-software&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464417},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464417\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4320544-review_eldenringshadowerdtree_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Z2o2UeDN.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1718719200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Z2o2UeDN" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree DLC Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">"After the release, I tend to not want to touch it, because I know I'm going to either find things that I left on the table or issues that will bug me," he said in a recent interview with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jun/26/pushing-buttons-meeting-hidetaka-miyazaki" rel="nofollow ">The Guardian</a>. "And once I become a player, I'm powerless to do anything significant to change it. So once a game is out in the wild, I tend to not play."</p><p dir="ltr">But things changed when it came to the development of the game's new DLC, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review-kill-them-with-kindness/1900-6418243/">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>. To prepare for the release of the DLC, Miyazaki played through the entirety of Elden Ring's main storyline, and just like many players, he faced some serious struggles.</p><p dir="ltr">"I want to preface this by saying I absolutely suck at video games, so my approach or play style was to use everything I have at my disposal, all the assistance, every scrap of aid that the game offers, and also all the knowledge that I have as the architect of the game," he explained. "The freedom and open-world nature of Elden Ring perhaps lowered the barrier to entry, and I might be the one who's benefiting the most from that, as a player, more than anyone else."</p><p dir="ltr">Historically, Miyazaki's games haven't had sequels (with Dark Souls being the exception), and it seems that Shadow of the Erdtree is the end of the road for Elden Ring--at least for now. But Miyazaki did claim he'd be open to a film project set in the Elden Ring universe, saying, "I don't see any reason to deny another interpretation or adaptation of Elden Ring--a movie, for example."</p><p dir="ltr">That said, Miyazaki and From Software aren't in a rush to sell off film rights to just anyone. If an Elden Ring movie happens, Miyazaki wants it done right.</p><p dir="ltr">"I don't think myself, or From Software, have the knowledge or ability to produce something in a different medium," he said of the potential for a film adaptation. "So that's where a very strong partner would come into play. We'd have to build a lot of trust and agreement on whatever it is we’re trying to achieve, but there’s interest, for sure."</p><p dir="ltr">As for his next game, there's no telling what Miyazaki is planning, but he did hint that future games will likely try to follow Elden Ring's slightly more forgiving game mechanics, as the game's open world allowed players to retreat from challenges that were too difficult, then return once they were better equipped to handle them.</p><p>"Traditionally, we've always liked the higher-difficulty curve type of games and experiences," he recently told <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/gaming/elden-ring-creator-hidetaka-miyazaki-talks-shadow-of-the-erdtree-new-weapons-and-more/#google_vignette">CNET</a>. "But I think that nature in and of itself alienates a portion of the game-playing audience, whereas Elden Ring succeeded in casting a wider net but at the same time keeping that core high learning curve."</p><p>Elden Ring's Shadow of the Erdtree expansion is available now and earned a rare 10/10. In <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review-kill-them-with-kindness/1900-6418243/" data-ref-id="1900-6418243">GameSpot's Shadow of the Erdtree review</a>, we said the new DLC "makes the game hard again." For players in search of a bigger challenge, Shadow of the Erdtree will not disappoint.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Dive: Designing a new dwarf race in The Last Spell]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/deep-dive-designing-a-new-dwarf-race-in-the-last-spell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deep-dive-designing-a-new-dwarf-race-in-the-last-spell.913392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/deep-dive-designing-a-new-dwarf-race-in-the-last-spell<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via DANGEN Entertainment.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer Deep Dives are an ongoing series with the goal of shedding light on specific design, art, or technical features within a video game in order to show how seemingly simple, fundamental design decisions aren’t really that simple at all.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer Deep Dives are an ongoing series with the goal of shedding light on specific design, art, or technical features within a video game in order to show how seemingly simple, fundamental design decisions aren’t really that simple at all.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Earlier installments cover topics such as </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/deep-dive-harnessing-the-power-of-player-feedback-with-dying-light-2">how</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/deep-dive-harnessing-the-power-of-player-feedback-with-dying-light-2"> </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/deep-dive-harnessing-the-power-of-player-feedback-with-dying-light-2">Techland centered player feedback in the development of</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/deep-dive-harnessing-the-power-of-player-feedback-with-dying-light-2">&nbsp;Dying Light 2</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>how the developers of</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;Insurgency&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/deep-dive-multiplayer-on-multiplatform-and-how-we-made-it-work-in-insurgency">created the architecture for console crossplay</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>, and how League of Geeks&nbsp;</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/deep-dive-solium-infernum">created a complex asynchronous multiplayer in</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/deep-dive-solium-infernum">&nbsp;Solium Infernum.</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>In this edition, Ishtar Games lead designer Robin Fau outlines the challenges in introducing a new race into their tactical roguelite RPG, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">The Last Spell</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hello, I’m Robin Fau, lead game designer for Ishtar Games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a tactical RPG with roguelite elements. In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the player defends the last bastion of humanity with a squad of heroes. Players fight to exterminate an overwhelming number of fiendish monsters with magic and brute force by night while also rebuilding their battered city defenses by day.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was first released in Early Access in 2021, and following months of implementing community feedback and growing the game, we released the V1 version in 2023. During the process of thinking about the content for the next DLC, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2795980/The_Last_Spell__Dwarves_of_Runenberg/">Dwarves of Runenberg</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which we released in 2024, we decided to integrate a brand new Game Design brick: a race system. An important point to begin: in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, what we call a "race system" here concerns a character class mechanism, separate from the narrative implications that character races can have in fantasy games. Our deep dive is focused on gameplay and game mechanics.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Setting up and creating a new race in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a complex process that requires harmonious integration with existing systems, while bringing in elements of novelty and excitement. The goal is to ensure that each new race brings a unique and interesting gaming experience, while respecting the game's initial balancing. In this article, we'll take a step-by-step look at how we integrated this new system.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Challenges"><span>Challenges</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When you start creating a new gameplay aspect for existing content that wasn't originally designed to be modified, you need to answer a number of questions:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">What is the current state of the game and what are our levers for action?</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">How can we create a malleable, iterative and sustainable system?</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">How can we weave the myths and clichés of a heroic fantasy race within </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> gameplay?</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">How can we offer a new aspect of gameplay, without unbalancing everything else?</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p>Image via DANGEN Entertainment.</p><h2 data-testid="content-text"><br>Step 1: Imagining the new race system</h2><h4 data-testid="content-text" id="How did heroes work before the DLC?">How did heroes work before the DLC?</h4><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, heroes are mainly defined by 2 systems: Traits and Perks. These elements are essential for customization and gameplay orientation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Traits </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">act as statistics that give a hero a specific history and role, slightly orienting their build. They allow you to differentiate each character from the outset by assigning them unique characteristics.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Perks </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">are powerful gameplay elements, the most exciting feature in character customization. They are chosen as you level up and allow you to customize your hero's build significantly. Perks offer passive advantages that can radically change the way a hero is played. There are eight perk collections available per hero:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Three fixed Archetype collections: Warrior, Archer, Mage.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Two Specialization Perk collections, chosen randomly from a pool of 4: Engineer, Plague, Hexer, Assassin.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Three miscellaneous collections, which select Perks from a pool.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="How can we embed the Dwarf Race into this system?">How can we embed the Dwarf Race into this system?</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We, therefore, have access to two powerful tools for customizing a hero. The first is changing attributes. By modifying them, we can better reflect the gameplay utility of the race. If we have a race with fewer hit points and a lot of dodging, we can easily project ourselves onto a nimble but frail race. However, certain Traits should be excluded for certain races, to avoid imbalances. For example, if a race has few health points via its attributes in conjunction with Traits that further reduce maximum health, you're going to have a major balancing problem.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For Perks, we decided on a collection based on the same principle as weapon collections (a collection of ten Perks, two Perks per tier), which will replace the "Miscellaneous" collection. The creative line of Perks should reinforce the unique identity of this race.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">However, a change of attributes doesn't offer a distinctive enough gameplay right from the start. That's why we're introducing an additional race-exclusive element: the racial Perk.</span></p><h4 data-testid="content-text" id="Racial Perk"><span>Racial Perk</span></h4><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The racial Perk is designed to offer a unique gameplay experience right from the start. A hero of one race should feel and play differently from a hero of another race. This Perk, available from the outset, brings a significant modification to gameplay that reflects the fundamental characteristics of the race. As a result, the player must immediately understand and adapt to the specifics of the chosen race. The racial Perk is the key to differentiating each race and offering varied gameplay strategies.</span></p><h4 data-testid="content-text" id="What defines a race in The Last Spell?">What defines a race in The Last Spell?</h4><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A new race in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is defined by several elements:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Race-specific starting stats: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">these stats give initial direction to the gameplay.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>A racial Perk: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">this unique Perk fundamentally changes the way the hero is played.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>A new collection of Perks: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">these Perks are designed to reinforce racial identity and offer rich and varied customization options.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Humans</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>: before embarking on the creation of new races, it's important to consider the race that’s already present in the game: the Humans. Although character customization allows for many variations, the basic characters are Humans. After careful consideration, we've decided to leave Humans unchanged so as not to disrupt player habits and to maintain a solid base for balancing. Humans serve as a stable reference for the introduction and balancing of new races.</span></span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Step 2: Designing a race in The Last Spell">Step 2: Designing a race in The Last Spell</h3><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Imagining a race">Imagining a race</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To illustrate our process, let's look at the creation of the Dwarves of Runenberg.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Dwarves of Runenberg are designed around five keywords: Robust, Brutish, Festive, Group, Slow.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These keywords guide the entire creation of their characteristics and gameplay. Once we've defined our guiding principles, all we have to do is transfer them to our race system:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starting statistics: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Dwarves have fewer movement points but more defense, reflecting their robustness and endurance. This also echoes the "Dwarf Blood" Trait that was already in the game, reinforcing their unique identity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Racial Perk: "Toss Me"</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - inspired by an iconic scene from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Lord of the Rings</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, this spell allows a nearby ally to throw a Dwarf, bypassing their natural slowness. This unique mechanic requires a nearby ally to activate, adding a new strategic dimension. "Toss Me" replaces the "Leap Frog" spell, an important skill (and highly appreciated by the community) for controlling your position on the battlefield.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Perk Collection: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">the Dwarves' Perk collection fully expresses their characteristics:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Jolly Drinker" counterbalances their slowness with a festive aspect, reinforcing their stamina.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Look At My Muscles" emphasizes their gruffness, enhancing their brute strength.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Warcry" and "Heart of the Party" emphasize the race’s robustness and togetherness, offering buffs to all allies.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p>Image via DANGEN Entertainment.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These Perks have been designed to integrate seamlessly with Dwarf gameplay and offer unique customization options. But that's not all: care must be taken to ensure they also integrate with all other non-racial Perk collections without favoring one Perk collection over another when generating the character. For example, we avoided having a Perk collection that focuses too much on poison and ends up having too strong a synergy with the existing poison collection, pushing the race to perform only with the available poison collection. It's all part of the bigger picture of balancing.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Balancing">Balancing</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Introducing a new race is a real challenge. One of the main ones is to ensure that the new race is balanced with the other races and does not create major imbalances in gameplay. To achieve this, we extensively tested the Dwarves in different game configurations, adjusting their stats and Perks as necessary.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> can be broken down into several configurations or phases during a game. For example, there's the beginning of the game, the middle and the end. You don't want a hero to be too strong at the start of the game, nor do you want them to be too weak at the end. Scaling is an important part of a hero's progress in the game. Then there's another configuration element to consider: scenarios where the player has one hero located all alone on one side of the Haven to individually defend against a wave of enemies, while having their other heroes far away on another side of the base defending against a different mob. This is where the perks that boost other heroes come into play, as well as a hero's mobility, etc. Last but not least, there's defense near/in the Haven and defense outside of the Haven. These configurations are not mutually exclusive, so you'll need to test each case several times, and with different hero setups... but it's impossible to cover every possible case. We also have to rely on the data we have on our spreadsheets, which are very precise, to get an overall idea of our balancing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We also took feedback from the community into account to fine-tune details and ensure that the race is both fun to play and competitive. The exercise is made all the more difficult by the integration of previously unknown mechanics. For example, "Warcry" and "Heart of the Party" are Auras, which are Perks that influence all Heroes on the map, not just the Perk holder. So far, there was no such mechanic, and it's a Perk that's cumulative </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>and</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> affects all the heroes on the map. We need to find a good middle ground. It's a fine balance, because you can quickly go from useless Perk to far too strong a Perk. This is where the testing and iteration phase comes in.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Iterating and testing">Iterating and testing</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Every change made to stats or Perks is carefully evaluated for its impact on gameplay. We have used combat simulations and in-game tests to observe how Dwarves behave in relation to other races. These tests have enabled us to identify potential imbalances and correct them before release. However, you have to remain humble with your work and be open to criticism. Beyond the initial design intent and our tests, we still need to listen to our players and be ready to make changes if necessary.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Visual and thematic design">Visual and thematic design</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition to the gameplay aspects, the visual and thematic design of Dwarves was a key element of the creative process. We worked closely with our artists to develop designs that captured the essence of the Dwarves. Their morphology, faces, skill VFX and animations were carefully crafted to reflect their story and character. Their visual design reinforces the player's immersion and complements the gameplay aspects to deliver a coherent and engaging experience.</span></p><h3 data-testid="content-text" id="Community feedback">Community feedback</h3><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The community plays a crucial role in the balancing process. Their feedback has been invaluable in adjusting aspects of gameplay and improving the gaming experience. For example, following a private Beta and since the release of the DLC, we were able to fine-tune the Dwarf race and ensure that it met our community's expectations. And even today, we're continuing this work to ensure the best possible version.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="In conclusion"><span>In conclusion</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">By following this methodical and creative process, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> manages to introduce its first new race and enrich the game while maintaining balance and coherence with existing elements.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This was no simple task, as balancing such a game is a difficult one: you have to bring relevant and interesting novelty to a systemically complex and complete game. Players can thus discover new ways of playing and new strategies, making the game experience even more captivating and varied. The creation of races such as the Dwarves demonstrates our commitment to offering innovative content and continually improving the gaming experience for our community.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The successful integration of the Dwarves of Runenberg into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> illustrates how a thoughtful and detailed approach can give rise to rich and engaging gameplay elements, offering players new challenges to overcome. We look forward to seeing how our players will continue to exploit the peculiarities of this new race, and how we will continue to enrich the world of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Last Spell</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gameloft Toronto staff laid off after studio 'substantially' reduces production activity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gameloft-toronto-staff-laid-off-after-studio-substantially-reduces-production-activity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gameloft-toronto-staff-laid-off-after-studio-substantially-reduces-production-activity.913389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gameloft-toronto-staff-laid-off-after-studio-substantially-reduces-production-activity<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Gameloft Toronto has laid off an undisclosed number of employees after reviewing its "production capacities."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Disney Mobile Kingdoms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-of-mass-layoffs-at-gameloft-toronto">confirmed the news in a statement to GI.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and said it had implemented a "reduction in workforce" due to fluctuating market conditions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As a company, we need to constantly review our production capacities. After careful consideration and in response to the ever-changing market conditions we are facing, it has become necessary to implement a reduction in workforce," reads the statement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Unfortunately, this leads us to substantially reduce our production activity in our Toronto studio and to let go some employees of the office. This decision has not been taken lightly, and we understand the impact it may have on affected employees. We will be working with them, on a case-by-case basis, to find the best way to handle their situation."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Most departments affected by the Gameloft Toronto cuts">Most departments affected by the Gameloft Toronto cuts</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">GI.biz was previously told 49 people, representing the majority of Gameloft Toronto, had been laid off. Speaking to the publication, sources claimed that only HR, IT, and management were unaffected by the job cuts, and that development of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Disney Magic Kingdoms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was being transferred to Gameloft's studio in Kharkiv, Ukraine. Another title the studio was reportedly working on has also been cancelled.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7211838073465184256/">Posting on Linkedin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, former Gameloft Toronto community team manager Tasha Huggins said "a lot of incredible talent has just entered the market. "If you are interviewing anyone from the Gameloft Toronto/</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Disney Magic Kingdoms</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> team, please reach out to me. I would love another opportunity to talk about just how amazing they are," she added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Layoffs and studio closures continue to decimate the video game industry. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/layoffs">Thousands of developers have lost their jobs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> since the turn of the year, including those working at major players like Microsoft, Sony, Embracer, Take-Two, EA, and more.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring's Shadow of the Erdtree DLC hits 5m sales]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-hits-5m-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-rings-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-hits-5m-sales.913362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-hits-5m-sales<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>20% of all players have returned.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ER_SOTE_screenshot-(7).png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Elden Ring DLC</a> Shadow of the Erdtree has reached 5m sales worldwide, in just three days of release.
</p>
<p>
Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-has-shipped-25m-units-worldwide">Elden Ring had shipped 25m units</a>, meaning 20 percent of all players have already jumped back in for the DLC in its opening weekend.
</p>
<p>
"To the many who tread the path left by Kindly Miquella, we extend our heartfelt gratitude," reads a social post to celebrate.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ELDEN RING Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ELDEN RING Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bGFvUgQyJ00?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Launch Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bGFvUgQyJ00" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
Let's just hope all those who <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/time-is-running-out-to-prepare-for-elden-ring-dlc-shadow-of-the-erdtree">bought the DLC have actually been able to access it</a> - as it requires killing two specific bosses in the base game which, as per Steam records earlier in June, only 37.8 percent of players had managed.
</p>
<p>
A quick check on Steam now shows 40.3 percent of players have the necessary achievement, so Tarnisheds have been busy.
</p>
<p>
Shadow of the Erdtree has received plenty of praise, as well as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-review">criticism from critics</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-dlc-falls-to-a-mixed-steam-rating-as-pc-players-complain-about-difficulty-and-performance">players alike</a> in part for its high difficulty.


</p>
<p>
One <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-legend-let-me-solo-her-is-back-but-with-a-new-name">returning player is Let Me Solo Her</a>, who's back with a new name to kill one of the DLC's toughest bosses.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Bounty Hunter gets a remake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-bounty-hunter-gets-a-remake</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-bounty-hunter-gets-a-remake.913359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-bounty-hunter-gets-a-remake<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
Star Wars: Bounty Hunter, the 2002 action-adventure game, is getting a remake courtesy of Aspyr.
</p>
<p>
The developer describes this as "a new title that brings the original Star Wars: Bounty Hunter to modern platforms with visual enhancements, improved environmental textures, new dynamic lighting effects, and a new flashlight tool."
</p>
<p>
It's set for release on 1st August across Switch, PS5, PS4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S and PC (Steam). It'll be priced at $19.99 (£TBA).
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="STAR WARS™: Bounty Hunter™ - Announce Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jiBmgse9GTc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>STAR WARS™: Bounty Hunter™ - Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jiBmgse9GTc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jiBmgse9GTc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Star Wars: Bounty Hunter<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jiBmgse9GTc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>

The game has players in the role of Jango Fett shooting and gliding his way across the galaxy, though in this version players will be able to unlock a new Boba Fett skin too as part of an Easter egg from the original game.
</p>
<p>
Our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-swbountyhunter-ps2">Star Wars Bounty Hunter review</a> from back in the day described the game as "pretty and stylish" but the Star Wars setting "can't mask the shallow, unexciting gameplay from view".

</p>
<p>
Aspyr, part of Embracer Group, has released a number of Star Wars re-releases and remakes, including most recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/players-criticise-star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-for-bugs-server-woes-at-launch">Star Wars: Battlefront Classic Collection</a>, which was plagued with bugs and server woes at launch.

</p>
<p>
It also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-2-the-sith-lords-restored-content-dlc-has-been-cancelled">cancelled expected DLC for Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic 2 - The Sith Lords</a>, which would have restored lost content.

</p>
<p>
Outside of Star Wars, the developer was mostly praised for its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tomb-raider-i-iii-remastered-review">Tomb Raider 1-3 Remastered collection</a>, but courted controversy with the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tomb-raider-1-3-remastered-will-restore-pin-up-posters">inclusion of pin-up posters</a>.

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I will literally PayPal you a fiver if you can tell me anything substantial about Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree’s gormless ghost worms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-will-literally-paypal-you-a-fiver-if-you-can-tell-me-anything-substantial-about-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-gormless-ghost-worms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-will-literally-paypal-you-a-fiver-if-you-can-tell-me-anything-substantial-about-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%E2%80%99s-gormless-ghost-worms.913356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-will-literally-paypal-you-a-fiver-if-you-can-tell-me-anything-substantial-about-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-gormless-ghost-worms<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-ghost-worm.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>YouTube is a stocked repository of hours upon hours of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-boss-locations">Elden Ring</a> lore. Ranni’s ending? No worries. Miquella and St. Trina? We got you. Mohg and the Formless Mother? Say no more. Turtle Pope? Sit back. The frenzied flame? Make yourself comfortable. The Elden Ring itself? One page is not enough to contain it all.</p>
<p>And yet, what use are any of you when I cannot find a single solitary lore snippet about these idiot worms?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Here is everything I know about these worms:</p>
<ul>
<li>They like to hang out near gravestones, but so do a lot of things.</li>
<li>They seem to be somehow connected to the spirit jellyfish in the Lands Between. They even glow red when they’re angry.</li>
<li>I found a bunch of them protecting a turtle once.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m honestly ravenous for lore here. They’re so numerous and prominent in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-how-to-start">Shadow Of The Erdtree</a> that I’m convinced that they’re absolutely vital to the entire setup. They don’t seem to drop any items. None of the NPCs will shut up about Miquella long enough to give me a scrap of information about them. I tried asking one some questions and it just very slowly retreated into the dirt.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-worm-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I’m lost. Rudderless. Completely stranded in a world in which I understand zilch about its most interesting inhabitants. This is not subtle worldbuilding - it’s deeply unethical. Please, help me understand. First person to tell me something good gets a fiver. I mean, not really, but you know.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take Out Conor McGregor In The Newest Hitman DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hitman-dlc-conor-mcgregor-elusive-target-mma-1851563950</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-out-conor-mcgregor-in-the-newest-hitman-dlc.913353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/hitman-dlc-conor-mcgregor-elusive-target-mma-1851563950<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Much as it stuns me to admit, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/hitman-world-of-assassination&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/hitman-world-of-assassination"><em>Hitman: World of Assassination</em></a></span><em> </em>is evidently <em>still</em> receiving DLC years after its release, and its latest bit might be my personal favorite. That’s because the newest mission tasks Agent 47 with eliminating none other than Conor McGregor, MMA’s most infamous fighter.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196653,196307" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Hitman: World of Assasination</em>, which bundles <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-the-hitman-trilogy-levels-from-worst-to-best-1846368844&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-the-hitman-trilogy-levels-from-worst-to-best-1846368844">the three IO Interactive-developed titles</a></span> into a single package,<em> </em>has long featured limited-time missions called elusive targets that provide players with one opportunity to kill the target or fail the mission forever. You are allowed to restart them if you haven’t died or completed all of the objectives already, but if you happen to do either of those, you will be locked out of the mission. So if you’ve got some shit to take out on McGregor in the game, you best make your shot count.</p><p>McGregor will be appearing in <em>Hitman </em>as a, you guessed it, MMA fighter known as The Disruptor, and will actually be facing off in a match against a character previously featured in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hitman-3-the-kotaku-review-1846083354&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hitman-3-the-kotaku-review-1846083354"><em>Hitman 3</em></a></span> on a map from <em>Hitman 2</em>. It is apparently Agent 47’s responsibility to take him out before the match actually begins, and according to the trailer, it doesn’t sound like the other guy stands a chance against The Disruptor.</p><p>The Disruptor is not only modeled after Mcgregor, but is in fact, fully voiced by the fighter-turned-movie-star too. Earlier this week, McGregor revealed he would be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dualshockers.com/conor-mcgregor-says-new-video-game-announcement-this-week/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dualshockers.com/conor-mcgregor-says-new-video-game-announcement-this-week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">starring in a game</a></span> that’d be announced sometime in the next few days before deleting his post on X (formerly known as Twitter). Now I guess we know what he was talking about!</p><p>McGregor has not only made a name for himself in the ring, but outside of it too. He’s taken on quite the reputation for mouthing off about opponents outside of fights, earning him the moniker “The Notorious,” and on top of that, the guy has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/conor-mcgregor-ufc-champion-timeline-arrests-abuse-1234772835/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/conor-mcgregor-ufc-champion-timeline-arrests-abuse-1234772835/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">courted controversy after controversy</a></span>, including sexual assault allegations against him, as well as the most assault charges I’ve ever seen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conor_McGregor&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conor_McGregor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on a Wikipedia page</a></span>. Talk about a distinguished record...</p><p>Unfortunately, none of it has slowed or hurt his career all that much, as evidenced by the fact that he appeared as one of the central villains in the piss poor remake of <em>Road House </em>on Prime Video earlier this year. Not only did I have the misfortune of watching that god awful CGI-ridden mess, but I eventually convinced my dad to watch it with me too. So if I do jump into the elusive target mission, I’ll get vengeance for myself as well as my dad.</p><p>McGregor’s mission will be available from June 27 to July 29, so in case you need to reinstall the game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hitman-studio-s-project-007-will-feature-a-new-james-bo-1846137133&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hitman-studio-s-project-007-will-feature-a-new-james-bo-1846137133">IO Interactive</a></span> has given you ample time. Get at it folks, let him know what you all really think of him.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Games Co-Founder Never Wanted A GTA Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-games-co-founder-never-wanted-a-gta-movie/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-games-co-founder-never-wanted-a-gta-movie.913350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-games-co-founder-never-wanted-a-gta-movie/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>There were talks for a Grand Theft Auto (GTA) movie, but it never got much further than that.</p>



<p>Dan Houser, the co-founder of Rockstar Games and former head writer at the studio, recently <a href="https://theankler.com/p/dan-houser-absurd-ventures-hollywood-videogames" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">spoke to The Akler</a> where he talked about the time Rockstar met with Hollywood executives about making a possible film.  These “awkward dates”, as he called them, had him never being convinced howa movie could benefit Rockstar more than the games themselves would.</p>



<p>“[W]e’d ask [the executives], why would we do this?” Houser said, to which the response would always be along the lines of, “You get to make a movie”.</p>



<p>“And we’d be like, no, what you’ve described is&nbsp;you&nbsp;making a movie and us having no control and taking a huge risk that we’re going to end up paying for with something that belongs to us,” he said.</p>



<p>He then continued to talk about how it felt like the executives pitching a movie to Rockstar thought the company would be “blinded by the lights” of Hollywood. Houser said, however, that the company never wavered on what it knew it had with the GTA franchise.</p>



<p>“We had what we considered to be multi-billion-dollar IP, and the economics never made sense,” he said. “The risk never made sense. In those days, the perception was that games made poor-quality movies.”</p>



<p>He did admit, though, that times have changed, especially with quality adaptations of games into TV shows such as The Last of Us and Fallout.</p>



<p>Houser left Rockstar Games in 2020. He now leads a new studio, Absurd Ventures, that is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dan-houser-rockstar-studio-open-world-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working on new third-person open-world game</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think about Rockstar ever working to make a GTA movie? For more Insider Gaming, read what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-addresses-the-length-between-its-major-game-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo had to say about how long it takes</a> to develop and release new games, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more. </p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home first details, screenshots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home-first-details-screenshots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home-first-details-screenshots.913347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home-first-details-screenshots<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Mobile Harvest Moon game due out in August.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Natsume [115 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/natsume">Natsume</a> has released the first information and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home">Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home</a></em>, its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home-announced-for-ios-android">recently announced</a> <em>Harvest Moon</em> game coming to iOS and Android in August. <span id="more-895601"></span></p><p>“In <em>Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home</em>, players are tasked with going back home to where it all started to help their childhood village get back on track,” said Natsume president and CEO Hiro Maekawa in a press release. “<a title="Platforms > Mobile [2,454 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">Mobile</a> gamers will love this robust new standalone farming experience where they can help their beloved village flourish with new tourists, new residents, new crops and more, all without any in-app purchases.”</p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p>In <em>Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home</em> it’s time to head back to your roots and leave the city life for your childhood village of Alba, where the freshest fish and tastiest veggies are grown and caught by the local farmers and anglers.</p><p>However, with its population getting older and younger villagers leaving for the big city, Alba Village has seen better days, so can you help turn it from a village on the decline to one of prosperity? With its beautiful surroundings, Alba definitely has the potential, but can you bring tourists and even new residents to this sprawling green village?</p><p><em>Harvest Moon: Home Sweet Home</em> is the biggest <em>Harvest Moon</em> game ever on mobile! In addition, you can woo four different bachelors and four different bachelorettes, and marry whomever your heart desires. Reunite with your childhood friend and other familiar faces to help put Alba on the map!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Harvest crops, take care of animals, fish, mine, and more. Collect and gather Happiness to grow the village and get new residents, while competing and taking part in various contests and festivals!</p></blockquote><p>View the screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/harvest-moon-home-sweet-home/june-27-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_895603"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>