<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:58:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Boss Says 'A Real Fan' Will Pay $80 For Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-games-1851781445</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-boss-says-a-real-fan-will-pay-80-for-games.1194027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-games-1851781445<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Game prices have been the subject of controversy since games had prices. How much is a game worth? What qualities or aspects of a game justify a higher price tag, or demand a lower one? Does a game that costs $70 deserve the same critical reaction as the identical game but $30? All this has gone on since time immemorial. But something that seems to rumble underneath so much of the discussion is rich people telling poor people that prices don’t matter. When asked about a potential $80 cost for <em>Borderlands 4</em>, multi-millionaire Randy Pitchford—CEO of developer Gearbox—told a potential customer, “If you’re a real fan, you’ll find a way to make it happen.”</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196163" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Firefight’s Back In Halo! What Is Firefight?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="106" data-playlist="196163,196653,195371" data-current="196163"><div><p>Firefight’s Back In Halo! What Is Firefight?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21695.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Pitchford offered his reasoning for being so certain of this. In 1991 when he had just left high school and was working a minimum-wage job at an ice cream parlor on Pismo Beach, he was able to find a way to pay $80 for <em>Starflight</em> on the Sega Genesis. So, you know, so can everyone else. Pitchford sent the message as a reply on X last week, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/games/borderlands/gearbox-boss-randy-pitchford-says-its-not-my-call-if-borderlands-4-costs-usd80-but-if-youre-a-real-fan-youll-find-a-way-to-buy-it-anyway/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/borderlands/gearbox-boss-randy-pitchford-says-its-not-my-call-if-borderlands-4-costs-usd80-but-if-youre-a-real-fan-youll-find-a-way-to-buy-it-anyway/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spotted by <em>GamesRadar</em> today</a></span>.</p><p>Randy Pitchford grew up in Fairfax, Virginia, then California. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20190112044349/https://www.kotaku.com.au/2012/05/randy-pitchford-and-the-perfect-shuffle/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190112044349/https://www.kotaku.com.au/2012/05/randy-pitchford-and-the-perfect-shuffle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His father worked in U.S. intelligence</a></span> in the 1970s, and his house was filled with all manner of technology throughout his childhood. While I cannot say for sure (although I have emailed to find out), it seems vanishingly unlikely that Pitchford was living off of his minimum wage ice cream job after he’d graduated high school, as his tweet seems to want to heavily imply. Pitchford soon after went to UCLA, so we can quite safely guess that this was a short-term job, one for earning a bit of extra spending money while still living at home with his parents.</p><p>I would suggest that to use this anecdote to explain to all living humans that if they really want a copy of <em>Borderlands 4</em>, they can easily find eighty bucks to spare is grotesque. It kind of makes me sick.</p><h2 id="h333136"><a id=""></a>Luxury viewpoints</h2><p>“Video games are a luxury.” That’s a point many people want to make in situations like this. “If you can afford the console to play the game on...” people might begin, as they argue that you can’t really be <em>that</em> poor if you can still afford entertainment. All those people living on welfare, but with those giant TVs, etc. It’s a fascinating perspective, almost exclusively proffered by those who <em>aren’t</em> living on welfare, and have rarely truly wanted for anything. Because if there’s one thing that’s pretty damned desirable when you’re living in real poverty, it’s some option for positive entertainment. For so many others, furiously working and saving and scraping together the money to be able to buy their children a games console, to give them that one thing they so desperately want when they’ve had to go without so much else, is not an act of opulence but of enormous sacrifice.</p><p>So no, this isn’t about abstract situations made up by armchair philosophers trying to justify Pitchford’s claim by arguing that any truly poor person have to choose between food or games entirely. This is about reality, where a person might go without so much extra food, or only buy the very cheapest food, so that they can pull together the $60 that year to buy the new entry in their favorite gaming franchise. That little bit of light. And then they find out it’s maybe now going to cost $80 instead.</p><h2 id="h333137"><a id=""></a>For 37 million Americans, there <em>isn’t</em> an extra $20</h2><p>In 2023 (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.census.gov/library/publications/2024/demo/p60-283.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.census.gov/library/publications/2024/demo/p60-283.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the most recent data</a></span>), <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/09/magazine/poverty-by-america-matthew-desmond.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/09/magazine/poverty-by-america-matthew-desmond.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23 percent</a></span> of Americans worked in low-wage jobs. In 2021, according to the U.S. Census Bureau, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/may/10/poverty-paradox-new-book-mark-rank-us-economic-hardship&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/may/10/poverty-paradox-new-book-mark-rank-us-economic-hardship" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11.6 percent</a></span> of Americans lived in poverty, a total of 37.9 million people. An example of “poverty” was given as “a family of three with income below $21,559.” In 2025, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://aspe.hhs.gov/topics/poverty-economic-mobility/poverty-guidelines&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/topics/poverty-economic-mobility/poverty-guidelines" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Department of Health and Human Services</a></span> describes poverty for an individual as living on less than $15,650 a year. This is all before the recent raids on welfare. </p><p>That breaks down to $1,300 a month. The average rental price for a one-bedroom apartment in the United States is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.apartments.com/rent-market-trends/us/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.apartments.com/rent-market-trends/us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$1,625 a month</a></span>. The average monthly household expenses for a single person <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ramseysolutions.com/budgeting/american-average-monthly-expenses&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ramseysolutions.com/budgeting/american-average-monthly-expenses" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">come to $4,641</a></span>, including food, insurance, rent, cell phone, internet, and personal care. Even taking into account that these are averages, it’s pretty obvious that when you’re one of the one-in-nine people living on $1,300 a month, you don’t have a lot of spare piles of $80. In 2012 (soon after the crash), <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/08/01/157664524/how-the-poor-the-middle-class-and-the-rich-spend-their-money&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/08/01/157664524/how-the-poor-the-middle-class-and-the-rich-spend-their-money" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">it was reported that the poorest people in America spent 98 percent of their income</a></span>, with one dollar per day to save. That study showed this group spends 4.8 percent of their income on “entertainment,” a broad category that even includes pets. An $80 copy of <em>Borderlands 4 </em>is 6.2 percent of $1,300.</p><p>Jump forward to the pre-covid boom in 2019, and on an annual family household income of $25,525, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://engaging-data.com/household-spending-income/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://engaging-data.com/household-spending-income/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">total spending is measured to be $25,525</a></span>. Of that, for an average family in this bracket, a total of $1,270 is spent on “entertainment.” That’s roughly $105 a month. But, again, it’s essential to understand that “entertainment” includes all sporting activities, all children’s extra-curricular education, toys, bikes, every electronic item from a TV to a camera, and even musical instruments and pets. If you own a dog, you’ll know that $105 a month could be taken up by it alone.</p><p>For so many of us, finding another $20 to buy a favorite game means grumbling and pulling out our wallet. But for so many others, it means not buying the one game we were hoping to play this year.</p><h2 id="h333138"><a id=""></a>“But if you’re a real fan...”</h2><p>Hopefully, this context suggests why it’s just so revolting for a man <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gearbox-has-been-bought-for-1-3-billion-1846186922&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gearbox-has-been-bought-for-1-3-billion-1846186922">who sold his company for a potential $1.3 billion in 2021</a></span> to tell someone on X that “if you’re a real fan, you’ll find a way to make it happen.” Because, you know, when he was doing a summer job at the beach in California, he somehow pulled enough cash together for that game he wanted.</p><p>It’s gross. It sucks. I’m fed up of it. I’m sick of rich people telling poor people that they can find the money if they just try hard enough. I’ve had my fill of people who’ve never known hunger, never struggled to pay a bill, flippantly dismissing the concept that life is extremely tough for millions and millions of people. It’s the rhetoric that allows for the myth of the “welfare queen” to be so readily accepted, to assume that the poorest people just aren’t pulling their weight or working hard enough, that if these people were <em>really</em> poor, they wouldn’t be playing video games at all. It’s <em>hateful</em>.</p><p>As for whether <em>Borderlands 4</em> will cost $80, Pitchford claims it’s “not my call,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-price-preorders-randy-pitchford-pax-east-1851780045&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-price-preorders-randy-pitchford-pax-east-1851780045">having previously said it’s still undecided</a></span>. Whether it will be <em>worth</em> $80—that’s entirely in the wallet of the beholder.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet the Man Who Designed Pokémon’s Iconic Logo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-man-who-designed-pokemons-iconic-logo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meet-the-man-who-designed-pok%C3%A9mon%E2%80%99s-iconic-logo.1194015/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-man-who-designed-pokemons-iconic-logo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">When you get a spontaneous call from the president of Nintendo of America, you don’t ask too many questions. You just take the call.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s the advice that was given to designer Chris Maple by a fellow designer friend back in 1998, who warned him the call would be coming later that day. At the time, Maple was no stranger to sudden phone calls from company executives. Maple ran his own design business, Media Design, which specialized in last-minute work for companies in emergency, time-crunch situations whose agencies weren’t equipped to handle the speed or size of their request. Though it was rarely, if ever, publicly credited for this type of work, over Media Design’s history, Maple says his company quietly developed a good reputation with clients throughout its local Seattle area. He recalls doing work for (among many others) Boeing, the Seattle Mariners, Holland America Line cruises, and others.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Maple had been in the business for several years when then-Nintendo of America president Minoru Arakawa’s secretary phoned him and asked him to come visit the office in Redmond. He was told over the phone that the company wanted him to work on a new game, but that was it. Maple, intrigued, accepted the invitation, not knowing he was about to become an instrumental part of one of the biggest cultural phenomenons in the world: Pokémon.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Go West, Pocket Monsters</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">“So I showed up there and I sat in their lobby for about a half hour and stared at this beautiful 21-inch crystal horse in their lobby, a crystal horse head,” Maple recalls of the day he went to Nintendo of America’s Redmond HQ. “And I was like, just staring. You get a sensation. Like I'd have to read a room when I go into these corporate arenas, since I'm the subjective person presenting the aspect of imagery and content behind whatever's bothering them that day or what's broken or what needs to be fixed. You just learn to pick up stuff. So I was sitting there staring at this crystal head, and it was the Nintendo lobby.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eventually, Maple was taken upstairs into a meeting room where a few individuals were sitting, waiting for something. “It looked like the inquisitor was going to come out,” Maple recalls. But when Arakawa entered, Maple says he “was a very magnetic personality. I could tell why he was in the seat.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ll let Maple relate what he remembers happening next:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“He introduced himself and said that they're going to be launching a game officially in the United States and Europe. Only problem is, the prior agencies they've tried out for the situation didn't quite hit the mark, and they burnt the budget and time element. Are you okay with that? And I go, ‘Yeah, sure. It's going to cost a penny.’</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/pokemon-15-1747669946566.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A photo of Maple and his son in Maple's home office. Photo provided by Chris Maple.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“So this other person, she comes down and she has a little cardboard box, and she dumps all these toys and pieces of paper and weird drawings and things all in front of me on the table, and I'm looking at them, and she's standing there with a smirk on her face holding the box, and I'm looking at Mr. Arakawa, and he's just staring straight at me and I go, ‘What is this?’ And he goes, ‘It's a Pocket Monster.’ And I said, ‘Oh, what's a Pocket Monster?’ He goes, ‘It's Pokémon. We're going to call it Pokémon.’”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>And I said, ‘Oh, what's a Pocket Monster?’ He goes, ‘It's Pokémon. We're going to call it Pokémon.’”</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Maple was being asked to make a new logo for Pokémon, which at the time existed only in Japan as Pocket Monsters Red and Pocket Monsters Green. Nintendo wanted to release the game in the West with a Blue version and, later, a Yellow Pikachu Edition. But the company wanted a new logo to fit the rebrand from “Pocket Monsters” to “Pokémon”, and was struggling to find someone to nail the look. Maple wasn’t given any instruction on what Nintendo was looking for though, he says. Just one parameter: he had just one month to make it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Attaching Energy</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Normally, Maple tells me, a logo like this would take something like six months, with lots of back and forth between the designer and client, drafts and redrafts. Nintendo’s one month deadline wasn’t arbitrary, though. The new logo had to be ready for the big unveiling of Pokémon Red and Blue that would take place at E3 1998.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Maple was used to cramming things like this into short spans of time. So he got to work. He drew numerous variations of a Pokémon logo by hand, on a light table, trying different letter shapes until he was happy with something. When he liked a logo, he’d set it aside, and try again to make something different, ultimately creating several variations to present to Nintendo so they could pick which they liked best. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Original Pokemon Logo Sketches by Chris Maple</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, there wasn’t much to go on. Maple wasn’t given copies of the games to play, or even a lot of information on what Pokémon was. “We were given nothing but paper and toys,” he says, recalling that one of the toys was a very tiny Pikachu figurine. Nintendo did explain the game a little bit, he says, and he saw some illustrations of both existing and in-progress monsters as well as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pokemon/comments/y3rfi/the_pok%C3%A9mon_are_coming_scan_from_may_1998/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an early version of a Nintendo Power magazine</u></a> that discussed the game (the final version of which would be the logo’s actual public debut). Maple was also instructed that the logo would need to be suitable for use on a tiny, pixelated GameBoy screen, and would have to work in both color and black and white.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After coming up with several variations, Maple took his suggestions back to Nintendo to present them. He tells me he opened by presenting a few versions he wasn’t as excited about, and says his audience was relatively unresponsive. But then, he showed his favorite.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The room was quiet, Maple says. He stayed quiet too. Then, again from Maple’s own recollection:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then Don James [former Nintendo of America executive VP of operations] speaks up and says, ‘I believe this is the one.’ And he starts shaking his head. He goes, ‘Yep, that's the one. It's the one.’ And everyone, Arakawa's just sitting there. He goes, ‘Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Okay.’ And Lance [Barr, former Nintendo of America designer] gets up and leaves and Gail [Tilden, former Nintendo of America VP brand management] leaves and then Don looks at me and goes, ‘Produce it.’ I went, ‘Okay.’ So I went back and produced it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And so the Pokémon logo was born. I asked Maple why he liked the final version best, and why he thinks Nintendo accepted it. He tells me he can’t fully explain it. It’s vibes, he says.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Energy in it. Also, when I was trying to take some of the real rough sketches from the original artists that did it for the person who started the game, I was trying to envision the story. There's a story in everything, the story, brand story, what it possibly could turn into.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/pokemon-12-1747670798361.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Color tests for the Pokémon logo, provided by Chris Maple.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Maple has a similar explanation for why the logo ended up yellow and blue. He tried a bunch of different color schemes. Maple admits it’s possible he was subconsciously thinking about the color-themed naming of the two new games being released in the West: Blue and Yellow. While Pokémon originally released in Japan in Red and Green versions, only Red was brought to global release alongside a slightly different, Blue version. Yellow, focused on Pikachu, came the following year. Maple was told about both Blue and Yellow in his work on the logo. But whether that was part of it or not, he says that the final version just seemed right to him. “It just feels a certain way,” he says. “I know it sounds flaky, but it's true.” </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It just feels a certain way. I know it sounds flaky, but it's true.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Once the logo was finalized, Maple was largely removed from the rest of the process as Nintendo got to work marketing and eventually releasing the games. He says he didn’t think too much of it until one day, a few months later, he took his son to Toys R Us.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We walk in the front door and there's a massive display, big arches and everything, and TVs going and noise and the Pokémon logo, and I'm like, ‘Holy smokes. This is crazy.’”</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pokémon Forever</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">This wasn’t Maple’s final interaction with Nintendo, though, or even with the Pokémon logo. After E3, Maple recalls Arakawa asked him to alter the logo slightly. He doesn’t remember receiving any specific instructions on what exactly Arakawa wanted altered, though he says that clients telling him to “just change it a little” without extra instruction is fairly common in his field. So Maple went back to the drawing board, literally, and made some minor adjustments to the interior of the “P” and the “E”, resulting in the version of the logo we now know today.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Later, Maple was called back to do some other design work, and remembers assisting with design projects for games like Major League Baseball Featuring Ken Griffey Jr., Mischief Makers, and a Star Wars game he doesn’t recall the name of (possibly the Nintendo 64 release of Star Wars: Rogue Squadron). He also was called upon to redesign the Nintendo 64 box for the console’s Atomic Purple release.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/na-pokemon-1998-1747670431704.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The first final version of the Pokémon logo Maple submitted, prior to the adjustments he made to the P and E.</figcaption></figure></output><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/international-pokmon-logo-svg-1747670511222.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Pokémon logo with Maple's adjustments, as we know it today.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">He did eventually play the Pokémon games, just a little bit, but didn’t get too far. Maple was a busy man. He does remember his son collecting the trading cards when they came out…until they were banned at school.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I'd be at a store or something and I'm buying something for my daughter and she'd be jumping up and down. She'd go, ‘My daddy did that logo,’ and a couple of moms would look at me in line and go, ‘Oh, so it was <em>you</em>, was it? You're the guy.’”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Maple’s work with Nintendo eventually ran its course, as the company began hiring more and more in-house artists and designers. That was fine with him, though. He had plenty of other work lined up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For years, Maple never spoke of his work on the Pokémon logo publicly. It wasn’t listed on his website, nor was he credited anywhere as the designer. He says that at the time, he wasn’t allowed to talk about it, and it’s fairly normal in his industry not to credit individual logo designers. But now, Maple’s started talking about it. He’s <a href="https://chrismaple.com/pokemon" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">put the logo up on his website</a>, alongside some newly-designed T-shirt mock-ups and other images, to showcase the massive project he took on all those years ago.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Why now?, I asked. Maple says a lot of it stemmed from conversations with his son, who urged him to come forward about his role and take credit where it was due. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's just after years, it didn't matter…So 27 years later, I thought I'm going to be changing what I do more and more, and I thought, why don't I just, if I'm going to put this as one of my accreditations, I should have some kind of validation to it and move on. For all the people that are interested in the games, you, IGN, wouldn't you want to know what really happened?”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Chris Maple Modern Mock-up Logo Images</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I ask Maple if there’s anything he would do differently if he had the opportunity to do the logo now. He says he’d probably revert it back to the original logo that was accepted in 1998, before Arakawa had him adjust it slightly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The other thing I would probably do, I would feel kind of almost responsible about and maybe a little bit strong about, is when Pokémon turns 30 next year, they'll probably try to do some celebration around that and whatever, and I know how things go, but they're going to dig an artist out of the woodwork and he's going to put 30th across that logo somewhere and it's not going to be right.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I know it won't be right because all the base, all the foundational thought that went into creating it in the first place to survive the way it did and for us to be talking to one another today, there is an energy and a skeleton in there, and to even add another component, like the word 30th or two numerical characters, TLC [tender loving care], big time. Don’t just get it done. It's going to be TLC. So I would hope that Pokémon International would ring me and say, ‘Hey, this would be great PR. The guy that did the logo gets to put the 30th on for us. Good PR for us.’ That would be smart of them to do. Of course I'm pitching for myself here.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>In some way I feel responsible about all the children and the other people that have grown up that take ownership of this.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Though Maple’s work with Pokémon only spanned a few months, and only one image, that effort has since been replicated across everything Pokémon. Aside from perhaps Pikachu, the Pokémon logo is the most well-known and iconic symbol of the global phenomenon that’s only grown in popularity in the years since Maple unwittingly stumbled into the process of its creation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So then, does he feel he had a hand in Pokémon's ultimate success? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I would say that in some way I feel responsible about all the children and the other people that have grown up that take ownership of this,” he says. “I feel really... I feel good about, that I did the thing responsibly for them. I teach children in challenged areas…And when I teach the children, they just go nuts. Once the teacher leaks the fact that I did this, I can't get a word in edgewise because they're saying, ‘Draw the characters for us, please.’ So I put it at the end of the lesson and I'll do a couple characters and I'll put the giant logo across the big white board in the classroom, and that became pretty popular.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Some of the experiences you get are just priceless. But I'm just happy that it's doing well…Yeah, I love it, and that's why I work still today.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ahead of Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Patch 8, Fans Believe Datamines Have Revealed Everything From the New Class to a New, Much-Wanted Melee Weap]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ahead-of-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-fans-believe-datamines-have-revealed-everything-from-the-new-class-to-a-new-much-wanted-melee-weapon-and-a-surprising-new-gun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ahead-of-warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-patch-8-fans-believe-datamines-have-revealed-everything-from-the-new-class-to-a-new-much-wanted-melee-weap.1194012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ahead-of-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-fans-believe-datamines-have-revealed-everything-from-the-new-class-to-a-new-much-wanted-melee-weapon-and-a-surprising-new-gun<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Grav it while you can.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> will soon see the release of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-detailed-horde-mode-mechanics-and-map-revealed">Patch 8</a>, which publisher Focus Entertainment and developer Saber Interactive have already said heralds the arrival of the hotly anticipated Horde mode.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But what else might it include? Recent datamines of Space Marine 2 itself may hold clues.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Warning!</strong></em><em> Potential spoilers for Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 follow:</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s start with perhaps the biggest question Space Marine 2 fans have right now: what is the new class? <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Spacemarine/comments/1jsr0k7/major_spoilers_for_upcoming_content_all_of_the/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Datamines suggest it is the Techmarine</a>. Why? Because in the files was mention of a perk called ‘shoulder gun bolter,’ which is a clear indication that Techmarines are finally in play.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For the uninitiated, a Techmarine is a Space Marine engineer-type class who’s a big fan of the Cult Mechanicus as well as their Chapter. They’re big on technology and specialize in fixing and maintaining vehicles and other big stuff, such as Dreadnaughts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see how a Techmarine might slot into a Space Marine 2 squad, which currently lacks a class of this type. And this ties into another datamined detail: the apparent ability to “summon” a Dreadnaught in Horde mode. Dreadnaughts are a part of the Space Marine 2 campaign (one viral moment involves a Dreadnaught being particularly heroic and badass), and you also fight alongside one in a PvE Operations mission. Could you earn the right to summon a Dreadnaught and, as a Techmarine, keep it alive, in Horde mode?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now onto the promised new melee weapon. Datamines suggest Space Marine 2 will finally get a Power Axe, which again, makes sense in the context of Games Workshop’s big Space Wolves push for the tabletop game. And let’s remember, in December, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/space-marine-2-modders-put-the-axe-from-secret-levels-warhammer-40000-episode-into-the-game">IGN reported on <u>Space Marine 2</u> modders who put the axe from Secret Level’s Warhammer 40,000 episode into the game</a>.</p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560" data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>THIS is why I’m a fan of Warhammer 40k! Hats off to <a href="https://twitter.com/PrimeVideo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@PrimeVideo</a> for producing Secret Level: And They Shall Know No Fear. Watch it here: <a href="https://t.co/Gf0i2d0Rus" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/Gf0i2d0Rus</a></p><p>I highly recommend giving the entire 19 min episode a watch. It’s immersive and awesome. It’s a happy grim dark ray of… <a href="https://t.co/iuYxprAo2J" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/iuYxprAo2J</a></p></div>— MiniWarGamer Dave (@MWGdave) <a href="https://twitter.com/MWGdave/status/1866570193708913144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 10, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">There’s more! As discussed in a recent video by Warhammer 40,000 YouTuber <a href="https://youtu.be/Emh-Qq-UNnE?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chapter Master Valrak</a>, dataminers recently unearthed evidence of a Grav-cannon in Space Marine 2. This is, typically, a big gun used by Space Marines that manipulate gravity to cause a target to crush itself to death. Could the Techmarine class, should it be a genuine upcoming arrival, exclusively wield the Grav-cannon? If so, I imagine there will be many players who gravitate towards it with the release of Patch 8.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that Patch 8 remains under wraps for now, but we’re expecting Space Marine 2-related announcements during the upcoming Warhammer Skulls livestream this Thursday, May 22. Perhaps we’ll find out more there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s a lot happening in the world of Space Marine 2, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-announced-development-officially-begins-at-saber-interactive"><u>despite the surprise announcement that development of Space Marine 3 development had begun</u></a>. Space Marine 2’s year one roadmap remains in place.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyrule Warriors: Age Of Imprisonment Will Show ‘How The People Contended With The Threat Of The Original Ganondorf’]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/20/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-will-show-how-the-people-contended-with-the-threat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-will-show-%E2%80%98how-the-people-contended-with-the-threat-of-the-original-ganondorf%E2%80%99.1194009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/20/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-will-show-how-the-people-contended-with-the-threat<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Last month, Nintendo and Koei Tecmo announced that <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/04/02/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-is-the-next-zelda-musou-game-for">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment is the next mainline Zelda musou</a> game and is launching on <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> this winter. Now, a Koei Tecmo studio head has pulled back the curtains on what players can expect from the narrative of this game, revealing Age of Imprisonment will show how the people of Hyrule defeated Ganondorf before the events of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom/such-great-heights">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>.</p><p>In a new Creator’s Voice behind-the-scenes video for Age of Imprisonment called “Beyond the Legend,” Koei Tecmo producer Ryota Matsushita and Koei Tecmo triple-A games studio head Yosuke Hayashi discuss the upcoming game, what’s to unfold in the story, and how the Switch 2 makes it possible. Hayashi reveals Age of Imprisonment shows the full story of the Imprisoning War, which is only seen in fragmented chunks in Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jT8ojj0HrzA"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jT8ojj0HrzA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>“This game takes place during the Imprisoning War, which is shown in fragments in The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom,” he says. “In this Hyrule Warriors game, you’ll see how the people contended with the threat of the original Ganondorf.”</p><p>Matsushita picks up this thread, stating, “As a story that you can only fully experience here, it doesn’t just depict the battles of the Imprisoning War via a Warriors game; it also shows the kingdom of Hyrule after Princess Zelda is sent back in time. You’ll also get to know the four masked sages from The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom.”</p><p>Elsewhere in the video, Matsushita and Hayashi discuss how the Switch 2 makes Age of Imprisonment possible. They explain that the console's power allows the game to feature more enemies on screen and maintain a high and stable frame rate (which looks like 60 FPS in the video).</p><p>Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment hits Nintendo Switch 2 sometime this winter.</p><p>In the meantime, read about how <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/15/nintendo-has-a-plan-for-continuous-flow-of-switch-2-through-the-holidays">Nintendo has a plan for “continuous flow” of Switch 2 through the holidays</a>, and then check out the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/16/nintendo-details-free-resolution-framerate-and-hdr-updates-for-select-switch-games-on">Switch games getting free updates on Switch 2</a>. After that, read <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2025/04/03/hands-on-with-nintendos-next-console"><em>Game Informer’s</em> hands-on preview of the Switch 2</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you picking up Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment this winter? Let us <span>know in the comments below!</span>&nbsp;</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker is a miniaturised circus act delight]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/sea-of-stars-throes-of-the-watchmaker-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-stars-throes-of-the-watchmaker-is-a-miniaturised-circus-act-delight.1193982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/sea-of-stars-throes-of-the-watchmaker-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>How do you add a new story to a sweeping RPG? That’s the tricky conundrum that faced <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/08/31/sea-of-stars-review-a-love-letter-to-jrpgs-of-the-past/">Sea of Stars</a> developer Sabotage Studio. Some games choose to continue the story, bolting it onto the back of the game and giving you new hyper powerful abilities at the same time, or it’s joined on at the side and has to face the tricky balancing act of creating new progression that doesn’t impact too heavily on the tail end of the main story. Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker straddles this divide, coming as both a post-game adventure and branching off to explore a separate, miniaturised clockwork world.</p>
<p><iframe title="Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker DLC | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tgFi2jXwzVI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>That’s right, we’re getting all Honey, Shrunk the Kids for this one. Answering the call for help from the crew of The Verspertine, and with Keenathan in a particular kind of existential crisis, the one person who can help them solve Keenathan’s troubles seems to be the Watchmaker. Once you arrive at her Clockwork Castle, she agrees to help, but only if you help her first to resolve a fearful state of affairs in the miniature world of Horloge that she created.</p>


<p>You see, this charming little world, filled with clockwork denizens, has been twisted and corrupted, brought under the power of an evil twin to the Watchmaker, known as The Puppeteer, making her fearful ever to return. It’s up to Valere and Zale to shrink themselves down and head into this clockwork circus world of Horloge to free it from The Puppeteer’s rule.</p>
<p>It doesn’t take long to run into The Puppeteer and her comedic clown duo of goons, Pif &amp; Pouf, doing battle and discovering, not only that the Solstice Warrior abilities of Valere and Zale have next to no power here, but also that this power can simply be whisked away from them and transformed into evil twins of themselves. It takes the Artificer’s new beam abilities to release everyone from their imprisonment, becoming a new playable character and permanent battle companion in the process, and it takes a fellow prisoner to explain that Valere and Zale will need to lean in and play some new circus-like roles in order to succeed.</p>


<p>Valere becomes an acrobat and Zale a juggler, with Arty bringing their own spin on circus acts alongside. Zale’s juggling attacks deal fire damage with a side helping of “bonk”, which is represented by a rubber mallet symbol, while Valere’s bonk comes with a side of magic, and Arty has beam attacks. Of course, there’s also all of the special abilities and combo attacks, and it’s here that the circus flair really comes to the fore. Valere launches herself into the sky on a pole vault, Zale juggles flaming balls off enemy faces, Arty bounces cannon balls or Valere and Zale of a trampoline, and there’s all the restorative properties of a cream pie to the face if you want Zale to heal an ally… or himself, I guess.</p>
<p>There’s the same rhythm to the turn-based combat here, where timing button presses increases the damage of an attack or extends the move for successive hits. At the same time, there’s a strategic layer of attacking certain enemies that have damage type ‘locks’ that can knock them out of turn order if you hit them with the right damage types enough times.</p>
<p>As a post-game addition, this is intended to be more challenging than the base game, making the importance of timing hits, blocks and breaking enemy locks all the more important. However, you do still have the Relics system that can tweak and modify the difficulty and certain other game elements. This can give you additional health, restore HP after battle instead and/or after levelling up (which is on by default), add a timing success indicator, and more. I do, as someone that’s not played an awful lot of the main game, wish that timing indicators were more deeply ingrained, perhaps giving a measure of whether you’re early, late or on time, but I can appreciate the game not wanting to hold your hand too much.</p>

<p>The clockwork world is quite delightfully realised by Sabotage Studio, really leaning in on this being a miniaturised land. All of the denizens have a wind-up key spinning from their backs, the town of Horloge is filled with circus tents that have a handful of circus minigames in them –&nbsp;such as needing to pole vault through large hoops against the clock –&nbsp;and as you explore you now gather restorative items from little milk tubs and cobs of corn that become popcorn.</p>
<p>There’s the same style of free traversal through the maze-like environments as well, clambering up ledges and ladders, grappling and leaping across gaps, and following paths that wrap around, through and under other parts of the scenery. It makes finding secrets and solving environmental puzzles satisfying and engaging.</p>

<p>And all that care and attention paid once more to the pixel art world is complimented by a bunch of catchy bops from Sabotage’s composer Eric W. Brown and guest composer Yasunori Mitsuda, and more gorgeously animated cinematics – Sabotage say these had the same budget as the main game.</p>
<p>Honestly, all of this could easily have been paid DLC, but for the fact that this was promised as a stretch goal from Sea of Stars’ original crowdfunding campaign. That it is a free addition to the game, coming after major updates that added 3-player co-op (which is playable throughout this DLC), overhauled combat and more, just makes it all the more special.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clash of Clans TV Show In the Works for Some Reason]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clash-of-clans-tv-show</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clash-of-clans-tv-show-in-the-works-for-some-reason.1193979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clash-of-clans-tv-show<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Netflix has announced that a&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans</em> TV&nbsp;show is in the works, so now you have to reckon with that being a thing in the real world as much as I do. Sorry about that.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/netflix/status/1924804801616871741" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, Netflix says that the "world" of&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>is "coming to life as an animated series on Netflix", although the streaming giant doesn't provide any kind of time frame for the series' arrival, nor does it specify what the story will be about.</p>

<p>However, if the mobile game is anything to go by, the series will probably revolve around chiefs trying to defend their village against attacks from other clans. I'd assume there will be a hefty dollop of self-referentiality and pop-culture gags, too, for such is the way these things often go.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/clash-of-clans-netflix-series-characters.jpg?itok=acCTnHEP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/clash-of-clans-netflix-series-characters.jpg?itok=Uq5lMiI4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>is getting a streaming series courtesy of Netflix.</figcaption></figure><p>In the (admittedly rather amusing) trailer announcing the&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>series on Netflix, Supercell staffers describe how there's at least one comment asking for a&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>show under every video made about the game by the studio "since 2012".</p>

<p>The video's description merely promises that the&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>show will star "your favorite moustachioed Barbarian and his high-pitched, hog-riding friends", so I guess if you were worried the show wouldn't be true to the game, you can put those worries to rest.</p>

<p>It sounds like we're going to have to wait quite a while for more information about the&nbsp;<em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>series, so for now, you can content yourself with Supercell's announcement trailer. Even I, swinging brick of a heart and all, can admit it's quite funny.</p>




<p><em>Clash of Clans&nbsp;</em>will follow in the footsteps of other video games to get animated Netflix adaptations, including the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/netflix-devil-may-cry-renewed-second-season" rel="nofollow"><em>Devil May Cry</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Castlevania</em>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cyberpunk-edgerunners-is-anime-set-in-cyberpunk-universe" rel="nofollow"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a>, among others.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see what kind of direction Netflix is going in with the show, as well as when we can expect it to launch. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Wandering Village launches July 17 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-wandering-village-launches-july-17-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-wandering-village-launches-july-17-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.1193964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-wandering-village-launches-july-17-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>City building <a title="Genres > Strategy [246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> <em><a title="Games > The Wandering Village [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-wandering-village">The Wandering Village</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,494 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,213 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,009 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,980 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1121640/The_Wandering_Village/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on July 17, publishers <a title="Companies > Stray Fawn Publishing [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stray-fawn-studio/stray-fawn-publishing">Stray Fawn Publishing</a> and <a title="Companies > WhisperGames [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whispergames">WhisperGames</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > Stray Fawn Studio [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stray-fawn-studio">Stray Fawn Studio</a> announced. <span id="more-965871"></span></p><p><em>The Wandering Village</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1121640/The_Wandering_Village/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on September 14, 2022, followed by Game Preview for Xbox Series, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/the-wandering-village-game-preview/9n8b7svl2dtl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on July 20, 2023.</p><p>A physical edition distributed by <a title="Companies > Serenity Forge [64 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/serenity-forge">Serenity Forge</a> will also be available for PlayStation 5 and Switch. The Collector’s Edition will include a copy of the game, a special box, a Washi sticker sheet, a soundtrack download card, a five-inch Onbu succulent pot, a wooden pin set, a cloth poster, an art book, a rubber keychain, and a set of postcards.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/The-Wandering-Village_05-20-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Stray Fawn Publishing:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In a hostile world stricken by toxic spores, a small group of survivors seek shelter on the back of a giant, wandering creature called ‘Onbu’. As the settlement’s new leader, navigate the many dangers this world holds in store, grow your village and, ultimately, ensure the <a title="Genres > Survival [412 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> of your people and Onbu alike.</p><p>Provide shelter, food and entertainment for your people. Plan and optimise production chains. Make sure your village is prepared for changing climates and environmental hazards. Take the opportunity to forage the world for treasures and rare resources. Overcome great odds in a poisoned post-apocalyptic world. And decide how to live with the gentle giant: will you form a symbiotic relationship based on mutual trust, or will you become a parasite and exploit Onbu, taking whatever you want? The choice is yours to make.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Survive Together</strong> – Expand and optimize your village on the back of a living creature, either as a helper or a parasite.</li><li><strong>Keep the Balance</strong> – Weigh the needs of the settlers against those of Onbu, facing tough decisions around every corner.</li><li><strong>A Changing World</strong> – Adapt your strategy as you travel through a multitude of biomes and face new challenges and threats.</li><li><strong>New Technologies</strong> – Find and research remnants of long-lost technology, but use them wisely, as progress can be a double-edged sword.</li><li><strong>Overcome Great Odds</strong> – Keep your small village alive through poisonous spores, merciless weather, bloodsucking parasites, and more.</li></ul><p>Since its Early Access in 2022, the game has received several major updates:</p><ul><li><strong>Story Mode</strong> – Adding more lore, quests and a story-based end goal to the game.</li><li><strong>Ocean and Ruins Biome</strong> – New challenges await in the form of new gameplay mechanics, events and scouting locations.</li><li><strong>Reworked Economy</strong> – Improved villager <a title="Genres > Management [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a>, a reworked research system and balancing tweaks have increased the game’s depth.</li><li><strong>Hostility Modifiers</strong> – Extra challenges for experienced players.</li><li><strong>Gameplay and Content Expansions</strong> – Such as trading, parasites, new buildings, resources, Onbu commands and much more.</li><li><strong>Controller and Steam Deck Support</strong></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Wandering Village - 1.0 Launch Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1dUWQ2ozeG0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Release Date and Physical Edition Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Wandering Village 1.0 Launch Date, PlayStation and Physical Edition Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VHhS3DIHg-I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Reportedly Using Samsung Chips As Nintendo Tries To Meet Demand]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-reportedly-using-samsung-chips-as-nintendo-tries-to-meet-demand/1100-6531666/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-reportedly-using-samsung-chips-as-nintendo-tries-to-meet-demand.1193961/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-reportedly-using-samsung-chips-as-nintendo-tries-to-meet-demand/1100-6531666/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531666">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">Switch 2</a> could be one of the must-have gaming consoles of 2025, and in an effort to ensure that supply meets demand, Nintendo is reportedly working with Samsung to increase its production efforts. While Nintendo had previously predicted that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-how-many-switch-2-consoles-it-expects-to-sell-during-its-first-year/1100-6531389/" data-ref-id="1100-6531389">15 million Switch 2 consoles would be sold</a> during its current financial year, it has been reported that Samsung may be able to significantly increase this number.</p><p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-05-20/nintendo-turns-to-samsung-to-make-chips-ramp-up-switch-2-output" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">According to Bloomberg</a>, 20 million Switch 2 consoles could be sold by March 2026 if Samsung is manufacturing chips for it. Samsung was competing with Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. to secure the Nintendo contract, and the Korean company will reportedly produce a customized Nvidia chip for the Switch 2. Samsung has worked with Nintendo in the past to supply it with memory chips and displays, and the company can reportedly ramp up production further if necessary. Sources told Bloomberg that Samsung is also pushing for OLED panels to be used for a potential Switch 2 hardware refresh in the future.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1278943154" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531666&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Switch 2 preorders have sold out at several retailers across the globe, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-warns-switch-2-lottery-will-leave-significant-numbers-of-fans-disappointed-in-japan/1100-6531049/">Nintendo recently apologized for being unable to meet demand in Japan</a> through its official store. The company received 2.2 million applications to purchase the console, but it warned customers that a "significant" number of them will not be selected as winners of the My Nintendo Store lottery sale.</p><p>In the US, Switch 2 preorders officially opened up on April 24 after weeks of uncertainty regarding tariffs. While the price of the console hasn't gone up yet--$450 for the base model, $500 for the bundle that includes Mario Kart World--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-accessories-will-be-more-expensive-than-originally-announced/1100-6530965/">first-party accessory prices have increased</a>. The Switch 2 will feature several hardware upgrades when compared to its predecessor, and there'll be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/">strong selection of third-party games available on launch day</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked Battlefield 6 Footage Gives Off Bad Company 2 Vibes, Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/leaked-battlefield-6-footage-gives-off-bad-company-2-vibes-dev-says/1100-6531668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leaked-battlefield-6-footage-gives-off-bad-company-2-vibes-dev-says.1193955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/leaked-battlefield-6-footage-gives-off-bad-company-2-vibes-dev-says/1100-6531668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531668">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Former Battlefield producer David Goldfarb has reacted to a newly emerged clip of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6 </a>gameplay footage, saying it's giving off Bad Company 2 vibes. For what it's worth, the game isn't necessarily called Battlefield 6, but that's what we're using until EA gives it an official title.</p><p>"Oh the BC2 vibes this is giving me," Goldfarb <a href="https://x.com/locust9/status/1924703470713516520" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said</a>, adding that the footage (below) is giving him flashbacks to the first time DICE playtested Bad Company 2's much-loved <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Arica_Harbor" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Arica Harbor map. </a></p><p>Goldfarb added that the player movement in the leaked Battlefield 6 clip looks "a little weird," adding that the character design <a href="https://x.com/locust9/status/1924705092432785470" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"seems very generic." </a> The gameplay footage shows a player fighting through buildings and squaring off against a tank down on the ground that blows away their cover. It's trademark Battlefield stuff.</p><p>Goldfarb left DICE in 2012 after working on Mirror's Edge, Battlefield: Bad Company 1 + 2, and Battlefield 3. He then moved to Overkill to become the game director for Payday 2. He is now the studio creative director and CCO at the Funcom-owned developer The Outsiders.</p><p>The footage stems from the Battlefield Labs testing program, so what we're seeing is unfinished and was never meant to be seen publicly anyway since the Labs tests forbid people from sharing footage. Despite that, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-gets-landing-roll-but-it-might-give-you-motion-sickness/1100-6531523/" data-ref-id="1100-6531523">numerous gameplay videos from the Labs program have emerged over the weeks and months.</a> You can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-play-the-new-battlefield-early-sign-up-for-a-chance-to-get-into-test-program/1100-6529190/" data-ref-id="1100-6529190">sign up for Battlefield Labs</a> to give yourself a chance to get into a future test.</p><p>EA will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-will-be-fully-revealed-this-summer-launching-by-march-2026/1100-6531349/" data-ref-id="1100-6531349">officially unveil the new Battlefield game this summer</a>. As for when it may launch, it's due for release by the end of March 2026, but now that GTA 6 has been delayed, some are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-battlefield-6-launch-window-clearer-than-before-following-gta-6-delay/1100-6531351/" data-ref-id="1100-6531351">theorizing it may come out this fall.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HBO’s The Last Of Us Showrunner Craig Mazin Says ‘There’s No Way To Complete This Narrative In A Third Season’]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/20/hbos-the-last-of-us-showrunner-craig-mazin-says-theres-no-way-to-complete-this-narrative</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hbo%E2%80%99s-the-last-of-us-showrunner-craig-mazin-says-%E2%80%98there%E2%80%99s-no-way-to-complete-this-narrative-in-a-third-season%E2%80%99.1193952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/20/hbos-the-last-of-us-showrunner-craig-mazin-says-theres-no-way-to-complete-this-narrative<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>The second season of HBO’s The Last of Us ends this coming Sunday with a finale that seemingly tees up a confrontation we’ve been waiting for all season. However, it’s clear season two will leave us with a lot of story left when it’s over. While many fans predicted that a third season, which has already been greenlit, could finish the story, showrunner Craig Mazin alludes to needing a fourth season to wrap up the events of The Last of Us Part II.</p><p>In a new interview with <a href="https://collider.com/the-last-of-us-series-length-season-3-showrunner-craig-mazin/"><em>Collider</em></a>, Mazin explains, “there’s no way to complete this narrative in a third season” when asked about a theoretical fourth season.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QtmC_0dTaKk"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QtmC_0dTaKk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p><span><strong>Spoilers For Season Two Of HBO's The Last Of Us</strong></span></p><hr><p>“I think there’s a decent chance Season 3 will be longer than Season 2, just because the manner of that narrative and the opportunities it affords us are a little different,” Mazin, who is also a director and writer on the show, told <em>Collider</em>. “The thing about Joel’s death is that it’s so impactful. It’s such a narrative nuclear bomb that it’s hard to wander away from it. We can’t really take a break and move off to the side and do a Bill and Frank story.</p><p>“I’m not sure that will be necessarily true for Season 3. I think we’ll have a little more room there. But certainly, there’s no way to complete this narrative in a third season. Hopefully, we’ll earn our keep enough to come back and finish it in a fourth. That’s the likely outcome.”</p><p>Though it seems like Mazin and the team behind the show are still waiting to see if a fourth season will be greenlit, which likely depends on the reception of season three, it’s clear he believes a fourth season is needed to finish the story of <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/the-last-of-us-part-ii/the-last-of-us-part-ii-review-a-perfect-circle">The Last of Us Part II</a>. It also sounds like we can expect a Bill and Frank-style episode in season three.</p><p>Regardless, this theoretical fourth season is years away. In the meantime, read about <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive-feature/2025/05/11/equal-parts-boring-and-intense-visiting-the-set-of-the-last-of-us"><em>Game Informer’s</em> boring but tense set visit to HBO’s The Last of Us</a>, and then read <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/03/26/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-on-the-creative-process-behind-season-2-of-the"><em>Game Informer’s </em>exclusive interview with Neil Druckmann about season two</a>.</p><hr><p><em>Is a fourth season necessary to complete the story? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Heart of Democracy Update Takes the Fight to Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-takes-the-fight-to-super-earth.1193946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arrowhead Game Studios and Sony have released another new&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>update, and this one is bringing the fight straight into the heart of managed democracy, so prepare to defend your home from filthy alien invaders.</p>

<p>This update comes hot on the heels of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-update-illuminate-weapon-customization" rel="nofollow">another patch last week</a>, which introduced new Illuminate enemies for you to take on, as well as a weapon customization system to give you somewhere to spend your Requisition resource.</p>

<p>In the Heart of Democracy update, however, the Illuminate are taking the fight to Super Earth, so it's up to you to head back to your home planet and defend "the towering skyscrapers and crowded streets" of your home turf.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-super-earth.jpg?itok=ivKOdluV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-super-earth.jpg?itok=rv-p4q08 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Helldivers 2</em>'s Heart of Democracy update tasks you with battling your enemies on Super Earth.</figcaption></figure><p>You'll be fighting inside the city biomes of Super Earth, battling Illuminate foes as they "rain down destruction all around you". Arrowhead says you'll be tussling with the Illuminate over control of certain areas, "gaining and losing control quickly".</p>

<p>As you fight, you'll meet squads of Super Earth troops, who can either battle Illuminate by themselves or join you to do battle against your alien foes. You can also activate Planetary Defense Cannons to "take down the Illuminate fleet in a grand show of power".</p>

<p>Civilians will also be roaming the streets of Super Earth's cities, and it's up to you to keep them safe. After all, friendly fire is very much not the Super Earth way, nor is it the way of managed democracy.</p>




<p>Elsewhere in<i>&nbsp;Helldivers 2&nbsp;</i>news, the game's new <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/helldivers-2-masters-of-ceremony-warbond" rel="nofollow">Masters of Ceremony Warbond</a> went live last week, giving you access to new gear on which to spend your Super Credits.</p>

<p>If you'd like to take the fight away from Super Earth and onto the tabletop, you'll be pleased to know that a board game adaptation of&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/helldivers-2-board-game-fully-funded-in-12-minutes-on-gamefound" rel="nofollow">fully crowdfunded in a staggering 12 minutes</a> last month as well.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/553850/HELLDIVERS_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/helldivers-2/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and the game's Heart of Democracy update is available now. Make sure to check out <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/helldivers-2-review-fighting-for-managed-democracy" rel="nofollow">our Dan's review</a> to find out what he thought of the game.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rip And Tear These Ominous Wolf Statues In Doom: The Dark Ages' 'Resurrection' Level]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-wolf-statue-wraithstone-resurrection-1851781368</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rip-and-tear-these-ominous-wolf-statues-in-doom-the-dark-ages-resurrection-level.1193940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-wolf-statue-wraithstone-resurrection-1851781368<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages"><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em></a></span> differs from many previous entries with more open-level design in some instances. “Resurrection,” the twentieth mission in the game, is the last one of these, after “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-siege-part-1-lion-statues-knight-ruby-1851780496&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-siege-part-1-lion-statues-knight-ruby-1851780496">The Siege Part One</a></span>,” “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-lion-statues-sorcerer-statue-ancestral-1851780714&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-lion-statues-sorcerer-statue-ancestral-1851780714">Ancestral Forge</a></span>,” and “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-wolf-statue-locations-wraithstone-1851781357&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-wolf-statue-locations-wraithstone-1851781357">Kar’thul Marshes</a></span>.”</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197567" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="104" data-playlist="197567,197565,197564" data-current="197567"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23091.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839"><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Review</a></span></p><p>In “Resurrection,” there are four of these wolf statues. Thankfully, the four statues are also relatively close together this time around.</p><figure id="" data-id="c4e2340ee2287383f102247f4c9de3a5" data-recommend-id="image://c4e2340ee2287383f102247f4c9de3a5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->id Software / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c4e2340ee2287383f102247f4c9de3a5" data-recommend-id="image://c4e2340ee2287383f102247f4c9de3a5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The sorcerer statue in this mission is all the way towards the back of the level. If you go from the left, you’ll come across a mandatory combat encounter where you’ll destroy one of the three Siege Towers. At the back of the level, you’ll see a little cave with the sorcerer statue and wolf statues.</p><h2 id="h69"><a id="1"></a>First wolf statue</h2><figure id="" data-id="0cd9f5cf57498ddc02bb78ce6366b5c2" data-recommend-id="image://0cd9f5cf57498ddc02bb78ce6366b5c2" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->id Software / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0cd9f5cf57498ddc02bb78ce6366b5c2" data-recommend-id="image://0cd9f5cf57498ddc02bb78ce6366b5c2" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The first wolf statue is near the area with the sorcerer statue. Simply go to the back of the room and look to your right. Past the circle of cultists, you’ll see the wolf statue.</p><hr><h2 id="h70"><a id="2"></a>Second wolf statue</h2><figure id="" data-id="41693cd8fc39a5d6c5f9b3aab8349d8b" data-recommend-id="image://41693cd8fc39a5d6c5f9b3aab8349d8b" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->id Software / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="41693cd8fc39a5d6c5f9b3aab8349d8b" data-recommend-id="image://41693cd8fc39a5d6c5f9b3aab8349d8b" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The second wolf statue location is close to the first. Go out one of the entrances of the cave and you’ll enter a combat encounter. After clearing the demons, you should see a broken down building nearby. At the top of the building is the wolf statue.</p><hr><h2 id="h71"><a id="3"></a>Third wolf statue</h2><figure id="" data-id="89242f29dc9455f28ebad7e98399258a" data-recommend-id="image://89242f29dc9455f28ebad7e98399258a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->id Software / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="89242f29dc9455f28ebad7e98399258a" data-recommend-id="image://89242f29dc9455f28ebad7e98399258a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The third wolf statue location is close to the second. From the second wolf statue, turn around and you should see an underpass nearby. Go through the path and the wolf statue is sitting there.</p><hr><h2 id="h72"><a id="4"></a>Fourth wolf statue</h2><figure id="" data-id="963573e2a912ccea2c3ae7aa49c64a1d" data-recommend-id="image://963573e2a912ccea2c3ae7aa49c64a1d" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->id Software / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="963573e2a912ccea2c3ae7aa49c64a1d" data-recommend-id="image://963573e2a912ccea2c3ae7aa49c64a1d" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A side-by-side image shows a map and the location of a statue." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The fourth wolf statue is closer than you think. From the third wolf statue, turn back around from where you came and go around the corner. Continue forward and you should enter a smaller combat encounter. After clearing those demons, you should see the fourth wolf statue in the corner between a giant tree and a tree stump.</p><hr><h2 id="h73"><a id="5"></a>Grabbing the jewel</h2><p>After shattering all four wolf statues, the barrier surrounding the Sorcerer statue will disappear. You can then interact with the statue and grab the Wraithstone, which can be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-the-dark-ages-upgrades-shotgun-flail-pulverizer-1851780282&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-the-dark-ages-upgrades-shotgun-flail-pulverizer-1851780282">used to upgrade</a></span> your weapons, shield, and melee capabilities</p><hr><p>For more <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages"><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em></a></span>, be sure to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839">check out our review</a></span>, as well as collectible guides for the first two missions of the game: “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-village-khalim-collectibles-toy-codex-1851780316&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-village-khalim-collectibles-toy-codex-1851780316">Village of Khalim</a></span>” and “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-hebeth-collectibles-toy-codex-secret-1851780487&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-dark-ages-hebeth-collectibles-toy-codex-secret-1851780487">Hebeth</a></span>.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[to a T demo now available for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/to-a-t-demo-now-available-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/to-a-t-demo-now-available-for-pc.1193931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/to-a-t-demo-now-available-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Save data from the demo can be carried over to the full game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A demo for <em><a title="Games > to a T [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/to-a-t">to a T</a></em>, the latest game from <em>Katamari Damacy</em> creator Keita Takahashi, is now available for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1875320/to_a_T/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Annapurna Interactive [176 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/annapurna-interactive">Annapurna Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > uvula [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/uvula">uvula</a> announced. <span id="more-965851"></span></p><p>The demo features the early moments of the narrative <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a>, which features a T-posing main character, sandwich-making giraffes, and “a couple of absolute bops” in the soundtrack. Save data from the demo can be transferred to the full game when it launches.</p><p><em>to a T</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1875320/to_a_T/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 28.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales of Seikyu Preview - Cute, Yokai Farming Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/tales-of-seikyu-preview-cute-yokai-farming-fun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-seikyu-preview-cute-yokai-farming-fun.1193916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/tales-of-seikyu-preview-cute-yokai-farming-fun<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>One of the hardest things to nail in games is worldbuilding, especially in a farming sim, and <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> does it so well that the bugs that crop up are hardly noticeable. The Early Access game is full of potential, and the roughly one-month in-game content is as gorgeous and vibrant as developer ACE Entertainment promised.</p>

<p><em>Tales of Seikyu</em> begins with the main character and their sister, Kon, moving to the town of Seikyu. The siblings are fox yokai, and Seikyu was founded by their ancestors to be a haven for yokai of all kinds.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-player-and-kon.jpg?itok=aGCgLoAA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-player-and-kon.jpg?itok=ZwDlOWfP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The player and Kon first appear sleeping, which is honestly a vibe.</figcaption></figure><p>However, now the fox clan has almost completely disappeared, including the player and Kon’s parents. The last note they have from their parents is to travel to Seikyu, where they’ll uncover secrets and hopefully find the last of the fox clan.</p>

<p>The Early Access launch of <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> only dives into the game’s first chapter, where Kon and the player learn the very beginning of the story and mingle with the town of Seikyu.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-harbor.jpg?itok=AoyoOmDY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-harbor.jpg?itok=I8jlQNWz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Tales of Seikyu&nbsp;</em>welcomes you on its beautiful harbor.</figcaption></figure><h2>Welcome to Seikyu, Home to All Yokai</h2>

<p>Seikyu itself somehow feels natural. Despite being filled with yokai characters, the town feels like a living, breathing town that has its own schedule regardless of the player. This is something that even the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="81cf7c96-4454-465b-950b-1d47c5873d28" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/how-stardew-valley-could-have-impacted-story-of-seasons" rel="nofollow">most popular farming/life sims</a> struggle to do, and <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> nails it from the start.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It also felt relaxing to play. Most games in the genre create a sense of urgency in terms of profit and optimizing how your time is spent, and <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> didn’t create that rushed pace. Instead, I felt no remorse for spending my time however I wanted – there was no rush, a hard thing to manufacture.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-main-square.jpg?itok=s3UpPpwo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-main-square.jpg?itok=eSs0Lcrm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Tales of Seikyu&nbsp;</em>conveniently puts all of the shops close together.</figcaption></figure><p>There’s currently about one season’s worth of content to play through, with Spring being the only season with a festival. However, the Carp Festival is incredible, and – dare I say – one of the best festivals I’ve seen in the genre.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Carp Festival has two mini-games for players to enjoy. The first is an egg hunt, which isn’t too special (though it is incredibly well-done). The second is a game where players are flying with carp, collecting different symbols in the air that flow with the beat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The graphics and music were beautiful, matching the rest of <em>Tales of Seikyu</em>. In general, the game is gorgeous. While there are a few stutters in performance, I was able to play with Medium settings on a ROG Ally X and High settings on my PC. Considering it’s in early access, these types of stutters were expected.</p>

<p>The characters are as gorgeous as they are well-written. The character portraits are gorgeous and fun, and they capture the characters’ personalities well.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Getting to know the characters was a pleasant surprise, and spending time with them was more fun than I expected. <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> has a unique system that lets players spend time with characters as they level up their skills.</p>

<p>It combined the two gameplay loops in a way that I haven’t seen in other farming sims, and it was refreshing and made the world feel even more alive.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-yoni.jpg?itok=IIvzbKIu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-yoni.jpg?itok=2CR3ZmVK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The characters in&nbsp;<em>Tales of Seikyu</em>&nbsp;have adorable models and portraits.</figcaption></figure><h2>Combat in Tales of Seikyu Is Rewarding</h2>

<p>The combat was also integrated with the other systems in the game. At the Early Access release, there’s one main dungeon where players will fight. These are broken up into 40 different rooms, and players will need to either beat the enemies or solve light puzzles to get through.</p>

<p>There’s a variety of weapons that sort of play differently, though I didn’t notice much of a difference between them. The stats of the weapon determined which I used – the more damage, the better.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Additionally, getting closer to one character in particular opens up the ability to buy weapons. This feels rewarding and, again, very natural.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are two main bosses currently in&nbsp;<em>Tales of Seikyu</em>, and both of them were a challenge (though I did get the second boss stuck in a hole and cheesed the fight). Between them and several of the tanky enemies, combat felt pretty rewarding.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-boar-farming.jpg?itok=tk3MtxB9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-boar-farming.jpg?itok=jmmICWEl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Farming in&nbsp;<em>Tales of Seikyu&nbsp;</em>is more interesting when you can take on different yokai forms.</figcaption></figure><p>Players also learn about different yokai forms in the dungeon, and these yokai forms are helpful in both combat and farming. For example, who needs a boring watering can when you can transform into a slime and quickly water everything?</p>

<h2>Early Access Bugs</h2>

<p>While there are endless positives, it’s worth noting the bugs. Every time I wanted to buy something from any shop, I had to save and reload the game. This applied to every shop around town, which was frustrating until I realized the quick workaround.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other bugs included falling through the map (though I got lucky and was pulled out by events each time) and clothes not fitting the female main character correctly. Though, to be honest, the skirts that didn't fit just looked like a skirt with slits in it, so it wasn't distracting, either.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-yui-bug.jpg?itok=trqxNDLL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tales-of-seikyu-yui-bug.jpg?itok=H3kiUzzz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A common bug in&nbsp;<em>Tales of Seikyu&nbsp;</em>is characters looking the wrong way when talking to you, like here.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Tales of Seikyu</em> is in Early Access. These bugs are expected to an extent, and nothing was so bad that it was unplayable. In fact, some of them were funny. Every time I went to bed, my player jumped at the same time (the A input being both jump and interact). And let’s be honest, who doesn’t like hopping into bed at the end of a long day?</p>

<h2><em>Tales of Seikyu</em> | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Overall, <em>Tales of Seikyu</em> is an enjoyable experience, and one that I can’t wait to explore more as content is released. While there are a few things to iron out in terms of bugs, it manages to do what even the biggest farming sim names can’t with worldbuilding and interconnected gameplay systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With games like <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b0667482-769b-4371-a186-298d48873c36" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/fields-of-mistria-review-next-best-cozy-farming-sim" rel="nofollow">Fields of Mistria</a> releasing in the genre as well, it's clear that the genre is making a return to the basics and completely polishing them.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Tails of Seikyu</em>&nbsp;</strong><em>was previewed over approximately 9 hours of gameplay with a key provided by the developer. All screenshots were taken during the preview process.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Brittany's been gaming since she could walk -- literally. A doctor told her parents to get her a handled console to improve her hand-eye coordination… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/brittany-alva">More about Brittany</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daggerheart GM Tools, High-Level Play, And Miniature Discussion With The Designers]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/daggerheart-gm-tools-high-level-play-and-miniature-discussion-with-designers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/daggerheart-gm-tools-high-level-play-and-miniature-discussion-with-the-designers.1193913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/daggerheart-gm-tools-high-level-play-and-miniature-discussion-with-designers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With the release of <em>Daggerheart</em>, many fans are opening up their core rulebooks, learning how to teach their players to roll up characters, and beginning to craft a variety of adventures in the many Campaign Frames. Ahead of the<em> Daggerheart Core Rulebook </em>release, we got to talk with Lead Designers Spenser Starke and Rowan Hall about their ethos behind designing Environments and Adversaries and how they hope to support high-level play.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>If you want to learn more about <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="599a4c8d-e714-4b90-8aba-04105d1db5b5" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/daggerheart-environments-seek-to-supply-gms-with-easy-to-insert-challenges-and" rel="nofollow">Environments in </a><em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="599a4c8d-e714-4b90-8aba-04105d1db5b5" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/daggerheart-environments-seek-to-supply-gms-with-easy-to-insert-challenges-and" rel="nofollow">Daggerheart</a> </em>be sure to check out our exclusive reveal of some Environments and conversation about how to implement them.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Daggerheart </em>has free-flowing combat, character builds with player-created experiences, and an emphasis on the adventure and narrative while trying to make sure mechanics don't get in the way. For a game that seems to lean into roleplay, I was intrigued to learn more about the tools that DMs would be offered.</p>

<h2>How <em>Daggerheart </em>Helps You Build Adversaries And Encounters</h2>

<p>"One of my favorite sections in the book is where we go through how we build different adversary types and why we make the choices that we do," Hall explained "Hopefully, it feels like a conversation with the designers. The goal there was to make it as approachable as possible with as many examples as possible so people can refer to it almost like a recipe book."</p>

<p>While the design of an Environment or Adversary can begin with the prompts and discussions with the designers, there's also careful math behind the balance of the game. Starke walked me through the process.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-tier-1-adversary.jpg?itok=Qa1SALf9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-tier-1-adversary.jpg?itok=QtsokSSQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In this example, Starke discussed building a Brawler adversary type and the questions that would prompt "Why do we want a Brawler? What's the whole reason why we're making the Brawler? Why wouldn't I want a Minion here?" It's those kinds of questions that help solidify the idea of the creature in your mind. Then the GM can use the Battle Point system, like ordering off a menu, to pick what Adversaries should be present.</p>

<p>For those who want to make encounters easier or harder for the party, there are also rules for how you should add or remove Battle Points from your 'menu' to ensure the encounter has the level of impact you want it to.</p>

<h2>Teaching A GM High-Level Play</h2>

<p>While we had spoken about building encounters and Adversaries, I wanted to touch on what resources were included specifically for high-level play. This kind of play is what many TTRPG players greatly look forward to, but it's also quite frequently where the game starts to ask you, as the GM, to perform your own heavy lifting.</p>

<p>"There's a section in the book that charts out story structure and the way you might approach it over the course of a campaign. It's a smaller section, but we wrote it in combination with one of our designers who also has a background in novel writing, one of our game designers who has also written on many seasons of Television."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"All of these storytellers put their brains together to figure out 'what is the most basic way we can present story structure so that someone who has never tried it and never thought about it can approach it'"</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Hall described a table that GMs will be able to use that should take the mystery out of creating a story from level 1 to level 10 without being intimidated by it.</p>

<p>For <em>Daggerheart </em>the level cap is 10, what the game calls Tier 4 play. There's also tips for GMs to explain what a Tier 4 Adversary would look like, what power do they have, etc. Starke explained that a lot of the feedback they got on Tier 4 play was that it was slower.</p>

<p>"When that armor score goes up to 14 or 17, now I'm having to do that math every time I'm getting hit. That became really crunchy and the game slowed down. [...] Armor changed that it now lowers a threshold and doesn't rely on doing heavy math in the moment and that was really core to make a game that focuses on storytelling."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-ancestry-and-community.jpg?itok=1Hihp-hT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-ancestry-and-community.jpg?itok=L1lMQJXO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Advice For New Players Getting Used To Roleplaying</h2>

<p>It's no secret that there is a heavy emphasis on roleplay and story-telling in <em>Daggerheart</em>, this isn't just intrinsic of the format but it's something that Hall explained was at the core of designing <em>Daggerheart</em>.</p>

<p>"One of the things that we do when designing - whether we're looking at a class, an ancestry, an adversary - is to say 'what story are we trying to tell by presenting it as an offering'" Past that Hall described that their goal was also to make those options as open ended as possible.</p>

<p>If you want to play to the tropes of high-fantasy, grimdark, etc then it's easy to find those ways to play but if you're also interested in creating a character that goes against or subverts those tropes they didn't want the system to hold back that creativity.</p>

<p>Another way that <em>Daggerheart </em>welcomes new players into roleplay is with Connection Questions. "When people are making their characters in the character guide, there's a selection of background questions and a selection of connection questions. The background questions are designed to help the player create their character, but most importantly, to let the GM know what the player wants. It prompts the players to give the villain from the backstory, their hometown, and the thing that they're seeking."</p>

<p>Starke joked that it's a way for a GM to know "who do you care about the most?" while slyly miming writing down notes.</p>

<p>"For the player-to-player side, by making connections from Session Zero, saying 'I am connected to you because…', now the players also have those same tags in those notes. They can plot ways to bring it out or support the stories that each other wants to tell."</p>

<h2>Manage Your Resources</h2>

<p>In reviewing how the game had evolved as the open beta period had continued, I was interested in just how much there is for a player to keep track of. They have their health and abilities, but also armor that can degrade, stress that can build up, and Hope to earn.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-character-sheet-and-sidecar.jpg?itok=CJwA4OGI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-character-sheet-and-sidecar.jpg?itok=H6_78uSj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>At a lot of junctions in the game, you'll be presented with choices: do I take some extra damage or use my armor to protect myself? Should I risk more stress to unleash a powerful attack if it leaves me vulnerable?</p>

<p>For lack of a better term I wanted to understand what led them to decisions to include resource management that could feel so 'crunchy' and how that affected the game mechanically as well as through story.</p>

<p>"One of the big reasons why is that we wanted it to feel different when you were blocking with a shield versus dodging out of the way of an attack," Starke explained. "We wanted to create some flow from mechanics to narrative."</p>

<p>"There's a little bit more mechanically, and resources to use," referencing Hope specifically as a resource that you gain almost every roll of the dice. "All of those contribute to the genre that we're playing with here in <em>Daggerheart </em>which is the Heroic Fantasy genre"</p>

<p>Hall added "we want all of that resource management, all of that math and the dice rolling, to also feel like it's narratively aligned." Pulling from a previous session that they had been playing in Hall explained that none of their rolls were earning them Hope. "That told me the place that my character was in, I was looking more towards my abilities that require me to spend stress."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Stress is one of my favorite mechanics because, to me, it feels like how actual stress works. You can spend your own stress to do cool things, you can decide to do things that will stress you out, and the world can inflict stress upon you."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Talking about this experience Hall not only discussed how it gave them totally different gameplay options, but also how it worked to inform the narrative of their character and how they were feeling in the moment.</p>

<h2><em>Daggerheart's </em>Beta and Live Stream Success</h2>

<p><em>Daggerheart </em>may just be releasing but it's been in the publics eye for some time, in the form of a public beta as well as being featured in multiple Critical Role mini-series and live shows. I asked Starke and Hall if they remember when during this period they really felt like <em>Daggerheart </em>was going to be something big.</p>

<p>"[Matthew] Mercer was so wonderful with us, learning mechanics as we were building them" Hall began</p>

<p>"He was on it, rolled with the punches of us being like 'Ok Matt, I know you're playing a game today but these things have changes'"</p>

<p>Recalling watching the first Menagerie stream with the development team Starke recounts, "It's live, we were all sitting there with bated breath [...] I remember the magic of watching them play and seeing them have a blast. We knew they were having fun when we were doing internal playtests but to have the relief of them on-stream just having the best time we thought 'We did it!'"</p>

<p>"TTRPGs at their core are about having fun with your friends and seeing people that we care so much about having fun with the game, it meant so much to us," Hall added "seeing people who were actively playing the beta also commenting on the stream and commenting on things going on at their own table was the peak version of 'your friends having fun.'"</p>

<h2><em>Daggerheart </em>Miniatures</h2>

<p>Knowing my own table's enjoyment from seeing the game brought to life with miniatures, I did try to get some information about when we might be able to get our hands on <em>Daggerheart </em>Miniatures? Unfortunately Starke's response was "We don't know, but in success anything could happen"</p>

<p>While we didn't get to learn about any plans that didn't stop Starke from highlighting how in design he wanted a game that was narratively focused, but was also intriguing in a way that players would want to purchase or create miniatures.</p>

<p>Talking about miniature wishlists, Hall began casually by stating, "I really want to see the Oracle of Doom as a miniature, it's one of the Adversaries that I just think is so terrifying"</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-tier-4-adversary.jpg?itok=fre3MOR1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-tier-4-adversary.jpg?itok=hJYBXuD- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Starke however teased that he's looking forward to "all of the minis for Matt's Age of Umbra run that he's doing." The Campaign Frame, that Matt wrote for <em>Daggerheart</em>, will be the setting for an 8-part mini-series with the cast of Critical Role beginning on May 29th.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"It's the stuff of nightmares (Affectionate)" - Rowan Hall on Age of Umbra</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Starke was able to share that the inspiration to have Age of Umbra written comes from a homegame that Starke and Mercer are in with fellow TTRPG performers, Erika Ishii, Aabria Iyengar, and Brennan Lee Mulligan, where they play Kingdom Death Monster together. When the idea of creating Campaign Frames came up Starke approached Matt to ask "Can we do a Soulsborne-inspire/Kingdom Death Monster inspired Campaign Frame for this?" and he said he was so in…</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daggerheart Review - A Narrative Forward 'yes and...' TTRPG That Is A Force To Be Reckoned With]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/daggerheart-review-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-force-to-be-reckoned</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/daggerheart-review-a-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-a-force-to-be-reckoned-with.1193910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/daggerheart-review-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-force-to-be-reckoned<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It was big news when <em>Daggerheart </em>was announced from Darrington Press, the tabletop publishing arm of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="taxonomy_term" data-entity-uuid="3f8817f0-9357-4cd7-a8da-195b567fe5e2" href="https://techraptor.net/topic/critical-role" rel="nofollow">Critical Role</a>. The company, built on <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons </em>Actual Plays, steps into the high-fantasy TTRPG space, and what they've come out with is a blast. Plenty of Character Options and DM tools are included, but I have a feeling I know just who this all won't click with.</p>

<h2>What Comes With <em>Daggerheart</em>?</h2>

<p>For the core set of <em>Daggerheart </em>you'll be receiving a 360+ page Core Rulebook. This includes everything you need to play the game from building a Player Character and how to interact with the world, to a list of different Adversaries a party might fight and information about the Campaign Frames to set your adventures within.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>To learn more about what went into the creation of Daggerheart and how designers, Spenser Starke and Rowan Hall, look to support DMs <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ec6ba1b0-bff9-42b1-a2d3-fccbe606c822" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/daggerheart-gm-tools-high-level-play-and-miniature-discussion-with-designers" rel="nofollow">check out our pre-release interview.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In addition to the physical book there is also a folder of cards, these cards include information about each of the different sub-classes (two sub-classes for each of the nine classes), Ancestry information, Community information, and a deck of cards for all of the abilities for each of the Domains (think of these like spell and ability lists)</p>

<p>When building a character out you can put it all into your character sheet, or you can juggle between the abilities and weapons that you might keep on your character sheet and the physical cards for quick referencing your abilities.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-preview-image.jpg?itok=qkhgjEXm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-preview-image.jpg?itok=Nds2Gsqv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Building A <em>Daggerheart </em>Character</h2>

<p>There's a lot of TTRPG where you'll hear people say "building a character is very fast" but <em>Daggerheart </em>is one where I would agree. With the cards laid out in front of you you get to pick a sub-class (that comes with the Class and it's Class features), Ancestry (species), Community (what type of upbringing your character has), starting equipment, and input basic stats.</p>

<p>You'll know as soon as you have picked your Sorcerer sub-class that you'll want to pick a Instinct weapon, then it's just a matter of picking two abilities for your domains.</p>

<p>Stats are based on a standard array (+2, +1, +1, 0, 0, -1) and other characteristics like your starting evasion, hit points are all based on your class.</p>

<p>You'll end up with a completely filled-out character sheet and five playing cards, and you're ready to go.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-character-cards.jpg?itok=6ar31RmD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-character-cards.jpg?itok=cMmPDqQS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Quick reference cards offer a nice change from the character sheet, but more places to look</figcaption></figure><p>I loved the character creation process. While it did feel like there were less options being presented to me the walls that each of those options presented were far more spaced out. An example might be the Sorcerer's Minor Illusion.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Make a Spellcast Roll (10). On a success, you create a minor visual illusion no larger than yourself within Close range. This illusion is convincing to anyone at Close range or farther out."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It's a simple roll and then the world is your oyster. Whether you use this for flavor, to try to fool an adversary, or include it as part of a performance. There's no nitty gritty about inspections, whether it can or can't make a sound, etc. This kind of prioritization for creativity is seen in a lot of the abilities.</p>

<h2>Character Growth</h2>

<p>Leveling up in <em>Daggerheart </em>offers characters a variety of options depending on what level they've reached (where the max is 10). These are things like gaining an additional Hit Point, Stress Slot, upgrading your experiences, or more.</p>

<p>Each level up has six or more possibilities for you to choose two from, letting you prioritize what you're most interested in and begin to create further diversification with your character.</p>

<p>This is also where the Tiers come into play. A level 1 character is Tier 1, but a Level 5-7 character is in Tier 3. Each of these Tiers is a good indicator for the GM, but also the players what kinds of experiences they should be having at the table. Each time you ascend a Tier you know that you've graduated to a new level of adventuring.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-faerie-ancestry.jpg?itok=IbT4LYLO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-faerie-ancestry.jpg?itok=daY9paGM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Where To Obtain What Information</h2>

<p>When first opening up all of the cards and reviewing the character sheets it seemed like there would be cards for abilities, whether those abilities be tied to what kind of creature you were playing or what they specialized in, and that the player sheet would be for tracking weapons, inventory, and stats/resources.</p>

<p>I was mistaken, realizing that class features instead go on your character sheet. It felt like an arbitrary line had been drawn between what would get it's own card and what would be on the character sheet and the most basic Class features didn't make the cut.</p>

<h2>Tools For A GM</h2>

<p>When playing <em>Daggerheart </em>at no point did I not feel supported by the Core Rulebook. This thing is absolutely packed with not just all of the rules that you'll need to manage the game, but also to make it your own.</p>

<p>A large number of rule explanations, like how to craft encounters, create new adversaries, and to deal with the results of player rolls don't just tell you what to do, but extrapolate on the different ways that you can handle these events, and even how the designers would approach these situations.</p>

<p>There's a lot of effort put into reassuring the GM that there's no one 'correct' way to play the game, and that in situations that call for it you can definitely fudge or ignore certain aspects of a stat block or rule.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-dm-assistance.jpg?itok=o63JZ1Rq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-dm-assistance.jpg?itok=TEmcFOdJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Hope and Fear Always Progressing The Story</h2>

<p>The most unique aspect for me in <em>Daggerheart </em>is that all skill checks are performed with two D12, one for Hope and one for Fear, as opposed to a D20 or a group of D6. You'll always add the numbers together, but whether the higher number was Hope or Fear will have different effects.</p>

<p>Succeeding your skill check with a 5 on the Fear die and a 9 on the Hope die will give you a total of 14 and you'll earn Hope for your character, if those numbers were reversed you may still pass your skill check, but the GM obtains a fear point and while there is a success there might be a consequence.</p>

<p>It's an easy method to create varying levels of success and when Hope is capped at six per player and Fear for the DM stops at Twelve. This resource will continue to gather for the player or DM with every single check or attack allowing you to be spending and receiving them freely. Your access to this resource will also let you pull off bigger and badder abilities.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-bard-class.jpg?itok=-C1vxXxp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-bard-class.jpg?itok=kjVjWEzr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I really think <em>Daggerheart </em>has nailed something here with these resources. It's a way to promote even the most basic of gameplay and mean that even if you fail a skill check there's a chance for you to gain at least something. There's no wasted action and it also allows for the DM to prompt for more actions knowing that they too can obtain more resources from it.</p>

<h2>Combat Is Freeform</h2>

<p>Combat is where I believe players will either really enjoy it, or really not like it. Combat in <em>Daggerheart </em>is freeform, letting the players make moves in whatever order they want until the GM decides to cut in, spending one or multiple Fear to activate an Adversary dealing some damage.</p>

<p>This style of combat creates a scenario of requiring patience and planning, knowing when you'd like to jump in, but it also requires you to maintain attention on the battlefield. You'll never know if the enemy you're next to is about to take multiple swings at you, or when a party member is going to invite you to participate in a combo attack.</p>

<p>Running <em>Daggerheart,&nbsp;</em>I personally enjoyed goading players into more attacks, seeing them roll with Fear to work my way towards consecutive attacks to push back on the party. It felt like there was more of an ebb and flow between what I was doing and getting to respond to them in the moment.</p>

<p>What I saw at my table from my players was really interesting compared to our standard game of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow"><em>D&amp;D</em></a>. I have multiple players who tend to disengage when it's not their turn while playing <em>D&amp;D</em> and return to focus when they're up, for <em>Daggerheart </em>through I got mixed responses.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-tier-1-adversary_0.jpg?itok=-SwoLkeJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-tier-1-adversary_0.jpg?itok=OotmcvCm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>One of my normally disengaged players ended up being the most engaged at the table, wanting to throw additional dagger slices into the fray any chance they got (that also meant they were the one potentially feeding me the most Fear) while the other player remained disengaged, hopping in when they wanted to.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>A line to take turns can allow space for disengagement, but everyone understands a line. Not everyone understands sharing the spotlight, or has the drive to take that spotlight if there are louder voices present</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There will be players who prefer an initiative, taking a turn to perform their action so everyone gets one turn per round, and there will be players that enjoy the freeform style of gameplay. This is likely something that is going to be very hard to determine for a player until they're put in the situation to try it out.</p>

<p>Without putting limitations on actions this kind of combat play style can also lead to introverted players not hopping in. The <em>Daggerheart Core Rulebook</em> does offer some suggestions to make sure that the spotlight is shared including adding a number of actions that each character can perform before everyone's actions are refreshed.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-beast-feast.jpg?itok=cealVhna 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-beast-feast.jpg?itok=lTOSSaRQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Campaign Frames For All Styles</h2>

<p>While there are no trial adventures for a GM to kick off with, there are a number of different Campaign Frames that are offered. While I had originally believed these to just be thematic settings, these are so much more.</p>

<p>Each Campaign Frame comes with a pitch to gauge player interest, a list of tones, themes, and inspirational touchstones, and pages of information detailing starting points for stories, Session Zero questions, Campaign Frame-specific mechanics and more.</p>

<p>Fans of <em>Princess Mononoke</em> or <em>The Legend of Zelda</em> can hop into a fantastical world at risk of corruption in the Witherwild Campaign Frame, Delicious in Dungeon fans can explore Beast Feast where the benefits of a short or long rest are replaced with mechanics for how to restore yourself by eating meals made of cooked monsters, and if you're a fan of Wild Wild West or Shadow of the Colossus you can be a cowboy scaling gargantuan beasts in Colossus of the Drylands.</p>

<p>One Campaign Frame has even included a completely made-up language that my mind went wild wondering how to slowly drip-feed that information to my players.</p>

<p>While I can't imagine some of the gimmicks of these Campaign Frames working for a multi-year campaign, I'm definitely excited to run short adventures of hungry adventurers or dungeon diving where the dungeon itself is a monster.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/daggerheart-colossus.jpg?itok=WTfG5ARh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/daggerheart-colossus.jpg?itok=9Pemn8ZR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2><em>Daggerheart </em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Having been a fan in the original beta period and getting to return I have been blown away by the level of polish that <em>Daggerheart </em>has received and by the amount of clear and concise information that has been provided to the players and GM alike.</p>

<p>I do still wish that there was additional Class cards for the Class abilities to create a separation between the kind of info on the Character Sheet and what's on the cards, but I suppose the easy workaround for this would be to keep the ability information on the sheets to.</p>

<p>I imagine the hardest part of deciding how to run this is the extra coordination required when reaching combat, making sure as the DM you're aware of all of the pieces on the board and how they can all act at any time, but also to make sure none of your players are getting left out of the fray. This will be the piece that is most hit or miss with players.</p>

<p>Overall, <em>Daggerheart </em>promotes strong narrative gameplay that is propped up by mechanics. It's not just schoolyard posturing, but you can have a unique experience that then lets you show off your prowess. It's supporting of the player and it's supporting of the GM which leads to a very happy table.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of <strong>Daggerheart </strong>used for this review was provided by Darrington Press. All photos were taken during the course of the review.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mission: Impossible's Secret Weapon Is Luther Stickell]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mission-impossible-luther-stickell-ving-rhames-mi8-1851781283</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mission-impossibles-secret-weapon-is-luther-stickell.1193904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mission-impossible-luther-stickell-ving-rhames-mi8-1851781283<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Tom Cruise’s blockbuster action spy franchise <em>Mission: Impossible</em> is ostensibly about his character, agent Ethan Hunt, pulling off extremely dangerous missions to save the world from terrorists and other evildoers. So it’s not surprising that Hunt appears in ever<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mission-impossible-final-reckoning-tom-cruise-stunts-1851780902&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mission-impossible-final-reckoning-tom-cruise-stunts-1851780902"><em> Mission: Impossible</em> movie</a></span>. But you know who else appears in every one of these films, including the latest, <em>Final Reckoning</em>? Ving Rhames as Luther Stickell. And I’m so happy to see him in each film. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197567" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="104" data-playlist="197567,197565,197564" data-current="197567"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Price Is Set at $450 for Now, But Could Go Higher</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197567/197567_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23091.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Luther Stickell is first introduced in the original <em>Mission: Impossible</em> movie as a genius computer hacker and “phone phreaker” who has been “disavowed” by the IMF for his actions, and who helps Ethan with his mission to be reinstated. In the next few films he helps Ethan over and over, often acting as the agent’s “second eyes,” someone who can help guide him during missions using hacked cameras. He often unlocks doors, shuts down security systems, or gains access to secret info using his hacking skills. Without Luther, Ethan would have likely failed some of his biggest missions or even died. And during all of this hacking and helping, Luther remains a loyal friend with a cool demeanor, slick style, and a big heart. <br></p><p>It’s not a debate that in both the fictional movie universe of<em> Mission: Impossible</em> and the franchise itself, Cruise’s Hunt is the most important person around. He’s on every poster. In every movie. He saves the day over and over again and each film is mostly focused on his struggles.  His defeats. His wins. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tom-cruise-promises-underwater-sequence-unlike-any-othe-1851779244&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tom-cruise-promises-underwater-sequence-unlike-any-othe-1851779244">And of course, all those sick stunts he does during missions</a></span>. But I think Luther Stickell is the second most important person because without him, Ethan would have failed many times. Plus, he acts as a close friend and confidant, an important role when you have a life as stressful and full of secrets as Ethan’s. </p><h2 id="h52644"><a id=""></a>Luther is always helping, even if he’s not around</h2><p>Case in point: Luther Stickell doesn’t show up until the very end of <em>Mission: Impossible Ghost Protocol</em>. But he still <em>shows up </em>at a bar, after the chaotic mission, to roast Ethan’s “corny” one-liner and share a beer with his bud. Cruise, who is heavily involved with these movies, as well as director Brad Bird, could have chosen to not include Luther. But I think Cruise understands how important it is for Luther to be around in Ethan’s life. And at this point, the audience loves him and expects him to show up over and over to save the day, make us laugh, and be the coolest person on screen. </p><p>Even when Luther isn’t around, he’s important and helping Ethan Hunt. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luther_Stickell#:~:text=It%20is%20revealed%20in%20later%20film%20Fallout%20that%20after%20Ethan%20and%20Julia%20fake%20her%20death%2C%20Luther%20is%20responsible%20for%20teaching%20Julia%20how%20to%20be%20a%20%27ghost%27%3A%20to%20disappear%20and%20avoid%20being%20hunted%20by%20anyone%20looking%20to%20use%20her%20against%20Ethan.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luther_Stickell#:~:text=It%20is%20revealed%20in%20later%20film%20Fallout%20that%20after%20Ethan%20and%20Julia%20fake%20her%20death%2C%20Luther%20is%20responsible%20for%20teaching%20Julia%20how%20to%20be%20a%20%27ghost%27%3A%20to%20disappear%20and%20avoid%20being%20hunted%20by%20anyone%20looking%20to%20use%20her%20against%20Ethan." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As revealed in <em>Fallout</em></a></span>, after the events of <em>Mission: Impossible 3</em>, Hunt leaves his wife to allow her to live a happy and safe life. But Luther helps train her on how to be a spy, hide from dangerous people, and how to protect herself. Luther is truly the nicest dude in the franchise. </p><p>It’s wild to think that we almost missed out on Luther appearing in every <em>Mission</em> film. Back during production on the first movie, Ving Rhames says that the original script has his character dying very early on. He pointed this out to star and producer Tom Cruise, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/mission-impossible-ving-rhames-luther-death-factoid/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/mission-impossible-ving-rhames-luther-death-factoid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as he explained in a recent interview with <em>ScreenRant</em></a></span>. </p><p>  “The first one, I died in the first 10 pages and I said, ‘Why is it the black man always dies in the first 10 pages?’ Tom said, ‘Yeah. Why is that?’ So, now, I just finished number eight, so I feel pretty fortunate,” said Rhames. </p><p>I’m so happy that Tom Cruise realized that was a silly decision and advocated for Luther to survive the first film. Since then, Luther has become a key part of the franchise, just as important and expected as big stunts, lifelike masks, secret messages, and Ethan Hunt. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Delay Could Wipe Out A Jaw-Dropping Amount Of Money From Global Games Industry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delay-could-wipe-out-a-jaw-dropping-amount-of-money-from-global-games-industry/1100-6531664/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-delay-could-wipe-out-a-jaw-dropping-amount-of-money-from-global-games-industry.1193901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delay-could-wipe-out-a-jaw-dropping-amount-of-money-from-global-games-industry/1100-6531664/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531664">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> being delayed to 2026 is tough news for the industry overall, with a new report saying the game's push to next year will wipe out an expected $2.7 billion in spending for 2025.</p><p>Ampere Analysis said in a report that the game's delay erases that much revenue, which would have been derived from game and hardware sales from the global market. A previous report from a different research company said GTA 6 would sell <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-ref-id="1100-6528605">40 million copies and earn $3 billion in its first year alone.</a></p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1505296903" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465958,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;EVERYTHING%20You%20Missed%20In%20The%20GTA%206%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:425,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/everything-you-missed-in-the-gta-6-trailer\/2300-6465958\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465958\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465958\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465958\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465958&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465958,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531664&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto-vi&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;rockstar-games&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465958},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465958\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4490138-gamespot_c_93.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/QP40CA0B.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1746631860,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="QP40CA0B" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> EVERYTHING You Missed In The GTA 6 Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Another previous report said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-gta-6-delay-and-switch-2-launch-could-impact-video-games-in-2025-and-beyond/1100-6531553/" data-ref-id="1100-6531553">Sony was specifically hurt by GTA 6's delay to 2026</a>, due to an expected uptick in game and console sales. It's also been theorized that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-includes-playstation-controller-and-console-references/1100-6531330/" data-ref-id="1100-6531330">Sony has a deal with Rockstar for GTA 6. </a></p><p>GTA 6 being delayed to 2026 creates a "vacuum" for other publishers to maximize the sales potential of their games during Holiday 2025, Ampere said. The company added that Nintendo is now "better placed to capitalized" in this environment with the launch of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a> and its marquee games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a>.</p><p>Like the game's release date, revenue deriving from GTA 6 is not canceled, but delayed. GTA 6 is expected to be a massive success whenever it's released. The game was delayed due in part to Rockstar's teams <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-exec-suggests-no-more-delays-says-recent-push-is-less-than-6-months/1100-6531629/" data-ref-id="1100-6531629">needing more time to polish the game and get it ready for launch. </a></p><p>Even with GTA 6's delay, Ampere's report said the total global video game industry is expected to reach $201.3 billion in 2025, which would be up from the all-time annual record of $199.4 billion in 2024. This is a growth of about 1%, but Ampere said 2026 should see an annual growth rate of 2.2% thanks in part to GTA 6.</p><p>Ampere's Piers Harding-Rolls said the video game industry's lack of a new transformative technology or updated monetization and distribution models means game companies are "looking for pockets of growth to exploit and to build content more efficiently and at lower cost."</p><p>As for the Switch 2, it's said to be the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-gta-6-delay-and-switch-2-launch-could-impact-video-games-in-2025-and-beyond/1100-6531553/" data-ref-id="1100-6531553">"most important product launch" of all time in gaming</a>, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-how-many-switch-2-consoles-it-expects-to-sell-during-its-first-year/1100-6531389/" data-ref-id="1100-6531389">Nintendo predicting it will sell millions of systems and games.</a> The system launches on June 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2: Heart of Democracy Out Now – Fight on the Streets of Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-out-now-fight-on-the-streets-of-super-earth/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-out-now-%E2%80%93-fight-on-the-streets-of-super-earth.1193883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-out-now-fight-on-the-streets-of-super-earth/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Arrowhead Game Studios has released the highly anticipated Helldivers 2: Heart of Democracy update on both PlayStation 5 and PC.</p>
<p>After fighting for democracy across the galaxy, players have swiftly been recalled back to Super Earth, where they'll have to fight against the <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-galactic-emergency-announced-new-enemies-and-weapon-customizations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">invading Illuminate</a>, a faction formed by an aquatic species known as Squ'ith. Super Earth Armed Forces had nearly annihilated them, but in secret, they built a fleet called The Great Host, which is now invading Super Earth.</p>
<p>In a major change of environment from the usual planet, Helldivers will fight among towering skyscrapers and crowded streets while the Illuminate rain down destruction all around. Inside the city biomes, players must tackle operations and work to liberate cities together, having a significant impact on planetary campaigns. They must fight to control areas where the fleet is landing, in what Arrowhead has described as a game of intergalactic tug-of-war, struggling against the incoming forces, with the potential to gain and lose control quickly.</p>
<p>Helldivers will find help in the Super Earth Armed Forces troops, who fight on their own but can be ordered to follow players and provide temporary backup as they navigate toward objectives. The ultimate goal is to activate Super Earth's Planetary Defense Cannons to take down the Illuminate fleet. However, Helldivers must also be aware of the many civilians still roaming the streets, fearing for their lives. Any civilian lives lost from friendly fire will be punished.</p>
<p><iframe title="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Helldivers 2 was just updated with a new and powerful primary weapon customization system. Most primary weapons now have levels that can be achieved by completing missions. These levels unlock new attachments that can be obtained through Requisition. Players can also unlock weapon patterns.</p>
<p>The weapon customization system allows tweaking sights for precision, changing color patterns, adjusting magazine capacity, optimizing weapon performance characteristics with muzzle adjustments, or customizing under-barrel attachments for optimal handling.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers II ‘Heart of Democracy’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/helldivers-ii-heart-of-democracy-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-ii-%E2%80%98heart-of-democracy%E2%80%99-update-now-available.1193874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/helldivers-ii-heart-of-democracy-update-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Bringing the fight to the streets of Super Earth.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,997 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Arrowhead Game Studios [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arrowhead-game-studios">Arrowhead Game Studios</a> have <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/20/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-live-brings-the-fight-to-the-streets-of-super-earth/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">released</a> the <em><a title="Games > Helldivers II [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers II</a></em> update “Heart of Democracy,” which brings the fight to the streets of Super Earth. <span id="more-965834"></span></p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p>The worst nightmare of all those who fight for <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ged Democracy has been made a grim reality.</p><p>Despite the valiant efforts of our Helldivers to push back the fleet, the Illuminate have reached Super Earth. Now they are swarming our cities, terrorizing citizens, and destroying our infrastructure. It’s time to rise up and take arms and fight for the precious foundations and soil of Democracy manifest. Helldivers, return to our planet and defend what is rightfully ours.</p><p><strong>Super Earth… Our Home</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Helldivers-II-Update_05-20-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The urban sprawl of Super Earth is the site of the conflict. Fight among the towering skyscrapers and crowded streets of our home turf as the Illuminate rain down destruction all around you.</p><p>Inside the city biomes, you will tackle operations and work to liberate cities together, having a significant impact on planetary campaigns.</p><p><strong>Repel the Invasion</strong></p><p>The Helldivers are tasked with a new objective: to repel the Illuminate invasion by gaining ground over the squids as they fight to control areas where the fleet is landing. It won’t be a walk in the park, divers. Like a game of intergalactic tug-of-war, you will struggle against the incoming forces, gaining and losing control quickly.</p><p><strong>Arm the Cannons</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Helldivers-II-Update_05-20-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><p>Even in the face of such danger, we are not helpless, and all is not lost. The might of Super Earth’s arsenal lies hidden beneath our peaceful, democratic streets. With your help, we must activate our Planetary Defense Cannons and take down the Illuminate fleet in a grand show of power.</p><p><strong>Call for Backup</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Helldivers-II-Update_05-20-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><p>It’s all hands on deck as you encounter SEAF troops who will help join the fight to defend our Freedom. These small squads will fight enemies on their own, or they can be ordered to follow Helldivers and provide temporary backup as you navigate toward objectives. Salute and lead them on the path to victory, divers!</p><p><strong>Protect Citizens</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Helldivers-II-Update_05-20-25_005.jpg"></a></figure><p>However, you must also be aware of the many civilians still roaming the streets, fearing for their lives. They may be panicked, Helldivers, but it is your sworn duty to keep them safe and they look to you as the ultimate protectors of liberty. Remember: any civilian lives lost from friendly fire will be punished.</p><p><strong>Prepare for the Fight</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Helldivers-II-Update_05-20-25_006.jpg"></a></figure><p>Last week, we released a powerful primary weapon customization system and expanded surplus options to fight against the Illuminate as they emerged from the singularity. Now that you have learned the tactics of these new squid troops—like the Crescent Overseer and the hulking Fleshmob—you must master these tools to continue the fight on Super Earth. Use every available resource, divers, and decimate their forces!</p><p>Our major update, “Heart of Democracy,” is now live. Helldivers, to your hellpods immediately! Citizens, enlistment centers will remain open for recruitment.</p></blockquote><p><em>Helldivers II</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,494 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/553850/HELLDIVERS_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers below.</p><h2><span>“Heart of Democracy” Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MmXtgHs2ODg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>“Heart of Democracy” Update Deep Dive</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3pPGgHieWok?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>