<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:35:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite's Chaotic Delulu Mode: What You Need To Know About Proximity Chat Battle Royale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-chaotic-delulu-mode-what-you-need-to-know-about-proximity-chat-battle-royale/1100-6534895/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnites-chaotic-delulu-mode-what-you-need-to-know-about-proximity-chat-battle-royale.1303125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534895">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Just when you thought <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> already had too many battle royale modes, Epic Games goes and drops another one. The new mode, dubbed Delulu, is completely unlike any of the other battle royale variations because it does two things the others don't: It has proximity voice chat, and encourages teaming mid-game with other players not in your group. But it's also a mode where only one person comes out as the winner. Katniss and Peeta's trick with the berries will <em>not</em> work here.</p><p dir="ltr">Delulu has been a blast so far, and matches feel vaguely like Epic mashed up its normal BR with its Party Royale mode--it's a battle royale about socializing. You can use an emote specific to Delulu to join and exit other players' parties on the fly. And since teaming is allowed in this mode, nothing prevents you from collaborating with even more players after you hit the max number for a party.</p><p dir="ltr">Since the social aspect is so crucial to the purpose of this mode, you're required to have a mic, and have the in-game voice chat on and set to Everybody before you can even queue up for it. You can join a round with your friends, but everyone drops in alone, and you'll eventually have to put them down if you want to win.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4571459-fortnitedelulu.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4571459" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4571459-fortnitedelulu.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4571459"></a><figcaption>Delulu is Fortnite's latest attempt to innovate with a new battle royale mode.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4571459-fortnitedelulu.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Right now, Delulu is live on the weekend only, which means it will be available from Friday morning until Monday morning--and it's slated to return next Friday for the same span of time, too. And while it's delightful, there's a bit of a learning curve since there are some nuances to it that Fortnite itself will not explain to you, so we figured we'd take a moment to highlight three important things you should know as you drop into Fortnite Delulu.</p><h2 dir="ltr">There are no reboots in Delulu, but any play can resurrect any knocked player</h2><p dir="ltr">No matter how you play it, Delulu is a solo mode that ends each round with just one winner. So when you're dead, the round is over for you. There will be no rebooting you. <em>However</em>, Delulu players are always knocked before they die, and any other player can res you regardless of which team they're on or if they're even in a squad at all. It's possible your foes will have mercy. It's not unheard of.</p><h2 dir="ltr">The proximity chat effect applies to your squad, too</h2><p dir="ltr">Nothing about the voice chat changes when you join a squad--you'll still only be able to talk to each other when you're in range of the proximity chat, unlike the way squad comms work in normal BR modes. You'll want to keep that in mind when you find that your three teammates are all hanging out together out of your earshot--they might be planning to betray you.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Playing as a Delulu non-hostile actually works</h2><p dir="ltr">While there are people who play Delulu the same way they would any other battle royale mode, most folks seem pretty willing to engage with the social aspect and just hang out. I've had games already where we had more than a dozen players roaming the countryside until the endgame forced us to turn on each other.</p><p dir="ltr">And, yes, I've had more than a few rounds that ended very abruptly after a group of sociopathic teens pretended to be chill, only to shoot me in the face when I let them get close, but I've had very few early deaths despite taking a pacifistic approach whenever I could. The whole thing is a lot less anxiety-inducing than I expected.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Don't try to win in Delulu</h2><p dir="ltr">While I understand that being the last person standing <em>is</em> the stated purpose of Delulu, this particular BR mode is best experienced with a "let's see how this plays out" sort of view on things. It's a rare situation where you can truly say that it's more about the journey than the destination, and that's because rounds of Delulu often play out in weird and unpredictable ways. In this mode, the most fun usually occurs from doing things completely differently than you would in the other battle royale modes.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-chaotic-delulu-mode-what-you-need-to-know-about-proximity-chat-battle-royale/1100-6534895/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swiped Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/swiped-movie-review-lily-james-whitney-wolfe-herd</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/swiped-review.1303107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Lily James stars in this thin but shiny look at dating app pioneer Whitney Wolfe Herd.</h2></div><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Swiped is now available to stream on Hulu in the United States.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As an installment in her filmography, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/swiped">Swiped</a> represents a major leap forward for director Rachel Lee Goldenberg. Coming up from direct-to-video entries for The Asylum and made-for-TV Lifetime movies, Goldenberg launched two more prominent features in 2020 with Valley Girl and Unpregnant, only for their rollouts to be affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. Five years later, she now has Disney money to spend (although under the 20th Century Studios name) with Swiped, certainly her most high profile project yet, garnering a Toronto Film Festival premiere before launching on Hulu and Disney+ worldwide. However, the end result is a decent film that could have been stronger if it were willing to take as many risks as its subject.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Swiped Images</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Swiped tells the story of Whitney Wolfe (she took the name Herd after marrying Michael Herd in 2017), famous for her integral role in Tinder’s rise and also for being the founder and CEO of Bumble. As a key player in the creation of two of the biggest dating apps in existence, it’s not unfair to say that Wolfe has had an astronomical impact on worldwide culture, especially with a younger generation who have had their entire dating life filtered through the presence of such apps. Yet you might not get the full sense of that impact by watching Swiped, which focuses more on the micro consequences in regards to Wolfe’s personal history with the companies, in particular her sexual harassment suit against her former colleagues at Tinder and her subsequent reemergence as the head of Bumble.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The dramatic arc of Wolfe’s rise, downfall and eventual return to prominence certainly makes for an easy enough three act structure, but it also makes Swiped into a movie too basic to do its subject justice. It’s an interesting story on its own merits, and certainly reflects the toxic and misogynistic tendencies of technology company culture. Yet if Wolfe is made undoubtedly sympathetic because of the way her cohorts treat her as she fights to make a name for herself in a male-dominated workspace, the movie never turns enough of a critical eye on Wolfe herself to make her three-dimensional. Swiped’s Whitney Wolfe is a relatable figure because of her struggles, but she never becomes a rounded figure because of her choices.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Swiped is a movie too basic to do its subject justice.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">That's not for lack of trying on the acting front, though. Lily James, of Cinderella and Baby Driver fame, has been an underappreciated actor for years, and turns in a performance that’s better than the script deserves. James’ most compelling attribute, present both on screen and stage (shout-out to her excellent work as Eve Harrington in Ivo van Hove’s 2019 production of All About Eve), is her ability to stealthily take over a scene with small gestures that eventually coalesce into a bigger moment later on. That ability to disarm the audience to produce pathos is what makes her so charming to watch, yet the depth she tries to add to her take on Wolfe isn’t always backed up by the writing. We understand by watching her why she’s good at persuading people to try her products, but charm can only take a character so far when there are reasons to treat her with skepticism.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This becomes a problem when the movie feels obligated to give Wolfe a “dark night of the soul” beat that isn't earned. Although one of Goldenberg’s best directorial touches is how she assembles a frantic montage of Wolfe’s life falling apart through her phone as she becomes the internet’s punching bag of the moment after the sexual harassment suit, this is followed up with Wolfe meeting with former work friend Tisha (Myha’la), who tells her that Wolfe didn’t do enough to help the other women in the office after she earned her co-founder status. James’ furious response to this (and the inherent racial dynamic of a white woman snapping at a Black woman who’s trying to hold her accountable for her actions) is one of the movie’s best moments because it feels emotionally honest about Wolfe’s failings while not taking away from the very real abuse that Wolfe suffered.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/19/lily-james-swiped-1758318606885.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Lily James stars as Whitney Wolfe in Swiped.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But instead of unraveling this thread for more substance, Wolfe and Tisha reconcile in their next encounter after a hasty apology, and Wolfe is restored to her “forward-minded feminist tech leader” status with nary a further mention of any wrongdoing. That the movie then mostly skips over the actual development of Bumble, going from shoebox operation to 35 million-user app in basically one scene transition, only makes this issue worse. This was the era where Wolfe developed the foundation of her personal fortune, which would make her a billionaire by the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/angelauyeung/2021/02/11/bumble-founder-whitney-wolfe-herds-fortune-rockets-past-1-billion-as-dating-app-goes-public/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>age of 31</u></a>. Nobody amasses that kind of money without making serious compromises along the way, but the movie presents Wolfe’s ascension as an easy enough matter because, well, a woman did it this time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The movie also never grapples with the fact that Wolfe’s impact on the world at large could arguably be considered a net negative. Sure, many couples have connected through dating apps, but said apps have also heavily commodified the very concept of meeting potential romantic partners, turning judging others based on a few seconds of visual impression into a gamified and monetized nightmare for many hapless users. Wolfe had a direct hand in creating this state of affairs, but Swiped never considers that worth examining. It’s a shame, because a better movie would have trusted its audience to make their own judgments of Wolfe based on a fuller account of her actions, instead of prescribing how it wants its viewers to feel.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Swiped is constructed well-enough for the movie it’s trying to be, but its lack of ambition and nuance keep it from being its best self. It can still be a worthwhile enough watch for Lily James’ admirable performance as Whitney Wolfe, but the movie never affords its subject the same level of depth as what James tries to imbue her with.</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3><div data-cy="objectcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="article-subtitle">Not yet available for streaming.</p></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-review-title">Swiped Review</h3><div data-cy="review-content"><p>okay</p><p>Swiped is a decent biopic on a craft level, but it never reaches its full potential beyond a strong lead performance from Lily James.</p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/swiped-movie-review-lily-james-whitney-wolfe-herd]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Puzzle Tables and Boards for the Ultimate Puzzle Station]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-tables</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-puzzle-tables-and-boards-for-the-ultimate-puzzle-station.1303098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As avid puzzlers know full well, the humble jigsaw puzzle is a thing of beauty in multiple ways. Not only are jigsaws an absorbing time sink, but multiple <a href="https://blogs.bcm.edu/2020/10/29/a-perfect-match-the-health-benefits-of-jigsaw-puzzles/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">studies have demonstrated</a> they are good for you both mentally and physically. As you fit the pieces into place, they can be enjoyed alone or as a communal activity, and remain to be a fun hobby for all ages. Plus, when you’re finished, you’re often left with a delightful piece of art and sense of accomplishment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The only downside to puzzles is they can take up a surprising amount of space, especially puzzles with 1000+ pieces. If you get into working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/largest-jigsaw-puzzles">bigger puzzles</a>, they can eat up your dining room table, coffee table or desk space for long stretches of time. This is why many jigsaw fans have a dedicated puzzle-solving table or board these days, often equipped with useful accessories. You have foldable and portable options, multi-purpose tables (for playing cards and the like), and ones with drawers to organize the pieces as you go. No matter what you're looking for or what your budget is, we've found some viable options for you below.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">TL;DR: These Are the Best Puzzle Tables and Boards</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve got the puzzle bug or simply want an easier setup for regular puzzling, below are our top puzzle table and board picks right now to solve your space and storage problems, no matter your budget. Each of our picks represent a different category of table or board to fit different jigsaw puzzle needs. There are a lot of different options to choose from within these categories, so we've narrowed it down to one entry for each that we think fits the category best.</p><h2 data-cy="title2" id="bits-and-pieces">1. Bits and Pieces Fold and Go Table</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best for portability</h3><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214828"><div id="214828" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bits and Pieces Fold-and-Go Wooden Jigsaw Puzzle Table</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This <a href="https://www.bitsandpieces.com/?srsltid=AfmBOorALjfg68C2gxeRGsics57Sap_amx4sJCjMnSZ1WATiMrbMDrth" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bits and Pieces</a> puzzle table has it all in one convenient package that can be easily moved around. It stores completely flat but extends into a good-sized table with fold-out legs and a felt covering to make it easy to pick up and push in pieces. The side arms can be used to arrange pieces you have yet to fit into the main puzzle, giving you plenty of room to work.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Because it stores flat, it also functions as a puzzle protector, allowing you to fold the flaps inward to cover your work in progress. It can then be slid conveniently under furniture until you’re ready to dive in again. And if you like puzzling on the go, this table’s lightweight and has a carry handle. As a bonus, this table is multi-purpose for card games, reading, writing and the like. It's a great portable puzzle table that is built to handle up to 1500 piece jigsaw puzzles.</p><h2 data-cy="title2" id="vociprooter">2. Vociprooter Puzzle Board</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best for laps</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214829"><div id="214829" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Vociprooter Jigsaw Puzzle Board</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Some puzzlers prefer the comfort of working from their laps on a favorite chair or sofa, but that can be almost impossible with larger puzzles. To solve this problem, consider one of these handy puzzle folders which offer a hard surface you can spread out and balance on your knees.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The wings offer trays to put puzzle pieces on while you’re still working. When you want to finish a session, you can move the trays into the center and zip the wings closed to seal the puzzle. It can then be tucked away out of sight until you’re ready to carry on. This handy design comes in a variety of sizes to suit your puzzling preferences.  </p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Jigitz Puzzle Spinner</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best for collaborative puzzling</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214830"><div id="214830" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Jigitz Jigsaw Puzzle Spinner</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Great for puzzles and board games.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Having a lazy susan for your jigsaw puzzle is such a great idea it’s surprising more companies haven’t put one on the market. If you’re puzzling with friends it’s much more convenient to reach the piece you’re working on. If you’re puzzling alone, it lets you easily access every side of the puzzle without having to leave your spot, as well as try different angles to see if a new perspective sparks a new idea for a match between possible pieces.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This particular Jigitz spinning table topper comes with a felt backing for convenience, a hardwood rim, and can hold puzzles up to 34” x 34” (which should cover most 1000 piece puzzles). And if you’re into jigsaws of different shapes, there’s a <a href="https://zdcs.link/YBpGr?object_uuid=1d7bfb97-f8ca-443f-8546-51315d70dbc9&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">circular option</a> from the same manufacturer, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to puzzle use, this spinning board is also excellent for playing board games like Scrabble where rotating the board is quite useful. Though a dedicated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-game-table">board game table</a> is still worthwhile if you are looking to mostly use it for that.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Jumbl 1000-Piece Puzzle Board Rack</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best for storing pieces</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214831"><div id="214831" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Jumbl 1000-Piece Puzzle Table</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Great for puzzle organization.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s another full puzzle table with fold-out legs for your consideration. From Jumbl, this table’s a little bulkier than some others on this list, but that’s because it comes with a hidden benefit: slide-out drawers to store your puzzle pieces. Anything you're currently clueless about can be hidden away until you’re ready, as can part-finished sections that aren’t quite ready to join the main puzzle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The table is thoughtfully designed in a number of other respects, from the attractive varnished finish to the two-sided rail that gives you clear access from different angles while keeping the puzzle in place. And if you don’t need it freestanding, it’s thin enough to sit conveniently on a tabletop or other surface.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This particular puzzle table is only meant to handle up to 1000-piece puzzles, but with the addition of the drawers, it should be able to scale up to 1500 pieces or more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2" id="playvibe">5. Playvibe Puzzle Board</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best table topper</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214832"><div id="214832" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>PlayVibe Puzzle Locker</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Works great for puzzles up to 1500 pieces.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Our previous recommendation will sit atop a table, but it’s a little bulky should that be your primary mode of play. This one, from Playvibe, is a dedicated, slimline table-topper with felt feet to grip surfaces and six handy drawers to help store and organize your pieces.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fully enclosed edging helps keep your puzzle secure, and the board comes with an acetate cover that fits between the rails to protect half-finished segments when not in use. It’s also made of lightweight wood, so it’s sturdy but still easy to move around from surface to surface as it suits you. </p><h2 data-cy="title2" id="all4jig">6. All4Jig Tilting Puzzle Table</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best dedicated tilting table</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214833"><div id="214833" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>All4Jig 1500 Piece Adjustable Puzzle Board</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>You can adjust the angle and height.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Regular puzzle players will be familiar with the postural problems that can arise from being bent over a surface for a long stretch. If that’s a problem for you, then the answer might be a tilting table like this one from <a href="https://all4jig.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ALL4JIG</a> that leans toward you from different angles, allowing you to sit back and relax in a comfy seat while enjoying your puzzle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The board has a thick lower lip designed to keep a separate puzzling board in place, but you can play directly on the table’s surface if desired. It’s on wheels, so you can maneuver it into position around your seat, and it comes in a neat wood laminate finish.</p><h2 data-cy="title2" id="becko">7. Becko Angle Puzzle Board</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Best table topper that tilts</h3></div><div catalogid="e7adf963-6ce1-4d39-aa82-8e8cf6a2bcd7" id="214834"><div id="214834" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Best Tilting Table Topper</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Becko Adjustable Puzzle Board</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes two adjustable amgles.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A table that tilts toward you as you play is obviously useful, but some players don’t want a whole table to do that, only a stand-alone board. This table from <a href="https://www.ibecko.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Becko</a> offers that convenience in a particularly solid and useful package with a natural pine wood frame.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s been thoughtfully designed, with a flannelette (like flannel, but not quite) surface to grip and sort your pieces, while the supplied bracket gives you a choice of angles and can actually be used with other boards. So it’s super useful if you’ve got more than one puzzle on the go at once.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Puzzle Board FAQs</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Puzzle Mats vs Puzzle Boards: Which is better?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Puzzle boards and puzzle mats are both tools avid puzzlers can use to organize their workspace and keep track of pieces. If you're looking to buy either as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-gifts">gift for the puzzler in your life</a>, there are a few things to consider/</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Boards are more expensive but offer more features, like pullout trays and other storage options, that help puzzlers organize their projects. The main benefit of a puzzle board is stability, as these boards are typically made from wood and offer a sturdy, flat surface. While they may take up more space, an in-progress or completed puzzle can still be safely moved between locations on a wooden puzzle board. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Puzzle mats are a cheaper and more lightweight alternative to puzzle boards. Mats, usually made with felt, can be rolled up and stowed away. Putting away a mat may be easier than finding a space for a full-blown board, but these mats are also flimsier. Pieces may not stay together as firmly on a softer surface, and there are no additional storage features to keep track of them. While mats help puzzlers establish a clear workspace, they require an existing flat surface for stability. </p></div><div catalogid="c533fd11-45af-41af-83ff-0a1bd409483c" id="214947"><div id="214947" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Becko Puzzle Mat</h3></p></div><h3 data-cy="title3">What is the best size for a puzzle board?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">When researching puzzle boards, consider the amount of space available to you as well as the size of puzzles you like to put together. Many boards indicate what size puzzles they work best for, and some even have dimensions for different puzzles drawn out on their surface.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Most puzzle boards range from about 27 to 35 inches in length. A 30" x 22" puzzle board can comfortably fit most 1000 piece puzzles, though daring puzzlers who tackle more than 1500 or 2000 pieces at a time may need a board closer to 35 inches long. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You may need to pick a specific space in your home to dedicate to a puzzle board. Alternatively, you may look into puzzle mats or foldable puzzle tables that can be stored when not in use. All in all, the ideal size for a puzzle board is what will support your favorite puzzles without dominating your space.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>For more, check out the </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzles-for-adults"><strong>10 best puzzles</strong></a><strong> for adults right now and the </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-brands">b<strong>est jigsaw puzzle brands</strong></a><strong> for all ages!</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Thrower is a contributing freelance board game and video game writer for IGN. (Board, video, all sorts of games!)</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Sep 19, 2025 1:01 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-tables]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Video Games You Should Play This Weekend – September 19, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/opinions/2025/09/19/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-september-19-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-%E2%80%93-september-19-2025.1303095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>What a week! We unveiled our next cover and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/09/18/cover-reveal-the-outer-worlds-2">it features The Outer Worlds 2</a>, published <a href="https://gameinformer.com/round-up/2025/09/18/all-40-games-shown-during-the-september-six-one-indie-showcase">a massive round-up of some cool looking indie games</a> from the equally excellent Six One Indie Showcase, and published multiple <a href="https://gameinformer.com/reviews">reviews</a>! But it's Friday and that means there's a weekend ahead of us and you!</p><p>Last week, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/12/what-you-should-be-playing-this-weekend-of-91225">we spotlighted some games</a> we're playing. This week, we want to give you a selection of games we think you should play this weekend, and it ranges from new releases to DLC to some favorites from over the years. Dig in and, if you check one of these out, come back on Monday and leave us a comment to let us know what you think!</p><h2>Hey Listen*</h2>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="56a59d53-51be-42d6-bc80-675c9523c0d0" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<h4>*Read</h4><p>Below, we'll list the names of <em>Game Informer </em>editors and their thoughts for this week's edition The Video Games You Should Play This Weekend (official name pending).&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/opinions/2025/09/19/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-september-19-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sucker Punch Studio Head Comments On Firing Dev Who Joked About Charlie Kirk’s Death]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sucker-punch-charlie-kirk-ghost-yotei-sony-2000627290</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sucker-punch-studio-head-comments-on-firing-dev-who-joked-about-charlie-kirk%E2%80%99s-death.1303083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For the last week, a war has been waging in the YouTube comments of each new <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> trailer as the PlayStation 5 exclusive nears its release date early next month. That’s because a developer at Sucker Punch Productions<a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-charlie-kirk-joke-playstation-sony-2000625478"> joked about the assassination of Charlie Kirk</a> on social media. Sony confirmed it parted ways with the employee following a right-wing pressure campaign, but declined to issue any further statement. Now studio head and co-founder, Brian Fleming, has commented on the firing directly in a new interview.</p> <p>The Sucker Punch artist Drew Harrison, a nearly 10-year veteran of the studio, had posted “I hope the shooter’s name is Mario so that Luigi knows his bro got his back” on the day the assassination took place. Less than 24 hours later she confirmed she fired. “Drew Harrison is no longer an employee of Sucker Punch Productions,” a spokesperson for Sony told&nbsp;<em>Kotaku</em> at the time.</p> <p>“The facts are accurate,” Fleming <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/sucker-punch-brian-fleming-interview-playstation-ghost-of-yotei">Stephen Totilo’s <em>Game File</em> on Friday</a> when asked about the situation. “Drew’s no longer an employee here. I think we’re aligned as a studio that celebrating or making light of someone’s murder is a deal-breaker for us, and we condemn that, kind of in no uncertain terms. That’s sort of our studio, and that’s kind of where we are.”</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000627297" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000627297"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000627297">YouTube / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Despite Harrison’s swift firing, angry internet users, urged on by clout chasing culture warriors like Mark ‘Grummz’ Kern, have been demanding Sony take action against any staff members who may have liked or reposted Harrison’s comment, while also targeting <a href="https://kotaku.com/ready-or-not-community-manager-fired-for-responding-to-charlie-kirk-assassination-with-nothing-was-lost-2000627182">other companies and their employees</a> over potential anti-Kirk sentiment. That included Bethesda, which was accused of mocking the right-wing podcast’s supporters when it posted a clip from <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> of the famous Nazi puncher saying to a kitten, “You don’t care much about these fascists, do you?” <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/bethesda-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-charlie-kirk-tweet-deleted/">It was later deleted</a>.</p> <p>Microsoft Gaming employees were also targeted, including by Elon Musk. “We’re aware of the views expressed by a small subset of our employees regarding recent events,” the company <a href="https://x.com/Microsoft/status/1966626714148368766">announced</a> in response on September 12. “We take matters like this very seriously and we are currently reviewing each individual situation. Comments celebrating violence against anyone are unacceptable and do not align with our values.” A spokesperson for the company declined to comment when asked if anyone had been fired from Microsoft following these investigations.</p> <p>“Sucker Punch is amazing &amp; one of the last few bright shining lights in the game industry,” Harrison posted this week. “I still support them and I cannot condone any animosity directed at them. It’s truly all the best people.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sucker-punch-charlie-kirk-ghost-yotei-sony-2000627290]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What A Shock, The Government Is Scapegoating Video Games Again]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-charlie-kirk-killer-steam-discord</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-a-shock-the-government-is-scapegoating-video-games-again.1303080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Between RFK Jr <a href="https://futurism.com/neoscope/rfk-mass-shootings-video-games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speculating</a> that video games are a root cause of mass shootings, the Secret Service <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-18/suspected-kirk-shooter-s-gaming-history-probed-by-secret-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">probing the alleged Charlie Kirk killer’s Steam history</a>, and the US Oversight Committee requesting the presence of Steam, Twitch, and Discord’s CEOs <a href="https://aftermath.site/us-oversight-committee-online-radicalization-hearing-discord-twitch-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at a radicalization hearing</a>, you’d almost think we were back in the 90s (except for the part where social media has broken everybody’s brains and Square is now remaking <em>Final Fantasy VII</em> instead of just making it). But nope, we’re in the present, once again snoozing our way through the steps of a song and dance that felt tired the moment it was first trotted out. Video games <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2020/jul/22/playing-video-games-doesnt-lead-to-violent-behaviour-study-shows" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">don’t cause violence</a>, but a small handful of very powerful, even stupider people sure wish they did. On the latest Aftermath Hours, we talk about what’s actually going on.</p><p>This time around, we’re joined by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/morgansung.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Morgan Sung</a> of KQED’s <a href="https://www.npr.org/podcasts/1267078032/close-all-tabs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Close All Tabs podcast</a> to discuss shootings as shitposts and media censorship following the death of Charlie Kirk. While we still don’t know the killer’s precise motive, bullet engravings that reference video game memes and largely nonpolitical Discord activity seem to suggest that he was just a guy, possessed with the incoherent politics and general nihilism characteristic of extremely online young people in these times. What does it say that someone like him could still be pushed to this level of violence?&nbsp;</p><p>How, if at all, can mainstream media – which has <a href="https://aftermath.site/tyler-robinson-journalism-wsj" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shed</a> most of its best internet-focused reporters over the years – accurately convey an online world that’s increasingly bleeding over into real life to aging normie audiences? And with the government moving quickly to crack down on free speech using Charlie Kirk as a cudgel, can independent media take up the torch where mainstream corporate media will inevitably falter?&nbsp;</p><p>Then we talk about <em>Silksong</em>!&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>You can find this week's episode below and on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7qtlX6MNeEoyNuHBU0chUJ?si=a2f12b75911f43cb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/aftermath-hours/id1727407094" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple</a>, or wherever else you prefer to listen to podcasts. If you like what you hear, make sure to leave a review so that Aftermath can rise to international prominence, take the place of the mainstream media apparatus, and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/09/17/nx-s1-5539164/npr-public-media-funding-budget" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">buy NPR</a> or something.</p><p>Here’s an excerpt from our conversation (edited for length and clarity):</p><p><strong>Morgan:</strong> Our source for this episode [of Close All Tabs], <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:xrz2r6zgcmdrjjgx3cqkybp4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aidan Walker</a>, is a meme researcher who literally has a degree in this kind of thing. The way he put it was really interesting. He pointed out how nihilistic a lot of the internet is – and how that nihilism isn’t really reflected or addressed in either political party. This is something that is so pervasive and also so overlooked that a lot of people just feel left out of the discussion entirely.</p><p>I’m just thinking of the way Twitter was so quick to try to blame groypers for this – trying to find a way that these references could be proof that this was the far, far right. Whereas conservative mainstream media was blaming the left. In reality, if you look at the court documents released after the alleged shooter was arrested, his politics seem a bit incomprehensible – just like a shitpost. It’s disruptive and incoherent.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> Even Luigi Mangione’s politics were incoherent. If you’re gonna take a person’s life in a really high-profile way, chances are you’re both not mentally well and a median voter, and the median American voter has incoherent politics – particularly younger people. I feel like there is this sort of millennial, gen Z, gen alpha divide where politics, particularly post-2020, feels almost [hopeless]. I don’t know if younger people are gonna come around to politics in the way millennials did in the Bernie era. It does feel a little more like “Nothing really matters” nihilistic in younger groups.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Nathan: </strong>The most telling piece of reporting I’ve seen on all of this is <a href="https://www.kenklippenstein.com/p/exclusive-leaked-messages-from-charlie" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ken Klippenstein’s article</a> about the Discord the alleged killer was in and the conversations that occurred between people in that Discord – and also the killer’s friends’ takes on what kind of person he was. They said he never really seemed all that political and mentioned that their Discord had a bunch of people of different political valences. They mostly just hung out and talked about video games. I think that’s very revealing: You don’t necessarily have to be a political radical to be driven insane by our current moment. This is bad for everyone. It leads to this prevalent nihilism where, if one thing pushes you too far or a few things do, that can lead to violence – especially when there’s not another pressure release valve on society in general.</p><p><strong>Morgan: </strong>It’s like what we said earlier with Luigi Mangione: People were joking that Luigi Mangione was the OG radical centrist, but I think it’s less that and more that he and Charlie Kirk’s alleged killer are just guys who have been subjected to a system that is very broken and decided to retaliate in a horrific and violent way that isn’t right, but at the same time, all of the discussions people are having are missing those core causes of the reason they are retaliating.</p><p><strong>Nathan: </strong>Yeah, that’s because I think – especially for mainstream media and the government – to talk about that element of things, they’d have to accept a degree of culpability, implicitly if not explicitly. And they sure as heck do not want to do that. So they’re going to point the finger at the typical scapegoats, like video games.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/arma-trans-platoon"><h3>Arma Can Be A Boys Club, But This Trans Women-Only Platoon Aims To Change That</h3></a><p>'It’s a community that is made for the trans community... I’ll never find another place that I feel more safe.'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/zenimax-unions-microsoft-layoffs-mmo-elder-scrolls"><h3>Months After Microsoft Layoffs, Zenimax Unions Never Stopped Fighting For Impacted Workers</h3></a><p>They won more time at the company, improved severance, recall rights, and saved a few jobs</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-charlie-kirk-killer-steam-discord]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Tips To Know Before Playing Borderlands 4]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/12-tips-borderlands-4-guide-help-better-loot-gold-keys-side-quests-tricks-2000626554</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/12-tips-to-know-before-playing-borderlands-4.1303068/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-the-kotaku-review-bugs-pc-performance-ending-gearbox-ps5-2000627149"><em>Borderlands 4</em> is a very big and mostly great game</a> that you’ll likely spend over 50 hours in if you try to do everything it has to offer. It also might be your first <em>Borderlands</em> in a long time, or possibly ever. This all might seem really intimidating. 10 billion guns! A giant open world! What should you do? Well, I’ve got your back. Here are 12 tips to help you get started and kick ass in <em>Borderlands 4.</em> And be not afraid, there are no spoilers below.</p> <h2>Don’t Get Distracted By Side Quests Until You Get Your Hover Bike</h2> <p>Look, I get it. Running around and doing every little side quest is fun, but I’d recommend focusing on the main story until you get your hoverbike. It won’t take more than two hours and it’s worth it. Well, unless you like walking everywhere in a big open-world game. And speaking of side quests and not doing them…</p> <h2>Maybe Don’t Do <em>Every</em> Side Quest Before Finishing The Main Story…</h2> <p>I’m a map cleaner in open-world games. I get it. I love to methodically clear out every piece of content in a big open world. But maybe don’t do that until you complete the main story. That’s because once you do that, regardless of your level, you unlock “Specializations,” which is a new set of passive bonuses and skills that act as an endgame grind. And you level this up with XP. So it might be better to mainline the story and then turn around and do all the side stuff later.</p>

 <h2>But…Focus On Getting SDU Credits To Make Your Backpack Bigger</h2> <p>While I advise not doing every side quest before the credits roll, I do suggest you look out for Propaganda Towers, Bunkers, and other open-world activities that reward you with SDU credits that can be used to upgrade how many items you can hold at once in your backpack. Trust me, you want to upgrade this ASAP. You are going to be grabbing so much random junk to sell and sort through, and running out of space sucks. So prioritize getting that backpack upgraded.</p> <h2>Use The Loot As Junk Button</h2> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-11-best-changes-borderlands-4-junk-loot-menus-legendary-guns-2000624953">New to <em>Borderlands 4</em> is the ability to loot items as junk.</a> This means that you can instantly sell it and every single item you’ve marked as junk with the press of a button just by walking up to a vending machine. It saves a lot of time and is one of the best features in <em>Borderlands 4</em>. Use it. You’ll thank me later.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000624984" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000624984"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000624984">©Gearbox / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2>Keep An Eye Open For Elemental Weapons To Help You Kill Quickly</h2> <p>It’s very easy to focus exclusively on getting guns with bigger numbers. But hold up! It’s not all about DPS. You might want to keep that SMG or shotgun because of its elemental damage type. You see, enemies in<em> Borderlands 4</em> all have different weaknesses to different elements. Enemies with red health bars burn fast, baddies with blue health bars are weak to shock, and aliens or robots with yellow health bars get melted quickly with acid.</p> <p>So before you drop that slightly weaker SMG for a cool new one, stop and think. Does the weaker one do acid damage? Is it your only weapon that does acid damage? You might want to keep it, then, so you can fight robots with ease.</p>

 <h2>Don’t Have Four Of The Same Type Of Gun Equipped</h2> <p>I love a good assault rifle in<em> Borderlands 4.</em> I’m always on the lookout for a new Daedalus AR to add to my collection. But I never run around with more than one AR equipped. Why? Because if all your guns are the same type–like all shotguns or whatever–then you’ll burn through that ammo type much faster. Variety is the spice of life, and it also means you don’t use up all your shotgun shells in a matter of minutes.</p> <h2>Look Down Your Character’s Skill Tree Before Unlocking Anything</h2> <p>Simple one, but important: Before you start upgrading your character’s skills, take a moment to look at what you’ll be able to unlock later on. You might see a skill you just desperately want, or you might realize the particular skill tree you are examining features bonuses and abilities you’ll just never use. And sure, the game lets you respec everything, but why waste time earning skills you don’t like when you can take a moment to plan ahead and have a much better time.</p>

 <h2>When Playing Co-op, Use Your Buddies As Fast Travel Stations</h2> <p>Playing with your friends is always better, but in <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-pc-performance-dlss-frame-gen-pitchford-gearbox-steam-2000625765">Borderlands 4</a>,</em> that’s especially true as you can fast-travel to them whenever you want. Tricky platforming section that you don’t want to do? Fast travel to your bud! Get lost and can’t find your way to the next part of the quest? Fast travel to your friend. Want to sell a bunch of stuff in the middle of a big fight? Fast travel to an area with vending machines, sell your junk, and then fast travel back to your friends. This feature is so useful and powerful that it almost feels like cheating.</p> <h2>Use The Newly Added Repkits!</h2> <p>It’s easy to forget about <em>Borderlands 4</em>‘s newly added Rep Kits, which are small items that can heal you during fights. They are brand new to the franchise and the game never warns you to use one when your health gets low. But use your Rep Kits! They can make a challenging ambush much easier.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000624986" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000624986"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000624986">©Gearbox / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2>If Lost, Just Use Echo 4, aka Hit Up On The D-Pad</h2> <p>Remember, you can always ask Echo 4, your new robot companion, to guide you to your next quest objective or your custom marker. This can be really handy when deep in a cave or building filled with multiple rooms and hallways. Just hit up on the D-pad, and Echo 4 will generate an easy-to-follow holographic line in the world pointing to your target location.</p> <h2>Grab Contracts Before Heading Out</h2> <p>Whenever you return to one of the many hub and town areas in <em>Borderlands 4</em>, take a moment to check the bounty board and grab some bounties. Many of these are very easy to complete and just want you to kill a few random enemies. You were going to do that anyway, so why not get some extra XP and rewards for doing so?</p>

 <h2>Hold Onto Gold Keys Until You Level Up</h2> <p>The moment you walk up to your first gold chest in <em>Borderlands 4</em>, you’ll be tempted to use any gold keys you currently have. Don’t do this. I know, it’s fun to open a big shiny box and get new guns, most of which will be pretty good. But if you’re below level 40, I’d avoid using your keys as the loot you get from them at that point will be made worthless in the not-too-distant future. That level 7 legendary sniper ain’t going to be worth using when, a few hours later, you’re level 12 and find a much better one. Save your gold keys for when you’re in the endgame portion of <em>Borderlands 4</em>.</p> <p>And if you need help getting more (or any…) gold keys, don’t you worry,<a href="https://kotaku.com/how-shift-codes-gold-keys-work-borderlands-4-help-get-more-2000626107"> I’ve got a guide just for you</a> that walks you through the process and even includes some codes you can use to get some fancy rewards.</p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/12-tips-borderlands-4-guide-help-better-loot-gold-keys-side-quests-tricks-2000626554]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Is Going Nuts, This 15″ Gaming Portable Monitor for Xbox and Switch Is Selling for Pennies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-is-going-nuts-this-15-gaming-portable-monitor-for-xbox-and-switch-is-selling-for-pennies-2000627251</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-is-going-nuts-this-15%E2%80%B3-gaming-portable-monitor-for-xbox-and-switch-is-selling-for-pennies.1303065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Screens can quickly become a source of frustration. Attempting to work on a small laptop screen is claustrophobic, gaming on the Nintendo Switch isn’t the most immersive gaming experience, and even gaming consoles such as PlayStation or Xbox sometimes leave you wishing for a more delineated or flexible screen setup.</p>
<p>That’s where a portable monitor changes the story. The <em>Forhelp</em> 15.6‑inch portable monitor provides a crisp 1080p display and a thin profile that you can take wherever you go, putting an end to all those screen frustrations at once. Even better, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4202/">Amazon has cut it down to just $59 (from $79), which happens to be its all-time low</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4202/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A Portable Screen That Travels With You</h2>
<p>What we love about this monitor is how much it manages to pack into such a compact body: <strong>Measuring only 0.3 inches thin and weighing slightly over 1.5 pounds</strong>, it slides perfectly into a backpack alongside your laptop or console. The aluminum alloy body adds strength and premium feel and the included magnetic smart case also doubles as a durable stand. You can stand it on a desk, an airplane tray table or a hotel nightstand with ease, and you still have some choice of viewing angles thanks to the grooves molded into the cover.</p>



<p>The screen is a Full HD 1920×1080 IPS display with a matte finish, so you have rich and true color, a wide 178‑degree viewing angle and less reflection. It even minimizes blue light emissions and eliminates flicker to make long sessions that much more comfortable on the eyes. Image quality is sufficient for this price to immerse you in movies and games and let you forget that compromised feeling when you’re not on your main display.</p>
<p>The monitor features two fully functional USB‑C ports and a mini HDMI port so you can connect it directly to a laptop, Xbox, PlayStation, or Switch with a single cable. Thunderbolt 3/4 and USB‑C DisplayPort Alt Mode‑enabled devices will also power the monitor without the need for adapters so you’re ready to go in no time when working on the go. It’s designed for work and play and includes a number of modes to match how you’re utilizing it. You can mirror your laptop screen during a meeting, extend your desktop for real productivity gains, or use second screen mode on the move.</p>
<p>Two built‑in speakers add audio on the fly without needing external accessories. They won’t rival a dedicated speaker setup but they handle gaming sessions or movies smoothly enough to make this monitor truly self‑contained.</p>



<p>What makes this deal hard to ignore is how much you’re getting at this price. Most travel monitors with a decent IPS panel, multiple connections, and a sleek aluminum case are more expensive, typically $100 or more. Here, for $59, you have a travel‑friendly second screen that can do double duty for productivity work and gaming rigs. Make sure you don’t miss this opportunity.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4202/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-is-going-nuts-this-15-gaming-portable-monitor-for-xbox-and-switch-is-selling-for-pennies-2000627251]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Console Prices Will Increase Again Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/19/xbox-console-prices-will-increase-again-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-console-prices-will-increase-again-next-month.1303062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Microsoft has <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates">announced plans</a> to increase the prices of its Xbox consoles in the United States for the second time this year, starting on October 5. The company cites “changes in the macroeconomic environment” as the reason for the price adjustments.&nbsp;</p><p>In a time when consoles are becoming more expensive over time rather than cheaper, the five available models of Xbox Series X/S will have their prices raised yet again. Microsoft already increased these prices <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/01/xbox-console-and-accessory-price-increases-begin-today-80-first-party-games-starting">only a few months ago</a>, on May 1.</p><p>Here are the new prices for each Xbox console. For comparison, we've also included the current price (as of May 1) and the original launch price of each piece of hardware.</p><p><u>Xbox Series S 512 GB&nbsp;</u><br><strong>New Price: $399.99</strong><br>Current Price: $379.99&nbsp;<br>Launch Price: $299.99</p><p><u>Xbox Series S 1TB&nbsp;</u><br><strong>New Price: $449.99</strong><br>Current Price: $429.99<br>Launch Price: 349.99</p><p><u>Xbox Series X Digital&nbsp;</u><br><strong>New Price: $599.99</strong><br>Current Price: $549.99<br>Launch Prince: $449.99</p><p><u>Xbox Series X</u><br><strong>New Price: $649.99</strong><br>Current Price: $599.99<br>Launch Price: $499.99</p><p><u>Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black Special Edition</u><br><strong>New Price: $799.99</strong><br>Current Price: $729.99<br>Launch Price: $599.99</p><p>"We understand that these changes are challenging, and they were made with careful consideration," reads Microsoft's statement. "Looking ahead, we continue to focus on offering more ways to play more games across any screen and providing value for Xbox players."</p><p>This second price hike comes in a year full of them. Sony <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/14/sony-raises-playstation-5-price-in-europe-australia-new-zealand-and-more">raised the prices</a> of the PlayStation 5 in the UK, Europe, and other territories in April, similarly citing the current economic conditions caused by the US tariffs. Sony then raised the price of the PS5 in the US <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/08/20/playstation-5-price-changes-in-the-u-s/">last month</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Nintendo, perhaps most famously, delayed pre-orders for the Switch 2 in the US due to the economic conditions before <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/18/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-begin-april-24-in-us-with-updated-pricing-for-certain">raising prices on the console's accessories</a> before launch.&nbsp;Last month, Nintendo <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-switch-pricing-update/?srsltid=AfmBOorllYqkrE8JsNVKW_xi1_3j_JLXXMlNa_BTAxerqdNWRmSI54cq">increased the prices of the original Switch models</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The updated Xbox prices come right before the busy holiday season, which will be more challenging than ever for those looking to purchase game consoles as gifts or for themselves. It's an unfortunate circumstance that, as things currently stand, doesn't appear will be going away in the foreseeable future.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/19/xbox-console-prices-will-increase-again-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Know What’s Going On And So Does Everyone Else]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jimmy-kimmel-fallon-colbert-stewart-trump-kirk-2000627249</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-know-what%E2%80%99s-going-on-and-so-does-everyone-else.1303035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Last night on <em>The Tonight Show</em>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-latest-chapter-in-jimmy-fallons-ongoing-love-affair-1789194585"><em>Mario Kart</em> superfan</a> Jimmy Fallon did what Jimmy Fallon does best: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Gma4TPZCXg">chuckle at his own jokes, make funny faces, and shrug his shoulders</a>. While he didn’t shy away from dunking on Donald Trump’s trip to the UK, he did pull his punches when talking about late night TV’s other Jimmy getting bullied off the air by a rogue president, his FCC goon squad, and a complicit c-suite. “To be honest with you all, I don’t know what’s going on, and no one does,” Fallon told viewers. That last part, at least, is an obvious lie. Why Jimmy Kimmel was kicked off the air by ABC is not complicated or confusing. Part of what’s so galling about it is just how stupid, craven, and obvious what happened is, and how none of that stopped it from happening.</p> <p>Jimmy Kimmel was kicked off the air for making fun of Trump. Not because he joked about Charlie Kirk’s assassination, which he didn’t do, or because he lied about it, which he didn’t do either. Comments about the “MAGA gang” trying to score political points off Kirk’s murder were just the setup to a punchline about how Trump <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/what-jimmy-kimmel-said-late-night-show-charlie-kirk-2025-9">can’t even muster a crocodile tear</a> over the right-wing podcaster’s death before gushing about his White House renovations. You can watch the tape. You can read the transcript. There is no ambiguity in what transpired, even as pundits paid to make hay of the controversy try to hedge by condemning something Kimmel didn’t say while advocating for a First Amendment that wasn’t directly violated.</p> <p>That’s because ABC, and it’s corporate owner Disney, rushed to comply before it even got to that point. One of the biggest TV operators in the country, Nexstar Media Group, is trying to buy another operator called Tegna in a deal valued at over $6 billion and that would require the approval of Trump’s Justice Department. Along with conservative network affiliate owner Sinclair, Nexstar announced it would stop carrying <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live! </em>(Nexstar <a href="https://t.co/ghiH7Zo0GP">denies</a> this was the reason.) FCC Chairman Brendan Carr threatened to investigate ABC and pull its broadcast licenses over Kimmel’s monologue. And then Disney Entertainment Co-Chairman Dana Walden and CEO Bob Iger <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/09/jimmy-kimmel-decision-disney-dana-walden-bob-iger-1236547651/">decided to preemptively pull the plug</a>, provoking a <a href="https://kotaku.com/jimmy-kimmel-abc-disney-boycott-marvel-marisa-tomei-2000627135">celebrity-led boycott in the process</a>.</p>

 <p>Trump has been desperately trying to get Kimmel fired for months. Shortly after Paramount sacrificed Stephen Colbert to get its merger approved with Skydance, the president made this as clear as possible. “Jimmy Kimmel is NEXT to go in the untalented Late Night Sweepstakes and, shortly thereafter, Fallon will be gone,” he posted in July. Anyone who keeps acting surprised by what’s going on, like Fallon, just hasn’t been paying attention or, worse, thinks that they can save themselves by trying to pretend none of it is happening. Even ex-Disney CEO Michael Eisner is going, in so many words, “<a href="https://x.com/Michael_Eisner/status/1969088566098870363">Wait, what the fuck is happening</a>?”</p> <p>Maybe that’s why it felt strangely nostalgic and refreshing to watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_GXNJ3V9lzg">Jon Stewart</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdGLJly6P7c">Stephen Colbert</a> last night, each tackling Kimmel’s firing in their own ways but in no uncertain terms. Like a lot of people, I watched <em>The Daily Show</em> and <em>The Colbert Report</em> a lot in college. Then I stopped. At some point the formula began to feel not only cringe but aimless. The news was getting grimmer and the stakes less funny. But last night reminded me what worked about them all those years ago. It’s cathartic to watch people call out obvious bullshit, especially when so many others keep running away from it, anxiously looking to their colleagues and bosses to make sure they don’t step out of line, even when the line is drawn by a dangerous buffoon. That’s how the Bush years felt. Nothing’s changed and yet now somehow it’s even worse.</p> <p>“I do know Jimmy Kimmel, and he’s a decent, funny, and loving guy, and I hope he comes back,” Fallon said last night. It is, of course, not up to Kimmel if he comes back. Fallon knows that. He also knows he could be next. And that cynical calculus is what will make sure he’s not the last.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/jimmy-kimmel-fallon-colbert-stewart-trump-kirk-2000627249]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft raises Xbox console prices for the second time this year]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/microsoft-raises-xbox-console-prices-for-the-second-time-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-raises-xbox-console-prices-for-the-second-time-this-year.1303032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<h2>Here we go again</h2>
<p>Higher than usual inflation can help explain some of the nominal price increases for the oldest Xbox consoles affected by today's price hikes. The $300 for an Xbox Series S at launch in November 2020 is worth roughly $375 in August 2025 dollars, for instance. And the $500 for an Xbox Series X in 2020 is now worth about $625.</p>
<p>But the particularly sharp price increases for more recent Xbox configurations can't really use that inflation excuse. The disc-drive-free Digital Xbox Series X Digital and 2TB "Galaxy Special Edition" are now a whopping 33 percent more expensive than they were at launch in October 2024. A year's worth of inflation would account for only a small fraction of that.</p>
<p>Even accounting for inflation, though, the current spate of nominal console price increases goes against <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/06/are-the-ps4-and-xbox-one-really-that-expensive-historically/">a near-universal, decades-long trend of game console prices dropping significantly</a> in the years following their launch. Those days <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/08/todays-game-consoles-are-historically-overpriced/">seem well and truly gone now</a>, as console makers' costs remain high thanks in part to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/thanks-to-new-tariffs-many-more-physical-game-discs-may-simply-not-get-made/">current tariff uncertainty</a> and in part to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/chips-arent-improving-like-they-used-to-and-its-killing-game-console-price-cuts/">the wider slowdown of Moore's Law</a>.</p>
<p>We'll see just how much the market can bear aging console hardware that increases in price over time rather than decreases. But until and unless consumers start balking, it looks like ever-increasing console prices are here to stay.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/microsoft-raises-xbox-console-prices-for-the-second-time-this-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two USB-C Ports, Two USB-A Ports and an HDMI: This 7-in-1 Adapter Is Going for Pennies on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/two-usb-c-ports-two-usb-a-ports-and-an-hdmi-this-7-in-1-adapter-is-going-for-pennies-on-amazon-2000627226</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-usb-c-ports-two-usb-a-ports-and-an-hdmi-this-7-in-1-adapter-is-going-for-pennies-on-amazon.1303017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Manufacturers of laptops have been working on making thinner and lighter laptops for years, and the byproduct of that is necessarily diminishing the amount of ports. You no longer need to deal with a string of ports for HDMI, SD cards, etc. That’s why carrying a USB‑C hub is now essentially a requirement, especially if you own a MacBook or a thin Windows laptop. This Acer <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4201/">7‑in‑1 USB‑C hub is the gap filler and now it costs a record low of $17 (down from $24) on Amazon</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4201/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A Little Hub That Widens Your Laptop’s World</h2>
<p>What this hub basically does is give your laptop the versatility that’s been taken away from it by manufacturers: Plug it into one USB‑C port and <strong>you’ve got seven handy connections at your fingertips</strong>. There are <strong>two fast USB‑A 3.1 ports</strong> for keyboard and external drives and <strong>two</strong> <strong>further USB‑C data ports</strong> capable of transfer speeds of up to 5Gbps. There’s even a <strong>full-size HDMI output</strong> to feed 4K video at 30Hz or Full HD at 1080p which makes it easy to plug in to monitors, projectors, or even your TV.</p>



<p>Through its Power Delivery port, this<strong> Acer hub can pass through up to 100W of power</strong> which is enough to keep a MacBook Pro charged while you’re running everything else at once. That means no worrying about draining your laptop mid‑presentation or mid‑flight. If you’ve ever been stuck unplugging accessories just to keep your laptop alive, this hub solves that daily frustration.</p>
<p>For photographers, content creators, or anyone who still uses SD cards in cameras and drones,<strong> the MicroSD and SD ports are a lifesaver</strong>. You do not need to carry extra adapters to transfer files directly into your laptop. The hub itself is housed in a rugged aluminum casing which protects it from damage and keeps it cool when used extensively.</p>
<p>It works with MacBooks, Windows laptops, ChromeOS, Linux, and even gaming systems like the Nintendo Switch or Steam Deck. If your tablet supports Samsung’s DeX mode, it turns your portable device into a desktop‑style setup with a display and peripherals connected through this hub. In practice, that means one tiny accessory can unlock a huge boost in productivity whether you’re working from home, commuting, or even gaming on the go.</p>
<p>And for just $17, this Acer 7‑in‑1 hub is like one of those rare upgrades that are worth it the moment you connect it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4201/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/two-usb-c-ports-two-usb-a-ports-and-an-hdmi-this-7-in-1-adapter-is-going-for-pennies-on-amazon-2000627226]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Just Made 65,000 GTA Fans Panic For No Reason]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/rockstar-made-65000-discord-gta-6-fans-panic-random-ping-here-gtaonline-2000627257</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-just-made-65-000-gta-fans-panic-for-no-reason.1303014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>In the span of about 20 seconds and with just a single Discord ping, Rockstar Games got 65,000+ people, nearly all of whom are waiting for<em> Grand Theft Auto 6</em>‘s launch, very excited and then crushed their hopes, dreams, and happiness.</p> <p>On September 19, at precisely 3:20 p.m. EST, Rockstar Games posted a single message in the <em>GTA Online</em> section of the <a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-rockstar-game-official-discord-server-launched-1851762536">company’s official Discord server</a>. The message was simply Rockstar Games acknowledging a bug involving a <em>GTA Online</em> weekly challenge that was supposed to unlock a piece of in-game clothing for those who completed it, but wasn’t working properly. Pretty basic <em>GTA Online</em> update. But for some reason, <a href="https://discord.com/channels/618327687701725194/1299025718440759357/1418678232735158292">Rockstar Games followed that message up with an “@here.”</a> They did this in a server with 68,097 members. Uh oh!</p> <figure id="attachment_2000627266" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000627266"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000627266">©Kotaku / Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure> <p>For those who don’t use Discord, dropping “@here” pings everyone in the server channel unless they specifically opt out of notifications. And most people don’t do that, especially not in Rockstar’s Discord server, where desperate fans cling to the hope that at any time, the studio could drop a new trailer for <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/grand-theft-auto-6-gta-vi-new-trailer-gameplay-story-1851779368">GTA 6.</a>&nbsp;</em> Rockstar Games has also not really done this before. So that random “@here” instantly caused around 68,000 fans to freak the fuck out. Making matters worse is that for many, myself included, the notification simply appeared as “Rockstar Games – @here” with no further context.</p> <p>I’ll fully admit that when I first saw it, I assumed the company was making some big random announcement about<em> GTA 6</em>. Instead, what I found when I opened Discord was a lot of confused, sad, and angry fans who weren’t sure why Rockstar had done this to them all. “Why!” “Whattt?” “Shut up!” “WTF?!” “No GTA 6??” “Stop it!” and “HOLY SHIT WHY” were just some of the hundreds and hundreds of messages that whizzed by my eyes when I opened Discord shortly after the ping.</p> <p>I’ve reached out to Rockstar Games about the Discord ping and why it decided to do this. But whatever the reason, it won’t change the fact that for a brief and chaotic moment, 65,000+ people went wild thinking they were about to watch a new<em> GTA 6</em> trailer or get news of another delay. Nope. There’s no new trailer or other big announcement, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/gta6-grand-theft-auto-6-release-date-delay-may-2026-1851778799"><em>GTA 6</em> is still set to launch in May of next year</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/rockstar-made-65000-discord-gta-6-fans-panic-random-ping-here-gtaonline-2000627257]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Series price increase announced for U.S.]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/xbox-series-price-increase-announced-for-us</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-series-price-increase-announced-for-u-s.1303011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Another price hike.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Microsoft will increase the price of <a title="Platforms > Xbox [26,696 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Series consoles in the United States once again on October 3, following a global price increase that occurred <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/xbox-series-global-price-increase-announced-for-consoles-controllers-and-games">back in May</a>. It cites “changes in the macroeconomic environment” as its reason for the increase. <span id="more-994118"></span></p><p>Xbox Series S consoles have increased by $20, while <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,936 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X</a> and Xbox Series X Digital have increased by $50, and the Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black by $70. Coupled with the May increase, Xbox Series consoles have increased in price up to $200.</p><p>Here are the new prices:</p><table><thead><tr><!-- AD: content -->
        <th>Products</th><th>Old Price</th><th>New Price</th><th>Increase</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Xbox Series S 512GB</td><td>$379.99</td><td>$399.99</td><td>$20</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series S 1TB</td><td>$429.99</td><td>$449.99</td><td>$20</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X Digital</td><td>$549.99</td><td>$599.99</td><td>$50</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X</td><td>$599.99</td><td>$649.99</td><td>$50</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black</td><td>$729.99</td><td>$799.99</td><td>$70</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Thanks, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/782079/microsoft-xbox-console-price-increase-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Verge</a>.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/xbox-series-price-increase-announced-for-us]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Series X price rises to $650 due to 'macroeconomic conditions']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/xbox-series-x-to-cost-650-after-microsoft-raises-prices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-series-x-price-rises-to-650-due-to-macroeconomic-conditions.1303008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image by stockcrafter via Adobe Stock.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates">has announced</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> it is raising the price of the Xbox Series X and Series S consoles just in time for the 2025 holiday season.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Starting on October 3, 2025, the price of Microsoft's flagship consoles will rise between 5 and 8 percent depending on the model. The cheapest Xbox, a 512gb Xbox Series S, will cost $400 (up about 5 percent from $380) and a standard Xbox Series X will cost $650 (up about 8 percent from $600).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This is the second time Microsoft has increased the price of its Xbox consoles in 2025 in the United States. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/xbox-is-increasing-hardware-prices-and-bumping-first-party-titles-to-80">In May</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it announced a major price hike that saw the Series S jump from $300 to $380, and the series X jump from $500 to $600.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On both occasions, the company blamed the price increase on "macroeconomic conditions." The price hikes coincided with major developments in the Trump Administration's planned tariffs on countries like China, where Microsoft manufactures its Xbox lineup.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There are no increases to Xbox accessories like controllers or headsets at this time. In its announcement, the company said that it "continue[s] to focus on offering more ways to play more games across any screen and providing value for Xbox players." This announcement comes months after Xbox president Sarah Bond </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/is-microsoft-signaling-a-multi-device-approach-for-next-gen-consoles-">proclaimed</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that the next generation of Xbox "experiences" wouldn't be "locked to a single store or tied to one device."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/game-professionals-form-new-coalition-to-combat-the-underrepresentation-and-dehumanization-of-palestinians-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Game professionals form coalition to 'push against the dehumanization of Palestinians'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;It also comes a month before Xbox and Asus roll out </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-first-xbox-handhelds-have-finally-arrived">the Xbox ROG Ally</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Its price has not been announced.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/xbox-series-x-to-cost-650-after-microsoft-raises-prices]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Shares Close-Ups Of Stunning Chrono Trigger Character Artwork]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/square-enix-shares-close-ups-of-stunning-chrono-trigger-character-artwork</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-shares-close-ups-of-stunning-chrono-trigger-character-artwork.1302981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Just breathtaking</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>It looks like Square Enix is still celebrating <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/chrono_trigger">Chrono Trigger</a>'s 30th anniversary — and why shouldn't it? This is one of the most-beloved RPGs of all time.</p>
<p>And today, as a tasty little treat, the company's Japanese YouTube channel has shared a video showcasing close-ups of some of the game's character art and promotional artwork. (thanks to modder and video producer <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ohpoorpup.bsky.social/post/3lz7edbj5mc2f">Christa Lee for highlighting</a>!)</p>
<p>The video appears to be a behind-the-scenes look at Square Enix's reproductions of the late, great Akira Toriyama's artwork. Individual characters, the campfire scene, and the battle scene that graces the game's North American box art are among the works shown off.</p>
<p>As for the reason? Well, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/novacrystallis.com/post/3lz5zz4bwxc2s">according to Nova Crystallis</a>, this is all for a social media campaign that Square Enix is holding. If you follow the company's <a href="https://x.com/squareenix_jp/status/1968885383627948195">Japanese account on X</a> (formerly Twitter) and respond with your favourite character along with the appropriate hashtag, you'll be in with a chance of winning a piece of art.</p>

<p>It looks like the competition itself is exclusive to Japan, but honestly, the video itself is also a great way of seeing these pieces of iconic art in 2160p, 4K resolution.</p>
<p>The colour and the linework is absolutely beautiful, and we're honestly jonesing to get a piece of that art for our offices...</p>

<p>Earlier today, Square Enix also announced the 'CHRONO TRIGGER Piano Soundscape Arrangement' album, which launches in Japan on 26th November 2025 for 3,300 yen (plus tax). With 12 newly-arranged songs, largely focusing on character themes, this is a must for fans of the iconic score, we think.</p>
<p>Let's hope even more Chrono Trigger celebrations are on the way.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you scrambling for some Chrono Trigger art now? What about an artbook? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/snes/related-articles:177779,179840 @ 1758322999 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gDI_9nAywzA" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gDI_9nAywzA">youtube.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/ohpoorpup.bsky.social/post/3lz7edbj5mc2f" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/ohpoorpup.bsky.social/post/3lz7edbj5mc2f">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/snes/related-info/27eb34afa0f9a6e145926748041ba916 @ 1758322999 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/square-enix-shares-close-ups-of-stunning-chrono-trigger-character-artwork]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Series X/S Consoles Will Go Up In Price Again in the US in Two Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-x-s-prices-will-reportedly-go-up-again-in-us-microsoft/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-series-x-s-consoles-will-go-up-in-price-again-in-the-us-in-two-weeks.1302978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Earlier this year, Microsoft <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-xs-price-increase-europe/">confirmed</a> that the price of the Xbox Series X/S consoles would be increasing globally, though the steepest increases would be hitting the US. Today, Microsoft <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates">announced</a> that, for the second time this year, the price of the Xbox Series X/S consoles will be increased again, with the new prices going into effect in two weeks time on October 3, 2025.</p>



<p>Microsoft didn't specify exactly why prices are going up, instead citing "<em>changes in the macroeconomic environment</em>." It added that understood "<em>that these changes are challenging,</em>" and reassures that they "<em>were made with careful consideration</em>." The price of accessories like controllers and headsets is staying the same for now, and the price of the console in countries outside of the US will also remain the same for now.</p>



<p>To recap, when the price of the consoles and accessories went up in may, the price of the Xbox Series S console went up $80, for both the 512GB and 1TB variants. The price of the Xbox Series X console went up $100, and the price of the 2TB special edition Xbox Series X went up $130. </p>



<p>Thankfully, today's increases aren't as steep, but it's still baffling to hear they're going up at all. While Microsoft doesn't mention the word 'tariffs,' the fact that the increases are isolated to the US points to the current US administration's tariffs as a likely reason behind the two price hikes within the last five months.</p>



<p>Starting October 3, 2025, these are the prices of the Xbox Series line of consoles: </p>



<ul>
<li>Xbox Series X - $649.99 ($50 increase)</li>



<li>Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Special Edition - $799.99 ($70 increase)</li>



<li>Xbox Series S 512GB - $399.99 ($20 increase)</li>



<li>Xbox Series S 1TB - $449.99 ($20 increase)</li>
</ul>



<p>To be fair, Microsoft isn't the only hardware maker to raise the prices on its consoles. Sony raised the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ps5-ps5-pro-price-increases-us-tomorrow/">price of the PS5 by $50 in the US just last month</a>, and while Nintendo has so far only raised the price of its <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-us-hardware-pricing-stays-the-same-accessories-bump/">Switch 2 accessories</a>, the threat of a console price hike<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-increase-us/"> still looms</a>.</p>



<p>One thing is for sure, though. These price increases won't help Microsoft move more units than they were before. Even if the <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-s-x-sold-less-30-million-units-profitable/">console is reportedly profitable</a>, it's difficult to imagine that the added revenue from these price hikes will have a meaningful impact due to how few units are actually being sold week-to-week.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-x-s-prices-will-reportedly-go-up-again-in-us-microsoft/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This 140W Laptop Power Bank Is a Dream Buy Now That Amazon Has It Back at Black Friday Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-140w-laptop-power-bank-is-a-dream-buy-now-that-amazon-has-it-back-at-black-friday-price-2000627209</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-140w-laptop-power-bank-is-a-dream-buy-now-that-amazon-has-it-back-at-black-friday-price.1302972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There are thousands of power banks on Amazon, but most of them fall between 5W and 60W. That is fine if all you do is charge a phone but when it comes to laptops and bigger devices, they are not much use. The <strong>Anker 737 power bank is in a league of its own</strong> and it is able to charge nearly everything you own – the new iPhone or a MacBook. And right now, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4200/">Amazon has cut it down to $87 (from $109), an all-time low price under the $100 threshold</a>, which is why that it is currently the best-selling product in its category.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4200/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The Power Bank That Charges Everything</h2>
<p>At the core of the Anker 737 lies its huge capacity and speed: Carrying a <strong>gargantuan 24,000mAh battery</strong>, it has the juice to charge an iPhone 17 Pro from zero all the way up more than four times. Need to charge an iPad Pro or a MacBook? It can do that too, more than once over so you will not be scrambling to find an outlet on road trips. The difference from an average power bank is noticeable day one, because with them you usually need to ration juice.</p>



<p>And there’s the speed: The 737 model <strong>supports 140W fast charging via Power Delivery 3.1</strong>, something that’s usually reserved for laptop-only charger like devices. This lets you go from nearly dead, empty MacBook to usable in a hurry even when you’ve got other devices along for the ride. To get that kind of speed, you’ll need a 5A USB-C cable and a hefty 140W wall adapter to get the job done. But once you’ve got that, the experience is silky.</p>
<p>Another clever thing is the clever display on the device: Instead of guessing how much battery you have remaining or when you’ll be ready to go again, the digital readout on the screen shows real-time figures like power in and out and an estimate of time remaining to charge. For those who are lugging a number of devices, that sort of openness spares heartache and allows you to plan more effectively.</p>
<p>Yes, portability matters, and despite all its muscle, the Anker 737 still fits into a bag. It’s about 6 inches long and 22 ounces, so it’s easily portable on a vacation and, most importantly, does fit under TSA guidelines for carry-on luggage. That means you can bring it on a plane without any problem, which isn’t the case with most large power banks.</p>



<p><strong>Three charging ports (two USB-C and one USB-A)</strong> mean that you can charge a few devices at once so you charge a laptop, phone, and earbuds at the same time instead of switching between them. That sort of freedom when you’re fully powered is what sets the Anker 737 power bank apart from the sea of tiny batteries that only get to keep one or two devices charged gradually. Add on top of that Anker’s excellent two-year warranty and many-year record of customer service, and there’s reassurance in the box.</p>
<p>Power banks are everywhere, but power banks like this one are not. If your definition of peace of mind is never running out of juice on your most important devices, now is the time to buy one.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4200/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-140w-laptop-power-bank-is-a-dream-buy-now-that-amazon-has-it-back-at-black-friday-price-2000627209]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton U-Turns In Its Lawsuit Against Unknown Worlds Founders On One Of Its Key Arguments Regarding Subnautica 2]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-unknown-worlds-founders-lawsuit-krafton-u-turn/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-u-turns-in-its-lawsuit-against-unknown-worlds-founders-on-one-of-its-key-arguments-regarding-subnautica-2.1302963/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Back in <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-launches-next-year-in-early-access-on-pc-and-xbox-will-also-be-on-game-pass/">October 2024</a>, Krafton and Unknown Worlds announced that Subnautica 2 would be launching in Early Access sometime in 2025. But as we passed the halfway mark of the year, a flurry of unexpected events happened.</p>



<p>It's been some time since we've heard an update regarding this suit, and in between the last update and today, <a href="https://wccftech.com/topic/gamescom/">Gamescom 2025</a> happened, <a href="https://wccftech.com/hollow-knight-silksong-5-million-audience-overlaps-soulslike/">Silksong was released</a>, and SEGA brought back its <a href="https://wccftech.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-calls-out-mario-kart-in-new-trailer-ahead-of-launch/">80s/90s-era tongue-in-cheek ad campaign</a> against Nintendo around its latest <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sonic-racing-crossworlds/">Sonic Racing game</a>, to name a few things. So you'd be forgiven if you need a refresher. There's a recap at the bottom of this article if you need it, but for now, let's jump into what's current.</p>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/founders-of-subnautica-2-studio-unknown-worlds-accuse-parent-company-krafton-of-changing-story-mid-litigation">GamesIndustry.Biz</a>, two of Krafton's requests have been denied by the court: a forensic inspection request and a compelling preservation order, with both being deemed "<em>unnecessary</em>." But more importantly, the denial comes largely due to Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire claiming that Krafton has suddenly changed one of its key arguments.</p>



<p>When Krafton fired the three co-founders, one of the reasons cited in the termination notices was the claim that Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire were trying to release Subnautica 2 before it was ready. That makes sense, since Krafton has claimed time and again that the game simply wasn't ready for its early access launch.</p>



<p>Now, Krafton has changed its argument and has "<em>pivoted to a new theory that it admittedly came up with only after the fact: that it terminated the Founders and seized control because the Founders backed up files they were entitled to access in their work for Unknown Worlds</em>," says Fortis Advisors, the group representing the co-founders.</p>



<p>"<em>Krafton's disorganized retreat raises more questions than answers. To say Krafton's new theory is a Hail Mary would be an understatement - both because the downloads were not wrongful and because Krafton claims not to have learned of them until after it had fired the Founders. The downloads cannot have been the actual motivation for termination</em>."</p>



<p>So, suddenly, it seems that according to Krafton, in this lawsuit, which was filed against them around Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire, alleging, among other things, that they were wrongfully terminated, and where Krafton initially claimed they were terminated because they tried to launch Subnautica 2 before it was ready, the subject of Subnautica 2 being ready or not for launch is not relevant. </p>



<p>Adding to that, the question of Subnautica 2's readiness for launch wasn't why Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire were fired. They were fired because of something Krafton learned about after they had already fired them.</p>



<p>Per a report from <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/survival-crafting/the-subnautica-2-lawsuit-is-getting-even-messier-with-krafton-doing-a-massive-u-turn-confusing-both-the-ousted-founders-lawyer-and-the-judge-this-is-a-little-bit-bewildering/">PC Gamer</a>, Krafton is now trying to focus on its claim that the co-founders abandoned their roles, and even the judge presiding over this case is confused by Krafton removing its argument that the co-founders tried to release the game early. "<em>Well, that's something that we definitely need to get to the bottom of today, because that is precisely what was cited as the reason in the answer</em>," said Judge Lori W. Will during a meeting between both sides to deliver a ruling on the motions presented.</p>



<p>PC Gamer also reports that Krafton hasn't been entirely cooperative as this suit kicks up, previously refusing to confer with Fortis Advisors, and only offering what Judge Lori W. Will described as a "<em>very narrow</em>" selection of emails for evidence, only offering ones where the words 'termination' and 'earnout' appeared.</p>



<p>The case is moving forward with both parties agreeing to confer, and we're back to waiting for the next major update.</p>



<p>To say that this has been a messy situation is yet another understatement to tack on to Krafton's alleged 'Hail Mary.' As I've mentioned before, it's unlikely we'll learn the whole truth of the situation, as allegations on both sides seem dire even if there's a bit of truth to them.</p>



<p>We'll continue to provide updates when new information is available. If you need a recap of what's happened before this, you can view it below.</p>



<ul>
<li>On July 2, it was reported that the founders of Unknown Worlds, Ted Gill, Max McGuire, and Charlie Cleveland, <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-developer-unknown-worlds-changes-leadership-krafton/">were fired</a> and replaced by former Striking Distance Studios head Steve Papoutsis. No concrete explanation for their dismissal was offered at the time, with Krafton instead emphasizing its commitment to delivering a game that players deserved.</li>



<li>On July 3, a <a href="https://unknownworlds.com/en/news/subnautica-community-letter">statement from the Unknown Worlds website</a> did its best to calm concerns from fans about the fact that the three original core creatives behind Subnautica were suddenly not at the studio.</li>



<li>The next day, on July 4, the situation began to grow even more confusing, as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lryw9o/what_is_a_wave_but_a_thousand_drops/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">Cleveland claims</a> Subnautica 2 was "<em>ready for early access release</em>" and that his and his fellow co-founders' dismissals were "<em>quite a shock</em>."</li>



<li>Five days later, on July 9, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-delayed-subnautica-2-2026-reportedly-to-avoid-250-million-bonus-pay/">report from Bloomberg</a> adds a shocking allegation to the mix: that Krafton was delaying Subnautica 2 to avoid paying Unknown Worlds a $250 million bonus the studio would have been owed if they hit particular sales goals, which they would have done with Subnautica 2's launch. The delay was <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-delay-confirmed-krafton-claims-delay-decision-was-not-influenced-by-any-contractual-or-financial-considerations/">confirmed</a> hours after the report went live, and Krafton held that the delay was due to Subnautica 2 not being ready, citing feedback from internal playtesting.</li>



<li>On July 10, Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-blames-founders-subnautica-2-delay/">went on the offensive</a>, blaming co-founders Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire, claiming they had "<em>abandoned</em>" their roles to pursue personal interests. Krafton also clarified that 90% of the aforementioned $250 million bonus would go directly to the co-founders, with the rest to be split among the employees. Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire held that they always intended to distribute the bonus to other employees.</li>



<li>Also on July 10, Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/889109175/Fortis-Advisors-v-Krafton-via-Aftermath">filed a lawsuit</a> against Krafton. </li>



<li>On July 11, an<a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-leaked-document-shows-krafton-delay/"> internal document from a milestone review of Subnautica 2's progress leaked</a> on Reddit, seemingly showing further support to Krafton's claims that the game wasn't ready, citing a lack of content on top of previously mentioned internal playtest feedback.</li>



<li>Over the following weekend on July 13, Krafton <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-confirms-subnautica-2-leaked-documents-are-real/">confirmed the documents to be real</a>. </li>



<li>A few days later, on July 17, when the co-founders' suit against Krafton became publicly available, we discovered allegations that Krafton had <a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-allegedly-sabotaged-subnautica-2-to-delay-avoid-paying-250-million-bonus/">been sabotaging</a> Subnautica 2 to ensure it would be delayed. There was even a claim that the CEO of Krafton met with the co-founders and admitted that having to pay out the $250 million bonus "<em>could be disastrous financially and hugely embarrassing for Krafton</em>." It also attacks every other claim Krafton had made up to this point, and that the feedback received on Subnautica 2 playtesting "<em>unequivocally proved</em>" the game was ready for an early access launch.</li>



<li>Jumping ahead to August 12, Krafton<a href="https://wccftech.com/krafton-fires-back-unknown-worlds-founders-lawsuit-subnautica-2/"> shoots back</a> at Gill, Cleveland, and McGuire's lawsuit, again arguing that the co-founders were absentee leaders who abandoned their roles, and continued to hold that the game wasn't ready for an early access launch.</li>



<li>Eight days later, Unknown Worlds <a href="https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-legal-battle-unknown-worlds-files-lawsuit-against-co-founders-krafton/">files its own separate lawsuit</a> against its co-founders, telling Wccftech in an email that this suit "<em>is a direct response to their misconduct, including the theft of confidential information and attempts to pursue personal financial gain to the detriment of the company's interest</em>s<em>."</em></li>
</ul>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/subnautica-2-unknown-worlds-founders-lawsuit-krafton-u-turn/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roborock Doesn’t Want You Struggling With Housework, It’s Selling Its Latest Model With No Margin]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roborock-doesnt-want-you-fighting-housework-anymore-its-selling-its-latest-model-with-no-margin-2000627205</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roborock-doesn%E2%80%99t-want-you-struggling-with-housework-it%E2%80%99s-selling-its-latest-model-with-no-margin.1302957/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Budget robot vacuum cleaners have three huge complaints. One, they’re never powerful enough so there’s always still some dust and some crumbs left behind. Two, they usually do mopping not so great so you’re left with streaks or worse still, no way to mop. And three, they need constant maintenance because you have to empty them almost every run. The <strong>Roborock Qrevo S5V</strong>, launched this summer, fixes all of that in one lean machine. Even better, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4199/">Amazon knocked it down to only $549 (from $899), its lowest price yet, which makes it a deal worth paying attention</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4199/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Solves Your Daily Hassles</h2>
<p>The new Roborock Qrevo S5V is all about sheer cleaning power: <strong>Its 12,000Pa HyperForce suction</strong> is several times stronger than many budget models which means it lifts stubborn dirt from rugs, carpets and hard floors. If you’ve struggled with pet hair tangling inside brushes, this model is certified to end that frustration. Roborock uses a floating rubber main brush designed to resist tangles, combined with an arc-shaped side brush that sweeps along edges while avoiding hair buildup.</p>



<p>Mopping is no afterthought here, either. Instead of a single plate scratching the floor, the<strong> FlexiArm design includes two turning mop pads</strong>. They turn around 200 times per minute to buff out stains, down into corners and chair legs. The arm goes so far that the pads can swing into spaces other robots cannot cover. In addition, the mop lifts automatically 10 millimeters when it drives over carpets so you never have soggy rugs. You can control water flow through 30 levels using the companion app to accommodate any floor surfaces, from delicate wood to hard tile.</p>
<p>Then there is the dock which is essentially having an assistant built-in: The device isn’t just dumping the dustbin into a large bin <strong>capable of holding seven weeks’ worth of garbage</strong>. The device also washes the mop pads with clean water and dries them with warm air so that they don’t smell. You won’t have to top it up as frequently either since the dock will charge the water tank in the robot automatically, giving it enough to clean a massive 3,500 square feet on one fill.</p>



<p>Navigation is accomplished by Roborock through LiDAR scanning: It <strong>maps rooms 360 degrees</strong> and then plans effective cleaning routes. If you have a multi-level house, it remembers up to four different floor plans and auto-switches as needed. Structured light sensors have obstacle avoidance, so it won’t chomp toy cars, run into cables, or get stuck under chair legs. In the app, you can even define no-go zones when you know a space is too messy.</p>
<p>For a record-low price of $549, the Qrevo S5V positions itself in a very desirable spot. Numerous competitors within the category either skip better mopping, compromise on suction, or lack a good self-maintenance dock. If you’ve been waiting for a vacuum and mop combo that truly reduces cleaning stress, this is the most convincing deal so far.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4199/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roborock-doesnt-want-you-fighting-housework-anymore-its-selling-its-latest-model-with-no-margin-2000627205]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Is Raising Xbox Prices In The US Again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-is-raising-xbox-prices-in-the-us-again/1100-6534892/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-raising-xbox-prices-in-the-us-again.1302954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534892">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you were planning on getting an Xbox console for the holidays, you might want to act sooner rather than later, because Microsoft has <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">just announced</a> that it's once again raising the price of its consoles starting October 3.</p><p>Beginning October 3, the most affordable Xbox on the market, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Xbox-512GB-SSD-Console-S/dp/B08G9J44ZN?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">512GB Xbox Series S</a>, will cost $400 in the US. The most expensive Xbox Series X model, which <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/d/xbox-series-x-2tb-galaxy-black-special-edition/8smbrt7wmfp9" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">comes with a disc drive and two terabytes of storage</a>, will run folks $800. Here are the rest of the price changes to the Xbox lineup:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Xbox-512GB-SSD-Console-S/dp/B08G9J44ZN?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series S 512GB</a> -- <strong>$400 </strong>(was $380)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-S-Console-White-1TB/dp/B0D934SHFG?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series S 1TB</a> -- <strong>$450 </strong>(was $430)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Xbox-Gaming-Console-video-game/dp/B0DCD9LGHY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series X Digital</a> -- <strong>$600 </strong>(was $550)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Xbox-Gaming-Console-video-game/dp/B08H75RTZ8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series X</a> -- <strong>$650 </strong>(was $500)</li><li><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/d/xbox-series-x-2tb-galaxy-black-special-edition/8smbrt7wmfp9" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black Special Edition</a> - <strong>$800 </strong>(was $730)</li></ul><p>This is the second price increase that Microsoft has issued this year alone after it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-consoles-games-and-accessories-see-price-increases-starting-today/1100-6531257/" data-ref-id="1100-6531257">raised prices</a> on the consoles earlier this May. In its announcement, Microsoft suggests that these price hikes are "due to changes in the macroeconomic environment." Prices outside of the US will remain as they are.</p><p>The increase in prices for consoles, as well as their games and accessories, has been an alarming trend over the last year and is believed to be connected to tariffs being imposed by the current US administration, though few of these companies have outright come forward and said as much.</p><p>Nevertheless, PlayStation <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-price-hikes-announced-for-the-us-every-system-going-up-by-50/1100-6534127/" data-ref-id="1100-6534127">similarly raised its prices</a> earlier this year, and the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/will-tariffs-increase-switch-2s-price-why-the-console-and-games-are-so-expensive/1100-6530591/" data-ref-id="1100-6530591">Switch 2 pre-orders were even briefly delayed</a> in the US while Nintendo weighed its options. When the console did finally become available, many of the prices for games and accessories were higher than audiences expected, and just last month, Nintendo even <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-increasing-price-of-switch-and-other-devices-in-the-us/1100-6533633/" data-ref-id="1100-6533633">raised the price of the original Switch</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-console-bundle-pokemon-mario-kart-deals-available-at-amazon/1100-6534885/">Nintendo Switch 2 Mario Kart Bundle In Stock At Amazon With Same-Day Delivery</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-deals-amiibo-figures-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-street-fighter-6/1100-6534260/">Save On All Four Zelda: Tears Of The Kingdom Switch 2 Amiibo At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-batman-movie-and-tv-series-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-deals/1100-6533035/">Batman Movie And TV Box Sets Are Cheaper Than Prime Day Prices At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyond-game-amiibo-preorder-buying-guide-nintendo-switch-2/1100-6530754/">Metroid Prime 4 And Samus Amiibo Preorders Available Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-games-amiibo-accessory-preorders-new-releases-2025-at-amazon/1100-6532451/">Nintendo Direct Switch 2 Preorders At Amazon - All New Games And Amiibo</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rosalinas-storybook-super-mario-galaxy-dark-horse-nintendo-book-amazon-preorder/1100-6534724/">Rosalina's Storybook From Super Mario Galaxy Is Up For Preorder At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-nintendo-switch-2-console-bundle-pokemon-legends-z-a-preorder/1100-6533331/">Nintendo Switch 2 Pokemon Console Bundle Is Finally Up For Preorder At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-joyful-dualsense-limited-edition-ps5-controller-2025-preorder-guide/1100-6534678/">Astro Bot Joyful DualSense Limited Edition Controller Preorders Are Live</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534800&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/you-can-play-little-nightmares-3-now-even-though-it-isnt-out-yet\/1100-6534800\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534759&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/valheim-is-finally-coming-to-playstation-in-2026\/1100-6534759\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534816&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/is-skate-coming-to-switch-2-what-the-devs-have-said\/1100-6534816\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534655&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-bundle-collects-two-of-the-best-spongebob-switch-games-for-35\/1100-6534655\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534871&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-resolution-and-frame-rate-targets-for-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-revealed\/1100-6534871\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534850&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/microsoft-flight-simulator-meets-the-world-of-pigeon-dating-in-this-new-game\/1100-6534850\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534406&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/upcoming-game-pass-titles\/1100-6534406\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534775&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/xbox-app-now-launches-games-from-steam-and-other-game-stores\/1100-6534775\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534732&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-to-have-largest-game-launch-in-history-rockstar-says\/1100-6534732\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534797&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-glitch-lets-you-cheat-gravity-by-clapping\/1100-6534797\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534736&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/xbox-controllers-are-getting-this-small-but-important-change-on-windows-11\/1100-6534736\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534730&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-didnt-win-a-single-primetime-emmy-this-year\/1100-6534730\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534861&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-2-doesnt-have-skate-but-will-get-this-rad-looking-skateboarding-game-this-year\/1100-6534861\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531332&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tomtoc-nintendo-switch-2-case-gets-limited-time-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6531332\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534729&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mega-man-star-force-legacy-collection-coming-in-2026\/1100-6534729\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534764&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hell-is-us-dev-is-a-little-salty-over-hollow-knight-silksongs-shadow-release\/1100-6534764\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534778&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-7-zombies-trailer-shows-iconic-characters-fighting-for-their-souls\/1100-6534778\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534825&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-has-a-special-bonus-for-game-pass-members\/1100-6534825\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534766&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/palworld-1-0-coming-in-2026-with-a-massive-amount-of-content-as-dev-teases-new-games\/1100-6534766\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534762&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-devs-love-the-sniper-memes-but-know-they-have-work-to-do\/1100-6534762\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-is-raising-xbox-prices-in-the-us-again/1100-6534892/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Unearthed Arcana Update Refines New Dungeons & Dragons Arcane Subclasses]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-unearthed-arcana-update-refines-new-dungeons-dragons-arcane-subclasses</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-unearthed-arcana-update-refines-new-dungeons-dragons-arcane-subclasses.1302939/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has released an Unearthed Arcana update for <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>. This updated batch of playtest material incorporates player feedback and design revisions to new <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/latest-dungeons-dragons-2024-unearthed-arcana-revisits-arcane-subclasses" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Arcane subclasses</a> for the world's most popular fantasy TTRPG.</p>



<p>In a recent post on <a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/posts/2061-designer-insights-from-unearthed-arcana-arcane" rel="nofollow">D&amp;D Beyond</a>, Wizards of the Coast released the new Unearthed Arcana update for the new D&amp;D arcane subclasses. The post was accompanied by design insight from the development team. The team cited player feedback from the initial playtest period when the first batch of Unearthed Arcana released in June.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dungeons-dragons-unearthed-arcana-update-transmuter-text.jpg?itok=HK2wVlz0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dungeons-dragons-unearthed-arcana-update-transmuter-text.jpg?itok=6pEKTZeY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As a result, the new Unearthed Arcana is packed with design notes explaining the changes to the six different character subclasses. Some of these changes include streamlining or redesigning certain class features, adding more versatility, or even bringing back features from the previous edition.</p>

<p>A good example is the Arcane Archer Fighter. The Curving Shot feature, which lets the Fighter redirect a ranged attack to another target, now uses the same piece of ammunition but lets the Fighter make a new attack roll. As for versatility, the subclass now has Magical Ammunition, which lets the Fighter cover an area in darkness, thick vines, or tactically unlock and unbar doors and gates with a magical AoE Knock.</p>

<p>The Tattooed Monk essentially got redesigned in the new Unearthed Arcana update. Much like the refined Warrior of the Elements subclass in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-5e-2024-player-handbook-review-mixed-messaging-around-strong" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">2024 Player Handbook</a>, the Tattooed Monk features aren't directly tied to spells. The Beast Tattoo feature provides some cantrip utility, and the Celestial Tattoo feature leans more into exploration bonuses. Finally new Monster Tattoos have been added like the Beholder.</p>

<p>Lastly, the the updated material revises the four new Wizard subclasses. The Conjurer can now grant temporary hit points to things summoned and, at later levels, can summon two creatures with a single cast. The Enchanter gets its Instintive Charm ability back as well as Alter Memories.</p>

<p>Necromancers now have more options on summoning and utilizing undead thralls. You can give them temporary hit points, bonus damage, and at later levels you can have them explode with necrotic energy. Lastly, Transmuter features have been streamlined. The Transmuter's Stone now grants Constitution bonuses in addition to any choices you make, and the Shapechanger feature from 5e returns.</p>

<p>The feedback survey for this new Unearthed Arcana will be going live on September 25.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-unearthed-arcana-update-refines-new-dungeons-dragons-arcane-subclasses]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft is raising prices on Xbox consoles in the US again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/782079/microsoft-xbox-console-price-increase-us</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-raising-prices-on-xbox-consoles-in-the-us-again.1302936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft is raising the prices of its Xbox Series S / X consoles in the US next month. The Xbox Series X will be priced at $649.99 in the US starting October 3rd, up from its existing $599.99 price. The Xbox Series S will move to $399.99, up from $379.99.</p><p><a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/hardware-network/console/may-2025-pricing-updates">Microsoft blames</a> the price hikes on “changes in the macroeconomic environment,” which is a lot of words to say: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/607947/donald-trump-tariffs-china-mexico-canada-explainer">tariffs</a>. Xbox console pricing outside the US will remain the same. Thankfully, pricing for controllers and headsets will remain in the same in the US.</p><p>The price rises mean Xbox Series S consoles will increase by $20, Xbox Series X consoles by $50, and the 2TB Galaxy Black Special Edition Xbox Series X is increasing by $70 all the way up to $799.99.</p><p>Here’s the full list of price increases in the US:</p><div><table><thead><tr></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>New US price (RRP)</td><td>Previous US price (RRP)</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series S (512GB)</td><td>$399.99</td><td>$379.99</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series S (1TB)</td><td>$449.99</td><td>$429.99</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X</td><td>$649.99</td><td>$599.99</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X Digital</td><td>$599.99</td><td>$549.99</td></tr><tr><td>Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black Special Edition</td><td>$799.99</td><td>$729.99</td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>Microsoft only just raised the prices of its Xbox products <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659430/microsoft-xbox-console-controller-game-price-increases-worldwide">worldwide in May</a>, with price hikes to the Xbox Series S / X consoles, controllers, and headsets. Those previous price increases already bumped the Xbox Series X up by $100, and the Xbox Series S by $80. Coupled with today’s announcement, that means the Xbox Series X has increased in price in the US by $150 and the Series S by $100 in just six months.</p><p>Microsoft’s Xbox Series X 2TB Galaxy Black Special Edition originally <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/21/24225188/microsoft-white-xbox-series-x-digital-2tb-special-edition-release-dates">debuted nearly a year ago</a> at $599.99, and it’s now about to be $799.99 — a $200 increase in just a year. Microsoft’s latest price increases are the second this year, following <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/21/23768400/microsoft-xbox-series-x-xbox-game-pass-price-increase">initial price hikes in 2023</a>.</p><p>Microsoft also planned to hike the price of some of its first-party Xbox games to $80 this holiday, but then <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/712371/the-outer-worlds-2-price-change-microsoft-xbox">walked back those changes in July</a>.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/782079/microsoft-xbox-console-price-increase-us#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/782079/microsoft-xbox-console-price-increase-us]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Sequel Experimenting With Multiplayer As CDPR Embraces Online Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2-online-multiplayer-witcher-4-sequel-cdpr-2000627198</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-experimenting-with-multiplayer-as-cdpr-embraces-online-gameplay.1302924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Asymmetric mercenary leaderboards? Co-op heists? A full-blown<em> GTA Online</em>-style live-service component? The multiplayer possibilities for <a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2-release-date-witcher-4-rpg-cdpr-1851782750">a <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> sequel</a> are easy to imagine, even if they’re hard to implement. A new job posting at CD Projekt Red suggests the studio is at least flirting with some sort of online component for its next sci-fi open-world RPG. It’s a small and noncommittal data point that’s nevertheless part of a larger trend.</p> <p>“Lead your team to develop and optimize multiplayer systems, including matchmaking, and address challenges related to latency, bandwidth usage, and server performance,” reads <a href="https://www.cdprojektred.com/en/jobs/20217-lead-network-engineer">part of the job description</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-looks-set-to-include-multiplayer-years-after-cyberpunk-2077-online-mode-scrapped">first spotted by <em>IGN,</em></a>&nbsp;for a new engineering role at CDPR’s Boston-based satellite studio leading development on <em>Cyberpunk 2</em>. That ambition gestures toward plans the studio originally had for adding multiplayer to the first game. Plans for that content were later set aside or abandoned as CDPR rushed to prioritize the stability and long-term viability of <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> after a disastrous 2020 launch.</p> <p>Will history repeat itself, or is multiplayer coming to the world of <em>Cyberpunk </em>for real this time? With the big-budget blockbuster still in pre-production as CDPR focuses on <em>The Witcher 4</em>, it’s impossible to say. But it’s clear the Poland-based company has been looking to experiment with multiplayer for some time now. CDPR told investors it was looking to bring “online gameplay” to more of its franchises in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IIAiGI-v6Y8">strategy briefing</a> four years ago, and co-CEO Michał Nowakowski <a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-orion-multiplayer-1851190429#:~:text=Kotaku%20reached%20out%20to%20CDPR%20for%20comment.&amp;text=Badowski%20and%20Nowakowski's%20comments%20on,works%20that%20we%20know%20of.">told<em> Reuters</em> last year</a> the team was “considering” bringing multiplayer to the next <em>Cyberpunk</em>.</p>

 <p>CDPR has also already confirmed at least one multiplayer project: a <em>Witcher</em> spin-off codenamed <em>Project</em> <em>Sirius</em>. That game has been in prolonged development at what used to be called The Molasses Flood, with layoffs, departures, and design pivots reportedly all taking their toll. The studio was officially absorbed into the rest of CDPR earlier this year. “Overall, it shows a very bright future for Project Sirius (aka ‘the multiplayer Witcher game,’ of which I was the Design Director for three years),” Molasses Flood co-founder Damian Isla wrote upon leaving <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/damian-isla-815a46_well-its-the-end-of-an-era-tucked-away-activity-7315404560620044288-Qazy/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAoO_OkB-VfPR7dhiZ-PZ-9sf_EfWliEy1k">back in March</a>. “It’s going to be an amazing game, one for the books, and I cannot wait until the rest of the world learns about what we’ve been working on.”</p> <p>One does not simply pivot to making an online multiplayer game any more than one simply walks into Mordor. CDPR’s own struggles with going from the third-person perspective of <em>Witcher 3</em> to the first-person<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em> speak to the tech and design difficulties inherent in taking on new development challenges. But it would be cool to see what CDPR can achieve if it takes that next leap. It ultimately worked out in the end for the studio’s last game, even if it took an extra three years after it came out.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2-online-multiplayer-witcher-4-sequel-cdpr-2000627198]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This iPhone Gimbal Costs Peanuts, Amazon Is Clearing Out DJI’s Budget Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-iphone-gimbal-costs-peanuts-amazon-is-clearing-out-djis-budget-model-2000627191</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-iphone-gimbal-costs-peanuts-amazon-is-clearing-out-dji%E2%80%99s-budget-model.1302918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Smartphones are incredible cameras in our pockets with the capability of capturing crisp snaps and 4K video, but there’s a further issue: <strong>shaky footage</strong>. If you’ve ever tried to film a birthday moment, a journey moment or a TikTok dance, then you’ll know how frustrating shaky video is. So, that’s why gimbals exist.</p>
<p>The DJI Osmo Mobile SE gets rid of that problem and you’re able to turn ordinary recordings into professional-quality videos that look as if they’re shot by pros. And since <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4198/">Amazon has dropped the price to just $58 (down from a previous low of $69)</a> — its lowest price ever — this is the perfect time to pick one up.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4198/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why This Gimbal Is Worth It</h2>
<p>The Osmo Mobile SE is <strong>DJI’s lowest-priced stabilizer</strong> but cheap doesn’t have to mean bare bones. In real life, it’s the category leader simply because it distills pro-level video stabilization into an accessible package. Its folding design means you can shove it neatly into a backpack but when you unfold it and clip your phone onto the magnetic clamp, you’re getting that liquid-smooth footage artists adore right away. It’s <strong>compatible with both iPhones and Androids</strong>, so compatibility issues are out of the question.</p>



<p>One of the real game changers in this regard is ActiveTrack 6.0: In essence, this <strong>permits the gimbal to automatically follow your subject</strong>. If you’re filming your children playing in the park or your dog running around on the beach, the Osmo Mobile SE holds them in frame without you scrambling for controls. It even works well for solo creators: just set the phone up, get in frame and let the gimbal take center stage in your own video. The DJI Mimo app also adds to those capabilities and offers Smart templates and shot ideas that help you get more cinematic with less effort.</p>
<p>Another intelligent aspect is that it allows pairing with an Apple Watch and gives you a remote in your wrist. Tilt, pan, or begin recording without needing to rush back to your phone. For vloggers, that is a real boost for how you record hands‑free. Throw in quick editing using the LightCut app which contains easy-to-use templates and your raw shots start looking like mini-movies to share in minutes.</p>



<p>And then the real magic: <strong>3-axis stabilization</strong>. DJI’s algorithm reacts in real time to eliminate jitters and bumps that ruin handheld video. Walking down urban streets, backpacking a path or merely shooting a travel blog at an airport, the video is stable and watchable. You can even switch between landscape shooting for cinematic use or portrait mode for social media updates with a single click of a button. And if you wish to get creative, the gimbal comes with<strong> various modes including Follow, Tilt Lock, FPV and Spin Shot</strong>&nbsp;which each unlock various artistic possibilities.</p>
<p>For a paltry $58, this deal is hard to hype. Most gimbals with this much stabilization and tracking tech run more, but DJI somehow crammed it all into a lightweight, tiny device for creators. Over 10,000 people bought it last month alone, and <strong>over 10,000 reviewers left it an average 4.5‑star rating</strong>. That should tell you everything you need to know about how dependable and adaptable it is.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4198/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-iphone-gimbal-costs-peanuts-amazon-is-clearing-out-djis-budget-model-2000627191]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4: Tech Experts Say 'Resetting the Game Every Hour Should Really Not Be an Expected Solution for Players,' Patch 'Cannot Come Soon Enough']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-tech-experts-say-resetting-the-game-every-hour-should-really-not-be-an-expected-solution-for-players-patch-cannot-come-soon-enough</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-tech-experts-say-resetting-the-game-every-hour-should-really-not-be-an-expected-solution-for-players-patch-cannot-come-soon-enough.1302912/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The tech experts at <a href="https://www.patreon.com/digitalfoundry" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry</a> have completed their analysis of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> on console, and confirmed a gradual worsening of framerate with continuous playtime, even on PlayStation 5 Pro and Xbox Series X.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As revealed in <a href="https://youtu.be/kRWW6qwjFBA?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new video published to YouTube</a>, Digital Foundry found performance starts dipping after around 30 minutes to an hour, which it called "too intrusive on the overall experience, too regular an interruption." Even after a completely fresh boot, the game is still prone to framerate drops.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox development chief Randy Pitchford has acknowledged the problem on social media, promising incoming improvements. As a workaround, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-performance-gets-worse-the-longer-you-play-on-console-randy-pitchford-suggests-quitting-the-game-and-restarting-as-a-workaround">Pitchford suggested console players quit Borderlands 4 and restart</a>. Digital Foundry’s Tom Morgan confirmed this does restore performance, but criticized the situation, saying “resetting the game every hour should really not be an expected solution for players.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Each console is prone to sizeable, sub-60fps lurches given enough time on the clock, and it's just a matter of how long you're willing to keep playing before deciding to reset," Morgan added.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Morgan also called for an emergency patch. Gearbox has promised more fixes are on the way, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-september-18-update-improves-stability-on-pc-and-smooths-out-progression-but-according-to-the-patch-notes-balance-changes-will-have-to-wait">after yesterday’s patch tackled PC crashes</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Borderlands 4 justifies the six-year wait since the last entry with some big technical upgrades via Unreal Engine 5,” Morgan said. “Despite the team's huge ambition here, though, the game's performance at launch is struggling on console if 60fps is the goal, and a patch cannot come soon enough. The gradually worsening framerates on PS5, Pro, and Series X lead to some dire mid-30fps passages of play after a while. And resetting the game every hour should really not be an expected solution for players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This lack in polish at launch also shows in its bugs where broken NPC pathfinding and flickering lighting are just a couple of issues I've experienced. The promise of Borderlands 4 is compelling, but following on from MGS Delta and Oblivion Remastered, we're once again looking at a major UE5 release with framerate issues on every format. And once again, we're having to hang tight for an update to save the day.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, what's causing the problem? As Morgan points out, the situation with Borderlands 4 rekindles memories of The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tech-experts-say-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastereds-camera-breaks-the-longer-you-play-and-eventually-crashes-when-loading-a-save-call-for-emergency-patch">another Unreal Engine 5 title where performance degraded over time on console and also improved with a fresh boot</a>. It's unconfirmed for now, but the leading theory for Borderlands 4, as with Oblivion, is there's some form of memory leak at play, or, as Morgan put it, "a cache of data not being flushed from system memory that eventually catches up on the player."</p><div id="borderlands-4-all-vault-hunter-skill-trees-ranked" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3><h3>Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">What about the PC version? Borderlands 4 is currently on a mixed Steam review rating, with most of the negative comments revolving around PC performance. Digital Foundry has said its <a href="https://youtu.be/2v1ST5qMoaY?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>initial analysis of Borderlands 4 on PC</u></a> shows significant stutter problems, and have advised against running the game on its ‘Badass’ graphics setting, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tech-experts-say-borderlands-4-on-pc-runs-worse-than-usual-for-an-unreal-engine-5-game-advise-against-badass-setting"><u>which suggests there are indeed problems with the Unreal Engine 5 title</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox has said addressing PC performance is a “top priority” for the studio. In the meantime, the studio pointed to a Borderlands 4 Nvidia Optimization guide on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1285190/view/679602429802577921" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam</u></a>, advising players how to optimize their graphics settings for “better performance and framerates” on PC with the Nvidia app, although users report mixed results.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox has also issued a piece of advice to PC gamers that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-dev-gearbox-asks-pc-gamers-to-keep-playing-for-at-least-15-minutes-after-they-tweak-settings-to-see-how-performance-has-changed-as-negative-steam-reviews-pile-up"><u>to me reads like an effort to prevent players from making knee-jerk reactions to the game's performance as soon as they’ve changed their settings</u></a>: “Please note that any time you change any of your graphics settings, your shaders will need to recompile. Please keep playing for at least 15 minutes to see how your PC's performance has changed.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Borderlands 4 Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">All eyes are on Gearbox right now amid an internet backlash to the performance of Borderlands 4 — which has come despite huge player numbers on Steam. Pitchford himself has set his sights on winning angry Borderlands 4 players over on social media. Since Borderlands 4’s huge Steam launch last week, Pitchford has issued <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/randy-pitchford-addresses-borderlands-4-console-fov-slider-complaints-theres-some-dreams-i-have-where-an-fov-setting-might-affect-fairness"><u>confusing comments on why the console version of Borderlands 4 lacks a field of view (FOV) slider</u></a>, promised <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-am-that-confident-randy-pitchford-says-its-impossible-for-borderlands-4-players-to-break-the-games-servers-this-weekend-challenges-them-to-try"><u>that it would have been impossible to break the Borderlands 4 servers through sheer weight of player numbers alone</u></a>, told people to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/code-your-own-engine-and-show-us-how-its-done-randy-pitchford-goes-on-the-offensive-as-borderlands-4-pc-performance-row-intensifies"><u>“code your own engine and show us how it’s done, please,”</u></a> and declared Borderlands 4 “a premium game made for premium gamers.” <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/my-advice-to-users-is-to-accept-reality-and-tune-or-to-not-play-randy-pitchford-is-at-the-get-a-refund-from-steam-stage-of-the-borderlands-4-pc-performance-backlash"><u>He's even started telling Borderlands 4 players to refund the game on Steam if they're that upset</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you are delving into Borderlands 4, don't go without updated hourly <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/borderlands-4/Borderlands_4_SHiFT_Codes"><u>SHiFT codes list</u></a>. We've also got a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/borderlands-4/kairos"><u>huge interactive map ready to go</u></a> and a badass <a href="https://maxroll.gg/borderlands-4/planner" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Borderlands 4 planner tool</u></a> courtesy of our buds at Maxroll. Plus check out our expert players' choices for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/borderlands-4/Which_Character_Should_You_Choose_in_Borderlands_4"><u>which character to choose</u></a> (no one agreed).</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-tech-experts-say-resetting-the-game-every-hour-should-really-not-be-an-expected-solution-for-players-patch-cannot-come-soon-enough]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>