<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 23:34:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds has a Summer Game Fest trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/08/monster-hunter-wilds-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-has-a-summer-game-fest-trailer.893832/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/08/monster-hunter-wilds-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Monster Hunter Wilds appeared at the end of Summer Games Fest with a new trailer and the promise of yet another trailer at this year’s Gamescom in August.</p>
<p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds - 2nd Trailer: The Hunter's Journey" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G_LtO6Mekjk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Monster Hunter Wilds was announced at the Game Awards last year, taking the series to a new desert lands, with all the challenges that this brings, such as battle monsters in sandstorms. The game also looks to take better advantage of the current generation consoles with larger herds and packs of animals, where you might try to lure a singular beast away from the pack to take them down individually.</p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds looks like a big expansion on the ideas of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/monster-hunter-world">Monster Hunter World</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/monster-hunter-rise">Monster Hunter Rise</a>, and Capcom can dream big with their push for cutting edge visuals that helped to make World such a huge success. Expect a few new tricks on top of Monster Hunter Rise’s Wirebugs, Palamutes along the way.</p>
<p>Since you’ve got a bit of time to kill before the next game is out, why not play some Monster Hunter Rise again? After all, it’s out on PS5 and Xbox Series, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/17/monster-hunter-rise-ps5-review-xbox-series-x/">Dom said of the port</a>, “Monster Hunter Rise remains one of the best action-RPGs of recent years, and the PS5 release is a perfect example of what should be going into this kind of port.”</p>

<p>There’s also <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/20/the-arrival-of-monster-hunter-stories-on-playstation-and-pc-finally-puts-the-series-in-one-place/">Monster Hunter Stories</a> coming to PlayStation and Xbox for the first time.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G_LtO6Mekjk&amp;ab_channel=MonsterHunter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Stanley Parable co-creator announces a tea-brewing sim that's secretly not-so-cosy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-stanley-parable-co-creator-announces-a-tea-brewing-sim-thats-secretly-not-so-cozy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-stanley-parable-co-creator-announces-a-tea-brewing-sim-thats-secretly-not-so-cosy.893829/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-stanley-parable-co-creator-announces-a-tea-brewing-sim-thats-secretly-not-so-cozy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Ivy Road's Wanderstop gets pretty bleak for a shop-keeping sim, but who's surprised?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wanderstop.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Annapurna Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
When the Summer Game Fest trailer for "narrative-centric cosy game" Wanderstop said it was from the creator behind <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-stanley-parable">The Stanley Parable</a>, I thought I had surely entered a different dimension where The Stanley Parable was actually a wholesome shop-keeping sim rather than a zig-zagging office-based nightmare. Then Wanderstop started to get rather bleak, and I finally stopped pinching myself. See for yourself.
</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Wanderstop - Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QF7EtyZdLMw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Wanderstop - Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QF7EtyZdLMw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QF7EtyZdLMw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QF7EtyZdLMw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Wanderstop casts us as "fallen fighter" Alta, who clearly has some unfinished business in the arena she left behind. In the meantime, she's trying to live a very different life running a tea shop and tending to customers in a lush forest that wouldn't be out of place in any number of similar sim games - Slime Rancher, Dreamlight Valley, My Time At Sandrock, take your pick.
</p>
<p>
Alta seems like an infinitely more interesting hero for a (seemingly) wholesome game because she just doesn't want to be here... at all. "I'm not really the patient type," she says while doing chores in service of the Almighty Cuppa, "but I'm surviving." Living a cosy life doesn't forcibly extract a smile from her face, and I imagine that friction will almost definitely come into play. Well, the trailer ends with Alta continually telling herself that she's happy, actually - <em>thank you very much, intrusive flashbacks</em> - so make of that what you will. Things probably aren't gonna stay cosy, though.
</p>
<p>
The game's Steam page details the more typical craft-y-management type stuff we can expect, from gardening and harvesting to experimenting to create different brews for travelers with unique tastes. The tea shop apparenlty "demands patience" and rejects "those who have come only in pursuit of growth unchecked." Alta better brew up a strong, strong mug, then.
</p>
<p>
Davey Wreden (who co-created The Stanley Parable and The Beginner's Guide) and Karla Zimonja (who co-developed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gone-home">Gone Home</a> and Tacoma) first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-that-happened-at-the-annapurna-interactive-showcase-2021">announced their new studio Ivy Road back in 2021</a>, with Annapurna Annapurna Interactive on publishing duty and Minecraft composer Daniel 'C418' Rosenfield behind the decks. We didn't have much info about their debut game at the time, but in hindsight, the co-founder's funky tea party announcement video should have been a clue. 
</p>
<p>
No release date yet but it's "coming soon" to PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1299460/Wanderstop/">Steam</a>) and PS5.
</p>
<hr>
<p><em>NotE3 and Summer Game Fest 2024 and the spread of summer games events are underway once more. Hit up our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/summer-game-fest-2024">Summer Game Fest 2024 hub</a> for all the news worth caring about from the show so far.  </em></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battle Vision Network is a competitive match-three puzzle battler from the makers of Grindstone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battle-vision-network-is-a-competitive-match-three-puzzle-battler-from-the-makers-of-grindstone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battle-vision-network-is-a-competitive-match-three-puzzle-battler-from-the-makers-of-grindstone.893823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battle-vision-network-is-a-competitive-match-three-puzzle-battler-from-the-makers-of-grindstone<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Players decide the evolving story by playing matches</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battle-vision-network-1.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capybara</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Grid-based <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-puzzle-games">puzzler</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grindstone">Grindstone</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grindstone-on-pc-is-going-to-be-the-end-of-me">was a favourite</a> of Katharine’s, who found it to be her go-to during regularly scheduled moments of “cat-based paralysis”. I didn’t spent quite so many hours of feline enforced stasis with it, but I too was drawn in for a respectable time chunk. It’s those detail-stuffed visuals and caffeinated animations that tipped it for me, and it’s the same art that have me excited for Capybara’s follow-up. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battle-vision-network">Battle Vision Network</a> is an online puzzle battler that pits you head to head against real-life humans (boo those guys). The conceit here is its a televised <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-space-games-on-pc">space</a> sport, in which you’ll steer the fate of its ongoing story arcs by winning or losing as your chosen team.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battle Vision Network [PC] Debut Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CSG9zSq6eKE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battle Vision Network [PC] Debut Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CSG9zSq6eKE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CSG9zSq6eKE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CSG9zSq6eKE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Like Grindstone, Battle Vision Network reaches deep inside the match three genre and yanks out all its bones before running off giggling in the opposite direction. Capybara describe it as a spiritual successor (they’re stealing souls now, too!) to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/might-magic-clash-heroes">Might &amp; Magic: Clash Of Heroes</a>. The aim here was to iterate on that one, specifically the multiplayer. Opponents will take turns thwacking each other using colour-matched formations. This is where I found myself getting interested. You make a vertical match to attack, horizontal to defend. You’ll also unlock new units as you progress, as well as fancy outfits to customise your team.</p>
<p>You’ll choose a team - each with their own visual style, home planet, all that jazz - and then the game tallies up winners at the end of each season. This goes on the affect the overall story, Capybara say. As a journalist, I’d love to see this escalate to the point where real-life fan gangs hit each other with bits of wood and crowbars over results, because that would be fun to write about. Terrible though. Shaming the sport, these hooligans. Battle Vision Network sounds to have a simultaneous launch on PC this time around, so you’ll be able to join in the rabid fan violence I assume is coming soon.</p>
<p><em>We saw this one at Day Of The Devs. You can keep up with all our picks using <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/day-of-the-devs">this here</a> tag. </em></p>
<hr>
<p><em>NotE3 and Summer Game Fest 2024 and the spread of summer games events are underway once more. Hit up our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/summer-game-fest-2024">Summer Game Fest 2024 hub</a> for all the news worth caring about from the show so far.  </em></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld’s Sakurajima update adds a new island and lots more and I can only assume that’s a good thing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworlds-sakurajima-update-adds-a-new-island-and-lots-more-and-i-can-only-assume-thats-a-good-thing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld%E2%80%99s-sakurajima-update-adds-a-new-island-and-lots-more-and-i-can-only-assume-that%E2%80%99s-a-good-thing.893820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworlds-sakurajima-update-adds-a-new-island-and-lots-more-and-i-can-only-assume-thats-a-good-thing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Nice things for people who enjoy these exact additions</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palworld-frog-new-pals-summer2024-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Pocketpair</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a> is getting a lot of new things! I’m going to write the names of these new things now. I really hope they mean something to you. I want you to have nice things. Here are the new things coming to Palworld: a new island. Some new Pals. A new level cap. A new arena. A new subspecies. A new raid. A new oil rig stronghold. A new faction and boss. Maybe some other, secret things? All this newness comes as part of the ‘Sakurajima’ update, which releases on June 27th, 2024.</p>

<p>“Palworld is essentially junk food of the highest order. There's no real joy or soul to be found here. All that's left is another neuron firing off in my brain, clapping its hands in a daze of stupefied glee,” Katharine (RPS in peace) wrote in our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworld-early-access-review">early access Palworld</a> review. “For as soon as I take my eyes off those carrots and start looking beyond the boundaries of my base, the rest of Palworld feels as tired and stale as its repetitive combat. It is, of course, still in early access at the moment, and future updates may well fill in some of the gaps it's currently lacking. But there are deeper flaws present here that I'm not sure can be fixed by fleshing out a few things.”</p>
<p>Thing is, this island didn’t exist when Katharine wrote that review, so we’ll never know exactly how she might have felt about things if she’d had a chance to experience: a new island. Some new Pals. A new level cap. A new arena. A new subspecies. A new raid. A new oil rig stronghold. A new faction and boss, and maybe some other, secret things?</p>
<p>But what about you, reader? How do you feel about:  a new island. Some new Pals. A new level cap. A new arena. A new subspecies. A new raid. A new oil rig stronghold. A new faction and boss, and maybe some other, secret things?</p>
<p>Actually, you know what? Don’t answer that.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>NotE3 and Summer Game Fest 2024 and the spread of summer games events are underway once more. Hit up our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/summer-game-fest-2024">Summer Game Fest 2024 hub</a> for all the news worth caring about from the show so far.  </em></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Gets Brand New Trailer; Cross-Platform Play Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-brand-new-trailer-cross-platform-play-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-brand-new-trailer-cross-platform-play-confirmed.893817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-brand-new-trailer-cross-platform-play-confirmed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gameplay/">Monster Hunter Wilds trailer</a> was shared today, providing a new look at the next entry in the series launching next year on PC and consoles.</p>
<p>Alongside the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZV1OJec0X94&amp;t=2s">new trailer</a>, which was shared during the Summer Game Fest 2024 show, it was also confirmed the game will support full cross-platform play when it launches on PC and consoles sometime in 2024. For another look at the game, we won't have to wait much longer, as it has been confirmed that another look at the game will be coming during Gamescom Opening Night with another trailer. The game will also be publicly available for the first time during Gamescom 2024.</p>
<p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds - 2nd Trailer: The Hunter's Journey | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZV1OJec0X94?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>Monster Hunter Wilds will launch in 2025 on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the latest entry in the series, Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak, by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-the-flame-of-kamura-burns-ever-hotter/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>With its huge number of new and returning monsters, new gameplay mechanics, and great refinements to the formula, Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak is the massive expansion that the latest entry in the series deserved to get. While the jump from High Rank to Master Rank doesn't feel as big as it was in previous entries in the series, Sunbreak does so many things well that most of the hunters traveling to Elgado and the Citadel will hardly be bothered by it.</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld’s first major expansion adds Pals and a whole new island]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24174051/pocketpair-palworld-expansion-sakurajima-new-pals-raids-building-arena</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld%E2%80%99s-first-major-expansion-adds-pals-and-a-whole-new-island.893811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24174051/pocketpair-palworld-expansion-sakurajima-new-pals-raids-building-arena<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="mRE4ZH">Pocketpair, the developer behind surprise survival hit <em>Palworld</em>, announced the first expansion at Summer Games Fest 2024. The new update will include a new island, Sakurajima, which includes a Japanese-style shrine, a mushroom-laden swamp, and a scary graveyard. There’ll also be new Pals, new Pal subspecies, a new faction and leader, and more.</p>
<p id="CGBrwT">The update will have a major building overhaul, which is good news for those of us who liked building strongholds and palaces for our Pals. Several building restrictions have been removed; players have a higher maximum number of bases; and new structures like pillars, glass structures, and work stations will be available.</p>
<p id="Sas37E">Once players have found their feet and conquered the new content, they’ll want to look to the new Stronghold, a massive oil rig that is defended by a poacher group. Players can engage in large-scale battles, fighting for rewards like the new resource Crude Oil. The update also includes a PvP Arena mode, where players can pit their Pals against each other. <em>Palworld’</em>s update will include Xbox-dedicated servers to help console players tackle the game’s island with friends.</p>
<p id="UsZNg2"><em>Palworld</em>’s Sakurajima update is set to release on June 27, 2024; the game first came out in January. When the game was first released, it had a startling hot streak of sales. However, player enthusiasm waned as the weeks went on. It’s good to see the game get an update, and I’m sure my friends and I will to explore these new regions and capture the elusive Pals within. </p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Monster Hunter Wilds Gameplay Revealed at Summer Game Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-monster-hunter-wilds-gameplay-revealed-at-summer-game-fest/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-monster-hunter-wilds-gameplay-revealed-at-summer-game-fest.893805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/new-monster-hunter-wilds-gameplay-revealed-at-summer-game-fest/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>During today’s Summer Game Fest 2024 showcase, Capcom revealed a new trailer for Monster Hunter Wilds that confirmed various fresh details.</p>



<p>First, the game has been confirmed to be released in 2025 on the PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and PC. The game will be playable at Gamescom 2024, including the first hands-on game demo. You can watch the brand new trailer below:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds - 2nd Trailer: The Hunter's Journey | PS5 Games" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZV1OJec0X94?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>The official game description reads, “Prepare to experience the most cinematic and immersive story in Monster Hunter series history. Find out what lies in store for you and your allies in this vast, seamless land teeming with monsters, when Monster Hunter Wilds launches on PS5 in 2025.”</p>



<p>In a previous trailer, Capcom only confirmed that Monster Hunter Wilds would be released sometime in 2025. A new release window for the game should undoubtedly build major buzz, especially as the franchise celebrates its 20th anniversary this year.</p>



<p>Capcom first <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-announced-at-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced Monster Hunter Wilds</a> at The Game Awards 2023 with a brief gameplay trailer. The trailer teased new environments and the Seikret mount system. </p>



<p>Since then, Monster Hunter socials regularly tease <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1798339539880018394" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming monsters</a>, characters, and more via Twitter.</p>



<p>Capcom recently revealed that the Monster Hunter series reached <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-series-hits-100-million-in-cumulative-sales/">100 million units in cumulative sales</a> as of March 2024, and Wilds will certainly boost those numbers.</p>



<p>So, although the core series is still in hiatus following Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak, it continues to thrive. Monster Hunter: World even earned <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-world-steam-numbers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">impressive Steam chart numbers</a> in January 2024, following the Wilds reveal and a notable discount.</p>



<p>For now, fans of the franchise can enjoy Monster Hunter Stories 2: Wings of Ruin on the Nintendo Switch. Capcom also confirmed that a Switch port for the original Monster Hunter Stories is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-stories-coming-to-switch-in-summer-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coming this summer</a>, too.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read our exclusive details about Doom: The Dark Ages <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coming to the Xbox Games Showcase</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capybara Games announces online PvP puzzle battler Battle Vision Network for PC, iOS, and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/capybara-games-announces-online-pvp-puzzle-battler-battle-vision-network-for-pc-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capybara-games-announces-online-pvp-puzzle-battler-battle-vision-network-for-pc-ios-and-android.893802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/capybara-games-announces-online-pvp-puzzle-battler-battle-vision-network-for-pc-ios-and-android<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Capybara Games [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capybara-games">Capybara Games</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Battle Vision Network" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/battle-vision-network">Battle Vision Network</a></em>, an online player-versus-player puzzle battler coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [20,287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam, and iOS and Android via <a title="Companies > Netflix [80 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netflix">Netflix</a> in 2025. <span id="more-887552"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Capybara Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Battle Vision Network</em> is an online player-versus-player puzzle battler fusing cozy color-matching puzzle gameplay with deep turn-based tactics. Teams from across the galaxy vie for the ultimate championship title in fast n’ fierce puzzle battles!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Compete in Fast-Paced Online One-Versus-One Battles</strong> – Take turns launching attacks by creating color-matching formations. Vertical matches create attackers, horizontal ones defenders. Rapid-fire matches are five minutes and gameplay is simple to jump into. Endless depth of strategy emerges with advanced play.</li><li><strong>Recruit New Units With Unique Abilities</strong> – Climb the intergalactic ranks and discover a giant roster of units with unique abilities. Choose between multiple teams bursting with style. Recruit charismatic captains who run the playfield with big personalities and tide-turning special abilities.</li><li><strong>Tailor the Game <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Fierce competition requires fierce customization. Ascend the win ladder and discover show-stopping new looks for your captains, expressive emojis and custom win screens to taunt your rivals, and surprises along the way.</li><li><strong>Shape the Community</strong> – <em>Battle Vision Network</em> is a live game with new seasonal twists, characters, rankings and challenges. Teams spend a season vying for the Champion title—and the player community decides who takes the crown! Win a match with the Rag Tags team? That win shapes the stats, outcome, and narrative events of the season for everyone.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/battle-vision-network/june-7-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Battle Vision Network - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HqreJoBp4cE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_887558"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Blade Zero ‘The Blade is Drawn’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/phantom-blade-zero-the-blade-is-drawn-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phantom-blade-zero-%E2%80%98the-blade-is-drawn%E2%80%99-trailer.893799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/phantom-blade-zero-the-blade-is-drawn-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Playable for the first time at various events throughout the year.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > S-GAME [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/s-game">S-GAME</a> has released a new trailer for <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Phantom Blade Zero [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/phantom-blade-zero">Phantom Blade Zero</a></em> dubbed “The Blade is Drawn.” <span id="more-887037"></span></p><p>The trailer features never before seen footage depicting high-speed combat and multiple weapons, among other gameplay elements. The end of the video also announces that the game will be playable throughout various events this year, including Summer Game Fest from June 8 to 10, ChinaJoy from July 26 to 29, Gamescom from August 21 to 25, and Tokyo Game Show from September 28 to 29.</p><p><em>Phantom Blade Zero</em> is in development for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,184 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>The Blade is Drawn Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Phantom Blade Zero Gameplay Trailer - SGF2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgBmIjaZraE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic X Shadow Generations launches October 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/sonic-x-shadow-generations-launches-october-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-x-shadow-generations-launches-october-25.893796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/sonic-x-shadow-generations-launches-october-25<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Editions and game details revealed.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Sonic X Shadow Generations [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sonic-x-shadow-generations">Sonic X Shadow Generations</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,184 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,460 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,766 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,217 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,430 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2513280/SONIC_X_SHADOW_GENERATIONS/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [338 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store on October 25 for $49.99, <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,595 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> announced. <span id="more-887043"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Editions</strong></p><p><em>Sonic X Shadow Generations</em>‘ Digital Deluxe Edition allows fans to play the game three days early and includes additional iconic music tracks from previous Sonic and Shadow games, a Terios skin based on Shadow’s original concept, behind-the-scenes art, an additional level and Shadow Skin, and more! Sonic fans can also pre-order the Digital Standard or Deluxe editions of <em>Sonic X Shadow Generations</em> ahead of launch to receive a legacy skin for Sonic, based on his look from <em>Sonic <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,521 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></em>! Players who pre-order the Physical Day One Edition will receive Gerald Robotnik’s Journal, a 28-page logbook chronicling Gerald’s innermost thoughts and drawings while he created Shadow the Hedgehog and the Ark Space Station, in addition to the legacy skin for Sonic.</p><p>Please see below for more details on each offering:</p><ul><li><strong>Digital Standard Edition</strong> ($49.99 USD)<!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Base game (digital)</li><li>Bonus <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> exclusive: Extended Prologue animations with deleted scenes</li><li>Pre-order bonus: Sonic Adventure Skin</li></ul></li><li><strong>Physical Day One Edition</strong> ($49.99 USD)<ul><li>Base game (physical only)</li><li>Bonus PlayStation exclusive: Extended Prologue animations with deleted scenes</li><li>Pre-order bonus: Sonic Adventure Skin and Gerald Robotnik’s Journal (28 pages)</li></ul></li><li><strong>Digital Deluxe Edition</strong> ($59.99 USD)<ul><li>Base game (digital only)</li><li>Bonus PlayStation exclusive: Extended Prologue animations with deleted scenes</li><li>Pre-order bonus: Sonic Adventure Skin</li></ul></li><li><strong>Digital Deluxe Season Pass</strong><ul><li>Play the game three days early</li><li>An additional character skin and level for Shadow (releasing Holiday 2024)</li><li>Terios Skin</li><li>Extra BGM Pack</li><li>Digital Art Book + Soundtrack</li><li>Skill Points (<em>Sonic Generations</em>)</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_889208"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Play as Shadow in a brand-new story campaign featuring never-before-seen abilities that prove why he’s known as the Ultimate Life Form! Speed through iconic stages from Shadow’s history, discover hidden secrets in an expansive hub world, and unlock new powers to take on Black Doom and save the world.</p><p><em>Sonic X Shadow Generations</em> also includes a complete remaster of the highly acclaimed <em>Sonic Generations</em>, a time-traveling adventure featuring a greatest-hits collection of 3D and 2D Sonic stages, now with upgraded visuals and new bonus content.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>The Return of Shadow</strong> – In this new standalone campaign, Shadow’s nemesis, Black Doom, has reemerged and threatens to take over the world once again. Shadow must journey into his past, confront his painful memories, and unlock new dark powers to save the world.</li><li><strong>Shadow Evolved</strong> – Harness Shadow’s new Doom Powers to battle hordes of enemies and tackle platforming challenges like never before. Surf on water, fly over obstacles, and stop time with the return of Chaos Control!</li><li><strong>A Journey Through Time and Dimensions</strong> – Relive signature levels from Shadow’s previous adventures and accelerate through mind-bending stages in both 3D and 2D, warped by Black Doom’s influence as Shadow works to piece together the timeline and thwart his evil plans.</li><li><strong>Explore the New White Space</strong> – Stretch your legs in an all-new hub world inspired by the open-zone gameplay of <a title="Games > Sonic Frontiers [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sonic-frontiers">Sonic Frontiers</a>™. As Shadow gains new powers, he can explore further and uncover the secrets hidden throughout!</li><li><strong>The Best of Both Worlds, Remastered</strong> – Spin dash through a greatest-hits collection of 3D and 2D versions of iconic stages from past Sonic games, now with updated visuals and reworked cinematics.</li><li><strong>New Collectibles, Bonus Content, and More!</strong> – Rescue Chao hiding in every level, rack up the highest pinball score in the Casino Nights Zone, and check out the museum for behind-the-scenes art, music, and more!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/sonic-x-shadow-generations/june-7-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="SONIC X SHADOW GENERATIONS - Summer Game Fest Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6E36fOpk-Yg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO launches October 11]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-launches-october-11</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-launches-october-11.893793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-launches-october-11<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-sparking-zero">Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,184 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,460 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1790600/DRAGON_BALL_Sparking_ZERO/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on October 11, publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,512 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Spike Chunsoft [837 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/spike-chunsoft">Spike Chunsoft</a> announced. <span id="more-887020"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>Developed by Spike Chunsoft, known for their work on the previous <em>Dragon Ball Z: Budokai Tenkaichi</em>, <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</em> lets players get into epic battles alongside legendary characters from the series. Episode Battle will let players pick one of eight characters and relive key battle moments in the <em>Dragon Ball</em> saga. Custom Battle introduces a new element to experiencing <em>Dragon Ball</em> as a game, where players can try their hands at a match imagined by the developers or create their own battle situation and share it with the world. The new trailer also reveals new additions to the playable character roster with Goku (Super), Ultra Instinct, Gohan (Adult), Super Saiyan 2, Golden Frieza, Bardock, Raditz, Goku Black, Zamasu, and Jiren, Full Power.</p><p><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</em> is available in the following editions:</p><ul><li>The Standard Edition</li><li>The Digital Deluxe Edition which includes the Standard Edition, three days of early access to the game, and the Season Pass, which contains more than 20 characters including characters from <i>Dragon Ball Super: Super Hero</i>&nbsp;and <em>Dragon Ball Daima</em> as well as the Shenron Summon that can unlock items. Early access to downloadable content characters is also included.</li><li>The Digital Ultimate Edition contains the Deluxe Edition content as well as the Ultimate Upgrade Pack which includes the Goku (Super) Costume with Power Pole, an Emote Voice Set, one Customisation item and two player card backgrounds. This edition also includes the possibility to summon Super Shenron to unlock items or characters.</li><li>The Collector’s Edition includes the content from the Digital Ultimate Edition along with an exclusive <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</em> diorama and a <a title="Platforms > Meta [103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>llic Bookmark.</li><li>The Premium Collector’s Edition, available exclusively on the Bandai Namco Store, includes all Collector’s Edition content as well as a SteelBook and four exclusive cards from the <em>Dragon Ball Super Card Game</em>&nbsp;Fusion Worlds.</li></ul></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/drgaon-ball-sparking-zero/june-7-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO - Release Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N8Zm___c4B8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_889240"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Gets New Gameplay Trailer At Summer Game Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-at-summer-game-fest/1100-6524057/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-at-summer-game-fest.893790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-at-summer-game-fest/1100-6524057/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524057">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><span>A new trailer for Monster Hunter Wilds was revealed as a part of 2024's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/summer-game-fest-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5449/" data-ref-id="2900-5449">Summer Game Fest</a>. </span><span>The new trailer blends gameplay with stunning cinematics, giving players a closer look at what the next entry in the popular action-RPG series holds in store.</span></p><p><span>Prominently featured in the trailer are a desert biome--completely with a Dune-esque sandworm, albeit much smaller--and a cold plain outside of a village. This time around, monster seem even more powerful, boasting lasers and brutal attacks. You can watch the full trailer below:</span></p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZV1OJec0X94" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZV1OJec0X94" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Monster Hunter Wilds is scheduled to release on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC in 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake 2's Night Springs DLC Is Somehow Even Weirder Than The Base Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alan-wake-2s-night-springs-dlc-is-somehow-even-weirder-than-the-base-game/1100-6523945/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-2s-night-springs-dlc-is-somehow-even-weirder-than-the-base-game.893787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alan-wake-2s-night-springs-dlc-is-somehow-even-weirder-than-the-base-game/1100-6523945/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523945">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">"If you thought we were meta before, wait until you see this," Remedy's Thomas Puha told me at the start of a recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/alan-wake-ii/" data-ref-id="5000-547391">Alan Wake 2</a> DLC preview. The first expansion for one of 2023's best games is on the way, with the Alan Wake 2 Night Springs DLC launching for all Expansion Pass owners tomorrow, June 8. It's the first of two expansions and is split into a trio of hour-long episodes, each made to look like Night Springs, the in-universe television anthology inspired by The Twilight Zone. In a hands-off demo I attended, it quickly became obvious that Puha is correct. Somehow, despite the chaotic, ouroboros-like metanarrative that is Alan Wake 2, the DLC seems <em>even weirder</em>.</p><p dir="ltr">The premise of the DLC is players experiencing three failed attempts by Alan to escape the Dark Place before the events of Alan Wake 2, meaning exactly <em>when </em>they land in the 13 years he's been trapped there is a bit unclear at this point. As Alan fought with fiction to create his own exit strategy, twisting and morphing three scripts from his time as a TV writer became his next effort, which lends itself very well to the high strangeness Remedy has leaned into more and more since 2019's Control.</p><p dir="ltr">In one episode titled Number One Fan, The Waitress--who looks like Rose Marigold but who is not literally her--steps away from her shift at Nite's Diner (an echo of the Oh, Deer Diner) to rescue her lover, the Bestselling Writer. The episode opens with a pastel pinkish filter, a saccharine monologue narrated by The Waitress, and our hero of this episode dispensing to her loyal customers both delicious coffee and "really good advice."</p><p dir="ltr">She doesn't know each customer by name, but she oddly has a level of intimacy with each of them, as the subtitles jokingly refer to names for speakers like Lady With Seven Corgis and Guy Who Works With Computers. The idyllic opening is soon stripped away across a 12-minute demo that starts with this sweetness and ends with The Waitress shotgun-blasting a dozen or so Taken on the shore of Cauldron Lake.</p><p dir="ltr">For players who may play these episodes as they experience the base game for the first time and discover the TVs that lead to them, the shift in tone may cause whiplash, and that's intentional.</p><p dir="ltr">"Coming from working on survival-horror for five years, yeah, you know, it [let us] have a bit of fun with this," said game director Kyle Rowley. "We've talked about how, because the base game is so important from a narrative perspective, everything [must] connect together and make sense. So we had a lot of ideas that were like, 'This is a cool idea, but it just doesn't make sense in the context of what we're trying to do.' Whereas in this, we're like, 'That sounds cool. Let's put it in.'"</p><p dir="ltr">"And I love how that gives us an avenue to explore different themes that we have established before but then lean into them heavily," added level designer Nathalie Jankie. "I love Rose, so playing a character that's inspired by her, The Waitress--it's such a good power fantasy, because I think a waitress is maybe a less glamorized job than an FBI profiler or a best-selling author, but it's a power fantasy that a lot of us really relate to. And we just had the best time fantasizing like, what does it mean to be a fan? We throw quite a few enemies at you, and that's all to reinforce this fantasy that you're in control. You're saving the love of your life, you know? I think it's something that we've all maybe felt, being meaningful and being important to someone."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312920-ns_ep3_gameplay_01.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4312920" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312920-ns_ep3_gameplay_01.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4312920"></a><figcaption>By bringing familiar faces into the framework of Alan Wake 2, the Remedy Connected Universe continues to unfold in unpredictable ways.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312920-ns_ep3_gameplay_01.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312921-ns_ep3_gameplay_13.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312919-ns_ep3_cine_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312918-ns_ep2_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312917-ns_ep2_gameplay_01.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312916-ns_ep2_cine_02.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312915-ns_ep1_gameplay_07.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312914-ns_ep1_gameplay_05.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312913-ns_ep1_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312912-ns_ep1_cine_03.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312910-ns_ep3_gameplay_12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312909-ns_ep3_gameplay_09.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312908-ns_ep3_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312907-ns_ep3_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312906-ns_ep3_gameplay_02.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4312921,1300-4312919,1300-4312918,1300-4312917,1300-4312916,1300-4312915,1300-4312914,1300-4312913,1300-4312912,1300-4312910,1300-4312909,1300-4312908,1300-4312907,1300-4312906" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312921-ns_ep3_gameplay_13.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312919-ns_ep3_cine_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312918-ns_ep2_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312917-ns_ep2_gameplay_01.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312916-ns_ep2_cine_02.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312915-ns_ep1_gameplay_07.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312914-ns_ep1_gameplay_05.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312913-ns_ep1_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312912-ns_ep1_cine_03.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312910-ns_ep3_gameplay_12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312909-ns_ep3_gameplay_09.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312908-ns_ep3_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312907-ns_ep3_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1632/16320660/4312906-ns_ep3_gameplay_02.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312921-ns_ep3_gameplay_13.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312919-ns_ep3_cine_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312918-ns_ep2_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312917-ns_ep2_gameplay_01.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312916-ns_ep2_cine_02.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312915-ns_ep1_gameplay_07.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312914-ns_ep1_gameplay_05.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312913-ns_ep1_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312912-ns_ep1_cine_03.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312910-ns_ep3_gameplay_12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312909-ns_ep3_gameplay_09.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312908-ns_ep3_gameplay_06.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312907-ns_ep3_gameplay_04.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1632/16320660/4312906-ns_ep3_gameplay_02.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Each of the other two episodes brings its own distinct genre touches, too. In North Star, players will control The Sibling, who looks like Control's Jesse Faden, as she searches for her brother in what lead writer Clay Murphy called "the creepiest" of the trio. The synopsis reads like Control, which would lend itself to the fan theory that Alan wrote the events of Control into existence, though creative director Sam Lake told me just last year that Remedy does not intend to say Control's story is sincerely born from Alan's mind. That suggests this funhouse-mirror version of Control's leading lady and the events she'll experience in the DLC aren't meant to be taken <em>too </em>literally--not for Jesse Faden, at least.</p><p dir="ltr">Perhaps no episode feels more fan-service-driven than the sci-fi-flavored Time Breaker, which also perfectly illustrates just how meta this DLC will be. In it, players take on the role of actor Shawn Ashmore--yes, he's playing himself--who portrays a character named The Actor, who is an echo of Tim Breaker from Alan Wake 2, who himself is--fans would argue, anyway--an echo of Quantum Break's Jack Joyce. In this episode, The Actor "must track down the Master of Many Worlds" and prevent him from murdering the many versions of The Actor existing throughout spacetime.</p><p dir="ltr">To a lore obsessive like me, that surely reads like allusions to Jack Joyce and Martin Hatch (now all but confirmed to be Alan Wake 2's Warlin Door). In one possible reading of the text, that could make Time Breaker a quasi-continuation or even epilogue to Quantum Break, an IP that Remedy can't actually work with but still ripples out into current Remedy Connected Universe stories. But the team says, squint as some fans may to see such a closing chapter for Jack Joyce, that's not exactly what's going on.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think in the most technical sense, they could [theory-craft that], but they'd really have to squint," said Murphy. "After you play the episodes, you'll see, but there's not a lot of, you know, straight connective sequential tissue between these stories and maybe the elements they're inspired by. I'm sure I'll read that theory on Reddit at some point, but I'll downvote it," he joked.</p><blockquote><p>Perhaps no episode feels more fan-service-driven than the sci-fi-flavored Time Breaker, which also perfectly illustrates just how meta this DLC will be.</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">And he's right; the fan theories will pour in no matter what, as they always have since 2010's Alan Wake. It comes with the territory and is part of the fun. "I've talked about this before, but seeing people's speculative videos or posts on Reddit or articles, sometimes we look at them and go, like, 'They're so wrong' or 'Okay, they're kind of getting somewhere,'" Rowley told me. "But you know, I think we like that. As a studio, a lot of our stories are mystery-driven, and even internally, some people are like, 'What the hell is going on here?'"</p><p dir="ltr">What if, I wondered out loud, Remedy happened upon a fan theory that got most everything right and cracked the case before Remedy is able to unveil it through its many interconnected games? Would they find it deflating or inspiring? "I don't think it's possible for them to crack the case," Rowley confidently said, "so we don't worry about it."</p><p dir="ltr">Alan Wake 2's Night Springs DLC launches tomorrow, June 8, for those who own the game's Deluxe edition on Xbox Series X|S, PS5, or PC via the Epic Games Store. The second DLC, The Lake House, is currently scheduled for October. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/embargo-june-7-4pm-pt-alan-wake-ii-is-finally-getting-a-physical-release-preorder-available-soon/1100-6524001/" data-ref-id="1100-6524001">physical edition, as well as a collector's edition from Limited Run</a>, are each on the way.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valorant On Controller Could Feel As Good As Mouse And Keyboard]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valorant-on-controller-could-feel-as-good-as-mouse-and-keyboard/1100-6524042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-on-controller-could-feel-as-good-as-mouse-and-keyboard.893781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valorant-on-controller-could-feel-as-good-as-mouse-and-keyboard/1100-6524042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Riot says it wants the console version of Valorant to provide just as strong a competitive experience as PC, so it adjusted controls to make controllers feel as flexible and precise.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Riot Games faced a big challenge when it started thinking about bringing its hit tactical shooter, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/valorant/" data-ref-id="5000-509039">Valorant</a>, to console. The essential part was maintaining the same feel that Valorant has on PC so that, regardless of the machine you're playing on, you're getting what Riot considers to be the definitive Valorant experience. Because of the major differences between PC and console inputs--specifically the fact that playing a shooter with a mouse and playing a shooter with a controller require completely separate skill sets--that meant Riot had to adapt the console experience to make the two feel as similar as possible.</p><p dir="ltr">Ahead of the announcement of a Valorant console edition at Summer Game Fest 2024, Riot invited journalists and influencers to its studio in Los Angeles to play the new version, both to show the game off to the community and to gather feedback from Valorant die-hards to make sure it felt <em>right. </em>We played around three hours of Valorant during the event, and though I'm by no means a Valorant regular, my impression was that Riot's work to find ways to make Valorant's controls feel as tight and precise as they do on PC were pretty successful.</p><p dir="ltr">That was the essential element, as production director Arnar Gylfason explained in an interview with GameSpot, and there was a time when Riot wasn't sure if it could get it right.</p><p dir="ltr">"There were so many ways, where if it wouldn't have worked out, we would have had to say that we can't make this game for console if we can solve this problem," Gylfason said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315198-valorantconsole_playstation-gameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315198" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315198-valorantconsole_playstation-gameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315198"></a><figcaption>Console gameplay is just as quick and lethal as on PC.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315198-valorantconsole_playstation-gameplay.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The stakes were so high both because of what Valorant is and because of the community that plays it. Valorant is the kind of game people take <em>seriously</em>--unlike more arcade-ish shooters like Fortnite or Call of Duty, the Valorant experience is a lot less casual. As a tactical shooter, the emphasis is on smart plays and anticipation, because in any engagement, one or two shots is almost always enough to take you out. Most matches are about attacking or defending territory, so losing a teammate to a bad play or a slow reaction can be devastating for your side's chances of winning. Valorant is a high-skill game whose focus is on being highly competitive, and that means that the controls for the game have to be reliable, regardless of whether you're aiming with a mouse or an analog stick.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to quick and deadly gunplay, Valorant mixes in hero shooter elements, with a huge cast of characters who all have their own special abilities. So in addition to anticipating player locations, locking down angles, and coordinating with your squad, you will also have opponents' abilities to contend with and counter.</p><p dir="ltr">As Gylfason explained, the issue is that on console, it can be difficult to do everything Valorant requires of you with the traditional way that shooters handle their controls.</p><p dir="ltr">"The biggest [challenge] is, how do you solve for this problem in Valorant that you have to be able to be really fast at looking around and assessing a scenario--swinging like a 50/50 angle, where you have to check left and check right really quickly, or shoot an ability that landed right behind you, and then turn around and kill the agent that shot it," Gylfason said. "But then you also have to be able to hit a pixel headshot really far away on a moving target."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315199-valorantconsole_xbox-focus.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315199" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315199-valorantconsole_xbox-focus.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315199"></a><figcaption>Focus mode gives you a different sensitivity to give you more precise aiming.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315199-valorantconsole_xbox-focus.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">When playing Valorant with a mouse, you can do those things--big movements of the mouse make for big movements of your character, but you can still get the precision of aiming that's essential to kill an opponent before they can take you down. On controllers, those vast differences can be tougher, and in many shooters, the experience can often include situations in which a player turning quickly will swing <em>past</em> their target and then have to dial back to readjust. In Valorant, that would make the experience extremely frustrating.</p><p dir="ltr">Riot's answer to that problem was to create an additional aiming mode called Focus mode, a sort of half-step between firing from the hip and aiming down sights. When you pull the left trigger on Valorant's default settings, you slip into Focus mode, which tightens your view a little on your gun and switches you into a more precise aiming sensitivity. The idea here is that you can set one sensitivity for looking around, one sensitivity for Focus, and one sensitivity for ADS, allowing you to get the precision you need.</p><p dir="ltr">In practice, the Focus mode system works well to balance your ability to take in the environment quickly with the need to hit a clutch headshot at a moment's notice. It tightens your view without completely sacrificing your situational awareness like you might if you were aiming down sights, and Riot allows you to adjust the sensitivities for the different aim modes so you can get exactly the right feeling and precision out of each one. And while my experience with Valorant on PC is, as mentioned, somewhat limited, I didn't get the sense on console that I was playing some weaker approximation of what the game is like on PC, or that I was battling the controls or constantly fighting to compensate for overshooting my aim when trying to quickly address a threat somewhere else.</p><p dir="ltr">Gylfason also said that another part of the battle was that Riot couldn't just port Valorant to console as it is on PC and be done with it. The differences in the controls make small but subtle changes to the whole experience in ways you might not expect, so Riot had to tune various small things to make sure that console and PC <em>felt</em> the same, even if things were a little different behind the scenes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315201-valorantconsole_xbox-buypage.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315201" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315201-valorantconsole_xbox-buypage.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315201"></a><figcaption>Much of the console version has a different user interface to make it easier to use with a controller.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315201-valorantconsole_xbox-buypage.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"One specific thing, for example, is when you think about the action of incoming abilities that you have to go deal with, say, a Reyna Leer [ability], or a Sova dart, or Gekko ability or whatever else. What it really does is, it's forcing the player to make a choice of, 'Do I deal with the ability by disbanding it, do I hide, or do I tank the ability and try to take the engagement?'" Gylfason said. "The tuning for that is, how hard is it to kill that ability or disband that ability? What it's really demanding of you is making a choice of, what are you dealing with at the moment. And dealing with that threat, to mitigate something, it takes a certain amount of time for you to, like, look away from the angle, deal with the ability, and then look back into the angle."</p><p dir="ltr">"And it's that disruption that needs to be the same, but that doesn't mean that the tunings need to be the same on PC and console," he continued. "So like, does it take the same amount of bullets to shoot a Reyna Leer on console and PC? No, but it takes roughly the same amount of distraction time to deal with it and turn it back. And so it's tunings like that that are important to us. It would have been really simple to just have ported over one to one, but then it wouldn't have really served the purpose that we needed to serve."</p><p dir="ltr">Making sure the controls feel good isn't the only element of console play Riot is focusing on. Performance is also an important part of the situation, and to keep console players from feeling like they're getting an inferior competitive experience as compared to players on powerful PCs, Riot is targeting a stable 120 FPS across all consoles. There's no cross-play between PC and other platforms, Gylfason said. Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5 players will find themselves in the same lobbies, but they'll never go up against PC players. Likewise, Riot is using its anti-cheat software to keep mouse and keyboard players out of console lobbies, so when you start a Valorant game with a controller in your hand, you'll know you're on an even playing field with everyone else in the match.</p><p dir="ltr">Your stats are also separated by platform, Gylfason said, so if you're pulling great kill/death ratios when you play on PS5, you won't have to worry about those numbers getting tanked if you decide you want to give mouse and keyboard on PC a shot.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315202-valorantconsole_xbox-kill.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315202" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315202-valorantconsole_xbox-kill.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4315202"></a><figcaption>Valorant on console carries over your progress and purchases from PC, but it does not pit console players against PC players through cross-play.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4315202-valorantconsole_xbox-kill.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Console players should also have the same experience as PC players when it comes to connection speed and server access.</p><p dir="ltr">"Once you log into Valorant, you're in Valorant--you're playing on the same infrastructure, the same net code, the same servers as PC players are playing on," Gylfason said. "You're not passing through layers of anything else, you are mainlined into the Riot infrastructure. And so our hope is also that being able to build on that experience and investment we've made over the past few years for PC, we're delivering that directly to the console players from day one."</p><p dir="ltr">While there's no cross-play between PC and console, there is cross-progression. As on PC, the console version of Valorant is free-to-play, and your account is shared across any platforms you might use. That means any skins or cosmetic items you purchase or unlock on PC will come with you to console, and vice versa.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was important for us that we honored the player investment in the game," Gylfason said. "No matter what platform they're playing on, whether that investment is time spent or money invested, that needs to be honored and respected, no matter where you're coming from."</p><p>Riot is running a limited beta test for Valorant on console starting on June 14 in the US, Canada, Europe, the UK, and Japan, with the possibility of the beta rolling out globally after that. You can sign up or learn more on Riot's website at <a href="https://beta.playvalorant.com/" rel="nofollow ">beta.playvalorant.com</a>.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
  
        
                    
        
        
          
                  


  

    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Is Getting A New Region And So Much More With The Sakurajima Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-is-getting-a-new-region-and-so-much-more-with-the-sakurajima-update/1100-6524055/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-is-getting-a-new-region-and-so-much-more-with-the-sakurajima-update.893775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-is-getting-a-new-region-and-so-much-more-with-the-sakurajima-update/1100-6524055/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524055">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/palworld/" data-ref-id="5000-532768">Palworld's</a> massive update, the Sakurajima Update, was revealed during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/summer-game-fest-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5449/" data-ref-id="2900-5449">Summer Game Fest</a>, bringing a new region, Pals, and much more on June 27. The update adds a new island, which appears to a have a number of different biomes, with a cherry-blossom forest and a mushroom-filled swamp shown in the trailer.</p><p>There will also be new Pals, with a scary ghost and an armored knight shown off. There are also new sub-species of existing Pals. Xbox players will be happy to know that dedicated servers are coming as part of the update as well.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fKzLdPZr2Fk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fKzLdPZr2Fk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The update will also add new buildings, an increased level cap, a new raid, a new faction and boss, and a new stronghold--the oil rig--which is exactly what sounds like. There is also a new arena being added, which looks like it could be a 3v3 PvP mode.</p><p>Palworld is an open-world survival-crafting game that blew up earlier this year thanks to its similarities to Pokemon. While the game does feature different creatures to capture and battle with, it's emphasis on survival and crafting, and some of the shadier ways you can use your Pals, has made it a stand out hit. The game is available in early access on Xbox Series X|S and PC and is currently a part of Xbox Game Pass.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark And Darker Is Out Now For Free On Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dark-and-darker-is-out-now-for-free-on-steam/1100-6524056/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-and-darker-is-out-now-for-free-on-steam.893772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dark-and-darker-is-out-now-for-free-on-steam/1100-6524056/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524056">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Dark and Darker is now available to play for free on Steam and the Epic Games Store, as announced at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/summer-game-fest-2024-date-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect/1100-6521816/" data-ref-id="1100-6521816">Summer Game Fest</a>.</p><p>Dark and Darker had originally released last year in Early Access, but has been delayed even with its multiple public test sessions due to developer Ironmace's legal clash with publisher Nexon.</p><p><em>Story is developing. </em></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Finals Season 3's New Map, Gadgets, Weapons, And More Revealed At Summer Game Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-finals-season-3s-new-map-gadgets-weapons-and-more-revealed-at-summer-game-fest/1100-6524058/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-finals-season-3s-new-map-gadgets-weapons-and-more-revealed-at-summer-game-fest.893769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-finals-season-3s-new-map-gadgets-weapons-and-more-revealed-at-summer-game-fest/1100-6524058/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524058">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Viewers got their first look at Season 3 of Embark Studios' hit FPS, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-finals/">The Finals</a>, via a new season launch trailer unveiled during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/summer-game-fest-2024-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-5449/">Summer Game Fest Live</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Season 3 is set to launch on June 13, and will introduce more weapons, a new map, new gadgets, and the return of Terminal Attack--a mode that will be sticking around for good.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8kWYWa3Jv2Q" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8kWYWa3Jv2Q" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The new map--an arena called Kyoto 1568--takes inspiration from the real Kyoto, featuring blooming cherry blossom trees and map features with a Japanese flair, including 16th century temples, beautiful gardens, and thick bamboo forests that are perfect for hiding in. The Kyoto 1568 arena stands out from the game's other maps, which thus far have all had a gritty, urban air about them.</p><p dir="ltr">The Finals is free-to-play on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6515851&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meta-quest-2-is-only-100-right-now-but-itll-sell-out-fast\/1100-6515851\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523969&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-removes-8k-claim-from-playstation-5-boxes\/1100-6523969\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-get-exotic-class-items-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape-and-how-they-work\/1100-6523922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523871&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preorders-are-already-discounted\/1100-6523871\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524007&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-27-warhammer-novels-for-only-18-for-a-limited-time\/1100-6524007\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523855&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hitman-3-is-reloading-for-another-run-at-vr-assassinations\/1100-6523855\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523973&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-boys-shares-a-closer-look-at-season-4s-new-supes\/1100-6523973\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523972&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/is-the-acolyte-the-gayest-star-wars-ever-amanda-stenberg-and-creator-discuss\/1100-6523972\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523846&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/astro-bot-ps5-preorder-guide\/1100-6523846\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6522438&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-new-atari-400-mini-is-on-sale-for-the-first-time\/1100-6522438\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518213&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/officially-licensed-call-of-duty-ps5-controller-gets-big-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6518213\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523894&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/google-employee-reportedly-leaked-nintendo-info-ahead-of-official-announcement\/1100-6523894\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6476419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-games-epic-games-store\/1100-6476419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-quickly-level-up-your-power-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape-and-how-it-works\/1100-6523930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6522790&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-the-final-shape-raid-launch-time-and-everything-we-know\/1100-6522790\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523783&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/preorder-evercade-alpha-street-fighter-and-mega-man-arcade-cabinets-at-amazon-before-they-sell-out\/1100-6523783\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Among us dev Innersloth starts new indie game fund Outersloth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/among-us-dev-innersloth-starts-new-indie-game-fund-outersloth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/among-us-dev-innersloth-starts-new-indie-game-fund-outersloth.893766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/among-us-dev-innersloth-starts-new-indie-game-fund-outersloth<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Six games already signed as studio aims to help fellow indies and create a "better, more sustainable industry"</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Innersloth, the studio behind hit social deduction game Among Us, has created a new indie games fund.</p>
<p>Entitled Outersloth, the project was announced on stage during today's Summer Game Fest Opening Showcase, where the studio said it wanted to share the success it has enjoyed with Among Us by funding other indie developers' games.</p>
<p>"There's been so many great indie games in recent years but it's also no secret that it's a rough time in the industry," said co-founder Forrest Willard. "Some devs don't really get the chance they deserve so we thought we could help out a bit."</p>
<p>Willard said it will offer devs "the kind of deals we would have wanted back in our less popular days."</p>
<p>On <a href="https://www.innersloth.com/outersloth/">the fund's website</a>, Innersloth emphasised that these deals are for funding only, with no plans to publish games or take IP rights.</p>
<p>Details on how much funding is available have yet to be revealed, but the site suggests it is most likely to fund projects between $50,000 and $2 million.</p>
<p>The fund is not open to virtual reality titles, blockchain or Web3 games, or titles that are already released or in Early Access.</p>
<p>Community manager Victoria Tran added: "This is our way of saying thank you to our crewmates, players and peers by helping some games and devs have the funding and freedom needed to ship their games. Then we all get to play them."</p>
<p>She added that Outersloth is a "passion project" for the team, and part of efforts towards shaping a "better, more sustainable industry."</p>
<p>The pair announced the first six games that have received funding, which are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mars First Logistics (Shape Shop)</li>
<li>Battle Suit Aces (Trinket Studios)</li>
<li>Mossfield Archives (Studio Any Percent)</li>
<li>One Btn Bosses (Midnight Munchies)</li>
<li>Rogue Eclipse (Huskrafts)</li>
<li>Project Dosa (Outerloop Games)</li>
</ul>
<p>Other studios have also received funding for unannounced games, including Strange Scaffold, Visai Games, and Coldblood Inc.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy's "no holds barred" approach to Alan Wake 2 expansions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/remedys-no-holds-barred-approach-to-alan-wake-2-expansions-1</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedys-no-holds-barred-approach-to-alan-wake-2-expansions.893763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/remedys-no-holds-barred-approach-to-alan-wake-2-expansions-1<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Developer talks about Night Springs expansion and the importance of collaboration during development</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>One of the biggest announcements to come out of Summer Game Fest today was Night Springs, the first expansion of Alan Wake 2.</p>
<p>Dropping tomorrow, Remedy also announced the release of photo mode in tandem with the DLC, as well as a physical edition of the game set to hit shelves later this year.</p>
<p>While the shadow drop is somewhat of a surprise, the expansion isn't. Night Springs was revealed alongside the second DLC, The Lake House, back when pre-orders were announced for Alan Wake 2. The first expansion will see players control three characters from Remedy's connected universe within narratives framed as episodes from the in-game anthology series Night Springs.</p>
<p>Prior to the Summer Game Fest announcement, <em>GamesIndustry.biz </em>spoke with game director Kyle Rowley, lead writer Clay Murphy, level designer Nathalie Jankie, and communications director Thomas Puha.</p>
<p>Puha says Remedy decided to time the release of Night Springs around Summer Game Fest because the event "is a huge platform for bringing the news to a massive audience." But, he also says it was for the benefit of fans.</p>
<p>"Marketing campaigns tend to be shorter these days, and it's good to try and do things differently," he explains.</p>
<blockquote>"We've always taken a very long view at Remedy. The first couple of months [are not] focused on sales; it's the next three years at least"<cite>Thomas Puha</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>"So, together with our publisher Epic, we figured this time around we would announce the expansion right before it's released so fans have a short wait to get their hands on it."</p>
<p>Promotion for Night Springs has been relatively short compared to the main game, but there have been hints on social media for the past week alluding to its release.</p>
<p>"There's always discussion about how much of the marketing budget should be saved for post-launch, but the thinking tends to be that, especially with a single-player game, the launch is the most important thing to get right, so that justifies the spend at launch," Puha notes.</p>
<p>Night Springs hasn't been in development for long, either. It started after the release of Alan Wake 2, but the concept was there before the game was even finished.</p>
<p>"We always wanted the idea of playing as multiple characters," Rowley says. "In the original concept of the base game, we wanted to have more playable characters than we ended up with. Night Springs as a concept came about as we were figuring that out. We parked it, then after we were done with the game, we wrote some more awesome, crazy stuff."</p>
<p>Murphy adds: "The writing process was very loose and fun – no rules, no holds barred. Just pure experimentation and trying to find the fun in each episode and push it as far as we could."</p>
<p>He also highlights the collaborative nature at Remedy, in that all departments working on the expansion were involved in shaping the narrative.</p>
<blockquote>"The writing process was very loose and fun – no rules, no holds barred. Just pure experimentation"<cite>Clay Murphy</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>"We're trying to have fun here and make it bizarre," he says. "So not every idea comes from the writers, the process definitely involves the team."</p>
<p>"I think everyone just sunk their teeth in and ran with it," Jankie adds. "It was really fun to see how every department [got involved]."</p>
<p>Rowley says that making this expansion was "a nice palate cleanser" for the team as well.</p>
<p>"Working on a horror game for five years is, you know, being stuck in The Dark Place with Alan – we wanted to do something a bit more freeform," he explains.</p>
<p>"There was no 'Is this too crazy?' during development. It was more like, 'Is this crazy enough?' That was the mindset coming into this, and it was a nice change of pace."</p>
<p>There's always a challenge in determining which parts of the team to utilise and balancing studio resources during production, but this changes significantly when making an expansion. Especially for Remedy, which has numerous projects in different stages of development <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/remedy-revenue-drops-222-to-339-million-in-2023">including Control 2 and the Max Payne remakes.</a></p>
<p>"That is a constant challenge when you work on multiple games at vastly various stages of production," Puha notes.</p>
<p>"We feel a lot better about it now than a few years ago. We've wrapped our heads around how to do this, but there is no denying that it's highly challenging to manage teams competing for developers and other resources. Having said that, we are all buzzing about the future roadmap of our games.</p>
<p>"We always planned for a dedicated post-launch team for Alan Wake 2," Puha continues.</p>
<p>"It's a small team, but everyone in it worked on Alan Wake 2, the tech and tools are ready, and creating the expansion is easier than the main game."</p>
<p>This isn't the first time Remedy has worked on DLC content.</p>
<p>Control saw two expansions following its release, as did the original Alan Wake in addition to the 2012 spin-off American Nightmare. Which, similarly, is framed as a Night Springs episode.</p>
<p>"American Nightmare was tonally quite different from the original game," Rowley notes. "In that same vein, we are creating a slightly different experience. From a gameplay perspective, we've shifted it for each episode to match the tone. We wanted to make the gameplay feel familiar, but also under a slightly different stylisation and context."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/NS_EP1_gameplay_04.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Each episode of Night Springs is set apart with different tones, stylistic choices, and game genres</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The time and resources spent making an expansion like Night Springs is a gamble, seeing as not all players of the base game will pick it up. But this is something that Remedy was aware of, Puha notes.</p>
<p>"It's about having realistic expectations, market data, and knowing who you are making the expansion for and what business purpose it serves," Puha explains.</p>
<p>He also notes the reception of Alan Wake 2, which has sustained solid momentum since launch through the release of its new game plus mode in December, various patches, developer streams, behind the scenes content, and fan interaction.</p>
<p>"The response was incredible," Puha says. "Alan Wake 2 was a very hard game to ship. But we always had the plan of once we ship it, there's still things we want to talk about in addition to this expansion, photo mode, and the second expansion that we're working on."</p>
<p>He continues: "We've always taken this very long view at Remedy. It's not like the first couple of months are focused on sales; it's the next three years at least – that's how we look at it.</p>
<p>"There's various bits and pieces we're doing that will hopefully keep the game out there. But it really resonated with people in an incredible way."</p>
<p>Jankie adds: "There's just something very infectious and motivating [about its reception]. I'm very grateful because it was received well and now it feels like, 'Yay, we can do more of this.' It feels really great."</p>
<blockquote>"There was no 'Is this too crazy?' during development. It was more like, 'Is this crazy enough?'"<cite>Kyle Rowley</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>Like the main game, Night Springs was developed with the fans in mind.</p>
<p>"There's quite a lot of fan service, I would say," Rowley notes. "We definitely wanted to make sure that we were using characters that players who have played our games would resonate with and would want to play as again in some instances."</p>
<p>"It's nostalgic for us, looking at what fans want," Murphy adds.</p>
<p>"Remedy fans engage with our games in such a way that is really inspiring. To see what they interpret our games to mean or what they theorise we're going to do in the future."</p>
<p>Jankie mentions that the team often looked at what fans were talking about online, and what they wanted to see in the expansions.</p>
<p>"That was a really nice motivator to have," she says. "We could see we were on the right track and we were doing something that hopefully they would appreciate and tap into as we have."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keighley declares devs have more ways than ever to be 'sustainable' at Summer Game Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/keighley-declares-devs-have-more-ways-than-ever-to-be-sustainable-at-summer-game-fest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/keighley-declares-devs-have-more-ways-than-ever-to-be-sustainable-at-summer-game-fest.893760/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/keighley-declares-devs-have-more-ways-than-ever-to-be-sustainable-at-summer-game-fest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via The Game Awards.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's Friday night and another Summer Game Fest has come and gone. This year, Geoff Keighley wowed players with trailers that we now know run in the cost of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-summer-games-fest-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-550k">hundreds of thousands of dollars</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. But developers who ponied up probably got their money's worth, what with the high-value production effort and the millions of viewers following along on YouTube and Twitch.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Once you're done calculating the total revenue, you no doubt are interested in the major trends that ran through Keighley's megapromo telethon. For the first time since the game industry's layoff spree beginning in 2023, he acknowledged the ongoing layoffs—before immediately pivoting to praising the power of "newer, smaller creators," pointing to a list of 2024's most popular new games on Steam (which included games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro, Hades II, and Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) as a sign of the industry's health.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's a reminder that developers need to treat their developers right, because there are so many paths to sustainability and success," he boasted.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sony's unveiling of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>LEGO Horizon Adventures</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, as a day-one cross-platform release on PC, Steam, and PS5 shone a spotlight on how PC and Nintendo Switch are drawing more interest from Microsoft and PlayStation, who have spent the last year lowering their platform-exclusive walls.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Firaxis' announcement that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sid Meier's Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would launch on consoles the same day as PC also showed publishers' hunger to get games in front of as many players as possible as soon as possible.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Innersloth also showed up to directly acknowledge the industry's woes and unveil a new publishing label called "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/innersloth-announces-outersloth-new-indie-publishing-label">Outersloth</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">," a moment that showed how much Summer Game Fest—and the industry—need indie devs to push themselves forward.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="What were the biggest Summer Game Fest announcements?">What were the biggest Summer Game Fest announcements?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Despite taking place in the week that would normally host the now-deceased E3, the broadcast contained few high-profile announcements of new games. That said, studios like Sony used the show to show off a Horizon spinoff, and Take-Two unveiled the next entry in the Side Meier's Civilization series.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The remainder of the broadcast showcased an impressive roster of indie and double-A games. Blumhouse Games and new publisher Outersloth Games were given time to show unveil their first slates of published titles, putting a bit more space between promotions for already-announced titles.</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>LEGO Horizon Adventures </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Guerilla Games/Studio Gobo</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>No Room in Hell 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Torn Banner Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Harry Potter</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Quidditch Champions</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Unbroken Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cuffbust</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Two Star Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars Outlaws</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Ubisoft</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sid Meier's Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Firaxis Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Black Myth Wukong</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Game Science</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metaphor RE Fantazio </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Atlus</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Batman: Arkham Shadow</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Camouflaj</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">King of Fighters characters appearing in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Street Fighter VI </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Capcom</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>DRAGONBALL: Sparking! ZERO </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Bandai Namco</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Delta Force Hawk Ops</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Team Jade</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - SNK</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mecha Break</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Amazing Seasun</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Crisol Theater of Idols</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Vermila Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grave Seasons - </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Perfect Garbage</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fear the Spotlight</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Cozy Game Pals</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Simulation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Playmestudio</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mighty Morphin' Power Rangers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>- Rita's Rewind</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Digital Eclipse</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deer &amp; Boy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Lifeline Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Warhorse Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Slitterhead</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Bokeh Game Studio</span></p></div></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unknown9 Awakening</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Reflector</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The First Descendant </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Nexon</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mars First Logistics - </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Shape Shop</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Trinket Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Mossfield Archives - </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Anypercent Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Project Dosa </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Outerloop Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sonic X Shadow Generations</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Sega</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battle Aces </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Uncut Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A new season of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Finals </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Embark Studios</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Downloadable content for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Alan Wake II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> titled </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Night Springs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Remedy</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>New World Aeternum</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Amazon Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Honkai Star Rail</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - HoYoGames</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dark and Darker -</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> IronMace Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kinitsu-Gami Path of the Goddess </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">- Capcom</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A new update for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Palworld</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Pocketpair</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A console debut for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Valorant</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Riot Games</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> - Capcom]</span></p></div></li><li></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a lineup that captures the conundrum facing the industry at this moment. The games above all look incredible. But that won't stop the tough economic conditions putting many developers out of work.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon MMO New World Coming To Consoles With Major Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/amazon-mmo-new-world-coming-to-consoles-with-major-updates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-mmo-new-world-coming-to-consoles-with-major-updates.893757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/amazon-mmo-new-world-coming-to-consoles-with-major-updates<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><span><span>Announced during today’s Summer Game Fest broadcast, Amazon Games is bringing its action role-playing MMO, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/new-world">New World</a>, to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC via an enhanced cross-play-enabled version. Debuting on October 15, 2024, New World: Aeternum features the entire base game and its previous updates while revamping the story, dialogue, and leveling experience. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Additionally, the pseudo-expansion introduces new content like a large-scale PvP zone, 10-player raid, new classes, end-game solo challenges, updated control schemes, and new gear, of course.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Amazon has confirmed to </span></span><span><span>Game Informer</span></span><span><span> that future updates will arrive day-and-date for PC and console players. New users will be able to purchase New World: Aeternum’s Standard Edition for $59.99 or the Deluxe Edition for $79.99, while PC players who own the Rise of the Angry Earth DLC will receive a free upgrade.&nbsp;</span></span></p>

<p><strong>Check out the New World: Aeternum announcement trailer below</strong>:</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c5HrkNz1pSU" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p><span><span>Stay up to date on all of the big announcements from Summer Game Fest <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/search?keyword=Summer+Game+Fest&amp;type=All&amp;items_per_page=20&amp;sort_bef_combine=created_DESC">right here.</a></span></span></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get A New Look At Phantom Blade Zero In New Gameplay Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/get-a-new-look-at-phantom-blade-zero-in-new-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-a-new-look-at-phantom-blade-zero-in-new-gameplay-trailer.893751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/get-a-new-look-at-phantom-blade-zero-in-new-gameplay-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>Developer S-Game has released a new trailer for its upcoming action game, Phantom Blade Zero, which features plenty of gorgeous (and gory) fast-paced action. Though we still haven't received a release date, the game is looking great, and it will be playable at Summer Game Fest's Play Days this weekend, so we could soon hear how it feels to actually play.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It will also be playable at a few other locations this year, including Gamescom in August and Tokyo Game Show this September.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Check out the latest look at Phantom Blade Zero gameplay in the trailer below</strong>:&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b68WE-eZ-Cc" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Revealed as a new entry in the Phantom Blade series during a PlayStation Showcase last year, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/phantom-blade-zero">Phantom Blade Zero</a> is inspired by Chinese martial arts and steampunk. In it, you control the Dark Raider, who is out for revenge against a group called "The Order."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Watch the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/playstation-showcase/2023/05/24/phantom-blade-0-is-an-upcoming-ps5-action-rpg">Phantom Blade Zero reveal trailer</a> from last year here.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Are you excited for Phantom Blade Zero? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supernatural Action Strategy Game Kunitsu-Gami: Path Of The Goddess Launches In July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/supernatural-action-strategy-game-kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-launches-in</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/supernatural-action-strategy-game-kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-launches-in-july.893745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/supernatural-action-strategy-game-kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-launches-in<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>Capcom's upcoming action strategy game&nbsp;Kunitsu-Gami: Path Of The Goddess has a new trailer and, perhaps more importantly, a release date. The game will be released on July 19.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The new trailer offers a brief highlight real of the fantastical action game, which sees players prepare a Japanese village by day for an otherworldly assault by demons at night. The game blends stylish action with real-time strategy elements as you'll take on massive, bizarre creatures to cleanse the mountain of defilement.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZuVS2SpFQz4" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>You watch a more <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/xbox-partner-preview/2024/03/06/capcoms-kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-gets-first-extended">in-depth trailer</a> from March's Xbox Partner Showcase.&nbsp;Kunitsu-Gami: Path Of The Goddess is coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.&nbsp;</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate: 'Pre-Pre-Alpha' Gameplay Revealed In New Trailer, Console Playtesting This Fall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/skate-pre-pre-alpha-gameplay-revealed-in-new-trailer-console-playtesting-this</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-pre-pre-alpha-gameplay-revealed-in-new-trailer-console-playtesting-this-fall.893742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/skate-pre-pre-alpha-gameplay-revealed-in-new-trailer-console-playtesting-this<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Publisher EA and developer Full Circle have released a new trailer for their long-in-development Skate, the fourth mainline entry in the Skate series and the first in more than a decade. Revealed during today's Summer Game Fest 2024 showcase, EA announced with the trailer that "console playtesting" for the game will begin this fall; there's still no release date for the game, though.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the trailer, which begins with a live-action segment starring comedian Tim Robinson (who actually shreds in real life, by the way), we see him as an employee of the fictional M-Corp before transitioning to a look at pre-pre-alpha gameplay of Skate. The gameplay admittedly looks early, but players can check it out on console this fall when "console playtesting" begins.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Check it out in the Skate. trailer for yourself below</strong>:&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cCM3EfAz8FY" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>EA announced in 2020 that it was working on a new Skate game, and we later learned it will be called "Skate." instead of Skate 4 like many presumed. We also learned in 2022 that <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/07/15/the-new-skate-will-be-a-free-to-play-title">it will be a free-to-play title as well</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2021/01/27/meet-full-circle-the-new-studio-making-the-next-skate">read this behind-the-scenes look at Ful Circle</a>, the newcomer studio making Skate, and then check out this <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/06/30/take-an-early-look-at-skates-fluid-movements-and-awesome-bails">early look at Skate's fluid movements and awesome bails</a> after that.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><i>What do you think of Skate's formal reveal? Let us know in the comments below!</i></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valorant For PlayStation And Xbox Coming Later This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/valorant-for-playstation-and-xbox-coming-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-for-playstation-and-xbox-coming-later-this-year.893739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2024/2024/06/07/valorant-for-playstation-and-xbox-coming-later-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>During the 2024 Summer Game Fest showcase, Riot Games announced that its popular free-to-play hero shooter, Valorant, will be coming to consoles sometime this year. Earlier this week, I had a chance to visit Riot Games, where I not only <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="71281df4-9e3e-44df-aa9c-adfbfd5f5b14" href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2024/06/04/finding-the-fun-fast">played its upcoming 2D fighting game set in the League of Legends universe, 2XKO</a>, but also learned all about Valorant for consoles and even got my hands on the upcoming Xbox Series X version.</p>

<p>When creating the console version of Valorant, Riot Games relied on one of the mantras that fueled its PC version: "Creativity Meets Clutch." This means the studio wants to retain the kind of experience where the game has a strong tactical foundation that caters to the competitive crowd. In speaking with production director Arnar Gylfason, he tells me that even as the team opens the game up to new demographics through the console release, the more dedicated and competitive crowds will always be Riot's main priority with Valorant.</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="13abce04-3a4e-4c05-9eb4-8a0b6c7c43b9" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>Through the transition to consoles, Valorant will retain the same anti-cheat and network performance found on the PC version, and Riot Games has renewed its commitment to growing with the players. Riot says it has no end date in mind for Valorant, so it will continue to add content for as long as the player base craves it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On consoles, Valorant will deliver the same wide-ranging customization and cadence of updates players have grown accustomed to on the PC version, but Riot insists it is not a straight port. However, despite PC having several years of a headstart, Riot says there is no flagship platform for Valorant, and players can enjoy cross-progression. This means that no matter where you play, your money, unlocks, loadouts, and more carry over from platform to platform. Valorant on consoles also has crossplay, but only with the other consoles; PC players can only play with other PC players to maintain competitive integrity since mouse and keyboard controls grant various advantages, particularly with first-person shooters.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the smooth controls on Xbox Series X. The development team has done an excellent job translating the controls from mouse and keyboard to gamepad, which Riot admits was one of the biggest hurdles in bringing its hero shooter to consoles.</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="380634f0-f7cb-4809-9f92-50fb6c75d186" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>"That was the big question to solve for on bringing the game to a console audience: How do we allow you the same range of control that you are used to on a PC from a keyboard and mouse to a controller?" Gylfason says. "With a controller, you just don't have the same input variability, and so we had to solve that for the console player. Our approach to solving that is what we call Focus Mode. So, when you're hip-firing and moving and shooting normally, you want to have your sensitivity way up so that you're very quickly looking around, scoping around, and understanding your environment. And then, when you engage Focus Mode, which is engaging your left trigger, have your sensitivity significantly lower so that you can fine-tune that aim and hit that headshot that you wanted or take that engagement that you wanted to take. While you don't have the same scale of variability as you have on PC, you at least have some scale of variability."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Focus Mode feels good in action, and since the last time I played Valorant was around its 2020 launch, it's great to see how much additional content has been added to the game since then. Alternating between the tactical Swiftplay mode and the all-out fun Team Deathmatch for my hours of hands-on time, I had an absolute blast. Since I'm much more of a console gamer than a PC gamer, I'm excited to dive into the Valorant competition in earnest when it finally comes out sometime later this year.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battle Aces is a fast-paced RTS featuring quick matches]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/battle-aces-is-a-fast-paced-rts-featuring-quick-matches/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=battle-aces-is-a-fast-paced-rts-featuring-quick-matches</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battle-aces-is-a-fast-paced-rts-featuring-quick-matches.893733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/battle-aces-is-a-fast-paced-rts-featuring-quick-matches/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=battle-aces-is-a-fast-paced-rts-featuring-quick-matches<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="306" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Developer Uncapped Games announced its upcoming new action RTS PC game, <em>Battle Aces,</em> during the Summer Game Fest 2024. The game takes place during the 26th century where humanity struggles and battles over land and resources. A closed beta for <em>Battle Aces</em> begins later this month and has sign-ups open now.</p> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Uncapped Games</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="247" data-current-count="547" data-injectable="true"><em>Battle Aces</em> is the debut title for Uncapped Games, a team comprised of developers with RTS-specific experience. In <em>Battle Aces</em>, players will create a preset loadout of units and bases of over 50 units before dropping into quick fast-paced battles.</p>
 <p data-characters="374" data-current-count="374" data-injectable="false">Due to its quicker games, <em>Battle Aces</em> streamlines the systems behind typical RTS features like resource gathering, unit spawning, and base expansion. Featuring both 1v1 and 2v2 matches, both options aim to have the match over in ten minutes or less due to more streamlined systems such as being able to switch between creating and controlling armies by pushing a single key.</p> <p data-characters="108" data-current-count="482" data-injectable="false"><em>Battle Aces</em> does not yet have a release window but will be holding a closed beta test later this year on PC.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld adds a new island, Pals, and more in just a few weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/palworld-adds-a-new-island-pals-and-more-in-just-a-few-weeks/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=palworld-adds-a-new-island-pals-and-more-in-just-a-few-weeks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-adds-a-new-island-pals-and-more-in-just-a-few-weeks.893730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/palworld-adds-a-new-island-pals-and-more-in-just-a-few-weeks/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=palworld-adds-a-new-island-pals-and-more-in-just-a-few-weeks<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="321" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Pocketpair’s <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/palworld-early-access-impressions-pc-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Palworld</a></em> took the world by storm when it was initially released in early access last year. Now, the game is getting its first expansion in the form of the Sakurajima Update. This update will finally add a new location for players to explore, as well as a host of other highly-anticipated new features. </p> <p data-characters="472" data-current-count="472" data-injectable="true">The Sakurajima Update will hit <em>Palworld</em> on <strong>June 27, 2024</strong>. In addition to the new island, presumably called Sakurajima, the update brings new Pals into the fray, a new raid, a higher level cap and new structures for Pals, and even an oil rig Stronghold for players to test their combat skills in. It takes everything that was already great in the game and improves upon it, giving us just a little bit more of what we need to see us through the next 100 hours of playtime. </p>
 <h2 id="h-palworld-s-sakurajima-update-finally-adds-dedicated-xbox-servers-and-so-much-more" data-injectable="false"><em>Palworld’s</em> Sakurajima Update finally adds dedicated Xbox servers and so much more</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Palworld | Sakurajima Update Trailer | Palnews | Pocketpair  | Summer Game Fest 2024" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fKzLdPZr2Fk?feature=oembed&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="423" data-current-count="723" data-injectable="true">One of the biggest issues I’ve had with <em>Palworld</em> since its release is that Xbox servers just aren’t as stable as those for PC players. Well, the Sakurajima Update finally adds dedicated Xbox servers for players like me, so it doesn’t matter how many players are hammering the PC ones. I’ll still probably be able to enjoy the game and get my Pals crafting everything I need whenever I want them to. </p>
 <p data-characters="416" data-current-count="416" data-injectable="true">It’s impossible to say what the new Pals are called or what their abilities might be. I’ve got a soft spot for the mimic-like chest puppy, the disappearing ghoul, and the mushroom-headed Pals myself. None of them look massively threatening, which is great, but possibly bad news for me if I want to tackle the colossal new raid boss or the additional faction boss who will also be added with the update. </p>
 <p data-characters="381" data-current-count="381" data-injectable="false">With this update, <em>Palworld</em> manages to retain its identity and actually dig a little deeper into it. The juxtaposition of such a beautiful island and new Pals is reminiscent of <em>Pokemon Gold and Silver</em>, but the darkness of this world is still very much present through those hiding away in the oil rig and the factions who definitely don’t want what’s best for our Pals. </p> <p data-characters="344" data-current-count="725" data-injectable="false">When it releases in a few weeks, the Sakurajima Update will almost certainly cause its fair share of error and server outages. So it’s probably worth diving into the game now unless you’re playing <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/hands-on-elden-ring-took-me-to-the-shadow-realm-in-its-expansion-and-it-ruled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shadow of the Erdtree</a></em>, so you can sort your base out, remember how the game works, and be ready for the update on the day it launches. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valorant coming to Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5, beta starts next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/valorant-coming-to-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-beta-starts-next-week/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=valorant-coming-to-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-beta-starts-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-coming-to-xbox-series-x-s-and-playstation-5-beta-starts-next-week.893727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/valorant-coming-to-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-beta-starts-next-week/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=valorant-coming-to-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-beta-starts-next-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="417" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Riot Games announced during 2024 Summer Game Fest that its popular free-to-play 5v5 FPS <em>Valorant</em>will finally be coming to consoles. According to Riot, the console versions of <em>Valorant</em> features custom-built gameplay in order to uphold the competitive gameplay it is known for. A beta will be available to global players on both platforms soon, with a more limited beta kicking off for certain regions on June 14, 2024.</p> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Clove Official Gameplay Reveal // VALORANT" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mdVGu6Cxtj0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <h2 id="h-world-s-most-popular-shooter-is-about-to-get-bigger" data-injectable="false">World’s most popular shooter is about to get bigger</h2> <p data-characters="299" data-current-count="599" data-injectable="true">Despite already being the most-played FPS in the world, <em>Valorant</em> is about to get a lot bigger by coming to consoles. Even though the PC player base is massive, there are still a ton of potential players who simply don’t like playing with mouse and keyboard or don’t have a PC to play on.</p>
 <p data-characters="416" data-current-count="416" data-injectable="true">Before you worry about console players with aim assist taking over your lobbies—a problem other cross-platform FPS titles usually suffers from—PC and console will not have cross-play available. However, <em>Valorant</em> accounts will share a connected inventory and gameplay progression across all platforms, meaning you can access your cosmetics and other unlockables regardless of the platform you’re playing on.</p>
 <blockquote data-current-count="609" data-injectable="true"> <p>“When exploring whether to bring&nbsp;<em>Valorant </em>to additional platforms, we knew we had to be able to offer the same uncompromising, competitive experience that we’ve provided to PC players for years: a precise, team-based, tactical shooter. We were adamant that&nbsp;<em>Valorant’s </em>core, competitive gameplay must feel natural on a controller; and – if we couldn’t deliver on that gameplay promise – we had to be prepared to walk away from it. We hope we nailed it, but ultimately, our players will have the final say.”</p> <cite>– Arnar Gylfason, Production Director of <em>Valorant</em> at Riot Games</cite></blockquote>
 <p data-characters="243" data-current-count="243" data-injectable="false">The console versions of <em>Valorant</em> won’t be lagging behind, either. According to Riot, both PC and console versions of the games will receive simultaneous releases including live patch balances, new agents, maps, premium content, and more.</p> <p data-characters="213" data-current-count="456" data-injectable="false">A limited beta will kick off on June 14, 2024, on both Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5 for players in the USA, Canada, United Kingdom, and Japan. Those interested in participating can <a href="https://www.beta.playvalorant.com./" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">register for the beta here</a>.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, beta starts June 14]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/valorant-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs-beta-starts-june-14/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s-beta-starts-june-14.893709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/valorant-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs-beta-starts-june-14/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Riot Games has announced that its free to play 5v5 tactical shooter VALORANT is coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X|S. Furthermore, the developer confirmed that there will be a limited beta on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, starting from June 14th. The beta will initially be available in e United States, Canada, United Kingdom, Europe, and Japan, and those interested in playing should register on the official website, <a href="http://www.beta.playvalorant.com/">http://www.beta.playvalorant.com/</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Valorant - Cinematic Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SkmTMha31qc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><em>“When exploring whether to bring VALORANT to additional platforms, we knew we had to be able to offer the same uncompromising, competitive experience that we’ve provided to PC players for years: a precise, team-based, tactical shooter,”</em> said Arnar Gylfason, Production Director of VALORANT at Riot Games. <em>“We were adamant that VALORANT’s core, competitive gameplay must feel natural on a controller; and if we couldn’t deliver on that gameplay promise we had to be prepared to walk away from it. We hope we nailed it, but ultimately, our players will have the final say.”</em></p>
<p>As mentioned in the quote above, the PS5 and Xbox Series X|S versions of VALORANT have been built with console specific features in mind. Riot Games has stated the console versions will have parity with the PC version of the game, including patches, new agents, new maps, and additional premium content.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/05/21/valorant-is-getting-a-full-release-in-june/">VALORANT was first fully released in June 2020 for PC.</a> The game broke records on Twitch when it entered into closed beta back in April 2020, with 1.7 million concurrent viewers, however, a lot of this would have been down to Riot Games using Twitch as a direct marketing tactic at the time. The only way to gain access to the beta was to watch a stream of someone else playing the game and get a code, something that was taken away with the full release of VALORANT.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess release date is July 19]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-release-date-is-july-19/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-release-date-is-july-19.893703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-release-date-is-july-19/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Capcom has confirmed the release its intriguing action strategy game Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess, stating it will be available from July 19th. The game is coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S and PC.</p>
<p><iframe title="Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess - &quot;Soh&quot; Gameplay Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZuVS2SpFQz4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess, the sacred Mt. Kafuku has been ruined by its inhabitants, creating a rift between the human and spirit realms. The Seethe, a corrupting force, emerge from this rift, further tainting the world, so to counteract this, the Spirit Stone Maiden must conduct a cleansing ritual, but she requires a protector and guide to achieve her mission and repel the Seethe once again. The complication arises when the 12 masks, which grant powers to their bearers, are stolen. Soh, the player’s character, and Yoshiro, the maiden, must collaborate to expel the Seethe from the villages.</p>
<p>Players don’t just control Soh; they can form alliances with villagers and bring them into combat. Daytime is for preparation: purifying the village, saving villagers to enlist their aid, and fixing devices for a tactical edge. At night, the focus shifts to defending the Maiden and the village from malevolent spirits, empowering villagers with masks for the fight. The gameplay is a fusion of real-time strategy and action.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZuVS2SpFQz4">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New World: Aeternum launches October 15th for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/new-world-aeternum-launches-october-15th-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-world-aeternum-launches-october-15th-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s.893700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/new-world-aeternum-launches-october-15th-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Amazon Games has announced that it is bring New World to PS5 and Xbox Series X|S under the name New World: Aeternum. The release date is October 15th. New World: Aeternum will include the full base game of New World along with the Rise of the Angry Earth, but that is not all as Amazon Games aims to make changes and add more content for all New World players on PC and consoles. Amazon has also stated that New World: Aeternum will have full parity with the PC version of New World.</p>
<p><iframe title="New World: Aeternum - Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6xNztUFRssM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>New World: Aeternum offers the flexibility to play the action RPG either solo or in groups, with group sizes that vary based on the different activities&nbsp; Players can complete the entire game campaign on their own and will also have access to solo end-game trials. For those who want a more social experience, it’s possible to form open-world groups of up to five, compete in 3 vs 3 arenas, or engage in wars with 50 players. Additionally, players can join raids, with Aeternum’s first raid accommodating up to ten players. Corruption breaches will also emerge in the world, which can be tackled by groups of 5 to 20 players.</p>
<p>New World: Aeternum will also be adding preset archetype character builds, giving people the option to choose a playstyle early on, focusing on proficiency in specific abilities, such as magic. The full character builder will be there for those who want to customise every element of their character too. Both approaches will still allow players to experiment with all the skills in the game, and change their style if they wish to.</p>
<p><em><span>“New World: Aeternum</span><span> is the culmination of years of focused development combined with input from the dedicated community of players who’ve already carved a path in the original </span><span>New World </span></em><span><em>on PC,”</em> said Christoph Hartmann, Vice President, Amazon Games. <em>“Listening to player feedback is fundamental to how we make games, and we know&nbsp;</em></span><em><span>New World: Aeternum</span><span>&nbsp;delivers on the promise of a fresh and compelling&nbsp;</span><span>New World</span><span>&nbsp;experience that players can enjoy together across platforms.”</span></em></p>

<p><span>Those who choose pre-order New World: Aeternum on PS5 or Xbox Series X|S, a well as all PC players who log in to </span><span>New World</span><span> from now through to October 14th, will receive the Azoth Stalker wolf mount. The base version of New World: Aeternum is priced at $59.99, while the Deluxe Edition is $79.99 This Deluxe Edition will include a a Bear mount and armour skin.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>