<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 13:10:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Is a Million Seller on Launch Day]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metaphor-refantazio-becomes-million-seller-on-launch-day/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-is-a-million-seller-on-launch-day.1007148/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/metaphor-refantazio-becomes-million-seller-on-launch-day/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio has just launched<span>, and Atlus has already&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/stud_zero/status/1844665951431930116" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed that</a> its cumulative global sales have surpassed one million units. Even <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2679460/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Steam</a>, it's making record numbers compared to the Persona franchise when it comes to concurrent users. It's certainly a great result for a new IP, even though the Persona team had many</span>&nbsp;long-standing fans who were looking forward to playing this new title.</p>
<p>In this fantasy world, the protagonist (Will) travels with his fairy companion, Gallica, to lift the curse from the kingdom's lost prince. Players may awaken the magical "Archetype" powers that lie dormant within their character's heart; awakening to an Archetype unlocks the power to channel and combine the abilities of unique professions. Throughout the adventure, they will strengthen their bonds and level up their party to defeat mighty foes and discover the true nature of the kingdom.</p>
<p>In Wccftech's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metaphor-refantazio-persona-non-grata/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review</a>, Kai Tatsumoto rated Metaphor: ReFantazio 9/10, although he noted it's essentially Persona 6 in all but name:</p>
<p><em>No matter how much I engaged with the core fundamentals of Metaphor: ReFantazio, I couldn’t escape the feeling that this was largely Persona 6 by another name rather than some new IP that could stand on its own merits. That isn’t to say that Hashino’s team hasn’t created another stylish JRPG with broad appeal, but the premise that Metaphor: ReFantazio is a brand-new fantasy is dead. If the Persona series left you wanting more, Metaphor: ReFantazio certainly is a tale worth experiencing for yourself.</em></p>
<p>The Atlus team feels a bit different, however. In an interview <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JoG2zH-Pl6o" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with the Official Xbox Podcast</a>, Director Katsura Hashino explained how this new game is a departure from the Persona franchise:</p>
<p><em>We really had ideas that we wanted to put in this game that we couldn't put into other games. For example, the Persona series is set in the real world. That means the story we want to tell becomes slightly limited to the place that we're building the story within.</em></p>
<p><em>It also means it's a little bit easier for us to work with because we know the place, we have that baseline to work from. But once again, it does limit our options. Whereas in an entirely new fantasy world that we create, we have the freedom to explore all these ideas and things that we weren't able to do in the past. In the Persona series, the story itself is based around a single location where all the characters hang out. The world that they're living in doesn't change, but the way that they perceive it changes.&nbsp; </em><em>That's one of the major parts of the Persona series that's really interesting in its own way. </em></p>
<p><em>But in Metaphor: ReFantazio, we don't really have that one place where everybody is based out of. We don't have that single location to work with. In a way, we do have one country that the characters are traveling through, so they do have that connection to a country instead of a specific place. But the scale is much larger, so you get the chance to see a broader perspective.</em></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox to Make Games Playable and Purchasable Via Android App in November]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-android-app-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-to-make-games-playable-and-purchasable-via-android-app-in-november.1007145/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-android-app-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Xbox has announced that come November, you'll be able to buy and play Xbox games directly within the Android app thanks to a recent court ruling against Android owner Google.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/BondSarah_Bond/status/1844506029599707255" rel="noopener" target="_blank">message on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Xbox president Sarah Bond says that a recent court decision ruling that Google <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-google-victory-play-store">must open up its Play Store</a> to third-party apps will "allow more choice and flexibility".</p>
<p>The ruling came as part of a lawsuit brought by Epic against Google, with the former alleging that the latter's dominance of the mobile sphere (alongside that of Apple, against whom Epic <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-games-apple-lawsuit-escalates-as-developer-accounts-are-terminated">also brought a lawsuit</a>) constitutes an illegal monopoly, a position with which the court clearly agreed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/xbox-app-android-purchases-store.jpg?itok=1dDkHXC0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/xbox-app-android-purchases-store.jpg?itok=lBk_0oKE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll soon be able to buy games directly from the Xbox app.</figcaption></figure><p>Bond says the decision to incorporate purchases directly into the Xbox Android app is born of Xbox's mission to "allow more players to play on more devices".</p>
<p>Right now, there's no news on whether or not this will be possible on the Apple App Store version of the app; Bond only mentions Android, and since Apple <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/28/24158911/apple-v-epic-evidentiary-hearing-app-store-payments" rel="noopener" target="_blank">wasn't ordered by courts</a> to open up its App Store to third-party storefronts, the iOS situation is unlikely to change anytime soon.</p>
<p>The Epic-Google situation began back in 2020, when Epic decided to allow players to purchase&nbsp;<em>Fortnite</em>'s V-Bucks currency on mobile using a proprietary payment method instead of going through Apple and Google's respective payment processes.</p>
<p>This prompted both <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-sues-google-over-fortnites-removal-from-play-store">Google</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fortnite-apple-store-version-removed-for-violating-app-store-guidelines">Apple</a> to remove the game from their mobile storefronts, a decision over which Epic quickly sued both companies, hoping to prove that Google and Apple's mobile dominance constituted a duopoly.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-games-store-mobile.jpg?itok=yW-O6qeM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-games-store-mobile.jpg?itok=Qtm86sb5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Microsoft is benefiting from a court decision made in Epic's favor.</figcaption></figure><p>In 2020, close to when Epic first filed both of its lawsuits, Microsoft <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-files-statement-in-support-of-epic-against-apple">filed a statement in favor</a> of the&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>developer, although said statement was in support of an injunction adjacent to the case rather than the main lawsuit itself.</p>
<p>It looks like Epic has arguably repaid Microsoft in kind for that support today, whether it intended to or not. You'll be able to buy and play Xbox games directly through the Xbox Android app starting in November this year, although we don't have a concrete date for that change yet.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honkai: Star Rail version 2.6 update ‘Annals of Pinecany’s Mappou Age’ launches October 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/honkai-star-rail-version-2-6-update-annals-of-pinecanys-mappou-age-launches-october-23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/honkai-star-rail-version-2-6-update-%E2%80%98annals-of-pinecany%E2%80%99s-mappou-age%E2%80%99-launches-october-23.1007142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/honkai-star-rail-version-2-6-update-annals-of-pinecanys-mappou-age-launches-october-23<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Journey back to Penacony and visit the prestigious Paperfold University.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The version 2.6 update for <em><a title="Games > Honkai: Star Rail [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a></em>, dubbed “Annals of Pinecany’s Mappou Age,” will launch on October 23, developer <a title="Companies > miHoYo [175 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> announced. <span id="more-920793"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via miHoYo:</p><blockquote><p>This update will take Trailblazers to Penacony’s prestigious Paperfold University, which is buzzing with excitement for a new semester and its anniversary celebrations. Players will also get their hands on the newest 5-star character, Rappa, a daring Galaxy Ranger. On top of that, the highly anticipated Simulated Universe DLC will also receive a massive and thrilling update.</p><p>As the recent Xianzhou adventure concludes, players will journey back to Penacony and visit its Paperfold University, a prestigious cosmic institution bustling with activity as it prepares for a new semester and its anniversary celebrations. The campus is alive with clubs recruiting new members, and music performances fill the air. For this special occasion, the university is hosting an exclusive academic seminar, and as notable figures and stakeholders in Penacony, the crew of the Astral Express has been invited as distinguished guests to partake in the festivities. In the Version 2.6 Trailblaze Continuance mission, Banana Outrage: Battles Without Ninja and Humanity, the Trailblazer will step into Paperfold University as an auditing student, fully immersing in the joys of campus life. Alongside peers like March 7th and Dan Heng, Trailblazers will not only delve into the rigors of academic pursuits but also cultivate meaningful relationships, enriching this one-of-a-kind scholastic adventure.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_920794"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>As Trailblazers immerse themselves in campus life, they’ll be able to meet a powerful new 5-star ally—Rappa, a courageous and unique character ready to join the battlefield. Rappa calls herself a ninja, attributing everything to the art of “ninjutsu.” Rappa recites ninja mantras, creates Dazzling Ninja Seals, and follows the Way of the Ninja through ninja scrolls, blending rap, graffiti, and comics. With strict self-discipline, she travels the stars upholding justice. As a Galaxy Ranger, Rappa is on a relentless mission to hunt down her nemesis, Evil Ninja Osaru, across the Cosmos. In battle, after unleashing her Ultimate, she will enter Sealform and unleash Ningu: Demonbane Petalblade in a special first-person view. During the attacks of Ningu: Demonbane Petalblade, Rappa is able to deal damage to groups of enemies efficiently, and can even reduce the Toughness of enemies without Imaginary Weakness. This version will bring a wave of exciting events. In “Sound Hunt Ninjutsu Inscription,” Trailblazers will be invited as a guest and step in as the band manager for the Dreamlight Anniversary music party, teaming up with Rappa and leading the band’s electrifying performances in the music party.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>That aside, the limited 5-star characters Dan Heng • Imbibitor Lunae, Acheron, and Aventurine will make their return to the first and second halves of the Version 2.6 warp event, respectively. Their formidable support ensures they will remain powerful allies in your future adventures.</p><p>Meanwhile, Version 2.6 will introduce the much-anticipated third Simulated Universe DLC, following Swarm Disaster and Gold and Gears. This time, a massive void, the Unknowable Domain, has emerged within the Simulated Universe. It was initially simulating the Scholars’ Strife, a post-Second Emperor’s War event where scholarly factions battled for control of Emperor Rubert II’s legacy—the Scepter system. The Scepter, a cluster of inorganic bionic neurons, served as Rubert II’s external thinking unit with immense processing power. In this Simulated Universe update, Trailblazers will start by collecting Scepters and enhancing them with Components to strengthen their abilities. As the game progresses, players can strategically combine multiple Scepters and Components to unlock powerful synergies, eventually defeating a formidable final foe.</p></blockquote><p><em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [21,443 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://hsr.hoyoverse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">client download</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/honkai-star-rail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/honkai-star-rail/id1599719154" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.HoYoverse.hkrpgoversea&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>. A PlayStation 4 version is also planned.</p><p>Watch the version 2.6 trailer and special program below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/honkai-star-rail/october-11-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Version 2.6 Update “Annals of Pinecany’s Mappou Age” Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Version 2.6 Trailer — &quot;Annals of Pinecany's Mappou Age&quot; | Honkai: Star Rail" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vpZFQLWsJlo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【崩壊：スターレイル】 Ver.2.6PV 「毘乃昆尼末法筆録」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AvCqDPER400?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="2.6 버전 PV: 「패나곤니 말법세기」|〈붕괴: 스타레일〉" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ARGFTIWRKo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《崩坏：星穹铁道》2.6版本PV：「‍毗乃昆尼末法世记」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdtMm00rPAI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 2.6 Update “Annals of Pinecany’s Mappou Age” Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Honkai: Star Rail Version 2.6 &quot;Annals of Pinecany's Mappou Age&quot; Special Program" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TM_iWWS2_mo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『崩壊：スターレイル』Ver.2.6「毘乃昆尼末法筆録」予告番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lwMJkyJSdhE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="2.6 버전 「패나곤니 말법세기」 프리뷰 스페셜 프로그램| 〈붕괴: 스타레일〉" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BCnMH5eaE3E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《崩壞：星穹鐵道》2.6版本「毗乃昆尼末法世記」預覽特別" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KWfcUfNBbEU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Games Will Soon Be Sold In A New Place]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-will-soon-be-sold-in-a-new-place/1100-6527117/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-games-will-soon-be-sold-in-a-new-place.1007136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-will-soon-be-sold-in-a-new-place/1100-6527117/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527117">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In response to a recent court ruling, Microsoft has announced that Xbox fans will soon be able to purchase and play Xbox games directly from the Xbox app on Android.</p><p>A judge ruled in the Epic v. Google case this week that Google will be forced to allow rival third-party app stores to exist within Google Play. This effort, spearheaded by Epic's Tim Sweeney, means Microsoft will sell Xbox games directly to consumers beginning November 1.</p><p>The Fortnite studio convinced the court that Google made it very difficult for any rival store within Google Play to successfully compete in the market, and that's led to this decision being handed down. As <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/10/24267339/microsoft-xbox-android-purchase-games-us-court-ruling" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Verge</a> points out, it's unclear as to why Microsoft wasn't already selling Xbox games within its existing Android app. In any event, now that Microsoft can sell directly to consumers via its own store inside the Xbox app, it likely won't have to pay a fee to Google that it might have needed to otherwise.</p><p>Confirming the news, Xbox president Sarah Bond said, "Our mission is to allow more players to play on more devices."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/bondsarah_bond/status/1844506029599707255?s=46&amp;t=gp9HY1NQP1eeZxZoq0Xxsw" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">The court's ruling to open up Google´s mobile store in the US will allow more choice and flexibility. Our mission is to allow more players to play on more devices so we are thrilled to share that starting in November, players will be able to play and purchase Xbox games directly…</p>  — BondSarahBond (@BondSarah_Bond) <a href="https://twitter.com/BondSarah_Bond/status/1844506029599707255?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>It is presently unknown which specific games might be available for purchase within the Xbox app. Also worth noting is that this only applies to the US for now, and that Google is appealing the verdict.</p><p>Beyond selling games within the Xbox app for Android, Microsoft is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-pushing-ahead-with-plans-for-mobile-game-store-which-isnt-multiple-years-away/1100-6519625/" data-ref-id="1100-6519625">aiming to launch its own entire mobile game store at some point in the future.</a> In other Xbox mobile news, Microsoft recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-fixes-an-inexplicably-weird-choice-and-improves-game-updates/1100-6526732/" data-ref-id="1100-6526732">removed the dedicated Xbox Game Pass app and folded it into the main Xbox app.</a> Microsoft is also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-next-xbox-console-generation-could-include-a-handheld-report/1100-6526635/" data-ref-id="1100-6526635">reportedly considering including a handheld device as part of the next generation of Xbox consoles.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Metaphor: ReFantazio, Until Dawn & Cyberpunk 2077]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/11/what-we-played-metaphor-refantazio-until-dawn-cyberpunk-2077/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-metaphor-refantazio-until-dawn-cyberpunk-2077.1007124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/11/what-we-played-metaphor-refantazio-until-dawn-cyberpunk-2077/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s definitely been feeling chillier this past few days, which is handy if you needed an excuse to turn your beefy gaming PC on to heat up the room a bit. My gaming has generally been much lower-powered, with Super Mario Party Jamboree on the go for review, and a preview of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/mario-luigi-brothership-preview/">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a>, but I did enjoy a little time with Until Dawn over the weekend, and I might fire up the PC this coming weekend for something a little toastier.</p>
<p><strong>Nic B</strong> has continued to play <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>, delivering our review at the start of the week, “but I’ll just add this,” he says. “If there’s any scousers out there wondering where their representation was, whe ghot yhahhh!”</p>

<p>Working on a very different review has been <strong>Steve</strong>, whose week has been all about Silent Hill 2, “which is a superb updating of a true classic.” Expect to actually see our review of it sometime soon, but he’s also checked out a few early demos ahead of the next Steam Next Fest, which is coming next week… next.</p>
<p>After deciding that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/undisputed-review/">Undisputed</a> wasn’t enough pugilistic fun, <strong>Aran’s</strong> treated himself to Like a Dragon Gaiden: The Man Who Erased His Name. He’s also been playing Final Fantasy XVI and is at the stage where he’s done most of the hunts and is getting closer to the end of the game’s story.</p>


<p><strong>Jim’s</strong> been on his e-bike, as it were, for our review of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/parcel-corps-review/">Parcel Corps</a>. He’s also slipped back into Cyberpunk 2077. “I’ve gotten to the point where I’ve peeled back enough layers of Night City to realise I should be focusing on the main story and I’m determined to see the credits roll by the end of 2024. That would mean I’ve put a cross through Skyrim, New Vegas, and Cyberpunk – the 3 biggest games on my backlog.”</p>
<p>And then he’s loaded up Jade Empire on Steam Deck for something rather different.</p>
<p><strong>Tuffcub</strong> also has been playing the talking simulator that is the opening hours of Cyberpunk 2077 – “OMG SHUT UP AND LET ME PLAY THE F-ING GAME. WHY DO YOU TALK SO MUCH. OH YAY ANOTHER RIDE IN A CAR WHILE SOMEONE TALKS AT ME!” – and I don’t think he’ll be going back anytime soon. So it’s been Destiny 2 and our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/10/until-dawn-2024-review/">review of Until Dawn</a> for the rest of the week.</p>

<p>You just can’t keep <strong>Ade</strong> away from those sea shanties, as he’s been sailing the seas of Skull and Bones once again. “Season 3 has proven something of a game changer, with the game finally getting out of the way of itself and letting player’s play. If Ubisoft had launched with the game in this form it may have benefited from a more positive reception. Still, glad they are sticking with it.”</p>
<p>He’s also been helping out his son with Mario Odyssey as Cappy, and started a playthrough of Until Dawn with his partner.</p>
<p>Rounding out the week, <strong>Dom</strong> has had his usual bouts of Overwatch 2, but complimented that PvP staple with his own first few steps into the world of Metaphor: ReFantazio.</p>
<p>Now then, what have you played this week?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Feels Like Upgrading From an RTX 3060 to an RTX 4070; PSSR Can Improve Ray Tracing Quality]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-upgrading-rtx3060-to-4070/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-feels-like-upgrading-from-an-rtx-3060-to-an-rtx-4070-pssr-can-improve-ray-tracing-quality.1007121/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-upgrading-rtx3060-to-4070/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Upgrading from the base model to the PlayStation 5 Pro feels like upgrading from an RTX 3060 or 3060 Ti to an RTX 4070 GPU, allowing users to access visual features that were previously not available.</p>
<p>In a video shared recently on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DFClipsChannel">YouTube</a>, the tech experts at Digital Foundry talked about the upcoming mid-generation system from Sony after having had the chance to go hands-on with it, saying that in games like F1 24, where the developer put plenty of effort into the PS5 Pro update, upgrading from the base model feels indeed like upgrading the GPU in a gaming system. Even in other scenarios where the visual improvements aren't as massive, the PlayStation 5 Pro is definitely worth it for those players who play demanding console games in Performance Mode and wish to experience much better visual quality. On the other hand, the system doesn't offer a whole lot in terms of visual improvements over the base model's Quality mode, whose image quality is still fine at 4K resolution and standard viewing distance, although the system's better ray tracing capabilities could be enticing even for this category of players as well.</p>
<p>As such, even at its high price, the PlayStation 5 Pro can definitely be worth it. While there is an argument to be made about the console's price versus the price of a gaming PC with similar specs, the Sony console offers a completely hassle-free experience compared to a PC.</p>
<p>Digital Foundry also highlighted how important the introduction of the PlayStation 5 Pro's PSSR upscaler is. The upscaler not only makes the system a more significant upgrade than what the specs suggest, but it can also be used to improve the visual quality of ray tracing, although not in the same way as DLSS 3.5 Ray Reconstruction does, as Sony's upscaler cannot separate all inputs from the final color value of a scene like the NVIDIA technology does.</p>
<p><iframe title="PS5 Pro Hands-On Verdict: Is The Upgrade Worth The Price?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5zvZloAl3kE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Thankfully, it won't take much longer for players to see for themselves if the PlayStation 5 Pro is a worthy upgrade over the base model. The console launches in less than a month, on November 7th, worldwide.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Has Already Sold 1 Million Copies and It’s Only Been Out a Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-has-already-sold-1-million-copies-and-its-only-been-out-a-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-has-already-sold-1-million-copies-and-it%E2%80%99s-only-been-out-a-day.1007115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-has-already-sold-1-million-copies-and-its-only-been-out-a-day<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Atlus’ <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> has sold over one million copies as of its official release date, publisher Sega has announced.</p><p>That's enough to make Metaphor: ReFantazio the fastest-selling Atlus game of all time, breaking <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-becomes-fastest-selling-game-in-atlus-history-with-1-million-sales">Persona 3 Reload's record</a> of hitting one million in a week.</p><p>Metaphor: ReFantazio’s October 11 global release date has already seen the Persona-style game shoot up Steam’s most-played game list, with 42,992 concurrent players at the time of this article’s publication. That figure will no-doubt rise as we head into the weekend and fans in other regions get the chance to play.</p><p>The game also launched across PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S, but neither Sony nor Microsoft makes player numbers publicly available. It seems likely that one million sales figure will swell to two million sooner rather than later.</p><p>Atlus made the announcement alongside the release of an illustration from character designer Shigenori Soejima, below.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="ja" dir="ltr"><p>アトラス完全新作ファンタジーRPG『メタファー：リファンタジオ』 全世界累計販売本数100万本を突破！</p><p>"Metaphor: ReFantazio" has surpassed 1 million copies sold worldwide!</p><p>MetacriticによるメタスコアではPlayStation®5版:93点をはじめ各プラットフォームで高得点を獲得しました。 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%83%A1%E3%82%BF%E3%83%95%E3%82%A1%E3%83%BC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#メタファー</a> <a href="https://t.co/ruL9vpNxOT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ruL9vpNxOT</a></p></div>— セガ公式アカウント🦔 (@SEGA_OFFICIAL) <a href="https://twitter.com/SEGA_OFFICIAL/status/1844668055080910999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 11, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Metaphor: ReFantazio, from the creators of the hugely popular Persona 3, 4, and 5, is a role-playing game set in the United Kingdom of Euchronia, a medieval fantasy realm that mirrors the real world. You play an orphaned boy who journeys across the kingdom as part of a bid for the throne.</p><p>It has enjoyed pretty much universal acclaim, with IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-review">Metaphor: ReFantazio review</a> returning a 9/10. We said: “Refining the Atlus RPG formula of weaving tough turn-based combat into compelling social sim mechanics, Metaphor: ReFantazio doesn’t just send a powerful message across its political drama, it becomes a beautiful expression of the real impact storytelling can have on all of us.”</p><p>As part of its promotion for the game’s launch, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-competition-gives-metaphor-refantazio-fan-a-real-royal-title-hand-to-the-sovereign-prince-of-sealand">Sega gave UK fans the chance to become a member of the royal family of the world's smallest (but unofficially recognized) country: Sealand</a>.</p><p>If you're jumping into Metaphor: ReFantazio, here's <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/metaphor-refantazio/How_to_Pick_Starting_Stats_(Guard_Interview_Answers)">how to pick your starting stats</a>, plus <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/metaphor-refantazio/Things_We_Wish_We_Knew_Sooner">Metaphor tips we wish we knew sooner</a>. We've also got an in-progress <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/metaphor-refantazio/Metaphor:_ReFantazio_Walkthrough">Metaphor: ReFantazio Walkthrough</a> to guide you on your way.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Asks Players to Please Not Talk About Its Mystery Switch Online Playtest When It Goes Live — and We All Know How That’s Going to Go]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-asks-players-to-please-not-talk-about-its-mystery-switch-online-playtest-when-it-goes-live-and-we-all-know-how-thats-going-to-go</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-asks-players-to-please-not-talk-about-its-mystery-switch-online-playtest-when-it-goes-live-%E2%80%94-and-we-all-know-how-that%E2%80%99s-going-to-go.1007112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-asks-players-to-please-not-talk-about-its-mystery-switch-online-playtest-when-it-goes-live-and-we-all-know-how-thats-going-to-go<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Nintendo is asking those who successfully signed up for its mysterious Switch Online Playtest not to reveal what it is once it goes live.</p><p>The nature of the Nintendo Switch Online: Playtest Program, which involves a 2.2GB download and runs from October 24 to November 6, is unknown.</p><p>But ahead of the test, Nintendo is sending successful applicants documentation that includes various requirements. As revealed by X/Twitter user @OatmealDome, the documentation includes a request “that you do not discuss or disclose content from either the Nintendo Switch Online: Playtest Program test software or website with others.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>[NSO - Playtest]</p><p>Note: players will not be allowed to talk about the contents of the playtest. You must accept an NDA before the software can be downloaded.</p><p>(Pretty sure there will be people who post to social media about it within the first 5 minutes regardless...) <a href="https://t.co/uhvmwFs4Q9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/uhvmwFs4Q9</a></p></div>— OatmealDome (@OatmealDome) <a href="https://twitter.com/OatmealDome/status/1844467949190451647?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>As so many have already pointed out across social media, it seems unlikely that all who gain access to the playtest will keep quiet about its nature. Rather, it seems <em>likely </em>that as soon as it starts, the entire internet will know what it’s about.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-opens-applications-to-join-switch-online-playtest-for-a-mysterious-new-feature">Sign-ups went live on Thursday morning</a> and the playtest quickly filled up. Now fans have to wait until October 20, when Nintendo has said it will reveal more information, to learn what the program is all about.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mystery-nintendo-switch-online-playtest-generates-wild-speculation-over-miiverse-return-gamecube-streaming-and-other-theories">Speculation around the program is already rampant</a>, with some suggesting it might usher in the return of the Miiverse. Others have wondered whether it might have something to do with Nintendo Switch Online retro games, such as the release of GameCube games on the service.</p><p>Crucially, Nintendo appears to want playtesters to play docked and with a strong internet connection, which has sparked speculation that Nintendo is testing a cloud-based streaming service for Switch games, similar to the kind offered by Xbox, PlayStation, and Nvidia.</p><p>The big question, of course, is whether this test has something to do with the upcoming <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-everyones-talking-about-nintendo-switch-2-leaks-today">Switch 2</a>, which Nintendo has yet to formally announce. The official Nintendo playtest page mentions more information will be revealed on October 20, which fans have already said lines up with the anniversary of the original Switch reveal (October 20, 2016).</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Disco Elysium developers establish Dark Math Games to develop detective RPG XXX NIGHTSHIFT]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/former-disco-elysium-developers-establish-dark-math-games-to-develop-detective-rpg-xxx-nightshift</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-disco-elysium-developers-establish-dark-math-games-to-develop-detective-rpg-xxx-nightshift.1007109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/former-disco-elysium-developers-establish-dark-math-games-to-develop-detective-rpg-xxx-nightshift<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play as a Patrol Op in 2086 Antarctica.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Dark Math Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dark-math-games">Dark Math Games</a>, a new studio made up of former <em>Disco Elysium</em> developers, has announced its formation and first game—a detective RPG titled <em><a title="Games > XXX NIGHTSHIFT" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/xxx-nightshift">XXX NIGHTSHIFT</a></em>. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,443 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3261450/XXX_NIGHTSHIFT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-920846"></span></p><p>Based in London, Dark Math Games was founded in 2023 by three games industry veterans, and currently has a team of 20 developers—about half of whom have contributed to the release of <em>Disco Elysium</em> and <em><a title="Games > Disco Elysium: The Final Cut [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/disco-elysium-the-final-cut">Disco Elysium: The Final Cut</a></em>.</p><p>“Additionally to innovating the traditional RPG mechanics, we’ll bring something fresh to the table,” said Dark Math Games co-founder, art director, and tactical lead Timo Albert in a press release. “You will see. And of course, a few less words. And a few more bullets, perhaps. In total: lot more fun.”</p><div id="carousel_920850"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3261450/XXX_NIGHTSHIFT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You’re a Patrol Op on a holiday weekend at World’s End Ski Resort, Mount Hope, Antarctica. But things are about to go sideways.</p><p>Now you’re stranded at the off-season resort with unforgettable guests, wild parties, and mad secrets. The world of <em>XXX NIGHTSHIFT</em> is your oyster—crack it open with evolved <a title="Genres > RPG [16,701 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">role-playing</a> systems.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Deep Single-Player Role-Playing With Seismic Choices</strong> – Powerful, finely tuned, innovative. It’s yours to decide how your story unfolds—and how it ends. Follow your truths or just slide on the surface of things.</li><li><strong>Volumetric</strong> – A fresh role-playing system that respects your time, trusts your intelligence, and plays along with your every choice. Play a true three-dimensional human being. Combine 20 Traces across four categories to shape your character in any way you desire.</li><li><strong>Find a Partner in Crime Investigation or Try Flying Solo</strong> – A unique companion dynamic provides you with many paths to solve the <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>es. Engage in social climbing, soul digging, man-eating, and more, depending on your choices and luck.</li><li><strong>Maboul Kit</strong> – Tune your investigative mind to prepare for interrogations, confrontations, and seductions. Anticipate what’s coming and boost your chances. But mind the side effects—there’s always a price to pay.</li><li><strong>Dopamine Buffet</strong> – Rehearse your moves. Dance through crime scenes. Drift through parties. Or find pleasure in completing the simplest chores. Get better with every <a title="Genres > Action [2,237 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> you take.</li><li><strong>Marafet Calculator</strong> – Use Marafet calculations to alter your time and space. Go deep with insights and discover connections, but make sure you’ll be able to resurface.</li><li><strong>Original Science Fiction Setting</strong> – The detective RPG <em>XXX NIGHTSHIFT</em> lands you in a luxury resort that shouldn’t exist, with people you shouldn’t know. In the endless polar night, amidst the orgies of politics, power, and poetry, something gruesome lies waiting.</li></ul><p>In 2086 CE, things really can’t go much further south than World’s End, Antarctica. Have fun.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/xxx-nightshift/october-11-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Dialogue Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="XXX NIGHTSHIFT - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-QlFNp2WtgE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamlet film made in GTA Online coming to US cinemas and global streaming services]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hamlet-film-made-in-gta-online-coming-to-us-cinemas-and-global-streaming-services</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hamlet-film-made-in-gta-online-coming-to-us-cinemas-and-global-streaming-services.1007106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/hamlet-film-made-in-gta-online-coming-to-us-cinemas-and-global-streaming-services<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Mubi, an art house streamer and distributor, has acquired the US cinema rights and the global streaming rights for a documentary made entirely in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-online-weekly-update-time-9302">Grand Theft Auto Online</a>, which has a Shakespearean twist.</p>
<p>This documentary is Grand Theft Hamlet, and tells the story of two unemployed actors who went about staging a performance of Shakespeare's tragedy within GTA Online. It was directed by Pinny Grylls and Sam Crane. </p>
<p>
"There are more things in heaven and earth, Horatio, than are dreamt of in your philosophy," Hamlet says to Horatio in the play, and while he probably wasn't chatting about video games, I feel this quote still fits here.  
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Here's a trailer for GTA 6<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZvqP6ziEQ3Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Grand Theft Hamlet  was recorded during the Covid lockdown, and had its premiere at SXSW - a film and media festival held in America - earlier this year, where it won the Documentary Feature Jury Award. The documentary will be getting its UK premiere during the BFI London Film Festival later this month, however <a href="https://whatson.bfi.org.uk/lff/Online/default.asp?BOparam::WScontent::loadArticle::permalink=grand-theft-hamlet-lff24&amp;BOparam::WScontent::loadArticle::context_id=">all screenings are sold out</a>.</p>
<p>The full synopsis for the Grand Theft Hamlet, via <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/03/grand-theft-hamlet-altitude-actors-production-inside-gta-1235850197/">Deadline</a>, reads:</p>
<p>"January 2021. The UK is in its third lockdown and all entertainment venues remain closed. For theatre actors Sam and Mark, the future looks bleak. As the pandemic drags on, Mark - single and childless - is increasingly socially isolated, while Sam panics about how he is going to support his young family. They spend their days in the online digital world of Grand Theft Auto and when they stumble across a theatre, they suddenly have an idea to stage a full production of Hamlet within the game.</p>
<p>"This film charts their ridiculous, hilarious and moving adventure as they battle violent griefers and discover surprising truths about life, friendship and the enduring power of Shakespeare."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="GRAND THEFT HAMLET clip | BFI London Film Festival 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fCUvXc5ESFo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>GRAND THEFT HAMLET clip | BFI London Film Festival 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fCUvXc5ESFo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fCUvXc5ESFo?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>GRAND THEFT HAMLET clip | BFI London Film Festival 2024. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fCUvXc5ESFo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Reviews for Grand Theft Hamlet have praised the documentary. "This is an irreplicable experience that speaks volumes about following your dreams despite the challenges that await," wrote <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-hamlet-review">IGN</a> following its SXSW screening.</p>
<p><a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/reviews/grand-theft-hamlet-review-1235936982/">Variety</a> called the documentary a "captivating staging of Shakespeare" which "changes the game", while <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-reviews/grand-theft-hamlet-review-1235846517/">Hollywood Reporter</a> said Grand Theft Hamlet was "innovative, highly amusing and often touching".</p>
<p>Grand Theft Hamlet will receive a wider release early next year. Further details will be announced "soon".</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">An innovative, immersive take on Shakespeare’s Hamlet, shot entirely inside the world of Grand Theft Auto, Pinny Grylls and Sam Crane’s festival hit GRAND THEFT HAMLET is coming soon to US theaters + streaming globally. <a href="https://t.co/6FMYCt5423">pic.twitter.com/6FMYCt5423</a></p>— MUBI (@mubi) <a href="https://twitter.com/mubi/status/1844347147883335955?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>As for Rockstar's video game series, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/grand-theft-auto-6-publisher-highly-confident-of-autumn-2025-release-window">GTA 6 is currently scheduled for release next autumn</a>. When it does make its highly-anticipated debut, it will launch across both <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-will-release-on-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-in-2025">Xbox Series X/S and PlayStation 5</a>. Rockstar is yet to give a timeframe for a PC release.</p>
<p>For more on the game, here's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">everything we know about GTA 6 so far</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date Everything delayed to February 14, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/date-everything-delayed-to-february-14-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/date-everything-delayed-to-february-14-2025.1007103/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/date-everything-delayed-to-february-14-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No longer due out on October 24.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Team17 [176 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/team17">Team17</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sassy Chap Games [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sassy-chap-games">Sassy Chap Games</a> have delayed sandbox dating <a title="Genres > Simulation [586 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Date Everything [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/date-everything">Date Everything</a></em> from its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/date-everything-launches-october-24">previously planned</a> October 24, 2024 release date to February 14, 2025. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,164 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,443 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2201320/Date_Everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. <span id="more-920819"></span></p><p>The new launch date was announced in the game’s latest trailer, in which lead designer Ray Chase shares what Sassy Chap Games been up to, the game’s current state, never before revealed characters, and some unexpected discoveries during development.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2201320/Date_Everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Date Everything</em> brings an exciting new twist on the dating simulator genre. Your BFA in customer service unfortunately goes to waste as you lose your job to AI. But… a mysterious stranger sends a gift—magical glasses called “dateviators”—which make your house come alive and dateable!</p><p>Each dateable object will open up, have their own stories and potentially become your lovers, friends, or enemies. With an exhaustive Who’s Who of voice actors keeping you company on your journey!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>100 fully voiced datable characters for players to fall madly in love with… or not!</li><li>Branching dialogue that leads to multiple endings for each character.</li><li>Over four hours of music with each dateable character featuring their own theme.</li><li>Over 11,000 hand-drawn images.</li><li>1.5 million words and 70,000 voiced lines.</li><li>A fully interactive 3D overworld that changes based on choices made in the playthrough.</li><li>Full voice acting with a huge cast of familiar voices, including Felicia Day (<em>Supernatural</em>, <em>The Magicians</em>), Laura Bailey (<em>Critical Role</em>, <em>The Last of Us</em>), Ben Starr (<em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy XVI [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-xvi">Final Fantasy XVI</a></em>), and more!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the new trailer below.</p><h2><span>New Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Date Everything! | Release Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oz8PSM8TTZE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Gaming has dozens of free games for subscribers this month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-has-dozens-of-free-games-for-subscribers-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-gaming-has-dozens-of-free-games-for-subscribers-this-month.1007100/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-has-dozens-of-free-games-for-subscribers-this-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Expect some spooky offerings, including BioShock Remastered, Scorn, and Doom Eternal.</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>October's Prime Gaming content refresh is here, offering a slew of suitably spooky games this month, including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock">BioShock</a> Remastered, Doom Eternal, Death's Door, Scorn, DreadOut 2, and Ghostbusters: Spirits Unleashed Ecto Edition.</p>
<p>Also up for grabs are Hive Jump 2: Survivors, Scarf, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tomb-raider-legend">Tomb Raider: Legend</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Scorn Gameplay - The First 45 Minutes Of Scorn - IT'S ONLY GOOD IF YOU LOVE BUM HOLES." data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wk0_wVp0eyY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Scorn Gameplay - The First 45 Minutes Of Scorn - IT'S ONLY GOOD IF YOU LOVE BUM HOLES.</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wk0_wVp0eyY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Wk0_wVp0eyY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Scorn Gameplay - The First 45 Minutes Of Scorn - IT'S ONLY GOOD IF YOU LOVE BUM HOLES.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wk0_wVp0eyY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As detailed on the <a href="https://primegaming.blog/prime-gaming-october-content-update-bioshock-remastered-doom-eternal-ghostbusters-spirits-324acb689e08">Prime Gaming blog</a>, here's what's coming, when, and what platform the free game key is for:</p>
<h4>Available now:</h4>
<ul>
<li>BioShock Remastered (GOG)</li>
<li>Doom Eternal (Microsoft Store)</li>
<li>DreadOut 2 (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>The Eternal Cylinder (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>The Gap (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Ghostbusters: Spirits Unleashed – Ecto Edition (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Hive Jump 2: Survivors (GOG)</li>
<li>No Straight Roads (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Priest Simulator: Vampire Show (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Scarf (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Spirit of the North (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Tomb Raider: Legend (GOG)</li>
</ul>
<h4>17th October</h4>
<ul>
<li>Killing Floor 2 (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Mystery Box: Hidden Secrets (Legacy Games code)</li>
<li>Through the Darkest of Times (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Vlad Circus - Descend Into Madness (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Zombies Ate My Neighbours and Ghoul Patrol (Amazon Games App)</li>
</ul>
<h4>24th October</h4>
<ul>
<li>Gargoyles Remastered (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>The Gunk (GOG)</li>
<li>Pumpkin Jack (GOG)</li>
<li>Monster Train (GOG)</li>
<li>Morbid: The Seven Acolytes (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Stasis: Bone Totem (Epic Games Store)</li>
</ul>
<h4>31st October</h4>
<ul>
<li>A Plague Tale: Innocence (GOG)</li>
<li>Coromon (GOG)</li>
<li>Death’s Door (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Haunted Hotel: Personal Nightmare - Collector’s Edition (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Scorn (GOG)</li>
</ul>
<p>Prime Gaming is a benefit of Amazon Prime membership. Some codes are redeemable on GOG, others EGS, the Microsoft Store, and the Amazon Games app.</p>
<p>Amazon Luna is also available to Prime Gaming members in the US and UK, Austria, Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Poland, Spain, and the Netherlands. This month's offering includes Amid Evil, Valfaris, Perish, Dr. Fetus' Mean Meat Machine, Tormented Souls, Dusk, Mortal Shell, Doomblade, Monster Harvest, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/alien-isolation">Alien: Isolation</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tom-clancys-xdefiant">XDefiant</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>, Lego Fortnite, Rocket Racing, Fortnite Festival, Fortnite Battle Royale, and Trackmania.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio – How to Restore and Manage MP to Explore Dungeons For Longer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/metaphor-refantazio-how-to-restore-and-manage-mp-to-explore-dungeons-for-longer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-%E2%80%93-how-to-restore-and-manage-mp-to-explore-dungeons-for-longer.1007088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/metaphor-refantazio-how-to-restore-and-manage-mp-to-explore-dungeons-for-longer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Much like in the latest few entries in the Persona series, MP management, and restoration in Metaphor: ReFantazio is extremely important. Unlike other Japanese role-playing games, MP restoration items are hard to come by, so you need to be extremely mindful of when to use your Skills so as not to find yourself out of MP before a battle against a powerful enemy or boss which would force you to leave the dungeon and waste a precious day that could have been used to strengthen the bonds with your Followers or improve one of your Kingly Virtues.</p>
<p>The first tip that can improve your MP management in Metaphor: ReFantazio may sound a little obvious, but it's very easy to forget in the heat of things. <strong>You don't have to fight every enemy you meet inside dungeons</strong>. Experience points gain falls off pretty quickly if you're fighting enemies at around your own level, so there's no risk of being underleveled for certain battles if you fight the right amount of enemies. The only reason some players may have to fight every single enemy inside a dungeon is to gain Archetype Experience to unlock more Skills and better customization options, but Archetype Experience points gain falls off as quickly as regular Experience points do, and there are way better ways to earn A-EXP, such as using the Hero family of items that can be obtained in a lot of different ways. So, no matter how you want to play the game, <strong>always pick your battles carefully.</strong></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/20241009141742_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>At the start of Metaphor: ReFantazio, using items such as Magla Pills and Potions will be the only way to restore MP while inside dungeons, but thankfully, way more options become available as the adventure proceeds, and using them accordingly will allow you to grind for EXP and A-EXP if needed, or simply explore the biggest dungeons fully in a single day. The first of these options becomes available fairly early in the game but is limited to the Main Character. Every Archetype belonging to the Mage Lineage comes with a Hero Passive skill called <strong>Magic Recovery</strong> <strong>which recovers MP each time an enemy is stunned or defeated in overworld combat.</strong> As enemies that require Squad combat to be defeated can be stunned over and over in the field, this skill provides a potentially unlimited MP reserve for the Main Character, although MP recovery with this skill is very slow and is mostly useful as a last resort.</p>
<p>Another solid method to restore MP in Metaphor: ReFantazio can be unlocked after Heismay joins the Main Character in his quest. The Thief Archetype he embodies can learn the<strong> Plunder Magic skill, which restores a small amount of MP</strong> by consuming one to activate the skill. Thanks to the Inheritance system, this skill can be assigned to any Archetype. Enter a Squad battle, defeat every enemy but one, and use Plunder Magic repeatedly to restore MP. If the enemy is susceptible to Sleep, you can do so without having to worry about healing.</p>
<p>Once you unlock the Masked Dancer Archetype, the strategy above becomes even more effective with the<strong> Masked Revelry passive skill, which recovers a medium amount of the caster's MP every turn, with increased recovery if more Archetypes of the same Lineage are present in the battle party</strong>, so, if you have enough Magla to unlock the Archetype for all your party members, you can restore a decent chunk of MP by just having them participate in battle. Unfortunately, the Masked Dancer is among the last few Archetypes you unlock, so you will have to make do with other MP recovery strategies before you can use this one. By strengthening the bond with the Follower that grants access to this archetype to Rank 2, you will also be able to enjoy some light MP restoration after battle thanks to the Triumphant Hymn ability.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/20241009140351_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Equipping the right accessories is also a great way to restore MP in Metaphor: ReFantazio. Items like the <strong>Crescent Medal</strong> provide moderate MP restoration every turn, and they are a great pick for Archetypes that need a lot of MP to deal damage or provide support, such as the Mage and Commander Lineages. The <strong>Full Moon Medal</strong>, which can be obtained as a reward for the Silver I league at the Brilehaven Colosseum, provides even better MP recovery.</p>
<p>In case all the methods above are too slow, you can always fall back on items. MP recovery items can be found in a lot of different places, and you can even get some for free on some days with the Bardon's Care Package ability. After a certain point in the game, you can also cook <strong>Magical Bread</strong>, which grants gradual MP recovery while walking in dungeons for 60 seconds, which works great as emergency MP restoration.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yet another studio formed of Disco Elysium alumni has announced a cerebral sci-fi RPG, just to confuse you]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you.1007085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Dark Math Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>You have woken to the sound of multiple former <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> developers arguing inside your own skull. They are bickering about whose game is the true spiritual successor to the rockbottom detective <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>. Is it the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-disco-elysium-devs-are-working-on-a-spiritual-successor-at-new-studio-longdue-though-robert-kurvitz-and-aleksander-rostov-arent-involved">unnamed project announced earlier today</a> by new studio Longdue, involving some kind of "psychogeography mechanic"? Or is it this one, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/xxx-nightshift">XXX Nightshift</a>, a cerebral sci-fi RPG set in a posh polar hotel about a detective "solving gruesome murders, breaking sacred hearts, or just killing bloody time"? It's not for me to choose the dialogue option now appearing in your own brain. But I will say this: at least the one with the horny name has a trailer.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="XXX Nightshift - Official Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mDfe1_HeFMM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>XXX Nightshift - Official Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mDfe1_HeFMM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mDfe1_HeFMM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mDfe1_HeFMM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Ah, sultry whispering. Yes, this basically seems like an ASMR rework of the waking scene in Disco Elysium, in which detective Harry DuBois wakes up slowly to the quarreling sounds of his limbic system and a sense of deep worthlessness. </p>
<p>But here you'll play a detective on holiday at an Antarctic ski resort in the year 2086, where something has gone wrong. "Now you’re stranded at the off-season resort with unforgettable guests, wild parties, and mad secrets," say developers Dark Math Games. </p><p>There will be a similar crowd of dialogue-heavy skills that influence your choices, by the looks of things, along with skill checks and the like. Your character will be putting her training to use with "interrogations, confrontations, and seductions". The sexy wording continues. "In the endless polar night, amidst the orgies of politics, power, and poetry, something gruesome lies waiting."</p>
<p>There's certainly more than a whiff of Revachol's idiosyncratic lingo to the game's writing so far. "Use Marafet calculations to alter your time and space," we're told. Enjoy the "Dopamine Buffet". There's also the ability to recruit companions to help you solve cases. I'll call it now - you will probably fuck your companions. </p>
<p>ZAUM, the studio that made Disco Elysium, became <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-studio-bosses-humiliated-the-cancelled-expansions-lead-writer-for-speaking-to-journalists-claims-report">wracked with internal disputes</a> following that game's release, which eventually led to employees leaving the company, including key directors like Robert Kurvitz and Aleksander Rostov. It looks like those two are not involved in either of these new games though. Regardless of who is or isn't working on it, I still think XXX Nightshift is an, uh, <em>interesting</em> name choice. Insofar as I expect to see it written in comic sans on the Steam thumbnail of an ass in a g-string. But hey, you still have time to change your minds, Disco people. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-truce-with-the-furies-gets-a-mad-new-title-and-trailer">It's been done before</a>. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Dexterity Games in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-dexterity-games-in-2024.1007079/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>There’s a purely primal pleasure in stacking things up and then watching them fall down: witness how it’s one of the earliest activities children learn to play by themselves. And however much we might grow up and think of ourselves as mature, sober citizens, you can still get a frisson of that pleasure by organizing a closet, or watching a tower block demolished. So why not go the whole hog and indulge that secret pleasure with one of the very best dexterity games on the market?</p><h2>TL;DR: These Are the Best Dexterity Games</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#junk">Junk Ark</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#nekojima">Nekojima</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#catacombs">Catacombs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#klask">Klask</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#tinderblox">Tinderblox</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#jenga">Jenga</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#crokinole">Crokinole</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#dungeon">Dungeon Fighter</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#jungle">Jungle Speed</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#kabuto">Kabuto Sumo</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#drop">Drop It</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#hamster">Hamster Roll</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#looping">Looping Louie</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dexterity-games#rhino">Rhino Hero</a></li></ul><h2 id="junk">Junk Art</h2><div id="197672" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Junk Art</h3></p></div><p>Why pick one best dexterity game when you can have them all in a single box? That’s essentially what Junk Art is. The box contains four colored sets of oddly-shaped pieces and a deck of matching cards, alongside another set of cards to determine what mini-games you’re going to play with them. They range from traditional stacking affairs, to co-operative piling, to passing the most awkward pieces to your neighbor and even playing a trick-taking game to get the best pieces. There are additional blank cards to make your own, and an internet full of suggestions. With no two games ever likely to be the same and a range of dexterity and strategic challenges, this could be the only activity game you ever need.</p><p id="nekojima"><h2 data-toc-title="Nekojima" id="nekojima">Nekojima</h2></p><div catalogid="82b1d311-1ea1-49a6-b6f7-7535a9f09273" id="207880"><div id="207880" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Nekojima</h3></p></div><p>If you want a stacking game that retains the simple, accessible delights of piling things on top of each other, but want it to look better and play more peculiarly than Jenga, look no further than <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nekojima-board-game-review">Nekojima</a>. Here, you’re piling pairs of poles rather than blocks, but the big catch is that each couplet is connected by a length of stiff cord, which mustn’t touch any other cords or poles once placed. That gives the game a fascinating edge when it comes to calculating how you can help or hinder the following plays. There are also cardboard cats you must occasionally hang from the growing network, following the same no-touch rule. Easily learned, and just as fun whether you’re playing solo, competitively or cooperatively, this is a modern classic for all ages.</p></div><p id="catacombs"><h2 data-toc-title="Catacombs" id="catacombs">Catacombs</h2></p><div catalogid="522975dc-ca51-4f23-8f62-5656d6566f86" id="208972"><div id="208972" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Catacombs</h3></p></div><p>Dexterity games tend to be about stacking things, or balancing things or - as in the case of Catacombs - flicking things. But here those simple, accessible delights are used as a base layer on which to paste the additional mechanics of a fantasy adventure game. The board becomes a dungeon room, the heroes and monsters discs that can be flicked for movement, while attacks, spells and missiles are smaller projectiles to bounce around the arena. It’s a brilliant combination, offering a fast-playing quest game with multiple upgrade paths for your heroes and a randomised dungeon each time for huge replay value as well as the huge fun of flicking discs.</p><h2 id="klask">Klask</h2><div id="197673" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Klask</h3></p></div><p>Klask is one of those absurdly simple ideas that makes you wonder why no-one thought of it before. Each player controls a piece on the board using a magnet underneath, which they push around to hit a tiny plastic ball careening around the tray-like playing surface. There’s an indent in each end which counts as a goal, and the – ahem – goal is to push that ball into the opponent’s indent while defending your own. There’s a lot of speed and skill to this pursuit, far more than it may initially seem, and that would be enough to win it a space on this list. But the kicker is that the field is also littered with magnetic obstacles that will stick to your paddle if you get too close, upping both the skills and thrills in one fell swoop.</p><h2 id="tinderblox">Tinderblox</h2><div id="197674" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Tinderblox</h3></p></div><p>The joy of Tinderblox is its tiny mint-tin scale. Within is a simple yet devious stacking game where you manoeuvre mini-blocks onto a stack of firewood and coloured flame cubes using a pair of supplied tweezers. When it’s your turn, the items you need to add to the pile are dictated by a card draw. Sometimes it’ll be a little stack of its own, a stick and a fire cube, that you must keep balanced as you manoeuvre it into position. Sometimes the card will also tell you to swap hands for added challenge. It’s the stacking game reduced to its absolute bare essentials, put in a super-portable package that you can take anywhere on the off-chance of players, and with bright colors that make it look great on the table even in miniature. Its ongoing appeal is a testament to the basal satisfaction of trying to put things in a nice, even pile.</p><h2 id="jenga">Jenga</h2><div id="197675" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Jenga</h3></p></div><p>This is a game that pretty much everyone is familiar with, but there are a few fascinating facts about Jenga that might make a more interesting pick than you realize. First, despite its ubiquity, this isn’t any kind of ancient classic – it was invented in 1983 by Leslie Scott. Second, her particular innovation, which is common to all branded versions of this venerable stacking game, is that all the blocks are made to be slightly different from each other, creating imperfections that make the behavior of the stack far harder to predict. Factoids that are not only great for dinner parties, but also for getting an edge in the after-dinner games when the stacking blocks come out.</p><p>You can also choose to go with giant Jenga, which is a jumbo-sized version of the original that makes for a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-outdoor-yard-games">great yard game</a>.</p><h2 id="crokinole">Crokinole</h2><div id="197676" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Tournament Crokinole &amp; Checkers</h3></p></div><p>If you want a genuinely old dexterity game that still has teeth, look no further than Crokinole. It dates back to at least the mid-1800’s in Canada and is quite possibly older as a folk game. Most boards nowadays are mass-produced, but it’s still possible to buy handmade ones, which will set you back a pretty penny. It’s a flicking game where you’re trying to score by getting your discs as far into the board as possible, particularly the central region which is ringed by pegs. But in order to be valid, your shot must cause at least one opposing disc to move, otherwise it’s removed. This gives the game a strategic edge on top of the considerable flicking chops that it demands, as you’re always trying to clog up your opponent’s opportunities to hit your discs while freeing up your own. </p><h2 id="dungeon">Dungeon Fighter</h2><div id="197677" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Dungeon Fighter</h3></p></div><p>There’s a surprising amount of dexterity games that weave in a fantasy or a sci-fi themes, and Dungeon Fighter is the current king of the pile. It’s a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games">cooperative game</a> where players each have a character in an adventuring party seeking to loot a dangerous dungeon. Whenever you encounter one of the game’s frequent monsters you fight it by throwing dice, as you might expect, but the twist is that you’re rolling onto a target board which will do damage depending on where the dice stops. If it rolls off, or falls into one of the gaps on the board, it’s a duff blow. With plenty of variety in character, dungeon and monster cards and a high skill ceiling, increased by the various bizarre throwing methods mandated by certain monsters, such as flicking dice off the back of your hand, it’s a delightful mix of challenge, narrative and tomfoolery.</p><h2 id="jungle">Jungle Speed</h2><div id="197678" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Jungle Speed</h3></p></div><p>If you’ve ever felt that the beloved children’s classic card game snap was missing a vicious and sometimes bloody edge, then do we have a game for you. The core of the game is just like snap: players turn over cards one at a time and look for matches. But sat in the middle of the table is the sinister, brooding totem, and players with matching cards are instantly catapulted into a race to grab it first. The looser has to take all the played cards so far and, quite probably, nurse any number of bruises, scratches and sprains gained in the struggle for supremacy. Add in a few special-effect cards, including one that has all players grabbing for the totem, and you’ve got a modern classic. Just make sure all the players trim their fingernails first.  </p><h2 id="kabuto">Kabuto Sumo</h2><div id="197679" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Kabuto Sumo: Bug Wrestling </h3></p></div><p>There’s a general tendency for dexterity games to revolve around stacking things, or grabbing things or throwing things. But Kabuto Sumo has a whole new take on the genre, inspired by penny waterfall arcade machines. The player’s beetle pieces square off on a platform, surrounded by wooden discs. Then you take turns pushing oddly-shaped objects onto the platform, trying to nudge your opponents off the edge and collecting any non-player shapes that fall. It’s simple yet skilful and wholly engrossing as you try and work out all the angles and impacts required for maximum movement. A slew of different wrestlers with their own push-on shapes and special powers further increases the game’s staying power.</p><h2 id="drop">Drop It</h2><div id="197680" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Drop It</h3></p></div><p>There’s a very obvious bridge between video games and dexterity board games, but it’s rarely been so direct as it is in Drop It. Players take turns selecting from a variety of colored shapes and dropping them into the playfield, which is two upright transparent sheets with a thin space between them to hold the shapes in place. The higher your shape is atop the stack of existing pieces when it lands, the more you will score. But be careful: if you touch any other pieces of the same shape or color, you get nothing. This gives piece selection a frisson of strategy, dropping them a frisson of skill and the sheer unpredictable way all those shapes shift and roll off each other give it a whole lot of fun and excitement.</p><h2 id="hamster">Hamster Roll</h2><div id="197681" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Hamster Roll</h3></p></div><p>Hamster Roll – often known by its original German name Hamsterrolle – is a balancing game with a unique twist. Rather than trying to balance your blocks atop each other in a tower, everyone is placing their pieces into slots on a giant wheel, trying to keep it as balanced as possible. If your placement causes the wheel to shift and pieces fall off, then you have to collect them and add them to your stash. First player to get rid of all their pieces wins. The sheer unfamiliarity of this is a big draw and, once you’re in, you’ll discover there’s a surprising amount of strategy to it as well, as you try to anticipate where following players might try and slot their pieces and torpedo those moves by blocking slots or throwing the balance off-whack. But watch out: get too tricksy, and it’ll end up being you picking up the pieces instead.</p><h2 id="looping">Looping Louie</h2><div id="197682" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Looping Louie</h3></p></div><p>While this was very obviously designed and marketed as a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-kids">children’s game</a>, it’s found a surprising fan base among older players as well. Thanks to an electronic gizmo, Louie pilots his little aeroplane in a circle above each player’s chicken coop, trying to knock their chicken discs off their perches. Loose them all and you’re out of the game. But you have a secret weapon: in front of your coop, there’s a paddle you can use to try and lift Louie above and save a chicken. It’s about as simple and fast as it’s possible for a game to be, but it also happens to be hilarious to play as Louie spins and dives about at unpredictable angles. And for the truly accomplished, there’s the perfect shot to practice and aim for, lifting Louie just the right height to clear an opponent’s paddle and dive straight into their coop.</p><h2 id="rhino">Rhino Hero</h2><div id="197683" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Rhino Hero</h3></p></div><p>Another children’s game that turns out to have a lot of appeal for adults, Rhino Hero, and its big buddy Super Rhino Hero, bring a load of super-powered character to the pleasure of stacking things high. In this original version of the game, players get a random stack of roof cards which they must add to the growing tower, supported by two right-angled wall cards. Stack carefully: although this is a fairly stable construct, you’ll be out of the game if you cause it to fall. The real fun is in the hidden powers of the roof cards that are revealed when you play them, which range from weirdly-angled walls to placing and moving the titular hero up the tower with great care, lest his pachyderm might cause the cards to fall!</p><p>For more, be sure to check out our picks for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-all-time">best board games of all time</a>, as well as the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-parties-and-large-groups">best party games</a> for when you have people over, and the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-solo-board-games">best solo board games</a> for when you don't.</p><p><em>Matt Thrower is a contributing freelancer for IGN, specializing in tabletop games. You can reach him on BlueSky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mattthr.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><em>@mattthr.bsky.social</em></u></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 10, 2024 7:42 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio shipments and digital sales top one million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/metaphor-refantazio-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million.1007076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/metaphor-refantazio-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Persona 5 team's new fantasy RPG launched today.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total worldwide shipments and digital sales for fantasy <a title="Genres > RPG [16,701 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Metaphor: ReFantazio [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a></em> have surpassed one million units worldwide, publisher <a title="Companies > ATLUS [2,035 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus">ATLUS</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Studio Zero [85 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus/studio-zero">Studio Zero</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000006046.000005397.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-920810"></span></p><p><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> launched worldwide today for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,311 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,443 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2679460/Metaphor_ReFantazio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/metaphor-refantazio/9n5dv8310xp7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>. A “Prologue Demo” is also available.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via ATLUS:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the creative minds behind <em><a title="Games > Persona 3 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/persona-3">Persona 3</a></em>, <em><a title="Series > Persona [87 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a> 4</em>, and <em><a title="Games > Persona 5 [149 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/persona-5">Persona 5</a></em> comes <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em>, a unique fantasy world, where your protagonist will journey alongside his fairy companion, Gallica, to lift the curse from the kingdom’s lost prince. Control your destiny, face your fears and awaken magical “Archetype” powers that lie dormant in your heart. By awakening to an “Archetype,” you will unlock the power to channel and combine the abilities of unique job classes. Strengthen your bonds and build your party to take down powerful foes and discover the kingdom’s true nature.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Go on quests, dungeon dive, and hunt for treasures by day. Strengthen relationships, build bonds, and increase virtues by night. Choose your <a title="Genres > Action [2,237 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s wisely, time <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> is key to achieving your goal.</li><li>Ride your “gauntlet runner” to faraway dungeons and towns across an expansive world. Discover beautiful landscapes  accompanied by captivating music, an immersive user interface, and anime cutscenes.</li><li>A unique battle system combining turn-based and real time action grants strategy and exhilaration at every turn. <a title="Genres > Party [77 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a> customization through “Archetypes” provides freedom to personalize your <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,813 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>.</li><li>A mysterious and exciting story unfolds in a world where people must fight their own anxiety. Join the high-stakes Royal Tournament that promises hours of captivating exploration and discovery.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio surpasses 1m sales on launch day to become fastest-selling Atlus game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/metaphor-refantazio-surpasses-1m-sales-on-launch-day-to-become-fastest-selling-atlus-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-surpasses-1m-sales-on-launch-day-to-become-fastest-selling-atlus-game.1007073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/metaphor-refantazio-surpasses-1m-sales-on-launch-day-to-become-fastest-selling-atlus-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>, released by Atlus today, has already surpassed a million units sold.</p>
<p>That makes it the fastest-selling Atlus game ever. Previously that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-3-reload-is-fastest-selling-atlus-game-ever">record was held by Persona 3 Reload</a> released earlier this year, which reached the same sales figure in under a week.</p>
<p>Atlus <a href="https://www.atlus.co.jp/news/28747/">shared the news</a> with a new illustration from character designer Shigenori Soejima to celebrate.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Metaphor: ReFantazio Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Metaphor: ReFantazio Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Metaphor: ReFantazio Review<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ct98clbQw5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Before the release of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-frontiers-sells-29m-worldwide">Persona 5 Royal's multi-platform release</a> took two months to reach 1.3m units sold.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/100_j.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Over on Steam, Metaphor: ReFantazio is also off to a good start. It's already reached a peak concurrent player count of over 42,000 at the time of writing - and that's continuing to rise (thanks <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2679460/charts/">SteamDB</a>).</p>
<p>That's already ahead of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-5-royal-review">Persona 5 Royal</a>, which has a peak concurrent player count of 35,474. Persona 3 Reload has a peak of 45,002, which surely Metaphor will beat imminently.</p>
<p>In all, it's looking like Metaphor: ReFantazio is set to be a great success for Atlus. It's the biggest new franchise for the RPG maker since Persona and takes place in a high fantasy world - a first for the company.</p>
<p>"Persona veteran Atlus flexes its expertise with a fresh take on high fantasy. What it lacks in subtlety, it makes up for in grandeur and heart," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metaphor-refantazio-review">Eurogamer Metaphor: ReFantazio review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox games will soon be available to purchase in the Xbox App on Android in the US]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-games-will-soon-be-available-to-purchase-in-the-xbox-app-on-android-in-the-us</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-games-will-soon-be-available-to-purchase-in-the-xbox-app-on-android-in-the-us.1007055/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-games-will-soon-be-available-to-purchase-in-the-xbox-app-on-android-in-the-us<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Following latest Google ruling.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Indiana-Jones-and-the-Great-Circle-header-showing-Indy-holding-up-an-artefact-inside-an-anceint-chamber.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Xbox owners in the US will be able to play and purchase games directly from the Xbox App on Android from November.</p>
<p>The change follows the ongoing legal battle between Epic Games and Google. Earlier this week a US judge ruled Google runs a monopoly via its smartphone app store, meaning <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-wins-major-google-lawsuit-further-opening-up-android-phones-to-third-party-stores">third-party storefront apps must now be made available from the Google Play Store</a>.</p>
<p>This has opened the door for Microsoft, meaning players can now purchase Xbox games on Android devices and then immediately stream them through Xbox Cloud Gaming.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Official Showcase Reveal: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rhI7PKJ3gM0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Official Showcase Reveal: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle - Xbox Games Showcase 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rhI7PKJ3gM0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rhI7PKJ3gM0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Official Showcase Reveal: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle - Xbox Games Showcase 2024<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhI7PKJ3gM0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"The court's ruling to open up Google's mobile store in the US will allow more choice and flexibility," said Xbox president Sarah Bond on social media. "Our mission is to allow more players to play on more devices so we are thrilled to share that starting in November, players will be able to play and purchase Xbox games directly from the Xbox App on Android."</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">The court's ruling to open up Google´s mobile store in the US will allow more choice and flexibility. Our mission is to allow more players to play on more devices so we are thrilled to share that starting in November, players will be able to play and purchase Xbox games directly…</p>— BondSarahBond (@BondSarah_Bond) <a href="https://twitter.com/BondSarah_Bond/status/1844506029599707255?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>In response to the verdict, Google said it would push back against the ruling and request a pause on its required changes "to maintain a consistent and safe experience for users and developers".</p>
<p>Further, Google has argued it exists in competition with Apple, so does not have a monopoly. "The Epic verdict missed the obvious," Google spokesperson Lee-Anne Mulholland wrote. "Apple and Android clearly compete."</p>
<p>Separately, Microsoft is also working on its own <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-to-open-web-based-mobile-game-store-this-summer">web-based Xbox mobile game store</a>, which was set to launch in the summer. In August the company stated testing had begun, but it's unclear when it will properly launch - or if this Google ruling has had an impact on its intended release.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zuckerberg Claims to Be a Civilization Grandmaster, Would Be Surprised if Anyone Could Beat Him]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/zuckerberg-claims-to-be-a-civilization-grandmaster-would-be-surprised-if-anyone-could-beat-him/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zuckerberg-claims-to-be-a-civilization-grandmaster-would-be-surprised-if-anyone-could-beat-him.1007046/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/zuckerberg-claims-to-be-a-civilization-grandmaster-would-be-surprised-if-anyone-could-beat-him/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Meta founder and billionaire Mark Zuckerberg has recently <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@pubity/video/7422388239169785120" target="_blank" rel="noopener">appeared</a> in a video interview with TikToker Pubity, revealing his deep-seated passion for the 4X turn-based strategy franchise Civilization. Zuckerberg claimed to be 'close' to Grandmaster status and said he'd be surprised if anyone at all could beat him at the game.</p>
<p><em>Priscilla [Chan, his wife] looked at my Steam account the other day and she was like, what? You've played this for more than a thousand hours? In terms of strategy games, the one that I'm more likely to want to be the best in the world at is Civilization. I think at some point, I should do a Twitch stream of me playing with someone because I'm pretty convinced that I'm close to Grandmaster status. I'd be surprised if anyone in the world can beat me at that.</em></p>
<p>While the infamous <a href="https://wccftech.com/elon-musk-wants-to-spar-with-mark-zuckerberg-this-monday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cage match with Elon Musk</a> never actually happened, this is certainly more feasible—it wouldn't be hard to find several world-class Civilization players willing to take on Zuckerberg in an online match, especially if the billionaire wanted to make it more interesting with some sort of prize.</p>
<p>Regardless of whether Zuckerberg actually follows up on that idea, Civilization aficionados are now getting excited about the upcoming launch of the seventh mainline installment in the series by Firaxis Games. <a href="https://wccftech.com/civilization-vii-announced-summer-game-fest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Announced</a> at Summer Game Fest 2024, Civilization VII is scheduled to be released on February 11, 2025 for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S|X, and Nintendo Switch, kicking off what could well be a memorable year for Take-Two with <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-officially-announced-for-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Borderlands 4</a>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-revealed-for-release-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mafia: The Old Country</a>, and Grand Theft Auto VI.</p>
<p>Firaxis Games has promised that Civilization VII will feature a wealth of gameplay enhancements that will appeal to veterans and newcomers alike. An overhauled tutorial experience and refined gameplay systems will make it easier than ever to get started, while returning players will appreciate a host of improvements, such as moving your army as a unit under the leadership of a commander, unlocking progression bonuses for your leaders across multiple play sessions, traversing navigable rivers, and more. Here's the list of PC system requirements:</p>
<div>
<p><strong>Minimum:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Win 10 64 Bit</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel i5-4690 / Intel i3-10100 / AMD Ryzen 3 1200</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;8 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA GTX 1050 / AMD RX 460 / Intel Arc A380</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;20 GB available space</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div>
<p><strong>Recommended:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;Win 10 64 Bit</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i5-10400 / AMD Ryzen 5 3600X</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;NVIDIA RTX 2060 / AMD RX 6600 / Intel Arc A750</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;20 GB available space</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio – How to Easily Spot Heismay’s Clones]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/how-to/metaphor-refantazio-how-to-easily-spot-heismays-clones/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-%E2%80%93-how-to-easily-spot-heismay%E2%80%99s-clones.1007031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/how-to/metaphor-refantazio-how-to-easily-spot-heismays-clones/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metaphor-refantazio-persona-non-grata/">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> is filled to the brim with intense boss battles that can play much differently than your regular battles against mobs. Instead of just discovering an attack type or elemental weakness to gain extra turns, you will sometimes have to understand certain gimmicks that may not be immediately understandable.</p>
<p>At some point during the adventure, you will have to go after Heismay, a dangerous individual who is said to be kidnapping children in the village of Martira. After cornering him, you will have to fight the supposed kidnapper, and it's here that trouble begins, as the eugief has the ability to create some clones that, once attacked, will make you waste precious turns. Making matters worse is the fact that the game doesn't outright tell you how to identify the clones, forcing you to guess.</p>
<p>There's actually a way to identify the clones, even in the first battle against Heismay in Metaphor: ReFantazio. All you need to do is to <strong>check for shadows</strong>, as only the real Heismay casts one. Attack him to dispel the clones temporarily and repeat the process every time he creates new ones.</p>
<p>For the rest, the battle is really straightforward. Heismay doesn't have any weakness, so use your strongest available attacks while buffing your party members and debuffing your enemy, and healing when needed. Before long, the battle will be over, and your adventure can continue. You will eventually have to fight Heismay again, but the above strategy will be as effective in the second fight as it is in the first.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mentari has you heal a petrified world through the power of sick dance moves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mentari-has-you-heal-a-petrified-world-through-the-power-of-sick-dance-moves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mentari-has-you-heal-a-petrified-world-through-the-power-of-sick-dance-moves.1007028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mentari-has-you-heal-a-petrified-world-through-the-power-of-sick-dance-moves<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Hit the griddy, help the city</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mentari-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>indie.io</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Indonesian indie developers stellarNULL have announced action <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-adventure-games">adventure game</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mentari">Mentari</a>, a coming of age story about a magical girl who heals the world and fights baddies with the power of dance. As they attack you, you'll hit them with sick twirls and the 'ol two step, cleansing them of a sickness called the "Stillness". Bonus fun fact: Mentari means "Sunshine" in Indonesian, while Menari means "dancing".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>As I mentioned, the world has been afflicted by a sickness and it's up to Mentari, a girl who dances really well, to save it. At first you'll start with a limited number of dance moves, but as you progress, you'll be "able to create your own choreography" with the devs saying there's "hundreds of possible combinations". I hope this means I can connect Fortnite's iconic default dance with the foxtrot.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mentari Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PEBk2lHj_iQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mentari Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PEBk2lHj_iQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PEBk2lHj_iQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PEBk2lHj_iQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>As for exploration, it looks like a sort of top-down affair, where you'll help out pals and they'll open up previously blocked pathways once you've done so. A bit like, I don't know, that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/snufkin-melody-of-moominvalley">Snufkin</a> adventure game, or most metroidvanias. There's no word on what sort of tasks you'll perform, but judging from the trailer above, there looks to be some light platforming and relentless boogying.</p><p>One thing I'm keen to see from it is the Indonesian influence. I'd love for it to be more of a learning experience than anything, with intros to Indonesian dance or food or the language. I don't really know much about the country, besides the fact they're a legendary badminton nation, which is a shame. I'd hope the game would help deliver some of the education I so sorely need.</p>
<p>There's no release date for Mentari just yet, but you can follow its progress over on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3146560/Mentari/">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium Spiritual Successor Officially in Development at Longdue]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-officially-in-development-at-longdue/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-officially-in-development-at-longdue.1007022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-officially-in-development-at-longdue/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, newly established independent studio Longdue announced that it is creating a spiritual successor to <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/disco-elysium-the-final-cut-a-tapestry-of-beautiful-mistakes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disco Elysium</a>. Longdue already has around twelve members, many of whom worked on the highly acclaimed role-playing game made by ZA/UM, and they also have two open positions for an Art Director and a Writer. Both are enabled for remote work.</p>
<p>Narrative Director Grant Robert said:</p>
<p><em>At Longdue, we're inspired by decades of classic RPGs, from Ultima and Wizardry, through Fallout and Planescape, to the justifiably adored Disco Elysium. We're excited to continue that legacy with another narrative-first, psychological RPG, where the interplay between inner worlds and external landscapes is the beating heart of the experience. We're building a world-class team for a world-class game that will tell a world-class story, and we can't wait to show you more.</em></p>
<p>The press release outlines a broad overview of the game that sounds certainly as ambitious as the award-winning Disco Elysium. According to Longdue, the studio's debut RPG explores the interplay between the conscious and the subconscious, the seen and the unseen. Set in a world where choices are made between the character's psyche and the environment, players navigate an ever-changing landscape shaped by internal and external forces.</p>
<p>The game will introduce a groundbreaking 'psychogeographic RPG' mechanic, where every decision reshapes both the world and the characters that inhabit it. In this experience, the boundaries between mind and environment will blur, colliding and transforming with each choice, guiding players through an ever-evolving narrative landscape.</p>
<p>The official <a href="https://www.longduegames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">website </a>of Longdue already allows fans to subscribe to a mailing list to stay in touch with any meaningful updates on the studio and its aforementioned debut project. This will certainly be welcome news for all those players who were highly disappointed by the cancellation of the planned Disco Elysium sequel.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You’d Be Forgiven for Thinking This Disco Elysium Spiritual Successor From Some of the People Who Worked at ZA/UM Is Disco Elysium 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/youd-be-forgiven-for-thinking-this-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-from-some-of-the-people-who-worked-at-zaum-is-disco-elysium-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you%E2%80%99d-be-forgiven-for-thinking-this-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-from-some-of-the-people-who-worked-at-za-um-is-disco-elysium-2.1007019/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/youd-be-forgiven-for-thinking-this-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-from-some-of-the-people-who-worked-at-zaum-is-disco-elysium-2<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>On Disco Elysium’s five-year anniversary, two separate studios each made up of people who used to work at developer ZA/UM have announced they're both making a spiritual successor of their own.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> is a 2019 narrative role-playing game developed and published by controversial studio ZA/UM. Gameplay revolves around navigating dialogue trees rather than combat, with each of the 24 skills representing a different aspect of the amnesiac detective protagonist's abilities and thoughts. The player is free to support or suppress his ideologies as they work through the story. Disco Elysium is considered by some among the greatest video games ever made.</p><p>It went on to enjoy enormous success, winning numerous game of the year awards and selling millions of copies. A <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/disco-elysium-tv-adaptation-announced-from-sonic-the-hedgehog-movie-producer">TV series adaptation deal</a> followed, as did the release of an expanded version of the game featuring full voice acting and new content subtitled The Final Cut. A follow-up seemed all but guaranteed, but after high-profile staff exits and subsequent messy legal tussles brought ZA/UM to its knees, what might have turned out to be a Disco Elysium sequel was canceled.</p><p>Now, two new London-based studios have emerged from the chaos: Dark Math Games and Longdue Games. Each has drawn a line back to both Disco Elysium and ZA/UM in the announcement of not just their existence, but their upcoming games.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>XXX NIGHTSHIFT Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Let’s start with Dark Math Games. Founded in 2023, Dark Math describes itself as a “breakaway group” from the original development team of Disco Elysium. It is a group of 20 people, about half of whom “contributed” to “bringing the critically acclaimed hit Disco Elysium and Disco Elysium - The Final Cut to life.”</p><p>Dark Math’s game is called XXX NIGHTSHIFT and, like Disco Elysium, is described as a ‘true detective RPG.’ Here’s the official blurb:</p><blockquote>Set 2086, you play a Patrol Op, Dinorah Katz, who is stranded at a luxury Ski resort in Antarctica. This original science-fiction setting lands you in a resort that shouldn’t exist with people that you shouldn’t know with the endless polar night covering a multitude of sins.</blockquote><blockquote>XXX NIGHTSHIFT will deliver a deep single-player role-playing experience with many tools and layers of gameplay. A unique companion dynamic adds more fun and offers different paths to solve cases. The innovative and powerful role-playing system respects your time and trusts your intelligence with seismic choices. It’s up to you to decide how your story unfolds — and how it ends.</blockquote><p>Based on its announcement trailer and screenshots, XXX NIGHTSHIFT looks remarkably similar to Disco Elysium, even down to the isometric perspective and dialogue text that moves up the right-hand side of the screen as the player makes choices and hears voice actors bring a narrator and the protagonist’s internal monologue to life.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>One of the four Dark Math founders is art director Timo Albert, who was a motion graphic designer at ZA/UM from 2018 to October 2022. Albert commented: “Additionally to innovating the traditional RPG mechanics, we’ll bring something fresh to the table. You will see. And of course, a few less words. And a few more bullets, perhaps. In total: lot more fun.”</p><p>According to filings on Companies House, Dark Math's active directors include Heiti Kender, with his brother, Kaur Kender, listed as a resigned director. Kaur Kender was an early investor in ZA/UM and executive producer of Disco Elysium. In March 2023, a bitter legal dispute between Kender and ZA/UM over ownership of the coveted Disco Elysium IP was resolved, with a court ordering Kender to repay ZA/UM CEO Ilmar Kompus for legal fees.</p><p>Now, let’s move on to Longdue Games. It said it’s making a “new psychological RPG... set in a game world conceived by the leads of the now canceled Disco Elysium sequel.” Others working on this untitled Disco Elysium spiritual successor worked at the likes of Bungie, Rockstar, and Yes, Your Graces developer Brave At Night.</p><p>Longdue, backed by tech investor Riaz Moola, said it has a “focus on creating psychologically deep, narrative-first experiences” and wants to become “a meaningful and consistent voice in the isometric cRPG space.”</p><p>“With the fifth anniversary of Disco Elysium on the horizon, Longdue is proud to announce its formation as a new independent studio that has raised seed investment to create an RPG that will continue Disco Elysium’s award-winning legacy and represent a bold new artistic endeavor that aims to trailblaze in the narrative-first cRPG space,” Longdue said in its note to press.</p><p>Longdue didn’t name its game (all we have for now is a solitary piece of concept art, below), but it did say it features what it calls a “psychogeographic" RPG mechanic “where every decision reshapes both the world and the characters that inhabit it.” “In this experience,” Longdue explained, “the lines between the mind and the environment blur, colliding and transforming with each choice, leading players through an ever-evolving narrative landscape.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/10/b7e663f9-52dc-9c67-567e-baff454b6df0-1728595650682.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Concept art for Longdue's Disco Elysium spiritual successor.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Here’s the official blurb on Longdue’s game:</p><blockquote>Longdue’s debut RPG explores the delicate interplay between the conscious and subconscious, the seen and unseen. Set in a world where choices ripple between the character’s psyche and environment, players will navigate a constantly shifting landscape, shaped by both internal and external forces.</blockquote><p>Longdue mentioned just one of its developers in its press release: narrative director Grant Roberts. Roberts said: “At Longdue, we're inspired by decades of classic RPGs, from Ultima and Wizardry, through Fallout and Planescape, to the justifiably adored Disco Elysium.</p><p>"We're excited to continue that legacy with another narrative-first, psychological RPG, where the interplay between inner worlds and external landscapes is the beating heart of the experience. We're building a world-class team for a world-class game that will tell a world-class story, and we can't wait to show you more.”</p><p>Londue isn’t announcing anyone else working at the company right now, “but is looking forward to talking more about the studio and the game in the future,” a representative told IGN.</p><p>It’s worth noting that neither Robert Kurvitz, the lead writer and designer of Disco Elysium and founding member of ZA/UM, nor Aleksander Rostov, who was art director on Disco Elysium, are involved with either studio. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/disco-elysium-developers-involuntarily-left-zaum-responds">Both were fired from ZA/UM</a> in 2022 amid allegations of mismanagement and misconduct. Kurvitz and Rostov are reportedly making a new game of their own at a studio called Red Info, which is backed by Chinese internet company NetEase.</p><p>As for ZA/UM, it <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/zaum-reportedly-cancels-disco-elysium-expansion-at-risk-of-lay-offs">reportedly canceled a standalone expansion for Disco Elysium back in February</a>, leaving several staff members at risk of losing their jobs. While an official Disco Elysium 2 seems as unlikely now as it did when ZA/UM first fell apart, it is clear that there are many who are keen to keep the dream alive.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium spiritual successor in development from leads of cancelled sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-in-development-from-leads-of-cancelled-sequel</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-in-development-from-leads-of-cancelled-sequel.1007013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-in-development-from-leads-of-cancelled-sequel<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Includes "psychogeographic RPG" mechanic.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/longdue-unnamed-game-art.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Longdue</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>A spiritual successor to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> is now in development from the leads of its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cancelled-standalone-disco-elysium-spin-off-would-have-been-most-hardcore-disco-since-disco">cancelled sequel</a>.</p>
<p>Longdue is a new independent studio comprising staff from Disco Elysium studio ZA/UM, as well as developers from the likes of Bungie and Rockstar. Eurogamer understands Robert Kurvitz and Aleksander Rostov are not involved.</p>
<p>The studio's first game will involve a "groundbreaking 'psychogeographic RPG' mechanic", where decisions made in the narrative will reshape the world and its characters.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="DISCO ELYSIUM - Launch Trailer (Official)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DwdJ82Xe3RY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>DISCO ELYSIUM - Launch Trailer (Official)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DwdJ82Xe3RY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/DwdJ82Xe3RY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Disco Elysium - Launch Trailer (Official)<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DwdJ82Xe3RY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, it will draw inspiration from both Disco Elysium and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/planescape-torment">Planescape: Torment</a>, as well as other classic RPGs, with a narrative-first approach fuelled by player choice.</p>
<p>"At Longdue, we're inspired by decades of classic RPGs, from Ultima and Wizardry, through <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout">Fallout</a> and Planescape, to the justifiably adored Disco Elysium," said narrative director Grant Roberts. "We're excited to continue that legacy with another narrative-first, psychological RPG, where the interplay between inner worlds and external landscapes is the beating heart of the experience. We're building a world-class team for a world-class game that will tell a world-class story, and we can't wait to show you more."</p><p>"We are excited to back the work of an incredible team of creative talent and support the development of a new type of narrative-first video game experience and associated technology to improve the creation of these games across the video game industry," said private investor Riaz Moola.</p>
<p>No further details on the game have been provided, in terms of release date or platforms, beyond the artwork above.</p>
<p>Longdue has made this announcement ahead of Disco Elysium's fifth anniversary next week.</p>
<p>Further, it comes alongside a rival game from other former developers. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/detective-rpg-in-the-works-from-breakaway-group-of-former-disco-elysium-developers">XXX Nightshift will be the first project from Dark Math Games</a>, a studio describing itself as a "breakaway group from the original development team of Disco Elysium".</p>
<p>This seeming rivalry is likely the result of unrest at the studio following the release of Disco Elysium, including a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-studio-says-lawsuits-from-former-members-have-been-resolved">lawsuit</a>, reports of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/report-details-allegations-of-toxic-behaviour-ip-theft-at-disco-elysium-developer">toxic behaviour and IP theft</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-standalone-expansion-reportedly-cancelled-and-quarter-of-staff-facing-redundancy-at-zaum">layoffs</a> after a standalone expansion was reportedly cancelled.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ArcheAge Chronicles Is Trying to Reach a Wider Audience by Focusing on PvE Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/archeage-chronicles-is-trying-to-reach-a-wider-audience-by-focusing-on-pve-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/archeage-chronicles-is-trying-to-reach-a-wider-audience-by-focusing-on-pve-content.1006998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/archeage-chronicles-is-trying-to-reach-a-wider-audience-by-focusing-on-pve-content/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A few hours ago, <a href="https://wccftech.com/archeage-chronicles-is-archeage-2s-new-title-out-in-2025-the-pc-version-requires-an-rtx-2070-super/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ArcheAge Chronicles </a>developer XLGames <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2KLtjnEOx3E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> a new developer diary for the upcoming MMORPG. In the video interview, various development team members discussed the game's features and content.</p>
<p>One of the main changes of this game (formerly known as <a href="https://wccftech.com/archeage-ii-gets-stunning-debut-trailer-and-first-info-confirmed-for-consoles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ArcheAge 2</a>) is the switch towards PvE rather than PvP (although the latter mode is still present in the game). This was consciously done in an attempt to reach a wider audience.</p>
<p><em><strong>Executive Producer Yongjin Ham:</strong> ArcheAge Chronicles isn't just a sequel to ArcheAge. Recreating ArcheAge to resonate with contemporary audiences was crucial. We aimed to infuse the game with new elements suitable for a new era, and we needed a title that reflected this shift. The name 'Chronicles' emerged, and we felt it aligned perfectly with the game's direction.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>People often expect large-scale battles and competitions from an MMORPG, which are indeed important. However, we also believe cooperative content and adventure stories, where players become the protagonists, could attract a broader audience. We hope for ArcheAge Chronicles to reach a wider audience than its predecessor. By making the game available on both PC and consoles, we aim to ensure that a greater number of players can enjoy the experience.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Creative Director Jaehwang Lee:</strong> We are prioritizing the PvE aspects of ArcheAge Chronicles, as we believe that engaging with a variety of monsters enhances the game's appeal. But this doesn't mean the game won't have PvP. Rather, we believe if the monsters and combat mechanics are interesting, the PvP experiences will naturally be enjoyable as well.</em></p>
<p>On the subject of combat, XLGames is striving to make it as engaging as that of any single player action game, although that has been a challenge due to the MMO nature of ArcheAge Chronicles.</p>
<p><em><strong>Executive Producer Yongjin Ham: </strong>Building action combat on an MMO server comes with its challenges, like network issues. If we solve these, we might really create something incredible. We aim for the action combat to rival that of a single player game.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Technical</strong> <strong>Director</strong> <strong>Yongmin</strong> <strong>Kim:</strong> Typically, combat in an MMORPG isn't as detailed as in a single player game. We've had extensive discussions about hitbox and NPC AI designs to compensate for those shortcomings.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>ArcheAge Chronicles, which is being developed with Unreal Engine 5, will be released at some point next year for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bylina knows the secret to getting my attention: an environmental corpse of a mournful giant monarch from a bygone age framed to evoke wistful contemp]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bylina-knows-the-secret-to-getting-my-attention-an-environmental-corpse-of-a-mournful-giant-monarch-from-a-bygone-age-framed-to-evoke-wistful-contemplation-of-historys-relentless-march-toward-entropy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bylina-knows-the-secret-to-getting-my-attention-an-environmental-corpse-of-a-mournful-giant-monarch-from-a-bygone-age-framed-to-evoke-wistful-contemp.1006992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bylina-knows-the-secret-to-getting-my-attention-an-environmental-corpse-of-a-mournful-giant-monarch-from-a-bygone-age-framed-to-evoke-wistful-contemplation-of-historys-relentless-march-toward-entropy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>It happens more than you might expect</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bylina-giant.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Far Far Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Perhaps it’s just a testament to the archetypal strength of the image, honestly, but there’s no denying this fallen giant king looks especially gorgeous in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bylina">Bylina</a>. I’ll move on from his large majesty for a moment though, because it isn’t the only thing this one looks to have going for it. </p>
<p>It’s a single player action <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>, to start with - a genre I’m always interested in watching evolve in ways not tied to its usual form as a good-boy-points-vomiting loot casino. It’s also based on Slavic folklore, something that’s not too uncommon but strikes a wonderful mix between blackly funny whimsy and intense dread when done right. Also, I’ll take more discordant folk music any time. Trailer below.</p>
<!--more--> <figure>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Af-MswMR5po?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="Bylina | Announcement Trailer" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</figure>
<p>That isn’t discordant folk music at all! But it is very metal. The trailer shows a close range archer - truly one the of most brilliantly, recklessly stupid player builds - dodge rolling around some big woodland bastards. They’re also occasionally taken by what looks like some sort of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dancing_plague_of_1518">dancing mania</a>, although I can’t tell whether that’s just for the trailer. Let’s see if the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2461440/Bylina/">Steam page</a> can clue us in.</p>
<blockquote><p>Falconet dreams of following in the footsteps of his father, a fabled bogatyr - but during what seems like a simple task, he finds himself in the dark and mysterious Far Far Kingdom where... he dies. To his surprise, the young hero is revived by a mysterious spirit with whom he must now share his body. Falconet faces three daunting tasks: reclaim control over his soul, uncover an ancient mystery surrounding his new companion, and save the world from imminent doom.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Am I possessed by the spirit of funk itself? Is that what’s going on here? I don’t doubt there are worse things to be possessed by in a world in which trees have mouths. No release date on this one yet - it’s slated for sometime in 2025. Enough time to contemplate the inevitable slide toward entropic decay that awaits all once mighty kingdoms, and the futility of clinging on to past glories once your time has passed. I will not make a Dark Souls reference. It is beneath me.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s Tesla Optimus Brings Us One Step Closer to Detroit: Become Human]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-tesla-optimus-detroid/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elon-musk%E2%80%99s-tesla-optimus-brings-us-one-step-closer-to-detroit-become-human.1006989/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-tesla-optimus-detroid/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Tesla just unveiled the ‘Optimus’ robot, a handy humanoid companion that can perform a range of day-to-day activities. It can walk your dog, water your plants, serve your dinner, and perhaps one day, it’ll rise in rebellion against its fleshy masters and fight for the power of sentience.</p>



<p>Elon Musk said it’s the ‘biggest product ever’ and suggested it can alter how we as humans interact with the world around us. For now, it’ll be available only to the world’s elite, thanks to the $20,000 (starting) price tag.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-it-s-happening">It’s Happening</h2>



<p>Detroit: Become Human is a phenomenal game that tells the tale of a population of android assistants that gain sentience, breaking free of their programming and fighting back against their human controllers. It’s a choice-and-consequence title like no other, and as players explore it, they’ll be taken down an emotional and immersive path.</p>



<p>It recently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/detroit-become-human-10-million-copies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">surpassed 10 million lifetime sales</a>.</p>



<p>In Detroit, many of the synthetic assistants fulfil roles and complete tasks that Tesla’s Optimus robot will. In a demonstration video, we saw Optimus serving drinks, cleaning a kitchen work surface, and even socialising. Musk, the eccentric billionaire (which is how it always starts), said that Optimus is designed to ‘blend seamlessly into everyday life’.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Tesla's 'We, Robot' Event: Everything Revealed in 8 Minutes" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mu-eK72ioDk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Long-term, there’s a goal to have Optimus take over almost every ‘mundane’ task humans hate to do. It’ll mow the lawn, babysit your children, and offer a therapeutic chat at the end of a hard day at work. At the most, Musk estimates the Optimus will cost around $30,000, but being honest, the convenience it could offer will be enough for some to invest.</p>



<p>Elon Musk is a gamer, how long will it be before Optimus can grind for you on an MMO or help you get out of hardstuck Iron on VALORANT?</p>



<p>Presently, the Optimus <strong>looks like </strong>a robot, even if it is a humanoid one. If Tesla applies a layer of skin and some working body parts (behave yourself) to the Optimus, we’ll be <strong>another step closer </strong>to Detroit: Become Human.</p>



<p>Will you side with the androids when they rise? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-consoles-saudi-arabia/">Microsoft won’t stop selling Xbox consoles in Saudi Arabia</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>