<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:16:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LET IT DIE: INFERNO Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/let-it-die-inferno-review/</link>
            <guid>1407076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I’m a massive fan of extraction games, just not the ones that everyone seems to be playing. The general gaming public has been obsessing over <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a>,&nbsp;wincing at the impending launch of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/maratho">Marathon</a>,&nbsp;and hunkering down for their 2000th hour of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/escape-from-tarkov">Escape From Tarkov</a>&nbsp;playtime. Meanwhile, my first exposure to the genre and my favorite game of 2025 was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/synduality-echo-of-ada">Synduality: Echo of Ada</a>.&nbsp;It’s not a smash hit or a majorly well-known game, but it’s full of enough heart and charm that it had me overlooking and even appreciating it’s flaws for the sake of enjoying the full experience. I’m also a huge, huge fan of the game&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/let-it-die">Let It Die</a> –&nbsp;it’s a world I think of often, and a soundtrack I listen to regularly. So all those qualifiers meant I was dropping everything to excitedly play&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/let-it-die-inferno">Let It Die: Inferno</a>&nbsp;as soon as I could, I just wish that excitement was rewarded with a game worth playing.</p>
<p><iframe title="Let it Die: Inferno - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v6Nlb1WnSoY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Let It Die: Inferno&nbsp;is a huge departure from the first game, and an equally experimental shift from the now non-existent second game, Deathverse: Let It Die. The former was an inventive mix of dungeon-exploration, single player Souls-like combat, and Metal Gear Solid V’s asynchronous base raids. You never directly battled people, but still felt their presence. Let It Die: Inferno&nbsp;is a different beast. Instead of climbing a tower of Babylon, you’re descending into an endless pit in search of treasures. While combat is the same as the original game, your goal now is to race a timer to explore your randomised drop point, gather goods, and find a randomly positioned escape rocket or die trying and lose everything.</p>


<p>At first, I was in love with this genre blend. A melee focused extraction shooter meant that I was always on edge in an exciting way – every encounter requires me to get head-on with my enemy and face them directly, constantly risking my death if I mess up a single attack input. Some cracks in the foundation appeared pretty quickly. Your map is almost indecipherable thanks to how dense with winding paths and verticality each map is, frequently frustrating me when I was tight on time and trying to locate an exit. As I got further into the game and moved beyond the starting areas, the cracks grew wider. Difficulty ramps up almost arbitrarily between sections of the map, as well as types of enemies. In the starting area, monsters are pretty easy to deal with while humanoid NPCs are just kind of engaging. Move into the second area, though, and all of a sudden those same human NPCs can shred through you in almost one hit.</p>


<p>When you die, you lose everything you were carrying as well as your currently equipped body – one of several archetypes that you can level up across successful runs to unlock special enhancements and abilities for. Annoyingly, you’re locked into one body at a time and can’t swap until your current one dies, even if you’ve paid for the more premium editions of the game that give you multiple body types to choose from at the start.</p>
<p>Even more frustrating, though, is that your slow and steady progression through the game ultimately won’t matter. For some reason, Let It Die: Inferno has built a server wipe into its seasonal structure, just as the extraction shooter genre is coming to favour making these optional. When the next season of the game begins, every players progress in the game will be fully reset. Not just items, gear, and body levels, but even story and mission progression will be reset. Server wipes in extraction shooters stemmed from the regular meta resets from Esc</p>
<p>can help in maintaining consistency of experience, especially for games going through early access updates, but more broadly in the extraction shooter for maintaining power balance between players. In Let It Die: Inferno, these wipes seem designed as a way to encourage repeated play, but all it makes me want to do is stop playing before I’ve even gotten all that invested.</p>

<p>Another element of Let It Die: Inferno is PvP. Like other extraction games, you can run into other players during your run and either peacefully let them be or engage them in battle. In other games of the genre, the reason to fight another player is to steal their items upon victory. In this game, though, players are tuned to have incredibly low carrying capacity, which means players are rarely carrying a large amount of items on them at all. As a result, the risk of PvP far outweighs the reward, so the rare times I did come across other players in-game, they spammed crouches and hops to signal non-combativeness and I happily obliged and went in the other direction. It’s my only other option, after all – unlike most games in the genre, there’s no way to directly cooperate or buddy up with encountered players if you aren’t planning on fighting them.</p>
<p>I would have likely given up on this game a lot sooner if it weren’t for the incredible, jaw-droppingly beautiful art and visuals. The world that&nbsp;Let It Die: Inferno creates is truly magical, and taps into so much of the same wild spark that made Suda51’s vision for the original game so strong and unforgettable. The dungeons you explore are always a strange hybrid of specifically Japanese interiors ripped out and slapped down onto overgrown, outdoor marshes and mazes. The result is a beautifully alien experience where a path through a dark cave will lead into the basement of a Japanese arcade, or a door covered in bloody thorns and fire will suddenly lead you to an abandoned festival ground full of food stalls and discarded toys.</p>

<p>It’s a shame, though, that this same creativity and flair isn’t reflected in the games music. One of the things that the original&nbsp;Let It Die&nbsp;is best known for is it’s soundtrack – which was iconic for featuring over 100 different songs from various underground Japanese punk and rock bands that were all titled some variation of “Let It Die.” The blend of Japanese rock and grim dungeon exploration was incredible, and that killer contrast is missing entirely from Let It Die: Inferno.&nbsp;In my time playing the game I only noticed a couple of ambient background tracks, and the ones that specifically played during missions were grating, inconsistent, busy, and annoying.</p>
<p>According to the developers, Let It Die: Inferno used generative AI for several elements in the game, and one example they gave was that there is AI-generated music in the game. Go figure. The other disclosed areas of AI use include some parts of the background signboard textures, Records images, InfoCast videos, and even some voices.&nbsp;<i></i></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/let-it-die-inferno-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition - A Cheap Upgrade, But Lacking Substance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition</link>
            <guid>1407070</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 1 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161473/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>It’s tough to consider that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> came out almost six years ago, and even tougher to get over just how good it looks on Nintendo’s first hybrid system. Switch 2 hasn’t been left behind, though - now it’s got its own version of the game, but if I’m being honest, it's not really bringing all that much to the table.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:97166 @ 1768492804 -->
<p>The most notable change is the bump in resolution. It was pretty before, but now everything is rendered at a resolution much more befitting the Nintendo Switch 2, although some jagged pixel edges are still present. They’re oddly softer, though, which to my eye (which is admittedly only made of meat) suggests that one of the primary sources of the bumped-up res is Nintendo’s own flavour of DLSS upscaling. As I said, though, meat eyes.</p>
<p>Whatever the tech, the result is noticeable, especially when you get up close to your TV in docked mode. Realistically, the original still looked excellent, so it’s not a glow-up of epic proportions or anything. If you didn’t see a stark difference when you booted it up, I’d forgive you wholeheartedly.</p>

<p>But that’s with HDR off. If you turn it <em>on,</em> you’ll see a bigger difference than I was expecting. Colours are that much more vibrant, and colour banding on things like environmental shadows in water is almost entirely diminished. ACNH has always been a game with colours worth popping, and the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Switch 2 Edition</a> makes said popping even poppier.</p>
<p>Oh, and if you’d missed the previous reveal, it’s still 30fps, unfortunately. Probably something to do with one of the game’s mechanics being tied to the frame rate, but a shame nonetheless.</p>
<p>And that’s not all! Although there isn’t an awful lot more left to discuss. Mouse controls allow you to decorate and arrange furniture within your home, the hotel, or the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/animal_crossing_new_horizons_-_happy_home_paradise_dlc">Happy Home Paradise</a> with a bit more ease, although it’s hardly a ‘power tool’. Bringing up <em>any</em> menu requires you to navigate with the standard controls again, which is a crying shame as we feel the ability to quickly whip through lists and drag and drop items into position would’ve been an easy win.</p>
<figure><a title="Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 2 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161475/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>You can also use the mouse controls in custom designs, and those posts you can stick up outside Resident Services if you want. It’s nice that it’s been included, and if mouse controls were omitted, it definitely would’ve felt like a missed opportunity. But truthfully, Nintendo hasn’t realised the potential that mouse controls could have brought either.</p>
<p>You can have 12 people on your island in multiplayer now instead of the original’s eight, which is certainly an improvement - and now with GameChat and CameraPlay support. But personally I don’t think I could sit through that bloody plane landing sequence 11 times in a row for a single session.</p>
<p>That being said, loading times are certainly improved over the Switch 1. I’m not sure I’ve seen a single loading screen that hasn’t been shorter, though — for me — they felt just as they were when playing the Switch 1 version on Switch 2 before this 'Edition' dropped. I wasn’t able to see any significant difference between either on Switch 2, which makes sense at the end of the day, but if that’s all you care about, then you might not need to drop the cash for the upgrade any time soon.</p>
<figure><a title="Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 3 of 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161474/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Testing among Team NL, we found minor improvements, but also significant variations between our S2 load times (almost certainly down to how much each person has on their island), so your mileage may vary.</p>
<p>The final inclusion is the megaphone, making its somewhat triumphant return from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/animal_crossing_new_leaf">New Leaf</a> on the 3DS, and it’s <em>fine</em>. You hold the 'A' Button, yell the name of a resident at your console, and if it understands you correctly, they’ll yell out in response, giving you an idea of where on your island they are, assuming they’re not indoors somewhere. It works fairly well, but it has to be said, it’s not exactly an exciting inclusion. Functional, yes, but do your neighbours really need to hear you scream "ANCHOVY!" at all hours?</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition is perfectly fine. It makes things a bit prettier, has a few more options to take advantage of the console’s new features, but all in all, it’s not an especially exciting upgrade.</p>
<p>If it were free, I don’t think anyone could reasonably complain, but even at the relatively low price, it’s only <em>just</em> scraping by to be worthwhile. It’s far from an essential purchase, but if you’ve got credit on your account and you’re a fan of the game, you could do worse.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quarantine Zone: The Last Check, Star Wars Outlaws, Guild Wars: Reforged and More Join GeForce NOW]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-quarantine-the-last-check-star-wars-outlaws-guild-wars-reforged/</link>
            <guid>1407067</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>After announcing several of the titles that'll be joining <strong>GeForce NOW</strong> throughout the <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-kicks-off-2026-14-new-games-added-throughout-january/">month of <strong>January 2026</strong> right at the start of the new year</a>, we have <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/geforce-now-thursday-quarantine-zone/">a new batch of games revealed today</a> for yet another GeForce NOW Thursday that will be joining the service. Some, like <strong>Quarantine Zone: The Last Check</strong>, which leads the group this week, have previously been announced. Others, like <strong>Star Wars Outlaws</strong> and <strong>The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon</strong>, are new reveals joining NVIDIA's cloud streaming service.</p>



<p>This week's new batch of games sees a total of <strong>nine titles</strong> entering the GeForce NOW library, including the aforementioned three titles, the first two games in the <strong>Styx</strong> franchise, both of which will be free on the <strong>Epic Games Store</strong> starting today, <strong>Guild Wars: Reforged</strong>, and <strong>Tavern Keeper</strong>.</p>



<p>The headliner for this week, Quarantine Zone: The Last Check, is the latest game published by renowned indie publisher <strong>Devolver Digital</strong>, the team known for publishing the likes of <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/heart-machine-next-game-possessors-release-date-november-pc-ps5/">Possessor(s)</a>,</strong> <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/ps-plus-extra-premium-december-2025-games/">Skate Story</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-talos-principle-reawakened-i-know-im-a-person-but-not-a-genius/">The Talos Principle: Reawakened,</a></strong> and <strong>Cult of the Lamb</strong>, to name a few. It sees you stepping into the shoes of a checkpoint officer, scanning people into the Quarantine Zone, acting as the last line of defense for the people in the zone. If you mistakenly let someone sick into the zone, you could set the plague loose on an already crumbling society.</p>



<p>Here's the full list of games joining GeForce NOW this week:</p>



<ul>
<li>Quarantine Zone: The Last Check<em> </em>(New release on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3419520?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>, Jan. 12, GeForce RTX 5080-ready)</li>



<li>Star Wars Outlaws (Ubisoft Connect, now available on Xbox Game Pass)</li>



<li>The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon (New release on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3316940?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>, Jan. 15)</li>



<li>Styx: Shards of Darkness (New release on <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/styx-shards-of-darkness-77c030?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, free on Jan. 15)</li>



<li>Styx: Master of Shadows<em> </em>(New release on <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/styx-master-of-shadows-4d9ab3?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, free on Jan. 15)</li>



<li>Guild Wars: Reforged (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/29720?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>)</li>



<li>Mon Bazou<em> </em>(<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1520370?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>)</li>



<li>Tavern Keeper (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/436780?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>)</li>



<li>Waterpark Simulator (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3293260?utm_source=nvidia&amp;utm_campaign=geforce_now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a>)</li>
</ul>



<p>As we noted at the start of the year, we still have no word on some of January's bigger releases, like <strong>Code Vein II</strong>, joining the service. There's still time, though, before its release at the end of the month, so hopefully, we'll see it added either later in the month or at least sometime soon this year.</p>



<p>If you're looking forward to Code Vein II, you should <a href="https://wccftech.com/code-vein-ii-hands-on-preview-kill-the-past/">check out our preview of the upcoming Souslike from Wccftech's Kai Tatsumoto</a>. For even more on the game, Kai and Wccftech's Alessio Palumbo got to speak with the game's producer, <strong>Keita Iizuka</strong> and director <strong>Hiroshi Yoshimura</strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/code-vein-ii-interview-time-travel-partner-system/">and you can read that interview here</a>. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-quarantine-the-last-check-star-wars-outlaws-guild-wars-reforged/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palestine Skating Game takes Jet Set Radio's rollerblades and spray paint to soldier-filled streets and towering concrete walls]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palestine-skating-game-takes-jet-set-radios-rollerblades-and-spray-paint-to-soldier-filled-streets-and-towering-concrete-walls</link>
            <guid>1407064</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/palesting-skating-game-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Palestine Skating Game team</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I only have to skate a few meters before the piercing drum of rifle fire fills my ears. Armed with my trusty can of spray paint, I cover the hostile soldiers in splotches of bright colour while rollerblading circles around them. They stumble about, trying to keep me in their sights. Stopping to complete an unfinished bit of graffiti on one of the walls, spreading colour between gaps in a template, the soldiers gather around me. Unable to target me, they mill about in the way as I try to finish, making it a touch more difficult to work out if I've left any blank spaces.</p>
<p>I'm playing an early version of Palestine Skating Game, which offers a test of its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/jet-set-radio">Jet Set Radio</a> and Tony Hawk's Pro Skater-inspired rollerblading and painting amid a stylised rendition of war-torn Gaza.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Palestine Skating Game - LaunchGood Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bOhNlVFB7t8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Palestine Skating Game - LaunchGood Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bOhNlVFB7t8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bOhNlVFB7t8?autoplay=1" title="Palestine Skating Game - LaunchGood Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bOhNlVFB7t8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Palestine Skating Game has been in the works for a number of years, but it came to my attention via Amaar Chowdhury's recent interview with its developers for <a href="https://www.huckmag.com/article/palestine-skating-game-rollerskating-resistance-video-development-graffiti">Huck</a>. Rather than summarise the excellent article, which I recommend reading in full, I'll focus on my impressions of the game's 0.8 demo.</p><p>After finishing the mural while watched by the paint-covered guards, I spent some time railgrinding through this early demo's version of the West Bank separation wall. The space is a recreation of a few city blocks, filled with real world artworks and murals emblazoned across the looming concrete facade. You pass drawings of <a href="https://www.gettyimages.co.uk/sets/hdYTtJwekUCU6HVVKREssg/political-graffiti-takes-over-the-west-bank-wall">Trump and Netenyahu kissing</a>, Morgan Freeman's face alongside a quote from Nelson Mandela, murals dedicated to both <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/7/6/israeli-court-acquits-officer-of-killing-autistic-palestinian-man">Eyad al-Hallaq</a> and <a href="https://www.plutobooks.com/blog/leila-khaled-the-poster-girl-of-palestinian-militancy-international-womans-day/">Leila Khaled</a>.</p>
<p>The reality of the environment grounds the otherwise loveably janky splattering of paint globs. The experience feels deeply unnerving, but I'm glad of that discomfort. Playing left me  aware of the real suffering the game's aiming to convey through the backdrop to its carefree sliding around. After respraying a massive tank as it fired booming shells my way, I returned to the wall. The structure makes me think how this wall, <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/gallery/2020/7/8/in-pictures-israels-illegal-separation-wall-still-divides">declared illegal many years ago by the International Court of Justice</a> impacts the <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/meetdocs/2009_2014/documents/droi/dv/905_impact_/905_impact_en.pdf">Palestinans living in its shadow</a>.</p>
<p>In its final form, the developers plan to include an electronic score, but currently Palestine Skating Game has no soundtrack. A cold silence is punctuated only by the discharging of weapons. I'd argue this makes those sounds hit harder than they might in the final version. For now, it remains a work-in-progress blend of video game silliness and brutal reality, made by a team who know that day-to-day of that brutality firsthand, some still living in the West Bank to this day.</p>
<p>If you fancy giving the most recent prototype of Palestine Skating Game a go, you can find it on <a href="https://palestineskatinggame.itch.io/prototype3">Itch.io</a>. The game's developers have <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/palestine-skating-game-fundraiser">GoFundMe</a> and <a href="https://www.launchgood.com/v4/campaign/palestine_skating_game__grind_shoot_paint__do_graffiti_to_arabic_electronic_music">LaunchGood</a> open to raise money for their Gazan staff, though the latter looks like it may be closed for donations as of writing.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palestine-skating-game-takes-jet-set-radios-rollerblades-and-spray-paint-to-soldier-filled-streets-and-towering-concrete-walls]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hytale Feels Like A Neat Minecraft Texture Pack But Not Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hytale-minecraft-hypixel-crafting-workbench-quests-2000660135</link>
            <guid>1407055</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A meepmoop doodah in the hub area.</span> © Hypixel / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>I’m having a lovely time playing the early access release of&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>. But then of course I am: I love playing&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em>. So I’m enjoying building a pretty little log cabin, exploring underground caves for precious ores, battling skeletons with a bow and arrows, and travelling far from spawn to visit distant biomes. Because that’s what I do when I play <em>Minecraft</em>. What I’ve yet to figure out is why&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> exists as anything other than a texture pack for Microsoft’s behemoth.</p> <p>There&nbsp;<em>are</em> differences. But when I describe them to you, they’re going to sound so minuscule. For instance, <em>Hytale</em> has a much better jump: you can jump two blocks high, and you can mantle up from four blocks below. I love that. That would make <a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/bukkit-plugins/highjump">a good&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em></a><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/bukkit-plugins/highjump"> mod</a>.&nbsp; And there’s the slightly improved combat in which enemies actually block and you need to time your attacks. Then again, I can just add the <a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/smart-mobs">Smart Mobs</a> option to Mojang’s game. And you can <a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/modpacks/realistic-mc-graphics">see where I’m going</a> when I point out that <em>Hytale</em> is a far prettier game with gorgeous sunrises.</p>

 <p>Ten years in the making, and famously cancelled by Riot in the middle of last year <a href="https://kotaku.com/hytale-riot-minecraft-hypixel-revived-cancel-shutdown-2000645248">before being revived in November</a>, this early access build of&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> is unquestionably a really good reimagining of <em>Minecraft. B</em>ut in its current form, as released this week for a minimum of $20, that’s <em>all</em> it is, and I’m left pretty bemused how that can be the case.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000660163" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660163"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660163">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>To give you an idea of how peculiarly the two games overlap—even beyond the core concept of a procedurally generated world made of cubes in which you dig, chop, mine and shovel to gather materials for crafting tools, construction materials and decorating items—let’s just look at the mobs. The main ones you’ll encounter at first are skeletons and spiders. Big, chunky spiders that are two blocks wide. It didn’t need to be skeletons and spiders, but it is. Are there zombies? Yes there are zombies. But surely not golems? I’m afraid there are golems. There <em>are</em> other mobs in there, with pillagers replaced by goblins and Outlanders, and villagers swapped out in favor of Ewok-like Kweebecs, as well as the most astonishingly overpowered underground-dwelling giant frogs. But then there’s also a place called the Void which I read contains a Void Dragon. Seriously?</p>

 <p>The other aspect I can imagine an angry person on Reddit bringing up in response to accusations of cloning is crafting. It’s…it’s a lot worse. While it’s true that <em>Minecraft</em> has a fairly broad array of workbenches, for the most part people are using the basic crafting table and then an anvil and enchantment table. Sure, there’s the cartography table, the loom, the stonecutter, but these aren’t exactly core to the game. In <em>Hytale</em>, within the first couple of hours, I had needed to build a Workbench, Furniture Workbench, Blacksmith’s Anvil, Tanning Rack, Armorer’s Workbench, Builder’s Workbench, Furnace, and Campfire. I had to upgrade my main workbench to be able to then build the Chef’s Stove and Salvager’s Workbench, but still haven’t crafted the Alchemist’s Workbench and Arcanist’s Workbench because I don’t have enough gold or thorium. Each is enormous, meaning I’ve twice had to add sizable new wings to my cabin just to fit them all in the same location. It’s bonkers!</p>

 <p>Legitimately great is that if you have chests directly next to workbenches, it’ll recognize their contents when showing what can be constructed. (Less great is the need for a small auditorium to fit all the benches in, and so of course not being able to have them all adjacent to the necessary chests.) This is a huge improvement, and I really appreciate it.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000660164" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660164"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660164">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>But the more I try to allow <em>Hytale</em> to be its own game in its own right, the more it fights back against that. When you pick up items from the ground, which bob up and down floating in the air, they emit a little “pop” sound, exactly like in <em>Minecraft</em>. Put two one-tile chests next to each other and they’ll ping into one double-width chest. Let alone that you already know what every block type is likely to be, given its visual similarity to the source. And the thing is, it’s necessary! This game both looks and feels so much like <em>Minecraft</em> that any time it does behave differently, it feels wrong.&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> is such an unabashed clone that it’s backed itself into a corner of needing to do everything the same way&nbsp;<em>Minecraft&nbsp;</em>does. From the nine-box inventory along the bottom of the screen with a space for a shield to the left to how chest inventories appear, it’s just the same designs. It feels like playing the same game, in the same way, with the same goals.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000660166" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660166"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660166">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>This&nbsp;is supposed to change, when&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> adds its Adventure Mode, which will offer RPG-like storylines and quests to solve, and that sounds great! It’s something I always longed for in the earliest days of&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> and that still only exist today through mods, and usually ones that eschew a lot of the core nature of <em>Minecraft</em> to do so. There are hints of this in place, like the Forgotten Temple which will teleport you to a peaceful hub-like area, almost entirely consisting of buildings with “Under Construction” signs over their doors, and a statue which catalogs every mob type you’ve encountered so far. It’s a cute idea, and unlocks more crafting options when you ding specified numbers.</p> <p>Adventure Mode should add in “Alterverses” and bespoke quests and all that good stuff that will make <em>Hytale</em> distinct from the game it’s so wantonly copied. You know, if it happens. Clearly none of us knows what happened over the last five years at Riot, and whether the Hypixel team had developed huge sections of this before Riot pulled the plug, forcing the developers to revert back four-and-a-half years for this early access version. Or perhaps even then the game was so much like a <em>Minecraft</em> texture pack that Riot couldn’t see a way to release it.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000660165" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660165"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660165">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>As I said at the start of this, I’m having a lovely time! There are a whole bunch of balancing issues, but that’s entirely expected at this point. (Those toads, man, with the tongues that grab you. And iron is wildly too rare just now.) But I’m not having as lovely a time as I do when I join my son on his <em>Minecraft</em> Realm, or <a href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-donut-smp-server-farm-notch-2000656412">goof around on DonutSMP</a>, because, you know, it’s the OG.&nbsp;<em>Minecraft </em>has&nbsp;had 17 years to make itself buttery smooth, balanced to complete perfection, and at the same time old enough to engender nostalgia and comfortable familiarity.&nbsp;<em>Hytale&nbsp;</em>is an awful lot prettier (albeit still in pixelly blocks), but right now it’s in no important way <em>better</em>. I mean, the jumping and mantling is great! But, you know, it needs to offer an awful lot more than that. I’m still left just wondering&nbsp;<em>why</em>? Why fight so, so hard to make the same game that already exists?</p>

 <p>I’ll happily keep playing it for a little bit, see what the biomes I’ve yet to reach have to offer (the one where everything’s on fire is pretty fun), but I fear that in its current state I won’t be the only one quickly drifting away.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hytale-minecraft-hypixel-crafting-workbench-quests-2000660135]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homura: The Crimson Warriors launches March 31 in the west]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/homura-the-crimson-warriors-launches-march-31-in-the-west</link>
            <guid>1407049</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-orders open on February 2.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Otome [126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/otome">Otome visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Homura: The Crimson Warriors [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/homura-the-crimson-warriors">Homura: The Crimson Warriors</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on March 31 in the west, publisher <a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a> announced. In North America, it will be available both physically and digitally on launch day, while in Europe the physical edition will launch on April 28. Pre-orders will open on February 2. <span id="more-1019527"></span></p><p><em>Homura: The Crimson Warriors</em> first launched for PS Vita on June 28, 2018 in Japan, followed by Switch on February 15, 2024.</p><p>The game will be available in the following editions:</p><ul><li><strong>Physical Standard Edition</strong> ($49.99 / €49.99 / £49.99)<ul><li>Physical standard edition</li><li>Trading card pack</li><li>Set of five cards (one random holographic + four regular finish)</li></ul></li><li><strong>Digital Standard Edition</strong> ($39.99 / €39.99 / £34.99)<!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Digital standard edition</li></ul></li><li><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> ($54.99 / €54.99 / £49.99) includes:<ul><li>Digital standard edition</li><li>Digital short stories (20 pages)</li><li>Digital soundtrack (26 tracks)</li></ul></li></ul><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Idea Factory International:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Fourteen years have passed since the Battle of Sekigahara split Japan in two.</p><p>Now firmly in control, the Tokugawa shogunate is scheming to eliminate the Toyotomi clan, a long-standing thorn in its side.</p><p>In response, the Toyotomi clan has decided to confront the Tokugawa head-on, using Osaka Castle as their stronghold. Calls for support were sent to daimyo throughout the nation and a mere few answered the call. One of these brave warriors was Nobushige Sanada, the second son of the Sanada family who was cast away to Mt. Kudo on house arrest after the Battle of Sekigahara.</p><p>Alongside Nobushige on his escape from Mt. Kudo are the Sanada Ten Braves, ten ninjas who serve him even after their exile. Standing in their way are the Ura Yagyu, a group comprised of assassins who have carried out many killings under orders from the shogunate, mysterious swordsmen, and mighty warriors.</p><p>This is the final chapter of the Warring States period. It is a tale of the bonds and way of life shared by the Nobushige Sanada and the Ten Braves who gather at Osaka Castle.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Amongst the Fire and Ashes, Love Will Prevail</strong> – Previously released in Japan on PS Vita in 2018, Western fans can experience the historical fantasy otome as the protagonist Mutsumi Mochizuki fights alongside the <a title="Companies > crim [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">Crim</a>son <a title="Series > Warriors [40 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/warriors">Warriors</a>. Accompanied with multiple endings and CGs, this legendary battle of love tangled with iconic historical events and original characters in the Warring States period is sure to capture the hearts of history otome lovers!</li><li><strong>Maintain Peak Performance With Energy Reading</strong> – Use Energy Reading to detect the affection level and Ring status of love interests. Mutsumi has the special ability to adjust the love interests’ Rings. When sped up, it allows them to utilize unique powers at the cost of their physical health. Make sure to keep their Rings balanced! If their health deteriorates too much, the consequences could be dire…</li><li><strong>Ninja Guidance</strong> – Use your ninja scrolls to keep track of where you are in the story and revisit moments of the past if you seek a different outcome of the path you’ve chosen. Adjust both your affection and ring levels with each warrior when you select previously viewed events to change the course of history!</li><li><strong>Path of the Samurai</strong> – Throughout the story, you can level up your ninja rank to keep up with the Crimson Warriors during battle. Take your ninja skills to the next level and make it your mission to reach <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter rank and ensure victory against the Ura Yagyu!</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/homura-the-crimson-warriors-launches-march-31-in-the-west]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fatal Fury Fans Spot Strange Detail In New Trailer, Igniting Generative AI Controversy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fatal-fury-fans-spot-strange-detail-in-new-trailer-igniting-generative-ai-controversy/1100-6537425/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407046</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537425">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The use of generative AI in video games has been controversial to say the least, but when it comes to art, the blowback has been even stronger. One game currently being accused of using the technology is<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves/"> Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a>, as the new trailer for the fighting game's upcoming second season of DLC characters is being picked apart online. Viewers and commenters have pored over the trailer, claiming that the character designs are inconsistent and that certain visual elements contain generative AI. The biggest smoking gun, according to viewers, is a quick shot of series antagonist Geese Howard, who appears to be missing an entire foot.</p><p>Other instances of generative AI pointed out include Blue Mary's motorcycle missing several vital components--and being a completely different model from what she normally rides--and Kim Jae Hoon having noticeably different wardrobes between his cinematic and gameplay character models. We have reached out to the developer, SNK, for details on the trailer and will update this post as soon as we hear back.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqe1RBmJ9S8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tqe1RBmJ9S8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>If Fatal Fury is using generative AI, it wouldn't be the first game to do so. Activision confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-developers-used-ai-tools-but-creative-process-is-led-by-humans-activision-says/1100-6536232/">AI tools were used in the development of Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>, but it has insisted that the creative process "continues to be led" by humans. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-has-ai-generated-art-just-like-call-of-duty-fans-believe/1100-6537131/">fans believe that Battlefield 6 </a><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-has-ai-generated-art-just-like-call-of-duty-fans-believe/1100-6537131/">features AI-generated art</a>, and the Indie Game Awards rescinded the awards given to Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 after it was discovered that developer Sandfall Interactive <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-lost-its-indie-game-of-the-year-awards-over-ai-concerns/1100-6537129/">used AI-generated assets during the game's production</a>.</p><p>Baldur's Gate 3 developer Larian Studios has also faced backlash after it was revealed that it had been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-ceo-says-a-lot-has-been-lost-in-translation-amid-divinitys-ai-blowback/1100-6537085/">experimenting with AI tools for concept art</a>. Studio CEO Swen Vincke later addressed the controversy and explained that the studio will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-studios-draws-harder-line-on-ai-clarifies-stance-in-reddit-ama/1100-6537296/">avoid using generative AI</a> entirely in concept-art creation for its next game, Divinity.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fatal-fury-fans-spot-strange-detail-in-new-trailer-igniting-generative-ai-controversy/1100-6537425/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guild Wars 3 Rumors Just Got Resurrected by an ArenaNet Job Ad (Which Mentions Unreal Engine)]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-3-rumors-just-got-resurrected-by-arenanet-job-ad/</link>
            <guid>1407031</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>In March 2024, NCSOFT Acting Chairman <strong>Park Byeong</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-3-was-reportedly-greenlit-by-ncsoft-but-dont-get-too-excited-yet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">let it slip</a> during an investor meeting that Bellevue-based subsidiary <strong>ArenaNet</strong> had already started working on <strong>Guild Wars 3</strong>. Of course, the studio was not ready for a proper announcement yet, so its response was that they were focused on new <strong>Guild Wars 2</strong> updates and expansions (which have been released annually since 2023). Not a confirmation, but crucially, not a denial, either.</p>



<p>Nearly two years later, <strong><a href="https://job-boards.greenhouse.io/arenanet/jobs/7536965" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new job ad</a></strong> was spotted by the Internet sleuths from Reddit, reigniting discussions around the project. The ad seeks a 'Contract Senior Writer/Narrative Designer' for an unannounced project, so definitely not for new Guild Wars 2 content. The most interesting part, though, is where ArenaNet details the expertise that the would-be employee needs to have: <strong>MMOs</strong> and <strong>Unreal Engine</strong>. The former is another hint that they are indeed talking about Guild Wars 3, or whatever the next installment in the series will be called, and the latter suggests <strong>the studio might switch from its proprietary engine to Epic's game-making technology</strong>. </p>



<p>Here's a full list of what you'll need to actually have a chance, just in case anyone reading might be looking to apply:</p>



<ul>
<li><em>Bachelor’s degree in literature, creative writing, screenwriting, or related field or an equivalent combination of education, training, and experience.</em></li>



<li><em>5 years of experience as a professional writer or copyeditor, with applicable portfolio samples, including <strong>2 years of experience developing MMORPGs</strong> and open-world games</em></li>



<li><em>Experience shipping one or more AAA-quality product(s) or nongame equivalent(s), in a writing or editing capacity.</em></li>



<li><em>Understanding of general writing and narrative design concepts</em>.</li>



<li><em>Dramatic writing skills, preferably in writing for games and at least one other narrative medium (e.g., screenwriting, playwriting, prose, etc.)</em>.</li>



<li><em>Copyediting skills</em>.</li>



<li><em>Practical and philosophical editing/writing knowledge</em>.</li>



<li><em>Understanding of breaking serialized stories at the season and episode levels</em>.</li>



<li><em>Understanding of or experience in interactive and non-linear storytelling, using non-traditional and non-verbal delivery systems (e.g., environmental storytelling, in-engine storytelling without cutscenes, etc.)</em></li>



<li><em>Knowledge of character creation, story arc design, and dialogue writing</em>.</li>



<li><em>Able to learn and use proprietary tools to create content.</em></li>



<li><em>Familiar with gameplay systems</em>.</li>



<li><em><strong>Experience using Unreal Engine</strong>.</em></li>



<li><em>Excellent written and verbal communication skills.</em></li>



<li><em>Excellent organizational skills.</em></li>



<li><em>Able to work independently and in a team</em>.</li>



<li><em>Understanding of and ability to use&nbsp;The Chicago Manual of Style</em>.</li>



<li><em>Familiar with video game narratives, <strong>preferably MMOs</strong>.</em></li>



<li><em>Familiar with narrative game systems.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>ArenaNet has been posting job ads about a new online game since 2022, so it might not be long until the studio shares something in an official capacity, but there's no telling exactly when. Still, given the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/is-the-mmo-genre-dead-for-western-aaa-developers-we-asked-three-industry-veterans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">near-complete absence of new triple-A Western MMORPGs</a></strong>, Guild Wars 3 might be the only hope on the horizon.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/guild-wars-3-rumors-just-got-resurrected-by-arenanet-job-ad/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails Beyond the Horizon Lets You Screw Up Its PC Settings on Purpose]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-beyond-horizon-pc-settings</link>
            <guid>1407028</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>is packing some pretty nifty PC features, and some of those features might not be compatible with your machine, but engineering studio PH3 says it deliberately allows you to screw those settings up if you want to.</p><p>In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3316940/view/492713648032056900" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">news post</a> on Steam to mark <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-beyond-the-horizon-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a8723995-8f57-4a9a-a7d9-11340a1ec1f8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">the game's launch</a>, PH3 CTO Peter Thoman says he's learned during his time working on PC ports for games that "some players don't read", and that even when including "bright red warning text", players will push settings to Ultra and then complain about performance.</p><p>As such, Thoman says it's better to let players "shoot themselves in the foot" instead of "arbitrarily capping the high-end scalability of a game"; he believes that "a good PC version can benefit from future hardware without re-buying some remaster", which is a very refreshing attitude.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>has a refreshing attitude to PC tinkering.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Amusingly, Thoman points to one instance in <em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>in which in-game settings are hard-capped at "high"; the scene is a grain field, and without this cap, "utterly absurd amounts of individual, fully modeled stalks of grain being rendered" would become an issue at Ultra.</p><p>If, however, you do want to crank this hard-capped setting up for some reason, you can find a parameter in the settings file marked "allow_silly_grain_levels", and switching this to "true" will let you render those stalks. As Thoman says, though, there is "absolutely no reason to do this".</p><p>As well as discussing the pitfalls of porting games to PC, Thoman also says <em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>is being optimized to work with as many hardware configurations as possible.</p><p>He points to the example of one of the game's testers, who still uses an Nvidia GTX Titan, a GPU that was current about 13 years ago but which has since begun to lag behind. Surprise surprise, <em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>will support that GPU.</p>
<p><em>Trails Beyond the Horizon </em>is the latest game in <em>The Legend of Heroes</em>' ongoing <em>Trails </em>sub-series, continuing story arcs from various other <em>Trails </em>games including <em>Cold Steel </em>and <em>Daybreak</em>.</p><p>The game is available now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3316940/The_Legend_of_Heroes_Trails_beyond_the_Horizon/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10012789" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon-switch/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch</a>. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/trails-beyond-horizon-pc-settings]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Modder Uncovers Bizarre Reason Why PC Performance Might Be So Bad]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-framerate-dlc-2000660149</link>
            <guid>1407025</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113"><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i></a><span>‘</span><span> performance on PC has been notoriously bad <a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mhw-tu4-title-update-4-pc-fixed-2000652579">going back to launch</a>, and nobody is quite sure why. One new theory suggests part of the problem could be related to all of the game’s DLC add-ons and how it checks for them. It sounds wild, but video footage has made it one of the most convincing possibilities yet.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Yesterday, user u/de_Tylmarande published a rather lengthy post on the r/MonsterHunter subreddit titled “</span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1qcy3hn/mh_wilds_bad_performance_mystery_solved/?share_id=sKxGG694fIAcaycKb_Qhd&amp;utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_name=androidcss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1"><span>MH Wilds – Bad performance mystery (Solved?)</span></a><span>” As they explain, they discovered the issue by mere chance after playing </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i><span> through a friend’s Steam account. They immediately noticed that, even though they were using the same machine, </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds’ </span></i><span>FPS was dramatically better when playing the game through their friend’s account than on their own.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>After some testing, u/de_Tylmarande came to a bizarre conclusion: the only difference was that their friend had bought all of </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds’ </span></i><span>downloadable content on Steam. As they explained, “on the account with no DLC I get heavy and stable FPS drops down to like 20-25 in hubs, while on the account with all DLC bought it’s 80+ FPS.”</span></p>

  <p><span>Obviously, this claim was a little hard to believe for some users on the subreddit, so u/de_Tylmarande </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uf5cICpDXX0"><span>provided a video</span></a><span> of themselves utilizing a custom mod they created that essentially bypasses </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i><span>’ DLC checks. The theory has gone viral online as a result. </span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>But the story gets even weirder, because u/de_Tylmarande revealed that this isn’t the first time they’ve discovered a performance fix for one of Capcom’s PC games. According to them, </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1qcy3hn/comment/nzmfveb/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>they contacted Capcom</span></a><span> with an FPS fix for </span><i><span>Dragon’s Dogma 2</span></i><span> back in 2024. They claim that fix was then incorporated into the next patch for the open-world RPG on Steam.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>It’s also worth noting that </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i><span> players on PC </span><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/monster-hunter-wilds-steam-reviews-absolutely-tank-as-players-lose-patience-with-its-technical-woes-every-time-the-game-gets-updated-my-performance-decreases/"><span>have felt</span></a><span> like performance keeps getting worse with each new update. Each new update for the game also comes paired with new DLC. As of writing, </span><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/dlc/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/list/162627"><span>190 individual pieces of DLC</span></a><span> are available for the game on Steam. This new theory would explain a lot.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Capcom hasn’t yet confirmed the modder’s findings or substantiated how much of the performance issues might be attributable to the DLC checks. The Reddit sleuth also made clear that they don’t think Capcom is doing any of this on purpose to incentivize players to buy DLC. “I did NOT mean Capcom did this on purpose,” de_Tylmarande wrote in an addendum. “No, no, and again no…it’s just a bug in the code they need to fix.”</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>No word from Capcom’s end yet on the veracity of de_Tylmarande’s findings, but it will be interesting to see if the issue is suddenly resolved once the next patch for </span><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds </span></i><span>drops on PC.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-framerate-dlc-2000660149]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Teases Its Next Hero And Fans Are Already Underwhelmed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anran-hero-tease-leak-voiceline-echo-wuyang-2000660148</link>
            <guid>1407022</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>As a competitive game, </span><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i><span> is in the best state it’s ever been, but its story and hero selection are in a much more tenuous place. Blizzard is finally </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-pve-canceled-campaign-null-sector-2000641177"><span>moving the hero shooter’s narrative along</span></a><span> and teasing heroes fans have been </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-emre-sarioglu-freja-animated-trailer-who-is-1851771309"><span>waiting to learn more about for years</span></a><span>, but it’s still mostly just gesturing at forward momentum rather than making significant leaps. Now, the team is teasing the next hero coming to the game, and the character in question is arguably emblematic of the rut </span><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i><span>’s found itself in.</span></p> <p><span>Anran, a fire-wielding hero and the older sister of Wuyang, has been teased already as an upcoming hero, but it seems now she might be imminent. Blizzard released a short audio drama of gorilla scientist Winston sending out invitations to join the Overwatch team while looking at footage of Anran and Wuyang fighting Omnic soldiers.</span></p>

  <p><span>If that wasn’t enough confirmation, fans have datamined voice files of Echo, a hero who can transform into other characters, replicating what seems to be Anran’s Ultimate voice line.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">❗ Anran ultimate voicelines are ALREADY in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Overwatch2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Overwatch2</a> game files</p> <p>You can find them among Echo phrases (her imitating other heroes ultimates). Fun fact: in non-English versions of the game these lines were voiced by a new voice, potentially voice of Anran in the corresponding… <a href="https://t.co/OeIpxCVa44">pic.twitter.com/OeIpxCVa44</a></p> <p>— OverFire / Overwatch (@overfire_news) <a href="https://twitter.com/overfire_news/status/2011521527468941516?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Anran could be a great hero, but her moving this quickly up the hero queue means a few things. First, it likely means that </span><i><span>Overwatch 2 </span></i><span>is once again passing up a chance to add a new tank hero. We’ve seen Anran in action </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytZnOGwEq9s"><span>in Wuyang’s promo trailer</span></a><span>, and she seems very light on her feet and offense based, unlike the usually bulky, brawling, defensive tanks in the game. 2025 came and went without a new tank being added to the roster, with Blizzard opting to release one support character in Wuyang and two damage heroes in Freja and Vendetta, so tank mains are feeling a little burned right now.</span></p>

 <p><span>Second, </span><i><span>Overwatch 2 </span></i><span>fans have criticized the game for what they perceive to be characters “made for skin sales,” which usually means young, conventionally attractive characters who aren’t quite part of the main story, and who some feel </span><a href="https://x.com/Kagamine_asheOW/status/2011493297731375575?s=20"><span>get skins churned out for them</span></a><span> but little other attention from the devs. Some also have called out that </span><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i><span>, a game often celebrated for its diversity, has been </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-kiriko-mercy-venture-reaper-season-12-skins-1851626893"><span>showing favoritism to its east Asian heroes</span></a><span> when it comes to skins, and Anran would be </span><a href="https://x.com/LALALLALLALA21/status/2011492390415053159?s=20"><span>another character</span></a><span> who falls into that category.</span></p>

 <p><span>Not everyone is upset, mind you, but Blizzard has said a few questionable things about upcoming heroes that have fans worried about the future of the game’s hero designs. Though the team did walk it back, there was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-oddball-aspirational-character-hero-design-2000617761"><span>a brief controversy</span></a><span> last year about the game moving away from “oddball” heroes like Winston and the robot-piloting hamster Wrecking Ball in favor of “aspirational” characters. Fans took this to pretty much mean “young and hot,” and Blizzard quickly responded saying that “oddities” were still important to the game, and that a character who matches that description is in the works. We’re still waiting on them, though. I guess we’ll see them sometime after Anran, who all evidence points to being the next new hero joining in a future season.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anran-hero-tease-leak-voiceline-echo-wuyang-2000660148]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile Developer Playtika Holds Mass Layoffs, Will “Leverage” AI]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mobile-developer-playtika-holds-mass-layoffs-will-leverage-ai/</link>
            <guid>1407016</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Playtika, the mobile developer behind games like Bingo Blitz and World Series of Poker, has announced plans for mass layoffs at the company.</p>



<p>In an SEC filing on Wednesday, the company revealed its plans to cut staff as part of company-wide restructuring.</p>







<p>Playtika says that the decision comes <strong>“as part of a larger adjustment to the company’s cost structure and reallocation of<br>resources within its portfolio of games.”</strong> Overall, the company is looking to let go around 15% of its staff during the first quarter of 2026.</p>



<p>That amounts to roughly 450-500 employees for a company with over 3,000 employees globally. </p>



<h2 id="h-what-playtika-told-employees-about-the-layoffs">What Playtika Told Employees About The Layoffs</h2>



<p>As part of the SEC filing, Playtika provided the email that CEO Robert Antokol sent to staff announcing the decision.</p>



<p>In his email, Antokol said that it<strong> “was not made lightly”</strong> and that it reflects a <strong>“fundamental shift in how we operate so we can invest in the future and remain a leader in a highly competitive mobile games market.”</strong></p>







<p><strong>“For years, we operated with a broad growth mindset, applying similar resourcing models across our portfolio of games,”</strong> Antokol said. <strong>“The economic reality of our industry has shifted.”</strong></p>



<p>He continued to say that if the company didn’t adjust their strategy, it would compromise its <strong>“ability to invest in tomorrow”. </strong></p>



<p>As far as what the future holds for Playtika, Antokol said that the company is <strong>“moving away from headcount-heavy operations to streamlined teams powered by AI and automation.”</strong></p>



<p>He said that with this move, it allows Playtika to offer clearer career paths and better compensation to the employees being kept. For those being let go, Antokol said that they are “committed to treating all impacted employees with respect and compassion.” All employees will be given severance packages and “support to help ease this transition”.</p>



<p>What do you think of the layoffs at Playtika seeing nearly 500 people lose their jobs, and the company’s plan to leverage AI and automation moving forward? Leave your thoughts down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-cut-nearly-30-jobs-abu-dhabi-studio/">Ubisoft cutting nearly 30 jobs</a> at its Abu Dhabi office late last year. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/mobile-developer-playtika-holds-mass-layoffs-will-leverage-ai/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Games Workshop Reveals Best-Selling Warhammer 40,000 Army Set of All-Time, Reinforcing Just How Popular This Space Marine Chapter Truly Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/games-workshop-reveals-best-selling-warhammer-40000-army-set-of-all-time-reinforcing-just-how-popular-this-space-marine-chapter-truly-is</link>
            <guid>1407007</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop has confirmed that a recently released Warhammer 40,000 army set a sales record for the company, reinforcing this Space Marine chapter as among the most popular in the setting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Delivering Games Workshop’s latest financial results, CEO Kevin Rountree confirmed that the Space Wolves secured a new record for army set sales at the company. This relates to the Space Wolves army set that launched in May last year, and which you can see in the image below. It contains 28 brand-new miniatures, a Codex Supplement for the Great Companies of Fenris, a set of datasheet cards, and a new transfer sheet. In terms of minis, the army set includes a Wolf Guard Battle Leader, a Wolf Priest, three Wolf Guard Headtakers, 10 Blood Claws, and 10 Grey Hunters.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/15/sundaypreview-may18-40k-image1-spacewolvesarmyset-0fwzioojgu-1768482702571.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Space Wolves army set. Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Rountree called the army set format one that is “specifically designed for hobbyists who want ‘all the new miniatures’ in a release.” Clearly, it proved popular. This army set benefited from amazing-looking minis, the amount of time since the Space Wolves had seen a refresh, and the enduring popularity of the Space Wolves themselves. The Space Wolves army set is sold out at Games Workshop, leaving fans faced with the prospect of paying a markup from the likes of eBay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For the uninitiated, the Space Wolves are a long-running and legendary chapter of Space Marines heavily inspired by Norse mythology and Viking culture. They’re a savage, in your face group who like getting up close and ripping their enemies to shreds with the help of actual space wolves. Their primarch (demigod sons of the Emperor who led the original Space Marine legions before the Horus Heresy tore them apart), is Leman Russ, one of the most popular in the setting despite the fact he has never been active in the 41st millennium (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-warhammer-40000-narrative-finally-looks-set-for-a-significant-jolt-forward-after-500-worlds-book-teases-long-awaited-meeting-of-primarchs-roboute-guilliman-and-lion-eljonson">there are rumblings he may return, as Ultramarines boss Roboute Guilliman and Dark Angels chief Lion El'Jonson have</a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Space Wolves — as evidenced by their army set sales record — are right up there in terms of Space Marine chapter popularity. Without having hard data to back up this claim, I’d suggest the Ultramarines are there or thereabouts given they’re the poster boys of Warhammer 40,000, and Ultramarines captain Titus, protagonist of the hugely popular Space Marine 2 video game, is leading the tabletop wargame's next narrative expansion. But I suspect the Blood Angels (glorious space vampires with a dark secret), and the Dark Angels (righteous space crusaders) aren’t far behind.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So! I’ve put together a poll, below, with what I suspect are the likely candidates for most popular Space Marine chapter, so that IGN’s readers can vote for their favorite. For science! For the Emperor!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In other Warhammer news, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-maker-games-workshop-bans-its-staff-from-using-ai-in-its-content-or-designs-says-none-of-its-senior-managers-are-currently-excited-about-the-tech">Games Workshop has banned the use of AI in the making of its various products</a>, much to the delight of fans. And we have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-workshop-addresses-long-wait-for-henry-cavills-warhammer-40000-cinematic-universe-confirms-standalone-warhammer-age-of-sigmar-animation-for-prime-video">a brief update on Henry Cavill’s Warhammer 40,000 Cinematic Universe</a>, which still feels some way away.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Games Workshop.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/games-workshop-reveals-best-selling-warhammer-40000-army-set-of-all-time-reinforcing-just-how-popular-this-space-marine-chapter-truly-is]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Secret "Ending" For Super Mario World Has Been Discovered, And It's Grim]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-secret-ending-for-super-mario-world-has-been-discovered-and-its-grim/1100-6537424/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407004</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537424">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Even after 35 years, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/super-mario-world-review/1900-6165471/">Super Mario World</a> players are unearthing weird new possibilities in the SNES game. The latest is an unsettling ending in which Yoshi can actually eat Princess Peach, leading to Mario and his green companion just staring at each other until the end of time.</p><p dir="ltr">Supper Mario Broth showcased the grim finale for Super Mario World <a href="https://x.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/2011493949412982845" rel="nofollow ">on X</a>, noting glitches are needed to achieve this conclusion. For instance, Super Mario World players might know that bringing Yoshi into the last battle with Bowser shouldn't be possible. Well, it's not without a glitch putting the green dinosaur in the reserve item box--which houses power-ups like the Cape Feather or mushroom. The latter comes into play to consume Peach, as timing is important to have Yoshi trying to eat that as the mushroom falls and then it's replaced with the princess. Basically, this isn't an easy trick to pull off while defeating Bowser.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/2011493949412982845" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Using a combination of glitches in Super Mario World, Yoshi can be taken into the final battle, where he can eat Peach upon Bowser's defeat. With Peach gone, the ending will not play, and Mario and Yoshi will simply stare at each other forever. <a href="https://t.co/nEHGOWnmAw" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/nEHGOWnmAw</a></p>  — Supper Mario Broth (@MarioBrothBlog) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/2011493949412982845?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2026</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">This isn't the first time Supper Mario Broth has highlighted a hilarious and hidden factoid about a popular Nintendo game. In September, the account pointed out that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-characters-are-stealing-cars-gta-style-sort-of/1100-6534813/">Toad NPCs are capable of stealing cars in Mario Kart World</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">The next time we'll see Mario, Peach, and Yoshi sharing a screen together is most likely with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-plot-release-date-and-everything-we-know/1100-6536141/">The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</a>, premiering in theaters April 3. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/whoops-pillsbury-just-gave-us-a-look-at-yoshi-in-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie/1100-6536080/">Yoshi will be a new addition</a> to the cast, alongside Princess Rosalina.</p><p dir="ltr">Yoshi is also starring in his own game for Switch 2 later this year. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/yoshi-and-the-mysterious-book-looks-like-a-proper-yoshis-story-successor/1100-6534694/">Nintendo announced Yoshi and the Mysterious Book</a> during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/nintendo-direct-september-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7026/" data-ref-id="2900-7026">September 2025 Nintendo Direct</a>, which will be the first Yoshi title since Yoshi's Crafted World in 2019. Meanwhile, don't forget that Super Mario World is playable on Switch and Switch 2 with a Nintendo Switch Online subscription.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-secret-ending-for-super-mario-world-has-been-discovered-and-its-grim/1100-6537424/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta lays off staff at Batman: Arkham Shadow dev Camouflaj]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-lays-off-staff-at-batman-arkham-shadow-dev-camouflaj</link>
            <guid>1407001</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">January 15, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Camouflaj, the virtual reality developer best known for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Batman: Arkham Shadow</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, is the latest studio to be affected by this week's round of layoffs issued by Meta, its parent company.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Meta spokesperson </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/meta-game-quest-vr-facebook-deadpool-sanzaru-twisted-pixel-layoffs-2000659376">confirmed the news with Kotaku</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> yesterday evening, saying that while there have been job cuts at Camouflaj, the studio is not shutting down.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The context for the clarification is due to Meta effectively </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/extended-reality/meta-shutters-three-vr-studios-as-part-of-reality-labs-layoffs">shuttering three other VR-focused developers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> under its mantle this week, as it laid off around 10 percent of its VR/AR-focused Reality Labs division. These were </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Asgard's Wrath</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Sanzaru Games, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deadpool VR</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Twisted Pixel Games, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Resident Evil 4 VR</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Armature Studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We said last month that we were shifting some of our investment from Metaverse toward Wearables," a Meta spokesperson said to Game Developer. "This is part of that effort, and we plan to reinvest the savings to support the growth of wearables this year."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Yesterday, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://aftermath.site/meta-layoffs-camouflaj-batman-arkham-shadow/">Aftermath reported</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that Camouflaj is now made up of "just a handful of employees" who are working on "the new user experience for upcoming hardware."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Aftermath's sources, studio heads have reportedly been let go, and active game projects under development have been shut down. Moreover, sources claimed that a sequel to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Batman: Arkham Shadow</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was in development at Sanzaru, one of the studios that was closed.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/playtika-cutting-15-percent-of-global-workforce-in-pursuit-of-ai-and-automation-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Playtika cutting 15 percent of global workforce in pursuit of 'AI and automation'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Meta's Reality Labs division has been bleeding out talent and billions of dollars for the past couple of years. This week's round of layoffs is at least the third occasion that Meta has cut jobs specifically in Reality Labs, following reports in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-laying-off-workers-within-reality-labs-division">June 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-meta-has-laid-off-over-100-reality-labs-employees">April 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of Meta's fiscal report published in July 2025, Reality Labs reported an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-reality-labs-is-still-losing-billions">operating loss of $4.5 billion</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> during the second quarter ended June 30, 2025—a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/extended-reality/roses-are-red-meta-is-blue-reality-labs-lost-4-5-billion-during-q2">not-at-all uncommon occurrence</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> if you've been following previous fiscal reports along.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-lays-off-staff-at-batman-arkham-shadow-dev-camouflaj]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We Wanted To Respond To The Players’ Requests As Quickly As Possible’: SNK Discusses Releasing One FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves Character Per Month]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/we-wanted-to-respond-to-the-players-requests-as-quickly-as-possible-snk-discusses-releasing-one-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-character-per-month-season-2/</link>
            <guid>1406989</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves</strong></em> is the first entry in the celebrated fighting game series by SNK, and it has been a successful release by all metrics, <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-fighting-games-of-2025-old-and-new-challengers/"><strong>rejuvenating the franchise</strong></a> and bringing it back into the spotlight after an absence of over two decades.</p>



<p>The game's launch, however, was only the beginning. Following Season 1 which brought back both fan favorites like Andy Bogard and Joe Higashi and iconic characters from the Street Fighter series like Ken and Chun-Li, Season 2 will bring even more iconic characters like Wolfgang Krauser, Blue Mary and Kim Jae Hoon, as well as two mystery characters - one<a href="https://x.com/SNKPofficial/status/2009414900343558604"><strong> teased to be none other than <em>Kenshiro</em> from <em>Hokuto no Ken</em></strong></a> (<em><strong>Fist of the North Star</strong></em>)</p>



<p>Ahead of the Season 2 announcement, we had the chance to speak with <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves</em> Producer Shinya Tamaki and Director Hayato Konya to discuss the new character additions, the balance changes coming with a big balance patch launching on January 22 and what's in store for the future.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Interview conducted via email.</em></strong></p>



<div><h2>Table of contents</h2><ul><li><a href="#h-the-return-of-wolfgang-krauser" data-level="3">The Return of Wolfgang Krauser</a></li><li><a href="#h-the-nightmare-of-south-town" data-level="3">The Nightmare of South Town</a></li><li><a href="#h-the-monthly-cadence-and-guest-characters" data-level="3">The Monthly Cadence and Guest Characters</a></li><li><a href="#h-upcoming-balance-changes" data-level="3">Upcoming Balance Changes</a></li><li><a href="#h-the-future-of-the-game" data-level="3">The Future of the Game</a></li></ul></div>



<h3 id="h-the-return-of-wolfgang-krauser"><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">The Return of Wolfgang Krauser</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Wccftech: FATAL Fury: City of the Wolves Season 2 brings back heavyweights like Blue Mary, Kim Jae Hoon, and the legendary Wolfgang Krauser. The latter, in particular, hasn’t been a playable character of the "main" timeline for quite some time. How does his return fit into the game with the presence of Rock Howard and the legacy of Geese?</strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">(Hayato</strong><strong> </strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Konya):</strong> <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">I can't say much now without giving away major spoilers, but this character will be one of the key figures delving into “a certain issue” surrounding Rock and Geese. Please look forward to his release for further details.</em></p>



<p><strong>Wccftech: Wolfgang Krauser is fondly remembered by long-time SNK fans for his iconic Dies Irae music track. Can fans expect a new arrangement of this classic to debut alongside him, or is the sound team exploring a completely new musical direction for his arrival in South Town?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Konya):</strong> <em>This is also something we cannot talk much about at this time, so please look forward to his release.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-the-nightmare-of-south-town"><strong>The Nightmare of South Town</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Wccftech: Including Nightmare Geese as a new character is definitely an interesting choice. Since Rock has spent his life trying to escape his father’s shadow, does Nightmare Geese appear as a literal haunting/vision for Rock Howard, or is he a simple gameplay addition to bring back an iconic character in some way?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Konya):</strong> <em>Since Geese himself has died, he cannot be involved in the main storyline. Therefore, this time he appears in the game solely as the “Nightmare of South Town.” Even after death, we believe he would still be a “nightmare” for those living in South Town.</em></p>



<p><strong>Wccftech: With Jae Hoon joining the roster, the Kim family legacy is now front and centre. How does his playstyle in CotW evolve from his Garou: Mark of the Wolves days, and can we expect any "family reunions" in the future?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Konya):</strong> <em>We wanted Jae Hoon to have a different evolution than his brother. We figured he would carry and refine his father's techniques more accurately, so he will have a distinct playstyle to his MotW version. We hope you look forward to it. If both sons continue to do well, we may even see their father again someday.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-the-monthly-cadence-and-guest-characters">The Monthly Cadence and Guest Characters</h3>



<p><strong>Wccftech: Season 2 will also see the debut of two other mystery characters. Without giving too much away, can you say if the two unannounced challengers in Season 2 follow the trend of "legendary fighters" from SNK's history, or should fans expect more guest characters like Ken and Chun-Li in Season 1?</strong></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">(Shinya</strong><strong> </strong><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Tamaki):</strong> <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">We'd like to keep this information a secret for now. We are sure fans will be delighted to see who they are, so please look forward to it.</em></p>



<p><strong>Wccftech: Speaking about guest characters, what is it that would make a character a good fit for FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves? Ken and Chun-Li were designed to feel like their SF6 versions but adapted to the REV system, but for the future, would you be looking for guests that contrast the South Town style, or guests that feel like they’ve always lived there?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Tamaki):</strong> <em>As you said, we think that characters that match the world and themes of Fatal Fury make for the best fit. However, we also want to challenge ourselves in terms of game design and make this a game where you can enjoy various kinds of fighting styles and characters with unique traits. Any character that adds to the world of Fatal Fury by their inclusion, as well as a character that fans would enjoy being added, these are the two things we want to prioritize.</em></p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/FATAL-FURY-City-of-the-Wolves-Season-2-Characters-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>The FATAL FURY City of the Wolves Season 2 character lineup</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Wccftech: Releasing a character every month is a very aggressive pace for a modern 2D fighter. What led to the decision to move to this monthly cadence for Season 2, and how does your development pipeline support a quick turnaround without sacrificing quality? Is a new character every month something that should be expected in future seasons as well?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Tamaki):</strong> <em>Since this is our first Fatal Fury release in 26 years, we heard from a great number of fans that they wanted to use "this character" or "that character." As developers, we wanted to respond to the players' requests as quickly as possible, so we immediately worked to expand our development scope and capacity. As a result, we finally have the resources to be able to add one character per month starting from October 2025. We will work hard to maintain this cadence for as long as possible going forward, aiming to deliver character additions and updates to the players at a rapid pace.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-upcoming-balance-changes">Upcoming Balance Changes</h3>



<p><strong>Wccftech: With the game changing every 30 days as a new fighter joins the roster, how do you expect the competitive landscape to keep up?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Tamaki):</strong> <em>While new characters will be joining the fray, the core gameplay remains unchanged. We hope that players will leverage the skills they've honed thus far to compete and enjoy fighting with these new characters as well.</em></p>



<p><strong>Wccftech: FATAL Fury: City of the Wolves Season 2 will be accompanied by a major system-wide balance patch. What are some of the most notable changes? And what's the philosophy behind all the upcoming balance changes?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Konya):</strong> <em>In Season 1, so-called "Standard" characters stood out a bit too prominently, and we felt like characters with other concepts did not get much opportunity to shine. Starting from Season 2, we want to make adjustments that allow those kinds of characters to thrive as well.</em></p>



<p><strong>Wccftech: It has been mentioned that the update will feature system adjustments based on player feedback. What was the #1 request from the community that you were able to address in this upcoming update?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Tamaki):</strong> <em>This update releasing on 1/22 includes changes in response to the many things fans have been asking for. We believe that the long time fans have been waiting has allowed us to thoroughly refine the game, so please look forward to it and enjoy it.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-the-future-of-the-game">The Future of the Game</h3>



<p><strong>Wccftech: FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves has successfully brought the series back into the global spotlight. As we look past Season 2, what is your long-term vision for the game? Do you see City of the Wolves as a platform that will continue to grow for years to come?</strong></p>



<p><strong>(Tamaki):</strong> <em>Thank you for your kind words. As developers, we are extremely happy that we were able to bring an IP as cherished by both us and the fans as Fatal Fury back after 26 years. We are deeply grateful to the fans for the positive messages and feedback as well. This has only made us more determined to continue showing off the appeal of the wonderful world of Fatal Fury to even more players. We will continue to work hard as developers to meet fan expectations, so please look forward to the continued growth of FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves.</em></p>



<p><strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">Thank you for your time!</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/we-wanted-to-respond-to-the-players-requests-as-quickly-as-possible-snk-discusses-releasing-one-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-character-per-month-season-2/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Just Took Over 1,000 Shovelware Games Down From the PSN Store]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-shovelware-psn-store-thigames</link>
            <guid>1406986</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It looks as though Sony has just deleted the entire back catalog of a certain publisher from the PlayStation Store, which means that if you're a PS5 owner, you now have significantly fewer shovelware games to slog through when you're browsing for discounts.</p><p>As spotted by self-proclaimed "trophy hunter" <a href="https://x.com/robthanatos/status/2011487254724952207" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">RobThanatos on X</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-wiped-over-1000-shovelware-games-off-the-playstation-store-without-warning-all-from-a-single-developer" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Eurogamer</a>), all of publisher ThiGames' titles appear to have been removed from the PSN Store, which amounts to precisely 1,194 titles.</p><p>If you're unfamiliar with the work of ThiGames, perhaps some of the studio's game titles will jog your memory; it's responsible for trophy-centric games like <em>The Jumping Food Memory</em>, <em>The Jumping Orange 2</em>, and <em>The Jumping Cheese Maze</em>. You may have spotted a pattern emerging here.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>If you've browsed the PSN Store during sales, you've probably seen stuff like this.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As RobThanatos points out, ThiGames enjoyed the distinction of having the fourth highest number of games on the PlayStation Store prior to Sony's cull, beaten out only by similarly low-scope publishers Webnetic and Ratalaika, as well as niche studio eastasiasoft.</p><p>It doesn't look as though games ThiGames has yet to release have been removed, however; at time of writing, the store page for <em>The Jumping Food Memory </em>(which I'm sure will buck the trend and turn out to be an all-timer) is <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10009259" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">still up</a>.</p><p>ThiGames' titles are, or at least seem to be, low-effort releases designed to rack up trophies quickly rather than to engage or stimulate. It's often possible to collect all of the trophies in a ThiGames release in a handful of minutes.</p><p>The games are usually incredibly simple in terms of gameplay and visuals, often consisting of a single backdrop accompanied by a familiar and very basic take on an existing genre (assuming the gameplay isn't just, well, jumping, that is).</p>
<p>Whether or not this is part of a wider effort on Sony's part to crack down on <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/shovelware-importance-games-industry" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9ec3beae-77dd-466c-9dbd-b14356e65d73" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">shovelware</a> on the PlayStation Store remains to be seen, but at the very least, your trophy hunting has just gotten more difficult, it seems.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-shovelware-psn-store-thigames]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skip Buying the MacBook Air M4 on Apple’s Site, Amazon Sells It New for Cheaper Than a Refurb Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/skip-buying-the-macbook-air-m4-on-apples-site-amazon-sells-it-new-for-cheaper-than-a-refurb-model-2000659929</link>
            <guid>1406980</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple wasted no time ushering in the new year with a compelling deal on one of its most popular laptops. Just weeks into 2026, the 2025 MacBook Air has already received a notable price drop, making it far more accessible for students, professionals, and everyday users alike. Amazon i<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/">s currently offering the M4-powered MacBook Air with 256GB storage for $799, a substantial reduction from its original $999 price tag</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>At just 2.7 pounds, this latest MacBook Air remains an ideal companion for commuters, travelers, and anyone who prefers a lightweight setup without sacrificing capability. The slim chassis hides impressive hardware, including a 10-core CPU and up to a 10-core GPU, along with support for as much as 24GB of unified memory. Powered by Apple’s M4 chip, the laptop delivers a major leap in speed – up to twice the performance of the M1 Air and dramatically faster than older Intel-based models (23 times faster to be exact).</p>
<h2>Everyday Performance</h2>
<p>Apple engineered the M4 chip to work seamlessly with its growing suite of Apple Intelligence features. This means smoother multitasking, quicker responses, and improved efficiency across demanding applications. Whether you’re juggling spreadsheets, editing photos and videos, or running multiple apps and browser tabs, the MacBook Air handles it all with ease while staying cool and silent even with its fanless design.</p>
<p>Battery life remains one of the Air’s strongest advantages. With up to 18 hours of use on a single charge, it’s built to last through long workdays or extended study sessions without constantly searching for an outlet.</p>



<p>The upgraded 12MP front-facing camera captures crisp 1080p video, making it a solid choice for remote work, online classes, and video calls. Paired with a three-microphone array, voice clarity is excellent even without additional accessories.</p>
<p>Everyday usability features are well covered. The backlit Magic Keyboard offers a comfortable typing experience in any lighting condition, while Touch ID provides quick and secure access. Connectivity includes two Thunderbolt ports for high-speed data transfers and external displays, MagSafe charging for added safety, and – thankfully – a traditional headphone jack for wired audio fans who refuse to give up their AUX-powered headphones.</p>
<p>For users already invested in Apple’s ecosystem, the MacBook Air integrates effortlessly with other devices. Features like AirDrop, iMessage, and Handoff make switching between an iPhone, iPad, and Mac feel seamless.</p>
<p>Several configurations are currently discounted. The base 256GB model starts at $799, the 512GB version sits at $999. Each of those comes with 16GB of RAM. A higher-end option with 24GB of RAM and 512GB of storage is priced at $1,199. All represent a $200 cut from their original prices and are available in four finishes: sky blue, silver, starlight, and midnight.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/skip-buying-the-macbook-air-m4-on-apples-site-amazon-sells-it-new-for-cheaper-than-a-refurb-model-2000659929]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IEM Rio 2026 Team Invites Revealed by ESL]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/esl-confirms-iem-rio-2026-teams-invited/</link>
            <guid>1406977</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The countdown to IEM Rio 2026 is well underway, and in the run-up to the event, ESL has unveiled the complete lineup of teams set to compete at the upcoming CS2 spectacle. The tournament kicks off on April 13 and will run for <strong>six days</strong>, with all comers battling for the biggest piece of the $1 million prize pool in Rio de Janeiro.</p>



<p>ESL confirmed the full roster of direct invites sent on January 15, along with the spread of teams selected for the GCQ and ACQ. From these qualifiers, another three teams will surface, two coming from the global bracket and one from the Americas bracket.</p>







<h2 id="h-all-teams-confirmed-for-iem-rio-2026-by-esl">All Teams Confirmed for IEM Rio 2026 by ESL</h2>



<p>The ESL posted a graphic on social media revealing the split of teams invited to IEM Rio 2026. Here’s the full rundown:</p>



<p><strong>Direct Invites</strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>PASSION UA</li>



<li>FURIA</li>



<li>Team Vitality</li>



<li>Team Falcons</li>



<li>Spirit</li>



<li>Natus Vincere</li>



<li>MOUZ</li>



<li>Aurora Gaming</li>



<li>B8</li>



<li>Legacy</li>



<li>G2 Esports</li>



<li>Team Liquid</li>



<li>3DMAX</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Global Closed Qualifier Invites</strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>PARIVISION</li>



<li>HEROIC</li>



<li>FUT Esports</li>



<li>BC.Game Esports</li>



<li>GamerLegion</li>



<li>BetBoom Team</li>



<li>Gentle Mates</li>



<li>HOTU</li>



<li>fnatic</li>



<li>EYEBALLERS</li>



<li>K27</li>



<li>9INE</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Americas Closed Qualifier Invites:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Imperial Esports</li>



<li>Fluxo</li>



<li>BESTIA</li>



<li>YNG Sharks</li>
</ul>



<p>Fans noticed a few notable absences, namely from the organizations that were quick to decline their invites: Astralis, NiP, and FlyQuest, for instance. In the Americas Closed Qualifier, PaiN, NRG, and M80 all declined a spot.</p>



<p>There’s more than the face-value price pool to play for at <a href="https://pro.eslgaming.com/tour/2026/01/iem-rio-2026-invited-teams/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IEM Rio</a>, of course. The tournament is one of the main contributors to the ESL Grand Slam, which awards <strong>one organization </strong>$1 million. It’s the most prestigious prize in the Counter-Strike 2 space, and it’s what many of these teams play for.</p>







<p>Will you be watching IEM Rio 2026? Let us know what your predictions are looking like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/imperialhal-controller-ban-algs-championship/">ImperialHal faced a controller ban in the ALGS Champs</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/esl-confirms-iem-rio-2026-teams-invited/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BlazBlue: Entropy Effect X demo now available for PS5, Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/blazblue-entropy-effect-x-demo-now-available-for-ps5-switch</link>
            <guid>1406974</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Descend into the mysterious Sea of Possibility.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A demo for 2D <a title="Genres > Roguelite [323 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Action [3,325 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > BlazBlue: Entropy Effect X [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/blazblue-entropy-effect-x">BlazBlue: Entropy Effect X</a></em> is now available for <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10013958" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/blazblue-entropy-effect-x-switch" target="_blank">Switch</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Astrolabe Games [51 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/astrolabe-games">Astrolabe Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > 91Act [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/91act">91ACT</a> announced. <span id="more-1019135"></span></p><p>The demo features three playable characters—Ragna, Es, and Hibiki—and the first three levels of the game. While progress from the demo will not carry over to the main game, users with demo save data will receive an exclusive in-game item in the full game.</p><p><em><a title="Games > BlazBlue: Entropy Effect [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/blazblue-entropy-effect">BlazBlue: Entropy Effect</a></em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,193 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, Xbox Series, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on February 12.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/blazblue-entropy-effect-x/january-15-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Demo Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BlazBlue: Entropy Effect X - Demo Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0MUjGBViqqc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『BLAZBLUE ENTROPY EFFECT X』体験版配信開始！コアシステム紹介映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8KWs3J8QgAM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1019136"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/blazblue-entropy-effect-x-demo-now-available-for-ps5-switch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relooted launches February 10]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/relooted-launches-february-10</link>
            <guid>1406971</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Reclaim real looted African Artifacts.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Africanfuturist heist game <em><a title="Games > Relooted [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/relooted">Relooted</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,565 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3255890/Relooted/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/relooted-89fdd7" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on February 10, developer <a title="Companies > Nyamakop [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nyamakop">Nyamakop</a> announced. <span id="more-1019512"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Nyamakop:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A crew. A job. A plan. Toss those ingredients together, and you’ve got yourself a classic heist—but with a few twists. Your crew members are everyday citizens (from different countries in Africa) with pretty normal careers. The job is to liberate African artifacts from Western museums. And the plan? Well, that’s up to you to create.</p><p><strong>Africanfutur-heist</strong></p><p>Near the end of the 21st century, the political powers that be brokered a Transatlantic Returns Treaty, promising the repatriation of African artifacts from museums. Good old fashioned diplomacy was working—until it wasn’t. An amendment switched up the terms and conditions of which objects were to be returned. Museums, now knowing that only publicly displayed artifacts would be given back, were slowly removing artifacts from public display.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>When life gives you lemons and museums pulling shady moves, it’s time to chuck the lemons back at life and try a new, <a title="Genres > Stealth [107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>ier form of diplomacy. You’ve got 70 of these artifacts to (re)loot, all of which exist in real-life and are of huge cultural, historical, and spiritual significance to the people they were taken from.</p><p><strong>Teamwork Makes The Heist Work</strong></p><p>It all starts with a troublesome little brother, who, yeah, gets you into all sorts of messes. But thankfully, as Nomali, you’ll meet more reliable crew members from different African countries. Recruit people from the classic hacker to… your prim and proper grandma? Don’t worry, grandma pulls her weight.</p><p><strong>Case the Joint</strong></p><p>Plan ahead to lay the groundwork for a beautiful masterpiece of an escape. Check the getaway route, fiddle with puzzles and obstacles, and find spots to recruit the help of the right teammates.</p><p><strong>Get In. Get Out.</strong></p><p>Once you’ve set the stage carefully and the artifact is sitting all pretty—looking quite not-stolen, but no worries, you’re gonna fix that ASAP—this is the moment to perform. Plucking an artifact from its resting spot starts the countdown timer, and with Nomali’s flow-based parkour abilities, escape should feel like you’re in the fun, montage part of a heist movie. But if you slacked on the planning phase, you’re gonna pay for it!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Pull Off Heists</strong> – Plan and prepare your escape route by solving puzzles and placing teammates in the right place. When you’re ready, take the artifact and escape with Nomali’s flow-based parkour abilities.</li><li><strong>Recruit a Crew</strong> – Meet and gradually recruit different team members with their unique abilities.</li><li><strong>Explore an Africanfuturist Setting</strong> – With a Hideout based in South Africa, you’ll see parts of Johannesburg imagined in the future.</li><li><strong>Reclaim Real Artifacts</strong> – Recover 70 artifacts that exist in real-life, all of which are of huge cultural, historical, and spiritual significance to the people they were taken from.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Relooted (2026) | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iM311P33398?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/relooted-launches-february-10]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Mario Actor Discusses Taking Over For Iconic Charles Martinet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-mario-actor-discusses-taking-over-for-iconic-charles-martinet/1100-6537420/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1406965</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537420">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Actor Kevin Afghani is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-new-voice-actor-may-have-been-revealed-thanks-to-a-hacked-demo/1100-6518372/" data-ref-id="1100-6518372">new voice of Mario (and Luigi)</a>, taking over for the iconic and legendary Charles Martinet. He's now discussed taking up the mantle of voicing one of the best-known characters in gaming and entertainment in general, saying Martinet will always be Mario.</p><p>"Look, Charles, as far as I'm concerned, IS Mario," Afghani told <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/movies/2026/01/14/nintendo-new-mario-kevin-afghani-video-games/88185428007/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">USA Today</a>. "He created something that is so unbelievably iconic. And he did it so masterfully. If I wasn't nervous, then I'm the wrong guy."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="261968326" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6462452,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Super%20Mario%20Bros.%20Wonder%20%E2%80%93%20Gameplay%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:395,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/super-mario-bros-wonder-gameplay-overview-trailer\/2300-6462452\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462452\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462452\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462452\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6462452&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6462452,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537420&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;super-mario-bros-wonder&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,platformer&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;mario&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;mario&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6462452},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6462452\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4196176-44.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Ml8mcXnz.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1695390180,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Ml8mcXnz" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Super Mario Bros. Wonder – Gameplay Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Afghani said he refers to himself as "the second guy who's doing Mario," with Martinet forever standing as "<em>the </em>guy."</p><p>"There is such an unbelievable respect for Charles. He is amazing," Afghani said.</p><p>Afghani began his career as Mario with 2023's Super Mario Bros. Wonder. Asked if he now gets recognized for his role, he said it "doesn't happen very often," in part because the job he does is mostly off screen.</p><p>"Nobody thinks about who does the voice of Mario. Ever. Everybody knows who Mario is. But the second you're like, 'He has a voice actor,' it's like, 'Oh, yeah, I guess he must,'" Afghani said.</p><p>Also in the interview, Afghani dispelled the rumor that he previously did narration work for Nintendo Directs in the past. It isn't true, he said. "There's this weird narrative online I was in Nintendo Directs; I narrated Nintendo Directs. I never worked for Nintendo before being Mario," he said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-mario-actor-discusses-taking-over-for-iconic-charles-martinet/1100-6537420/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Get A PS5 And PC Update When It Arrives On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-get-a-ps5-and-pc-update-when-it-arrives-on-switch-2/1100-6537421/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1406962</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537421">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Square Enix has announced that Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade will receive an update on PC and PS5 on January 22. This patch will feature <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-gets-ridiculously-easy-mode-on-switch-2-and-xbox-series-x-s/1100-6534874/">the ridiculously easy mode previously revealed for Switch 2 and Xbox Series X|S</a>, meaning all versions of the RPG will be comparable.</p><p dir="ltr">The official Final Fantasy VII account <a href="https://x.com/finalfantasyvii/status/2011740264772305213" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> unveiled the upcoming update, calling it a celebration of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-switch-2-release-date-confirmed/1100-6534646/">the game's launch for Switch 2 and Xbox Series X|S</a>. The Streamlined Progression options include toggles to always deal 9,999 damage or have your HP maxed out. Players can also just switch on double EXP or max Gil. Basically, Square Enix is letting people decide how chill they want to make their Final Fantasy VII Remake experience.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/finalfantasyvii/status/2011740264772305213" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">To celebrate Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade launch day on Nintendo Switch 2 &amp; Xbox, a patch for the PS5 and PC versions will launch next Thursday.<br>This introduces Streamlined Progression, including the ability to keep HP and MP topped up, and always hit for 9,999 damage! <a href="https://t.co/XMuEdhreTP" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/XMuEdhreTP</a></p>  — FINAL FANTASY VII (@finalfantasyvii) <a href="https://twitter.com/finalfantasyvii/status/2011740264772305213?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Last month, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/surprise-you-can-start-playing-final-fantasy-7-remake-right-now-on-switch-2-and-xbox/1100-6537002/">a demo for Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade dropped</a> on Switch 2 and Xbox Series X|S. You can play the whole first chapter of the game on those consoles and even carry forward all of your progression to the full release next week.</p><p dir="ltr">For Switch 2 owners, be aware that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/time-to-clear-our-your-switch-2-storage-for-final-fantasy-vii-remake/1100-6536395/">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade will take up at least 90GB</a> of hardware space. That's almost 30% of the hybrid system's internal storage. The game originally came to PS4 in 2020 before arriving on PS5 and PC in 2021 with Intergrade tacked on to the title. This edition also comes with a story expansion starring Yuffie.</p><p dir="ltr">Be sure to check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-review-materia-improvements/1900-6417445/">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade review</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-get-a-ps5-and-pc-update-when-it-arrives-on-switch-2/1100-6537421/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Charts: Nintendo's Dominance Continues As Switch 2 Flies Past 4 Million Units Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/japanese-charts-nintendos-dominance-continues-as-switch-2-flies-past-4-million-units-sold</link>
            <guid>1406935</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="b7b82d0662eb0"><a title="Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b7b82d0662eb0/switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The first two weeks' sales data of 2026 is in from <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63273">Famitsu</a>, and it'll come as a surprise to nobody to hear that the Switch 2 is still <em>dominating</em> the proceedings.</p>
<p>It's yet another Switch 1/2 washout in the software chart to kick off the new year, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> leading the charge, followed by Konami's immensely popular <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/momotaro_dentetsu_2_anata_no_machi_mo_kitto_aru_-_higashi_nihon_hen_plus_nishi_nihon_hen">Momotaro Dentetsu</a> board game sequel. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> continues to stay hot on both consoles, and it'll be interesting to see how far <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> moves up the ranking once the sales data for the Switch 2 Edition is in.</p>
<p>Here's the latest top ten physical sales in Japan:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Game</th>
<th>Platform</th>
<th><strong>Unit Sales</strong> <strong>(29th Dec - 11th Jan)</strong></th>
<th>Total Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>
<p>Mario Kart World</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>92,869</td>
<td>2,761,250</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/shin_megami_tensei_v_vengeance"><br></a></td>
<td>
<p>Momotaro Dentetsu 2: Anata no Machi mo Kitto Aru – Higashi Nihon Hen + Nishi Nihon Hen</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>61,588</td>
<td>
<p>294,142</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>
<p>Momotaro Dentetsu 2: Anata no Machi mo Kitto Aru – Higashi Nihon Hen + Nishi Nihon Hen - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>52,848</td>
<td>241,383</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>
<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>52,360</p>
</td>
<td>1,056,514</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>
<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>47,840</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1,577,663</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>
<p>Kirby Air Riders</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>47,712</td>
<td>472,549</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>
<p>Donkey Kong Bananza</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>24,974</td>
<td>460,180</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>
<p>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>23,057</td>
<td>149,493</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>
<p>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>22,944</td>
<td>
<p>8,334,062</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td>
<p>Minecraft</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>18,843</td>
<td>
<p>4,128,035</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p>Nintendo hardware has started the new year with a bang, with Switch 2 shifting a crisp 313,838 units in the first two weeks and sailing past four million Japanese sales as a result. The Switch Lite and OLED models hang in there, too, but it's the PS5 Digital Edition that takes the silver this time, with an additional 36,856 sales to its name.</p>
<p>The three Switch 1 SKUs combine for 46,360, while the PS5 models total in at 46,753 — talk about a close-run contest!</p>
<p>Here's a look at the week's full hardware charts:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Console</th>
<th><strong>Unit Sales</strong> <strong>(</strong>29th Dec - 11th Jan)</th>
<th>Lifetime Unit Sales</th>
</tr><tr><td colspan="100%"></td></tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>313,838</td>
<td>4,097,905</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>36,856</td>
<td>
<p>1,154,384</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>
<p>Switch Lite</p>
</td>
<td>18,460</td>
<td>6,822,925</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Switch OLED</td>
<td>16,916</td>
<td>9,414,838</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>10,984</p>
</td>
<td>20,224,740</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5</p>
</td>
<td>6,033<br></td>
<td>5,875,458<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7<br></td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Pro</p>
</td>
<td>3,864<br></td>
<td>315,121<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>149<br></td>
<td>24,860<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series S</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>103</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>340,464</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>29</p>
</td>
<td>323,884<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11<br></td>
<td>PlayStation 4<br></td>
<td>
<p>25</p>
</td>
<td>7,930,176</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/japanese-charts-pokemon-legends-z-a-surpasses-1-million-sales-on-switch-2">&lt; Previous charts</a></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196160 @ 1768491865 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on this week's Japanese charts? Let us know down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63273" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63273">famitsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1768492220 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/japanese-charts-nintendos-dominance-continues-as-switch-2-flies-past-4-million-units-sold]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds' Poor PC Performance Could Be Down to a DLC Check]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-poor-pc-performance-dlc-check-report</link>
            <guid>1406932</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>launched almost a year ago, and since it released, players have been complaining about poor PC performance despite having machines more than capable (theoretically, at least) of handling things. Now, we might know why.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1qcy3hn/mh_wilds_bad_performance_mystery_solved/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">lengthy post</a> on Reddit, user de_Tylmarande outlines an experimental process by which they attempted to glean the reason behind <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' PC performance, which Capcom has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-optimizations-winter" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="69cb0344-d686-4265-ba86-2163d899fb4c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">acknowledged and pledged to fix</a> (the performance, not the post).</p><p>To boil the post down, de_Tylmarande essentially noticed that when playing <em>Wilds </em>on their friend's Steam account, which owns all of the available DLC, the frame rate was stable and there were no drops. On their own account, however, de_Tylmarande experienced frequent drops.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>The cause of <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' poor PC performance may have been solved.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This naturally led the user to conclude that <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' frame drops and PC problems are down to what they call "an insanely crooked and aggressive DLC ownership check function".</p><p>In order to prove their theory, de_Tylmarande created a sort of mod that essentially fools <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>into thinking the player owns all of its associated DLC. The mod doesn't actually unlock any of that DLC; instead, it just tricks the game into passing the check.</p><p>According to de_Tylmarande, once that mod was in place, "performance went through the roof". They stress that they don't recommend trying this solution and don't promote "using mods of this type" in <em>Wilds</em>, but that they did so in order to prove a point.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1qcy3hn/comment/nzlrkxg/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">response</a>, a user suggests that this issue might be an example of "good enough for now" code being left in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, then never being fixed, leading to unpredictable problems later down the line. It's entirely possible.</p>
<p>In any case, unless you're looking to create a mod like de_Tylmarande's yourself (which they don't suggest), it's unlikely you'll be able to solve this problem for yourself. Still, it's an interesting thing to ponder.</p><p>The poor PC performance players have reported didn't stop <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-8m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a0bfff7f-18bd-4b40-b07b-fe8c94d70a1a" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">selling like hot cakes</a> in its initial <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-sales-10m" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3047bd12-37c9-4b65-bd39-064968be79fa" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">launch window</a>, although sales have since slowed, with Capcom blaming that slowdown not on the PC version, but <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-ps5-barrier-capcom" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a0c5ff11-5fb9-4929-804b-8a8d4f7adae0" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">the PS5 release</a>.</p><p>You can check out <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9NMT6XFN0LVD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read our very own Tyler's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="4b7be4a2-09a5-4299-a13c-a7bff937e081" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">review of the game here</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-poor-pc-performance-dlc-check-report]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>