<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 17:30:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tactical Breach Wizards Review - Breach and Seer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tactical-breach-wizards-review-breach-and-seer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tactical-breach-wizards-review-breach-and-seer.957000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/tactical-breach-wizards-review-breach-and-seer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You might not know them by name, but developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-developer-tips-shared-by-gunpoint-dev-tom-francis">Suspicious Developments</a> has been around the indie scene for quite a while. The creators of <em>Gunpoint</em> and <em>Heat Signature</em> are back with what might just be their best game yet, which is saying a lot since this studio takes risks and isn't afraid to be weird and different.</p>
<p>So for their latest game, <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em>? Like I said, it's definitely weird and different, but also cleverly designed and wildly inventive.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat.jpg?itok=gk2wk9fC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat.jpg?itok=VW6EJeaC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Throwing someone out of a moving train is also an option.</figcaption></figure><h2>Hurling Baddies Out of Windows in <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em></h2>
<p>Here's a little lesson on defenestration. Even as an English major, I hadn't heard of this word, but once you learn it, it captures the essence of <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> quite well. To defenestrate someone is to throw them out of a window, which goes to show there truly is a word for everything.</p>
<p>On the surface, one wouldn't put wizards and throwing folks out of windows together, but <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> says otherwise. As a <a href="https://techraptor.net/genre/turn-based-tactics">turn-based tactics</a> game, you use the magical powers of your units to move enemies around in strategic ways -- usually involving windows.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-objectives.jpg?itok=LCmLjC_e 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-objectives.jpg?itok=lL-Jl1wG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In the absence of windows, there's always alternatives... like hacking the turret here.</figcaption></figure><p>In this regard, the strategic elements of <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> follows the same philosophy as <em>Into the Breach</em>: using abilities to move enemies into positions that put them at a disadvantage or outright dispose of them. You can approach each mission like it's a puzzle and you'll do just fine -- finding how to optimize your strategy and defeat enemies in the least amount of turns is half the fun.</p>
<p>With quite a few missions across a roughly 15 hour campaign, <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em>' employs exceptional level design and combines that with an array of powers that make anything seem possible. Mission objectives are often accompanied by secondary, optional tasks that add a bit more difficulty, and in turn, variety.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-lore-2_0.jpg?itok=OKSTNtAt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-lore-2_0.jpg?itok=cpnKQzDj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I'm sure you can figure out who the main characters are.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Colorful Cast of Characters in <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em></h2>
<p>But the real star of the show are your units themselves. As you progress across <em>Tactical Breach Wizard</em>'s campaign, you'll recruit a few extra members. Once your party is complete, everything comes together and a whole world of possibilities are revealed.</p>
<p>Jen and Zan are the first two units players start with, and this duo starts out a bit underwhelming but become powerhouses as time goes on. Now Jen, she's especially useful when it comes to defenestration, as her abilities push enemy units pretty far. She can even chain together lightning to push around multiple enemies at once, so you can just imagine the possibilities she offers.</p>
<p>Zan, on the other hand, is arguably the most important unit in the game. This multi-talented Navy Seer has the ability to create mirages that distract enemies and even shoot at them later on. The attack with his weird-ass gun/staff hybrid moves enemies a bit, too, so on top of dealing a lot of damage, he can also move people around.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-4.jpg?itok=SevyADGs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-4.jpg?itok=nNsUVhAr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Dessa might just be the most fun to play, but that's just my preference.</figcaption></figure><p>His quintessential power is that of foresight, enabling players to make moves <em>before</em> a turn ends and see how solutions play out -- and thankfully, this ability extends to other units even when he's not in a battle. This allows you to commit and experiment, so <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> encourages players to test out different strategies rather than punish you for silly mistakes.</p>
<p>The other units that'll join you are extremely helpful in their own right, like Dessa. She's a necromancer, so she can revive teammates, but don't just think of her as your traditional healer. She has some awesome abilities, like a spell that creates Death's Door that, when you push an enemy into it, they're thrown into the void, never to return. Now <em>that</em> is metal.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-2.jpg?itok=Tesd04Yu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-2.jpg?itok=R6dAjl6M 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You might not be able to walk from building to building here, but with spells, there is a way.</figcaption></figure><h2>Spells: <em>Tactical Breach Wizards' </em>Tools of the Trade</h2>
<p>Here's how one scenario could play out: use Dessa to put Death's Door on a wall behind another of your units, Dall. Use Dall to swap with an enemy halfway across the map. Now that the enemy is in close range to your other allies, have Zan use a spell to push the enemy into the door and have them removed from combat for good.</p>
<p>Two more characters join you, and it's when all five members of the party are together that <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> shows its full potential. Only a few missions will have all members of the team on at each time and you can't choose, so I would have liked to see them all in action at the same time more often.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-3.jpg?itok=JPDJMUHT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-combat-3.jpg?itok=6lDUCrrf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>As time goes on, missions start to feel a bit more ambitious.</figcaption></figure><p>Nonetheless, the ever-expanding arsenal of abilities and even skill trees keep each unit more or less on par with the others. I can't begin to imagine the work it took to create levels revolving around so many unique abilities, but they make it work.</p>
<p>Environmental hazards like exploding barrels and electrified walls on top of the copious amount of windows means you can and should take full advantage of the environment around you, especially since enemies become more complex in their own abilities as time goes on. <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> is a game that demands to be broken, and with your teammates, nothing seems impossible.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-dialogue.jpg?itok=ZXRR7x1_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-dialogue.jpg?itok=yrrkyyDh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Um, okay?</figcaption></figure><h2>Tactical Breach Wizards' is Quirky, Alright</h2>
<p><em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> leans pretty hard into the narrative side of things, so it pains me to say it didn't captivate me nearly as much as the gameplay did. There's a lot of back-and-forth dialogue, which in itself is fine<em>, </em>but it has to be intriguing to keep my attention. This is not the case, and in fact, turns out to be more annoying than anything else.</p>
<p>The characters are pretty goofy and quip at one another, so dialogue is definitely more lighthearted and jokey than anything else. Try as <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> might to be humorous, it didn't resonate with me at all. I wanted to like the characters, but some of the things they said to each other were just so unrealistic and weird, it was hard to get over.</p>
<p>The goofy dialogue and the serious content of the story clash with one another. The stakes of the plot are high, so for the characters to be these goofballs the whole time while attempting to stop a giant war feels wrong.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-lore.jpg?itok=-Oo9WSTZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-lore.jpg?itok=pB0BB_v4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Don't do mana dust, kids.</figcaption></figure><p>We're led to believe every single enemy we defeat isn't killed, even though some of them are quite evil. We're throwing enemies out of windows, slinging spells, and knocking explosive barrels into them. That's not something you can just walk away from alive.</p>
<p>Even still, the world-building is admirable, if a bit messy. <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> drops you into the deep end and creates a modern fantasy world where Traffic Warlocks and the Druid Mafia are just everyday things. Some elements of this world can be pretty funny, even if the vast majority of dialogue suffers from too many jokes.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-outfits.jpg?itok=I9VhYfaN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tactical-breach-wizards-outfits.jpg?itok=mitXPK_p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Cosmetics are always welcome! All you need is a little confidence.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Tactical Breach Wizards </em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>I usually play turn-based tactics games with a controller, but <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> makes that difficult. The Gamepad's joystick moves a mouse cursor on the screen, which is a huge pet peeve of mine. It only ends up making the controller an absolute burden to use.</p>
<p>Using a controller for most tactics games makes things quick and snappy, but it's the exact opposite here. It feels like you're swimming against the current where instead, gamepad should be an easy alternative to mouse and keyboard controls.</p>
<p>It's easy to forgive <em>Tactical Breach Wizard</em>'s shortcomings when the core gameplay itself is so inventive and addicting. It's definitely one of those games where you'll be surprised by your own ingenuity, and <em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em> encourages you to think outside the box. So go on -- defenestrate to your heart's content!</p>
<hr><p><strong>Tactical Breach Wizards</strong><em> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of around 15 hours of gameplay. All screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div>
<h2>Review Summary</h2>

<p>
Tactical Breach Wizards delivers a fresh and addicting tactical experience. Using an array of awesome spells, there are limitless ways to complete the mission, making for a very inventive experience. Now, if only the story was up to snuff... (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Pros</h3>
<div><ul><li>Creative Map Design</li><li>Great Variety in Unit Abilities</li><li>Ingenuity Feels Rewarding and Addicting</li></ul></div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Cons</h3>
<div><ul><li>The Weird, Humorous Tone Doesn't Appeal to Me</li><li>Using a Controller is Not Optimal</li></ul></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy faces no "existential risk" despite lower-than-hoped PS5 sales, says FF16 director]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-faces-no-existential-risk-despite-lower-than-hoped-ps5-sales-says-ff16-director</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-faces-no-existential-risk-despite-lower-than-hoped-ps5-sales-says-ff16-director.956997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-faces-no-existential-risk-despite-lower-than-hoped-ps5-sales-says-ff16-director<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>FF16 PC port release date arrives alongside demo</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff16-eyes.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Please lock your Chocobos to attack position and set your Phoenix Downs to stun: Square Enix have released fresh details of Final Fantasy 16's PC port, which has now been dated for launch on 17th September. They've also shared a little about why it's taken so long to arrive - the (generally decent) action-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> hit PS5 over a year ago, back when I was still some filthy <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-review-16-easy-to-like-hard-to-adore">console-playing freelancer</a>.</p>
<p>According to director Hiroshi Takai, it was "impossible" to create the PC and PS5 versions at the same time, even if Square Enix hadn't been restrained by a timed exclusivity clause. He also thinks that the Final Fantasy series faces no "existential risk" right now, despite lower-than-hoped returns from both Final Fantasy 16 and, going by Square Enix's latest financial reports, the more recent and currently PS5-only Final Fantasy 7: Rebirth.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC3oQe1EtYY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Final Fantasy has a track record for showing up fashionably late on PC - it took Final Fantasy 7: Rebirth, first of the FF7 reboots, well over a year to land on Epic Games Store following its PS4 launch. As regards Final Fantasy 16 specifically, Square Enix had to work around a six month exclusivity deal with Sony and PS5 following the initial release in June 2023. Producer Naoki Yoshida has also indulged in a touch of bait-and-switch with journalists, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nobody-said-a-word-about-a-pc-version-says-final-fantasy-16-producer">jocularly denying that Square Enix had ever announced the game for PC</a> at one point. I suspect the uneven communication there has less to do with trolling than with the unpredictable nature of game development.</p>
<p>"The reasons vary for each title, but in the case of FFXVI, it primarily comes down to the original game being tailored for the PS5 in a lot of different ways, and it was impossible to do this at the same time as all the optimization work that was needed for the PC version," Takai told me over email, when I asked why this and other Final Fantasy games tend to arrive later on PC. He was unable to tell me anything about the specifics of the PC version's development, other than that this is the same team who made the original PS5 version.</p>
<p>So what do PC Final Fantasisers get for their patience? For starters, the port will accompany a Complete Edition which includes two DLC packs, Echoes Of The Fallen and The Rising Tide. I haven't played either of those, but they seem reasonably juicy. Echoes Of The Fallen's offerings include a new final dungeon, while Rising Tide packs a new region, an endgame mode and new abilities for this iteration's protagonist Clive Rosefield - "Devil May Clive", as I boisterously call him down the pub, forgetting that all my friends got sick of that joke over Xmas.</p>
<p>Square Enix have also added a bunch of new graphics and performance settings, as you'd expect. "Since PC gamers all have different PCs with different specs, we've provided extensive configuration options to maximize flexibility," Takai told me. "We've increased the frame rate cap to 240fps, and you can choose from various upscaling technologies such as NVIDIA DLSS3, AMD FSR, and Intel XeSS." </p>
<p>Argh, so many letters and numbers! Where is hardware editor James to translate? Oh dang, I think he's gone to Gamescom. I feel like Final Fantasy games should have their own bespoke jargon for graphics features, blending third-party terminology with the series own naming conventions. Any PC RPG can boast of supporting upscaling, but only a Final Fantasy game could get away with e.g. Fabula Nova CrystaLSSIII or AMD Fenrir Shiva Ragnarok.</p>
<p>Square Enix have made a big noise about pushing beyond console lately. In May this year, the publishers promised "aggressive" expansion to other platforms, perhaps in light of the fact that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-sales-did-not-meet-high-expectations-says-square-enix-president">FF16 did not meet the company's expectations on PS5</a>. They said they wanted to "win over PC users" especially. With that in mind, I asked Takai whether Square Enix feels the audience for Final Fantasy games differs much between console and PC. "That's a difficult question!" he said, before proceeding to answer it very straightforwardly. </p>
<p>"Honestly, there's not much difference between playing games on PC and consoles these days, so I don't know if there's any real difference when it comes to FF fans," Takai commented. "However, more people have access to a PC, so I'm hoping we can get the game into the hands of a broader audience of gamers with the PC version."</p>
<p>The company have yet to share sales of Final Fantasy 7: Rebirth, which released on PS5 in February, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sales-drop-year-on-year-despite-release-of-final-fantasy-7-rebirth">they have reported a year-on-year overall game sales drop</a>, offset by relatively steady returns from subscription-based MMO Final Fantasy 14. All this notwithstanding, Takai doesn't think the Final Fantasy series has become unsustainable and in need of a fundamental rethink, not least because Square Enix are always rethinking it.</p>
<p>"While it's always important to balance development costs with sales, I don't think there's any kind of existential risk for the series," he told me. "As developers, we just need to keep creating what we think is fun - and if players think to themselves, 'they went in a new direction this time, but it was still fun', then maybe that's all the dramatic change we need."</p>
<p>If you're curious about FF16 on PC, I've saved the best for last: there's now a demo on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2738000/FINAL_FANTASY_XVI_DEMO/">Steam</a> and the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/final-fantasy-xvi-demo-c289c2">Epic Games Store</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 6 Zombies Might Have An Early-Access Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-might-have-an-early-access-launch/1100-6525925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-might-have-an-early-access-launch.956985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-might-have-an-early-access-launch/1100-6525925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525925">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> arrives later this year with the return of Treyarch's iconic round-based Zombies mode. While an official announcement about early access hasn't been made by Activision, leaks suggest that players could get to play Zombies one week before the game's launch on October 25.</p><p dir="ltr">As seen in the post below, <a href="https://x.com/Tridzo/status/1825211847953486085" rel="nofollow ">content creator Tridzo</a> claims that, when viewing the PlayStation dashboard, Zombies is listed as playable on October 17, which is a week before the official release. Recent Call of Duty launches have included one week of campaign early access, but Activision haven't announced any early-access plans for campaign or Zombies.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Tridzo/status/1825211847953486085" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps6</a> Zombies may have an ENTIRE Week of Early Access.<br>Playstation dashboard says the game will be playable on Oct 17th. One week before the official release.<br>Would you rather have Zombies or Campaign Early Access? <a href="https://t.co/bRIdWtGegA" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/bRIdWtGegA</a></p>  — Tridzo (@Tridzo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Tridzo/status/1825211847953486085?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 18, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Black Ops 6 has suffered several leaks due to a version of the game being uploaded to the PSN database. These leaks include gameplay <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-leaks-continue-this-time-with-a-graphic-new-ability/1100-6525547/">showing off new game mechanics</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-leaks-reveal-a-controversial-warzone-map-with-caldera-2-0-vibes/1100-6525560/">a potential Warzone map</a>, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">If early access is planned for Zombies mode, the announcement could potentially arrive next week during Activision's Call of Duty: Next event on August 28. The showcase will include live gameplay for multiplayer, the reveal of the Liberty Falls Zombies map, and announcements about the future of Warzone.</p><p>Players can get early access for multiplayer during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/">Black Ops 6 beta</a>. The first week of the beta begins on August 30, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-preload-begins-soon-file-sizes-revealed/1100-6525838/">preload details can be found here</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">For more on Black Ops 6 Zombies, make sure to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-gameplay-reveal-and-everything-we-know/1100-6525644/">check out our highlights of all the major announcements</a>, including story details, a new Wonder Weapon, updated game features, and more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Classic Bully Launches On New Platforms Via GTA+ This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstar-classic-bully-launches-on-new-platforms-via-gta-this-week/1100-6525916/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-classic-bully-launches-on-new-platforms-via-gta-this-week.956982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstar-classic-bully-launches-on-new-platforms-via-gta-this-week/1100-6525916/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525916">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockstar Games' new GTA+ subscription service offers a rotating library of games by the Grand Theft Auto developer, and Bully is next on tap. Rockstar announced back in April that Bully and LA Noire would be coming to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/la-noire-and-bully-free-for-gta-members-this-year-along-with-millions-in-gta-online-cash/1100-6522333/" data-ref-id="1100-6522333">GTA+</a> "later this year." A recent post on the developer's site <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/o337151o33aa79/the-new-benefactor-vorschlaghammer-sedan-free-with-gta" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that Bully will be available through GTA+ starting on August 20.</p><p dir="ltr">A listing on the Taiwan Digital Game Rating Committee indicates that a version of the game called Bully (Canis Canem Edit) is coming soon to new platforms, including PS5, Xbox Series X|S, PS4, Xbox One, and PC (per <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bully-rated-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-pc-in-taiwan">Gematsu</a>). An emulated version of the PS2 classic is available to buy on PS4, and previous re-release Bully: Scholarship Edition has been <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/12200/Bully_Scholarship_Edition/" rel="nofollow ">out on Steam</a> for over a decade.</p><p dir="ltr">GTA+ is a rotating library, but it's unclear if this new Bully will replace any of the service's existing offerings, which include LA Noire, Red Dead Redemption, GTA Trilogy, GTA: Liberty City Stories, and GTA: Chinatown Wars. GTA+ offers a variety of benefits in addition to these older Rockstar titles, including a monthly $500,000 deposit in GTA currency, multipliers on currency earned within GTA Online, a new vehicle workshop, and access to an app that makes vehicle requests easier. Rockstar <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ahead-of-gta-6-release-rockstar-raises-gta-price-by-33/1100-6522616/" data-ref-id="1100-6522616">increased the cost</a> of the GTA+ service from $6 to $8 a month back in April.</p><p dir="ltr">One of Rockstar's most beloved games of the PS2 era, reports of a shelved Bully sequel emerged <a href="https://x.com/lyluancake/status/1825204275238322593" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">back in 2022</a>. That hypothetical Bully 2 would've come out in the early 2010s, but was ultimately canceled. As for newer projects, Rockstar plans to release Grand Theft Auto 6 next fall, though it's very possible the game is delayed beyond that point.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Let's compare the narrative design of Tactical Breach Wizards and Into the Breach]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/let-s-compare-and-contrast-the-narrative-design-of-tactical-breach-wizards-and-into-the-breach</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lets-compare-the-narrative-design-of-tactical-breach-wizards-and-into-the-breach.956976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/let-s-compare-and-contrast-the-narrative-design-of-tactical-breach-wizards-and-into-the-breach<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Suspicious Developments.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Some spoilers for </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Tactical Breach Wizards </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>ahead</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I love Suspicious Developments' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and Subset Games' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (not as much as editor-in-chief Danielle Riendeau does, but hey I do my best). Both games boil down the essence of grid-based turn-based tactical games like Firaxis' XCOM series to simple simple, efficient forms, and each gives players some degree of autonomy to test out different moves before committing to a full turn.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There's plenty to learn comparing the design decisions around both games, but I've been fixated one major point of divergence: how each game approaches narrative design.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Their strategies are completely different. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> makes the most of a sparse storytelling strategy, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> weaves an international escapade with snappy dialogue, fully-fleshed out characters, and a "red string" investigation board that helps players understand the who, what, where, when, and why of the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With such similar game design fundamentals, we have a window to explore how each game's low-budget (but still high-impact) methods improve—or maybe at times worsen—the experience.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Into the Breach"><span>Into the Breach</span> goes for a (lean, and maybe too mean), narrative</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Subset Games took a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>very </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">light-handed approach to game narrative, stripping the game story back to very simple elements. The player controls a team of mech pilots jumping from timeline to timeline, fending off a neverending invasion of alien bugs on the verge of overwhelming Earth.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a data-discover="true" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/tactical-breach-wizards-shows-how-strategy-games-can-tickle-the-funny-bone" target="_self">Tactical Breach Wizards shows how strategy games can tickle the funny bone</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On each run they encounter different leaders for each of the four "zones" they can explore who offer brief context on the game mechanics unique to each zone, and comment on the players' successes and failures at achieving mission objectives. After the player begins the final mission, one specific leader gives them instructions for how to blow up the bugs for good. If the player is defeated at any point, or if they win, these leaders (and their own pilots) will lament their defeat or celebrate their win before sending the player to the next timeline.</span></p><p>Image via Subset Games.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The pilot characters offer an equally sparse amount of dialogue, though they stand out by their unique reactions to being damaged, killing bugs, or protecting civilians in each mission. Their visual design and barks offer brief glimpses of their backstories and motivations, expanding the scope of the game world by implying the existence of alien creatures and fully-sentient artificial intelligence.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Aaaaand that's it. Even though this game pays tribute to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/why-do-game-developers-love-mechs-">thunderous mechs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of Gundam, Battletech, and Neon Genesis Evangelion, it tosses out the dense political and sometimes religious themes that accompany each series. This approach compares to the "narrative design" of a board game: the goal isn't to tell a linear narrative, but to use the essence of narrative to inspire players to engage with the core mechanics. Those core mechanics are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>really really really really good</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but never build up to a grand finale.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A deeply-invested player can take inspiration from different pilot characters to decide their moves, but most players focused on winning will only be lightly influenced by these trappings. They mostly add an element of "oh that's cool" while you scan their related abilities.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This approach is far easier for production, as game writer Chris Avellone (who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/fallout-new-vegas-writer-chris-avellone-settles-sexual-assault-allegations">in 2023 settled sexual assault allegations levied at him</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) could prioritize unique, clever character barks instead of stressing over everyone's motivations and how they'd drive the plot.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I find there are flaws in its simplicity. This method never gives the player an "off ramp" to put down the game. The Subset Games team correctly identified that getting players quickly from run to run would drive interest more than any amount of dialogue, and the dense gameplay and promise of unlocking new tools would motivate players invested in the turn-based tactics.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But because there's no definitive finale (or even the illusion of one), most players' time with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will end with them ending a session and then just...never picking it up again. There isn't a killer last memory to leave players with, one they'll want to tell other prospective players about—there's just a vibe of "oh, I've seen all there is to see."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This decision also reflects in the themes and "vibes" of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s story. If you care about saving the worlds at all, this game's story is downright Sisyphean. The alien invasion can never be beaten back, and only a fraction of a fraction of the infinite universes can be saved. After a while I felt myself going "what's the point?" I'd regularly sacrifice worlds just to preserve pilots I'd heavily invested in, treated the end of the world as an inevitability and not something worth fighting for.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">By the time I put down </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Into the Breach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, I'd spent hours and hours delighting over the turn-based tactical synergy, but I didn't feel proud of the worlds I'd saved (especially because there's no way to reconnect with them), I just felt like it wasn't worth saving any more.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Tactical Breach Wizards"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span> celebrates its "loveable idiots"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> tells its tale on a shoestring budget—there's no voice acting, cutscenes have very simple animations, and Suspicious Developments put in effort to ensure players who only want to engage with the turn-based strategy game can skip as much as possible and get right to the tactical defenestrating. But for those who dive into the plot, they'll find Tom Francis' dry dialogue and sincere characters ready to engage with them.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The plot is ambitious, but possibly difficult-to-follow for players hyperfocused on the turn-based tactics. In an alternate Earth where video game-style magic is real, Magic users Zan, Jen, and their comrades race to stop a rogue group of commandos trying to kick off a catastrophic world war. Zan has a personal connection with the lead antagonist Liv Kennedy, Jen is struggling to find purpose in her post-enlisted life, and the rest of the crew has their own hangups worth digging into.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There are other design efficiencies you can spot in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. A lot of dialogue beats play out between encounters with two characters facing each other on either side of a door. It's a familiar, repeating beat that saves on character animation and captures the sense of two people arguing or debating while they should be focused on the fight around them (something the fight mines for comedy). Jokes and character reactions are sometimes nestled in the user interface, giving players a chuckle when they go check relevant data.</span></p><p>Image via Suspicious Developments.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The most ambitious narrative swing is in the personal "dreams" of each character. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has a bit of fun treating its "optional" missions as the characters gaming out combat scenarios while they sleep. These missions can have more creative setups, like including multiples of characters that couldn't appear in the game's main story.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Then the game goes a step further, creating optional missions that are crafted around each character in the squad. In the first of these, Storm Witch Jen is confronted by her own inner critic, and the pair argue while blasting away the enemies inside her own mind.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The international conspiracy element of the story is a little bit "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Putting%20a%20hat%20on%20a%20hat">putting a hat on a hat</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" (one character even points out that the gang hasn't progressed in their core objective for two missions), but it's hardly a great narrative sin.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The narrative design is fun! Suspicious Developments does a great job weaving the dialogue-driven tale in with charming vignettes with the same assets used in gameplay. They make for a nice respite between missions, and play nicely with the "slow and brain-stimulating" nature of its turn-based tactical combat.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I don't want to play the mission just to see the next puzzle, I want to play to see what happens next in this fantasy thriller.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="So which narrative style is better?">So which narrative style is better?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's not helpful to say any one way of making games or telling stories is objectively "better." Stories (and games) are experienced subjectively, and plenty of folks may bounce off of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">' narrative design, wishing that time had gone into new missions instead.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But...</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I believe more developers should follow in Suspicious Developments' footsteps, and squeeze every ounce of story out of their game that they can.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In my decade or so writing about games (and occasionally working on them) I've crossed paths with developers frustrated by how resource-consuming narrative design can be. They're tired of games bogged down by cutscenes, dialogue, or gigantic tomes full of way-too-dense-and-not-useful worldbuilding. They'd prefer to focus on efficient design and fantastic art direction. "Most game writing is really bad," is a phrase I've heard from a few professionals.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Swing by the the GDC Narrative Summit and you'll hear great arguments about how good storytelling will make your game appealing to players. That's true, but it can force writers to re-stage this argument over and over again to justify each story for each kind of game they work on.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I'd put it like this: good storytelling isn't just good for your players, it's good for you too.</span></p><p>Image via Suspicious Developments.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Suspicious Developments founder Tom Francis pulled double-or-triple duty designing, coding, and writing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. While playing, I could feel him getting something out of his brain and into the world that you can't do just by writing a blog or lobbing ideas around with friends. His ideas about how games should play and how people experience the world are imparted to the player while they figure out the best way to tactically yeet a traffic cop named Steve out a window.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"But I'm not as good a writer as Tom Francis," you might say. That's okay! I've played a few other great games recently where the writing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>didn't</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> click with me, including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>WarTales</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cobalt Core</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sea of Stars</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I loved these games for other reasons but in the end just didn't connect with the words on the screen. But I still felt a connection to the people making the game while I read them. Each game swung for the fences in a way that made me think "huh, someone on the other side of this screen was really, really passionate about this."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As a B2B game journalist I'm not as harsh as many players will be, and it can be scary to put yourself out there when you're not confident in your writing. But something good comes out of everyone when you try to say something about the world even while you're trying to entertain people.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Give yourself permission to tell the story bouncing around your head.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Survey reveals devs consider genAI double-edged sword in game development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/survey-reveals-devs-consider-genai-double-edged-sword-in-game-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/survey-reveals-devs-consider-genai-double-edged-sword-in-game-development.956973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/survey-reveals-devs-consider-genai-double-edged-sword-in-game-development<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A new survey from the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://omdia.tech.informa.com/collections/afcme012/game-developer-collective-survey">Game Developer Collective</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> shows developers remain at an impasse when it comes to generative AI.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Of those asked, 30 percent believe the technology will reduce </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/why-is-it-so-expensive-to-make-games-in-the-united-states-">development costs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the next 12 months. Conversely, 8 percent are certain it'll lead to rising costs, while 35 percent are skeptical and 20 percent think its impact will be insubstantial.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">GenAI is controversial both in and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-and-apple-back-away-from-openai-board-amid-regulator-scrutiny">out of</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> games, and the survey shows it'll remain divisive for some time. The main arguments against it include its environmental harm and reduced quality compared to using human artists.</span></p><p>Image via Game Developer Collective.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On the quality front, 17 percent of surveyed developers think genAI will improve the quality of games in the next year. 28 percent are neutral on the matter, while 35 percent think its use will make games worse.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That fear has been previously expressed in regards to in-game art and voice acting. Since late July, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sag-aftra-performers-to-hold-first-strike-picket-outside-wb-games">SAG-AFTRA actors</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have gone on strike over the "existential threat" of genAI, and previously talked about contracts forcing them to sign away </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/voice-actors-reportedly-urged-to-sign-voices-away-to-ai-companies">voice rights</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On the other side, its effectiveness has been touted as vital to get real-world athletes into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-ceo-says-studio-needed-genai-for-ea-college-football-25-development">EA Sports College Football 25</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Some studios, like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-president-says-generative-ai-can-be-used-in-creative-ways-">Nintendo</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, haven't fully written off the technology, it just can't be a quick fix during the development process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this year, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/near-half-of-game-devs-say-they-re-working-with-generative-ai-tools">49 percent</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of developers observed by the Collective said their studios were already using genAI at work, and 31 percent were using it outside the office. Most in-office use was from financial, community, and production management.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Good Afternoon's co-founder Sarah Brin recently spoke on how executives have been so caught up in the promise of AI that it's made the creative process of games a "clusterfuck," which you can read </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/generative-ai-tools-have-created-a-clusterfuck-but-do-they-have-a-creative-future-">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer and GDC are sibling companies under Informa Tech.</span></span><br></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI Comes To PC September 17]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-comes-to-pc-september-17/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-comes-to-pc-september-17.956955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-comes-to-pc-september-17/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy XVI has been wanted by those on different platforms for a long time, with the game finally coming to PC as of September 17. Initially, when the game was being developed, it was established as being on PC before they decided to make it a PlayStation 5 exclusive, which was released in June 2023. Since then, the game has received two paid DLC episodes, with multiple fixes coming out to make the game more accessible, especially with camera controls.</p>
<p>While the announcement dropped today with a brand-new trailer for Final Fantasy XVI, it is also on good authority from a known leaker named NateDrake that the game is potentially <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-xbox-happen/">coming to Xbox in the future</a> on ResetEra forums, as developers have stated in the past that they want as many people as possible to play the game.</p>
<p>In the new trailer for Final Fantasy XVI titled "Deliverance," you can see some of the action you can expect throughout the game as you fight against Eikons and other enemies. The DLC will be available to purchase on release for those who plan on purchasing it on PC. You can buy the base game on PC for $49.99 or the Complete Edition of Final Fantasy XVI, which includes the two DLCS: The Rising Tides and Echoes of the Fallen, for $69.99.</p>
<p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE”" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fx7orYF5UJs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Surprisingly, the system requirements for Final Fantasy XVI aren't as heavy as some might expect. Below are both the minimum and recommended specifications for Final Fantasy XVI. The most surprising thing on the list is probably that the game is a whopping 170 GB.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=87.72">MINIMUM:</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=84.09">RECOMMENDED:</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=65.47">OS: Windows 10/11 64-bit</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=86.85">OS: Windows® 10/1164-bit</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=73.94">Processor: AMD RyzenTM 5 1600 / Intel® Core™ i5- 8400</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=79.27">Processor: AMD RyzenTM 5700X / Intel@ CoreTMi7- 10700</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.24">Memory: 16 GB RAM</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=96.93">Memory: 16 GB RAM</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=74.02">Graphics: AMD Radeon™ RX 5700 / Intel® Arc™&nbsp;A580 / NVIDIA® GeForce® GTX 1070</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=70.72">Graphics: AMD Radeon™ RX 6700 XT/NVIDIA&nbsp;GeForce® RTX 2080</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=91.13">DirectX: Version 12</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=92.01">DirectX: Version 12</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=97.25">Storage: 170 GB available space</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=98.81">Storage: 170 GB available space</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.36">Additional Notes: 30FPS at 720p expected. SSD&nbsp;required. VRAM 8GB or above.</td>
<td title="Character Accurarcy=99.23">Additional Notes: 60FPS at 1080p expected. SSD&nbsp;required. VRAM 8GB or above.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>For those who want to see whether the game will be something they enjoy, there is currently a demo <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2515020/FINAL_FANTASY_XVI/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available on Steam</a> where people can download it and get stuck in some of the Final Fantasy XVI action. Once you've completed the demo, you'll unfortunately have to wait until September 14.</p>
<p>Past that, if you want to read a review of Final Fantasy XVI, check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-xvi-the-planets-dyin-clive/">Kai's review</a> of the latest entry in the Final Fantasy series.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI launches on PC in September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/19/24222173/final-fantasy-xvi-ff-16-pc-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-launches-on-pc-in-september.956952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/19/24222173/final-fantasy-xvi-ff-16-pc-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You can now preorder <em>Final Fantasy XVI</em> <a href="https://x.com/finalfantasyxvi/status/1825565489734770753">on Steam</a> and the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/final-fantasy-xvi">Epic Games Store</a>, and there are complete editions that include both DLCs available for preorder, too. You can also check out a demo for the game from <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F2738000%2FFINAL_FANTASY_XVI_DEMO%2F">both</a> <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/final-fantasy-xvi-demo-c289c2">stores</a>, and your progress from the part of the demo that covers the opening section of the game will transfer to the full version.</p><p>Since <em>Final Fantasy XVI</em> first launched, Square Enix has introduced <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/update-final-fantasy-xvi">numerous updates</a> to fix bugs and add quality-of-life features, including a “quick complete” function to zip back to quest givers.</p><p><em>Final Fantasy XVI</em> producer Naoki Yoshida announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/4/23858209/final-fantasy-16-windows-pc-port-dlc-expansions-announcement">last September</a> that the RPG would be getting a PC port. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What You Need To Know About Armor Sets In 7 Days To Die]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/7-days-to-die-crafting-armor-sets-guide-1851625310</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-you-need-to-know-about-armor-sets-in-7-days-to-die.956946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/7-days-to-die-crafting-armor-sets-guide-1851625310<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When you first start your zombie survival adventure in <em>7 Days to Die</em>, you’re immediately dumped into a massive game world. You have an objective—to find the nearest trader—but otherwise, you’re flying solo. It’s challenging, with terror around each corner, and if you’re caught unaware a single zombie can end your run. But with the right armor sets, you’ll survive!<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193831" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="226" data-playlist="193831,195410,196299" data-current="193831"><div><p>The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19283.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Here is what you need to know about armor in <em>7 Days to Die</em>!</p><h2 id="h7518"><a id=""></a><strong>How to craft armor sets</strong></h2><figure id="" data-id="1501e7ad37dffb9138983c3aa5b30313" data-recommend-id="image://1501e7ad37dffb9138983c3aa5b30313" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A workbench, hiding in the shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A workbench, hiding in the shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Fun Pimps / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1501e7ad37dffb9138983c3aa5b30313" data-recommend-id="image://1501e7ad37dffb9138983c3aa5b30313" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A workbench, hiding in the shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Don’t expect to craft many of the game’s armor sets straight away. They’re expensive and require loads of resources, various workbenches, and time. Your first set, the Primitive Armor Set, you can craft directly from your inventory system with a handful of resources. It’s adequate, but you’ll want to upgrade quickly.</p><p>Once you progress deeper into the game, you require a Workbench and Forge to smelt iron ore into forged iron, which is a key component of many armor sets. But for that, you must first track down iron deposits, which typically spawn underground. If you can find a mine POI, you’ll have much better luck. But you can also dig deep into the ground with a shovel in the hopes of finding a small deposit.</p><p>On top of resources like iron, many armor sets also require Armor Crafting Kits, which you can find in high-value loot containers and as quest rewards for the traders.</p><h2 id="h7519"><a id=""></a><strong>Types of armor in the game</strong></h2><figure id="" data-id="b18565e0252e9da4b623006d05ff8e88" data-recommend-id="image://b18565e0252e9da4b623006d05ff8e88" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The armor crafting UI." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The armor crafting UI." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Fun Pimps / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b18565e0252e9da4b623006d05ff8e88" data-recommend-id="image://b18565e0252e9da4b623006d05ff8e88" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The armor crafting UI." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In total, <em>7 Days to Die</em> features 16 unique armor sets, with the majority offering a set bonus that boosts your stats and abilities for wearing every piece. These armor sets fall under four categories: Primitive Armor, Light Armor, Medium Armor, and Heavy Armor.<br></p><p>In the early game, you’ll likely rock the Primitive Armor. It’s the most cost-effective to craft, but it’s also the only armor set in the game that doesn’t offer a bonus. The whole set includes the Primitive Hood, Primitive Outfit, Primitive Gloves, and Primitive Shoes. It’s the absolute basics, but they’ll help keep you alive.</p><p>You’ll want to progress to a better suit of armor quickly, though.</p><h3 id="h7520"><a id=""></a><strong>Light Armor Sets</strong></h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Lumberjack</li><li>Preacher</li><li>Rogue</li><li>Athletic</li><li>Enforcer</li></ul><h3 id="h7521"><a id=""></a><strong>Medium Armor Sets</strong></h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Farmer</li><li>Biker</li><li>Scavenger</li><li>Ranger</li><li>Commando</li><li>Assassin</li></ul><h3 id="h7522"><a id=""></a><strong>Heavy Armor Sets</strong></h3><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Miner</li><li>Nomad</li><li>Nerd</li><li>Raider</li></ul><p>Unless you enjoy allowing zombies to munch on your bare skin, you’ll want to prioritize crafting armor sets in <em>7 Days to Die</em>. A basic weapon, early-game armor, and a few medical aid items will see you through your first few days, likely through the first Blood Moon, but not much further than that.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ESL FACEIT Group Announces Partnership Extension With DHL]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/esl-faceit-group-announces-partnership-extension-with-dhl/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/esl-faceit-group-announces-partnership-extension-with-dhl.956940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/esl-faceit-group-announces-partnership-extension-with-dhl/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>More and more companies are getting involved in esports. DHL, the popular logistics organization, has officially announced an extension of its partnership with the esports tournament organizer, ESL FACEIT Group. This is a multi-year deal that will showcase the brand across various ESL broadcasts.</p>



<p>DHL already has a prominent presence within the Snapdragon Pro series, which is the world’s largest mobile esports competition. </p>



<h2 id="h-esl-faceit-group-extends-partnership-with-dhl">ESL FACEIT Group Extends Partnership With DHL</h2>



<p>DHL first found themselves in a deal with ESL FACEIT Group back in 2018. In those six consecutive years working together, DHL has obtained immense success from the partnership, with a result of gaining more than 10,000 job applications just since 2022. It is a no-brainer as to why the company is choosing to continue working with ESL.</p>



<p>Not only will DHL be a title sponsor for ESL, but they will also be managing the logistics of staging and broadcasting technologies required for events, such as DreamHack and more.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>“Through its partnership with EFG, DHL has become a brand that inspires gaming fans like none other,” said Rodrigo Samwell, Chief Commercial Officer at ESL FACEIT Group. “We see thousands of fans chanting ‘DHL’ at our live events, and the love the esports community shows to DHL is nothing short of extraordinary.”</p>



<p>ESL has been consistently adding more and more partners to its brand, making it one of the biggest names in esports.</p>



<p>“That support is a testament to the fact that EFG’s and DHL’s joint long-term strategy resonates with the most important people: our fans.”</p>



<p>The industry continues to thrive as more and more brands are beginning to partner with esports.</p>







<h2 id="h-about-dhl">About DHL</h2>



<p>DHL is a global leader in the statistics industry. The company specializes in international shipping, courier services and transportation. The company was first founded back in 1969 in San Francisco, California, and has long since been catering to different businesses, people and organizations.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more esports news.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI Launches On PC In September, Demo Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-xvi-launches-on-pc-in-september-demo-out-now/1100-6525923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-launches-on-pc-in-september-demo-out-now.956937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-xvi-launches-on-pc-in-september-demo-out-now/1100-6525923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525923">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Square Enix has revealed that the PC version of Final Fantasy XVI will launch on September 17, and players can access a demo right now.</p><p>According to its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2515020/FINAL_FANTASY_XVI/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam page</a>, those who preorder the game will receive the Cait Sith's Charm accessory, the Brave Blade Weapon, and the Sixteen Bells Orchestrion Roll item. The base game costs $50 while the "Complete Edition" costs $70 and includes the expansion pass with both the Echoes of the Fallen and The Rising Tide DLC.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="185051052" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464867,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;FINAL%20FANTASY%20XVI%20%E2%80%9CDELIVERANCE%E2%80%9D%20-%20PC%20Release%20Date%20and%20Demo%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:93,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/final-fantasy-xvi-deliverance-pc-release-date-and-demo-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464867\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464867\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464867\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464867\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464867&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464867,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525923&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy-xvi&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;square-enix&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464867},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464867\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4352829-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/F9yxU5Ur.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724084100,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="F9yxU5Ur" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Release Date and Demo Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>As for the specs, it takes up a whopping 170GB of storage and requires 16GB of RAM. Its minimum system requirements include an AMD Ryzen 5 1600 or Intel Core i5-8400 processor and an AMD Radeon RX 5700, Intel Arc A580, or NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1070 graphics card.</p><p>The recommended specs include an AMD Ryzen 7 5700X or Intel Core i7-10700, and an AMD Radeon RX 6700 XT or NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2080 graphics card.</p><h2>Final Fantasy XVI PC specs</h2><h4>Minimum specs</h4><ul><li>OS: Windows 10 / 11 64-bit</li><li>Processor: AMD Ryzen 5 1600 / Intel Core™ i5-8400</li><li>Memory: 16GB RAM</li><li>Graphics: AMD Radeon RX 5700 / Intel® Arc A580 / NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1070</li><li>DirectX: Version 12</li><li>Storage: 170GB available space</li><li>Additional Notes: 30FPS at 720p expected. SSD required. VRAM 8GB or above.</li></ul><h4>Recommend specs</h4><ul><li>OS: Windows 10 / 11 64-bit</li><li>Processor: AMD Ryzen 7 5700X / Intel® Core i7-10700</li><li>Memory: 16GB RAM</li><li>Graphics: AMD Radeon RX 6700 XT / NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2080</li><li>DirectX: Version 12</li><li>Storage: 170GB available space</li><li>Additional Notes: 60FPS at 1080p expected. SSD required. VRAM 8GB or above.</li></ul><p>In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/final-fantasy-16-review-on-its-own-terms/1900-6418081/" data-ref-id="1900-6418081">Final Fantasy XVI review</a>, we said, "FFXVI is a bold shift in both gameplay and narrative, yet captures the Final Fantasy magic in stunning fashion, earning a place within the pantheon of incredible entries in the beloved franchise."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 16 on PC gets September release date and immediate demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-on-pc-gets-september-release-date-and-immediate-demo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-16-on-pc-gets-september-release-date-and-immediate-demo.956931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-on-pc-gets-september-release-date-and-immediate-demo<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/FF16---Clive-extreme-close-up.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Eninx</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-xvi">Final Fantasy 16</a> will launch on PC on 17th September across both the Epic Games Store and Steam.
</p>
<p>
The PC version has been long-awaited since the game was released as a PS5 console exclusive last year.
</p>
<p>
Today's news comes with a new PC specific trailer, see below. A demo is available to try out now.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PC3oQe1EtYY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Final Fantasy 16 'Deliverance' - PC Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC3oQe1EtYY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>
The game will arrive as a complete edition, including all DLC: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16s-first-dlc-opens-that-one-mysterious-door-and-its-characters-minds">Echoes of the Fallen</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-is-finally-complete-though-its-dlc-wont-appease-critics">The Rising Tide</a>.
</p>
<p>
Earlier this month speculation rose that an announcement was imminent when <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-profile-in-latest-nvidia-driver-leads-to-speculation-of-imminent-pc-release">Nvidia's latest driver included mention of the game</a>, along with a demo.
</p>
<p>
The demo begins at the start of the game and data can be carried over to the full game. This is the same as the PS5 launch.
</p>
<p>
Final Fantasy 16 received a mostly positive response, though some longtime fans were less keen on the series shift from traditional turn-based combat to real-time action combat.
</p>
<p>
The simultaneous release across Epic and Steam differs from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-remake-review-a-faithful-remake-with-a-few-missteps-along-the-way">Final Fantasy 7 Remake</a>, which first launched as an Epic exclusive before arriving on Steam the following year. However it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2021-final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-pc-barebones-port">criticised at launch for its performance</a>.

</p>
<p>
Let's hope Final Fantasy 16 doesn't suffer the same fate.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Commandos: Origins Gets New Trailer Ahead of Gamescom]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/commandos-origins-gets-new-trailer-ahead-of-gamescom/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/commandos-origins-gets-new-trailer-ahead-of-gamescom.956919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/commandos-origins-gets-new-trailer-ahead-of-gamescom/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Commandos: Origins, the latest game to be developed by Claymore Game Studios and published by <a href="https://wccftech.com/commandos-kalypso/">Kalypso Media</a>, has dropped a new trailer ahead of their showcase at Gamescom 2024. This game is the highly anticipated sequel in the Commandos franchise, which has been around since 1998. This will be the eighth game in the franchise, and it is a completely new story compared to the previous two, which were HD remasters.</p>
<p><iframe title="Commandos: Origins | Gameplay Trailer (US)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HImqjeqCANo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The trailer offers an exclusive look into the stealth-oriented game, which will be released later this year. "We are incredibly proud to present Commandos: Origins for the first time to a wide audience at Gamescom 2024. This represents a significant milestone for our studio after working secretly on our game for so long. As we draw closer to release, we're excited to offer gamers the opportunity to embark on their first mission at the show floor and we are eager to hear their feedback as they experience the compelling tactical gameplay from Commandos: Origins firsthand," says Juergen Reusswig, Studio Director at Claymore Game Studios.</p>
<p>Technically, Commandos: Origins is a prequel. It delves deep into the beginning of the Commandos' journey and allows players to embark on missions with iconic characters from the franchise. Players will reunite with characters such as Jack O'Hara (The Green Beret) and Thomas Hancock (The Sapper) while navigating through a World War II setting.</p>
<p>The new gameplay trailer showcases intense combat sequences, demonstrating the Commandos' multiple mission approaches and abilities. These demonstrations show players that they can lurk in the shadows and use stealth tactics to complete the sequences, or they can go in guns blazing, utilizing Flak-Vierlings to their advantage to cause dramatic explosions and kill enemies with flair.</p>
<p>For those attending gamescom 2024, you can test Commandos: Origins in person at the Xbox Booth in Hall 7. In addition to being on platforms such as <a href="https://kalypso.shop/click.html?x=a62e&amp;lc=hOl&amp;mc=H&amp;s=ySOl&amp;u=X&amp;z=7Xp4FrA&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation 5</a>, Xbox Series X|S, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1479730/Commandos_Origins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC</a>, they've also expanded the game to be available to those using a PlayStation 4 and Xbox One. In addition, to those who have Xbox Game Pass, you'll be able to play it as a Day One release on both Xbox and PC.</p>
<p>Commandos: Origins features a 2-player cooperative multiplayer where you can team up with a friend on either a local split-screen or via online gameplay. There will be more than 10 missions for players to get through while seeing six infamous characters from the previous games for nostalgia as you travel through a World War II campaign.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Black Myth: Wukong Content Creators Prohibited From Mentioning 'Feminist Propaganda']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-reviews-sexism-controversy-feminist-1851625743</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-black-myth-wukong-content-creators-prohibited-from-mentioning-feminist-propaganda.956913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-reviews-sexism-controversy-feminist-1851625743<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Codes for review and content creation around <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-pc-ps5-review-round-up-is-it-good-1851624656&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-pc-ps5-review-round-up-is-it-good-1851624656"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></a></span>, the highly-anticipated action game from Chinese studio Game Science, went out earlier this month ahead of its August 20 launch. It now appears that at least some streamers and YouTubers who received the game early were also told explicitly not to mention several topics ranging from covid and to “feminist propaganda.” </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193831" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="226" data-playlist="193831,195410,196299" data-current="193831"><div><p>The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19283.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Ex-<em>Gamekult</em> journalist Benoit “ExServ” Reinier was one of the people who received the bizarre set of restrictions in a document attached to review code request. Reinier shared the document <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/exserv.bsky.social/post/3kzvr3jr54225&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/exserv.bsky.social/post/3kzvr3jr54225" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on social media</a></span> over the weekend and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YVuo-oqw2EU&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YVuo-oqw2EU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">made a video about it</a></span>, while <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://videogames.si.com/news/black-myth-wukong-streamers-feminist-propaganda&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://videogames.si.com/news/black-myth-wukong-streamers-feminist-propaganda" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>GLHF</em> reports</a></span> that the person who sent the list of content prohibitions is a member of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/realherogames_we-are-working-with-game-science-in-bringing-activity-7122876214192586752-lbtY/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/realherogames_we-are-working-with-game-science-in-bringing-activity-7122876214192586752-lbtY/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hero Games</a></span>, the co-publisher of <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>. </p><p>The document now circulating includes a list of “Do’s &amp; Don’ts.” “Enjoy the game” is under the “Do” heading. The Don’t heading includes the following: <br></p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>● Do NOT insult other influencers or players. </p><p>● Do NOT use any offensive language/humor. </p><p>● Do NOT include politics, violence, nudity, feminist propaganda, fetishization, and other content that instigates negative discourse.</p><p>● Do NOT use trigger words such as ‘quarantine’ or ‘isolation’ or ‘COVID-19'.</p><p>● Do NOT discuss content related to China’s game industry policies, opinions, news, etc<br></p></blockquote><p><em>Kotaku</em>, like many gaming sites, received advanced access for the PC version of the game (PlayStation 5 codes are still MIA), and was asked to abide by a normal set of requests around not mentioning various spoilers in the roughly 30-40 hour adventure loosely inspired by the classic Chinese story <em>Journey to the West</em>. There was no mention of these restrictions, and it’s not clear how may other content creators received it. Game Science didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment. </p><p>The restriction around mentioning “feminist propaganda” comes in the midst of an ongoing discussion around Game Science that kicked off early this year, after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em> reported</a></span> on past sexist remarks and statements from developers associated with the studio. The investigation put some of the <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> founders’ history in the larger context of sexism within the Chinese video game industry and how that will or won’t change as the market becomes more open. </p><p>One of the most notable things about that report was the fact that Game Science never responded to it, and has so far resisted acknowledging any of the controversy surrounding it, which included online harassment from certain toxic fans targeting the authors’ of the <em>IGN</em> report as well as even recent reviewers of the game who gave it <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/black-myth-wukong-review/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/black-myth-wukong-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anything less than a top score</a></span>. In previews earlier this summer, Game Science <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-hands-on-with-an-impressive-first-2-hours&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-hands-on-with-an-impressive-first-2-hours" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">refused to comment</a></span> on the report about past sexism by some of the game’s developers, and recently <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/kezamacdonald/status/1825508185735663649&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/kezamacdonald/status/1825508185735663649" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">denied <em>The Guardian</em></a></span>, one of the outlets that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jul/25/black-myth-wukong-the-summers-most-exciting-and-most-controversial-video-game&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/article/2024/jul/25/black-myth-wukong-the-summers-most-exciting-and-most-controversial-video-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pressed the studio on the controversy</a></span>, a code for the game. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full Intel Core Ultra 200 Lineup Leaks With October 10 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/full-intel-core-ultra-200-lineup-leaks-with-october-10-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/full-intel-core-ultra-200-lineup-leaks-with-october-10-launch.956910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/full-intel-core-ultra-200-lineup-leaks-with-october-10-launch/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-53458">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The full lineup for the upcoming Intel Core Ultra 200 family of CPUs has leaked along with its release date. According to <a href="https://benchlife.info/intel-core-ultra-2-desktop-cpu-will-announce-10th-oct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">benchlife</a>, the new line of Intel Core Ultra 200 CPUs will launch October 10 and feature 14 SKUs at the start.</p>



<p>The new Arrow Lake-S processors are the first to use the new Intel Core Ultra naming convention. Prior to the new chips, Intel had used the “Core i” scheme.</p>







<p>The highest-level CPU, the Ultra 9, will have three SKUs for consumers. The Ultra 7 will have five SKUs while the Ultra 5 will launch with six options.</p>



<p>You can check out the current specs for the known new Intel processors below via benchlife. No information on pricing is currently known.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">CPU </th><th data-align="center">THREADS/CORES</th><th data-align="center">BASE (GHz)</th><th data-align="center">TURBO (GHz)</th><th data-align="center">CACHE (L3)</th><th data-align="center">TDP</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 9 285K</td><td data-align="center">24/24 (8+16)</td><td data-align="center">3.7 / 3.2 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.4 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">36 MB</td><td data-align="center">125W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 9 285</td><td data-align="center">24/24 (8+16)</td><td data-align="center">2.5 / 1.9 GHz</td><td data-align="center">4.6 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">36 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 9 285T</td><td data-align="center">24/24 (8+16)</td><td data-align="center">1.4 / 1.2 GHz</td><td data-align="center">4.7 / 4.5 GHz</td><td data-align="center">36 MB</td><td data-align="center">35W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 7 265K</td><td data-align="center">20/20 (8+12)</td><td data-align="center">3.9 / 3.3 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.2 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">33 MB</td><td data-align="center">125W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 7 265KF</td><td data-align="center">20/20 (8+12)</td><td data-align="center">3.9 / 3.3 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.2 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">33 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 7 265</td><td data-align="center">20/20 (8+12)</td><td data-align="center">2.4 / 1.8 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.1 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">33 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 7 265F</td><td data-align="center">20/20 (8+12)</td><td data-align="center">2.4 / 1.8 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.1 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">33 MB</td><td data-align="center">35W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 7 265T</td><td data-align="center">20/20 (8+12)</td><td data-align="center">1.5 / 1.2 GHz</td><td data-align="center">4.6 / 4.5 GHz</td><td data-align="center">33 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 245K</td><td data-align="center">14/14 (6+8)</td><td data-align="center">4.2 / 3.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.0 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">24 MB</td><td data-align="center">125W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 245KF</td><td data-align="center">14/14 (6+8)</td><td data-align="center">4.2 / 3.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">5.0 / 4.6 GHz</td><td data-align="center">24 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 245</td><td data-align="center">14/14 (6+8)</td><td data-align="center">TBD</td><td data-align="center">TBD</td><td data-align="center">24 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 235</td><td data-align="center">14/14 (6+8)</td><td data-align="center">TBD</td><td data-align="center">TBD</td><td data-align="center">24 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 225</td><td data-align="center">10/10 (6+4)</td><td data-align="center">3.3 / 2.7 GHz</td><td data-align="center">4.7 / 4.4 GHz</td><td data-align="center">18 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Core Ultra 5 225F</td><td data-align="center">10/10 (6+4)</td><td data-align="center">3.3 / 2.7 GHz</td><td data-align="center">4.7 / 4.4 GHz</td><td data-align="center">18 MB</td><td data-align="center">65W</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Intel has not responded to requests for comment on the CPU leak.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to pick up a new Intel Core Ultra 200 CPU when they become available? For more Insider Gaming Tech, check out what new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/zotac-gaming-zone-preorder-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">handheld gaming PC is now available</a> for pre-order.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-cells-gets-final-update-from-evil-empire/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-cells-gets-final-update-from-evil-empire/">Dead Cells Gets Final Update From Evil Empire</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>After 7 years, Dead Cells has received its 35th and final update from developer Motion Twin called “The End is Near”.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trailer-reveals-october-2024-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trailer-reveals-october-2024-release-date/">Pokémon TCG Pocket Trailer Reveals October 2024 Release Date</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Mobile game Pokémon TCG Pocket has a new trailer revealing more footage and a release date for late October 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-posts-new-death-stranding-2-tease/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-posts-new-death-stranding-2-tease/">Hideo Kojima Posts New Death Stranding 2 Tease</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hideo Kojima has teased a new character for Death Stranding 2: On the Beach. Players seem to have figured out who it is.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nearly-90-of-developers-surveyed-say-premium-games-dont-need-microtransactions/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nearly-90-of-developers-surveyed-say-premium-games-dont-need-microtransactions/">Nearly 90% Of Developers Surveyed Say Premium Games Don’t Need Microtransactions</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a new survey among developers, nearly 90% believe that major premium games don’t need microtransactions to be a  success.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your 10-year-old graphics card can run Dragon Age: The Veilguard]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043994</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-10-year-old-graphics-card-can-run-dragon-age-the-veilguard.956904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043994<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>
      Still kicking    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description">2014's Nvidia GTX 970 is still a "minimum requirements" workhorse.</h2>
                    </div><div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
<figure>
  
      <figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/gtx970.jpg" data-height="928" data-width="894">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> At this rate, it might be the only graphics card you'll ever need?</p></figcaption>  </figure>

  




<!-- cache hit 220:single/related:c6a0d80af6f366d9f3e5a482762baaef --><!-- empty -->
<p>When <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em> came out <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2014/11/dragon-age-inquisition-review-lets-spend-some-time-together/">nearly 10 years ago</a>, PC players could have invested $329 (~$435 in today's dollars) in a brand-new GTX 970 graphics card to make the game look as good as possible on their high-end gaming rig. Surprisingly enough, that very same 2014 graphics card will still be able to run follow-up <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> (<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/06/bioware-reveals-dreadwolf-as-the-next-dragon-age-title/">previously known as <em>Dreadwolf</em></a>) when it launches on October 31. If you're using AMD cards, an even older Radeon R9 that you purchased back in 2013 will be able to run the game.
</p><p><em>Veilguard</em>'s minimum specs are just the latest to show the workmanlike endurance of the humble GTX 970, which is currently available used on Newegg for <a href="https://www.newegg.com/p/pl?N=100007709%20600536049&amp;Order=1">as low as $140</a>. Relatively recent big-budget PC releases like <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/08/baldurs-gate-3-early-impressions-youll-spend-whole-weeks-in-here-and-love-it/"><em>Baldur's Gate 3</em></a>&nbsp;and <em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</em> both use the old card (or the less powerful follow-up variant, the GTX 960) as their "minimum requirement" benchmark.</p>
<p>Not every big-budget PC game these days is so forgiving with its minimum specs, though. When <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/12/a-week-spent-in-cyberpunk-2077s-beautiful-messy-urban-future/"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/03/doom-eternal-review-a-welcome-return-to-hell-on-earth/"><em>Doom: Eternal</em></a> launched in 2020, they both asked players to be sporting at least a GTX 1060, which had come out around four years prior.</p>
<figure><p><iframe type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8DkDQhPx2A?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure>
<p>For a bit of context, the GTX 970 was used as the "recommended" baseline spec for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/02/oculus-reveals-first-oculus-ready-pcs-bundled-starting-at-1499/">the mid-range "Oculus Ready" PCs</a> needed to power the then-new Rift VR headset when it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/03/the-ars-review-oculus-rift-expands-pc-gaming-past-the-monitors-edge/">launched in 2016</a>. Today, a $500 <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/10/meta-quest-3-review-mixed-reality-version-0-5/">Meta Quest 3 headset</a> gives you much better graphical performance in a self-contained portable package, no gaming PC required.</p>                                                                        
                                                                                
<p><em>Veilguard</em> players sticking with a GTX 970 shouldn't expect to get the best graphical experience, of course. EA suggests an RTX 2070 (circa 2018) or a Radeon RX 5700Xt (circa 2019) to run the game at "recommended" specs. And you'll need at least 16 GB of RAM and 100 GB of storage space.</p>
<p>Since work on <em>Veilguard</em> began in earnest in 2015, the game has suffered a string of high-profile staff departures: Creative Director Mike Laidlaw <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/b/features/archive/2018/02/23/dragon-ages-mike-laidlaw-opens-up-on-why-he-left-bioware.aspx">left in 2017</a>; Executive Producer Mark Darrah and BioWare General Manager Casey Hudson <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/12/bioware-studio-gm-and-dragon-age-lead-are-both-leaving-company/">left in late 2020</a>; Senior Creative Director Matt Goldman <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-ages-senior-creative-director-has-left-bioware-1848114644">left in late 2021</a>; replacement Executive Producer Christian Daley <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/dragon-age-4-executive-producer-has-left-bioware/">left in early 2022</a>; and producer Mac Walters <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/01/dragon-age-dreadwolf-loses-another-veteran-bioware-producer/">left in early 2023</a>.
</p><p>The full requirements for <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> are as follows.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Requirements</strong><br>
<em>OS:</em> Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
<em>Processor:</em> Intel Core i5-8400 / AMD Ryzen 3 3300X* (see notes)<br>
<em>Memory:</em> 16GB<br>
<em>Graphics:</em> Nvidia GTX 970/1650 / AMD Radeon R9 290X<br>
<em>DirectX:</em> Version 12<br>
<em>Storage:</em> 100GB available space<br>
<em>Additional Notes:</em> SSD preferred, HDD supported; AMD CPUs on Windows 11 require AGESA V2 1.2.0.7</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Requirements</strong><br>
<em>OS:</em> Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
<em>Processor:</em> Intel Core i9-9900K / AMD Ryzen 7 3700X (see notes)<br>
<em>Memory:</em> 16GB<br>
<em>Graphics:</em> Nvidia RTX 2070 / AMD Radeon RX 5700XT<br>
<em>DirectX:</em> Version 12<br>
<em>Storage:</em> 100GB SSD available space<br>
<em>Additional Notes:</em> SSD required; AMD CPUs on Windows 11 require AGESA V2 1.2.0.7</p>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost 90% of Developers Surveyed Says Premium Games Don’t Need Microtransactions]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/almost-90-of-developers-surveyed-says-premium-games-dont-need-microtransactions/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/almost-90-of-developers-surveyed-says-premium-games-don%E2%80%99t-need-microtransactions.956883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/almost-90-of-developers-surveyed-says-premium-games-dont-need-microtransactions/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Microtransactions are a hot topic in the gaming industry, especially as they become increasingly frequent. Even in " completed games," microtransactions are finding a way to worm themselves into the game. For example, look at Star Wars Outlaws, an upcoming game made by Massive Entertainment and published by Ubisoft. The game isn't even out yet, and they already <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-post-launch-roadmap-revealed-including-season-pass/">have a roadmap for microtransactions</a> planned.</p>
<p>However, 90% of developers who participated in a survey at <a href="https://www.devcom.global/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Devcom 2024</a> said that premium games don't need microtransactions. While the general audience already knows this, game companies still incorporate them into premium games.</p>
<p><a href="https://venturebeat.com/games/devcom-opens-with-indie-game-awards-and-survey-results-from-300-speakers/#:~:text=Devcom%20speaker%20survey%3A%20Key%20insights&amp;text=Best%20Use%20Cases%20for%20AI,marketing%20and%20communication%20(18%25)." target="_blank" rel="noopener">89% of developers surveyed</a> at Devcom 2024 said they believe premium games can be "financially successful just by being Buy-to-Play." It seems that premium games released without microtransactions are becoming rarer each day.</p>
<p>Regarding business models, 65% of people believe in a premium game's business model for physical and digital edition games. Additionally, 81% of survey participants believe that cross-platform play is essential for a premium game to be successful. Surprisingly, one person believed that free-to-play with ads was the best business model in gaming. While this may be true for mobile gaming, it'd be hard to imagine games like Elden Ring or Call of Duty being free-to-play with ads. Even in mobile gaming, plenty of people refuse to play games if there are ads or will spend a small amount of money to eliminate ads.</p>
<p>Looking at other insights from the Devcom survey, 31% prefer minimal AI usage in their work, with 21% wanting to leverage AI for code and production to make the development job simpler. 18% would like to use AI for marketing and communication. Considering how rapidly AI is expanding and evolving, it'll be interesting to see the results of next year's AI usage.</p>
<p>Regarding challenges that the games industry faces, 55% believe that the biggest issue is market saturation, with 46% saying the biggest issue is development costs. Both are significant issues in the games industry, with genres becoming more saturated with each new game. For example, the Soulslike genre exploded, and there are more games than ever to choose from in that genre compared to last year.</p>
<p>Finally, when asked about layoffs within the games industry, 57% of speakers anticipated that layoffs would continue at the same pace or faster over the next 12 months, with 43% believing that the layoffs would decrease and more jobs would open up in the industry for people.</p>
<p>The games industry is rapidly changing and evolving—not necessarily for good, either. However, it'll be interesting to compare the results of this Devcom 2024 survey to next year's.</p>



				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Are Final Fantasy XIV's Daily Roulettes?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-daily-roulettes-guide-1851625306</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-are-final-fantasy-xivs-daily-roulettes.956871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-daily-roulettes-guide-1851625306<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>An MMO wouldn’t be complete without a generous dose of grinding, and while this is true for <em>Final Fantasy XIV</em>, Square Enix’s online game eases the pain slightly by adding Daily Roulettes. These missions help more efficiently procure some of the different resources in the game. This guide will help explain what Daily Roulettes are, as well as how they should be used.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195519" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="148" data-playlist="195519,195618,195752" data-current="195519"><div><p>I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21013.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h13675"><a id=""></a><strong>What are Daily Roulettes?</strong></h2><p>Daily Roulettes are a matchmaking option <em>FFXIV</em> offers to allow you to grind out different resources such as EXP, Gil or other currencies. The idea behind them is that you select the type of Roulette you wish to join based on the rewards you want, and the game will put you in a randomized Duty, which are <em>FFXIV</em>’s version of missions. Most Roulettes also specify which type of content you will encounter, so it can also be used if you are in the mood for say a boss battle, but not sure which one to do.<br></p><p>Roulettes are a great way to complete whatever goal you are currently working for in <em>FFXIV</em>. You will receive bonuses for finishing multiple categories of Roulettes a day, but only if it was the first time that type was completed in that period. For example, if you run through the “Leveling” and “Main Scenario” Roulettes on the same day, you would get an EXP and Gil bonus for both of them, as well as Seals for “Leveling” and Tomestones of Poetics for “Main Scenario,” but if you ran “Leveling” twice in the same period, you would only receive the bonuses for your first completion until they reset. In order to maximize your time, you should be completing different Roulettes to capitalize on all the rewards instead of just playing through the same one.</p><p>Your Daily Roulettes can be found by navigating to the “Duty” Option of the Main Menu and then selecting the “Duty Finder” Option. From there, it will be the leftmost option, signified by the question mark icon.</p><figure id="" data-id="bd8eea493c37d64b0f39726be6d6d1bf" data-recommend-id="image://bd8eea493c37d64b0f39726be6d6d1bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Duty Menu screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Duty Menu screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bd8eea493c37d64b0f39726be6d6d1bf" data-recommend-id="image://bd8eea493c37d64b0f39726be6d6d1bf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Duty Menu screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h13676"><a id=""></a><strong>How to Unlock Daily Roulettes</strong></h2><p>Since there are many different types of Roulettes, they are unlocked in many different ways. Generally, you will unlock them as you play through the Main Storyline or reach certain milestones. One of the first Roulettes you will unlock is the “Leveling” option as all you have to do is complete the second and third dungeons. However, others like the “Expert” Roulette require you to reach level 90. The best advice is to just keep working through the main story and complete any optional dungeons you come across, as this will provide access to a bulk of the Roulette options.</p><h2 id="h13677"><a id=""></a><strong>Types of Roulettes</strong></h2><p>Given the large number of options in the Roulette Menu, it can be a little overwhelming, here are all the different types as well as the bonuses they give:</p><h3 id="h13678"><a id=""></a><strong>Expert</strong></h3><p>This option will put you in the newest dungeons <em>FFXIV </em>has to offer so it is updated alongside the game. Currently, it contains Duties from the newest expansion <em>Dawntrail</em>, and provides Tomestones of Aethestics and Heliometry, two of the newest currencies in the game which can be used to buy Neo Kingdom and Quetzalli Gear. It also rewards you with Gil and EXP. Note that you can only receive the two types of Tomestones once you reach level 100.</p><figure id="" data-id="b6abeef89b6a549d74baf12a27695c4d" data-recommend-id="image://b6abeef89b6a549d74baf12a27695c4d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A sparkly battle in one of the game's dungeons." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A sparkly battle in one of the game's dungeons." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b6abeef89b6a549d74baf12a27695c4d" data-recommend-id="image://b6abeef89b6a549d74baf12a27695c4d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A sparkly battle in one of the game's dungeons." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h3 id="h13679"><a id=""></a><strong>High Level Dungeons</strong></h3><p>You’ll unlock this category at level 50. This allows you to enter any level 50 dungeon you have access to. This category will also add new tiers for every ten levels you gain until you reach level 90. Rewards for these roulettes include Tomestones of Poetics, and Aesthetics as well as Gil and EXP. Note that unlike Aesthetics and Heliometry, Tomestones of Poetics can be received once you reach level 50.<br></p><h3 id="h13680"><a id=""></a><strong>Leveling</strong></h3><p>The Leveling Roulette will have you play through a random dungeon or trial (i.e. boss battle), however it will only be one that you have previously unlocked. The great thing about this roulette is that even though you will most likely be synced to a lower level to complete the duty, you will receive bonuses based on the difference between your synced level and actual level. For example, if you are Level 90 and doing a level 50 dungeon, you will receive better rewards than someone who is Level 60 running the same instance, which encourages a playthrough no matter your level. Leveling Roulettes provide EXP, Gil and Grand Company Seals upon completion so it is a great option to level up a secondary Job or your GC rank.</p><figure id="" data-id="bdad5a8b9e718d38128085f7bd37b541" data-recommend-id="image://bdad5a8b9e718d38128085f7bd37b541" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A man and his pet in front of a boring wall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A man and his pet in front of a boring wall." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bdad5a8b9e718d38128085f7bd37b541" data-recommend-id="image://bdad5a8b9e718d38128085f7bd37b541" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1194" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A man and his pet in front of a boring wall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h3 id="h13681"><a id=""></a><strong>Trials</strong></h3><p>These Roulettes will place you in <em>FFXIV’s </em>version of Boss Battles. As you progress through the game and conquer these fights, they will be added to the Duty Roulette. Rewards include Aesthetics, Heliometries, EXP and some of the largest quantities of Gil the Roulettes offer.</p><h3 id="h13682"><a id=""></a><strong>Main Scenario</strong></h3><p>Currently, the Main Scenario Roulette has you play through one of three Duties which are the final Main Scenario Quests from the launch version of the base game, <em>A Realm Reborn. </em>As such, it will either be one of the two dungeons or a boss battle. These are a little longer missions, so they are not the most efficient method of grinding out EXP or Gil, but they also provide a healthy amount of Poetics which can be used to buy the Ironworks Armor—one of the best armors for you if your character is between Level 50 and 60.</p><figure id="" data-id="00760dee0bbb484c6b9542c965fab9b4" data-recommend-id="image://00760dee0bbb484c6b9542c965fab9b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Oh goodness, this chap doesn't look very nice." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Oh goodness, this chap doesn't look very nice." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="00760dee0bbb484c6b9542c965fab9b4" data-recommend-id="image://00760dee0bbb484c6b9542c965fab9b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Oh goodness, this chap doesn't look very nice." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h3 id="h13683"><a id=""></a><strong>Guildhests</strong></h3><p>This Roulette will place you in a random Guildhest and is unlocked once you have completed two different instances of this content type. Guildhests are some of the first content you will unlock in <em>FFXIV, </em>so they don’t provide bonuses as large as some of the other Roulette options, but they are good for new players learning how their class works in the confines of a party. Guildhest Roulettes provide EXP, Gil and Grand Company Seals upon completion.</p><h3 id="h13684"><a id=""></a><strong>Alliance Raids</strong></h3><p>These are the big ones. Alliance Raids are some of the most intense content in <em>Final Fantasy XIV</em> and will place you in a 24-person raid. This Roulette option is available after you unlock two of these Raids. Depending on your level, rewards include any of the types of Tomestones (Poetics, Aesthetics and Heliometry) as well as EXP and Gil.</p><h3 id="h13685"><a id=""></a><strong>Normal Raids</strong></h3><p>These are the small ones. Normal Raids are like Alliance raids only one-third the size (that means eight players). Rewards are the same as their larger brethren, though the quantity of Tomestones received is slightly smaller given the less strenuous nature.</p><figure id="" data-id="bfdef58499f7038993f975c75ee19f8d" data-recommend-id="image://bfdef58499f7038993f975c75ee19f8d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1170" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A man doing a mentor by some rocks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A man doing a mentor by some rocks." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bfdef58499f7038993f975c75ee19f8d" data-recommend-id="image://bfdef58499f7038993f975c75ee19f8d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1170" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A man doing a mentor by some rocks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h3 id="h13686"><a id=""></a><strong>Mentor</strong></h3><p>Mentor Roulettes should not be confused with <em>Final Fantasy XIV’s</em> mentor system, which encourages longtime players to help out newer ones. The Roulette will place you in an instance that has been waiting the longest, usually some of the more unpopular content. However, to be eligible you need to be experienced with the game, as it requires you to be level 100 and have an armor level of 685. On completion, Mentor Roulettes reward you with Aesthetics, Heliometries EXP and Gil.</p><h3 id="h13687"><a id=""></a><strong>Frontline</strong></h3><p>Frontline is <em>FFXVI’s </em>PvP mode, so this option is basically just a bonus for completing a round every day. To make it even simpler, there is only one Frontline map per day, so this Roulette is really just to get full queues for those interested in going head to head with other players. After you complete a Frontline match, you will be rewarded with Aesthetics and Heliometries.</p><hr><p>Daily Roulettes are a great way to take some of the grind out of <em>Final Fantasy XIV.</em> Given the numerous options available, you’re sure to find the perfect roulette to help you reach your current goals, whether that is getting a fantastic piece of end-game armor, or leveling up your secondary job. They can be a little intimidating, but just look at the list of rewards each one provides and pick the option that sounds the most enticing, then see what <em>FFXIV </em>is going to throw at you today!<br></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Cells Gets Final Update From Evil Empire]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dead-cells-gets-final-update-from-evil-empire/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-cells-gets-final-update-from-evil-empire.956868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dead-cells-gets-final-update-from-evil-empire/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After seven years and 35 updates, Dead Cells has received its final update from developer Evil Empire. </p>



<p>“Welp, this is it – the last update we made for Dead Cells (and its last update ever) is out now,” Evil Empire said <a href="https://x.com/Studio_Evil/status/1825466895853645859" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via social media</a>.</p>







<p>Dubbed “The End is Near” this update includes updates to the popular Curse mechanic with three new mobs, three new weapons, and three new mutations. There’s also a a new biome effect for players to choose.</p>



<p>Also included in the update are new legendary affixes, over  40 new heads for customization, new routing, and more accessibility options. You can check out the full notes in the update <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/588650/Dead_Cells/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">via Steam</a>.</p>



<p>“To the players – Thank you for everything,” Evil Empire said. “Thank you for all of your dedication, passion, and feedback. Dead Cells wouldn’t be what it is today without all of you.”</p>



<p>Despite this being the final update for the game, Dead Cells will continue on in various ways, per <a href="http://To the players - Thank you for everything. Thank you for all of your dedication, passion, and feedback. Dead Cells wouldn't be what it is today without all of you." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the studio itself</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to check out the final update to Dead Cells? For more Insider Gaming, check out what developers <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nearly-90-of-developers-surveyed-say-premium-games-dont-need-microtransactions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had to say about microtransactions</a> in AAA premium games. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones' Iconic Hat Just Sold for $630,000]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-iconic-hat-just-sold-for-630000</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-iconic-hat-just-sold-for-630-000.956865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-iconic-hat-just-sold-for-630000<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It belongs in a museum.</h2></div><section><p>The iconic hat worn by Harrison Ford in <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom</a> has just sold at auction for a whopping $630,000.</p><p>As reported by the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cj4x542vlrwo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BBC</a>, the hat came from the collection of Ford's stunt double Dean Ferrandini, who died in 2023.</p><p>The hat wasn't worn by Indy in the first film, Raiders of the Lost Ark, but was made specifically for Temple of Doom. It featured in early scenes such as when Indy, Willie Scott, and Short Round jumped from a crashing plane.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/19/indy-1724079529509.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Harrison Ford in Indiana Jones And The Temple Of Doom, 1984. Photo by Paramount/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Not to be confused with any other brown felt fedora, and evidence of the attention to detail literally stitched into the film, the inside lining of the hat features the gold monogrammed initials IJ.</p><p>The auction sold plenty of other film memorabilia alongside the Indiana Jones prop, including a Scout Trooper helmet from Star Wars: Episode 6 - Return of the Jedi for $315,000, a wand used by Daniel Radcliffe in Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban for $53,550, and a suit worn by Daniel Craig in Skyfall for $35,000.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Indiana Jones Movies in Chronological Order</h3></div></output><p>Indiana Jones is still going strong in 2024 despite the original trilogy having been released in the 1980s. A fifth film called <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-review">Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny</a> was released in 2023, while <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-gets-new-trailer-but-still-no-release-date-xbox-showcase-2024">a major video game adaptation called Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> is launching soon too.</p><p><em>Photo by Paramount/Getty Images.</em></p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Everything Coming to The First Descendant With Season 1 Invasion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-everything-coming-to-the-first-descendant-with-season-1-invasion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-everything-coming-to-the-first-descendant-with-season-1-invasion.956862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-everything-coming-to-the-first-descendant-with-season-1-invasion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Nexon has unveiled <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> Season 1, called Invasion, alongside fresh details on a new playable character, lore, and plenty more coming to its popular free-to-play co-op focused looter shooter.</p><p>The new Descendant is Hailey, a legendary sniper who stars in the trailer, below. Also coming with Season 1 are new Invasion Dungeon challenges and seasonal power scaling. Here’s the story setup:</p><blockquote>Following the disappearance of Karel's fleet, the Vulgus altered their strategy, targeting the depths of Ingris's dungeons. As they raid the Ancestors' facilities in a bid to reclaim their lost outpost, the defenders of Ingris have deployed their latest scout, Hailey, to intercept and counter these new threats.</blockquote><p>Season 1 starts on August 29 and will be available via a series of three updates across PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Series X and S, and PC via Steam.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>The First Descendant Season 1: Invasion’s three big updates will introduce:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>New Descendant: Hailey - </strong>Rising from a supply soldier in the guerilla unit is Hailey, a legendary sniper.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Armed with an anti-material sniper rifle, sub-zero bullets, and a storm snare, Hailey eliminates enemies with a single, devastating shot. </li><li>Her unique ability to lower her body temperature and emit cold air gives her a chilling edge in battle. </li></ul></li><li><strong>New “Invasion Dungeon” - </strong>Occurring randomly in two dungeons of the Hard Difficulty Infiltration Operations, players will have a choice between the existing operations or the all-new Invasions. Designed to disrupt the Descendent’s operations, these dungeons are perfect for speedrunning enthusiasts. = The faster players clear the Invasion, the greater the rewards.</li><li><strong>New Season Growth: Inversion Reinforcement - </strong>Upon encountering the Iron Heart, Descendants undergo a powerful Arche resonance phenomenon, unlocking new potentials and abilities known as Inversion Reinforcement. With Inversion Reinforcement, Descendants will be granted new incremental powers in hunting, attribute, recovery, survival and seasons that increase as players progress through the season.</li><li><strong>New Descendant: Ultimate Freyna - </strong>Freyna has harnessed the power of Arche’s toxicity, evolving it into a formidable weapon. Now, as the newest Ultimate Descendant, she makes her powerful entrance into Albion.</li><li><strong>New Descendant Story: Freyna - </strong>This season, players can delve into the gripping backstory of Freyna and her haunting “Room Zero Trauma” skill. Will Freyna conquer her inner trauma? Discover her journey in the Season 1: Invasion update.</li><li><strong>Void Intercept Boss Battle: Death Stalker -</strong> In the darkness of the Void, Death Stalker, a being far more powerful than any Colossus encountered before, lurks and hunts down the Descendants. Emerging from the shadows, it unleashes attacks laced with venom and horror. To protect Albion from Death Stalker’s threat, players must uncover the mysteries hidden in the darkness and intercept Death Stalker.</li><li><strong>Ultimate Weapon: Excava and Frost Watcher – </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Excava is a versatile weapon that combines the unique versatility of an assault rifle with a powerful charged shot. As you attack enemies, it charges voltage, which can then be converted into an energy grenade with a precise shot. This powerful weapon can be obtained as a Battle Pass reward and is also available through the free Battle Pass rewards.</li><li>Frost Watcher is a scout rifle obtainable through Season 1 content. Ideal when paired with Viessa and Hailey, it reduces chill resistance and enhances the damage of the player’s chilling skills. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Many more updates and additions, including a mysterious trade agent, are making their way to Albion. </strong></li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The First Descendant Season 1: Invasion Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The First Descendant has enjoyed enormous popularity <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-is-a-massive-hit-despite-its-various-controversies"><u>with over 10 million players in just 10 days</u></a>. But it has been heavily criticized for its ultra aggressive monetization, which includes the cost of Ultimate versions of its playable characters. IGN has reported on one player <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-community-reacts-in-disbelief-as-one-player-grinds-for-200-hours-to-unlock-every-ultimate-descendant"><u>who spent an eye-watering 200 hours to unlock every Ultimate Descendant currently available in the game without paying money</u></a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grab A New iPad For Only $199, Lowest Price Yet For Apple's 9th Gen Tablet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-a-new-ipad-for-only-199-lowest-price-yet-for-apples-9th-gen-tablet/1100-6525912/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grab-a-new-ipad-for-only-199-lowest-price-yet-for-apples-9th-gen-tablet.956859/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-a-new-ipad-for-only-199-lowest-price-yet-for-apples-9th-gen-tablet/1100-6525912/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525912">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you're in the market for a quality tablet but only want to spend a couple hundred bucks, there's a tremendous iPad deal worth checking out before it disappears. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1834057228489743355%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-a-new-ipad-for-only-199-lowest-price-yet-for-apples-9th-gen-tablet%2F1100-6525912%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Ddlvr.it%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a> are offering the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple iPad (9th Gen)</a> for $199 (was $329). This is the lowest price ever for the 9th Gen iPad. You'd struggle to find a tablet as high-performing as the 9th Gen iPad at this price.</p><div title="6525912 - iPad 9th Gen Deal" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2599" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6525912 - iPad 9th Gen Deal" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Apple iPad 10.2-Inch (9th Gen)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G9CJM1Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$199 (was $329)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>Equipped with the speedy A13 Bionic chip, a 10.2-inch Retina display, 64GB SSD, and two cameras (12MP front and 8MP back), this is a well-rounded tablet for gaming, streaming, and surfing the web. You'll get up to 10 hours of battery life on a single charge, and Touch ID helps keep your device secure while not in use.</p>                      </div><p>You'll get. the iPad (9th Gen), a Lightning to USB-C cable, and a 20W USB-C Power Adapter. Both the silver and space gray models are eligible for the discount, though it's unclear when the sale will end. Because of this, we'd recommend checking it out soon.</p><p>Though it's not included, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Pencil-1st-Generation-Adapter/dp/B0BJLG69QR?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Pencil (Gen 1)</a></strong> is fully supported by the tablet--as is the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Smart-Keyboard-iPad-Generation/dp/B0863F5KCT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Smart Keyboard</a></strong>. So if you want to use the tablet for drawing or as a versatile workstation, you have that flexibility. The Apple Pencil is currently on sale at Amazon for $69 (was $99), while the Smart Keyboard is $135 (was $159). You have seemingly endless case options for your new iPad, but one good option is a <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ProCase-Generation-Cover-Smart-Blue/dp/B07XY28FZG?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">budget third-party case that mimics Apple's Smart Folio</a></strong>. The black version of that case is only $8.</p><p>For a more powerful iPad that's still on the budget side, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-2022-10-9-inch-iPad-Wi-Fi/dp/B0BJLCWFNM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">10th Gen iPad with A14 chip is available for $320 at Amazon</a>. And if you want a more compact tablet, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/2021-Apple-iPad-Mini-Wi-Fi/dp/B09G91LXFP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8.3-inch iPad Mini--which has the better A15 chip--is discounted to $380</a> (was $500).</p><p>The newest iPads, iPad Pro M4 and iPad Air M2, released in May. Amazon has slashed $100 off the price of the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">2024 iPad Pro 11-inch</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-13-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J98W75?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">13-inch models</a> with Apple's new M4 chips. You can save $50 on the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Air-11-inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J617D7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch</a> with an M2 chip.</p><h3>Best Deals on 2024 iPads</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-13-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J98W75?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Pro M4 - 13-inch, 256GB</a> -- $1,197 (<del>$1,299</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Pro-11-Inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J6L2ZC?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Pro M4 - 11-inch, 256GB</a> -- $899 (<del>$999</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Air-11-inch-Intelligence/dp/B0D3J617D7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air M2 - 11-inch, 128GB</a> -- $549 (<del>$599</del>)</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-retro-game-preorder-guide/1100-6525752/">Halloween And Ash Vs. Evil Dead Retro Games Revealed - Collector's Bundle Preorders Live</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/">Rare Nintendo Amiibo Figures Restocked - Ness, Mr. Game &amp; Watch, ROB, Charizard, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-north-america-release/1100-6525641/">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection Anniversary Edition Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-brick-sets-in-stock-at-target-pixel-art-mew-pikachu-charmander-and-more/1100-6525719/">Retro Pokemon Brick Sets In Stock At Target - Pixel Art Mew, Pikachu, Charmander, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals-games-controllers-nintendo-consoles/1100-6525715/">Best Nintendo Switch Game Deals This Week - Zelda And Mario Games For Big Discounts</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/horror-movies-new-releases-4k-blu-ray-halloween-2024/2900-5645/">Biggest Upcoming Horror Movie Blu-Ray Releases Ahead Of Halloween</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525814&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/deadpool-and-wolverine-actor-shares-his-response-for-former-wrestler\/1100-6525814\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525861&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/transformers-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-preorder\/1100-6525861\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525887&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/glen-powell-who-was-in-dark-knight-rises-says-hes-never-been-asked-to-do-a-dc-or-marvel-movie\/1100-6525887\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525827&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/inside-out-2-4k-steelbook-preorders-live-releases-soon\/1100-6525827\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525710&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hellblazer-omnibus-1-preorders\/1100-6525710\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525883&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/batmobile-crocs-revealed-do-not-fire-missiles\/1100-6525883\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525764&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/randy-pitchfords-reaction-to-borderlands-flopping-might-be-funniest-thing-about-the-movie\/1100-6525764\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525888&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/terry-brooks-shannara-humble-bundle-get-20-books-in-the-high-fantasy-series-for-18\/1100-6525888\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525842&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-crpg-bundle-has-baldurs-gate-warhammer-40k-rogue-trader-and-5-more-games-for-35\/1100-6525842\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525880&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/im-not-used-to-backstep-dodging-in-metroidvanias-but-marko-beyond-brave-might-make-me-a-believer\/1100-6525880\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525819&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halle-berry-was-never-asked-to-cameo-as-storm-in-deadpool-wolverine\/1100-6525819\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525868&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-myth-wukong-pc-preorders-discounted-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch\/1100-6525868\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525751&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-minecraft-gift-set-comes-with-three-builds-for-only-30\/1100-6525751\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6516719&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-dribbles-the-clown-guide\/1100-6516719\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525546&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/elden-ring-manga-series-volume-4-shadow-of-the-erdtree\/1100-6525546\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525835&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legacy-of-kain-is-getting-a-re-release-kind-of\/1100-6525835\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525765&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-last-years-best-games-is-finally-coming-to-consoles\/1100-6525765\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game performers demand more support from studios over 'graphic' scenes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/game-performers-demand-support-from-studios-over-graphic-scenes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-performers-demand-more-support-from-studios-over-graphic-scenes.956853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/game-performers-demand-support-from-studios-over-graphic-scenes<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Video game performers are demanding studios provide more support when asking actors to work on intimate and explicit scenes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c23l4ml51jmo">In a wide-ranging BBC News report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, multiple actors working in the game industry recalled feeling "shaken” and "upset" after being cast in scenes that involved scenarios such as sexual assault and "full-on" intercourse.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">They claimed the industry has normalized a culture of secrecy around projects that means actors are often unaware of what they're signing on for until the very last minute. it means they might not know they'll be asked to perform intimate or explicit scenes that could be distressing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We'd get an email or a call from a studio saying we need you on these days for a shoot," said professional casting director Jessica Jeffries, who largely works in the game industry, speaking to BBC News. "That was all the information we'd get."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Jeffries explained she was once asked to act out a "graphic rape scene" with no prior warning. "This act could be watched for as long or as little time as the player wanted through a window, and then a player would be able to shoot this character in the head," she added. "It was just purely gratuitous in my opinion."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She refused to participate and eventually convinced the studio involved to ditch the "disgusting" moment.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"There's no nudity involved, but it's still an act and there's an intimacy in that act and also a violence in this situation," she continued. "So yes there may be a layer of Lycra between us, but you are still there and still having to truly immerse yourself in this scene."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Lax practices can turn working on explicit scenes into an 'excruciating' experience">Lax practices can turn working on explicit scenes into an 'excruciating' experience</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another actor who spoke out anonymously explained those working in games are "told almost nothing" when signing on to projects and must accept non-disclosure agreements to secure work. It's an approach that resulted in them having to record a "full-on sex scene" without any prior warning.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I had to [vocally] match the scene and through the glass in the booth was the entire team, all male, watching me," they recalled. "It was excruciating. At that stage I had been in the games industry a while, and I had never felt so shaken."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">They felt "upset" at being put on the spot and explained "nobody thought to ask me if I was okay with it, and nobody checked to see if I was okay afterwards." As a freelancer, they also felt uneasy voicing her concerns for fear of losing work.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">UK performing arts and entertainment trade union, Equity, has echoed those calls for more protections and support. The union recently published two new guides (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.equity.org.uk/advice-and-support/sector-specific-advice/videogames/best-practice-for-videogame-companies">Best Practice for Video Game Companies</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.equity.org.uk/advice-and-support/sector-specific-advice/videogames/working-as-a-videogame-performer">Working as a Video Game Performer</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) that aim to combat common issues for performers working in games–including a lack of notice for explicit and intimate scenes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"A full summary and outline of the story, scene breakdown and scripts (where possible) should be distributed to all cast members ahead of shooting or recording," reads the guide for game companies, which also calls for intimacy co-ordinators and closed sets.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Any explicit scenes with explicit language or content should be flagged up to a performer before recording. A safe line of communication should be in place between talent and production should the performer have any concerns or questions about content."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Read the full article on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c23l4ml51jmo">BBC News</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for more insights. For additional resources, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.equity.org.uk/advice-and-support/sector-specific-advice/videogames/working-as-a-videogame-performer">visit the Equity website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[C-Smash VRS: New Dimension Preview – No VR? No problem!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/19/c-smash-vrs-new-dimension-preview-no-vr-no-problem/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/c-smash-vrs-new-dimension-preview-%E2%80%93-no-vr-no-problem.956832/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/19/c-smash-vrs-new-dimension-preview-no-vr-no-problem/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/11/14/c-smash-vrs-review/">C-Smash VRS</a> was easily one of the best games from the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/psvr-2">PlayStation VR 2’s</a> launch window. Taking the cult classic arcade and Dreamcast game Cosmic Smash, it shifted the perspective, giving us a minimalist blend of Breakout and real-life Squash for a compelling VR sports game.</p>
<p>But shouldn’t everyone be allowed to smash cosmically? Not just the relative few with fancy hats? Enter C-Smash VRS: New Dimension, a fresh launch and free update coming at the end of September that will bring back flat-screen play and arcade delights alongside all the VR goodness of before.</p>
<p><iframe title="C-Smash VRS New Dimension - Date Announcement Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS VR2 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nMxDfVt-dG4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>



<p>New Dimension feeds a lot more of the original Cosmic Smash back into C-Smash VRS, specifically with the shift back to a third-person camera – there’s both a dynamic tracking cam and a pulled-back fixed camera – and seeing your avatar race back and forth as you position yourself to slap the ball back down the arena.</p>

<p>Going hands-on back-to-back with a classic arcade cabinet, there’s a very familiar feel between them, with the way that your avatar is animated in running, jumping and hitting, the ease and accessibility of timing shots, and more. However, New Dimension has added a few extra flourishes and moves on top of that. Whether they’re new moves or old, it’s pretty cool to see your character pulling off wall jumps, seeing the spinning flourish of a power shot, or a last ditch dive to reach a ball that’s heading outside of your hitting sweet spot.</p>

<p>Every mode from C-Smash VRS is available to play in New Dimension, whether it’s the Journey mode through strings of action puzzle stages, the endless Infinity mode, co-op or head-to-head multiplayer. Through all of the multiplayer modes, one of the key factors to New Dimension is that this bridges the divide between VR and flat-screen play.</p>
<p>This isn’t quite the first time that this has been done in VR gaming, since we have cross-play in digital board games like Demeo, or more significantly with racing games like Gran Turismo 7 and flight games. However, C-Smash VRS: New Dimension is possibly the first time that we’re dealing with two completely different styles of motion and control.</p>
<p>GT7 or Star Wars Squadrons might give VR players a greater awareness of their surroundings, but you’re still fundamentally fixed in the cockpit and have the limits of your vehicle. New Dimension has VR players with a first-person view and full motion tracking of your arms going up against the abstracted arcade action of the flat-screen game.</p>

<p>It’s a really fascinating problem, but one that RapidEyeMovers and Wolf &amp; Wood are very close to getting just right. We went through the gamut of head-to-head multiplayer options, myself playing on TV in London against Wolf &amp; Wood’s Ryan Bousfield up in Newcastle, and had some good fun and close matches, despite the completely different controls.</p>
<p>A few things stood out the more that I played, though. Depending on your preferences, C-Smash VRS is perhaps a bit too lenient with allowing you to press the hit button well before the ball gets back to you. You do want to try to position yourself and time the button press to get the best power and control, but there’s a lot of give here and your avatar can almost always make that diving hit to dribble the ball back down the court.</p>
<p>At the same time, there’s more advanced moves that have much, much less margin for error. A jump shot is very easy to end up with whiffing at clean air, and cool as it looks, so can a wall jump shot. When playing against another person who’s actively aiming for the edges of your reach, these are pretty important to master, and hopefully the final product can bring these two extremes a bit closer together.</p>

<p>VR versus TV play works wonderfully well and feels like it should be well balanced. A VR player will need to have better natural hand-eye coordination than a TV player, especially when trying to pinpoint a shot at a small target, but that physical control gives a higher ceiling for play.</p>
<p>Coming out on 26th September, C-Smash VRS: New Dimension is set to be all things to fans of hitting balls with rackets. This is probably the game that fans of the original would have hoped for, a modern successor with a bunch more modes, block types and power ups, but with familiar gameplay and feel. And you can always still pop a VR headset on as well, now hopefully with more people to play with online.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>