<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:58:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dynasty Warriors 3 Remaster Delayed To Unannounced Date On Switch 1 & 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/dynasty-warriors-3-remaster-delayed-to-unannounced-date-on-switch-1-and-2</link>
            <guid>1416298</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Originally due out in March</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="430965cbfb8a2"><a title="Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/430965cbfb8a2/dynasty-warriors-3-complete-edition-remastered.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Koei Tecmo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Just two months ahead of launch, Koei Tecmo Games and Omega Force have <a href="https://x.com/KoeiTecmoUS/status/2015726489149276652/photo/1">delayed</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-3-complete-edition-remastered">Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered</a>, which was due to come to Switch 1 and Switch 2 on <strong>19th March 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>The new date? There isn't one yet, unfortunately, with the game's producer Tomohiko Sho sharing that it will be "announced at a later date".The postponement has been made "in order to fully satisfy our fans" to give the development team time to "further improve on the quality of the game."</p>
<p>While not quite a last-minute delay, it's still a little surprising, though we've had very little news on the remaster since <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/dynasty-warriors-3-complete-edition-remastered-is-coming-to-switch-2-and-switch-in-2026">its announcement last year</a>.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067mgzpuv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Here's Koei Tecmo's statement in full:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>A message from the Producer</strong></p>
<p>The release of <em>Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered</em> has been postponed from the previously announced March 19, 2026.</p>
<p>As the first remaster of the <em>Dynasty Warriors</em> series, in order to fully satisfy our fans, we have made the decision to further improve the quality of the game. The new release date will be announced at a later date.</p>
<p>We appreciate your patience as we take a little more time before the game releases.</p>
<p>~<em>Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered</em> Producer, Tomohiko Sho</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="b48637727c0dc"><a title="Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered delay statement" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b48637727c0dc/dynasty-warriors-3-complete-edition-remastered-delay-statement.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://x.com/KoeiTecmoUS/status/2015726489149276652">Koei Tecmo</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>In case you need a little reminder, Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered is a complete rerelease of <strong>Dynasty Warriors 3</strong> and <strong>Dynasty Warriors 3: Xtreme Legends</strong>, which launched in 2001 and 2003 in North America on the PS2.</p>
<p>It was the first game in the series to sell over 1 million copies and introduced some of the series' most-famous features, including True Musou Attacks, two-player simultaneous play, and the officer development system.</p>
<p>In the meantime, you can at least check out the recently-released <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a> on Switch 2, which — in our eyes — <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins">is a fabulous game</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you disappointed by the delay? Still excited for Dynasty Warriors 3: Complete Edition Remastered? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188378,195984 @ 1769441403 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/KoeiTecmoUS/status/2015726489149276652/photo/1" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/KoeiTecmoUS/status/2015726489149276652/photo/1">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/4cf44be563369fc3db333c4c571eecc6 @ 1769442617 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/dynasty-warriors-3-remaster-delayed-to-unannounced-date-on-switch-1-and-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Insignia’s 32″ Smart Fire TV Is Nearly 50% Off Before the Super Bowl, Now Cheaper Than No-Name Portable Monitors]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/insignias-32-smart-fire-tv-is-nearly-50-off-before-the-super-bowl-now-cheaper-than-no-name-portable-monitors-2000662872</link>
            <guid>1416289</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Entertainment upgrades can cost a pretty penny, whether you’re after a new screen or just want to add some nice speakers for fuller sound to your setup. That’s not the case today, though.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6881/">Right now, the 32-inch Insignia Class F20 Series smart Fire TV can be yours for just $70, after Amazon took a whopping 46% (or $60) off the usual price.</a> The offer is open to both Prime and non-Prime shoppers. Delivery is free, too, so $70 is all you’ve got to pay. You might want to act fast, though. The retailer has marked this offer as a limited time one, so it’s likely going to wrap up soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6881/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Great for Casual Viewing</h2>
<p>The 32-inch size isn’t huge, but it’s also not too small to make content feel cramped. It’s perfect for smaller living areas and also bedrooms if you want to catch up on shows in your cozy blanket. The modest 720p resolution offers bright, clear visuals for everything from shows to movies and games. Yes, it won’t match the level of Full HD or 4K picture quality, but it’s still better than standard definition, especially on a screen this size. Lower resolutions typically feel more noticeable on bigger screens, but it works just fine here. You’ll enjoy the latest TV shows, your all-time favorite movies, and even catch up with friends on video calls perfectly well!</p>
<p>Speaking of TV shows and movies, Fire TV integration offers instant access to thousands of popular streaming platforms, apps, and Alexa skills, including Prime Video, Netflix, Hulu, HBO Max, YouTube, Apple TV+, Disney+, ESPN+, Sling TV, Paramount+, and other services. That translates into over 1.5 million movies and episodes ready to be watched. Some platforms require a subscription to get started, but a few free, ad-supported options are included, too. Maybe start the night with a classic thriller on Netflix, and switch to Prime Video later for a quick episode of a comedy show; the possibilities are endless.</p>



<p>There’s DTS Virtual-X sound to match the visuals. It’s an immersive sound format that delivers a three-dimensional audio that surrounds you. Expect footsteps, dialogs, whispers, mumbles, and laughter to come through clearly. Additionally, Alexa Voice Remote makes it easy to control content, adjust volume, switch inputs, and search across apps using just your voice. Just press and hold the microphone button on the remote to activate the assistant. You can say something like, “Alexa, show me the latest crime thrillers on Netflix”, or “Alexa, switch to Disney+”, without fiddling with the remote in the dark or getting up from your couch.</p>
<p>Connectivity options include two HDMI ports, composite (AV) jacks, digital optical output, USB port, headphone jack, coaxial jack, and Wi-Fi. This wide range lets you easily connect your home theater components, such as a Blu-ray player, game console, speakers, and cable, to the screen without feeling limited.</p>
<p>There’s a lot more to like about this 32-inch Insignia Smart Fire TV. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6881/">It normally sits at $130, which is already affordable, considering all that the screen offers. However, the current discount lets you pick one for just $70.</a> Grab it fast before it’s too late!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6881/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/insignias-32-smart-fire-tv-is-nearly-50-off-before-the-super-bowl-now-cheaper-than-no-name-portable-monitors-2000662872]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem’s Leon is a Brutal Powerhouse To Offset Grace’s Weakness]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-brutal-grace-weak/</link>
            <guid>1416283</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Resident Evil Requiem will be released in one month, and fans are <strong>excited</strong>. It’s a solid return to Raccoon City as <strong>both </strong>Leon Kennedy and Grace Ashcroft, and it’s a diverse title shot from two perspectives – first- and third-person. It also features the kind of dual story that has been seen in the series before, with Leon and Grace exploring the same locations at different times.</p>



<p>In a recent walkthrough by Xbox Wire, the nature of this duality is perfectly portrayed. While Leon Kennedy is a combat master and a powerhouse of the apocalypse, Grace Ashcroft is, by all accounts, demure and frightened – but <strong>willing to survive</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-leon-cracks-skulls-grace-kind-of-avoids-them">Leon Cracks Skulls, Grace Kind of Avoids Them</h2>



<p>The mixed perspective available in Resident Evil Requiem effectively makes this ‘two games’, as recently explained <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">by Xbox Wire</a>. Grace’s journey puts players in control of a timid, terrified individual with a tighter inventory, a lack of combat experience, and the clear inability to take down the game’s heftier enemies.</p>



<p>Leon, on the other hand, is blasting the undead and tearing enemies to shreds (even ones Grace can’t touch) while offering quips and one-liners.</p>



<p>When you assume control of Grace, you’re taking a more investigative approach, and combat is more of a last resort than a first approach. Leon flips that script and weilds chainsaws, a hatchet, and hands and feet that must be registered as lethal weapons somewhere to dispatch all comers.</p>



<p>Xbox Wire referred to Leon’s sections of the game as ‘big, loud, and dumb, and a relieving change of pace’ compared to Grace’s slower, methodical approach that orders you to think twice about every door you open and every corner you turn.</p>







<p>Resident Evil Requiem will be released on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC on February 27. Let us know which character you’re most excited to control on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-state-of-play-arriving-in-february-its-claimed/">new PlayStation State of Play might be coming soon</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-brutal-grace-weak/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Much Does YAPYAP Cost? Price, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/yapyap-cost-price/</link>
            <guid>1416280</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>YAPYAP is talking aloud, as it could be a huge indie hit, and wants everyone’s attention. Its yapping is literal, but one thing it’s remained silent on is the pricier tag.</p>



<p>The genre of games that includes hit titles such as Lethal Company, REPO, and PEAK has lovingly been titled ‘Friendslop.’ Seen as cheap and easy-to-make indie titles with a pure multiplayer appeal, centered around bedlam and busy work. It’s harsh, but it doesn’t matter when the games are so much fun. Besides, plenty of people seem to like them! <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/yapyap-official-release-date-countdown/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YAPYAP</a> looks to be the first of many ‘Friendslop’ games in 2026, and its concept means it could be the best.</p>



<p>However, a quick dive into YAPYAP’s price first is on the cards.</p>







<h2 id="h-do-we-know-yapyap-s-price">Do We Know YAPYAP’s Price?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It shouldn’t be too spooky. Credit to Maison Bap</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>So far, Maison Bap has yet to reveal YAPYAP’s price across any of its social media, and Insider Gaming has also tried reaching out for an early sneak peek at the price, to no avail.</strong></p>



<p>Either Maison Bap is keeping its cards close to its chest until YAPYAP’s launch, or the developer simply sees no reason to let people know. There’s nothing wrong with this, and it’s something many indie games on Steam opt for.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will keep checking for price updates, so check back to this guide. If you hear or see nothing, it’s probably a case of waiting until release day to find out.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-much-is-yapyap-expected-to-cost">How Much Is YAPYAP Expected To Cost?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A magical price tag surely awaits. Credit to Maison Bap</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>A reasonable price tag of between $7.99 and $9.99 is expected for YAPYAP.</strong></p>



<p>There’s a similar trending price tag for these types of games, and based on YAPYAP’s first trailer and announcements, it’s safe to assume the game will go in a similar direction to those that have come before it.</p>



<p>For example, Lethal Company’s RRP on Steam is $9.99 or £8.50, PEAK is $7.99 or £6.39, and REPO has also opted for the $9.99 or £8.50 approach.</p>



<p>Unless there’s a staggering amount of work and production that has gone into YAPYAP, you should expect to pay no more than $9.99 for YAPYAP.</p>



<p>Never say never in this industry. How much do you think YAPYAP will end up costing? Drop your guesses via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>YAPYAP is one of many indie games releasing this year. If you’re on the hunt for more, or want to see what the calendar has in store, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/8-biggest-indie-games-coming-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">8 biggest Indie games coming in 2026</a>, and maybe even the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/big-shooters-releasing-2026-best-fps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">8 big shooters releasing in 2026</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/yapyap-cost-price/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem - The Final Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-the-final-preview</link>
            <guid>1416274</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">With the triumphant return of Leon Kennedy, Resident Evil Requiem is forced to straddle an awkward line between all-out action and methodical survival horror. I’ll be honest, before getting my hands on the game and seeing the transition in action, I was extremely skeptical that Capcom would be able to create a coherent experience involving both Leon and Grace, the series’ latest, highly vulnerable protagonist. The switching between their polar opposite styles sounded jarring, which is almost never a good thing, and although it's been a while, it’s not like we haven’t been burned by Capcom’s desire to push the series towards action before. But I’m pleased to share that, from my all-too-brief three hours of hands-on time with Resident Evil Requiem, not only does this design really, really work, but there’s a lot more going on than just a merging of Resident Evil’s greatest hits.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">My playtime started with a short test drive of Leon, and Resident Evil 4 muscle memory kicked in immediately. Make no mistake, this plays just like the recent remake, enhanced with some clever new additions suitable for a veteran badass. Leon is more handy than ever, with a deadly hatchet that he can swing mercilessly added to his regular arsenal. Leon can also heave axes found in the world, can perform new contextual finishing moves such as a handgun shot to the chin, and <em>finally</em> wield the violent chainsaw. There was once a time Leon feared the chainsaw, but now, Leon has become chainsaw, destroyer of ghouls. After a short 15 minutes, the gameplay shifted perspective to Grace Ashcroft, Requiem’s second protagonist, picking up her journey immediately after the events of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-hands-on-preview">previous demo I wrote about in August</a> last year. Grace and Leon are polar opposites. Gone were the tense gunfights and forward momentum of Resident Evil 4, as I was immediately thrust into what felt like a sterile, white, clean version of Resident Evil 7. For the next two hours, I explored the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center, a somewhat traditional Resident Evil mansion that contains much of what you might expect among its rooms and corridors, but with plenty of new surprises. Surprises that mostly arise thanks to Grace’s abilities, or rather, lack thereof. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Much like in the previous demo, Grace’s section was focused almost exclusively on survival horror. She<em> is</em> armed with small pistols she finds in the environment, but her firepower and combat skills are negligible compared to our favorite floppy-haired icon. Where Leon can round-house kick zombies in the face, Grace makes do with a clumsy push. Leon is all-out assault, but the best course of action for Grace is slow and deliberate stealth, because if you <em>do</em> try to take some of the new enemies head-on, you’re going to have a bad time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last year’s demo revealed a new and much-celebrated stalker enemy, a towering, hunched, bug-eyed warden, but even within the span of my short three-hour session, I was introduced to another two, giving me the impression that Resident Evil Requiem won’t have one Mr. X or Nemesis-like persistent threat, but rather several smaller pursuers that seem to guard certain wings of the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center. Most notable was a hulking mass of blubber called Chunk, who burst through the wall and into my heart as he very slowly, but surely, ground his way through halls, stairwells and doorways in pursuit of me. Uniquely, Chunk fills the space entirely, so your only chance of survival is to find and navigate the loops built into the level design in order to outmaneuver the walking lardarse. It’s a clever design that generates a (somewhat) living, breathing wall of terror, and one you can’t simply sidestep or combat roll away from.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph">Much like the stalker I escaped last year, Chunk is cleverly implemented in the context of traditional safe rooms. Where the room’s bright light caused the previous stalker pain, Chunk simply can’t physically squeeze his sheer mass through the door, making sure there’s a logical in-world justification for a room of respite. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As well as Chunk, I also ran into a 7-foot-tall hulking unit masquerading as a chef, who, until he noticed me, was completely focused on his chopping chores. This soon-to-be stalker wasn’t yet in searching mode; rather, he was fulfilling, I assume, his pre-infection duties. This kind of behavior isn’t unique to the chef: It turns out in Resident Evil Requiem, the traditional zombie fodder is just as much the star of the show. You see, zombies not only talk now, but also have their own personalities.
</p><p>Resident Evil Requiem, aside from being packed with action and fear, is now also funny, something the series has never (at least intentionally) achieved before.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The undead are no longer unfortunate, generic lost souls, but rather husks that retain a smidge of living personalities, hanging out in the space they once occupied. There’s the lounge singing shrieker in the bar area, who, before being alerted, entertains herself by belting out a ditty. There are the zombies who were formerly patients in recovery that insist on wheeling around their drip stands, which are then, unsurprisingly, wielded as weapons when they’re aggro’d. Some zombies hate loud noises and will repeatedly yell at you if you even so much as smash a vase, and then there’s one that loves nothing more than turning lights on and off until you rudely interrupt him.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If it’s not clear by now, Resident Evil Requiem, aside from being packed with action and fear, is now also funny, something the series has never (at least intentionally) achieved before. As Grace creeps around the hospital, there’s the continual threat that around every corner awaits horror, or laughter, or sometimes even both! When you can hear the undead nattering away in a room you know you have to enter to achieve your next objective, it’s hard to know whether to be scared or have a good chuckle. On paper, this sounds like it could be awful – I’m aware of that, but honestly, it’s so good! I laughed so hard when I caught one particularly dopey zombie red-handed (both literally and figuratively), lifting a large and, importantly, red canister to throw my way. I’m sure you can imagine what happened next.  </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><div data-cy="paragraph"><p>The zombie fodder isn’t just around to entertain and quickly be disposed of, though. As Grace, the undead are a significant threat, always moving a little faster than you anticipate. Their fallen corpses also pose a significant conundrum, as they have the ability to turn into “Blister Heads,” a reinvention of the Resident Evil remake’s Crimson Heads for a new generation that reanimate with a bulbous cranium and become significantly tougher to take down. Fortunately, Grace has a new tool at her disposal: a Hemolytic Injector that weaponises the buckets of blood lying around the place (seriously, it’s <em>everywhere</em>), creating a lethal injection that can be used as a preventive measure against Blister Heads when injected into fallen enemies, and as a stealth attack against anything moving.</p><p>Beyond the new enemy types, playing as Grace does feel very familiar if you’ve played either Resident Evil 7 or Resident Evil 2, although obviously it leans more towards the latter if you choose to play as Grace in third person. You’re exploring a huge mansion with locked doors, there are obtuse puzzles to solve, antique coins to find that can upgrade your equipment, Mr. Raccoons to shoot, safe rooms with a typewriter for saving and a storage box for inventory management, and so forth. Leon, however, can brute-force open certain doors that Grace can’t and is far more aggressive with combat compared to Grace’s methodical stealth. You <em>can</em> also choose to play as Leon in first person, though after a brief dabble, it felt very unnatural to do so. I can’t help but think Capcom built this game with Leon in third person and Grace in first person in mind, but it’s hard to complain about more choice, despite knowing deep down the development team surely has a preference.</p></div><p>To Grace, Chunk and his fellow creeps are stalkers; to Leon, they’re targets.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">My demo ended with a second, all-too-short stint as Leon, which allowed me to revisit sections of the Care Center I’d previously experienced with Grace. Interestingly, this section demonstrated perhaps my favorite element of this hybrid experience. Leon is also exposed to some of the tougher combat encounters that I’d suffered through as Grace, although the perspective (much like my viewpoint of choice) is very different. When I met Chunk as Grace, I immediately retreated and was forced into a game of cat-and-mouse. The threat is intimidating and encourages you to tread lightly. As Leon, however, emboldened by my newly acquired shotgun, I felt instantly trigger-happy, unloading shells right up in Chunk’s face and launching hatchet attacks on his head as part of a fight that felt somewhat reminiscent of the El Gigante encounters of Resident Evil 4. To Grace, Chunk and his fellow creeps are stalkers; to Leon, they’re targets. This ethos was reaffirmed when taking on a wave of Blister Heads with Leon at the end of my play time. With Grace, I waited patiently for a stealth attack opportunity; with Leon, I was hurling hand grenades and throwing axes for fun.
</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Resident Evil Requiem - Leon Gameplay</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This year is the 30th anniversary of the Resident Evil series, so it feels like no coincidence that 2026’s Resident Evil Requiem is combining the best ideas of the saga into what appears to be a fantastically constructed tribute to everything that makes the series so great. Do you like tense survival horror? It’s here. Wanna go all guns blazing with intense action and a quip-obsessed hero? You get that too. Do you prefer playing RE games in first or third person? Doesn’t matter; you can do either. All these choices, along with my fears of a jarring play experience being mostly squashed, make it easy to believe that Capcom’s bold move to have its cake and eat it is going to pay off in a big way. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Dale Driver is an Associate Director of Video Programming at IGN. Be thoroughly bored by following him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/daledriver.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@daledriver.bsky.social</em></a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-the-final-preview]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Super Mario Bros. Wonder Amiibo Are Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-bros-wonder-amiibo-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>1416271</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Elephant Mario, Captain Toad, and more.</h2></p><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">I know it’s been sacrilege for nearly three decades now, but I’ve always preferred 2D Mario games to those newfangled 3D ones. (I’m an elder Millennial; leave grandpa to his ramblings). So I couldn’t be happier Super Mario Bros. Wonder is getting the “<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Switch 2 Edition + expansion</a>” treatment in March. To celebrate the new-gen upgrade and the Meetup in Bellabel Park DLC, Nintendo is releasing three new amiibo based on the game. They cost $24.99 each, and are set to release March 26, the same day as the game’s new content. They’re available to preorder now (<a href="https://zdcs.link/Qb8Z4E?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see them at Amazon</a>).</p><p id="super-mario-bros-wonder-amiibo"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Super Mario Bros. Wonder amiibo">Super Mario Bros. Wonder amiibo</h2></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qb8Z4E?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QLpxq0?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See at GameStop</a> </li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/9yP2JO?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See at Target</a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The new amiibo are <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPx2Jo?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Elephant Mario</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/91w3xA?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Captain Toad &amp; Talking Flower</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/aX4l3e?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Poplin &amp; Prince Florian</a>. Elephant Mario is a delightful amiibo, with the pachyderm plumber squeezing his portly torso into a pipe. As for the Poplin amiibo, the orangesicle-colored character holds a watering can while Prince Florian sits on his head. And in the Captain Toad amiibo, our hero is doing a victory pose in front of the Talking Flower.</p><p id="talking-flower-preorders-are-live"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Talking Flower preorders are live">Talking Flower Preorders Are Live</h2></p><div id="234737"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234737" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Talking Flower</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of talking flowers, Nintendo is also releasing another plastic curiosity to add to its lineup of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/alarmo-latest-in-long-line-of-weird-nintendo-hardware-some-failed-hard">weird hardware</a>. This one is a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/talking-flower-super-mario-bros-wonder-where-to-buy">toy version of the Talking Flower</a> that actually talks to you. It’s available to preorder now as well.</p></div><p id="super-mario-bros-wonder-on-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Super Mario Bros. Wonder on sale">Super Mario Bros. Wonder (Switch) on Sale</h2></p><div id="234734"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234734" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Bros. Wonder (Switch)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the Switch 2 version of Super Mario Bros. Wonder, Nintendo is pulling a Nintendo and charging $79.99 for the game. That’s obviously absurd, so here’s a workaround if you don’t already own the original Switch game. You can buy a copy of the original Switch game <a href="https://zdcs.link/aN3XjV?object_uuid=5334a388-8ca8-434b-bf6b-80bbc095296c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">on sale now at Woot for $46.99</a> and then upgrade it on the eShop for an additional $19.99 once the expansion comes out. That gets you the full Switch 2 experience of the game for $64.99, which saves you $15. Not too shabby.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a commerce editor and deals expert for IGN. He also runs IGN's board game and LEGO coverage. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-bros-wonder-amiibo-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Direct Announced For This Week, Focused on Tomodachi Life: Living The Dream]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-announced-for-this-week-focused-on-tomodachi-life-living-the-dream</link>
            <guid>1416265</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Another Nintendo Direct is coming this Thursday, January 29, dedicated to the company's upcoming social sim game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream">Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Coming just days after a Nintendo Direct focused on The Super Mario Galaxy Movie which debuted our first look at Yoshi, Birdo and more, the next scheduled broadcast from the company will instead return to its games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You'll be able to tune in for more details on the Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 life sim game this Thursday at 6am Pacific, 9am Eastern or 2pm UK time. The stream is set to run around 20 minutes.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Living the Dream will be the third game in Nintendo's Tomodachi Life franchise, which lets you oversee a community of Mii characters. While a relatively niche series in the West compared to its bigger brands, Tomodachi Life enjoys a strong following among its fans, and particularly so in Japan. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, the franchise will be getting its first dedicated Nintendo Direct, similar to how Kirby Air Riders was treated to its own presentation (and then a second!) last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The series' first game, Tomodachi Collection, launched in 2009 for Nintendo DS (albeit only in Japan). Its 3DS sequel, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomodachi-life">Tomodachi Life</a>, was then released worldwide and went on to sell a very respectable 6.72 million units.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Memorably, Tomodachi Life experienced a backlash over its lack of same-sex relationships, something that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/05/08/nintendo-strikes-down-gay-marriage-requests-for-tomodachi-life">Nintendo found itself having to comment on</a> after rumors spread online that they were something that had been originally programmed into the game that was later removed. Nintendo denied this, though not before the controversy blew up to the point that it was parodied on late night TV by John Oliver, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XV5w8OFrm6U" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via a skit which featured crudely animated versions of Mario and Link snogging</a>. Notably, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/05/09/nintendo-next-installment-of-tomodachi-life-will-be-more-inclusive">Nintendo then promised that if it did make another Tomodachi Life game</a>, it would make it "more inclusive, and [something that] better represents all players."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the status of same-sex relationships is yet to be confirmed (though may be this week), Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream is already notable for finally allowing Mii characters to have ears. It only took 20 years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-announced-for-this-week-focused-on-tomodachi-life-living-the-dream]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart Series Veteran Hideki Konno Retires After Almost 40 Years at Nintendo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-series-veteran-hideki-konno-retires-after-almost-40-years-at-nintendo</link>
            <guid>1416262</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"The people who defined an era are leaving Nintendo."</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">It has recently been revealed that Nintendo veteran Hideki Konno retired from the company last summer after almost 40 years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Joining Nintendo in 1986, Konno shaped many of the Japanese game company’s major series. He worked as assistant director on Super Mario Bros. 2 and 3, as well as designing the games’ levels and characters. Later, as a director, he helmed games including Yoshi's Island, the SNES version of SimCity, and Luigi’s Mansion on the GameCube.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Konno is probably best known for his extensive work on the Mario Kart series. He directed the original Super Mario Kart and Mario Kart 64, before going on to produce Mario DS, Mario Kart Wii, Mario Kart 7, Mario Kart 8 (plus the Deluxe version), and Mario Kart Tour. He got a special thanks credit on Switch 2 launch title Mario Kart World.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/26/gettyimages-53398735-1769436256644.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">German model Eva Padberg (R) and game developer Hideki Konno (L) show a Nintendo DS on August 17, 2005 in Leipzig, Germany. Photo by Andreas Rentz/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Konno produced many other games like Nintendogs and was also hardware director for the 3DS. As head of Nintendo mobile, he produced titles such as Animal Crossing Pocket Camp and Fire Emblem Heroes, as well as contributing to the global success of Pokémon Go!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As reported by Japanese news outlet <a href="https://www.gamespark.jp/article/2026/01/26/161984.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Game*Spark</u></a>, last year Konno updated his employment status on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hideki.konno.10" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Facebook</u></a> to say that he left Nintendo in July 2025. This was recently spotted by fans over on the <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/hideki-konno-producer-and-game-designer-has-left-nintendo.16356/#post-2146844" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Famiboard forums</u></a> and has become a <a href="https://x.com/Stealth40k/status/2014862231368790495?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>talking point </u></a>on Twitter / X over the weekend. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Noticing the discussion of Konno’s departure, Takaya Imamura (another former Nintendo employee who was art director on Star Fox 64 and The Legend of Zelda: Majora's Mask) <a href="https://x.com/ima_1966/status/2014949188841439270?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>tweeted</u></a>: "Konno's resignation is starting to attract attention. The people who defined an era are leaving Nintendo." Imamura himself departed Nintendo in 2021 to pursue his own projects, resulting in the Omega 6 manga and Switch game Omega 6: The Triangle Stars (he even wrote <a href="https://note.com/imamura_1966/n/n09b6dd5931a3" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a blog post </u></a>on why he left). </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, it was revealed that another longtime Nintendo creator, Kensuke Tanabe, had recently retired, with Tanabe confirming that Metroid Prime 4 was his last game at Nintendo (as reported by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/veteran-nintendo-producer-kensuke-tanabe-known-for-metroid-and-paper-mario-reportedly-confirms-retirement/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Video Games Chronicle</u></a>). Many of the legendary game creators who shaped the NES and SNES eras are now in their 60s and 70s, including Mario creator Shigeru Miyamoto (72). We will likely be seeing many more of these influential game designers departing Nintendo in the coming years, especially with the Switch 2 out the door.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Andreas Rentz/Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-series-veteran-hideki-konno-retires-after-almost-40-years-at-nintendo]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem final hands-on previews]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/resident-evil-requiem-final-hands-on-previews</link>
            <guid>1416259</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>One last look ahead of the February 27 release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Several outlets have gone up with final hands-on previews of <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil Requiem [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a></em>, which include new gameplay footage. <span id="more-1021261"></span></p><p>Previews are available at <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/917/G091773/20260126037/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4Gamer.net</a> (<a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/917/G091773/20260126055/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://dengekionline.com/article/202601/64267" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dengeki Online</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-9-final-preview" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eurogamer</a> (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-requiems-director-on-why-re9-wont-suffer-the-same-multi-protagonist-woes-as-re6-and-why-its-more-like-sushi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/64140" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Famitsu</a> (<a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202601/63877" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2026/01/26/exciting-emulation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Game Informer</a>, <a href="https://www.gamer.ne.jp/news/202601270003/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gamer.ne.jp</a> (<a href="https://www.gamer.ne.jp/news/202601270002/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/resident-evil/resident-evil-requiem-the-last-preview-grace-and-leon-gameplay/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GamesRadar+</a>, <a href="https://game.watch.impress.co.jp/docs/preview/2080571.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GAME Watch</a> (<a href="https://game.watch.impress.co.jp/docs/interview/2080575.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://giantbomb.com/videos/quick-looks/resident-evil-requiem" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Giant Bomb</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-the-final-preview">IGN</a>, <a href="https://jp.ign.com/resident-evil-9/82354/preview/re2re4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IGN Japan</a> (<a href="https://jp.ign.com/resident-evil-9/82360/interview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-9-requiem-preview-leon-gameplay-grace-2000662270" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kotaku</a>, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-everything-you-need-to-know-about-leon-s-kennedy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Blog</a>, <a href="https://blog.ja.playstation.com/2026/01/27/20260127-requiem-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Blog Japan</a> (<a href="https://blog.ja.playstation.com/2026/01/27/20260127-requiem-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a>), <a href="https://www.polygon.com/resident-evil-requiem-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polygon</a>, <a href="https://www.shacknews.com/article/147511/resident-evil-requiem-final-preview-pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shacknews</a>, <a href="https://www.videogamer.com/features/resident-evil-requiem-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VideoGamer</a>, and <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Wire</a>.</p><p><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,620 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [899 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,340 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3764200/Resident_Evil_Requiem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on February 27.</p><p>Watch the footage below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay</span></h2><p><strong>4Gamer.net</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="【バイオハザード レクイエム】先行プレイ映像4K  │ 頼もしい「レオン」パートと怯えて逃げ回る「グレース」パートの2本立て試遊バージョン" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LEZ0Nv7vqr4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Bahamut</strong></p><p><iframe title="《惡靈古堡9：安魂曲》最新版 里昂+葛蕾斯雙章節實機試玩解說" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qe5yC9V2nlU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Degenki Online</strong></p><p><iframe title="『バイオハザード レクイエム』レオン先行プレイ動画。超爽快アクションで強敵たちとバトル！　進化した体術やパリィも紹介【4K動画】" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/siSuDRcVYag?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『バイオハザード レクイエム』グレース先行プレイ動画。アイテム管理がシビアでゾンビが超怖い。『バイオ』の原点に近い恐怖が味わえる！【4K動画】" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cmhbyvU3HD4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Easy Allies</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Resident Evil Requiem is Raising the Bar - Hands-On Preview w/ Leon and Grace" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HsDzDqZCwM0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Famitsu</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『バイオハザード レクイエム』グレースとレオン両方のパートを先行プレイ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k83Zi2WtRk0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>IGN</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Resident Evil Requiem - The Final Preview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NC52PP2gieM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>IGN Japan</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="名作「RE:2」と「RE:4」が融合！『バイオハザード レクイエム』試遊感想トーク" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4xkoEjumOP8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Kit &amp; Krysta</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="We Played Resident Evil Requiem for THREE HOURS - Our Hands-On Impressions" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a76P10SDlBM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [49,424 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Access</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Leon's Still Got It - Resident Evil Requiem Hands-On" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TzSVPrRH-Wk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/resident-evil-requiem-final-hands-on-previews]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK Appeals court state RuneScape gold counts as property and can be stolen, in $700k bombshell case]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-appeals-court-state-runescape-gold-counts-as-property-and-can-be-stolen-in-700k-bombshell-case</link>
            <guid>1416223</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-gold-custom-header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The UK Court of Appeals has ruled that MMO currency can be treated as property, and the stealing of such currency can be deemed criminal theft.</p>
<p>This comes following a verdict against a former Jagex developer who allegedly accessed nearly 70 player accounts to harvest large quantities of gold, selling this in-game currency for Bitcoin. Jagex claims the total value of gold taken amounts to £543,123, based on the rate that in-game Bonds can be bought for with gold. These bonds can be exchanged for an in-game subscription, which otherwise must be bought with real-world money.</p>
<p>The original verdict on this case, which went the way of the defence, deemed that: "gold pieces were not rivalrous and were more akin to pure information," and therefore could not be stolen. Taking this gold was not deemed theft as, per the 1968 Theft Act, something stealable is: "money and all other property, real or personal, including things in action and other intangible property. As they believed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/runescape">RuneScape</a> gold more akin to pure information, there was no legal basis for it to be a stealable good.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Leagues VI: Demonic Pacts - RELEASING APRIL 2026 (Cinematic Trailer)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IzRNQ_cXRK4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Leagues VI: Demonic Pacts - RELEASING APRIL 2026 (Cinematic Trailer)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IzRNQ_cXRK4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IzRNQ_cXRK4?autoplay=1" title="Leagues VI: Demonic Pacts - RELEASING APRIL 2026 (Cinematic Trailer)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>You can watch the trailer for the upcoming Old School RuneScape league here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IzRNQ_cXRK4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Fast forward to the Court of Appeals, and as can be seen in <a href="https://caselaw.nationalarchives.gov.uk/ewca/crim/2026/4">R v Andrew Lakeman [2026]</a>, Lord Justice Popplewell, His Honour Judge Mayo DL and Mr Justice Soole believed this previous verdict did not "bear analysis". Basically, they disagreed.</p><p>As seen in the conclusion (the full document is very interesting to read for those eager to dig through the minutia) it was deemed that RuneScape gold does fall under the "intangible property" portion of the Theft definition. Section 85 reads:</p>
<p>"They are properly described as something which can be stolen as a matter of normal use of language. They do not fall within any of the established exceptions. They are not 'pure knowledge': functionally they exist as identifiable assets distinct from the code which gives rise to them and outside the minds of people. There is no good policy reason for excepting them from the category of property which can be stolen.</p>
<p>"On the contrary, they are assets which have an ascertainable monetary value and which may be traded for that value both in the game and outside the game. Within the rules of the game they represent money’s worth as the product of purchase of a bond. Outside the game they are regularly traded for money’s worth. They are capable of being subject to dishonest dealing which deprives their possessor of their use and value. It would be surprising and unsatisfactory if such dishonest dealing did not amount to the offence of theft."</p>
<p>This not only brings to a close a chapter in Jagex's ongoing battle against one of its former employees, but also raises some interesting questions about the legal future of video game currencies. If stealing in-game gold is considered theft as a legal precedent, then what does this mean for other UK-based hackers for other games? If in-game items have value and are not just packets of valueless data, does this throw a curveball into the 'are loot boxes gambling' debate within UK institutions? This court case may very well be the gift that keeps on giving over the next few years.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-appeals-court-state-runescape-gold-counts-as-property-and-can-be-stolen-in-700k-bombshell-case]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Preview – Action and horror in perfect harmony]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-preview-action-and-horror-in-perfect-harmony/</link>
            <guid>1416202</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Until very recently, everything we’d seen of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/resident-evil-9-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> was framed through one lens: Grace Ashcroft’s reluctant, fearful exploration of unfamiliar and hostile environments. It was quiet, tense, and deliberately uncomfortable. Then Leon Kennedy steps in, and suddenly the tone shifts.</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Showcase | January 15, 2026" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i9HIc7GZLa0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Leon is no longer the wide-eyed rookie we first met in Resident Evil 2. He isn’t even the cocky, quip-throwing action hero of Resident Evil 4. This version of Leon feels like a natural endpoint to everything Capcom has built toward: a grizzled veteran who has survived too much, seen too much, and now moves through horror with brutal efficiency. And honestly? I loved it.</p>


<p>Our hands on time began by putting me firmly in Leon’s shoes, and as you’d expect, the action ramps up almost immediately. Leon is armed to the teeth: a large gun, a trusty hatchet, and the confidence of someone who knows exactly what they’re doing. He swings that hatchet with reckless abandon, carving through enemies in a way that almost made me feel like I was playing Devil May Cry, albeit grounded by one important limitation. Overuse dulls the blade, forcing you to think about when to commit and when to fall back.</p>


<p>That restriction keeps the melee from becoming mindless, but the dulling blade rarely feels punishing. If the hatchet isn’t enough, Leon can simply blast his way out of trouble. The balance between melee and gunplay feels deliberate, encouraging aggression without completely abandoning the survival roots of the series.</p>
<p>At this stage in his career, Leon feels closer to John Wick than a traditional survival horror protagonist. He handles his weapons with extreme flair, holding his gun at angles that suggest years of hard-earned muscle memory. Every movement communicates experience. This is a man who has survived Raccoon City, cults, bio-weapons, and government conspiracies. Seeing his progression realised so confidently is genuinely satisfying. It feels earned.</p>

<p>That contrast becomes even more apparent when Requiem switches perspectives back to Grace Ashcroft, and it’s here that the game really starts to show its ambitions.</p>
<p>In many ways, Resident Evil Requiem feels like two games sharing the same world. Grace’s sections are deliberately slower, more methodical, and far more vulnerable. Her default perspective is first person, and the reasoning is obvious: first person is scarier. You can’t see your own back. You feel boxed in. Every sound feels closer than it should.</p>
<p>This isn’t new territory for Resident Evil, but what Requiem does smartly is allow you to play both characters from whichever perspective you prefer. That flexibility feels like Capcom fully embracing the idea of a “customised horror experience.” Want more action? Switch to third person. Want maximum tension? First person has you covered. It’s a smart evolution of what Village experimented with, but this time it’s reinforced by having two protagonists who are fundamentally different.</p>

<p>Grace, unlike Leon, is a fledgling FBI agent. This is her first real exposure to this kind of horror, and the game communicates that clearly through both mechanics and animation. Her movements are cautious. Her reactions feel human. Her inventory space is limited, meaning classic Resident Evil backtracking returns in full force, unlike Leon who is still lugging around his very large attache case!</p>
<p>You’ll be visiting item boxes often, making hard decisions about what to carry, and constantly weighing risk versus reward. Ammo and health are scarce, and I never once felt truly comfortable while exploring. Every encounter demanded consideration, because the zombies are aggressive and varied.</p>
<p>One standout moment had me entering a bar area where I spotted a female zombie dressed in white, quietly humming to herself. It was unsettling in that distinctly Resident Evil way. The moment she noticed me, she began screaming and suddenly I was swarmed. That calm-to-chaos transition is something the series has always done well, and Requiem nails it.</p>

<p>Enemy variety plays a big role here too. There’s a clear nod to Resident Evil Remake’s Crimson Heads – zombies that can return later, faster and far more dangerous if they aren’t properly dealt with. These new variants scramble like wild animals, leaping over obstacles, swiping relentlessly, and forcing you to rethink how you approach combat. They are a nightmare in the best possible way.</p>
<p>Dealing with them ties into one of Requiem’s more interesting new mechanics: blood collection. Blood is now a resource, used in crafting alongside traditional materials. You can find it in buckets scattered throughout the environment or harvest it from defeated enemies. How you kill a zombie affects how much blood you can extract, adding another layer of strategy to encounters. One item that can be crafted is a neat injector that once inserted into a zombie, will make it explode in a shower of blood… yum.</p>
<p>It’s an elegant system that reinforces Resident Evil’s identity: everything has a cost, and efficiency matters.</p>

<p>Of course, no Resident Evil game would be complete without puzzles, and the section I played delivered exactly what you’d hope for. Nothing overly obtuse, nothing insultingly simple; just solid, classic puzzles that reward observation and attention to detail. Combined with light backtracking, it all feels comfortably familiar.</p>
<p>Requiem is stunning to behold. Every surface gleams. The lighting is moody and precise. Blood splatter feels tactile. Every little detail is ridiculous, right down to seeing individual beard hairs on Leon’s face. It’s one of those games where you constantly stop to take in the surroundings, even when you really shouldn’t.</p>
<p>Naturally, there are larger threats lurking. What little I saw of the primary antagonist was intriguing enough to make me want answers. There’s also a giant, bloated zombie that stalks you through corridors, shouting and taunting as it goes. It barely fits through doorways, slowly forcing its way through tight spaces, and if it catches you, that’s it.</p>
<p>The idea of zombies now being able to chin wag is… unsettling. And I’m very curious to see how that’s explained.</p>
<p>After a couple of hours with Grace, control switches back to Leon — and the tonal whiplash is incredible. That same hulking enemy? Leon just fights it. Head-on.&nbsp;His action heavy gameplay is relentless: Crimson Heads, window dives, grenades flying everywhere, and some of the most stylish gunplay I’ve experienced in a Resident Evil game. It was pure adrenaline.</p>

<p>What really strikes me about Resident Evil Requiem is how confidently it embraces this division. These days, the fanbase is split: tank-control purists, third-person lovers, first-person fans, and those who just want more Resident Evil, regardless of format. Requiem feels like Capcom acknowledging all of them and saying, “Why not?”</p>
<p>For me, this is an evolution. Not a reinvention, not a rejection of the past, but a synthesis of everything the series has learned.</p>
<p>Resident Evil Requiem will divide people, but in a healthy way. For me, this is an evolution that is a synthesis of everything the series has learned. It’s bold, confident, and unafraid to let different playstyles coexist. And honestly? It’s just good to have Leon back, to revisit Racoon City, and to be introduced to a new protagonist who feels genuinely tied to the series’ roots.</p>
<p>Resident Evil: Outbreak was a banger, and I cannot wait to see how Requiem ties everything together.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/26/resident-evil-requiem-preview-action-and-horror-in-perfect-harmony/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will There Be a PlayStation State of Play in February 2026?: “There Will Be, Yes,” Says Insider]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2026/</link>
            <guid>1416196</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><strong>PlayStation</strong> is planning to host another <strong>State of Play </strong>event in <strong>February 2026</strong>, according to the well-known and reliable insider, NateTheHate. They don't provide any more information as to what the event will focus on or what it might feature, but they do confidently confirm there is an event planned for next month.</p>



<p>When directly asked by <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/2015679942957138341">a user on X (formerly Twitter)</a> if there will be a State of Play in February this year, NateTheHate simply replies, "<em>There will be, yes</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>PlayStation has gotten into the habit of only confirming these showcases a day or two before they actually happen, so we probably won't know if this claim is correct or not until next week at the earliest, but it is good to hear that we should have something to look forward to when it comes to PlayStation news for 2026.</p>



<p>That said, the timing of these showcases is becoming so predictable that you can probably already predict next year's run of shows. <strong>Since 2021</strong>, PlayStation has held a State of Play showcase of some kind in the second month of the year. <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2021-new-announcements-10-games/">That initial February event was a general State of Play</a> that showcased upcoming games at the time, like <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/returnal-in-my-restless-dreams-i-see-that-house/">Returnal,</a> <a href="https://wccftech.com/arkanes-deathloop-is-free-for-a-week-on-the-epic-games-store/">Deathloop</a>,<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-fixed-doors-and-flying-ninjas/"> Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a>, </strong>and <strong>Sifu, </strong>to name a few. </p>



<p>2022's February State of Play was instead <a href="https://wccftech.com/gran-turismo-7-state-of-play-cars-tracks-cafe/">a dedicated event for <strong>Gran Turismo 7</strong></a>, with 2023's February State of Play returning to a general event, <a href="https://wccftech.com/street-fighter-6-reveals-its-final-3-launch-characters-during-state-of-play/">featuring looks at <strong>Street Fighter 6</strong></a>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-gameplay-reveal/">Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a></strong>, and more. The 2024 February State of Play was once again a dedicated event, this time for <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a></strong>, though interestingly, it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-state-of-play-playstation-january-31-15-games-40-minutes/">preceded by a general event that took place on January 31 that year</a>, so it was a bit of 'have your cake and eat it too' to start the year. </p>



<p>And finally, in case you forgot, there was <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-playstation-state-of-play-confirmed-for-february-12th/">a general State of Play event last year</a>, which included a look at <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/saros-will-be-the-ultimate-evolution-of-housemarques-gameplay-launches-in-2026-on-playstation-5/">Saros</a></strong>, the release date for <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-releases-august-28-on-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-and-pc/">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a></strong>, a look at <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-creators-mindseye-game-slated-to-launch-this-summer/">MindsEye</a></strong>, and more.</p>



<p>Considering the fact that PlayStation has used the month of February to host one of these events for the last five years, it was already a pretty good bet it would do so again in 2026. These events aren't exactly locked into place every year, so we can't exactly take it for granted that we'll always have one in February, but for now, the pattern of showcases in a year for PlayStation seems to always include one in February.</p>



<p>The big remaining question is whether this year's event will be dedicated to one game, or a more general event. If it's a dedicated event, it could perhaps be a dedicated event for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-unreal-engine-4/">third installment of the <strong>Final Fantasy Remake Trilogy</strong></a>, or a dedicated event for <strong>Saros</strong>, which we know is <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-saros-trailer-shows-provides-new-look-at-story/">due to arrive in the first half of the year on <strong>April 30, 2026</strong></a><strong>.</strong> It might even be one last hype-up event for <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-reveals-mild-marathon-pc-system-requirements/">Marathon</a></strong>, ahead of its arrival in March. Hopefully, we'll know as early as next week.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cards To Upgrade The Lorwyn Eclipsed Commander Decks]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/cards-to-upgrade-lorwyn-ecllipsed-commander-decks</link>
            <guid>1416193</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Magic has returned to the classic world of Lorwyn and Shadowmoor for the first time since we left following <em>Eventide </em>in 2008, almost 20 years ago.</p><p>A world defined by duality, by light and dark, <em>Lorwyn</em>/<em>Shadowmoor </em>drew on Celtic mythology and used many typal themes on the Lorwyn side of things with 8 races focused on (along with a number of classes), and Shadowmoor, the dark counterpart focused on color and -1/-1 counters. <em>Lorwyn Eclipsed</em> has the tough job of capturing 4 sets in one newly merged world where both light and dark co-exist.</p><p>Beyond the set itself, one other element of duality is the pair of commander decks releasing with <em>Lorwyn Eclipsed</em>. For Lorwyn, we appropriately have a typal deck focused on one of the creature types that are classically Lorwyn in elemetals with Dance of the Elements. For Shadowmoor, Blight Curse is a deck focused on -1/-1 counters and all the wonderful things you can do with them.</p><p>Any pre-constructed deck though has some spaces it can be improved. New ideas to be sprinkled in, and that's where I come in with my special spice kit for you. Let’s get cooking a few <em>Lorwyn Eclipsed</em> commander deck upgrades.</p><h2>Dance of the Elements Upgrades</h2><p>A quick look at <a href="https://mtg.wiki/page/Lorwyn_Eclipsed/Commander_decks#Dance_of_the_Elements" rel="nofollow">Dance of the Elements </a>shows it as a 5 color Elemental typal deck. It focuses heavily on enters and leaving abilities on elements, with Evoke, Encore, and Myriad all showing up in the deck and fueling those abilities, along with tokens. The face commander <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/1/ashling-the-limitless" rel="nofollow">Ashling, the Limitless </a>wants to focus on Evoke, while the alternate commander <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/3/mass-of-mysteries" rel="nofollow">Mass of Mysteries</a> wants to focus on Myriad.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dance-of-the-elements-commanders.jpg?itok=C_kZmBpm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1122" height="780">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dance-of-the-elements-commanders.jpg?itok=y7UTW1Ls 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1122" height="780">
                  

  </picture><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/2x2/171/animar-soul-of-elements" rel="nofollow">Animar, Soul of Elements</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/animar-soul-of-elements_0.jpg?itok=rtZjLO5R 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="372" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/animar-soul-of-elements_0.jpg?itok=l4YRJmsy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="372" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>One elemental missing from the deck but a natural friend to Ashling, the Limitless is Animar, Soul of the Elements. &nbsp;Aanimar’s ability to reduce cost of creature spells means that with only a few plays all future elementals will be evokable for free with Ashling, the Limitless. Meanwhile, Animar himself gets bigger, and is relatively resistant to removal with protection from black and white.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/who/146/the-master-multiplied" rel="nofollow">The Master, Multiplied</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-master-multiplied_0.jpg?itok=V4YQxGEx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-master-multiplied_0.jpg?itok=nIKSAuK1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>If you’re wanting to explore Mass of Mysteries more, The Master Multiplied is I think a must-add to the deck, from the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/best-lore-deep-cuts-of-doctor-who-commander-universes-beyond" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9113edf5-8cfc-4569-b9c0-bd636f0ddcdd" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Doctor Who </em>commander decks</a>. This will turn all the myriad tokens you make into permanent keepers and will quickly transform your board into an out-of control zone if someone doesn’t take out either your commander or The Master, Multiplied. It’s less useful alongside Ashling, because Ashling wants you to sacrifice them, but even there it might have a spot.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/tsb/7/enduring-renewal" rel="nofollow">Enduring Renewal </a>and/or <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/usg/299/lifeline" rel="nofollow">Lifeline</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/enduring-renewal-and-lifeline.jpg?itok=m0BJufEK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="754" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/enduring-renewal-and-lifeline.jpg?itok=oATCLmIr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="754" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>Alternatively for Ashling, the Limitless, I’d look at resurrection type abilities a bit more. Perhaps the strongest option is Enduring Renewal, which with Animar and Ashling is an infinite token evoke engine, and even without that keeps you going on creatures. Lifeline is a slower, more value ridden approach, with it giving you the creatures back at the end of the turn.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/inr/117/heartless-summoning" rel="nofollow">Heartless Summoning</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/heartless-summoning.jpg?itok=H5Jm0bBB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/heartless-summoning.jpg?itok=ibYFRZe_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>Only a few of the creatures in Dance of the Elements die to Heartless Summoning, but getting half off all of your evoke costs from Ashling is a huge benefit. With Heartless Summoning it is much more plausible to evoke and elemental, and pay the WUBRG cost to keep the token around, effectively double spelling.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/drc/7/renewed-solidarity" rel="nofollow">Renewed Solidarity</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/renewed-solidarity.jpg?itok=yQxrT2bA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/renewed-solidarity.jpg?itok=jTciNGhI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>This rare from the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/aetherdrift-top-10-vehicles-and-mounts" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6835fe23-96da-4b98-88c2-ac1b4dde1d34" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Aetherdrift</a> <a href="https://mtg.wiki/page/Aetherdrift/Commander_decks#Eternal_Might" rel="nofollow">Eternal Might pre-constructed</a> deck is a perfect fit with Ashling, the Limitless. The copies Ashling makes when you sacrifice the evoked elementals are essentially doubled at end of turn, and at a price point that is far far below other token doublers, while also costing less mana and giving a boost to your creatures.</p><h2>Blight Curse Upgrades</h2><p>For the first time in years, Magic has brought a focus to -1/-1 counters, capturing the Shadowmoor side of the plane. The last time we saw -1/-1 counters in a primary spotlight was in <em>Amonkhet </em>back in 2017, and <a href="https://mtg.wiki/page/Lorwyn_Eclipsed/Commander_decks#Blight_Curse" rel="nofollow">Blight Curse </a>features the first two Jund -1/-1 counter commander options in <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/2/auntie-ool-cursewretch" rel="nofollow">Auntie Ool, Cursewretch</a>, and <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/4/the-reaper-king-no-more" rel="nofollow">The Reaper, King No More</a>. Auntie is a value commander gaining cards and damage from your counters, while The Reaper is more theft focused.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blight-curse-commanders.jpg?itok=8VXIA_fK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1134" height="780">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blight-curse-commanders.jpg?itok=FzNc-R6N 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1134" height="780">
                  

  </picture><p>A quick aside: this deck has a 2 card low mana infinite combo in <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/123/hapatra-vizier-of-poisons" rel="nofollow">Hapatra, Vizier of Poisons </a>and <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ecc/46/blowfly-infestation" rel="nofollow">Blowfly Infestation</a> creating infinite death and enters triggers. This moves it out of the default bracket 2 state, so is something to talk about in rule 0 discussions, especially if you make any changes to the deck.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/hou/141/obelisk-spider" rel="nofollow">Obelisk Spider</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/obelisk-spider.jpg?itok=qUwFUyy7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/obelisk-spider.jpg?itok=b1grhSLB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>From <em>Hour of Devastation</em> in <em>Amonkhet</em> block, Obelisk Spider is such an obvious addition I almost didn’t include it here. But sometimes, the obvious needs to be said, and this spider’s ability to turn all your counter shenanigans into little damage cuts and life gain can help close out a game, and provide useful advantages.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/dsc/22/persistent-constrictor" rel="nofollow">Persistent Constrictor</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/persistent-constrictor.jpg?itok=9YWHhM39 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/persistent-constrictor.jpg?itok=OMRseIog 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>When they made the <em>Duskmourn c</em>ommander decks I wonder if they were seeding this guy as an upgrade option for the future Blight Curse deck. While a bit costly, the Constrictor will ensure you have fresh new counters on your opponent’s creatures to manipulate, and help bleed out your opponent.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/rex/3/spitting-dilophosaurus" rel="nofollow">Spitting Dilophosaurus</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/spitting-dilophosaurus.jpg?itok=ROoRUoJ_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/spitting-dilophosaurus.jpg?itok=eZGhVTPf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>Traveling outside the Magic multiverse for a moment, from the <a href="https://scryfall.com/sets/rex" rel="nofollow">Jurassic Park cards</a> in <em>Ixalan</em>, we come across a perfect fit for this deck, as Spitting Dilophosaurus not only produces counters on entrance and attack, but ensures your opponents can’t blow when you’ve weakened their creatures.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/som/145/contagion-engine" rel="nofollow">Contagion Engine</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/contagion-engine.jpg?itok=BSI56wr9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/contagion-engine.jpg?itok=hLX7xVDh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>With Auntie Ooi, Cursewrench, Contagion Engine goes beyond a targeted board wipe, to also potentially being a killshot against token players. This shrinkage, along with the ability to multiple proliferate make the Contagion Engine a powerful tool for Blight Curse players to adopt.</p><h3><a href="https://scryfall.com/card/som/145/contagion-engine" rel="nofollow">Generous Patron</a></h3><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/generous-patron.jpg?itok=yf_KR5oX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/generous-patron.jpg?itok=qhHl9iaj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="373" height="520">
                  

  </picture><p>This esteemed patron is a star of my <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/ncc/7/kros-defense-contractor" rel="nofollow">Kros, Defense Contractor </a>deck where they ensure we get paid in cards for handing out new weapons (+1/+1 counters) to various parties. They have assured me that it will work much the same for the withering blighting counters that Blight Curse hands out, giving a consistent set of cards as you weaken your foes monsters.</p><hr><p>Overall, the Lorwyn Eclipsed Commander decks pay homage to the original block in flavorful and fun ways. They address player requests (like a June -1/-1 counter commander), and complement a banger of a set with even more fun.</p><p>Of the two, Blight Curse is the more powerful, and intriguing in many ways, as well as having higher valued reprints. That’s not to say that Dance of the Elements is without its upsides, but if I were picking one to grab it’d be Blight Curse, and working on adding a few more cards to it.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/cards-to-upgrade-lorwyn-ecllipsed-commander-decks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream Is Getting a Nintendo Direct This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tomodachi-life-living-dream-nintendo-direct-announced</link>
            <guid>1416190</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Weirdo life sim <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em> is getting its own Nintendo Direct show this week, and if we don't get a release date for the game, I'll be very surprised indeed.</p><p>As announced on <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/2015787236264915199" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">social media platform X</a>, <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em>'s Nintendo Direct presentation will be airing on January 29th (that's this Thursday at time of writing) at 6am Pacific/9am Eastern/2pm GMT.</p><p>Nintendo hasn't specified exactly what you can expect from the Direct showcase, of course, but the aforementioned release date will almost certainly be included, along with some more gameplay footage and a better idea of what you can expect when <em>Living the Dream </em>rolls around.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream </em>is getting its own Nintendo Direct this week.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Given that the Switch 2 has been released since <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-march-2025-all-news-and-announcements" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9e9f0043-e970-4bd3-85c9-1c2e96dcc7e7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">original announcement back in March</a>, I'd also be very surprised if we don't see a Switch 2 Edition for the game, but hey: if there's one thing Nintendo likes to do, it's surprise people.</p><p>According to Nintendo, you can expect roughly 20 minutes of new information about <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em>, so that should be more than enough to give you an idea of whether you want to grab this one or not.</p><p>If you're unfamiliar with <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</em>, it's a sort of ambient life sim in which you can populate an island with Miis and watch them interact with one another in fun and strange ways.</p><p>The debut trailer for the game very much played up <em>Tomodachi Life</em>'s inherent weirdness, concluding as it did with a Mii being confronted by a giant version of one of their friends, <em>Metal Gear Solid 2 </em>Gurlugon-style.</p>
<p>Whether or not <em>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream </em>gets a Switch 2 release, you'll be able to check it out when it launches sometime this year for the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/Tomodachi-Life-Living-the-Dream-2786386.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Switch</a>. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tomodachi-life-living-dream-nintendo-direct-announced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Play viral Tetris with Winnie the Pooh's horrible guts in this not very Disneyfied turn-based roguelite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/play-viral-tetris-with-winnie-the-poohs-horrible-guts-in-this-not-very-disneyfied-turn-based-roguelite</link>
            <guid>1416187</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/winnieshole.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Twice Different</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://ipo.blog.gov.uk/2025/03/06/a-bear-of-very-little-copyright-winnie-the-poohs-journey-into-the-public-domain/">Back in 2022</a>, Winnie The Pooh entered the public domain in the USA, meaning that any denizen of that nation can publish work featuring the OG incarnation of A.A. Milne’s honey-supping woodland bear (the UK copyright expires in 2027). At some point in the future, once the newly founded Poohlike genre has matured, we can surely expect a renaissance of Winnie derivatives, ranging from erasure Pooh-ems through josei anime interpretations to Kaufman-ass Hundred Acre existentialism. Right now, though, it’s mostly about horror, because <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cronenbergian-bear-mutator-winnies-hole-gets-a-steam-demo">the logical thing to do</a> when the lawyers finally abandon a beloved children’s character is break out the chainsaws.</p>
<p>The movie folk have already given us Winnie the Pooh: Blood and Honey and its sequel, both apparently dreadful in a bad way. Now here comes Steven H. Videogames with Winnie's Hole, out in early access today. In this roguelite from Twice Different, the nectar-chugging teddy has become a rambling cosmic abomination, and your job is to mutate his insides using tetrominoes. Oh botherlyeh wgah'nagl fhtagn.</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Winnie's Hole - Official Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ejb-fdD0xfM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Winnie's Hole - Official Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ejb-fdD0xfM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ejb-fdD0xfM?autoplay=1" title="Winnie's Hole - Official Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ejb-fdD0xfM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>“Capture cells to mutate and build a deck of actions to unleash in combo-driven combat,” explains <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2319730/Winnies_Hole/">the Steam page</a>. “A genre-blending roguelite with a dark yet charming story.”</p>
<p>It’s a game of two halves, together forming a scissoring rictus of strategy-puzzling. On the one paw, you’ll place blocks within Winnie to create a pathway for the spreading infection, absorbing resources and unlocking mutations. On the other tentacle, you’ll wage turn-based battles against other animals who may take exception to the Cronenbergification of the Hundred Acre Wood. The battles also involve tetrominoes, each block inciting Winnie to perform an ability, providing it fits the contours of his brain.</p><p>The other animals don’t look very nice – partly, I imagine, because developers Twice Different are concerned to draw a firm line between the game and the still-copyrighted Disney animations. Look at them waving their torches and pitchforks in poor Winnie’s face. Based on the trailer, I have few qualms about melting Rabbit's eyes with gastric fluids. Screw that guy. Remember when he tried to “unbounce” Tigger? Who’s the real monster here?</p>
<p>If you are the kind of Tigger who doesn’t like cosmic monsters, maybe look forward to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3748320/WinnieThePooh_Beyond_The_Hundred_Acre/">Winnie-The-Pooh: Beyond The Hundred Acre</a>, notable for its concussed Ico mimicry and zealous adherence to Milne's original title punctuation. If you like cosmic monsters but find Winnie's Hole unsubtle (well, la di da!) try out Disney adaptation Piglet's Big Game, which was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lo-8sImJr44">sneakily inspired by Resident Evil</a>.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/play-viral-tetris-with-winnie-the-poohs-horrible-guts-in-this-not-very-disneyfied-turn-based-roguelite]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K-Inspired FTL Mash-Up Removed From Steam After Seemingly Bogus DMCA Takedown]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/warhammer-40k-inspired-ftl-mash-up-removed-from-steam-after-seemingly-bogus-dmca-takedown-2000663076</link>
            <guid>1416178</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Captain Mal is very concerned about potential copyright violations.</span> © Tundra / Fox / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p><em>FTL-</em>but-make-it-<em>40K</em> strategy roguelite <em>Void War</em> has been delisted from Steam for a very strange reason. The removal of the game from Valve’s store (thanks <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ftl-in-a-warhammer-40000-skin-game-pulled-from-steam-after-what-may-be-a-nuisance-dmca-takedown-from-a-troll-claiming-to-be-games-workshop"><em>IGN</em></a>) occurred after a DMCA takedown was purportedly sent by <em>Warhammer&nbsp;</em>owners Games Workshop. Except it appears to have been written by <em>Firefly</em>‘s cowboy captain Mal Reynolds, who doesn’t work for Games Workshop on account of being a fictional character.</p> <p>It’s fair to say that&nbsp;<em>Void War</em> is not the most innovative of games. Very much inspired by 2012’s&nbsp;<em>FTL</em>, but delivered through the aesthetic (and a fair amount of the IP) of <em>Warhammer 40,000</em>, it’s the sort of indie project for which the word “derivative” was invented. Also, that sounds like a completely brilliant idea and I want to play it. Except right now I can’t do that via Steam, where the game’s store page has been removed. (It’s <a href="https://tundra-interactive.itch.io/void-war">still available via Itch</a>, and ridiculously enough that comes with a Steam key that players are reporting still adds the game to your account.) <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2853590/discussions/0/685243980153162137/">According to the indie game’s developers</a>, Tundra, this has happened because of a DMCA notice sent to Valve from Games Workshop over copyright infringement claims. Except, Tundra received no such communications from GW, and as parenthetically mentioned, the game remains available on Itch. So what’s going on?</p>

 <p>Tundra says that Valve’s evidence for the complaint from GW is “Games Workshop’s public-facing infringements inbox and the name ‘Mal Reynolds’.” The studio’s statement continues,</p> <blockquote><p>“We have not gotten any response from GW when we emailed that inbox. So right now we can’t independently verify who submitted it beyond what’s in the notice.</p> <p>We’re proceeding through the standard DMCA process to get the page back up, and we’ll post updates as soon as we have confirmed info.”</p></blockquote> <h2>Imperium Takedown</h2>   <p>Now, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xi5bOpBcD7g">Games Workshop is not shy</a> about <a href="https://copyrightaid.co.uk/forum/viewtopic.php?t=3932">issuing DMCA notifications</a>, with some alleging this is performed by <a href="https://www.brandshield.com/">a third-party company’s AI</a> scouring the net for anything that might violate the company’s copyrights. Given the small scale of&nbsp;<em>Void War</em>, there’s a good chance it only survived this long because GW didn’t know about it, and it’s not impossible to imagine that this bogus takedown could result in the <em>Warhammer</em> corp turning its sights on the game. Heck, the owner of the Imperium also asks its own customers to snitch on copyright violations:</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000663083" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663083"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663083">© Games Workshop / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>We’ve contacted Games Workshop to ask if the company has been involved at all, and indeed whether it currently employs space pirate Mal Reynolds to issue such takedowns. (Which would be a devastating fall for the once-proud rebel.)</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/warhammer-40k-inspired-ftl-mash-up-removed-from-steam-after-seemingly-bogus-dmca-takedown-2000663076]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UGREEN’s Apple Find My Certified Tracker (4-Pack) Gets Cleared Out at an All-Time Low, Several Times Cheaper Than AirTags]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ugreens-apple-find-my-certified-tracker-4-pack-gets-cleared-out-at-an-all-time-low-several-times-cheaper-than-airtags-2000662875</link>
            <guid>1416175</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The last thing you want when you’re already running late is forgetting where you left your keys or wallet – again. Losing track of important stuff isn’t uncommon, but it is avoidable. An air tracker can be a true lifesaver in these situations, and you can now pick a pack of four without shelling out big bucks.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6880/">Amazon has dropped the price of the 4-pack bundle of Ugreen FineTrack air tracker tags by 34%, offering it now for $23.</a> That works out to just over $5 per tracker. For comparison, Apple AirTags cost around $30 each, so you’re getting four with similar functionality for less than the price of one with this deal. It’s also a great time to snap more than one bundle to cover all your essentials without overpaying!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Multiple Ways to Track</h2>
<p>These mini trackers fit in the palm of your hand, and come with a built-in loop that makes it easy to attach them to keys, bags, and even your water bottle without needing extra accessories. Getting started is straightforward and doesn’t take much time. Simply pull out the insulation paper from the tracker, and press it for two seconds to turn it on. Enable “Find My” and Bluetooth on your iPhone. Then, head over to the “Items” page on the Find My app and click “Other supported items”. Locate the smart tracker and click Connect. You can now give your tracker a name, and it will be ready to use.</p>
<p>The tracker comes with a speaker built right into it. You can ring it using the Find My app to spot your essentials around the house. The alarm is quite loud, so you’ll hear it even when the tracker is buried under the cushions or is placed in another room. You even get a notification on your phone when you leave it behind and move out of the coverage range. This makes it easy to avoid forgetting essentials like your wallet in a cafe or your keys in a public restroom.</p>



<p>When something is out of the Bluetooth range of your phone, the Apple Find My network uses its vast ecosystem of Apple devices to provide the item’s latest location. If it still cannot be found, you can switch on Lost Mode and add your contact information. When the track is near an iPhone or Apple device in the Find My network, its location will automatically update in your app, and you will be notified immediately. Additionally, iOS 17 and later let you share your tracker’s location with family members, so everyone can keep an eye on the whereabouts of your luggage and more.</p>
<p>There’s an anti-tracking feature, too. With this, if someone else’s tracker finds its way into your stuff and the network notices that it’s traveling with you, it will send an alert on your phone. If you still can’t find it, the tracker will play a sound to let you know where it’s hiding.</p>
<p><strong>Ugreen’s Bluetooth trackers feature a replaceable battery that lasts up to 2 years</strong>. That means you can go up to 24 months without worrying about running out of it! When it’s time to replace, all you need to do is insert the included stuck needle into the dedicated hole from the top of the tag. Swap in a new battery with the positive side facing up, then align the cover into position and press until it’s closed. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6880/">You can now enjoy all these features (and ease of mind) for just $23. Be sure to grab the offer while the discount is still live!</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ugreens-apple-find-my-certified-tracker-4-pack-gets-cleared-out-at-an-all-time-low-several-times-cheaper-than-airtags-2000662875]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Hours With Resident Evil Requiem: The Best Of The Series’ Horror And Action Wrapped In One]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-9-requiem-preview-leon-gameplay-grace-2000662270</link>
            <guid>1416172</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Spending three hours with </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-9-capcom-grace-leon-2000632633"><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i></a><span>, I wasn’t surprised to find that Capcom’s big 30th anniversary tentpole game feels like a Greatest Hits album for the long-running horror series. Between its two main characters’ shifting perspectives and the genre shakeups that come with them, </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>has a little bit of something for everyone.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>No matter what era of </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>you have the most attachment to, odds are you’ll get at least a fleeting glimpse of what first drew you to Spencer Mansion, Raccoon City, or anywhere else Capcom has sent Chris, Jill, Leon, and all these other poor saps who keep facing these zombie outbreaks with nothing but a handgun and a dream.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>You’d think that in an effort to please the folks who were drawn to the original game’s claustrophobic, isolating atmosphere, and the action aficionados who want to watch Leon do sick roundhouse kicks, </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>would feel like a discombobulated mismatch of disparate eras, but Capcom has put such a hard divide between </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/capcom-leon-kennedy-is-playable-in-resident-evil-requiem-re9-game-awards-2000652755"><span>Leon’s over-the-top, campy action </span></a><span>and newcomer Grace’s methodical horror that swapping between them feels less like an interruption and more like enjoying the contrasting peanut butter and jelly in a Jill Sandwich.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000662277" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000662277"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000662277">© Capcom</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I had already </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849"><span>played a bit of Grace’s side</span></a><span> of the game, so I was particularly eager to get back in Leon’s combat boots. Leon’s third-person shooter segments are a stark contrast to Grace’s stealthy survival ones. Though Leon’s aim retains a bit of its shakiness from </span><i><span>Resident Evil 6</span></i><span>’, to the point where I found it useful to force myself to stop and shoot, </span><i><span>Resident Evil 4 </span></i><span>style, to line up my shots better, the man is an absolute tank, even in his old age. His action movie camp comes through not only in his cheesy one-liners but in just how silly and over the top his combat segments can get.</span></p>

 <p><span>The first Leon segment I played had the ex-Raccoon City cop arriving at the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center just as an outbreak of some unknown virus began spreading through the hospital. The hotel’s staff was rapidly turned into zombies, including one that swings a chainsaw around with reckless abandon. It was a close call, and I had to parry away the chainsaw with the hatchet I had on me a few times, but I managed to take him out with my handgun and the chainsaw fell to the floor…only for another zombie to pick it right back up and chase me around the arena’s corridors. This happened a few times before it finally hit me that </span><i><span>I</span></i><span> could pick up the chainsaw myself, and once I did that I made quick work of the remains of the horde.&nbsp;</span></p>

  <p><span>Even when Leon is running low on ammo (an irregular occurrence in my time playing), dude just powers through zombies, almost like he’s done this before. The hatchet, which you can sharpen mid scrap, means you’re never without some tool at your disposal to take on even the biggest, most grotesque monstrosities in the hospital. Then, if you stun them with a well-placed gunshot or two, you can kick groups of zombies away to make space while you reload, run to a more fortified area, or pull out the whetstone. Or, if you’re lucky, you get an opening for one of Leon’s cunty-ass takedowns where he does some violent stunt that usually ends with a zombie losing its head and him doing a hair flip. Whether his back is against a wall or he’s tied up in a chair being interrogated, Leon always feels like he’s in control, and, in comparison, Grace’s sections are filled with long stretches of time in which you’re barely scraping by.</span></p> <p><span>I played one of Grace’s early segments last year and came away feeling like her sections were evocative of hide-and-seek games like Capcom’s 2005 hidden gem </span><i><span>Haunting Ground</span></i><span>. Now, having played about two hours as her, I can say that comparison was pretty apt. When I switched from Leon to Grace, the ex-cop gave a handgun to Grace in case she needed it, but while a gun in Leon’s hands is a weapon of mass destruction, in Grace’s, it’s…maybe more of a flyswatter?&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>clearly wants you to view Leon and Grace as characters with different skillsets, but even so, it’s surprising just how differently the two play, even when using a similar tool. Grace’s segments are characterized by sneaking, puzzle-solving, and a dearth of bullets for the handgun. Using a full clip to try and kill a zombie is wasteful, and you’re better off firing a few warning shots into their head until they’re stunned enough for you to shove them to the ground and run past them. Grace does get some upgrades to her firepower and strength, but I’m doubtful she’ll reach the “walking tank” status of Leon by the end. </span></p> <p><span>The Grace section I played involved a lot of backtracking through the same area of the hospital for two hours, and I think I maybe actually killed only a handful of enemies in that time. Not from lack of trying, mind you. Bullets just don’t seem to hit as hard when they’re coming from Grace’s untrained hand. Navigating these spaces as </span><i><span>Requiem</span></i><span>’s new heroine was more about remembering what threats were around each corner, and hoping I would be able to take advantage of the zombies’ one-track minds to get through unscathed.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000662281" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000662281"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000662281">© Capcom</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Capcom says the dichotomy between Grace and Leon’s playstyles is meant to give the game a cadence of hours of tense atmosphere punctuated by flashes of violent catharsis, and that was most evident when I swapped back to Leon and walked through the same area I’d spent a long time sneaking around as Grace with a newfound confidence radiating from the shotgun in my hands. When playing as Grace, I kept finding cabinets that were “warped” beyond opening, and wondered why Capcom let me interact with them if they were all just going to be distractions, only to find that, when I returned here as Leon, they opened when I used my hatchet on them. These were never meant for her, and were instead a reminder that I would walk through these halls in a different context much later.</span></p>

 <p><span>Will these contrasting playstyles work over the course of a dozen hours, or will it make </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>one of the more uneven entries in a series already full of those? We’ll know when the game launches on February 27, but for now, I can get on board with a game that recognizes </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>has been a lot of things over the past 30 years and wants to pay tribute to eras old and new. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-9-requiem-preview-leon-gameplay-grace-2000662270]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>