<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 15:07:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows' Canon Mode Will Pick Canon Dialogue Choices For You]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-will-pick-canon-dialogue-choices-for-you.1059033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft has revealed that it's including something it calls "Canon Mode" in upcoming action RPG&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>, and if you've ever wondered which dialogue option your character would actually pick, this one's for you.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/hi_we_are_brooke_charles_jonathan_and_thierry/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">recent Reddit AMA (Ask Me Anything) session</a>, creative director Jonathan Dumont says Canon Mode was included to address the fact that&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed</em>'s fanbase is "divided on branching dialogues".</p>

<p>If you select Canon Mode, then dialogue choices will be made for you so that you don't have to worry about whether what you're doing is in character or not. Dumont says this should give players a "choice free experience", which feels like a slightly odd way of wording it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-conversation.jpg?itok=5Yj3fe7q 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-conversation.jpg?itok=ceIC5JxH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>will let you have the game decide which response it should give on your behalf in dialogue trees.</figcaption></figure><p>When it comes to the length of the game, Dumont says that while it's "hard to evaluate" such things in open-world games due to player variables, he thinks&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>' main campaign is "comparable to&nbsp;<em>Origins</em>/<em>Odyssey&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Valhalla</em>" in terms of length.</p>

<p>Again, that feels like a slightly odd answer to give when considering that these three games take different amounts of time to beat.&nbsp;<em>Origins</em>' campaign sits at around 25-30 hours, while&nbsp;<em>Odyssey</em>'s takes about 45 hours and&nbsp;<em>Valhalla</em>'s can take up to 60.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Suffice it to say that you're probably not in for a short ride with&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>, so hopefully it doesn't have the same level of bloat that&nbsp;<em>Odyssey&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Valhalla&nbsp;</em>could often exhibit.</p>

<p>The AMA offers plenty of other interesting information about&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>; it'll <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/comment/m1jz42g/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">feature an "immersive mode"</a> with a full Japanese voiceover, for instance, and its <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/comment/m1jv74t/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">modern story</a> will be "limited" and connected to the new Animus Hub, although we'll get more on this "later".</p>




<p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is the latest mainline installment in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>series. Set in Sengoku-era Japan, it'll follow the RPG stylings of the likes of <i><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/assassins-creed-odyssey" rel="nofollow">Odyssey</a>&nbsp;</i>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla" rel="nofollow">Valhalla</a>&nbsp;</em>and not the back-to-basics approach of last year's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/assassins-creed-mirage" rel="nofollow"><em>Mirage</em></a>.</p>

<p>Since its announcement, the game has garnered its fair share of controversy. Some players <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-assassins-creed-shadows-controversy" rel="nofollow">objected to the inclusion of historical figure Yasuke</a> as one of the main playable characters, an inclusion Ubisoft says demonstrates its ability to take "creative license" to construct "engaging and immersive experiences".</p>

<p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>also prompted outcry when a concept art book was found to have <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-concept-art-apology" rel="nofollow">appropriated images from a Japanese group</a> without permission, and when an "insensitive" figurine depicting a one-legged Torii gate was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/insensitive-assassins-creed-shadows-figurine-controversy" rel="nofollow">pulled from sale in October</a>.</p>

<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>when it launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3159330/Assassins_Creed_Shadows/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/assassins-creed-shadows/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/assassins-creed-shadows" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> in February next year, having been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february" rel="nofollow">delayed</a> from its original November release date.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Will Have A 'Canon Mode' For Animus Purists]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-canon-mode-1851719396</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-will-have-a-canon-mode-for-animus-purists.1059024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-canon-mode-1851719396<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft is an strange ol’ publisher, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0j8p8l26pgo&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0j8p8l26pgo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">closing down teams</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-7-canceled-games-splinter-cell-assasin-s-creed-1849976552?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-7-canceled-games-splinter-cell-assasin-s-creed-1849976552?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..">killing off so many projects</a></span>—but the games that <em>do</em> reach us tend to be the most extraordinarily accessible, replete with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-settings-options-accessibility-guide-1851636696?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-settings-options-accessibility-guide-1851636696?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..">groundbreaking</a></span> options to make the games <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/before-you-start-six-settings-to-change-in-far-cry-6-1847821551?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/before-you-start-six-settings-to-change-in-far-cry-6-1847821551?_gl=1*tkkqyi*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk1NTg0NC4xMTUuMS4xNzMzOTU3NzAwLjQ4LjAuMA..">playable</a></span> for the widest numbers of people, in the most specific ways possible. With next year’s <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, there’s to be yet another innovative step: a “canon mode” that will optionally streamline its narrative to one historical path.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196299" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="385" data-playlist="196299,196470,195922" data-current="196299"><div><p>You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21849.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>During <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/hi_we_are_brooke_charles_jonathan_and_thierry/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/hi_we_are_brooke_charles_jonathan_and_thierry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a Reddit AMA last night</a></span>, four developers working on the game answered questions about <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, including news that the game will feature an “immersive mode” that will have all the game’s characters speaking in Japanese, while explaining that the game’s months-long delay has been used for polish, debugging and balancing, specifically fine-tuning the parkour and improving the parry mechanics. But perhaps the most interesting reveal is the “Canon Mode,” designed to appease players who are concerned about the game’s branching storylines, given the series’ focus on synchronizing with the past.</p><p>“Choices come more into play when recruiting allies and romance [sic] some of the characters,” said Jonathan Dumont, the director on <em>Shadows</em>. “Since the fan base is divided on branching dialogues, we have incorporated an option called CANON MODE which allows you to play the game with choices already made for you, to give you a choice free experience.” Elsewhere in the thread Dumont adds, “You will still be able to switch characters in [the] open in this mode.”</p><p>This news was met with delight by those taking part in the AMA. “Wait, WHAT??? Are you serious? That’s basically what the fanbase has been asking for since 2018,” said one person. “Oh my god, amazing,” replied another. A third suggested, “Wild pitch: retroactively add this mode to <em>Odyssey</em> and <em>Valhalla</em>.”</p><figure id="" data-id="0f054038f8cb7a853b5feaa9adccb21d" data-recommend-id="image://0f054038f8cb7a853b5feaa9adccb21d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1435" data-height="807" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The choice screen for playing as Yasuke or Naoe." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The choice screen for playing as Yasuke or Naoe." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Ubisoft</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0f054038f8cb7a853b5feaa9adccb21d" data-recommend-id="image://0f054038f8cb7a853b5feaa9adccb21d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1435" data-height="807" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The choice screen for playing as Yasuke or Naoe." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>While there are some very loud voices that strongly believe all games should only be playable in their hardest modes, back in real life everyone approaches games very differently. Some seek super-hard, reflex-heavy combat, and want to be told the story by a fixed narrator, while others love to become embroiled in a twisting narrative on which they have huge influence but want to walk away at the sight of a boss fight. And indeed, everything in-between, outside of that, and the whole lot combined.</p><p>Ubisoft has been making some big strides in the games it <em>does</em> release regarding letting players structure a game according to their own tastes, and while it’s fair to say the publisher has led the way in this regard, many others are now following. Where once we were lucky to choose between Easy, Normal and Hard, it’s becoming more commonplace to let a player tweak specific aspects of their $70 purchase, creating the tone of game that best suits their desires. (We’re edging closer and closer to my <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-origins-tourism-difficulty&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-origins-tourism-difficulty" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">skippable boss fight future</a></span>.)</p><p>It seems yet another step in this direction to offer an option to those who simply don’t want to make narrative choices for whatever reason. There are many <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> die-hards who want a single, pure storyline, to make sense of the game’s reliving history through memory, and find the player-driven deviations, well, deviant. For others it could be choice paralysis—that awful fear that you might be picking the “wrong” option, and then worrying about that instead of enjoying the game. The Canon Mode will automatically select what the developers consider the true, historical path through the game, which the same AMA confirms will have a single canon ending.</p><p>And, of course, for those who find the idea plain strange, it is just an option, with a branching storyline for the two different characters set as the game’s default.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket Mythical Island Set—Release Date, How Many Cards & What’s Included]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-set-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-set%E2%80%94release-date-how-many-cards-what%E2%80%99s-included.1059021/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-set-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Mythical Island is the first proper Pokémon TCG Pocket mini-set since the title’s launch. It brings with it the second-ever booster pack for players to pull new cards, and we know its release date, as well as a bunch of cards revealed for the set.</p>



<p>The Pokémon TCG Pocket <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-next-expansion-rumors-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next expansion leaks</a> continue to be true. We heard weeks ago a mini-set was scheduled for the third week in December, and now we know what it is. Pokémon TCG Pocket Mythical Island is a fully-fledged mini-set not quite on the scale of Genetic Apex, but it’s easily the most significant collection of cards—outside of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-promo-a-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-to-unlock/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Promo A</a> series.</p>



<p>The Mythical Island debut trailer gave us a huge glimpse into the set and what to expect.</p>



<h2 id="h-mythical-island-set-release-date-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">Mythical Island Set Release Date in Pokémon TCG Pocket</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Just look at it. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Pokémon TCG Pocket’s Mythical Island set launches on Dec. 17.</strong></p>



<p>No official release time was given in the debut <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eUYHC2ReohA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Pokémon TCG Pocket: Mythical Island trailer</a>. So, expect a midnight rollout for the set in your region. Once it’s live, select the new booster pack, start ripping them open, and get building the newest set in Pocket.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-open-mythical-island-packs-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island">How to Open Mythical Island Packs in Pokémon TCG Pocket: Mythical Island</h2>



<p>We don’t know for sure, but I imagine once Mythical Island is live, the <strong>advertised packs on the home page are going to change to reflect the new set</strong>. Meaning, you can press on any of the advertised Mythical Island packs, and it takes you straight to them.</p>



<p>On the other hand, if it still shows Genetic Apex packs on the home screen once the new set launches, try this:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to the home screen.</li>



<li>Press on any of the Genetic Apex packs to take you to the pack screen.</li>



<li>Choose “Select other booster packs” in the bottom-right corner to presumably choose Mythical Island.</li>



<li>Now, open Mythical Island packs!</li>
</ol>



<p>It’s hard to know fully what Pokémon TCG Pocket looks like when Mythical Island launches, so we’ll update this once we have a clearer indication.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-cards-in-mythical-island-set-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">How Many Cards in Mythical Island Set in Pokémon TCG Pocket?</h2>



<p>NetEase hasn’t divulged how many cards are coming in Mythical Island, but thanks to the debut trailer, we’ve identified at least <strong>15 new cards coming in the set</strong>.</p>



<p>Here’s every card we think we’ve spotted in Mythical Island so far:</p>



<ul>
<li>Aerodactyl ex</li>



<li>Blue (Supporter Card)</li>



<li>Dedenne (Full Art)</li>



<li>Dhelmise</li>



<li>Exeggcute</li>



<li>Larvesta</li>



<li>Leaf (Supporter Card)</li>



<li>Magmar</li>



<li>Marshadow (Full Art)</li>



<li>Mew ex</li>



<li>Morelull</li>



<li>Pikachu</li>



<li>Snivy</li>



<li>Tauros</li>



<li>Vaporean (Full Art)</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-rarest-cards-in-mythical-island-set-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">Rarest Cards in Mythical Island Set in Pokémon TCG Pocket</h2>



<p>So far, <strong>Dedenne, Marshadow, and Vaporean Full Art</strong> cards, along with <strong>Mew ex</strong> and <strong>Aerodactyl ex</strong>, are the rarest cards we’ve seen in the Mythical Island set.</p>



<p>More could still be announced, and the full set is likely keeping some secrets under its belt. We can all find out together once Mythical Island is live!</p>



<hr>



<p>I’m excited about Mythical Island, but are you? Drop a comment to let us know your thoughts on the upcoming booster pack addition. For more on Pokémon TCG Pocket, take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rarest-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rarest cards</a> in the game, as well as what we know about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-trading-coming-to-pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-release-date-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trading</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farewell North now available for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/farewell-north-now-available-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/farewell-north-now-available-for-ps5.1059018/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/farewell-north-now-available-for-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Previously released for Xbox Series, Switch, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Mooneye Studios [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mooneye-studios">Mooneye Studios</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Kyle Banks [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kyle-banks">Kyle Banks</a> have released narrative <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Farewell North [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/farewell-north">Farewell North</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,522 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10012510" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Store</a> for $23.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-932807"></span></p><p><em>Farewell North</em> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/03/narrative-adventure-game-farewell-north-launches-august-15-for-xbox-series-switch-and-pc">first launched</a> for Xbox Series, Switch, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,949 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1432850/Farewell_North/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on August 15.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1432850/Farewell_North/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Restore color to the desolate islands of <em>Farewell North</em>, an atmospheric journey where you play as a border collie traveling with his owner. Explore land and sea, uncover hidden paths and free wildlife to bring color back to the world, all while revealing an emotional story about saying farewell.</p><p><strong>Restore Color to the World</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Explore the islands and uncover memories in order to restore color to the archipelago, unlocking new paths, extinguishing hazards and revealing hidden objects. Explore the hand crafted, atmospheric islands while evading the creatures that would hold you back.</p><p><strong>Free Wildlife</strong></p><p>Discover and activate frozen wildlife to temporarily bring color back to the world, revealing hidden objects and paths, and distracting the monsters who would harm you.</p><p><strong>Discover Hidden Paths</strong></p><p>Solve puzzles based on perspective and coloring to reveal hidden objects and paths in the environment. Find the perfect vantage point to reveal the secrets of the islands.</p><p><strong>Explore Land and Sea</strong></p><p>Journey at your own pace, running through lush grassy fields, hiking steep cliffs, and canoeing the ocean between an open world chain of islands inspired by the Scottish archipelagos of St. Kilda and Orkney. Discover new islands and challenges throughout the world as you work to restore color.</p><p><strong>Uncover a Unique Story About Saying Farewell</strong></p><p>Unravel a unique story about saying farewell as memories reveal a glimpse into the life of the characters. Discover the events in the past which have led the characters to the archipelago, and caused all color to leave the world.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Restore color to a vibrant, hand crafted world, inspired by the Scottish highlands and the famous isles of St. Kilda and Orkney.</li><li>Play as an energetic border collie helping a young woman recover the memories of her life, and uncover the mystery of a colorless world.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> two distinct visual modes, with unique challenges and mechanics in each.</li><li>Unravel an original story of overcoming depression, and saying farewell.</li><li>Discover monsters, creatures and wildlife inspired by the rich history of Scottish folklore.</li><li>Travel by foot and by canoe as you make your way through the atmospheric isles.</li><li>For fans of games like <em>Journey</em>, <em><a title="Games > GRIS [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gris">GRIS</a></em>, and <em>Lost Ember</em>.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO update now available, adds split-screen battle support for all stages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-update-now-available-adds-split-screen-battle-support-for-all-stages</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-update-now-available-adds-split-screen-battle-support-for-all-stages.1059015/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-update-now-available-adds-split-screen-battle-support-for-all-stages<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No longer limited to the "Hyperbolic Time Chamber" stage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,611 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Spike Chunsoft [869 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/spike-chunsoft">Spike Chunsoft</a> have released a free update for <em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-sparking-zero">Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</a></em>, which adds split-screen battle support for all stages, among various functionality, battle system, skill, and character adjustments. Previously, split-screen battles were limited to the “Hyperbolic Time Chamber” stage. <span id="more-933690"></span></p><p>Here are the <a href="https://www.bandainamcoent.asia/sea/news/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-free-update-1112" rel="noopener" target="_blank">full patch notes</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Game Mode Adjustments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Battle</strong><ul><li>All stages can now be selected in offline P1 vs. P2 battles.</li></ul></li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Functionality Adjustments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Battle Setup</strong><ul><li>A function allowing you to change a character’s display method has been added.</li><li>The “My Sets” function has been added for Team Members.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Ranked Match / Player Match</strong><ul><li>You can now skip the intro battle animations (requires both players to input the skip command).</li></ul></li><li><strong>Player Match</strong><ul><li>You can now set your team to “hidden” or “revealed” to your opponent when editing your team.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Custom Battle Mode</strong><ul><li>Texts can now be sorted alphabetically.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Options</strong><ul><li>You can now set the battle camera distance to be closer.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Battle System Adjustments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>High-Speed Dragon Dash (New <a title="Genres > Action [2,363 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>)</strong><ul><li>The new quick movement action, “High-Speed Dragon Dash”, where you can move quickly towards your opponent, has been added. Perform with R2 and holding X (PS5) or RT and holding A (XSX|S).</li></ul></li><li><strong>Smash Attack</strong><ul><li>You will no longer be stunned when hit by a Rush Ki Blast when charging a Smash Attack.</li><li>When charging a Smash Attack during a Rush Attack, charge time reduction based on hit count has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Rush Ki Blast</strong><ul><li>The time between being able to fire the next Rush Ki Blast after firing the maximum consecutive amount at once (different for each character) has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Rush Ki Blast Deflection</strong><ul><li>You can now move while deflecting Rush Ki Blasts.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Steps</strong><ul><li>You will now no longer be able to be hit by certain attacks immediately after performing a Step.</li><li>Rush Ki Blast and Smash Ki Blast can now also be evaded.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Z-Burst Dash</strong><ul><li>The amount of Ki consumed when activating it has increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Burst Smash</strong><ul><li>Ki will no longer be consumed when activating it, and will instead consume an amount based on the distance traveled.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Blast</strong><ul><li>Damage has been increased when using a boost.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Z-Search</strong><ul><li>Z-Search will no longer lose track of your opponent when characters are swapped.</li><li>You will now quickly regain sight of your opponent if they enter your line of sight from the front when Z-Search is not locked onto them.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Z-Counter</strong><ul><li>The input window has been shortened.</li><li>Z-Counter will become more difficult to perform if performed consecutively.</li><li>Ki consumed has been increased when successfully performing a Z-Counter.</li><li>Skill Count increase speed has been reduced when successfully performing a Z-Counter.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Revenge Counter</strong><ul><li>Skill Count consumed when using Perception against Revenge Counter has been reduced from 2 to 1.</li><li>Rush Attacks during Sparking! Mode</li><li>Gradual damage reduction of consecutive hits has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Combos</strong><ul><li>The final attack of Aerial Combos and Aerial Slash Combos will no longer be interrupted by guarding.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Character Switch</strong><ul><li>Health recovery rate of Standby characters has been reduced.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Z-Burst Dash (Giant Characters)</strong><ul><li>The tackle done by Giant characters during Z-Burst Dashes is now guardable.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Skill Adjustments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Skills that cause instant Sparking! Mode</strong><ul><li>Skill Count consumed has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Skills that increase stats in general</strong><ul><li>Skill Count consumed has been decreased.</li></ul></li><li><strong><a title="Games > Afterimage [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/afterimage">Afterimage</a> Strike</strong><ul><li>Effect duration has been reduced to 10 seconds, and will be removed if your opponent uses Perception while you are under the effect.</li></ul></li><li><strong>False Courage</strong><ul><li>Skill Count consumed has been increased from 1 to 2.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Technique: All I Need Is Five Seconds!</strong><ul><li>Skill Count consumed has been increased from 3 to 2 and status increase upon activation has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Stardust Barrier</strong><ul><li>You can now activate it while receiving melee attacks from the front.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Blast Adjustments</strong><ul><li>Long-Range Blasts and Ultimate Blasts</li><li>Speed has been reduced.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Super Vegito: Final Kamehameha</strong><ul><li>Ki consumed and damage has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Goku (Mini): Quick Rush</strong><ul><li>Trajectory can now be changed while Rushing.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Mr. Satan: Present Bomb</strong><ul><li>Increased ending lag after activation.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Character Adjustments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Android 19/ Dr. Gero</strong><ul><li>Health/Ki amount absorbed on successful throw has been adjusted.</li><li>Dragon Dash, Quick Ascend, and Quick Descend now consume Ki.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Cell 2nd Form</strong><ul><li>You can now escape the throw.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Cooler</strong><ul><li>Amount of Health restored upon transforming has been increased.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Giant Characters</strong><ul><li>Increased the time it takes to charge a Smash Attack and reduced its power.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Great Ape Vegeta / Dr. Wheelo</strong><ul><li>Maximum health has been reduced.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Other</strong></p><ul><li>We have improved performance and ease of use.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,522 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,949 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1790600/DRAGON_BALL_Sparking_ZERO/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Free Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO - Free Update Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c-Se47KEfsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon TCG Pocket Mythical Island Expansion Adds 80 Cards, Including One That Turns Off Evolutions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion-adds-80-cards-including-one-that-turns-off-evolutions/1100-6528407/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion-adds-80-cards-including-one-that-turns-off-evolutions.1059012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion-adds-80-cards-including-one-that-turns-off-evolutions/1100-6528407/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528407">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With over 60 million downloads reported so far, Pokemon TCG Pocket is proving to be another smash-hit mobile game for Pikachu and his thousands of Pokemon pals. Those 60 million people have only had one set to work with--until next week, when the first expansion Mythical adds 80 new cards on December 17.</p><p dir="ltr">Mew is the featured Pokemon on the packs of this new expansion, which will also offer new binder and display-cover options. Other cards teased in the expansion's reveal trailer are foil-bordered versions of Tauros, Supporter cards for Blue and Lass, and alternate art versions of Marshadow, Vaporeon, and Dedenne.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eUYHC2ReohA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eUYHC2ReohA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Two EX cards have also been revealed for the Mythical Island expansion: Mew EX and Aerodactyl EX. Their abilities are as follows:</p><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mew EX</strong> (Psychic Type)  <ul><li dir="ltr">130 HP, retreat cost 1 Colorless energy</li><li dir="ltr">Attack 1: Psyshot (Requires one Psychic energy, deals 20 damage)</li><li dir="ltr">Attack 2: Genome Hacking (requires three Colorless energy)  <ul><li dir="ltr">Choose 1 of your opponent's Active Pokemon's attacks and use it as this attack.</li></ul></li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Aerodactyl EX</strong> (Fighting Type, evolves from Old Amber)  <ul><li dir="ltr">140 HP, retreat cost 1 Colorless energy</li><li dir="ltr">Ability: Primeval Law  <ul><li dir="ltr">Your opponent can't play any Pokemon from their hand to evolve their Active Pokemon.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr">Attack: Land Crush (Requires one Colorless and one Fighting energy, deals 80 damage)</li></ul></li></ul><p>Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket-is-out-now/1100-6527486/">launched October 30</a> on iOS and Android devices, where it offers a new way to experience the Pokemon TCG, which originally launched in America in January 1999. Players can open free packs of cards daily, then use those cards to build decks and battle opponents in a streamlined version of the physical card game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528365&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-members-can-get-72-free-games-right-now\/1100-6528365\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528386&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-exclusive-pokemon-tcg-holiday-premium-collection-gets-big-discount\/1100-6528386\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528320&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-dualsense-hall-effect-stick-replacements-now-available\/1100-6528320\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526344&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/yu-gi-oh-early-days-collection-all-14-games-revealed-switch-edition-includes-rare-card\/1100-6526344\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528307&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/back-to-the-future-delorean-lego-set-gets-rare-discount-at-walmart\/1100-6528307\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528322&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/path-of-exile-2-best-monk-build-guide\/1100-6528322\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528331&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/path-of-exile-2-how-to-get-uncut-spirit-gems\/1100-6528331\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528302&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/woot-has-over-40-nintendo-switch-game-deals-including-many-of-the-best-exclusives-and-rare-finds\/1100-6528302\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528354&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/path-of-exile-2-best-sorceress-build-guide\/1100-6528354\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528350&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/8bitdos-new-30-wireless-switch-controller-has-hall-effect-sticks-and-extra-bumpers\/1100-6528350\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528368&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/microsoft-is-selling-an-xbox-360-red-ring-of-death-ugly-sweater-but-you-cant-have-it\/1100-6528368\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523498&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/square-enixs-xenogears-model-kit-is-over-50-off-at-amazon\/1100-6523498\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528314&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-parody-game-shows-up-on-playstation-store\/1100-6528314\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528390&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/xbox-game-pass-adds-a-nice-new-feature-but-only-for-testers-right-now\/1100-6528390\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528345&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-studios-pc-games-are-steeply-discounted-for-amazon-prime-members\/1100-6528345\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528278&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/path-of-exile-2-how-to-get-uncut-skill-gems\/1100-6528278\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Adds The Thing: Remastered, Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver 1&2 Remastered and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-the-thing-remastered-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-12-remastered-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-adds-the-thing-remastered-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remastered-and-more.1058988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-the-thing-remastered-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-12-remastered-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NVIDIA's weekly GeForce NOW Thursday update focuses on two classic PC games that just got remastered: The Thing and Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver 1&amp;2.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2958970/The_Thing_Remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Thing: Remastered</a> enhances 2002's third-person shooter game based on John Carpenter's seminal 1982 movie. Computer Artworks originally developed the game, but the remaster was handled by Nightdive, the studio behind so many excellent remasters (System Shock, Turok, Doom 64, Shadowman, Quake, Quake II, Star Wars: Dark Forces) and the recent full-fledged remake of System Shock. Once again, they delivered a great PC remaster that adds anti-aliasing, per-pixel lighting, 4K resolution and up to 144 frames per second. On GeForce NOW, Performance tier subscribers can play up to 1440p, while Ultimate tier subscribers can play at up to 4K and 120 frames per second.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2521380/Legacy_of_Kain_Soul_Reaver_12_Remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver 1&amp;2 Remastered</a>, on the other hand, celebrates the franchise's 25th anniversary with a remaster of Raziel's classic tale of vampiric vengeance. The game originally developed by Crystal Dynamic has been remastered by Aspyr, another development studio well versed with remasters (but not with remakes, as we <a href="https://wccftech.com/knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-delayed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> with Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic), and it features cut-scenes rendered with higher fidelity models, brand new hero models for Raziel and Kain, new enemy and boss models, a new glow effect to Raziel's eyes and the Wraith Blade, real-time shadows applied to all characters and objects, a Day and Night cycle that was cut from the final version of the original game, a Photo Mode, and a brand new map and compass.</p>
<p>Of course, earlier this week, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> also became playable via GeForce NOW wherever you have the license for it (Steam, Microsoft Store, and PC Game Pass). GFN Ultimate subscribers can even enable the gorgeous path tracing that was <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-update-enables-path-tracing-on-nvidia-rtx-gpus-amd-fsr-to-be-added-later/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">added </a>on Monday with the first update.</p>
<p>The rest of the weekly GeForce NOW list includes the following additions to the cloud platform's library:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fast Food Simulator (New release on Steam, Dec. 10)</li>
<li>The Spirit of the Samurai (New release on Steam, Dec. 12)</li>
<li>Diablo Immortal (Battle.net)</li>
<li>The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria (Steam)</li>
</ul>

			
			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
	</div>

		
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Sales Hit 3.5m in Less Than a Year as Game Awards Near]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-hit-3-5m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-sales-hit-3-5m-in-less-than-a-year-as-game-awards-near.1058985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-hit-3-5m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>developer LocalThunk and publisher Playstack have announced another major new sales milestone for the game, further cementing its massive success as this year's Game Awards loom.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://x.com/BalatroGame/status/1866905061609078866" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a message on social media platform X</a>,&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>has managed to rack up an eye-watering 3.5 million sales since its release earlier this year, which is a pretty monumental figure given the game's relatively small size and niche subject matter.</p>

<p>As the post itself says, developer LocalThunk started out simply wishing to make "a game for myself and a few friends", but&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>quickly grew beyond those boundaries, reaching the kind of global audience many indies can only dream of.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/balatro-3.5m-sales-cards.jpg?itok=hzNSLVYb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/balatro-3.5m-sales-cards.jpg?itok=JAID0XoJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>has hit yet another big sales milestone.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>was released back in February, and since then, it's become an absolutely huge hit. The game managed to rack up <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-half-million" rel="nofollow">half a million sales in just ten days</a>, and its pace didn't let up; just twelve days after that,&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-one-million" rel="nofollow">crossed a million sales</a>.</p>

<p>By August, the poker roguelike's sales figures <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-reach-2-million-as-devs-promise-first-major-update-soon" rel="nofollow">had hit two million</a>, with developer LocalThunk promising that&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>'s first major update would arrive in 2025, bringing "new ideas and strategies" to freshen the game up.</p>

<p>As an indie darling,&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>has hardly stayed in its own pen, either. It's crossed over with other indie smash hits like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-update-crossovers-cyberpunk" rel="nofollow">Stardew Valley</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Potion Craft</em>, as well as the likes of&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/big-dave-diver-collaboration-update-balatro" rel="nofollow"><em>Dave the Diver</em></a>.</p>

<p>While the game was initially released for PC and consoles, it also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-mobile-release-date" rel="nofollow">secured itself a mobile release</a> back in September, and given the bite-sized nature of&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>, it's hard to imagine that release hasn't contributed significantly to the game's success.</p>




<p>Such is&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>'s monumental success that it's the only indie game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/game-awards-2024-nominees-announced" rel="nofollow">nominated for the Game of the Year award</a> at this year's Game Awards, the ceremony for which will take place later today.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2379780/Balatro/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/balatro/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/balatro/9PK087LNGJC5" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/balatro-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>, and mobile devices.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon TCG Pocket Reveals New Mythical Island Expansion Set]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-tcg-pocket-reveals-new-mythical-island-expansion-set.1058982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Pokemon Company has announced a brand new&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>expansion set, which will bring over 80 new cards for you to collect and battle with next week.</p>

<p>Landing on December 17th, the Mythical Island set isn't the game's next full expansion; rather, it's a sort of stopgap set that introduces a new kind of booster pack. It looks from the pack's in-game artwork that Mythical Island represents expansion A1a.</p>

<p>Although this set won't quite be on the same level as&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket</em>'s base Genetic Apex set, it will introduce new EX cards, new Trainer cards, and some new immersive artwork cards as well, so it's still worth getting excited about if you're a&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>fan.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion-mew-ex.jpg?itok=NoIvBy3U 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion-mew-ex.jpg?itok=nHlZd1x5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pokemon TCG Pocket</em>'s new set may not be Genetic Apex-sized, but it's got plenty of new cards for you to collect.</figcaption></figure><p>Among the new cards are EX versions of Mew and Aerodactyl. The former packs a move called Genome Hacking that allows you to use one of your opponent's attacks, while Aerodactyl has the Primeval Law ability, preventing an opponent's active Pokemon from being evolved.</p>

<p>Plenty of other new cards will be introduced as part of this set, including full art versions of Marshadow, Vaporeon, and Dedenne, as well as an EX version of Marowak.</p>

<p>You can also look forward to Trainer cards depicting iconic Pokemon Trainers like Blue and Leaf, as well as new basic cards for the likes of Magmar, Tauros, and Exeggcute, among others.</p>

<h2>When is the new&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>expansion launching?</h2>

<p>Since&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket</em>'s Mythical Island set doesn't represent the next major expansion, you might well be wondering when that expansion will launch.</p>

<p>If a <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1855422922384351518" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Centro Leaks event leak</a> from November (which accurately predicted the launch of this A1a pack) is to be believed, then we can expect the new expansion to arrive on January 30th. It's currently codenamed A2, although we don't know what it will actually be called or what the theming will be yet.</p>




<p>If you're wondering exactly what&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>is, it's a condensed mobile version of the popular trading card game that allows you to collect and battle lots of different Pokemon in card form.</p>

<p>Released <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-release-date" rel="nofollow">in late October</a>, the game features a basic version of the standard&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG&nbsp;</em>battle system, as well as over 200 cards to collect as part of the Genetic Apex set. Future updates will also add <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-future-updates" rel="nofollow">new features like trading</a>&nbsp;in the coming months.</p>

<p>You can download&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>for free right now on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket/id6479970832" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemontcgp&amp;hl=en_GB" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Android</a> devices.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic and Lego have a long-term plan to make Fortnite more than battle royale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319151/lego-fortnite-epic-games-future-battle-royale-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-and-lego-have-a-long-term-plan-to-make-fortnite-more-than-battle-royale.1058979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319151/lego-fortnite-epic-games-future-battle-royale-interview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>A year ago, Epic kicked off a bold plan to turn <em>Fortnite</em> into a broader ecosystem for all kinds of games. And that plan was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/7/23990660/lego-fortnite-release-epic">led by the launch of <em>Lego Fortnite</em></a>, a <em>Minecraft</em>-style survival game that sits alongside the likes of battle royale and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/9/23992574/fortnite-festival-harmonix-guitar-hero-rock-band">the music-themed <em>Fortnite Festival</em></a> inside of <em>Fortnite</em>. Now, Epic is pushing into another new direction with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316954/lego-fortnite-brick-life-social-roleplay-game">the launch of <em>Brick Life</em></a>, a Lego-themed city where players can live virtual lives, much <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/11/23828431/rockstar-cfx-re-mod-tools-roleplay-server">like in <em>Grand Theft Auto </em>roleplaying servers</a>.</p></div><p>The ongoing goal, according to Devin Winterbottom, Epic’s executive vice president of game development, is to keep expanding in ways that make people rethink what <em>Fortnite</em> actually is. “The worst outcome for us is that everything looks like battle royale,” Winterbottom says. “That’s not what we want to do.”</p><p>For <em>Brick Life</em>, that takes the form of a family-friendly nonviolent space where players can explore and socialize inside of a Lego city. It launches today as part of a broader rebranding of Lego Fortnite; now, those two words refer to a hub that houses all of the Lego experiences in the game, while the survival title has been renamed <em>Lego Fortnite Odyssey</em>. In between those two major releases, Lego has also released <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/27/24084644/fortnite-new-lego-games-raft-survival-obby-fun">a handful of smaller, more experimental games</a> meant to broaden the audience even more.</p><p>Remi Marcelli, head of games at Lego, says that the initial plan for these experiments was to be very different from <em>Fortnite</em> as we know it now — that’s why one of the first releases was about <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/@thelegogroup/4051-8342-2747?lang=en-US">taking care of cats on a cozy island</a>. “We launched Cat Island Adventure, where you had to find kittens and nurture them, which is the furthest away from battle royale that we could think of,” he explains. “We had a decent playerbase at launch, but it was sort of lost in an environment where nobody was opening <em>Fortnite</em> to play that specific type of game.”</p><div><p>“The worst outcome for us is that everything looks like battle royale.”</p></div><p>One of the key things the Lego team learned over the last 12 months through those kinds of launches, according to Marcelli, is to attempt to appeal to as broad an audience as possible. “If we want to be relevant, we need to appeal to everyone, including the hardcore battle royale players,” he explains. “We need to find things that are exciting enough for them to visit us. Finding that match is what we’ve been trying to do for the entire year.” A hope is that the new hub area will help make some of those more offbeat experiences like the cat island easier to discover for players.</p><p>An issue for all of these new game experiences within <em>Fortnite</em> is competing with the behemoth that is battle royale. Right now, all of the various iterations of BR — like Zero Build or <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/12/24294616/fortnite-og-permanent-december-release-date"><em>Fortnite</em> OG</a> — still dominate in terms of pure player count. And while some other games, like <em>Odyssey</em>, have carved out a large audience, others, like <em>Rocket Racing</em> from <em>Rocket League</em> developer Psyonix, <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/learn-whats-new-in-rocket-racing-v31-40">have struggled</a>.</p><p>“The battle royale product can kind of distort and make it difficult to see success,” says Winterbottom. “<em>Odyssey</em> can look smaller compared to some of the other stuff that’s in the ecosystem, but it’s actually a successful game. It has a lot of players. If you were to see it as a standalone product outside of the ecosystem, the numbers that it generates would be considered very successful.” But he adds that “we believe success comes in a lot of different sizes. There are games that can be really compelling for a small group of players, and that variety is good. Not everything needs to be a monolithic mega game. That’s actually bad in our opinion.”</p><p>And while we’re already a year out, it’s also still early in the grand scheme of this plan to turn <em>Fortnite</em> into a video game platform. Right now, that includes everything from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24315134/fortnite-ballistic-counter-strike-first-person-shooter-fps">first-person shooters</a> to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/14/24296627/fortnite-tmnt-roguelike-user-made-games-creators">Ninja Turtles roguelikes</a> to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/30/24305460/fortnite-chapter-2-remix-concert-eminem-snoop-juice-wrld-ice-spice">musical experiences</a>, in addition to an ever-growing list of battle royale variations (and eventually <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest">something big with Disney</a>). Lego, meanwhile, offers a big opportunity to appeal to a very broad audience — and both teams are thinking very far out. “We’re in this for a very long term partnership,” says Winterbottom. “We talk about this in decade increments, not years.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket’s new expansion drops next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319498/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket%E2%80%99s-new-expansion-drops-next-week.1058976/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319498/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Pokémon TCG Pocket’s new expansion drops next week</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>The Mythical Island expansion releases on December 17th.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/charles-pulliam-moore">Charles Pulliam-Moore</a></span><span>, <span>a reporter focusing on film, TV, and pop culture. Before The Verge, he wrote about comic books, labor, race, and more at io9 and Gizmodo for almost five years.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-12-12T13:45:46.059Z"> <!-- -->Dec 12, 2024, 1:45 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div><p>If you buy something from a Verge link, Vox Media may earn a commission.<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/ethics-statement">See our ethics statement.</a></p></div></div><div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>If you’ve been playing <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/19/24248306/pokemon-tcg-pocket-hands-on"><em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em></a><em> </em>since launch, you’ve probably already collected most of the cards from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/19/24223570/pokemon-tcg-pocket-hits-ios-and-android-october-30th">the game’s first expansion</a>. But a new set is about to debut in just a few days.</p><p>Today, The Pokémon Company announced that Mythical Island, a new expansion set featuring the pokémon Mew, is coming to <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket </em>on December 17th. A trailer for the expansion reveals a handful of new Pokémon cards coming to the game for the first time like Purrloin, Serperior, and Marshadow. Previously, the only way to obtain a Mew card was by collecting cards featuring each of the 150 original pokémon from the Kantonian Pokédex, but it should be much easier to snag the new Mew EX card simply by ripping a few packs.</p><p>The Pokémon Company <a href="https://press.pokemon.com/en/releases/Pokemon-Trading-Card-Game-Pocket-Celebrates-60-Million-Downloads-Since">also announced</a> that <em>TCG Pocket </em>has exceeded 60 million <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket/id6479970832">iOS</a> and <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fplay.google.com%2Fstore%2Fapps%2Fdetails%3Fid%3Djp.pokemon.pokemontcgp">Android</a> downloads since the game launched at the end of October. The ability to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/14/24296690/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trade-cards">actually trade cards with other people</a> hasn’t come to the game just yet, but it’s going to be very useful, given that there’s a bunch of fresh cards on the way.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318908/facebook-instagram-threads-down-outage-meta"><h2>Facebook, Instagram, and Threads have recovered after a massive outage</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318444/google-gemini-2-0-flash-ai-model"><h2>Google launched Gemini 2.0, its new AI model for practically everything</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent"><h2>Google’s AI enters its ‘agentic era’</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318434/youtube-living-room-tv-growth-2024"><h2>YouTube is a hit on TVs — and is starting to act like it</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317119/ios-18-2-apple-intelligence-chatgpt-genmoji"><h2>iOS 18.2 is rolling out now, adding ChatGPT integration and more Apple Intelligence tools</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s New Update Unlocks All Stages for Local Multiplayer]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-new-update-unlocks-all-stages-for-local-multiplayer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero%E2%80%99s-new-update-unlocks-all-stages-for-local-multiplayer.1058970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-new-update-unlocks-all-stages-for-local-multiplayer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-73663">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s update Ver.2006.005.003.004.003 is live now. It allows players to access all stages when playing couch coop.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, when players tried to play local multiplayer in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero, they were restricted to one stage, The Hyperbolic Time Chamber. After the new patch, you can fight against your friends in all of the game’s 12 stages, allowing you to experience high-speed 3D battles with beautiful visuals and destructible environments.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-balancing-changes-in-new-sparking-zero-patch">Balancing Changes in New Sparking Zero Patch</h2>



<p>The new Dragon Ball Sparking Zero patch also features several character adjustments; check them out below.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Android 19 and Dr. Gero’s amount of stamina and energy absorbed during a successful throw has been changed. Also, Dragon Dash, rapid ascend, and fast descent will consume energy when using these characters.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Cell 2nd can now throw-escape&nbsp;</li>



<li>Cooler’s transformation now recovers an increased amount of stamina.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Giant characters’ power has been reduced, and the time it takes to charge up smash attacks has been increased.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Great Ape Vegeta and Doctor Willow’s maximum health has been reduced.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Super Vegito’s Final Kamehameha has increased energy consumption and damage dealt.</li>



<li>Players can control the trajectory of Son Goku (mini)’s Quick Rush while charging.</li>



<li>Lastly, Mr. Satan’s Present Bomb has increased stiffness after activation.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>You can check out the changes and adjustments to functions, battle systems, skills, blasts and more in the <a href="https://dbsz.bn-ent.net/information/?p=13" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">full patch notes</a>. Dragon Ball Sparking Zero update Ver.2006.005.003.004.003 was released for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S and Steam.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news,&nbsp;Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s 90% of sales&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-90-of-sales-came-from-europe-and-na/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came from Europe and NA</a>. If you are new to Sparking Zero, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-attack-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Attack</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-movement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Movement</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-defense-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Defense</a>&nbsp;guides. Also, here are the game’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guides-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Episode Battles</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-bonus-battles-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bonus Battles</a>&nbsp;guide hubs. What are your thoughts on Dragon Ball Sparking Zero unlocking all stages for local multiplayer in the latest patch? Let us know in the comments or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Balatro selling 3.5 million units</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year/">Balatro Sells 3.5 Million Units Within the First Year</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Balatro developers have revealed that the game has managed to sell 3.5 million units since February 20, 2024. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-has-confirmed-their-intent-to-acquire-kadokawa-group/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-has-confirmed-their-intent-to-acquire-kadokawa-group/">Sony Has Confirmed Their Intent to Acquire Kadokawa Group&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has officially confirmed their intent to acquire FromSoftware’s parent company, Kadokawa Group. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bend-studio-live-serivce-images/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bend-studio-live-serivce-images/">Early Images of Bend Studio’s Potential Next Game Reveal a Brand New Live-Service IP</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Early images of what could be a new live-service IP by Bend Studio’s have been posted online.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/">Mafia The Old Country Trailer Leaks Online, Releasing Summer 2025</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A trailer for Mafia: The Old Country has leaked online, revealing that the game will be released in Summer 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cooldown Games announces establishment – publisher focused on games that accommodate busy players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/cooldown-games-announces-establishment-publisher-focused-on-games-that-accommodate-busy-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cooldown-games-announces-establishment-%E2%80%93-publisher-focused-on-games-that-accommodate-busy-players.1058967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/cooldown-games-announces-establishment-publisher-focused-on-games-that-accommodate-busy-players<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Led by former Gearbox Publishing president Steve Gibson.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Cooldown Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cooldown-games">Cooldown Games</a>, an independent publisher of console and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,949 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> games, has announced its establishment. It is founded by industry veterans with experience from multiple top-tier game companies including Gearbox Entertainment, <a title="Companies > id Software [152 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/id-software">id Software</a>, and Warner Bros., and will focus on delivering “premium titles that emphasize bringing more refined gaming experiences that players can enjoy at their own pace without the need of large time investments.” <span id="more-933531"></span></p><p>The company’s founders include:</p><ul><li>Steve Gibson, chief executive officer – Former president of <a title="Companies > Gearbox Publishing [110 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-gearbox-entertainment-company/gearbox-publishing">Gearbox Publishing</a></li><li>Matt Charles, chief product officer</li><li>Erick Cobbs, chief business officer</li><li>Jackson Hardesty, chief operations officer</li><li>Brad Schliesser, chief revenue officer</li><li>Jimmy Sieben, chief technology officer</li><li>Jeff Skal, chief marketing officer</li></ul><p>“Our team is confident rational business models will be a long-term strength of Cooldown Games and that just might be a refreshing contrast from many recent industry trends,” said Cooldown Games CEO Steve Gibson in a press release. “My passion of helping game makers reach as many game players as possible while making sure that it’s a rewarding experience for everyone involved is at the center of all of this. Let’s make some great games together.”</p><p>Cooldown Games chief marketing officer Jeff Skal added, “Over the last five years, we all individually noticed that we’ve been gravitating away from many of the predictable new releases. We noticed that was because most of us already have ‘forever’ games—for me and Brad that’s <em>World of Warcraft</em>, and for Jackson that’s <em>DayZ</em>—and most of these giant new releases were just asking for more than we could give. When we started Cooldown Games, we quickly realized that there’s a ton of gamers out there just like us—and we wanted to find the best games that can fit in between our sessions, or seasons, or even just after raid night.”</p><p>Chief product officer Matt Charles said, “Many talented developers weathered the recent industry turbulence and now more than ever seek a partner that understands their project’s vision and how it will resonate with an audience. We are looking to work with astute and passionate teams that share our philosophy and observation about player behavior, and we can create a force-multiplying partnership on the path to release.”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Developers interested in potential publishing partnerships with Cooldown Games are encouraged to contact the company via its <a href="https://cooldowngames.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Overdrive for Switch launches April 10, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/star-overdrive-for-switch-launches-april-10-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-overdrive-for-switch-launches-april-10-2025.1058964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/star-overdrive-for-switch-launches-april-10-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Traverse an expansive alien world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Star Overdrive [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/star-overdrive">Star Overdrive</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,430 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on April 10, 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > Dear Villagers [85 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plug-in-digital/dear-villagers">Dear Villagers</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Caracal Games [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/caracal-games">Caracal Games</a> announced. <span id="more-933528"></span></p><p>A <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2055590/Star_Overdrive/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a> for the game has also been up since its initial announcement, but has yet to be acknowledged by Dear Villagers, suggesting it will come to additional platforms at a later date.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Dear Villagers:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>As players traverse the game’s expansive alien world, they will face challenging enemies, solve intricate puzzles, and uncover secrets hidden across diverse biomes. The game also lets players customize their hoverboard, adapting its speed, handling, and gravity to their personal style or the challenges at hand.</p><p>Following its <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> Direct reveal in August 2024, <em>Star Overdrive</em> captured the attention of sci-fi and action-<a title="Genres > Adventure [1,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> fans. During the reveal, the developers cited <em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em> as one of their biggest inspirations. While <em>Star Overdrive</em> draws inspiration from classic <a title="Genres > Open-World [531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,363 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action games</a>, its hoverboard-based navigation and physics-driven powers offer a truly distinct experience.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>After intercepting a mysterious distress signal, you’ll start your daring adventure through an uncharted alien planet. The journey reveals stunning landscapes ranging from shimmering deserts to vast aquatic zones, each biome pushing their traversal skills to the edge. Along the way, players will encounter remnants of an ancient civilization and piece together the mystery behind the signal.</p><p>Combat is a creative blend of physics-based powers, melee strikes and the Hoverboard companion’s special moves, challenging players to find new ways to outmaneuver and defeat enemies.</p><p>Every challenge brings players closer to uncovering the connection behind the distress signal, the protagonist’s past and the fate of the galaxy.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Hoverboard Navigation and <a title="Genres > Racing [214 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">Racing</a></strong> – Speed through vast landscapes, perform incredible tricks, and gain the edge in intense combat.</li><li><strong>Emergent Physics-Based Gameplay</strong> – Unleash and combine powers to battle enemies, bend the laws of physics, and solve intricate puzzles.</li><li><strong>Mysterious and Diverse Alien World</strong> – Journey through four uniquely distinct biomes, each brimming with challenges and secrets to uncover.</li><li><strong>Epic Battles Against <a title="Companies > Creature [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a>s of All Sizes</strong> – Engage with unique creatures, from small-scale rivals to towering bosses, each requiring strategy and skill to overcome.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="STAR OVERDRIVE - Release date trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4Rh3wsWHbU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows' Canon Mode Can Make All Of The Big Choices For You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-can-make-all-of-the-big-choices-for-you/1100-6528401/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-can-make-all-of-the-big-choices-for-you.1058958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-canon-mode-can-make-all-of-the-big-choices-for-you/1100-6528401/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528401">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Player choices have been a big part of the Assassin's Creed franchise, and that's still going to be true in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-gameplay-and-everything-we-know/1100-6523576/" data-ref-id="1100-6523576">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>. However, for any fans who don't want to agonize over which branching dialogue option to pick or who to romance, Ubisoft is introducing a new canon mode in Shadows that will let the players simply experience the story without having to make any choices of their own.</p><p>Shadows director Jonathan Dumont revealed the new option during <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/hi_we_are_brooke_charles_jonathan_and_thierry/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a Reddit appearance</a> alongside other developers from the game.</p><p>"Choices come more into play when recruiting allies and [romancing] some of the characters," said Dumont. "Since the fan base is divided on branching dialogues, we have incorporated an option called Canon Mode which allows you to play the game with choices already made for you, to give you a choice-free experience. Hope this makes it fun for everyone."</p><p>Dumont also noted that Shadows is close to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/assassins-creed-origins-review/1900-6416794/" data-ref-id="1900-6416794">Assassin's Creed Origins</a> in terms of scale. Associate Narrative Director Brooke Davies added that the two main characters, Naoe and Yasuke, can pick their preferred romantic partners outside of Canon Mode for both "shorter and longer romance opportunities." She also said, "The story of Shadows culminates in a single, [canonical] ending. That said there are many unique paths leading to this point, and in particular that will determine who is (and isn't) at your side along the way."</p><p>The developers confirmed that Shadows <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-introduce-a-new-direction-for-its-modern-day-story/1100-6527555/" data-ref-id="1100-6527555">will introduce a new direction for the modern-day storyline</a>. Dumont indicated that Shadows "will be different than what we have done in the past, but that is connected to our modern-day lore and will develop over time in the Animus Hub and subsequent titles." He also said that Hattori Hanzō from Assassin's Creed: Memories will appear in Shadows.</p><p>Additionally, Davies indicated that Naoe and Yasuke won't immediately be on the same side.</p><p>"Their paths do ultimately converge and we see them form a league together around common cause," said Davies. "That said, this path is not always smooth and straight, and their unique backgrounds and perspectives do not always align. This is something we will see them and sometimes even help them to work through by making some interesting choices."</p><p>Ubisoft recently shared a lengthy overview of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-dramatically-alter-how-it-plays-based-on-your-character-and-weapons/1100-6528362/" data-ref-id="1100-6528362">how combat will work in Shadows</a>. Details about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-battle-pass-allegedly-leaks-showing-off-futuristic-and-mythological-cosmetics/1100-6527789/" data-ref-id="1100-6527789">the game's battle pass</a> have leaked online, and Ubisoft has stated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-clarifies-rumors-about-animus-hub-the-new-name-of-assassins-creed-infinity/1100-6527804/" data-ref-id="1100-6527804">the rewards in the Animus Hub are free</a>. Assassin's Creed Shadows will hit PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC on February 14, 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Past Black Ops Map Is Off The Table For A Remaster, Says Call Of Duty Dev]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-past-black-ops-map-is-off-the-table-for-a-remaster-says-call-of-duty-dev/1100-6528400/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-past-black-ops-map-is-off-the-table-for-a-remaster-says-call-of-duty-dev.1058955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-past-black-ops-map-is-off-the-table-for-a-remaster-says-call-of-duty-dev/1100-6528400/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528400">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-review/1900-6418306/" data-ref-id="1900-6418306">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> Season 1 had an unexpected surprise for players when it brought back the Hacienda map from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-4-review-zombies-blackout-m/1900-6417010/" data-ref-id="1900-6417010">Call of Duty: Black Ops 4</a>, and it may not be the only classic map to get a remaster. During a recent interview, Treyarch's Associate Creative Director Miles Leslie hinted that the team already has its favorite maps to revisit, and no map is off the table.</p><p>"We put a ton of consideration into the prospective remasters with each new game," Leslie told <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/call-of-duty/black-ops-6-dev-hints-at-more-classic-map-remasters-in-the-works-3004483/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dextero</a>. "We know there are certain fan favorites that players would like to see again, and we have some of our own favorites that we've had on a wish list over the years. I'll just say that while we're still focused on delivering original designs as the majority of our post-launch maps, no previous Black Ops title is off the table for potential remasters."</p><p>Earlier this month, a Call of Duty leaker reported <a href="https://twitter.com/ForwardLeaksAlt/status/1865886089459724507?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1865886089459724507%7Ctwgr%5E6a71a8dbfc6110c6c0e803b26c91df7fe95a62f3%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dexerto.com%2Fcall-of-duty%2Fcod-leak-reveals-fan-favorite-black-ops-map-set-to-return-in-near-future-3002067%2F" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that the Launch map</a> from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-review/1900-6283815/" data-ref-id="1900-6283815">Call of Duty: Black Ops 1</a> will return with a new title, Cosmodome, in either Black Ops 6 or the next Call of Duty game that's coming in 2025. This rumor has yet to be confirmed.</p><p>Prior to the launch of Season 1, Treyarch laid out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/free-black-ops-6-gameplay-trial-is-coming-this-month-provides-access-to-zombies-and-multiplayer/1100-6528203/" data-ref-id="1100-6528203">everything players can expect to see in Black Ops 6</a>. The developer also revealed that a free trial for Black Ops 6's multiplayer and Zombies modes will begin on December 13 for a limited time. Players also recently discovered <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-players-discover-game-ending-nuke-easter-egg/1100-6528328/" data-ref-id="1100-6528328">a game-ending Easter egg</a> in Black Ops 6's Nuketown. Additionally, Treyarch teased a collaboration between <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-teases-squid-game-collab-for-black-ops-6-and-warzone/1100-6528158/" data-ref-id="1100-6528158">Black Ops 6 and Netflix's Squid Game</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunless Sea Director Announces New Narrative CRPG Travelling At Night]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sunless-sea-director-travelling-at-night</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sunless-sea-director-announces-new-narrative-crpg-travelling-at-night.1058913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sunless-sea-director-travelling-at-night<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Sunless Sea&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Cultist Simulator&nbsp;</em>designer Alexis Kennedy has announced&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night</em>, which he describes as a "dialogue-driven choices-matter combat-free CRPG" that's not a million miles away from the likes of&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://weatherfactory.biz/announcing-travelling-at-night/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">an announcement post</a> on his studio Weather Factory's official website, Kennedy says that while he's been "making narrative games for fifteen years", he's "never made a traditional isometric CRPG", likening doing so to a composer "hav[ing] a go at opera".</p>

<p>Rather tantalizingly, Kennedy says he was once contracted as a narrative consultant on a "really promising and heavily NDA'd RPG for a developer [he admires] and on a franchise [he likes]". Of course, he doesn't name what that RPG is, but he does say its cancellation made him regret not working within the genre.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/alexis-kennedy-sunless-sea-travelling-at-night.jpg?itok=zxv5TDBP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/alexis-kennedy-sunless-sea-travelling-at-night.jpg?itok=nX5qPVyA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Sunless Sea&nbsp;</em>designer Alexis Kennedy is back with a brand new project.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're thinking that&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>looks an awful lot like&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>from the screenshot above, then you're not wrong, and it's a game Kennedy himself brings up in the game's announcement post.</p>

<p>He says that while he and his partner Lottie Bevan considered using the word "discolike" to describe their game, they didn't want players thinking they were pursuing&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>'s "distinctive nihilistic funny sex'n'drugs'n'disco vibe".</p>

<p>However, Kennedy and Bevan did incur a "creative debt" to&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>is aiming to find the same "audience for something CRPG-esque with really unorthodox creative choices".</p>

<p>As such, while Weather Factory isn't <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-disco-elysium-devs-new-studios-spiritual-successors" rel="nofollow">one of a number of studios</a> currently operating out of the ashes of&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>developer ZA/UM (including <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/game-development/for-a-while-it-seemed-like-miracles-were-possible-and-with-them-redemption-a-follow-up-to-the-legendary-disco-elysium-might-have-been-ready-to-play-within-the-next-yearzaums-devs-loved-it-management-canceled-it-and-laid-off-the-team/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ZA/UM itself</a>), you can consider&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>another contender for the&nbsp;<em>Disco&nbsp;</em>crown.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/travelling-at-night-stats.jpg?itok=U1PhEwQT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/travelling-at-night-stats.jpg?itok=saT476ht 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>isn't subtle about its influences.</figcaption></figure><p>With regards to the production cycle, Kennedy says he estimates&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>will take "between two and four years", and that he's hoping for a day one Steam Deck launch as well.</p>

<p>He describes the game's art direction as "determinedly non-realistic" while still being "plausibly CRPG", and confirms that&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>won't have an "intentionally inchoate player-cipher" character, but instead a defined protagonist by the name of Spencer Hobson.</p>

<p>We'll bring you more on&nbsp;<em>Travelling At Night&nbsp;</em>as soon as we get it. In the meantime, you can read our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/book-of-hours-review-fascinating-journey-of-many-words" rel="nofollow">review of Weather Factory's last game&nbsp;<em>Book of Hours&nbsp;</em>right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii details Minato Girls, substories, and minigames]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-details-minato-girls-substories-and-minigames</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-details-minato-girls-substories-and-minigames.1058907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-details-minato-girls-substories-and-minigames<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ Minato Girls</strong></p><p><a title="Genres > Party [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a> it up with the exquisite Minato Girls!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_001.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>When he finds out his crewmate <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>aru is dying to hang with the Minato Girls, Captain Majima pitches in to make that dream come true.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Party</strong></p><p>Put together an unforgettable party, mingle with five gorgeous ladies, and try to score their contact info!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_010.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_009.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Cast</strong></p><p><em>—Ena (voiced by Enako)</em></p><p>A prominent cosplayer who takes pride in being part of the community. She also has a bit of a stoic side.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_012.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Seiko (voiced by Seiko Kirishima)</em></p><p>A spokesmodel for <a title="Genres > Racing [214 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> events. While friendly and affable, her sheer beauty makes her difficult to approach.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_013.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Kaho (voiced by Kaho Shibuya)</em></p><p>A published author who frequently hosts seminars. Her intelligence and class make her incredibly attractive, but she also has a secret.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_014.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Ai (voiced by Ai Hongo)</em></p><p>A popular adult film actress. Her friendly and curious nature makes her all the more appealing.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_015.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Misoshii (voiced by Misoshiru)</em></p><p>A streamer with a focus on gaming videos. She’s always coming up with new ways to entertain her fans.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_016.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Substories</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a treasure trove of substories on land or at sea!</p><p><strong>If I Weren’t An Idol</strong></p><p>Majima comes across a young man agonizing over whether to join an idol’s bus tour. He senses that the boy is madly in love but too afraid to act on it, so Majima decides to tag along and encourage him. However, what starts as a fun experience with a bunch of idol fans slowly takes a turn for the worse…</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_017.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_018.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Getting With The Times: Pirates and Compliance</strong></p><p>Majima becomes acquainted with a captain whose old-school methods have made him fall out of favor with his crew. Just as they’re about to discuss what went wrong, the pair are approached by a man from a consulting firm. The two old sea dogs must undergo compliance training to become better captains. Do Majima and his new friend have what it takes to get with the times and master the art of modern pirating?</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_019.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_020.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Minigames</strong></p><p>Have a blast around the Hawaiian coastline!</p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii | Minigames" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hFgp76kCbdU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Karaoke</strong></p><p>Enjoy a Majima-filled karaoke experience!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_021.jpg"></a></figure><p>In addition to the Goro Pirates theme song and brand-new idol hits, some favorites from the series are making their return! Karaoke is also available while aboard your ship.</p><p>Be it on land or at sea, get ready to sing your heart out!</p><p><em>—Song of Departure -Journey to the New World-</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_022.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—The Sun at 36.5°C</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_023.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Midnight Desire</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_024.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—The Goro Pirates Theme</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_025.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Get to the Top!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_026.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—24-Hour Cinderella</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_027.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Dragon Kart</strong></p><p>Modify karts and race across metropolitan Hawaii!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_028.jpg"></a></figure><p>The thrilling yet dangerous Dragon Kart racing minigame comes to Hawaii for the first time! Compete against rivals in battle mode! Try to hone your skills or lay waste to your foes. Blow away the competition with your rocket launcher and aim to be number one in all of Hawaii!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_028.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_029.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_030.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Crazy Delivery</strong></p><p>Complete wacky deliveries in a brand-new area!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_031.jpg"></a></figure><p>Deliver meals in style around packed Hawaiian streets to make some dough! Anaconda Shopping Center makes its debut as a delivery spot!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_032.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_033.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_034.jpg"></a></figure><p><strng>Outfits</strng></p><p>Dress up Goro Majima in your favorite apparel! From Goro Majima’s classic attire to flashy idol costumes, there are over 200 outfits to choose from. You can also customize his hairstyle, eyepatch, piercings, and more. Have fun giving Goro Majima your own unique flair!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_035.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_036.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_037.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_038.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_039.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_040.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Other Entertainment</strong></p><p>You can also have fun with the Bang Bang Batting Center, Sicko Snap, vocational school, and many other activities!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_041.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_042.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_043.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_044.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_045.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_046.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_047.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Game Centers and the Master System</strong></p><p>Play some classic titles on the Master System and at <a title="Platforms > Arcade [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a> around Hawaii!</p><p>The underwater <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,951 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em>The Ocean Hunter</em> has been added to game centers! Enjoy the beautiful world that awaits at the bottom of the sea!</p><p>Additionally, new titles have made their way to the Master System! Go wild with a variety of classic shooters such as <em>Poseidon Wars 3-D</em>, <em>Space Harrier 3-D</em>, <em>Star Jacker</em>, and more!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_048.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_049.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_050.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Like-a-Dragon-Pirate-Yakuza-in-Hawaii_2024_12-12-24_051.jpg"></a></figure></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mew headlines next Pokémon TCG Pocket booster packs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mew-headlines-next-pokemon-tcg-pocket-booster-packs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mew-headlines-next-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-booster-packs.1058901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mew-headlines-next-pokemon-tcg-pocket-booster-packs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Mythical Island available next week.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pok%C3%A9mon-TCG-Pocket_-Mythical-Island-_-Coming-Soon!-0-11-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Pokémon Company</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The next themed booster pack coming to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a> will be Mythical Island and features Mew as its cover star.</p>
<p>The Gen 1 Mythical Pokémon is already in the mobile game as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-secret-missions">part of a secret mission</a>, but now headlines this major new addition.</p>
<p>The Mythical Island booster pack will be available from next week: Tuesday 17th December.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Pokémon TCG Pocket: Mythical Island  | Coming Soon!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eUYHC2ReohA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Pokémon TCG Pocket: Mythical Island  | Coming Soon!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eUYHC2ReohA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eUYHC2ReohA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Pokémon TCG Pocket: Mythical Island | Coming Soon!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eUYHC2ReohA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>A trailer for the pack shows off a new EX Mew card, which will presumably be one of the fancy immersive cards.</p>
<p>Also shown are an EX card for Aerodactyl, and cards for Marshadow, Tauros, Magmar, Exeggcute, Morelull, Larvesta, Snivy, Dhelmise, and more.</p>
<p>The Mythical Island booster pack will join the current batch of Genetic Apex booster packs starring Charizard, Mewtwo, and Pikachu.</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Oh hey, what's this? Let me go ahead and drop this here.</p><p>I kicked in a lot of doors to get this information to you.🦶🚪 (Realistically, I asked REALLY nice and cried a little)</p><p>BEHOLD! Mythical Island! ✨ 🏝️ <a href="https://t.co/DpG2qWw24S">pic.twitter.com/DpG2qWw24S</a></p></div>— Pokémon TCG Pocket (@PokemonTCGP) <a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonTCGP/status/1867193268015862067?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 12, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>It's unclear if or when the current booster packs will no longer be available, but make sure to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/psa-dont-forget-to-spend-your-pokemon-tcg-pocket-pack-points">use your Pack Points</a>.</p>
<p>Pokémon TCG Pocket has proven incredibly popular since its release at the end of October. The mobile game reportedly <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-reportedly-surpassed-200m-in-first-month">surpassed $200m in revenue in its first month</a>.</p>
<p>What's more, The Pokémon Company confirmed today the game has exceeded 60m downloads across iOS and Android.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Portable 20th Anniversary – Is that a PlayStation in your pocket?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/12/playstation-portable-20th-anniversary-is-that-a-playstation-in-your-pocket/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-portable-20th-anniversary-%E2%80%93-is-that-a-playstation-in-your-pocket.1058889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/12/playstation-portable-20th-anniversary-is-that-a-playstation-in-your-pocket/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>There’s a remarkable synergy to PlayStation hitting its 30th Anniversary at right around the same time the PSP marks its 20th. Sony are exactly the kind of company to gift their fans a perfectly formed handheld device on their 10th birthday, but its success was hardly guaranteed, despite the remarkable foothold the Japanese tech giant had found in the games industry. They were entering waters that Nintendo ruled over at the time, who themselves were following up on the Game Boy Advance with the somewhat confounding dual-screen Nintendo DS. There was every possibility that Sony’s effort would be swallowed up, and while they never quite usurped the dominion built on Tetris and Italian moustaches, the PSP was an innovative, powerful and occasionally bonkers device that changed the face of handheld gaming forever.</p>
<p>I still have a PSP. That’s probably a given, but I thought I should clear it up from the start. It’s a Japanese Monster Hunter special edition, with enlarged rear handholds to make it more comfortable, and a stunning black and gold paintjob. I love it, and it handily ties together a number of the most important things about the PSP: its popularity and success in Japan, and the role and importance that Monster Hunter played within that.</p>



<p>Launching in 2004, the PSP was the perfect next step in Sony’s foray into the games industry. Just as it had done with the original PlayStation and its successor, Sony produced a piece of hardware that was built for that technological era. Its 4.3” widescreen LCD display was also incredibly sharp, detailed and huge for the time, and allowed developers to make the most of its powerful dual 333MHz chipset (originally limited to 222Mhz) and 32MB of memory. Those are amusingly small numbers by today’s standards, but they were incredible at the time in this form factor, not least when compared to Nintendo’s quirky and underpowered DS line.</p>
<p>Sony also sought to repeat a few tricks from its home consoles by using optical media with the UMD, allowing for much larger game sizes compared to Nintendo DS and GBA cartridges, and a cottage industry of selling films on UMD for portable movie watching. Add to that the use of Memory Stick Duo for save data and WiFi, the PSP was set up for a future that would include the early PlayStation Store and online multiplayer.</p>


<p>At launch, the PSP had a host of killer software. Prime among them, an amazing version of Ridge Racer – honestly, I still play it to this day – and Sony’s answer to Tetris in the form of Lumines. Lumines embodied the PlayStation difference in such a succinct way, taking a block-dropping puzzler, leaning on club and dance music, and then tying the experience together with a surreal and ever-changing colour scheme. Its sequel took it one step further, adding in licensed music tracks, with both destroying any sense of time or place, especially when you added a pair of headphones to the mix.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, that launch line-up catered to the PlayStation faithful with games like Wipeout Pure and Twisted Metal: Head On while hoping to draw in newcomers with a keen eye for the biggest sports titles, bringing FIFA, NBA, NHL, MLB and NFL to the party from day one. That’s not to say there weren’t also the oddities that would help to define the PSP as a place for more unusual experiences, and at the head of that was Metal Gear Acid, a game that translated the successful Metal Gear Solid stealth-action line into a tactical card-based strategy title. I still don’t quite understand it, and I’ve bought it three times.</p>
<p>Then there was Monster Hunter. This wasn’t where the series started, but as sure as a Rathalos is red (except when its blue), this was where it found its success. Monster Hunter Freedom rebalanced the game to make it a better singleplayer experience, but it was the PSP’s ability to hook up with other consoles for multiplayer that cemented Monster Hunter within the Japanese consciousness. I marvelled at tales of people spending their lunchbreaks sat on benches and playing Monster Hunter – especially as a lonely Monster Hunter player in the UK – but in Japan, Monster Hunter, and the PSP, were a phenomenon, and sales for the console and the game were huge.</p>

<p>While the PSP would have still had success without Monster Hunter – it went on to sell nearly 80 million units after all – &nbsp;it ensured that it was part of the Japanese development scene at its height, and that then in turned played into the vibrant and often unusual software that became available for it.</p>
<p>Idiosyncratic exclusives like Patapon and LocoRoco sat happily next to hugely impressive entries in Sony’s tentpole series like Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories and God of War: Ghost of Sparta. It felt as though the PSP wasn’t just a handheld, but a real, fully grown console, and owners will undoubtedly wax lyrical about just how good the games for it were, whether it was RPGs, puzzlers or action titles.</p>
<p>This was a time when Sony was still able and willing to be adventurous, putting the resources and faith into games away from their main home console line up. It was a sign of both the power of the PSP and the quality of its line up that games like the GTA Stories spin-offs, Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker, and Ready at Dawn’s God of War games were later ported to PS2 or remastered for PS3.</p>

<p>Was it perfect? Far from it, and one of the clearest oversights was the inclusion of only one analogue stick, just as the world was becoming used to two. This caused all sort of control craziness – trying to play with both the D-Pad and the analogue stick requires your hands to be in a position known as ‘the claw’ – but overall it didn’t detract from the games too much, with some interesting implementations to combat it like constantly spamming the right shoulder button to reset the camera behind you.</p>
<p>UMDs were also a blessing and a curse, with the physical disc media proving to be hugely power hungry and slow to read from, while they could also be damaged despite being in a plastic case, and movie releases for the format were both expensive and less complete than their DVD siblings. UMD never found their way into any other devices other than the PSP, ultimately meaning that the format was abandoned by studios long before the PSP actually died out. Still, I love – <em>LOVE</em> – the ‘schnikt’ sound the PSP makes when its reading from them, and the format’s comparatively huge storage capacity meant that PSP games looked and sounded far superior to anything Nintendo’s handhelds could muster.</p>
<p>The PSP’s legacy is clear to see today. Though its successor the PS Vita never enjoyed anywhere near the same level of success, thanks in part to the rise of mobile gaming, but also a lack of first party support, handheld gaming has now come out the other side with the Nintendo Switch and Steam Deck. Meanwhile, many of its best series have made the leap to home consoles – Mizuguchi, we need a new Lumines game please – and Monster Hunter, far from being just a handheld experience, is now an all-conquering behemoth, taking the world by storm.</p>
<p>If Sony do make a new handheld, as has been rumoured this last month, here’s hoping that they look to the design philosophy of the PSP; a cutting edge piece of technology, with Sony’s biggest franchises, but one that has room for the quirkier side of gaming. And one that, twenty years on, will have the same level of impact on people’s gaming lives.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country Early Ad Shows Gorgeous Visuals, Summer 2025 Release Window]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-early-ad-shows-gorgeous-visuals-summer-2025-release-window/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-early-ad-shows-gorgeous-visuals-summer-2025-release-window.1058886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-early-ad-shows-gorgeous-visuals-summer-2025-release-window/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A Mafia: The Old Country ad has leaked online today ahead of the game's showing at tonight's The Game Awards show, providing a quick look at the game's visuals and its release window.</p>
<p>The ad, which can be watched below courtesy of X user <a href="https://x.com/DJari2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Damon Andrews</a>, likely went live before it was intended, as it features some short sequences that look like part of a bigger trailer, possibly the one that is coming later tonight during The Game Awards 2024 show, providing a quick look at the game's visuals, which look gorgeous even in the off-screen low-quality recording. The ad also confirms a Summer 2025 release window for the game.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">SUMMER 2025 <a href="https://t.co/njHNxoWttW">pic.twitter.com/njHNxoWttW</a></p>
<p>— Damon Andrews (@DJari2020) <a href="https://twitter.com/DJari2020/status/1867162950349320328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 12, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>With Mafia: The Old Country, developer Hangar 13 will go back to the<a href="https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-revealed-for-release-in-2025/"> roots of what fans loved about the franchise</a>, featuring a deep, linear narrative with a classic mob movie feeling, a stunning Italian setting that will allow players to learn the origins of organized crime in Sicily and more that will make for a highly immersive package.</p>
<p>Mafia: The Old Country is currently in development for PC and consoles and will launch sometime next Summer. Stay tuned for a better look at the next entry in the series coming<a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-and-mafia-the-old-country-to-be-shown-at-the-game-awards-2024/"> later today.</a></p>

			
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Band Of Crusaders is a dark fantasy party RPG with heady overtones of XCOM and Diablo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/band-of-crusaders-is-a-dark-fantasy-party-rpg-with-heady-overtones-of-xcom-and-diablo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/band-of-crusaders-is-a-dark-fantasy-party-rpg-with-heady-overtones-of-xcom-and-diablo.1058883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/band-of-crusaders-is-a-dark-fantasy-party-rpg-with-heady-overtones-of-xcom-and-diablo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Archdemons mount European package tour in face of local objections</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_RIGyUlR.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Virtual Alchemy</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2">Space Marine 2</a>'s wanton devil-mulching left you hungry for more fantastical depictions of medieval zealotry, maybe take a look at Band Of Crusaders, an open-world party-based <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> in which you are the Grandmaster of a knightly order, trying to keep a bunch of wily Archdemons out of Europe. It seems to play a bit like XCOM, with an oppressive world map that is slowly encroached upon as you travel around recruiting soldiers, interacting with settlements, and picking real-time fights with hellfiends "inspired by biblical descriptions and European folklore". Naturally, parallels with real-life xenophobia and sectarian hatred abound. Here's the trailer.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Band of Crusaders - Official Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N_EzXS4ztMg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Band of Crusaders - Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N_EzXS4ztMg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N_EzXS4ztMg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_EzXS4ztMg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>And here are some more details from the Steam page. Your Band Of Crusaders can hire up to 20 knights, and you can train, equip and rearm them at an expanding campsite of upgradeable buildings. "Each crusader brings novelty to your camp with their own backgrounds, strengths and weaknesses as well as the ability to synergize with their Brothers," the developers explain. There are no fixed character classes, but each crusader has a skill tree made up of active, passive and "semi-active" abilities, and there's an emphasis on "versatile" multi-role builds.</p>
<p>The overworld sort of looks like they modded <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/darkest-dungeon">Darkest Dungeon</a> into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine">Where The Water Tastes Like Wine</a>. It worsens steadily as the demons invade and various human factions fight back, a darkening of the mood that (assuming you last long enough) culminates in a scrap with one of the Archdemons. Conditions such as time of day and season affect how you play. As for your opponents, "each of the enemy families has its strengths and weaknesses, encouraging the player to strategize and adjust their combat tactics".</p><p>I'm in two minds about the real-time combat, which sees you giving orders in slow motion. They're calling it "deep" but going by trailers, it's a bit of a scrum. Still, there's the threat of character permadeath to keep you on your toes.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2526570/Band_of_Crusaders/">Read more about Band Of Crusaders on Steam</a>. It doesn't have an exact release date yet. Developers Virtual Alchemy are a new indie studio from Warsaw, Poland, whose ranks include former CD Projekt and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/war-hospital">War Hospital</a> staff (nobody senior, going by their<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/virtual-alchemy/people/"> LinkedIn page</a>).</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Sells 3.5 Million Units Within the First Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year.1058880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-sells-3-5-million-units-within-the-first-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-73632">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The official Balatro <a href="https://x.com/BalatroGame/status/1866905061609078866" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter) revealed that the poker-inspired roguelike deck builder game had sold 3.5 million units.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developed by LocalThunk and published by Playstack, Balatro has hit the 3.5 million units sold milestone within its first year of release. In this game, you use unique Joker cards to combine them with valid poker hands to create new possibilities. The title is available on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch, and PC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Balatro has also introduced several collaborations over the years, featuring unique cards from popular games like Cyberpunk 2077, Among Us, The Witcher, Stardew Valley, and more. Recently, CD Projekt Red repaid the favour by adding a Balatro-themed side quest to Cyberpunk 2077 in its recently released <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077s-update-2-2-includes-hidden-balatro-quest/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">update 2.2</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Balatro has managed to generate close to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-has-generated-approximately-4-4-million-on-mobile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$4.4 million on its mobile version</a>. Also, the developers have promised a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-hits-2-million-units-sold-major-gameplay-update-coming-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major gameplay update in 2025</a>. What are your thoughts on Balatro selling 3.5 million units?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-has-confirmed-their-intent-to-acquire-kadokawa-group/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony confirming their intentions to acquire FromSoftware parent company, Kadokawa Group</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-has-confirmed-their-intent-to-acquire-kadokawa-group/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-has-confirmed-their-intent-to-acquire-kadokawa-group/">Sony Has Confirmed Their Intent to Acquire Kadokawa Group&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has officially confirmed their intent to acquire FromSoftware’s parent company, Kadokawa Group. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bend-studio-live-serivce-images/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bend-studio-live-serivce-images/">Early Images of Bend Studio’s Potential Next Game Reveal a Brand New Live-Service IP</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Early images of what could be a new live-service IP by Bend Studio’s have been posted online.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-trailer/">Mafia The Old Country Trailer Leaks Online, Releasing Summer 2025</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A trailer for Mafia: The Old Country has leaked online, revealing that the game will be released in Summer 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/">Day Of The Devs 2024 Game Awards Edition: Every Game Shown</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Devolver Digital held its Day of the Devs: Game Awards Edition 2024, and with it came a look at 19 upcoming indie games.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Has a 'Canon Mode' That Makes Every Dialogue Decision For You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-has-a-canon-mode-that-makes-every-dialogue-decision-for-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-has-a-canon-mode-that-makes-every-dialogue-decision-for-you.1058877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-has-a-canon-mode-that-makes-every-dialogue-decision-for-you<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> features a Canon Mode that makes every dialogue decision for the player instead of having them choose, Ubisoft has revealed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Creative director Jonathan Dumont was asked by a fan on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1hbq6qg/comment/m1jc9mj/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> how much weight player choices have in Assassin's Creed Shadows. "Choices come more into play when recruiting allies and romancing some of the characters," Dumont said, before revealing the ability to remove these choices altogether.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Since the fanbase is divided on branching dialogues, we have incorporated an option called Canon Mode which allows you to play the game with choices already made for you, to give you a choice free experience," he added. "Hope this makes it fun for everyone."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Role-playing games have long included dialogue options that allow players to shape the story, but Assassin's Creed picked up branching dialogue when it shifted to a full-on RPG series with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/10/26/assassins-creed-origins-review">Assassin's Creed Origins.</a> Clearly, some fans preferred more concrete stories like that of Ezio's in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/03/12/assassins-creed-ii-review">Assassin's Creed 2</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mainline Assassin's Creed Games in Chronological Order</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft will therefore hope fans of both options will pick up Assassin's Creed Shadows, which could be the most important entry in the franchise's history. Not only does it have a lot riding on it as the long-awaited Feudal Japan-set entry and the first full Assassin's Creed since 2020, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-shares-take-a-hit-as-analysts-predict-lower-than-expected-star-wars-outlaws-sales">a struggling Ubisoft needs it to perform well</a> following recent flops.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's not enjoyed a particularly positive promotional period so far, however. Issues began as some fans expressed frustration with inaccuracies in the game's depiction of Japan, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-team-issues-apology-to-japanese-fans-for-marketing-that-has-caused-concern">leading the development team to issue an apology</a> and say the game is not intended to be a factual representation of history but instead "a compelling, historical fiction." This comes despite art director Thierry Dansereau telling IGN that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-inside-ubisofts-ambitious-open-world-japan">Ubisoft looked to make Shadows as "authentic as possible to match historical events"</a> just two months prior.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Concern was also raised when <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-apologizes-to-japanese-historical-re-enactment-group-for-using-its-flag-in-assassins-creed-shadows-art-without-permission">the developer used a flag from a Japanese historical re-enactment group</a> in artwork for Assassin's Creed Shadows without permission. Ubisoft apologized for doing so but refused to remove the artwork from the aforementioned and presumably already printed artbook available in the Collector's Edition. The historical re-enactment group said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-apology-for-using-historical-re-enactment-group-flag-in-assassins-creed-shadows-not-enough-group-says">this was not good enough</a>, but Ubisoft hasn't publicly acknowledged it since.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Yet another controversy came as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-figure-removed-from-sale-over-insensitive-design">collectible figure maker PureArts removed an Assassin's Creed Shadows statue from sale</a> over its "insensitive" design.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans are also frustrated by the delay to the game, as Assassin's Creed Shadows, which was originally <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-to-february-2025">due out in November before being pushed to February 14</a>. This puts Assassin's Creed Shadows in more direct competition with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-2-confirmed-as-ghost-of-yotei-at-state-of-play-releasing-2025">PlayStation's Ghost of Tsushima sequel, Ghost of Yotei</a>, another 2025 open-world action adventure game set in Feudal Japan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-delay-ghost-of-yotei-ubisoft">Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot maintained confidence</a>, however. "There's a lot of space for very high-quality games, and those two games can sell very well," he said in the company's latest earnings call. "The focus is to really make sure that we deliver a fantastic experience with this dual protagonist approach and two different and complimentary gameplays."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famitsu Sales: 12/2/24 – 12/8/24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/famitsu-sales-12-2-24-12-8-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famitsu-sales-12-2-24-%E2%80%93-12-8-24.1058874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/famitsu-sales-12-2-24-12-8-24<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Super Mario Party Jamboree back on top once again.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202412/27277" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Famitsu</a> has published its estimated physical game software data for Japan for the week of December 2, 2024 to December 8, 2024. <span id="more-933148"></span></p><p>On the hardware side, the <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,430 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> family sold 80,428 units, the <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,522 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> family sold 46,450 units, the <a title="Platforms > Xbox [25,200 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Series family sold 1,607 units, and the <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,525 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> family sold 52 units.</p><p>Get the full sales charts below.</p><p><strong>Software Sales</strong> (followed by lifetime sales)</p><ol><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Mario Party Jamboree [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-mario-party-jamboree">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a></em> (<a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>, 10/17/24) – 73,087 (605,726)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,321 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, 11/14/24) – 58,741 (801,659)</li><li>[NSW] <em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em> (Nintendo, 04/28/17) – 18,924 (6,096,622)</li><li>[NSW] <em>Minecraft</em> (Microsoft, 06/21/18) – 12,641 (3,703,555)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mario-luigi-brothership">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a></em> (Nintendo, 11/07/24) – 11,341 (111,250)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Animal Crossing: New Horizons [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/animal-crossing-new-horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a></em> (Nintendo, 03/20/20) – 11,072 (7,979,244)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a></em> (Nintendo, 09/26/24) – 10,750 (323,504)</li><li>[NSW] <em>Hone Hone Zaurus X Chou Gattai! Build &amp; Battle</em> (<a title="Companies > Nippon Columbia [62 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-columbia">Nippon Columbia</a>, 12/05/24) – 10,393 <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Smash Bros. Ultimate [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-smash-bros-ultimate">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a></em> (Nintendo, 12/07/18) – 9,248 (5,636,573)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > FANTASIAN Neo Dimension [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fantasian-neo-dimension">FANTASIAN Neo Dimension</a></em> (Square Enix, 12/05/24) – 9,078 <strong>(New)</strong></li></ol><p>Rankings 11 to 30 will be announced on December 13.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ol><li>[PS5] <em>FANTASIAN Neo Dimension</em> (Square Enix, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Fitness Boxing 3: Your Personal Trainer [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fitness-boxing-3-your-personal-trainer">Fitness Boxing 3: Your Personal Trainer</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Imagineer [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/imagineer">Imagineer</a>, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Harry Potter: Quidditch Champions [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/harry-potter-quidditch-champions">Harry Potter: Quidditch Champions</a></em> (<a title="Companies > SEGA [2,633 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Himitsu no AiPri: Atsumete! Secret Memories [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/himitsu-no-aipri-atsumete-secret-memories">Himitsu no AiPri: Atsumete! Secret Memories</a></em> (Nippon Columbia, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[PS5] <em><a title="Games > Pacific Drive [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pacific-drive">Pacific Drive</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Teyon [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/teyon">Teyon</a> Japan, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Stella of The End [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/stella-of-the-end">Stella of The End</a></em> (<a title="Companies > PROTOTYPE [110 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/prototype">PROTOTYPE</a>, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Under Defeat (2024) [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/under-defeat-2024">Under Defeat</a></em> (<a title="Companies > City Connection [181 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/city-connection">City Connection</a>, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[PS5] <em>Under Defeat</em> (City Connection, 12/05/24) – <strong>(New)</strong></li><li>[PS5] <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> (Square Enix, 11/14/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Momotaro Dentetsu World: Chikyuu wa Kibou de Mawatteru! [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/momotaro-dentetsu-world-chikyuu-wa-kibou-de-mawatteru">Momotaro Dentetsu World: Chikyuu wa Kibou de Mawatteru!</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,095 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a>, 11/16/23) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Ring Fit <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></em> (Nintendo, 10/18/19) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > The Exit 8 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-exit-8">The Exit 8</a></em> / <em><a title="Games > Platform 8 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/platform-8">Platform 8</a></em> (<a title="Companies > PLAYISM [285 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a>, 11/28/24) –</li><li>[NSW] Hakoniwa Kaitaku <a title="Companies > Hamster Corporation [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hamster-corporation">Hamster</a> to Taiyou no Sato (<a title="Companies > SUCCESS Corporation [95 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/success-corporation">SUCCESS Corporation</a>, 11/28/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <a title="Games > Madou Monogatari: Fia and the Mysterious School [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/madou-monogatari-fia-and-the-mysterious-school">Madou Monogatari: Fia and the Mysterious School</a> (<a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,201 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a>, 11/28/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Romancing SaGa: Revenge of the Seven</em> (Square Enix, 10/24/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Mario RPG [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-mario-rpg">Super Mario RPG</a></em> (Nintendo, 11/17/23) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival">Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,611 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a>, 09/22/22) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Disney Music Parade: Encore [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/disney-music-parade-encore">Disney Music Parade: Encore</a></em> (Imagineer, 11/21/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Bang! Bang! Bandits" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bang-bang-bandits">Bang! Bang! Bandits</a></em> (Nippon Columbia, 11/28/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Luigi’s Mansion 3</em> (Nintendo, 10/31/19) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Mario Bros. Wonder [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-mario-bros-wonder">Super Mario Bros. Wonder</a></em> (Nintendo, 10/20/23) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025 [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/powerful-pro-baseball-2024-2025">Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025</a></em> (Konami, 07/18/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>irem Collection Vol. 2</em> (Tozai Games, 11/28/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2</em> Special Price (SEGA, 11/17/22) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Pikmin 4 [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pikmin-4">Pikmin 4</a></em> (Nintendo, 07/21/23) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Momotaro Dentetsu: Showa, Heisei, Reiwa mo Teiban! [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/momotaro-dentetsu-showa-heisei-reiwa-mo-teiban">Momotaro Dentetsu: Showa, Heisei, Reiwa mo Teiban!</a></em> (Konami, 11/19/20) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Splatoon 3 [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/splatoon-3">Splatoon 3</a></em> (Nintendo, 09/09/22) –</li><li>[PS5] <em><a title="Games > Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Activision [62 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/activision">Activision</a>, 10/25/24) –</li></ol><p><strong>Hardware Sales</strong> (followed by lifetime sales)</p><ol><li>Switch OLED Model – 47,464 (8,365,460)</li><li>PlayStation 5 – 39,920 (5,342,900)</li><li>Switch Lite – 21,012 (6,274,705)</li><li>Switch – 11,952 (19,975,513)</li><li>PlayStation 5 Digital Edition – 6,530 (889,921)</li><li>PlayStation 5 Pro – 3,915 (112,831)</li><li><a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X</a> – 1,399 (313,365)</li><li>Xbox Series X Digital Edition – 990 (11,112)</li><li>Xbox Series S – 617 (326,761)</li><li>PlayStation 4 – 52 (7,928,936)</li></ol></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arma Reforger now available for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/arma-reforger-now-available-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arma-reforger-now-available-for-ps5.1058871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/arma-reforger-now-available-for-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Previously released for Xbox Series and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bohemia Interactive [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bohemia-interactive">Bohemia Interactive</a> has released Cold War-set <a title="Genres > Open-World [531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> multiplayer <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,576 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Arma Reforger [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/arma-reforger">Arma Reforger</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,522 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10010198" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a> for $39.99, the developer announced. <span id="more-930315"></span></p><p><em>Arma Reforger</em> first launched in Early Access for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1874880/Arma_Reforger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on May 17, 2022, followed by a full release on November 16, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10010198" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Arma Reforger</em> introduces tactical, combined arms, military simulator gameplay to <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,600 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a>. The unparalleled sandbox capabilities of the <em>Arma Platform</em> allow you to engage in immersive operations and create your own scenarios, opening an entirely new world of possibilities for the PlayStation community.</p><p>Powered by the new Enfusion engine, Arma Reforger enlists you in the fight for two incredible islands, spanning a total of 61 km², in an authentic Cold War setting. Battle it out in the Conflict <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [424 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer game</a> mode, or create your own scenarios in Game <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter, a real-time editor where anything can happen.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Arma Reforger</em> is the first ever <em>Arma</em> installment on PlayStation, offering a versatile and creative platform that redefines the mil-sim genre.</p><p><b>Key Features</b></p><ul><li><strong>Everon</strong> – Return to Everon, a 51 km² mid-Atlantic island in the Malden archipelago. Revisit familiar locales from Operation Flashpoint and revel in the natural beauty of a massive open world; a stunning landscape of pine and broadleaf forests, flowing rivers, ponds, idyllic towns, and austere mountains, surrounded by pebble beaches and rocky coastlines.</li><li><strong>Arland</strong> – Capture new ground and explore the remote, overseas territory of Arland; a small, 10 km² island belonging to the microstate of Everon. Situated with its mother state in the mid-Atlantic, it occupies a strategic Cold War faultline and is well-known for its military airbase, leased to the Soviet Union.</li><li><strong>Conflict</strong> – Join players online and experience realistic Cold War combat as a US or Soviet Army soldier. Capture strategic positions, dominate the battlefield, and work with others to secure objectives in a dynamic, unforgiving environment. With a selection of period-authentic weapons and vehicles, recreated in meticulous detail, <em>Arma Reforger</em>‘s multiplayer game mode returns you to war.</li><li><strong>Game Master</strong> – Control events, create unique missions, and guide players towards victory in Game Master—or submit yourself to the challenges devised by all-powerful creators and fight your way through a responsive sandbox where anything can happen.</li><li><strong>Combat Ops</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> <a title="Genres > Co-Op [220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">co-op</a>erative gameplay and dynamic objectives with Combat Ops; a new game mode focusing on small-team tactics. In Combat Ops Arland, infiltrate the island as an elite US unit: strike hard, strike fast, and reach the extraction point. In Combat Ops Everon, join the FIA resistance faction and engage in guerrilla operations to take back your home island.</li><li><strong>Capture and Hold</strong> – Battle it out against an enemy faction to hold key points in fast-paced, tactical gameplay. Capture and Hold is a rapid-fire, high-pressure game mode that concentrates the immersive and realistic gameplay of Arma Reforger into short and intense matches.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Arma Reforger - OUT NOW on PlayStation 5!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-JsDfd_oMvw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Plucky Squire adds Streamlined Mode for "those who don't need as much hand-holding"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-adds-streamlined-mode-for-those-who-dont-need-as-much-hand-holding</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-plucky-squire-adds-streamlined-mode-for-those-who-dont-need-as-much-hand-holding.1058868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-adds-streamlined-mode-for-those-who-dont-need-as-much-hand-holding<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_Yzrq05I.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Devolver Digital</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Enjoyable picture book adventure The Plucky Squire is adding a Streamlined Mode in response to feedback around the game's difficulty and overly-chatty characters.
</p>
<p>
This option is available now via a free update on PC and is coming soon to Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S.
</p>
<p>
Changes for Streamlined Mode include "trims" to "less necessary dialogue", of which there is plenty. I enjoyed my time with The Plucky Squire, but its dialogue was overly verbose - to the point I ended up speeding through it as much as possible. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Plucky Squire | Launch Trailer | Out Now!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xREgLxEzZE4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Plucky Squire | Launch Trailer | Out Now!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xREgLxEzZE4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xREgLxEzZE4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The launch trailer for The Plucky Squire.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xREgLxEzZE4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Other alterations will see the game remove or reduce camera hints, tutorial content, and moments where control of the game is taken away from players. 
</p>
<p>
All of these sound like smart changes and, while I doubt I'll go back for a second playthrough, will very likely improve the experiences of anyone still yet to experience The Plucky Squire afresh.
</p>
<p>
"The game is a victim of its own delights, perhaps: there's so much invention here that the repetition stands out all the more," our Christian Donlan wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-review-the-power-of-imagination">Eurogamer's The Plucky Squire review</a>. 
</p>
<p>
"There's also a handful of pacing issues, not least that the game has a habit of interrupting its own flow to explain things. I think this comes from the game having to balance two audiences - kids and adults - but there are still a few too many unskippable conversations when even younger players will want to just get on with things."
</p>
<p>
These issues aside, The Plucky Squire is still one of the most inventive games I've played this year - and now it sounds like it'll be even better. If you get the oppurtunity, do give it try.
</p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>