<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 12:14:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Starbites for PS5, Xbox Series, and Switch launches October 16 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/the-starbites-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-launches-october-16-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-starbites-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-launches-october-16-in-japan.1245783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Physical edition available for PlayStation 5 and Switch.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Science-fiction <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [1,226 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > The Starbites [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-starbites">The Starbites</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,913 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,348 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on October 16 in Japan for 6,380 yen, publisher <a title="Companies > Happinet Corporation [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/happinet-corporation">Happinet</a> and developer <a title="Companies > IKINAGAMES [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ikinagames">IKINAGAMES</a> announced. Physical editions will be available for PlayStation 5 and Switch. <span id="more-978992"></span></p><p>A western and PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2199080/THE_STARBITES/" target="_blank">Steam</a>) release is also planned, but IKINAGAMES told <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> that the announced release date is only for the console versions in Japan. Release timing for the west and PC will be announced at a later date.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via IKINAGAMES:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>The Starbites</em> is a classic science-fiction <a title="Genres > RPG [17,421 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> set in a futuristic space era. The planet BITTER has been ravaged by the aftermath of a galactic war, but Lukida, the protagonist, and her friends live a bright and cheerful life in Delight City, their only sanctuary. A journey into a cheerful dystopia, but the secrets hidden on planet BITTER and the thrilling mech battles are anything but lighthearted.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Planet BITTER: Traces of Destruction and Unknown Worlds</strong> – BITTER was once a vacation destination and a thriving hub of agriculture and trade. Though devastated by the massive energy released from fallen spaceships during the galactic war, remnants of its glorious past can still be found. As you explore the planet’s backstory and traverse the map, you may discover treasures crafted by its advanced technologies!</li><li><strong>Mechs: Companions of <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,402 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> and Avatars of the Protagonists</strong> – Mechs are tools for exploring the desolate planet and companions in battle. Each mech has a unique appearance that reflects the personality and traits of its pilot, with their roles in combat also being carefully detailed. How you develop your mech and customize its appearance is entirely up to you.</li><li><strong>Battles: Strategic and Spectacular Turn-Based Combat</strong> – <em>The Starbites</em>‘ battles are based on a traditional turn-based system, enhanced with various mechanics to boost speed, impact, and strategy. Utilize the mechs’ unique characteristics to exploit enemy weaknesses, minimize damage to allies, and, with the special “Driver’s High” ability and powerful “Support System” team attack, turn the tide of battle in an instant. The thrill of seeing your strategic choices come to life in dynamic and spectacular battle sequences is at the heart of <em>The Starbites</em>‘ turn-based combat.</li><li><strong>And the Story: A Grand Epic Told Through Cinematic Movies</strong> – Lukida, born on the ruined planet BITTER and raised amidst its desert sands, has no memories of the galactic war or the once-glorious BITTER. Her journey begins with a single resolve: “I will escape this hopeless planet.” But fate will not allow her to leave BITTER so easily. With over 50 high-quality cinematic movies, Lukida’s journey invites you to uncover the secrets of BITTER and the massive story behind the galactic war.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「STARBITES」トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FXsumppmlVw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/the-starbites-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-launches-october-16-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>