<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 19:38:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Tides demo launches February 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24.1101141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/demon-tides-demo-launches-february-24<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Save data can be carried over to the full game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Fabraz [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fabraz">Fabraz</a> will release a demo for <a title="Genres > Open-World [560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> 3D platformer <em><a title="Games > Demon Tides [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-tides">Demon Tides</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3477260/Demon_Tides_Demo/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 24 as part of Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition, the developer announced. <span id="more-942420"></span></p><p>The demo includes the beginning of the story, the tutorial, and a small part the open world for players to explore. This includes several levels, challenges, and gear to collect. The in-game leaderboard is also present, and save data from the demo will carry over to the full game when it launches in 2025.</p><p>Here is an overview of the demo, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3477260/Demon_Tides_Demo/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Welcome to the Demo</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the beginning of the game to get your appetite wet for the full game! Your save data will carry over into the main game. You can also directly compete with other players using the demo’s leaderboards.</p><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Follow Beebz and her crew on a journey of self-discovery as they travel the vast oceans of Ragnar’s Rock.</p><p>Navigate the open seas and explore each distant structure, uncovering every hidden nook and cranny with your diverse, expressive move-set. Beat challenges or find hidden chests to collect talismans along the way that modify and even expand your abilities or switch up your drip with a plethora of discoverable outfits!</p><p>And never forget, you’re not alone in this journey! Compete with other players for speedrunning times by challenging their ghosts or tag a wall and share your message in the form of graffiti with the entire world!</p><p>Are you ready to conquer this kingdom and expose all of its mysterious secrets? Or will Beebz be crushed by what awaits her… Only one way to find out!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A deeply expressive platforming move-set that enables you to travel through the world in countless unique ways. Express yourself through your schmovement and get lost in the flow!</li><li>Travel the seamless, open ocean and reach any point of interest at blazing speeds! Explore each locale and figure out creative ways to beat challenges or reach certain areas!</li><li>Hang out on your mobile hub, the Floating Fashionista, to chill with your crew or buy new items of interest!</li><li>Discover hidden secrets and use context clues to unravel this world’s mysteries alongside the main story told through major, cinematic story events!</li><li>Place your own checkpoints wherever you want and return to them any time you meet your untimely demise.</li><li>Collect over 50 unique talismans that uniquely modify or add to your move-set! Get a paraglider to soar the skies, spawn a bubble to float in place indefinitely, change your spin form into a hookshot and so much more!</li><li><a title="Companies > ACQUIRE [341 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/acquire">Acquire</a> a ton of unique head gear, outfits and hair dyes to change up your appearance! With over 50,000 possible combinations there’s no shortage of drip.</li><li>Compete for the best completion times of each locale by <a title="Genres > Racing [224 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> other player’s ghosts! Get notified if your ghost was beaten to challenge them right back, may the best runner win!</li><li>Create and share graffiti that will appear in other player’s worlds! Make something pretty, hint towards a secret nearby or troll the players with lies you little rascal!</li></ul><p><strong>Frequently Asked <a title="Companies > Question [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/question">Question</a>s</strong></p><ul><li><strong>How long is the demo?</strong><ul><li>The demo includes the beginning of the story, the tutorial as well as a small part of the open world for you to explore and platform in! This includes several levels, challenges and gear to collect! Additionally you can also compete for completion times with the in-game leaderboard and even race other people’s ghosts!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Is this a sequel to <em><a title="Games > Demon Turf [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-turf">Demon Turf</a></em> and do you need to play it before playing <em>Demon Tides</em>?</strong><ul><li>You can definitely play <em>Demon Tides</em> without ever having played <em>Demon Turf</em> before! In fact, we encourage new players to jump right into <em>Demon Tides</em>! It takes place after <em>Demon Turf</em>‘s story but is designed for new players to jump right in with a brand new narrative and world to explore. Any backstory is carefully reintroduced while returning players will notice plenty of fun references harkening back to <em>Demon Turf</em>.</li></ul></li><li><strong>What does “Expressive” platforming mean, exactly?</strong><ul><li>A platformer with a lot of combinatorial depth, allowing you to express yourself through the game’s movement. Meaning a gap can be crossed in a multitude of creative ways!</li><li>We’re pushing the concept of this subgenre to new limits with an incredibly deep, combinatorial move-set that can even be heavily customized! The further you get into the game, and the more comfortable you get with the movement, the more unique your gameplay will end up looking to others!</li></ul></li><li><strong>What’s Fabraz done before <em>Demon Tides</em>?</strong><ul><li>We’re most well known for the 3D <a title="Genres > Platformer [607 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">Platformer</a> <em>Demon Turf</em> and 2D platformer <em>Slime-san</em>! But we’re also behind lesser known titles such as <em>Cannon Crasha</em>, <em>Planet Diver</em>, and even acted as publisher for friends on two games called <em>Skellboy</em> and <em>SpiritSphere DX</em>!</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Demo Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Demon Tides - Demo Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j46GGr-8nz0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind] launches March 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind-launches-march-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rendering-ranger-r%C2%B2-rewind-launches-march-20.1101072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind-launches-march-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind] [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind">Rendering Ranger: R² [Rewind]</a> will launch digitally for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,767 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,656 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2167260/Rendering_Ranger_R2_Rewind/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/rendering_ranger_r_rewind" target="_blank">GOG</a> on March 20, publisher <a title="Companies > Ziggurat Interactive [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ziggurat-interactive">Ziggurat Interactive</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Limited Run Games [199 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limited-run-games">Limited Run Games</a> and Rainbow Arts announced. Physical standard and “Armageddon” editions will also be available for pre-order via <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/collections/rendering-ranger-r2-rewind" target="_blank">Limited Run Games</a> from February 14 to March 16. <span id="more-942416"></span></em></p><p><em>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2167260/Rendering_Ranger_R2_Rewind/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</em></p><blockquote><p><em><strong>About</strong></em></p><p><em>The legendary <a title="Platforms > SNES" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/snes">Super Famicom</a> cult classic is back.</em></p><p><em>Developed by Manfred Trenz (creator of the <em>Turrican</em> series) and published by German software powerhouse Rainbow Arts, this game was originally released in 1995. Originally slated to come to the West as Targa, the game ultimately ended up as a Japan-only title, with only 10,000 copies printed, making it one of the most sought-after collectibles in retro gaming.</em></p><p><em>You are the Rendering Ranger known as Double R, a special forces soldier who must defend the Earth from a devastating alien invasion. Through nine levels of <a title="Genres > Action [2,463 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> platforming as well as blisteringly fast horizontal <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,992 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> stages, Rendering Ranger: R² is one of the greatest technological showcases ever seen on the Super <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,418 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>!</em></p><!-- AD: content --><em>
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Faithful emulation of <em>Rendering Ranger: R²</em> and its unreleased PAL version Targa with rewind and save features.</li><li>Gut-wrenching <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [891 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> action with sprawling stage design and cinematic presentation.</li><li>Mind-blowingly fast horizontal shooting stages unlike any seen before on Super Nintendo.</li><li>Upgradable weapons, tons of enemies, dynamic on-scene mayhem at nearly every turn.</li><li>Gigantic bosses in <a title="Companies > sprite [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sprite">sprite</a>s converted from pre-rendered 3D models.</li><li>Timeless 16-bit action at its best from legendary game creator Manfred Trenz.</li></ul></em></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Interactive Entertainment to integrate subsidiary SN Systems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems.1101012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-integrate-subsidiary-sn-systems<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>A provider of programming tools for PlayStation developers.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,950 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> will integrate wholly owned subsidiary SN Systems, a developer of programming tools for game creators on <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,856 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> consoles, as one unified company on April 1, the company <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/sony-interactive-entertainment-announces-the-integration-of-wholly-owned-subsidiary-sn-systems/" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-942412"></span></p><p>SN Systems was founded in 1990 and acquired by Sony Interactive Entertainment, then Sony Computer Entertainment, in 2005. Since then, it has collaborated closely with Sony Interactive Entertainment to create software development kits and tools for <a title="Platforms > PS3 [15,622 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps3">PlayStation 3</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS Vita [7,378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vita">PS Vita</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,656 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,767 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>.</p><p>“The exceptionally talented team at SN Systems has been an integral part of Sony Interactive Entertainment by driving innovation in tools development, which has been central to our success across multiple PlayStation generations,” said Sony Interactive Entertainment Platform Business Group CEO Hideaki Nishino in a press release “This next step in our partnership will strengthen our shared sense of unity. Together, we look forward to continuing to empower developers to create compelling gaming experiences for PlayStation players.”</p><p>According to Sony Interactive Entertainment, the integration of SN Systems will “drive further innovation and creativity for PlayStation products and services,” while also enhancing operational efficiencies.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>