<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:54:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devolver Digital and Francis Coulombe announce pixel art survival horror RPG Look Outside for PC, now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/devolver-digital-and-francis-coulombe-announce-pixel-art-survival-horror-rpg-look-outside-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devolver-digital-and-francis-coulombe-announce-pixel-art-survival-horror-rpg-look-outside-for-pc-now-available.1141404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/devolver-digital-and-francis-coulombe-announce-pixel-art-survival-horror-rpg-look-outside-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Or maybe don't look outside.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Devolver Digital [394 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital">Devolver Digital</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Francis Coulombe" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/francis-coulombe">Francis Coulombe</a> have announced pixel art survival horror <a title="Genres > RPG [17,074 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Look Outside [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/look-outside">Look Outside</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,667 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3373660/Look_Outside/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It is available now for $9.99. <span id="more-951815"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3373660/Look_Outside/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Look Outside</em> is a survival horror RPG set in a single apartment building. A mysterious event turns anyone who looks out the window into grotesque monsters, leaving the world in absolute chaos. Scavenge the building to seek food, supplies, and weapons while encountering strange characters—human and otherwise.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Survival [393 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> <a title="Genres > Horror [580 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">Horror</a> and Resource <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">Management</a></strong> – Plan tense expeditions outside your apartment as you fend off grotesque monsters dwelling in and around your building. Return to your home with gathered resources and partial answers to your questions to recuperate by playing games, making dinner, <a title="Genres > Crafting [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> tools, and getting to know your neighbors turned allies.</li><li><strong>Inventive Turn-Based Combat</strong> – Clash with over 150 hand-crafted creatures in turn-based combat that accounts for space between you and your foes as you wield makeshift weapons and items you’ve gathered in the corridors of the building.</li><li><strong>Impeccable Body Horror Aesthetic</strong> – Meet your macabre fate in a bizarre world teeming with an unconventional and occasionally psychotic cast of characters – some of which you can recruit and offer safe harbor in your apartment as the mystery unravels.</li><li><strong>Small, Experimental, and Unwaveringly Weird</strong> – Offering three to six hours of playtime with a dozen boss encounters, friends to recruit, and visitors to invite back to your home, <em>Look Outside</em> offers different experiences for every player on their way to uncover several different endings.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/look-outside/march-21-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Look Outside - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ROR6tH8ed1I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_951825"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma interview with producer Hisashi Fujii – setting, village building, romance, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-interview-with-producer-hisashi-fujii-setting-village-building-romance-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-interview-with-producer-hisashi-fujii-%E2%80%93-setting-village-building-romance-and-more.1141308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-interview-with-producer-hisashi-fujii-setting-village-building-romance-and-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> recently had the opportunity to sit down with <em><a title="Games > Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a></em> producer Hisashi Fujii ahead of the game’s launch in May to discuss what players can expect in the Eastern-inspired entry in the farming <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> franchise. <span id="more-950904"></span></p><p>Get the full interview below.</p><p><strong><em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em> has a noticeably different tone and setting compared to previous <em><a title="Series > Rune Factory [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/rune-factory">Rune Factory</a></em> games. What inspired the shift to a more Eastern-inspired world?</strong></p><p><strong>Hisashi Fujii, Producer:</strong> “As you know, up until now the <em>Rune Factory</em> series was set on a Western continent. And previously in the series there have been several references to the Eastern country, and several characters from the Eastern country who would make appearances in the games. One of the reasons we set <em>Guardians of Azuma</em> in this Eastern country is to have a new approach to the series outside of the numbered titles—basically to try a new approach and new gameplay elements that we wouldn’t necessarily do in the numbered titles. So that’s the main reason why we decided to set <em>Guardians of Azuma</em> in the Eastern country of Azuma.”</p><p><strong>With this game, you are introducing the concept of the Earth Dancer. How did the idea of using dance as a combat and purification mechanic come about?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “With the move to the Eastern country as the setting, we wanted to emphasize the Japanese-ness of the world—the ‘Wa.’ And part of that was introducing a traditional Japanese dance style into the gameplay, so that includes the <a title="Genres > Action [2,588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and other parts of the gameplay as you mentioned. That was the main impetus for the focus on dance in this title.”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>The village rebuilding system is something entirely new for&nbsp;<em>Guardians of Azuma</em>. Can you talk a bit about that—how large it is, what types of building features players can expect?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “There are four villages in the game based around the four seasons, and in each village there’s an area that you can completely and freely edit using the village building system. And the areas actually differ depending on the village. So the Autumn Village has the largest area, and we think that players will actually have difficulty potentially even filling it in—it’s so massive. This gameplay feature itself is something that’s fairly new to the series—it’s really never been done before. And one of the ways it changes the gameplay is that, by revitalizing the villages over the course of the game, you’ll attract more villagers to come to the villages. And those villagers can be assigned tasks in the edit area, such as farming or collecting lumber. And so in some ways the player basically no longer has to do that kind of work if they don’t want to, which can change the gameplay cycle if that’s not where you’re focusing as a player.”</p><p><strong>Do different setups offer different benefits or change the way NPCs interact, or does customization mostly fall into the category of aesthetics?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “Basically, the choices that the player makes in the village building area, depending on what they place down—such as buildings or decorations—can impact their basic stats. So if you place a certain building, you may get a certain stat increase. There are still the typical stats that have been in the series up until now—things like HP, Rune Points, strength, and magic attack—and the choices that the player makes when customizing their village can be used to essentially level up these parameters.”</p><p><strong>Are the villages different in terms of gameplay? Do they have their own farming mechanics, enemies, and event types?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “As I mentioned, there are the four seasonal villages. Each village has plants that you can grow that are characteristic of that village. So if it’s the Spring Village, spring plants and spring flowers are more suited to growth in that village. And of course the enemies outside of each village are also themed around the villages, so they do differ depending on which village you’re in. In terms of gameplay differences, there are certain objects that you can place in the village building mode that will only have an effect on the player—like a positive effect—if they’re placed in a certain village. If you place something in the Winter Village, it will give you a specific effect that you wouldn’t get by placing it in the Spring Village. Finally, each village has its own seasonally themed special festivals that you can hold.”</p><p><strong>The Blight appears to be the main threat standing in the player’s way. Is it a persistent threat that players have to manage over time, or is it something tackled through progression?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “The Blight is something spread by the Black Dragon that appears in the game. And as it’s spread, it affects the earth, causing plants to wither and impacting the natural world. The player will receive what are known as Sacred <a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a>s from the gods in the game, and those Sacred Treasures can be used to purify the Blight and remove it from the world. At the beginning of the game, they’ll only be able to get rid of certain kinds of Blight from the world. And then as they receive more Sacred Treasures, the kinds of Blight they can purify and how far they can progress in the game will expand.”</p><p><strong>Do Sacred Treasures only function as key items? Or do they work as traditional equipment that can be used during gameplay as well?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “Other than purifying the Blight, Sacred Treasures can be used in battle as well as in the farming gameplay as regular items. In battle, they replace what was previously the magic system. Basically, they can be used for very special attacks, depending on which one you’re using, as well as for very powerful attacks. When it comes to farming, they have different roles. For example, the Drum can be used to restore withered plants or encourage their growth. The Umbrella can be used to water plants, and to water a much wider range of space than would be normally possible. So they have a lot of benefits if you use them for farming.”</p><p><strong>Romance is always a core element of a <em>Rune Factory</em> game. Have there been any new mechanics or major changes to relationship building? </strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “Up until now, when you were trying to advance a romance with a character, pretty much all you could do was give them presents and say ‘Hi!’ to them every day. But in this game, we’ve added some new features to deepen those mechanics. You can choose conversation topics from a list of set topics, and different characters will respond differently to different topics. You can also invite them to do all sorts kinds of activities. And similarly, there are certain activities that will raise your affection level with some characters more than others. So there’s a lot more depth in the different kinds of interactions you can have with them this time.”</p><p><strong>Romance candidates can be recruited for battle. Can you talk a little bit about how that works? Does their combat effectiveness depend on how far into a relationship you are with them? And are you limited to just one romance candidate in battle?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “You have a bond level with each character in the game that’s developed as you talk to them more—typically as you grow closer to them. In battle, as the bond level increases, characters will learn new abilities and become more powerful as allies in battle, the closer you are with them. And being in battle with them also increases their bond level with you. So the more you battle with them, the higher their bond level will get, and the more skills they will learn. In total you can take up to six characters with you into battle, so you’re not limited if you’re dating one character, as that doesn’t mean you can’t bring the other romance candidates into battle. You can, again, recruit up to six—or seven if you’re including the player.”</p><p><strong>What does a post-marriage life look like? Does it unlock any special sorts of interactions or events?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “Once you marry, your spouse will come and live with you and there will be a rhythm to your life together. When you wake up each day, your spouse will have a bento ready for you and give it to you. And then, eventually, you will be able to have a child. So that’s pretty much the kind of main flow of the post-marriage life.”</p><p><strong>Before we go, which one aspect of the game are you most excited about players experiencing?</strong></p><p><strong>Fujii:</strong> “The main new feature of the game is village building, so I’m really excited to see what kinds of different villages players will make. Because they can make things that are totally different, so I’m just really looking forward to seeing what kinds of different villages are created in the game once it’s out!”</p><p><strong>Thank you so much for your time, Fujii-san!</strong></p><p><em>*Gematsu also asked for a status update on <em><a title="Games > Rune Factory 6 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rune-factory-6">Rune Factory 6</a></em>, which was <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2023/05/rune-factory-6-announced">announced</a> alongside <em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em> in 2023, as well as whether there are any plans to release <em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em> for PlayStation, Xbox, or <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,817 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> 2, but <a title="Companies > Marvelous [1,331 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous">Marvelous</a> was not able to provide any information beyond what has already been announced.</em></p><p><em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em> is due out for Switch and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,667 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2864560/Rune_Factory_Guardians_of_Azuma/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 30. </p><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma/march-21-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_951789"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>