<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:46:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romance visual novel LOVEPICAL-POPPY! coming to PS4, Switch on June 25 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/romance-visual-novel-lovepical-poppy-coming-to-ps4-switch-on-june-25-in-japan</link>
            <guid>1406626</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > AirVelocity" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/int/airvelocity">AirVelocity</a>, a new console games publishing brand under INT, will release <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> versions of <a title="Companies > Sony Music Entertainment Japan [285 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-music-entertainment-japan">SME</a>E-developed <a title="Genres > Romance Visual Novel [94 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/romance-visual-novel">romance visual novel</a> <em>LOVEPICAL-POPPY!</em> on June 25 in Japan, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/AirVerocity/status/2011694846642442344" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1019365"></span></p><p>The Switch version will be available both physically and digitally in 7,490 yen standard and 12,720 yen limited editions, while the PlayStation 4 version will be digital-only.</p><p><em>LOVEPICAL-POPPY!</em> first launched for PC on April 26, 2024 in Japan, followed by a global <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4041240/LOVEPICALPOPPY/" target="_blank">Steam</a> release on December 19, 2025.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4041240/LOVEPICALPOPPY/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>LOVEPICAL-POPPY!</em> is a sweet, comedic <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [644 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> from the beloved Japanese brand SMEE. In this game, you’ll find yourself surrounded by a charming cast of heroines, enjoying the delightful and hilarious moments of everyday life together.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This title features a talented team of SMEE’s best, with a story penned by Yakamoto Uto, Minase Takumi, Nanao Yuhi, and Nakajima Taiga. Hanamaru’s fresh and vibrant art style brings the characters to life, while the adorable chibi art from Ameno Ame adds a touch of lighthearted humor. Under the direction of Yakamoto Uto and production coordination of Asami Akira, the game achieves a perfect balance of character development, narrative progression, and audiovisual experience, offering players a deeply immersive story.</p><p>Note: The protagonist’s name can be changed.</p><p>Through a series of strange coincidences, Yaotome Tetsuya finds himself the new manager of an all-girls dormitory. He looks after the residents by <a title="Genres > Cooking [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking</a> their meals and tending to their daily needs, all while working a part-time job at the dorm’s attached crepe café. This charming café, located on the first floor to give the girls real-world experience, becomes a place where he shares the sweet and sour moments of work life alongside them in their cute uniforms.</p><p>His tireless efforts do not go unnoticed, and the heroines come to hold his kindness deep in their hearts. And when so many bright personalities live together under one roof, isn’t it inevitable that a single spark will ignite a flame?</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>On one fateful day, my apartment burns down.</p><p>My younger sister, Yaotome Suzuka, secures a room in Hoshikuzu Academy’s dormitory. As for me, I’m left unemployed and homeless. </p><p>Just when things look bleak, an unexpected opportunity appears: a job as the live-in dorm mother of the very same all-girls dormitory where my sister is staying! Room, board, and pay—there’s no reason to refuse! </p><p>But there’s a catch: I have to work at the crepe café next door as well. It’ll be a lot of work, sure, but I’m not about to turn it down! Plus, I’ll be watching over a group of distinct girls as their dorm mother… </p><p>The gorgeous, full-bodied girl who seems to know my past. My socially awkward younger sister who struggles with group life. The narcissist who craves the approval of others. The petite dorm president who hides a deep desire to be dependent. The pure-hearted, carefree gyaru who wears her heart on her sleeve. The mature older woman who has seen it all.</p><p>No problem! I’ll make sure to take good care of every single one of them!</p><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Omi Nozomi</strong> (voiced by Nekota Mike) – “Good morning, sunshiiine!” Nozomi is the perfect senpai, admired by everyone at Hoshikuzu Dormitory. <a title="Games > Beneath [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/beneath">Beneath</a> that polished exterior, though, lies a girl with an unshakable will and a secret she’s kept close to her heart: the dorm mother (ơ) changed her life when they were kids. Reunited under the same roof, her long-held gratitude transforms into something far more complicated… and she’s determined to use her courage-and her curves-to finally make him notice her.</li><li><strong>Yaotome Suzuka</strong> (voiced by Moriya Kokoro) – “You don’t need to baby me, Oniichan.” After losing her home in a fire, Suzuka is set to be separated from her beloved Oniichan as she moves into Hoshikuzu Dormitory. Luckily for her, however, the dorm gets a new mother (8) and it happens to be… her brother?! A sweet girl who’s also a bit of a brocon, Suzuka must learn to become independent and cope with her new environment. Will she learn to rely on her brother less, or will their bond grow ever stronger?</li><li><strong>Kinugawa Miu</strong> (voiced by Hazuki Hikari) – “Hey, do you really not know who I am?” Miucha is the hottest up-and-coming influencer on Inshta, hoping to inspire young girls everywhere. Behind the filters and followers, however, she’s secretly a needy, attention-starved brat with a fragile ego… and a burning desire to prove herself. The dorm mother (o) is entirely unimpressed with her antics. Can he knock some sense into her, or will they just drive each other insane?</li><li><strong>Kotobuki Tamaki</strong> (voiced by Hara Popoko) – “Perserverance is admirable and all, but try to take it easy.” Tamaki’s the perfect president for Hoshikuzu Dormitory. She’s diligent, well-mannered, and takes her responsibilities very seriously. However, due to her short stature and her babyface, many people treat her like a kid. She’d never admit it, but deep down, she doesn’t mind being spoiled… and the dorm mother (ơ) is ready to dole out some pampering.</li><li><strong>Okai Tanpopo</strong> (voiced by Tsukishiro Mahiru) – “Just sit back and chillax! Mamarin’s the pride of our cafe!” Tanpopo is a carefree gyaru at Hoshikuzu Dormitory with a personality as easygoing as her smile. She’s friendly with everyone, and a little bit silly, and doesn’t bother with formalities-especially not with the dorm mother (o), whom she’s dubbed “Mamarin.” Her innocent, spacey nature makes her impossible to hate, but when Mamarin starts indulging her whims, things start spiraling out of control. After all, once Tanpopo decides something’s “fun,” there’s no telling where she’ll take it next…</li><li><strong>Urushihara Ayako</strong> (voiced by Aono Musubi) – “We goody two-shoes are only good for being gears in the grander machine of society.” Ayako is the manager of Honey &amp; Beary, the cute café attached to Hoshikuzu Dormitory. She keeps everything running smoothly, including managing a gaggle of girls from the dorm. She’s sharp, capable, and endlessly dependable… until someone pushes the wrong button. Beneath all this, though, she’s vulnerable, and lately, a certain dorm mother (ơ) has caught her eye.</li></ul><p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p><ul><li>Become the dorm mother (male) of an all-girls dormitory.</li><li>Live together with a diverse cast of heroines and work with them at a crepe cafe.</li><li>Get to know each girl through heartwarming and hilarious daily interactions.</li><li>Unlock sweet romantic events and guide the story toward a happy ending with the one who captures your heart.</li><li>Get a unique perspective by viewing the girls’ thoughts.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the opening movie below. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.int-creative.com/air/lpp/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Opening Movie</span></h2><p><iframe title="【CS版】ラブピカルポッピー！ OPムービー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZgiQbN6nDA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/romance-visual-novel-lovepical-poppy-coming-to-ps4-switch-on-june-25-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yakuza Kiwami 3 & Dark Ties details LaLaLa Loveland, karaoke, Reapers, play spots, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties-details-lalala-loveland-karaoke-reapers-play-spots-and-more</link>
            <guid>1406590</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,730 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio [518 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/ryu-ga-gotoku-studio">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</a> have released new information and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties">Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties</a></em>, introducing more substories, LaLaLa Loveland, cell phone customization, karaoke, outfits, Reapers,  more Kanda’s Damage Control details, and play spots. <span id="more-1019303"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ <em><a title="Games > Yakuza Kiwami [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yakuza-kiwami">Yakuza Kiwami</a> 3</em></strong></p><p><strong>◆ Substories</strong></p><p><strong>A Star’s Debut at Stardust</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_001.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>When Stardust, a popular host club, faces a sudden staff shortage on the day a group from Hokkaido is scheduled to visit, Kiryu decides to lend a helping hand by stepping in as an impromptu host under the name Kazzy-chan. Watch as he dresses for the part, livens up conversations, and charms clients with his unconventional hospitality!</p><p><strong>Keep at It, Parents!</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Having found a dirty magazine on the beach, Kiryu decides to hide it from the children by burying it in the yard. However, Mame, the orphanage dog, digs it back up. When Mame runs off with it, it’s up to you to chase him down and maintain the peace of the orphanage!</p><p><strong>◆ LaLaLa Loveland</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_003.jpg"></a></figure><p>Make LaLaLa Friends through the red thread of fate transmission!</p><p>Kiryu’s phone is getting so old that it could catch fire at any moment. When he finally trades it in for a new model, Lala Aizawa—CEO of LaLaLa Mobile—asks him to try out LaLaLa Loveland, a brand-new social platform. With it, Kiryu can bond with owners of similar flip phones through the red thread of fate transmission, make them his LaLaLa Friends, and gradually unlock more of their profiles.</p><p><strong>Red Thread of <a title="Series > Fate [70 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a> Transmission</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_005.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_006.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_007.jpg"></a></figure><p>In addition to connecting with your LaLaLa Friends, the Red Thread of Fate transmission lets you open up Loveboxes for a variety of rewards. While exploring Downtown Ryukyu and Kamurocho, be on the lookout! Loveboxes can be found all around town, from a truck loaded with boxes to the back of a random townsperson.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_008.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_009.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>◆ Cell Phone Customization</strong></p><p>You can personalize Kiryu’s flip phone by adding straps, swapping out the antenna, and changing the lock screen. As each part comes with a unique effect that boosts Kiryu’s abilities, there are tons of combinations to try out. Rhinestones and stickers are also available as decorations, so feel free to style it your way!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_010.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_012.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_013.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>◆ Karaoke</strong></p><p>Sing your heart out to classics and new tunes!</p><p>In <em>Yakuza Kiwami 3</em>, Kiryu can perform 2 new songs alongside hits from past titles at karaoke. You can have Haruka, Majima, Akko-san, and more join in on the fun too!</p><p><strong>“Pararirai: Happiness Blooms”</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_014.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_015.jpg"></a></figure><p>Comment from Ryosuke Horii: “I wanted to compose an Okinawa-themed song that Kiryu could sing with all of the kids at Morning Glory. The lyrics are simple enough for anyone to sing along, and they echo my own wish for peace. Give it a listen! Also, the music video packs so much punch that it might even claim a top spot in karaoke history. I hope you enjoy it!”</p><p><strong>“Kamurocho Rhapsody”</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_016.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_017.jpg"></a></figure><p>Comment from Ryosuke Horii: “I’ve composed a number of tracks centered around Kamurocho in the past. However, since most of them are enka ballads, I wanted to try my hand at something more rock ‘n’ roll this time. With its mix of danger and emotion, this song captures what Kamurocho is all about. The music video also features footage of Kiryu’s past encounters, making it a must-watch for fans of the series.”</p><p><strong>◆ Outfits</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_018.jpg"></a></figure><p>Pick out styles perfect for Downtown Ryukyu and Kamurocho!</p><p><em>Yakuza Kiwami 3</em> lets you put together a variety of outfits for the two key locations of Kiryu’s <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,816 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>: Downtown Ryukyu and Kamurocho. Embrace the mellow way of life in Downtown Ryukyu with beach sandals and a kariyushi shirt, or dress like a party animal with wild hair while indulging in Kamurocho’s nightlife!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_019.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_020.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_021.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_022.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>◆ Reapers</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_023.jpg"></a></figure><p>Take out dangerous opponents bent on revenge against the Tojo Clan!</p><p>The Reapers are a ruthless band of former Tojo Clan members who were expelled for their vile conduct and have held a grudge against the clan ever since. Kiryu, at the request of his former comrade Kashiwagi, must capture them.</p><p>It’ll be your job to find out where they’re lurking.</p><p>By giving them the smackdown, you’ll be compensated generously in cash and valuable rewards!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_024.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_025.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_026.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ <em>Dark Ties</em></strong></p><p><strong>◆ Kanda’s Damage Control</strong></p><p><strong>Good Deed <a title="Platforms > Quest [164 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_027.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_028.jpg"></a></figure><p>Following the Good Deed Plans created by Zenba, one of Kanda’s subordinates, Mine must look into the incidents happening around town.<br>Many stories await at the end of each lead, including ones seeped in tragedy.</p><p>Witness the normally cool Mine tackle the people of Kamurocho’s troubles head-on.</p><p><strong>To Catch a Serial Killer</strong></p><p>A young man approaches the Nishikiyama Family with an odd request: to track down the Kamuro Killer, a mysterious serial killer causing a stir throughout Kamurocho and the one responsible for his sister’s death. As Mine gets closer to the truth, the man finds himself drawn ever deeper down a dark path of revenge.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_029.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Public Intoxication Awareness Campaign</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_030.jpg"></a></figure><p>After a few too many drinks, a lively gathering of movie and game fanatics descends into wild and unruly chaos. When Mine arrives on the scene, he encounters the unthinkable: a party of pirate cosplayers and pretend yakuza. In his own way, he’s about to teach these troublemakers that life isn’t all fun and games.</p><p><strong>Helping the Little People</strong></p><p>Take on missions that involve aiding distressed civilians to raise Kanda’s reputation. From people tormented by thugs to a guy who can’t stop sneezing, get out there and help the citizens around town!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_031.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_032.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_033.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Damage Control Challenge</strong></p><p>You can complete a variety of Damage Control Challenge missions to raise Kanda’s reputation. These range from taking out punks on the streets to winning big in minigames.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_034.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_035.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Charisma Rank</strong></p><p>This indicates Kanda’s reputation in the eyes of the public.<br>Initially labeled as Actually Trash, Mine’s efforts can bring him to the level of Actually God by the final rank, possibly changing him as a person.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_036.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_037.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>◆ Karaoke</strong></p><p>Witness the fiery vocals of the usually stoic Mine!</p><p>In Dark Ties, you can unwind with a round of karaoke as Mine. His passionate performances—especially the fan-favorite hit “Baka Mitai”—are something you won’t want to miss. For some backup vocals, invite Kanda!</p><p><strong>“Baka Mitai”</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_038.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_039.jpg"></a></figure><p>Comment from Ryosuke Horii: “Since we were making Mine a protagonist, I knew I wanted to see him take on karaoke. Figuring there was nothing to lose, I asked his voice actor, Shido Nakamura, if he’d be willing to do it—and I was overjoyed when he gave an enthusiastic yes. During the recording session, he threw himself into the performance. We did multiple takes, including some ad-libs, and ended up with wonderful results. I hope you can feel that energy in the finished song!”</p><p><strong>■ <em>Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties</em></strong></p><p><strong>◆ Play Spots</strong></p><p><em>Yakuza Kiwami 3</em> brings back multiple fan-favorite minigames, from bowling to the Print Club. For the first time in series’ history, SEGA’s classic handheld console, the <a title="Platforms > Game Gear" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/sega/game-gear">Game Gear</a>, is playable in-game with multiple titles available—including the Game Gear versions of <em>PAC-MAN</em>, <em>MAPPY</em>, and <em>GALAGY ’91</em>, in cooperation with <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco Entertainment</a>. At the <a title="Genres > Arcade [103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a>, you can also cut loose with a treasure trove of machines, including <em>UFO Catchers</em>, <em>Emergency Call Ambulance</em>, and <em>SlashOut!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_040.png"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_041.png"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_042.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_043.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_044.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_045.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Yakuza-Kiwami-3-and-Dark-Ties_2026_01-14-26_046.jpg"></a></figure></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties-details-lalala-loveland-karaoke-reapers-play-spots-and-more]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HoloType: Treasure Zombie Island launches February 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/holotype-treasure-zombie-island-launches-february-5</link>
            <guid>1406584</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>hololive typing game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Typing [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/typing">Typing game</a> <em><a title="Games > HoloType: Treasure Zombie Island [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/holotype-treasure-zombie-island">HoloType: Treasure Zombie Island</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4195460/HoloType_Treasure_Zombie_Island/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 5 for 980 yen, publisher <a title="Companies > holo Indie [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/holo-indie">holo Indie</a> and developer <a title="Companies > BeXide [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bexide">BeXide</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000071.000104705.html" target="_blank">announced</a>. It will support English and Japanese language options. <span id="more-1019299"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4195460/HoloType_Treasure_Zombie_Island/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Houshou Marine sets sail again, this time with typing! Due to Crazy Ollie’s mischief, the captain’s precious treasure has transformed into “<a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a> Zombies”! Can the captain recover her original, adorable treasure? A typing game like no other, filled with Hololive’s most memorable lines! It begins now!</p><p><strong>How to Play</strong></p><p>The basic operation is a “typing game” where you type the characters displayed on the screen with your keyboard. In each stage, the selected Hololive member and their companions will appear as “Treasure Zombies.” Type the displayed “memorable Hololive lines” with your keyboard and heal the Treasure Zombies! At the end of each stage, a powerful boss will appear!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Conquer their chaotic, memorable lines and reclaim your precious treasure!</p><p><strong>Treasure Collection Room</strong></p><p>The treasures you collect can be displayed and played with in the captain’s room. Collecting more treasures doubles the fun! Gather as many treasures as possible and create your own unique collection room!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Official Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="『ホロタイプ お宝ゾンビの島』公式PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XL6M4DHrTiM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/holotype-treasure-zombie-island-launches-february-5]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Compile Heart to announce new ‘school RPG’ by Megami Tensei co-creator Kouji Okada on January 29]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/compile-heart-to-announce-new-school-rpg-by-megami-tensei-co-creator-kouji-okada-on-january-29</link>
            <guid>1406560</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Other former ATLUS staff also on board.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,251 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000961.000080401.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched</a> a <a href="https://www.compileheart.com/vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teaser website</a> for a new “school <a title="Genres > RPG [17,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a>” by <em>Megami Tensei</em> and <em><a title="Series > Persona [93 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a></em> series co-creator Kouji Okada to be announced on January 29. It is described as “Kouji Okada’s final message to the next generation.” <span id="more-1019282"></span></p><p>The game’s staff includes other former <a title="Companies > ATLUS [2,074 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus">ATLUS</a> employees:</p><ul><li><strong>Project Producer:</strong> Kouji Okada (ATLUS co-founder, <em>Megami Tensei</em> and <em>Persona</em> series co-creator)</li><li><strong>Scenario:</strong> Tadashi Satomi (<em>Persona: Revelations</em> and Persona 2: Innocent Sin / <em><a title="Games > Ete [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ete">Ete</a>rnal Punishment</em> scenario writer)</li><li><strong>Sound Composer:</strong> Tsukasa <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>uko (<em>Megami Tensei</em>, <em>Megami Tensei II</em>, <em><a title="Series > Shin Megami Tensei [96 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/shin-megami-tensei">Shin Megami Tensei</a></em>, <em>Shin Megami Tensei II</em>, etc.)</li><li><strong>Character Design:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/Kuvshinov_Ilya" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ilya Kuvshinov</a></li></ul><p>Watch a teaser trailer below. Follow the game on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/compileheart_vc" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="新作学園RPG ティザームービー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4r12nMDVxOo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/compile-heart-to-announce-new-school-rpg-by-megami-tensei-co-creator-kouji-okada-on-january-29]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Factory automation meets anime-style RPG’ moorestech announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/factory-automation-meets-anime-style-rpg-moorestech-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>1406524</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out around August 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Independent Japanese developer <a title="Companies > sakastudio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sakastudio">sakastudio</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > moorestech [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moorestech">moorestech</a></em>, a “factory automation meets anime-style <a title="Genres > RPG [17,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a>.” It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1958160/moorestech/" target="_blank">Steam</a> “around August 2026.” <span id="more-1019244"></span></p><p>“This title has been in development for about five years,” sakastudio said in a press release. “We believe that we can deliver a new experience that is not found in existing factory games, specifically the mechanism of transmitting energy with gears. We are also focusing on the story, and we hope you will enjoy building a factory while following the story. We have created this game so that both automation fans of <em><a title="Games > Factorio [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/factorio">Factorio</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Satisfactory [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/satisfactory">Satisfactory</a></em>, as well as those who are playing this genre for the first time, can enjoy it, so please add it to your wishlist!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1958160/moorestech/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Factory automation meets anime-style RPG. Harness gears and shafts to power machines and conveyors, building an automated factory. Produce items and research tech, evolving from windmills to fusion as you trace humanity’s tech evolution, then launch a rocket home to uncover the truth of your exile.</p><p><strong>Build a Fully Automated Factory</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Build a colossal factory as you trace humanity’s technological history.</p><ul><li>From waterwheels to steam engines, electricity, and fusion. With every leap in technology, what you can do expands.</li><li>Automate everything from mining and smelting to processing and assembly—build a production network where materials flow on their own.</li><li>Your ultimate goal is to build a rocket. Develop your factory and aim for a return home.</li></ul><p><strong>A New <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> with the Gear System</strong></p><p>Windmills spin, gears mesh, and machines roar to life. Tune rotation speed and torque to design your very own power network.</p><ul><li>High RPM or high torque? Tinker with gear ratios to pursue efficient power transmission.</li><li>Run short on power and your machines grind to a halt. This is hands-on, physical engineering you can’t get from simply connecting wires.</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_1019240"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>A Beginner-Friendly Tutorial</strong></p><p>A gentle tutorial explains the basics of factory automation from scratch—no experience needed.</p><ul><li>A complete step-by-step tutorial that teaches the fundamentals of factory automation.</li><li>No more “I don’t know what to do next.” Your companions will guide you toward your next objective.</li><li>Veteran players can skip the tutorial and jump straight into serious construction.</li></ul><p><strong>A Story Driven by Charming Characters</strong></p><p>Exiled Princess Yori and her colorful companions. Why was she cast out? The truth awaits in the story.</p><ul><li><strong>Yori</strong> – The second princess of planet Celestal. Exiled to planet Arcadia without even knowing why. She starts out as a sheltered young lady who can’t do much, but with Ereno’s help, she pushes industrialization forward.</li><li><strong>Ereno</strong> – A general-purpose support AI system who came to planet Arcadia with Yori as her attendant.</li><li><strong>Kurua</strong> – Athletic, genuinely bright, and easygoing. Friendly and chatty. She loves money—and will do anything to survive.</li></ul><p><strong>Highly Flexible Mod Development Environment</strong></p><p>The Ultimate Modding Environment—Powered by Open Source and Dedicated Tools</p><ul><li>Create mods with a dedicated editor—no coding required.</li><li>The game’s full source code is publicly available on GitHub.</li><li>Planned support for Steam Workshop.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/moorestech/january-14-2026/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://moores.tech/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="moorestech 限定公開 仮トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sOYIfvKVeM8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/factory-automation-meets-anime-style-rpg-moorestech-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: New Horizons version 3.0 update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-3-0-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>1406515</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New resort hotel, new themed items and characters, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Platforms > Nintendo [23,414 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> has <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/49112/~/how-to-update-animal-crossing%3A-new-horizons" target="_blank">released</a> the version 3.0 update for <em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</em>, which adds the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-3-0-update-and-nintendo-switch-2-edition-announced">previously announced</a> new content and features, as well as various other features and updates. <span id="more-1019221"></span></p><p>Here are the patch notes:</p><blockquote><p><strong>General updates (<a title="Platforms > Switch [18,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a>&nbsp;2 and Nintendo Switch)</strong></p><ul><li>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-3-0-update-and-nintendo-switch-2-edition-announced">previously announced</a> new content and features&nbsp;have been added.</li><li>It’s now possible to craft up to 10 items at once if you have enough materials.</li><li>Items stored in your home storage can now be used as DIY materials.</li><li>The DIY Recipes app now includes a page where you can check hotel DIY requests and items requested by Tom Nook as you progress through the game.</li><li>Items obtained by linking with&nbsp;<em>Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp</em>&nbsp;can now always be ordered from Nook Shopping.</li><li><em>Super Mario Bros.</em>&nbsp;items can now be ordered from Nook Shopping without linking to a Nintendo Account.</li><li>While outdoors on an island, holding down the L Button allows you to move while facing the same direction.</li><li>When changing the island tune at Resident Services, Isabelle will now suggest recommended melodies, including the original island tune.</li><li>When changing the island flag at Resident Services, you can now revert it to the original design from when the island was created.</li><li>You can now purchase up to 50 Customization Kits at once from Nook’s Cranny.</li><li>Several items, including Snowflakes, can now be sold at the drop-off box at Nook’s Cranny.</li><li>You will receive a Pearl every time you give a scallop to Pascal.</li><li>You can now ask Leif to remove weeds when there are 30 or more weeds on your island, either on Harv’s Island or during his visits</li><li>The fee for asking Leif to remove weeds has been reduced.</li><li>New tips have been added to the Island Life 101 app.</li><li>Additional Nook Miles tasks have been added alongside the new features.</li><li>The order of some collaboration items has been updated in the catalogs used for photo studios and hotel decorating.</li><li>Other adjustments and corrections were made to improve the gameplay experience.</li></ul><p><strong>Nintendo Switch&nbsp;2 Specific Updates</strong></p><ul><li>Fixed an issue where the startup sound for Nook Shopping on the smartphone would not play correctly.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>NookLink (Nintendo Switch App) Updates</strong></p><ul><li>Added new articles to the Island Newspaper.</li><li>The Catalog now supports new items added in Ver. 3.0.0.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</em> is available now for Switch, and <em><a title="Games > Animal Crossing: New Horizons [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/animal-crossing-new-horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></em> will launch on January 15.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-3-0-update-now-available]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>