<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 15:54:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Midnight Murder Club launches in Early Access on March 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/midnight-murder-club-launches-in-early-access-on-march-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/midnight-murder-club-launches-in-early-access-on-march-13.1120599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/midnight-murder-club-launches-in-early-access-on-march-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Grant five friends access to the game at no additional cost with the "Guest Pass Edition."</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Multiplayer [450 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,612 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Midnight Murder Club [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/midnight-murder-club">Midnight Murder Club</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,948 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2698870/Midnight_Murder_Club/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 13 for $19.99, publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,961 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Velan Studios [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/velan-studios">Velan Studios</a> announced. It will support cross-play and cross-progression at launch. A “Guest Pass Edition” will also be available, which grants access to five friends at no additional cost. <span id="more-947087"></span></p><p>The Early Access release will include a new game mode called “Wldcards,” where players can play cards from their collection that change the rules for everyone in the game.</p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>Welcome back to the <em>Midnight Murder Club</em>. Here at Velan Studios, we’ve been toiling away in the shadowy halls of Wormwood Manor, coming up with fresh, new ways for you to hunt your friends in the darkness. We’ve got a new game mode to announce and an exciting new way to get your friends in on the fighting!</p><p><em>Midnight Murder Club</em> is a first-person shooter/<a title="Genres > Party [86 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">party game</a> where you and five friends hunt each other in the pitch-black rooms of the mysterious Wormwood Manor. Armed with only a revolver and a flashlight, search the shadows for every flicker of light and every bump in the night as you stalk your prey. The tension turns to hilarity as you discover just how tricky it is to navigate and shoot in complete darkness! You sprint toward your friends’ shouting voices echoing through the mansion, only to bump into someone else hiding in a dark corner! Shots ring out, luring the other hunters to your location. Every flash of light is the promise of a deadly firefight. This is <em>Midnight Murder Club</em>.</p><p><strong>New Game Mode: Wildcards</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>On top of the existing Free for All, Thief in the Night, Team Deathmatch, and Headhunters modes, we’re excited to introduce a brand-new mode that lets you break the rules like never before! In the new Wildcards game mode, players will play cards from their collection that change the rules for everyone in-game in wild new ways! From hijacking the toys that appear in vendors, to giving everyone super speed, to exploding into flames when you die—use these cards to show your wild side! Then, when the dust settles and the match is over, you’ll be gifted brand new cards to add to your collection giving you even more ways to change the game. In the new Wildcards game mode, it looks like chaos is in the cards!</p><p><strong>Play at No Additional Cost with the <em>Midnight Murder Club</em> Guest Pass Edition!</strong></p><p>We know that playing with friends is the best way to play any game and with the <em>Midnight Murder Club</em> Guest Pass Edition, it’s easier than ever! <em>Midnight Murder Club</em> Guest Pass Edition allows your friends to join your game and play for no additional cost!</p><p>To put it simply: If one person buys the game, they can invite up to five Guest Pass Edition players to play together for no additional cost in public or private matches, in all current game modes, as much as you want.</p><p>We’re really excited about the Guest Pass Edition because <em>Midnight Murder Club</em> is the perfect party game to play with friends. Now players can simply invite their friends into the club and let the mayhem begin.</p><p><strong>Burning the Midnight Oil</strong></p><p>To sum it up, we’re adding the brand-new Wildcards game mode and introducing a brand-new way to play with friends with the Guest Pass Edition. That’s a lot of new development work! Because of that, we’re going to need a little more time, so we’re pushing our Early Access launch date to March 13th, 2025. The full version of the game will be available in Early Access for $19.99 (or equivalent in your region), and the Guest Pass Edition will be launching on the same day for no additional cost.</p><p>As a member of the <em>Midnight Murder Club</em>, your opinion on the direction the club should go matters! We’re really excited about evolving this game with the community as we continue developing through Early Access. We want your opinions and ideas, which will help shape our roadmap (which we’ll be sharing before launch!). Our Discord, the Steam Community Hub, and our socials will be open for discussions, feedback, and updates directly from us!</p><p>With these major changes and much more to come, we can’t wait to dive back into the darkness and haunt the hallowed halls of the Wormwood manor with you. Prepare yourselves for <em>Midnight Murder Club</em> coming to Early Access on PlayStation 5 and Steam on March 13, 2025.</p><p>See you in the shadows!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new developer diary below.</p><h2><span>Developer Diary: Wildcards Mode</span></h2><p><iframe title="Midnight Murder Club - Wildcards Mode Developer Diary" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3dXxeQe2CT8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reburn, formerly 4A Games Ukraine, announces sci-fi first-person shooter La Quimera for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/reburn-formerly-4a-games-ukraine-announces-sci-fi-first-person-shooter-la-quimera-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reburn-formerly-4a-games-ukraine-announces-sci-fi-first-person-shooter-la-quimera-for-pc.1120521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/reburn-formerly-4a-games-ukraine-announces-sci-fi-first-person-shooter-la-quimera-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Set in a futuristic Latin America.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Reburn, an independent games studio formerly known as <a title="Companies > 4A Games [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive/4a-games">4A Games</a> Ukraine, has announced <em><a title="Games > La Quimera" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/la-quimera">La Quimera</a></em>, a story-driven science-fiction shooter set in a futuristic Latin America, running on the 4A Engine. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2282350/La_Quimera/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-946567"></span></p><p>“Reburn is proud to introduce <em>La Quimera</em>, which draws upon our success <a title="Genres > Crafting [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> narrative-driven <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,016 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter games</a> for the Metro series,” said Reburn founder and CEO Dmytro Lymar in a press release. “We look forward to sharing this mysterious new world with players and hope they revel in suiting up to join the fight.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Reburn:</p><blockquote><p><em>La Quimera</em> is a story driven science-fiction shooter set in a futuristic Latin America.</p><p><em>La Quimera</em> takes place across a breathtaking Latin American megalopolis and lush jungle setting, where the player steps into the customizable exosuit of a down-on-their-luck PMC soldier battling against rival factions. The world and narrative of <em>La Quimera</em> is written and created by Nicolas Winding Refn (<em>Drive</em>, <em>The Neon Demon</em>) and E.J.A. Warren. Combining Latin American folklore with highly advanced weaponry and technology, <em>La Quimera</em> will be playable in single-player or with up to two friends in <a title="Genres > Co-Op [236 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play—for a total of three players. Fans of the <em>Metro</em> series will enjoy familiar tense gunplay and intimate storytelling combined with new game experiences through unique and highly detailed environments, characters and weapons.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/la-quimera/february-27-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="La Quimera - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YMsAUHFyJdo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_946841"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>