<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:21:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doraemon Dorayaki Shop Story coming to PS4, Xbox Series, and Xbox One on January 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16.1082928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><em>Doraemon Dorayaki Shop Story</em> first launched for Switch on August 27, 2024, followed by iOS and Android on September 23, 2024, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2934180/Doraemon_Dorayaki_Shop_Story/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 9, 2024.</p><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A game where you run a sweets shop with the popular manga character Doraemon.</p><p>Let’s make Doraemon’s favorite dorayaki and create a store that will be the talk of the town.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>First, make the sweets, set up the shelves, prepare the tables, and get ready to run the shop!</p><p>In addition, various characters from Fujiko・F・Fujio’s works will appear as customers!</p><p>Many characters will come, including T・P BON and Kiteretsu Encyclopedia.</p><p>During your <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> to find ingredients, you will encounter many difficulties. Even in such a situation, Doraemon’s secret gadgets will help you solve difficult problems without any difficulty!</p><p>A management game created by Kairosoft, a company popular for its <a title="Genres > Simulation [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation games</a>.</p><p>Enjoy Doraemon’s unique adventures.</p><p><strong>Game Flow</strong></p><p>First, let’s make a dorayaki.</p><p>Set up seats and shelves of sweets inside the shop and open it.</p><p>As you discover different sweets while making them, you will attract more customers.</p><p>Occasionally, you will fulfill your customers’ requests and make your dorayaki shop famous and known throughout the country.</p><p><strong>Doraemon and Friends</strong></p><p>Five friends will become shop staff and help out in the shop. Shop staff have two parameters.</p><ul><li><strong>Exploration</strong> – Helps you find ingredients and get rid of obstacles.</li><li><strong>Skill</strong> – Helps you make sweets in the kitchen and improve sweets in the prototype room.</li></ul><p><strong>Let’s Make Sweets!</strong></p><p>Making many new sweets will lead to the development of the shop. Let’s collect ingredients by searching for ingredients and make them as you go.</p><p>You can make sweets by looking at hints on combinations, but there are also rare sweets that don’t have any hints.</p><p><strong>Be Particular About the Decorations</strong></p><p>You can decorate your sweets. Basically, it’s best to choose freely based on your preference for appearance. The decorations you choose will improve the quality and reputation of the sweets at the tasting event. It will also have a positive effect when you improve the sweets.</p><p>The decorations may go well with the staff who puts the finishing touches on them.</p><p><strong>Let’s Search for Ingredients</strong></p><p>Go find ingredients in various places. When you discover ingredients, you will be able to make new sweets.</p><p>When searching for ingredients, the staff’s exploration parameters are important. If the numbers are high, it will be easier to meet new characters and discover items. The staff’s exploration ability also affects the rank of books that can be used to improve sweets.</p><p><strong>Build a Facility</strong></p><p>Installing facilities is important for the development of your shop.</p><p><strong>Facility Parameters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Charm</strong> – The higher it is, the higher the satisfaction will be and the more points you will receive.</li><li><strong>Genre</strong> – There are types such as wabisabi or retro, and building facilities of the same genre nearby will generate area bonuses.</li></ul><p><strong>Aim to Rank Up</strong></p><p>As you rank up, you’ll be able to manage your shop more advantageously, and the number of things you can do and the facilities you can build will increase.</p><p>You’ll also be able to use the Lander-Expander more times, which will allow you to expand your space.</p><p>Meet the conditions to reach the highest rank.</p><p><strong>About the Ending</strong></p><p>The game will end 1 year after you start at the end of the fourth week of March, but you can continue to play the game after that.</p><p>If you start a new game after reaching the ending and use the “New Game+” data, you can start the game with some of the data you cleared, which can give you an advantage in running your business.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sports: Renovations launches March 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/sports-renovations-launches-march-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sports-renovations-launches-march-27.1082886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/sports-renovations-launches-march-27<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Save your hometown old basketball court by restoring numerous sports venues.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>First-person renovation <a title="Genres > Simulation [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Sports: Renovations [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sports-renovations">Sports: Renovations</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,565 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2230960/Sports_Renovations/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Dear Villagers [87 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plug-in-digital/dear-villagers">Dear Villagers</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Goat Gamez [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/movie-games/goat-gamez">Goat Gamez</a> announced. <span id="more-938488"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2230960/Sports_Renovations/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Restore the glory of sports in a relaxing renovator sim!</p><p>How do you save your beloved team’s court from being torn down by a real estate developer? You do what you do best—renovate dilapidated sports facilities to collect the money you need to help out.</p><p>Restore gyms, courts, pools and pitches to their former glory, upgrade your tools and expand your headquarters. Collect trophies and mementoes during your renovation missions and display them proudly in a special room for everyone to see.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Step Into the Story</strong></p><p>Your hometown basketball court is in danger. The shining star of your youth where you watched fantastic matches played by your favourite team. It’s a place where many young talents started their careers. It’s a home of many fond memories, now covered in cobwebs and dust.</p><p>The court is deteriorating rapidly. A big developer is only waiting to get his grubby hands on the place, tear it down and build a new shopping mall instead. But you won’t accept that.</p><p>Do what you do best! Grab your tools, roll up your sleeves and breathe some life into other old sports facilities to earn money. See the spaces normally unavailable to normal visitors. Learn the inner workings of sports and listen to fascinating tales about their history.</p><p>And when you’ve earned enough, step up and renovate your hometown’s court.</p><p><strong>Level Up</strong></p><p>Collect trash, clean up the dirt from walls and floors, give the place a fresh coat of paint, fix broken fixtures, furnish and decorate the place.<br>Remember to take a photo before and after to prove how good a job you did! Use the money you earn to upgrade your equipment and expand your headquarters—each unlocked room comes with its own perks and advantages.</p><p><strong>Achieve Perfection</strong></p><p>Leave no corner undusted and no wall unpainted. Carefully design the area and arrange every room with its functionality in mind. You have all the time in the world so use it to polish your skills and plan out the space—some designs are better than others so be creative! Tinker with sports equipment and assemble the furniture to the best of your ability.</p><p>And remember: just have fun and be proud of your achievements!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Play in two game modes! Thwart the plans of a developer who wants to tear down your beloved basketball club in Campaign mode. Later, replay levels to renovate old facilities in different styles in the Free Play mode.</li><li>Buy new tools and upgrade the equipment you already own.</li><li>Earn money for your renovation jobs and use it to expand your own base of operations—unlock additional perks and side missions.</li><li>Buy cosmetic items you can place around your office.</li><li>Trophy room where the player sees various memorabilia collected during renovation missions.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch an old trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SPORTS RENOVATIONS - Release date trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yfU2BjKMeAI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Promise Mascot Agency voice cast announced, including Shuhei Yoshida and SWERY]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/promise-mascot-agency-voice-cast-announced-including-shuhei-yoshida-and-swery</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/promise-mascot-agency-voice-cast-announced-including-shuhei-yoshida-and-swery.1082820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/promise-mascot-agency-voice-cast-announced-including-shuhei-yoshida-and-swery<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Kazuma Kiryu voice actor Takaya Kuroda to voice the protagonist.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Kaizen Game Works [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kaizen-game-works">Kaizen Game Works</a> has announced the main voice cast for “<a title="Genres > Open-World [545 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> mascot <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> <a title="Companies > crim [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e drama” <em><a title="Games > Promise Mascot Agency [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/promise-mascot-agency">Promise Mascot Agency</a></em>, which includes Kazuma Kiryu (<em>Yakuza</em>) voice actor Takaya Kuroda in the role of protagonist Michi, as well as a couple of games industry icons like former <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,941 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> head of indies Shuhei Yoshida and <a title="Companies > White Owls Inc. [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/white-owls-inc">White Owls</a>, Inc. president Hidetaka “Swery65” Suehiro. <span id="more-938553"></span></p><p>The list of confirmed voice actors include:</p><ul><li>Michi (Protagonist) (voiced by Takaya Kuroda) – known for Kazuma Kiryu in the <em>Yakuza</em> / <em>Like a Dragon</em> series</li><li>Pinky (voiced by Ayano Shibuya) – known for Purah in <em><a title="Games > The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a></em></li><li>Matriarch Shimazu (voiced by Eri Saito) – known for <em>Chainsaw Man</em>, <em><a title="Platforms > Meta [129 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>l Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots</em>, and <em>Way of the Samurai 3</em></li><li>MonouGe (voiced by Shuhei Yoshida) – former Sony Interactive Entertainment head of indies</li><li>Kannushi-kun (voiced by Hidetaka “SWERY” Suehiro) – head of White Owls, Inc.</li><li>And so many more friends to meet!</li></ul><p>And here is the official story blurb:</p><blockquote><p>Takaya Kuroda voices the disgraced ex-yakuza Michi, exiled to the forgotten (and quite definitely cursed) Japanese town of Kaso-Machi with two goals: pay off his debt and restore glory to the town’s defunct mascot agency! Recruit the weird and wonderful mascots across town with help from your severed finger assistant manager and chaos goblin, Pinky☆, voiced by Ayana Shibuya, negotiate their contracts and assign them jobs they love.</p></blockquote><p><em>Promise Mascot Agency</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,565 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,512 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585830/Promise_Mascot_Agency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/promise-mascot-agency-dd7a9c" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> in 2025.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the voice cast reveal trailer below, via <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/promise-mascot-agency-voice-cast-includes-playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-and-deadly-premonition-dev-swery" rel="noopener" target="_blank">IGN</a>.</p><h2><span>Voice Cast Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Promise Mascot Agency - Exclusive Voice Cast Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WQOxgxvtFaw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lil Gator Game expansion ‘In the Dark’ announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/lil-gator-game-expansion-in-the-dark-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lil-gator-game-expansion-%E2%80%98in-the-dark%E2%80%99-announced.1082817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/lil-gator-game-expansion-in-the-dark-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out alongside "Gator of the Year Edition."</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a> and developer <a title="Companies > MegaWobble [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/megawobble">MegaWobble</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Lil Gator Game [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lil-gator-game">Lil Gator Game</a></em> downloadable content “In the Dark,” a “huge expansion” currently in development. A release date was not announced, but it will launch alongside a “Gator of the Year Edition” for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,565 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,512 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, bundling the base game and expansion. <span id="more-938527"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the expansion, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3205060/Lil_Gator_Game_In_the_Dark/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The world just got a whole lot bigger for this Lil Gator!</p><p>Make way for <em>Lil Gator Game: In the Dark</em>. Lil Gator is back with an all new big downloadable content expansion, doubling the size of <em>Lil Gator Game</em>.</p><p>In this charming downloadable content, you’ll find that new <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>s and friends are just beneath the surface—literally! Get ready to “cave in” to the fun and find that you’re stalag-right where you belong!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This big downloadable content is filled to the brim with all the charm and humour you loved in Lil Gator Game. There is a buddy in every cave and crevasse in this new, big, underground adventure!</p><p><strong>A Gorge-eous Location</strong></p><p>Getting to the caves is as easy as following your nose. In the base game’s island, you’ll stumble upon a lil’ entrance that’s been there all along, to take you below ground.</p><p>Wander a beautiful cave network where glowsticks light your path and cozy tunnels host hidden nooks and crannies filled with cute critters, secret treasures, and places to relax and take in the peaceful atmosphere.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_938529"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>All New Friends to Discover</strong></p><p>On your travels you’ll meet a bunch of new pals! But remember making new friends isn’t always easy, you just might need to complete a quest or two!</p><p><strong>Face Your Frenemies</strong></p><p>In a narrative twist, Lil Gator will take on some teenage troublemakers looking to disrupt the wholesome fun. Can Gator use their relentless optimism to bring these angsty adolescents onside, and just who is their leader?</p><p><strong>Bring on the Brand New Gear</strong></p><p>This downloadable content has all sorts of new toys to play with, including never before seen item types. Lil Gator can now double jump his way across canyons with a flick of a gymnastic ribbon and slams into cardboard crooks from above.</p><p>Embark on an expedition of family friendly fun in this cozy conclusion to Lil Gator’s epic adventure.</p></blockquote><p><em>Lil Gator Game</em> is available now for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, Switch, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1586800/Lil_Gator_Game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/lil-gator-game/january-15-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “In the Dark” Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Lil Gator Game: In The Dark | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6s2TaAzqplQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>