<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 16:35:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squeakross: Home Squeak Home now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/squeakross-home-squeak-home-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/squeakross-home-squeak-home-now-available.1211109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/squeakross-home-squeak-home-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Solve, decorate, and create your dream rodent residence.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Puzzle game <em><a title="Games > Squeakross: Home Squeak Home [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/squeakross-home-squeak-home">Squeakross: Home Squeak Home</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,176 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,336 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2871440/Squeakross_Home_Squeak_Home/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://alblune.itch.io/squeakross-home-squeak-home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">itch.io</a>, developer <a title="Companies > Alblune [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alblune">Alblune</a> announced. <span id="more-969493"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Alblune:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Welcome Home!</strong></p><p>Welcome to the Home Squeak Home program! In this program, you will meet Nini, the program’s official <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ger, who has a passion for nonogram puzzles. Nini has provided you with a cozy rat residence, but there’s just one condition: you must solve <em>Squeakross</em> puzzles to earn furniture and fill your empty home! Your puzzle catalog contains 650 solvable <em>Squeakross</em> puzzles. Each completed puzzle will reward you with furniture for your rodent residence. The hint numbers on the sides indicate how many squares to fill with cheese in each row or column. Mark the largest hint numbers, leaving spaces as needed. Then, analyze different arrangements to complete the puzzle. Strike out hint lines one by one and repeat the process until the picture of your brand-new furniture is revealed!</p><p><strong>Get Solving!</strong></p><p>If you haven’t solved a nonogram before, don’t worry! In <em>Squeakross</em>, anyone can quickly become a nonogram natural. Nini provides in-game guidance to help players learn how to solve nonograms step by step, and players can revisit the manual at any time for additional tutorials. Whether you are a whisker away from solving a puzzle or looking for a more relaxed experience, you can ask your furry friend for assistance in Logic Assist mode. This feature shows possible solutions to help complete puzzles with two options: An “automatic case-solving” button and a “show mistakes” button. For experienced nonogram players seeking a greater challenge, “Nini’s Challenge” offers a more difficult variant of each puzzle, unlocking colorways for furniture in your home. To ensure an inclusive experience, <em>Squeakross</em> also incorporates many gameplay options for players to tweak their own experience and overall difficulty of puzzles!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Fur-nish your dream home!</strong></p><p>Decorate your space to your heart’s content with unlockable 3D furniture models. Even in the demo, get a head start on personalizing your home using matching wallpapers, carpets, chairs, and more. You can make your rodent uniquely yours by selecting from various fur colors, patterns, tail lengths, ear sizes, and costumes. After all your hard work, sit back and enjoy watching your rodent friend in <a title="Genres > Action [2,770 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>650 solvable <em>Squeakross</em> puzzles.</li><li>Logic-Assist System that lets you preview possible solutions.</li><li>Nini’s Challenges elevated difficulty, unlocking color variants for furniture.</li><li>No time limit for relaxing puzzle solving, accommodating new players.</li><li>Rodent editor allows you to fully customize your rodent friend and their personality.</li><li>Hundreds of furniture pieces to choose from.</li><li>“Streamer Mode” to turn off Content ID-tagged music.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Squeakross: Home Squeak Home - Available on SWITCH &amp; PC/MAC" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2xURGBuS6yM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2 ‘New Features’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-new-features-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-%E2%80%93-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-%E2%80%98new-features%E2%80%99-trailer.1211106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2-new-features-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Enhanced combat mechanics, new Gear system, and Path of Training mode.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publishers <a title="Companies > Aniplex [283 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-music-entertainment-japan/aniplex">Aniplex</a> and <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,669 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > CyberConnect2 [619 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberconnect2">CyberConnect2</a> have released a trailer for <em><a title="Games > Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba - The Hinokami Chronicles 2 [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-2">Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2</a></em>, introducing the game’s enhanced combat mechanics, new Gear system, and Path of Training mode. <span id="more-971452"></span></p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p>A variety of new systems and features make their debut in <em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2</em>, including:</p><ul><li><strong>Dual Ultimates</strong> – Players will be able to team up through certain character combinations to unleash stylish new Dual Ultimates to devastate your opponent. Use this power of forged bonds to your advantage!</li><li><strong>Gear System</strong> – Customize your loadout to your advantage in battle! In either Story Mode or VS Mode, players will be able to equip up to three items on their character, such as one that increases your resistance to poison, or one that slowly regenerates your health over time. There are a lot of different items to unlock through the game, so choose carefully!</li><li><strong>Training Paths</strong> – Challenge yourself against the Hashira! After choosing which path to follow and which Hashira to challenge, players will advance through a series of tournament brackets with ever-changing victory conditions that keep every tournament round fresh and engaging.</li><li><strong>The Path of a Demon Slayer</strong> – Need a refresher? This mode lets players review the story covered in <em>The Hinokami Chronicles 1</em> by engaging in key battles from the Unwavering Resolve Arc up to the Mugen Train Arc.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>tery</strong> – By using different characters in either Story Mode or VS Mode, players will be able to increase that person’s “mastery” level. Each level up unlocks different rewards such as stickers or background images that can be used to customize their Slayer ID (the online player profile).</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Hinokami Chronicles 2</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,059 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,005 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,176 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,336 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2928600/Demon_Slayer_Kimetsu_no_Yaiba_The_Hinokami_Chronicles_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on August 1 in Japan and August 5 in the west. While digital pre-orders were previously available for <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [47,743 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox [26,054 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a>, and PC, pre-orders are also now available for Switch.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>New Features Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles 2 | New Features Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NbYPYJskqI4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-world action adventure platformer Tire Boy announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/open-world-action-adventure-platformer-tire-boy-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-world-action-adventure-platformer-tire-boy-announced-for-pc.1210902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/open-world-action-adventure-platformer-tire-boy-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Leap, roll, and battle your way through an unfamiliar world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > GameTeam6 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gameteam6">GameTeam6</a> has announced <a title="Genres > Open-World [647 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,770 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,315 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [690 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Tire Boy [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tire-boy">Tire Boy</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,336 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2258070/Tire_Boy/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-971449"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via GameTeam6:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Tire Boy</em> is an upcoming open-world action adventure platformer video game by GameTeam6.</p><p>Tire Boy is fast and nimble, leaping through lush environments, solving environmental puzzles, and taking on heroic battles—all while helping the locals, and uncovering his own past. Tire Boy may be the last of his kind, and was lost as a child. At the start of the game, we learn he was found and raised by a large owl named Nestwijk and doesn’t know much about his family or ancestors.</p><p>It’s a story about connection and curiosity, as Tire Boy journeys through a vast, unfamiliar world, searching for purpose and traces of his forgotten origins. <em>Tire Boy</em> is weird, heartfelt, and full of little surprises—and we’ve built it to feel like a place you’ll want to come back to, whether you’re chasing big moments or just soaking in the quiet ones.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dynamic Traversal and Platforming</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter momentum and timing with specialized tire upgrades—spike treads for icy paths, wide sand tires for riverbanks, and flower gliders for soaring across valleys. Navigate between towns and biomes while discovering shortcuts and secret passages.</li><li><strong>Whimsical Combat and Customization</strong> – Defend against bears, snails, wolves, and ducks using an eclectic arsenal of found objects. Wield everything from dried fish to saxophones, each with unique fighting styles and surprising powers that complement your rolling abilities.</li><li><strong>A World of Grand Proportions</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the island from Tire Boy’s unique perspective, where giant mushrooms become trampolines and ordinary slopes transform into thrilling rampways. Every location—from vibrant Flower Town to the busy docks of Port Town—towers magnificently above you.</li><li><strong>Colorful Cast of Characters</strong> – Race against Mallow the speedy bunny, help fish folk with peculiar requests, and return regularly to Nestwijk’s cozy nest to share treasures. Build bonds with the island’s quirky aquatic community while piecing together the broken radio transmitter.</li></ul><p><strong>Unique Selling Points</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Playful and Absurd</strong> – Makes players smile.</li><li><strong>Heartfelt Storytelling</strong> – Genuine emotion and soul in spite of its absurdity.</li><li><strong>Highly Accessible</strong> – Emphasizes fun, exploration, and discovery over difficulty.</li><li><strong>Childlike Perspective</strong> – Everything towers above you, creating a sense of scale and wonder.</li></ul><p><strong>Inspirations</strong></p><ul><li><em>The Legend of Zelda</em> (most of all <em>Ocarina of Time</em>, <em>Majora’s Mask</em>, and <em>Breath of the Wild</em>)</li><li><em>ICO</em> / <em>Shadow of the Colossus</em> / <em>The Last Guardian</em></li><li><em>Super Mario 64</em> (and later 3D <em>Mario</em> titles)</li><li><em><a title="Series > Sonic the Hedgehog [60 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/sonic-the-hedgehog">Sonic the Hedgehog</a></em></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the first look gameplay trailer below.</p><h2><span>First Look Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tire Boy - First Look Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hFsDKHoRIgU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>