<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 14:49:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Any and ArtePiazza announce Tensei Game for Switch – sugoroku-style game with Yuji Horii, Muneyuki Kaneshiro]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/any-and-artepiazza-announce-tensei-game-for-switch-sugoroku-style-game-with-yuji-horii-muneyuki-kaneshiro</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/any-and-artepiazza-announce-tensei-game-for-switch-%E2%80%93-sugoroku-style-game-with-yuji-horii-muneyuki-kaneshiro.1177554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/any-and-artepiazza-announce-tensei-game-for-switch-sugoroku-style-game-with-yuji-horii-muneyuki-kaneshiro<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2026 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Japanese studio Any, in cooperation with developer <a title="Companies > ArtePiazza [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/artepiazza">ArtePiazza</a>, have <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000002.000157995.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Tensei Game" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tensei-game">Tensei Game</a></em>, a sugoroku-style game coming to <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> via <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [21,929 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> eShop in 2026 in Japan. It will only be playable in Japanese. <span id="more-962292"></span></p><p>The project is advised by <em><a title="Series > Dragon Quest [97 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/dragon-quest">Dragon Quest</a></em> series creator Yuji Horii and concepted by <em>Blue Lock</em> and <em>As the Gods Will</em> author Muneyuki Kaneshiro, marking the pair’s first collaboration.</p><p><em>Tensei Game</em> is a sugoroku-style game built around the themes of “reincarnation,” “karma,” and “fate,” where players compete to “reincarnate” by sabotaging one another. As you repeatedly reincarnate, you will use karma to obstruct and betray other players. It is being developed around the concept of “a game guaranteed to ruin your friendships,” where the closer you get to victory, the more your friendships begin to fall apart. The game is set in “Rinnekai,” a dark fantasy world of the afterlife where players will encounter unique characters who aid in this ruin.</p><p>Beyond games, Any is considering expanding <em>Tensei Game</em> to multiple forms of media, including anime, merchandise, and TikTok content.</p><p>The project’s staff is as follows:</p><ul><li><strong>Planning and Production:</strong> Any</li><li><strong>Adivsor:</strong> Yuji Horii</li><li><strong>Original Concept:</strong> Muneyuki Kaneshiro</li><li><strong>Game Director:</strong> Ayaka Sato</li><li><strong>Character Designer:</strong> Shintarou Majima</li><li>Project Director: Koyakky (YouTuber, Ikushimaru.com)</li><li><strong>IP Commerce <a title="Genres > Strategy [240 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">Strategy</a> and Service Provider:</strong> SUPER STUDIO</li><li><strong>Development and Publishing:</strong> ArtePiazza</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea of Stars free DLC ‘Throes of the Watchmaker’ launches May 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-throes-of-the-watchmaker-launches-may-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-%E2%80%98throes-of-the-watchmaker%E2%80%99-launches-may-20.1177509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sea-of-stars-free-dlc-throes-of-the-watchmaker-launches-may-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Over eight hours of new content.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Sea of Stars [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sea-of-stars">Sea of Stars</a></em> free downloadable content “Throes of the Watchmaker” will launch on May 20 for all platforms, developer <a title="Companies > Sabotage Studio [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sabotage-studio">Sabotage Studio</a> announced. It will adds over eight hours of new areas, music, dungeons, mini-games, enemies, bosses, and puzzles, including new playable classes for Valere and Zale, and new playable character Arty. <span id="more-962096"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via Sabotage Studio:</p><blockquote><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” returns to one of the most intriguing characters encountered in <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ main <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>—the genius inventor known as the Watchmaker, architect of the Clockwork Castle and creator of Wheels, a tabletop pastime enjoyed throughout Sea of Stars’ world. The downloadable content explores a fascinating invention by the Watchmaker, the miniature clockwork world of Horloge, a land threatened by a cursed carnival. Zale and Valere must adapt to Horloge’s peculiar rules to fully realize their mastery of Sun and Moon powers, the abilities they’ve refined since the beginning of <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ central journey to stop the Fleshmancer with Eclipse Magic.</p><p>This post-game bonus adventure downloadable content is designed around a self-contained progression loop featuring completely new classes, skills and combos to master for Zale, who trades his signature sword to become a skillful juggler, and Valere, who sets aside her trusty staff to dazzle as an acrobat. Throughout “Throes of the Watchmaker,” the duo fights alongside a new playable party member in Artificer, a mechanized, laser-wielding sharpshot.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_962097"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” features never-before-seen areas, puzzles and enemies throughout a compelling storyline wholly unique from <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ core adventure. “Throes of the Watchmaker”‘s cinematic budget is equivalent to that of the main game, allowing Sabotage to richly realize key narrative moments and deliver a dense, delightful new tale spanning eight hours of new content. Crafted as a quest to enjoy after completing <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ critical path, “Throes of the Watchmaker” is the perfect reason to begin a New Game+ playthrough or dive into the world of <em>Sea of Stars</em> for the first time ahead of this all-new journey arrives on May 20.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>A stirring new score from <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ Lead Composer, Eric W. Brown, accents the journey, with additional original songs composed in collaboration with Yasunori Mitsuda (<em><a title="Games > Chrono Trigger [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a></em>) who returns as a guest composer.</p><p>“Throes of the Watchmaker” follows “Dawn of Equinox,” a separate free update which added local <a title="Genres > Co-Op [257 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, combat refinements, and more to <em>Sea of Stars</em>‘ celebrated campaign.</p></blockquote><p><em>Sea of Stars</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1244090/Sea_of_Stars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/sea-of-stars/april-30-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “Throes of the Watchmaker” Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker DLC | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tgFi2jXwzVI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of Industry 2 launches June 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3.1177458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rise-of-industry-2-launches-june-3<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Business tycoon game sequel dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Business tycoon game sequel <em><a title="Games > Rise of Industry 2 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rise-of-industry-2">Rise of Industry 2</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2532490/Rise_of_Industry_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/rise-of-industry-2-456a5c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on June 3, publisher <a title="Companies > Kasedo Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kasedo-games">Kasedo Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > SomaSim [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/somasim">SomaSim</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2532490/view/506201612758286361" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-962253"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Kasedo Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>80s U.S.A…. a time and place of rapid innovation, globalization and unprecedented profits. To dominate this competitive industrial landscape, you’ll need to build a cutting-edge manufacturing powerhouse and cultivate a rolodex full of jet-setting business contacts. Welcome to the land of opportunity!</p><p>In pursuit of unprecedented profits, you’ll need to seize every opportunity to innovate and grow each business you’re tasked with managing. Ever dream of running a hub of automotive production? A world-class winery with sweeping vineyard vistas? A sprawling mining operation extracting and refining valuable minerals? Or an aviation enterprise that assembles airplanes that will soar through the skies of an increasingly interconnected world?</p><p>You’ll need to optimize your production chains, import and export goods within the global market, keep up to date with the latest and greatest technologies, maintain strong relations with the local government and expand your business network to stay on top. Make all the right decisions along the way and you just might be able fulfill your American dream.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rise to the Challenge</strong> – Conquer 15 unique and exciting scenarios in campaign mode, each with a different challenge. Alternatively, define your own path to success in sandbox mode.</li><li><strong>Optimize your Production</strong> – Set up manufacturing businesses featuring factories, power plants, industrial furnaces and farms! Establish utility networks to power your industries, making use of the natural resources around you. Provide the media industry with televisions, cameras, vinyl records, cassettes, computers, and video game consoles. Get distilleries and breweries up and running to create drinks such as vodka, whiskey and beer. Churn out candy, toys, dyes, batteries and so much more!</li><li><strong>Import and Export Resources</strong> – Capitalize on the emerging global market by signing contracts with executives around the world. Import goods and resources to accelerate your production chains and export your products to make the big bucks!</li><li><strong>Research Technologies</strong> – Build labs and set research strategies to help you acquire new technologies that will broaden your horizons and improve your production chains.</li><li><strong>Make Global Connections</strong> – Your social connections are vital – to stay on top you’ll need to know the right people and stay on their good side. Network with CEOs of other companies to trade in materials and finished products, and get introductions to their powerful friends in the industry.</li><li><strong><a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge Your Business</strong> – Satisfy your board of directors by keeping your profit margins high and completing goals to ensure further investment. Don’t worry, you’re not alone out there – hire integral executives to expand your business and increase efficiency.</li><li><strong>Maintain Civic Relations</strong> – Invest in the local town to keep your workers happy and ensure a strong relationship with the local government.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Comes After coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One on May 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9.1177455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/what-comes-after-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-on-may-9<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Side-scrolling adventure game currently available for Switch and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Dolores Entertainment [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dolores-entertainment">Dolores Entertainment</a> will release <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > What Comes After" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/what-comes-after">What Comes After</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and Switch on May 9, the publisher announced. <span id="more-962268"></span></p><p>Developed by <a title="Companies > Pikselnesia [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pikselnesia">Pikselnesia</a> and <a title="Companies > Rolling Glory Jam" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rolling-glory-jam">Rolling Glory Jam</a>, <em>What Comes After</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1421760/What_Comes_After/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on November 5, 2020, followed by Switch on April 1, 2021.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via the developers:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the creator of <em><a title="Games > Coffee Talk [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/coffee-talk">Coffee Talk</a></em>, in collaboration with Rolling Glory Jam the creator of <em>Rage in Peace</em>.</p><p><em>What Comes After</em> is a short experience, a heartwarming story, and a love letter to all of you who think you’re a burden for other people.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Help Vivi finds herself through the journey that takes her to where people go after they died, to what comes after. Ride the train filled with the souls of the people, animals, and plants that are on their way to leave this world, and talk to them to learn about love, regrets, life, and death that haunt us every day until our time has come. All presented in a light-hearted way with a sprinkle of comedy and philosophy.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A short heartwarming story that will stay in your heart and memory.</li><li>A personal journey of learning how to love yourself.</li><li>A tale filled with love and comedy.</li><li>Colorful art to accompany your journey in the train not bound for the living.</li><li>An easy to pick-up gameplay.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cattle Country launches May 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/cattle-country-launches-may-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cattle-country-launches-may-27.1177407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/cattle-country-launches-may-27<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Cowboy life <a title="Genres > Simulation [727 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Cattle Country [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cattle-country">Cattle Country</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Castle Pixel [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/castle-pixel">Castle Pixel</a> announced. A demo is now available for Xbox Series, Switch, and PC, with a PlayStation 5 demo coming soon. <span id="more-962275"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2818150/Cattle_Country/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Cattle Country</em> straddles the saddle of cozy wholesome gaming and <a title="Genres > Action [2,703 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. Serving up hours of the slice-of-life you’d expect on the frontier—including mining, fishing, <a title="Genres > Crafting [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a>, and farming—along with deep-rooted Wild West <a title="Platforms > Quest [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s delivering stories of romance, cattle drives, bandits, and robberies.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Ranchin’ and Handcraftin’</strong> – Making your home on the range is a modern departure. From sunup to sundown, you’ll be rollin’ up your sleeves and gettin’ your hands dirty working the land and raising your cattle. Building and crafting as you go to make your own little slice of heaven under the blues skies of <em>Cattle Country</em>.</li><li><strong>Swappin’ Stories and Settlin’ in With Your Neighbors</strong> – Get to know the townsfolk, hear their stories, help them out. The people here are a hardy bunch- you’ve got be to survive here. But they have hearts as warm as a hearth in the wintertime if you make the effort to stoke the flames.</li><li><strong>Beware of Bandits</strong> – Not everyone in <em>Cattle Country</em> is the warm and <a title="Companies > fuzz" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fuzz">fuzz</a>y type, so watch out for nefarious plots and shady characters. Protect your homestead and your community.</li><li><strong>Rodeos to Romance</strong> – Making friends is a must in the Wilderness, relying on each other through the thick and the thin. But maybe you’ve got a yearnin’ for more? With 18 romanceable characters, take a chance and grab love by the reigns.</li><li><strong>Buried <a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a></strong> – Did yer hear? There’s treasure in the mines, for those who are brave enough to look for it. From precious metals and minerals to bandit stashes. Grab your pickaxe and venture out into the thrill of prospecting.</li><li><strong>Trackin’ Game in the Wild</strong> – From bunnies to bovine, there’s many a critter waiting in the woodlands for a keen adventurer. Hunting to eat or venturing out just to see all of nature’s wonders, it’s your call.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This is just a taste of the adventures on offer, so throw down roots and work the land. Become part of a story that’s as old as these hills and a part of this small community of settlers. Welcome to <em>Cattle Country</em>!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Cattle Country launches May 27th!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T_yWgRPXWPI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcade racing game Formula Legends announced for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/arcade-racing-game-formula-legends-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcade-racing-game-formula-legends-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.1177404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/arcade-racing-game-formula-legends-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > 3DClouds [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/3dclouds">3DClouds</a> has announced motorsport <a title="Genres > Arcade [76 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> racing game <em><a title="Games > Formula Legends" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/formula-legends">Formula Legends</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,038 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3194360/Formula_Legends/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/formula-legends-f82195" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>). It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-962065"></span></p><p>“Race fast and have fun is a mantra that has driven this game’s development from day one,” said 3DClouds CEO Francesco Bruschi in a press release. “We’ve made lots of <a title="Genres > Racing [244 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing games</a> before (from <em>Xenon</em> to <em>Paw Patrol Karts</em>, to <em>Hot Wheels Monster Trucks</em> and more), but <em>Formula Legends</em> is a true labor of love. We have some of the biggest motorsport fans in the world in our office which is only a stone’s throw away from Monza, so all of us being able to put our unbridled passion and expertise into this game has been an absolute joy. We really hope fans will dig <em>Formula Legends</em> and that we can help kickstart an arcade racing renaissance once more.”</p><div id="carousel_962068"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via 3DClouds:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Formula Legends</em> is an over-the-spoiler racing game that perfectly blends arcade accessibility with the strategic nuance found at the peak of competitive motorsports. Tyre-wear, fuel consumption, rubbering in of racing lines, damage <a title="Genres > Simulation [727 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> and changeable weather are just some of the elements that make the moment-to-moment gameplay of <em>Formula Legends</em> challenging, unpredictable and most importantly, fun.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Race faithful reimaginings of some of open-wheel racing’s most iconic cars across tracks inspired by fan-favorite locations. Developed with a deep passion and reverence for motorsports, 3DClouds is building <em>Formula Legends</em> with established racing game fans in mind and those who are just stepping into the virtual cockpit for the first time.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Drive Through Time</strong> – Slide into the cockpit of legendary cars spanning decades of motorsport history. 16 unique models, each with 7 different liveries recalling the most iconic teams of all time, for a total of 112 vehicles to experience.</li><li><strong>Iconic Circuits, Reimagined</strong> – Race across 14 circuits inspired by historic racing locations, each evolving through the years. From sun-soaked yacht docks to sweeping elevations, these tracks blend nostalgia with a fresh twist.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter Every Element</strong> – Rain-soaked asphalt, strategic pit stops, and changing eras demand more than just speed. Fine-tune your racecraft, from battery <a title="Genres > Management [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> to slipstreaming, and chase the perfect lap.</li><li><strong>Legends Behind the Wheel</strong> – Every era has its heroes. The game features over 200 fictional drivers, inspired by real-life icons, each with custom helmets and skill perks: tire whisperers, wet-weather masters, and pit-stop strategists. Their strengths could be the key to victory.</li><li><strong>A Journey Through Racing History</strong> – Story Mode invites you to relive the defining moments of Formula racing. Compete in era-based championships, master legendary cars, and carve your name into history.</li><li><strong>Customize and Compete</strong> – Create your own custom races and championships, climb the global leaderboards in Time Attack, and personalize your ride with modding support—from liveries to helmets and trackside sponsors.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/formula-legends/april-30-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Formula Legends - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oNqoFB_w1rM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>