<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 18:58:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SCP-inspired PvP tactical first-person shooter Active Matter announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/scp-inspired-pvp-tactical-first-person-shooter-active-matter-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scp-inspired-pvp-tactical-first-person-shooter-active-matter-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1021233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/scp-inspired-pvp-tactical-first-person-shooter-active-matter-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Closed beta test registration now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Gaijin Entertainment [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gaijin-entertainment">Gaijin Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Team Matter" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gaijin-entertainment/team-matter">Team Matter</a> have <a href="https://activematter.game/en/news/5" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Active Matter [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/active-matter">Active Matter</a></em>, an SCP-inspired player-versus-player tactical <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,554 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,259 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,312 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,573 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2887580/Active_Matter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A release date was not announced. Registration for an upcoming closed beta test registration is available now via the <a href="https://activematter.game/en/cbt" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>. <span id="more-924251"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2887580/Active_Matter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>You’re an operative stuck in a time loop, always brought back from the dead to the same point. Choose your loadout and enter quantum unstable zones rich with active matter—the most valuable and the most dangerous resource in all multiverse. Fight against rivals from other timelines, survive physics-breaking anomalies and try to stay alive. Harvest active matter, gather loot and extract to a safe place before the whole zone ceases to exist with everything inside it.</p><p>Active matter changes things and bends space and time, so you might encounter operatives and other survivors that lost their mind and humanity after exposure to this substance. Other players, though, would always be your most dangerous enemy. Expand your syndicate base, upgrade your arsenal and participate in fierce battles between syndicates over the key sources of active matter, as they’re your only chance to break out of the loop and gain control over your destiny.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_924259"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Player-Versus-Player-Versus-Environment Extraction-Style Raids</strong> – Players go solo or in small squads inside the quantum unstable zones in their quest for active matter and other loot. Active matter can be harvested by killing AM-transformed creatures, taken away from other players or picked up directly from active matter clusters. Join this never ending hunt to improve your chances to find the way out of the time loop.</li><li><strong>Realistic Weapons and Gear</strong> – Active matter randomly brings things from other timelines to the quantum unstable zones and allows you to replicate a specific item from other timelines in the safety of your base. Despite the mysterious origin of your weapons, your arsenal is always rooted in real-world military technologies and tactics, as war seems to be the only constant in this chaotic multiverse.</li><li><strong>Gameplay-Influencing Active Matter Effects</strong> – Mind-bending anomalies that change gravitational force and space topology right in front of your eyes. Thrilling encounters with eerie SCP-inspired objects would send shivers down your spine, and creatures transformed by active matter would attack you on sight.</li><li><strong>Intense Player-Versus-Player Battles</strong> – Syndicates of operatives fight over control of a passive source of active matter, using all the weapons and other gear they can bring into battle or craft on site. Join player-versus-player battles you like and make a real impact on the fate of the multiverse!</li><li><strong>Fascinating Maps</strong> – Battles take place at locations that exist outside of space and time boundaries. Active Matter features a variety of maps, including a huge island with rusty Soviet industrial complexes and cryptic science labs that were among the first to study this new phenomena. Explore these places to find hints on the origin of active matter.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/active-matter/october-28-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Active Matter — Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vb9Ys_Q2ypY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>