<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:45:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOKAPON! Sword of Fury for PC launches January 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/dokapon-sword-of-fury-for-pc-launches-january-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dokapon-sword-of-fury-for-pc-launches-january-21.1083630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/dokapon-sword-of-fury-for-pc-launches-january-21<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available in English and Japanese.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PC [22,132 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version of <em>DOKAPON! Sword of Fury</em> will launch via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3077020/DOKAPON_Sword_of_Fury/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250122T0100" rel="noopener" target="_blank">January 21 at 5:00 p.m. PT / 8:00 p.m. ET</a>, developer <a title="Companies > Sting [78 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sting">Sting</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/dokapon_jp/status/1879771863653683513" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. It will support English and Japanese language options. <span id="more-938679"></span></p><p>The game, a remastered version of the 1998-released PlayStation title of the same name, first launched for Switch on August 1, 2024 in Japan. It is currently unclear whether the English PC release means Sting plans to release the Switch version outside of Japan.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3077020/DOKAPON_Sword_of_Fury/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Engage in good-natured fighting with soon-to-be ex-friends! The ultimate relationship-ruining <a title="Genres > Board Game [51 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/board-game">board game</a> x <a title="Genres > RPG [16,925 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> is back, where the best way to succeed is to play dirty!</p><p>Spin the wheel and set off on an exciting <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,999 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with your friends!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Defeat monsters, purchase weapons, and level up, just like in an RPG. Once you’ve gathered enough strength, face off against powerful bosses in epic fashion! Your journey will take you across a wide, diverse world… Just don’t forget that your true goal is to get filthy rich!</p><p>Money is everything! Anything goes, as long as it lines your pockets…and as long as you’re cool with it! Will you walk the path of thievery and plunder, or will you hold firm to your morals? Will you join hands with your friends, or plot to betray them? It’s dealer’s choice around these parts!</p><p>Play even with faraway friends in Online Mode, and feel free to pause your adventure anytime with the Autosave function; it’ll be ready and waiting for you whenever you’re available again!</p><p>There’s also a full range of display settings on offer, including HD and widescreen support, allowing full immersion like never before! Game too slow for you? No problem! Speed options up to 5x ensure you can always keep things moving along at your own pace. A virtually endless array of options allows you to play the game your way: you can substitute in battle background music from earlier titles, set the number of weeks to play, adjust game balance, and more! You can even give yourself an advantage if you’re new to the <em>Dokapon</em> experience; come one, come all, as this game’s for everybody!</p><p>The Iron Sword of Rage returns to cut through all the nonsense of the 2020s in style. Come grab its hilt and give it a swing for yourself!</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_937116"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Stick it to your friends and aim to become the richest of the rich!</strong><ul><li>Whosoever winds up wealthiest in the end (meaning, the bearer of the most assets) shall be deemed the winner!</li><li>How do you achieve that? Well, by fighting monsters, plundering, pillaging, and betraying your best buds; that’s how! All the rules are made to be broken in this board game!</li><li>Need to fast-track your earnings? No problem! Try engaging with the alliance system, entering the Tenkaichi Tournament, or participating in other unique events to ka-ching like a king!</li><li>And hey, if you just want an RPG adventure in an expansive (expensive?) overworld, that’s perfectly within your reach here too!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Possibly the most heinous <em>Dokapon</em> game of them all?!</strong><ul><li>Can this even fly in the 2020s?! I guess we’ll find out, since this remastered version retains all the same irreverence the original was known for!</li><li>That classic pixel-art world from before is kept intact, but with all illustrations and 3D models updated and given new effects for their debut on the big, high-def screen!</li><li>Every 3D model is a full-on ‘toon now, while the illustrated 2D art has been fully smoothed out. But if that’s too much change for you, no problem: the original pixel art can still be tagged in as desired!</li></ul></li><li><strong>“Rock-Paper-Scissors”-style battles anyone can enjoy!</strong><ul><li>Encounter an enemy and it’s battle time! But not to worry, because these battles are simple as can be.</li><li>First off, a coin toss decides who goes first. When it’s your turn, you choose one of four possible attack types.</li><li>Choose wisely, and you’ll be doing some good old-fashioned weak-point hitting for massive damage!</li><li>But fail to predict your opponent’s defense type, and that massive damage may be yours to bear instead…</li><li>Will you be able to read your opponent like a book? Will your opponent be able to read you? The tides can turn in an instant with a single slip-up, so make your move and cross your fingers!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Same old <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> madness, but now with online matches, too!</strong><ul><li>Up to four players can rumble locally, with only a single copy of <em>Dokapon</em> among them!</li><li>Don’t have any friends nearby? (Lost them all to <em>Dokapon</em> fights?) No problem! Online multiplayer’s got your back. The world’s your oyster now!</li><li>Best of all, you can stop playing anytime you’d like (you swear!), then jump right back into the fray later on by loading up your save data!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Utilize the speed multiplier and up the game’s tempo to your liking!</strong><ul><li>Yes, you can even speed things up to make the game match your pace.</li><li>At 3x or 5x speed, even the busiest players have no excuse not to give <em>Dokapon</em> a try!</li><li>The speed multiplier can even be used online, cutting down wait times and making the sparks fly faster than ever!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Add some sugar and spice to make everything twice as nice!</strong><ul><li>Call them X-factors or secret ingredients; either way, you can access them in the System menu and rebalance the whole game as you see fit!</li><li>Just give it a pinch of this and a dash of that—only as much as you’d like.</li><li>Maybe turn down the number of rounds, for example, if you’ve got a busy schedule and can’t quite handle the usual length?</li><li>Or fine-tune the gameplay experience by giving yourself infinite magic, or limiting the number of times Wallace appears!</li><li>You can even change the background music to some classic battle themes from past <em>Dokapon</em> games, for that little extra kick of nostalgia!</li><li>What would a remaster be, after all, without that certain “je ne sais quoi” that gives this series its edge?</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria for PC launches January 23 in Asia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/the-legend-of-heroes-kai-no-kiseki-farewell-o-zemuria-for-pc-launches-january-23-in-asia</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-heroes-kai-no-kiseki-%E2%80%93-farewell-o-zemuria-for-pc-launches-january-23-in-asia.1083627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/the-legend-of-heroes-kai-no-kiseki-farewell-o-zemuria-for-pc-launches-january-23-in-asia<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PC [22,132 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version of <em><a title="Games > The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki - Farewell, O Zemuria [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-legend-of-heroes-kai-no-kiseki-farewell-o-zemuria">The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria</a></em> will launch via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3319980/The_Legend_of_Heroes_Kai_no_Kiseki_Farewell_O_Zemuria/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on January 23, publisher <a title="Companies > Clouded Leopard Entertainment [91 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/clouded-leopard-entertainment">Clouded Leopard Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> announced. It will support Japanese audio, with Korean, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese subtitles. <span id="more-938665"></span></p><p><em>The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria</em> first launched for PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 on September 26, 2024 in Japan and Asia.</p><p>Here is an overview of the PC version and game, via Clouded Leopard Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ About the Steam Version</strong></p><p><strong>Engine Powered by DirectX 12</strong></p><p>With a DirectX 12-based engine, <em>The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria</em> offers enhanced performance and cutting-edge AI-powered upscaling technologies (Intel XeSS, NVIDIA DLSS, AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution). These advancements ensure improved frame rates while maintaining stunning visuals, allowing players to experience the beautiful world of <em>The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria</em> with greater clarity and comfort.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Exclusive Features for the Steam Version!</strong></p><p>The Steam version supports 21:9 ultra-wide monitors and the Steam Deck’s 16:10 display, enabling gameplay at 4K resolution and frame rates exceeding 60 frames per second*. Enjoy a broader field of view and smoother motion for an elevated gaming experience.</p><p>*Note: Resolutions and frame rates unsupported by your monitor will not appear in the settings list.</p><p>Options like switching between windowed and full-screen modes, adjusting rendering resolution, and configuring aspect ratios can all be customized directly from the in-game settings menu. Additionally, the game’s user interface supports mouse input for <a title="Genres > Action [2,422 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s like menu navigation and item selection, ensuring a seamless experience when playing with a keyboard and mouse.</p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese Subtitles Added!</strong></p><p>To make the game accessible to even more players, Simplified Chinese has been added as a subtitle language option.</p><p><strong>■ About <em>The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki – Farewell, O Zemuria</em></strong></p><p>“In the year 120X, everything comes to an end.”</p><p>C. Epstein, the father of the orbal revolution, prophesized the end of the Zemurian continent.</p><p>As “X Day” approaches, a massive orbal rocket is about to be launched from a large military base built in the Kunlun Range.</p><p>“Can man make it past the planet’s atmosphere?”<br>“What lies at the end of the continent?”<br>“Will mankind be able to uncover the true nature of the ‘world’?”</p><p>While the whole world watches to witness the largest undertaking since the dawn of history, somewhere in the singularity that is Ored, forces from all over the land were about to gather, including a young “Spriggan.”</p><p>Will the single trail toward the distant heavens ultimately shape the future of Zemuria, or…</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. </p><h2><span>PC Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Steam The Legend of Heroes: Kai no Kiseki -Farewell, O Zemuria- Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I6jGeb8nWc4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="Steam『영웅전설 계의 궤적 -Farewell, O Zemuria-』 발표 트레일러" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/134W-pW63G8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="Steam《英雄傳說 界之軌跡 -告別塞姆利亞-》發表宣傳影片" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y-EYgNLKJlA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Steam《英雄传说 界之轨迹 -告别塞姆利亚-》發表宣傳视频" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_pc_mBHl_eU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves physical edition pre-orders now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-physical-edition-pre-orders-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-physical-edition-pre-orders-now-available.1083594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-physical-edition-pre-orders-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available in Special and Deluxe editions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > SNK Corporation [407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/snk">SNK</a> has opened physical edition pre-orders for <em><a title="Games > Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a></em>. The game will be available in a $59.99 / €59.99 Special Edition for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,662 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,594 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,572 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, as well as a $79.99 / €79.99 Deluxe Edition for PlayStation 5. <span id="more-938479"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Special Edition</strong> ($59.99 / €59.99) (for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Xbox Series)</p><ul><li>A copy of the game</li><li>Season Pass 1 (five downloadable content characters)</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Fatal-Fury-CotW_Pre-Order_01-15-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> ($79.99 / €79.99) (for PlayStation 5 only)</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>A copy of the game</li><li>Season Pass 1 (five downloadable content characters)</li><li>SteelBook</li><li>Two-disc original soundtrack</li><li>100-plus-pages art book</li><li>Stickers</li><li>Collector’s box</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Fatal-Fury-CotW_Pre-Order_01-15-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Pre-Order Bonus</strong></p><p>Physical copies of <em>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</em> will include an exclusive <em>Fatal Fury 2</em> Terry downloadable content costume (limited availability).</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Fatal-Fury-CotW_Pre-Order_01-15-25_003.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p><em>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2492040/FATAL_FURY_City_of_the_Wolves/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/garou-city-of-the-wolves-556c5a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on April 24.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fuga: Melodies of Steel 3 teaser website opened, news coming January 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/fuga-melodies-of-steel-3-teaser-website-opened-news-coming-january-23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fuga-melodies-of-steel-3-teaser-website-opened-news-coming-january-23.1083576/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/fuga-melodies-of-steel-3-teaser-website-opened-news-coming-january-23<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > CyberConnect2 [601 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberconnect2">CyberConnect2</a> has opened the <a href="https://www.cc2.co.jp/fuga3/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">teaser website</a> for <em><a title="Games > Fuga: Melodies of Steel 3" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fuga-melodies-of-steel-3">Fuga: Melodies of Steel 3</a></em>, which teases more information to come on January 23. <span id="more-938644"></span></p><p><em><a title="Games > Fuga: Melodies of Steel [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fuga-melodies-of-steel">Fuga: Melodies of Steel</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Fuga: Melodies of Steel 2 [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fuga-melodies-of-steel-2">Fuga: Melodies of Steel 2</a></em> are available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,662 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,572 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,594 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,706 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,520 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,132 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, having launched in July 2021 and May 2023, respectively. <em>Fuga: Melodies of Steel 3</em> is planned for release in 2025.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma second trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-second-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-second-trailer.1083564/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-second-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on May 30.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Marvelous [1,329 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous">Marvelous</a> has released the second official trailer for <em><a title="Games > Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a></em>, which was <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-launches-may-30">recently announced</a> as launching for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,520 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,132 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2864560/Rune_Factory_Guardians_of_Azuma/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 30. <span id="more-938634"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a title="Companies > Marvelous USA [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous/marvelous-usa">Marvelous USA</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The classic <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,466 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> and life-<a title="Genres > Simulation [629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a>play beloved by <em><a title="Series > Rune Factory [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/rune-factory">Rune Factory</a></em> fans across the globe is boldly reimagined in Guardians of Azuma. This all-new <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,999 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> takes place in the never-before-seen eastern country of Azuma where you will assume the Earth Dancer powers and fight against the corruption spreading throughout Azuma to bring hope back to this once-prosperous land.</p><p>Choose from one of two protagonists whose destinies are intertwined by mysterious forces. Use sacred treasures to fight against the Blight’s many forms to restore the people, and even gods, to their natural glory. Take farming further, as you’ll manage more than a plot, rebuilding entire villages and cultivating new allies and resources along the way. Explore seasonal-themed villages heavily inspired by traditional Japanese culture, each with brand-new festivals and revamped fan-favorites, as well as charming romance candidates. Embrace your fate. The adventure of a new world awaits.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The Celestial Collapse—a calamity caused by a colossal object crashing into the eastern lands known as Azuma. The devastating impact sent fragments of terrain to the skies above and the seas below. With the earth shattered, the power provided by the runes ceased to flow. The gods of nature vanished soon after. Mountains crumbled and fields withered, leaving the people with nothing…not even hope.</p><p>You awaken, startled by a dream of dueling dragons. You don’t remember how or why, but a voice resonates within you.</p><p>“Accept the power of an Earth Dancer. Use this power to save the land.”</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Bold New Abilities and Weapons</strong> – As an Earth Dancer, use the power of dance, sacred treasures, and fresh weapons like the Bow and Talisman to purify the land, your farms, and undo the Blight’s damage.</li><li><strong>It Takes a Village</strong> – Don’t just mind the farm—rebuild entire villages! Construct and place buildings, enticing people to return to the villages and contribute. Revive the gods to bring vitality and valuable resources back to the plagued lands.</li><li><strong>Your Fantasy Japanese Life</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> beautiful Japanese-inspired character designs and aesthetics—from festivals to events to monsters. Explore Azuma’s natural landscapes and its seasonal-themed locales steeped in tradition.</li><li><strong>Classic Romance and Relationships</strong> – Choose between male and female protagonists, then befriend or romance any of the eligible candidates in fully voiced scenarios. Recruit these new friends to aid you in battle, too.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Trailer #2</span></h2><p><iframe title="『龍の国 ルーンファクトリー』プロモーション映像②" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ngB2ikJszeQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Trailer #2: Short Version</span></h2><p><iframe title="『龍の国 ルーンファクトリー』プロモーション映像② ショートVer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cQV0FF0zPH4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP free update adds ‘Photo Mode’ and ‘Goth Outfit’ in early February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-free-update-adds-photo-mode-and-goth-outfit-in-early-february</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-free-update-adds-%E2%80%98photo-mode%E2%80%99-and-%E2%80%98goth-outfit%E2%80%99-in-early-february.1083543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-free-update-adds-photo-mode-and-goth-outfit-in-early-february<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Adjust camera angle, depth of field, poses, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Dragami Games [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/extreme/dragami-games">Dragami Games</a> will release a free update for <em><a title="Games > Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lollipop-chainsaw-repop">Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP</a></em> in early February that adds a “Photo Mode” and “Goth Outfit” costume, the company announced. <span id="more-938630"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Capture Your Unique Moments with the New “Photo Mode”!</strong></p><p>The “Photo Mode” allows players to pause the game at any moment and take stunning in-game photos. Once activated, players can adjust the camera angle, depth of field, Juliet’s poses, and facial expressions to create their own original shots. By using the screenshot functionality of each platform, players can capture their masterpiece.</p><p>Additionally, players can enhance their photos with filters and frames for a more personalized touch. Be sure to check the official LOLLIPOP CHAINSAW RePOP website for detailed instructions on how to use this feature. Don’t miss the opportunity to create your perfect shot!</p><p><strong>Introducing the Long-Awaited “Goth Outfit” Costume!</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The “Goth Outfit” costume was originally distributed as a store-exclusive bonus for the previous <em>Lollipop Chainsaw</em> game, characterized by its distinctive black rouge.</p><p>This outfit exudes a dark atmosphere, allowing you to enjoy a different side of Juliet’s charm.</p><p>Be sure to experience this new style along with the “Photo Mode”!</p><p><strong>Free Major Update Release Schedule</strong></p><p>The free major update is scheduled for release on all platforms in early February. Please look forward to it!</p></blockquote><p><em>Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,662 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,572 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,594 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,706 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,520 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,132 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2658450/LOLLIPOP_CHAINSAW_RePOP/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>