<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 03:50:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Omega Crafter launches May 14]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/omega-crafter-launches-may-14</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/omega-crafter-launches-may-14.1157901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/omega-crafter-launches-may-14<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently in Early Access.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Open-world <a title="Genres > Survival [402 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Crafting [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,189 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Omega Crafter [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/omega-crafter">Omega Crafter</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,811 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2262080/Omega_Crafter/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 14 for @4.99, developer <a title="Companies > Preferred Networks [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/preferred-networks">Preferred Networks</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2262080/view/502821376452723239" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-956429"></span></p><p><em>Omega Crafter</em> first launched on Early Access on March 28, 2024. The version 1.0 release will introduce the fifth biome, “Lost World,” as well as new features that further enhance automation and building.</p><p>Here are the latest details, via Preferred Networks:</p><blockquote><p>Can the top engineer on a game design team save the developing virtual world from malicious programs manifesting as in-game monsters? Enter the game solo or form a debugging committee with five additional friends alongside sidekick Grammi, and begin a bespoke journey through five procedurally-generated digital landscapes—filled with distinct enemies, items, and resources—creating new adventures in every instance.</p><p>In 1.0, survive meteor showers amidst futuristic ruins in the all-new fifth biome, “Lost World.” Assemble a radar from discovered spare parts to track meteor cycles, and take refuge underneath towers during each shower of rocky rain. Uncover the locations of twenty-five Shrines of Programming dispersed throughout <em>Omega Crafter</em>‘s world, where coding acumen can unlock new skills and exclusive items.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_956432"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>Uncover the root cause of <em>Omega Crafter</em>‘s mysterious buggy behavior… after learning to survive the digital realm! Learn the basics of shelter, weaponry, and dungeon-diving in the Meadows of New Beginnings, then upgrade gear along the way to best each biome’s boss in battle and advance to the next world. Explore the edges of the Endless Wilds, face the fearsome Halloween Forest, and journey to Japan-inspired Fallen Samurai Isle.</p><p>Cultivate a cozy village, fashion a fully-functioning metropolis, and anything in between with the new Creative Mode featuring 250+ building elements and no resource restrictions. Enjoy additional quality-of-life improvements such as simplified item searching with the new Reverse Item Lookup List, added skills, minigames, items, an improved tutorial, updated background music, and much more.</p><p>No journey is too arduous with Grammi’s help! Program behaviors that speed up everyday tasks with both simple and complex automation options: activate simple single-click behaviors like automatic resource-gathering, or program multi-step behaviors with “if / then” sequences, variables, and error detection. With the right commands, Grammi can chop down trees, turn trees into lumber, and place resources into storage bins with a single command!</p><p>Enjoy <em>Omega Crafter</em>‘s epic battle themes and relaxing melodies outside of the game with the original soundtrack available for purchase at launch, featuring 19 original tracks.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/omega-crafter/april-7-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Omega Crafter - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MH0Xf48a100?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>