<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 16:27:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Monthly Games lineup for September 2025 announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/playstation-plus-monthly-games-lineup-for-september-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-monthly-games-lineup-for-september-2025-announced.1281990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Psychonauts 2, Stardew Valley, and Viewfinder.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,046 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/08/27/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-september-psychonauts-2-stardew-valley-viewfinder/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the September 2025 Monthly Games lineup for <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,379 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Plus Essential subscribers. All titles will be available from September 2. <span id="more-988537"></span></p><p>The full list of Monthly Games is as follows:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Psychonauts 2 [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/psychonauts-2">Psychonauts 2</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,296 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a>) – Razputin “Raz” Aquato, trained acrobat and powerful young psychic, has realized his lifelong dream of joining the international psychic espionage organization known as the Psychonauts! But these psychic super spies are in trouble. Their leader hasn’t been the same since he was rescued from a kidnapping, and what’s worse, there’s a mole hiding in headquarters. Combining quirky missions and mysterious conspiracies, <em>Psychonauts 2</em> is a platform-<a title="Genres > Adventure [2,514 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> with cinematic style and tons of customizable psychic powers. <em>Psychonauts 2</em> serves up danger, excitement and laughs in equal measure as players guide Raz on a journey through the minds of friends and foes on a quest to defeat a murderous psychic villain.</li><li><strong><em>Stardew Valley</em></strong> (PS4) –&nbsp;You’ve inherited your grandfather’s old farm plot in Stardew Valley. Armed with hand-me-down tools and a few coins, you set out to begin your new life. Can you learn to live off the land and turn these overgrown fields into a thriving home? It won’t be easy. Ever since Joja Corporation came to town, the old ways of life have all but disappeared. The community center, once the town’s most vibrant hub of activity, now lies in shambles. But the valley seems full of opportunity. With a little dedication, you might just be the one to restore Stardew Valley to greatness!</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Viewfinder [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/viewfinder">Viewfinder</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,254 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a>, PS4) –&nbsp;Use an instant camera to challenge perception, redefine reality and reshape the world. View the world through a new lens in this charming and unique first-person puzzle adventure. Reshape a wealth of stunning environments through your instant camera’s viewfinder in order to solve a variety of mind-bending puzzles. Bring photos, paintings, sketches and postcards to life as you reshape reality and slowly uncover the surprising mysteries that lie behind this colorful world.</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/playstation-plus-monthly-games-lineup-for-september-2025-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Games announces free-to-play MOBA strategy game March of Giants for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/amazon-games-announces-free-to-play-moba-strategy-game-march-of-giants-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-games-announces-free-to-play-moba-strategy-game-march-of-giants-for-pc.1281987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Closed alpha test set for September 2 to 10.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Amazon Games [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/amazon-games">Amazon Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Amazon Games Montreal" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/amazon-games/amazon-games-montreal">Amazon Games Montreal</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > March of Giants [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/march-of-giants">March of Giants</a></em>, a  <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [434 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> four-versus-four war <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> online battle arena <a title="Genres > Strategy [280 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [24,100 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1924600/March_of_Giants/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A closed alpha test will run from September 2 to 10. <span id="more-988555"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1924600/March_of_Giants/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A free-to-play four-versus-four war multiplayer online battle arena game where you play as a Giant, lead an army of soldiers and deploy tactical structures known as “Battleworks” on a ravaged urban battlefield.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Play as a Giant</strong> – Dominate the battlefield as a towering war commander in strategic 4v4 combat. From crowd controllers to burst and sustained damage specialists, harness your Giant’s unique abilities to secure victory for your team.</li><li><strong>Lead Your Soliders</strong> – Lead thousands of fearless soldiers, guiding their movement to support your team’s advance. Send them charging into enemy Giants, storm outposts and assert relentless lane pressure.</li><li><strong>Deploy Battleworks</strong> – Position powerful reinforcements like trenches, tanks, and bunkers to turn the tide of battle. These Battleworks can be the difference between a tactical advantage and a strategic retreat. How will you outplay the enemy team?</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the closed alpha announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.marchofgiants.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Closed Alpha Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="March of Giants:  Closed Alpha Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qRPtu6guX9Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/amazon-games-announces-free-to-play-moba-strategy-game-march-of-giants-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>