<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:16:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Legends: Z-A DLC ‘Mega Dimension’ reveals Mega Lucario Z]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/pokemon-legends-z-a-dlc-mega-dimension-reveals-mega-lucario-z</link>
            <guid>1370254</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Plus, add the Legendary Pokemon Mewtwo to your team.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > The Pokemon Company [437 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-pokemon-company">The Pokemon Company</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Game Freak [288 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/game-freak">Game Freak</a> have released a new trailer and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Pokemon Legends: Z-A [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a">Pokemon Legends: Z-A</a></em> downloadable content “Mega Dimension” introducing the Mega-Evolved <a title="Series > Pokemon [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/pokemon">Pokemon</a> Mega Lucario Z. <span id="more-1010375"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Mega Lucario Z</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Category:</strong> Aura Pokemon​</li><li><strong>Type:</strong> Fighting/Steel</li><li><strong>Height:</strong> 4’3″ (1.3 m)</li><li><strong>Weight:</strong> 108.9 lbs. (49.4 kg)</li></ul><p>A newly discovered form of Lucario, Mega Lucario Z was determined to be a Mega Evolution based on how its form changes through exposure to a Mega Stone and its increase in power far outshining that of an average Lucario.</p><p>The long fur around Mega Lucario Z’s head and waist, as well as its fan-shaped tail, make it difficult to get a full view of Mega Lucario Z’s powerful movements. In close combat, this can work to visually disorient opponents. Areas of its body, such as the backs of its hands and its shins, have been hardened with steel energy—allowing it to deliver powerful blows by concentrating its strength precisely into these hardened parts.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Z Mega Evolutions, such as Mega Lucario Z, need less time to fire off moves but burn through Mega Power very quickly, making them less suited for long battles but a good option when trying to settle matches as fast as possible.</p><p>While Mega Lucario, the Mega Evolution of Lucario, appears in <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em>, the newly discovered Mega Lucario Z will appear in the downloadable content “Mega Dimension.”​</p><p><strong>Extra Side Mission Now Availalbe</strong></p><p>Starting today, Trainers can receive a Mewtwonite X stone and a Mewtwonite Y stone through the <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>ery Gift feature in <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>and <em><a title="Games > Pokemon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokemon Legends: Z-A – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></em>. Once the player receives the Mewtwonite X and Mewtwonite Y stones, Mewtwo’s extra side mission will become available. It appears heading to Lysandre Cafe and venturing into the deepest areas of Lysandre Labs may cause some systems to reactivate in response to the Mega Stones, and beating this side mission will allow you to add the Legendary Pokemon Mewtwo to your team.</p></blockquote><p><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,036 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>. The downloadable content “Mega Dimension” is due out on December 10 for $29.99 / 3,000 yen.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/pokemon-legends-z-a/december-2-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “Mega Dimension”: Mega Lucario Z Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Pokémon Legends: Z-A – Mega Dimension | Mega Lucario Z Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V_UkrLROjkA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『Pokémon LEGENDS Z-A M次元ラッシュ』紹介映像「メガルカリオＺ」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hzoJMEzMNLU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Get Mewtwo and Mewtwonite Stones</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Pokémon Legends: Z-A | Get Mewtwo and Mewtwonite Stones" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRt5h-Yrp_0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【公式】ミュウツーを仲間に！｜『Pokémon LEGENDS Z-A』でＥＸサイドミッション配信開始" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E9FrB2-KJ80?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1010377"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/pokemon-legends-z-a-dlc-mega-dimension-reveals-mega-lucario-z]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drag x Drive version 1.2.0 update now available, adds Survival Tag]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/drag-x-drive-version-1-2-0-update-now-available-adds-survival-tag</link>
            <guid>1370197</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Plus other updates and bug fixes.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Platforms > Nintendo [23,201 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> has <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68646/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> the version 1.2.0 update for <em><a title="Games > Drag x Drive [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a></em>, which adds the chasing game <a title="Genres > Survival [489 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> Tag to friend parks, local wireless parks, and LAN parks. <span id="more-1010554"></span></p><p>Get the patch notes below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>General Updates</strong></p><ul><li>Added the chasing game Survival Tag to friend parks, local wireless parks, and LAN parks.<ul><li>Note: To play Survival Tag when in the parks listed above, the player who created the park opens the X Menu, then selects&nbsp;<strong>Start Survival Tag</strong>&nbsp;on the Players tab.</li><li>Depending on the wireless environment, there may be times where player positioning does not perfectly match between users. For that reason, there may be cases where, even if it appears to one player as if contact was made, from the other player’s perspective no contact occurred. In order to limit unpleasant experiences in situations like these as much as possible, in basketball games this may be determined as no contact.</li><li>On the other hand, in Survival Tag, the question of contact is the whole crux of the game and is particularly important to game progression. Therefore, it has been designed such that a tag is considered successful if there was contact from either perspective (the tagging player, or the one who was tagged).</li></ul></li><li>Corrected the calculation of Iso Wins on the Game Stats tab under Stats. Previously, it counted the total number of Isos, not just wins.</li><li>Added Rope Jumps to Other Stats tab under Stats.</li><li>Changed the target of the Focus Cam when near the sumo ring to the sumo ring itself.</li><li>Made some adjustments to bots in friend parks, local wireless parks, and LAN parks.<!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Note: We slightly lowered the strength level of the Easy and Standard bots that the player who created the park can add under the Players tab of the X Menu.</li></ul></li><li>Added a feature to enable players to delete their own records.<ul><li>On the screen that displays players’ records before starting time trials or shooting contests, simultaneously press and hold the ZL Button, left directional button, and right directional button on the Joy-Con 2 (L) for 10 seconds to delete the record.</li><li>Once deleted, records cannot be restored.</li><li>Obtained trophies will remain, even if records are deleted.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p><ul><li>Fixed a very rare issue where, due to unintended behavior, the displays for level or total distance would reach the upper limit.</li><li>Fixed a rare issue in Circuit Sprint where players sometimes passed through terrain.</li><li>Fixed an issue where bunny hops made it possible to accelerate to and maintain speed that exceeded top speed.<ul><li>The intended design is that it is only possible to accelerate beyond the normal top speed when driving down a slope or successfully pulling off a halfpipe or ramp trick. However, unintended behavior occurred, such as players accelerating beyond top speed when landing after rotating, or not decelerating while in midair even if they had exceeded top speed. We fixed this because this issue required players to control their character in unintuitive ways in order to achieve good results.</li></ul></li><li>Fixed various issues to create a smoother gaming experience.</li></ul><p><strong>Note</strong>: Version 1.1.1 for the&nbsp;<em>Drag x Drive Demo</em>&nbsp;(formerly&nbsp;<em>Drag x Drive: Global Jam</em>) was also released.</p><p><strong>General Updates</strong></p><ul><li>Changed software title from&nbsp;<em>Drag x Drive: Global Jam</em>&nbsp;to&nbsp;<em>Drag x Drive Demo</em>.</li><li>Changed the software icon that displays in locations such as the HOME Menu.</li><li>Made it possible to play the tutorial and certain bot games any time.</li><li>Fixed various issues to create a smoother gaming experience.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Drag x Drive</em> is available for <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/drag-x-drive-version-1-2-0-update-now-available-adds-survival-tag]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>