<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:22:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gravelord launches in Early Access on January 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/gravelord-launches-in-early-access-on-january-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gravelord-launches-in-early-access-on-january-22.1077069/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/gravelord-launches-in-early-access-on-january-22<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Putting the fun back in funeral.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Fast-paced “boomer” <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,587 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Gravelord" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gravelord">Gravelord</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,077 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1823990/Gravelord/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on January 22, developer <a title="Companies > Fatbot Games [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fatbot-games">Fatbot Games</a> announced. A demo is currently available. <span id="more-937344"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1823990/Gravelord/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Gravelord</em> is a fast-paced boomer shooter voiced by a badass protagonist featuring hand-crafted levels filled with secrets and hordes of enemies to kill. Dish out some brutal carnage with powerful guns and collect Tarot Cards to gain even more killing power. Let’s put the fun back in funeral!</p><p><strong>Proven Boomer <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,970 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">Shooter</a> Formula</strong></p><ul><li>Run and jump around levels like a complete badass.</li><li>Beat the living hell out of enemies and blow them up with powerful weapons like there’s no tomorrow.</li><li>Abstract level design heavily aimed at fun and engaging gameplay rather than realism.</li><li>Figure out how to beat each level and find its deviously hidden secrets.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>So What’s the Special Sauce?</strong></p><ul><li>Badass Protagonist: We’re bringing back the sassy, witty one-liners like Duke Nukem mixed with the rotten charisma of Frankenstein’s monster.</li><li>Use your Spectral Shovel to get around quickly and confuse enemies.</li><li>Collect Tarot Cards to significantly boost your power level and combat options.</li><li>Upgrade your weapons to unlock additional fire modes and synergies.</li><li>Make your own levels with the integrated Level Editor! (This will officially come out with the full release of the game.)</li></ul><p><strong>Badass Protagonist</strong></p><ul><li>Queedo the Gravedigger, dumb as hell but as strong as an ox, sets out to avenge his father while using his trusty Total Uber Shovel to beat the living crap out of his enemies and give them a first-class ticket to the underworld.</li><li>Big boy has opinions: Queedo comments on what’s going on with his typical sense of rotten humor and Cockney accent.</li><li>Comic book cutscenes fill in the blanks and drive the story forward.</li><li>Find and collect comic book pages to learn more about the world and the backstory.</li><li>See Queedo’s face react to events and get smashed to a pulp when you’re getting your ass handed to you!</li></ul><p><strong>Spectral Shovel</strong></p><ul><li>Use your Spectral Shovel to cover great distances in an instant.</li><li>Overcome seemingly unbeatable obstacles and hazards.</li><li>Enable shortcuts to previously discovered parts of a level.</li></ul><p><strong>Tarot Cards</strong></p><ul><li>Collect magical Tarot Cards that empower you in various ways.</li><li>Because only a few can be equipped at a time, you’ll be faced with a difficult choice!</li><li>Find the combination that best fits your playstyle.</li><li>Discover synergies with weapons and alt fire modes.</li></ul><p><strong>Weapons and Upgrades</strong></p><ul><li>Choose from an array of meaningful weapons.</li><li>Use the best weapon for any given situation, or just rely on your favorite—both ways are viable!</li><li>Upgrade your weapons to unlock a second, powerful fire mode.</li><li>Discover synergies between weapons and their fire modes to create maximum carnage!</li></ul><p><strong>Level Editor</strong></p><p>Note: We will officially release the Level Editor with the full release of the game.</p><ul><li>Use our integrated level editor to make your own levels and episodes, right within the game. It’s the same tool we use ourselves.</li><li>Instantly playtest your level from wherever you are in the editor. The transition between the editor and the game is quick and seamless.</li><li>Script the level to your liking, from simple monster closets to complicated overarching puzzles.</li><li>Tools, such as automatic texture hotspotting, intuitive geometry tweaking and cutting, and more, will make it a breeze to build a level of your dreams very quickly.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GRAVELORD - Official Early Access Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WnlYMvxAsv4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>