<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 17:19:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: E-Day co-developed by People Can Fly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/gears-of-war-e-day-co-developed-by-people-can-fly</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-e-day-co-developed-by-people-can-fly.1092888/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/gears-of-war-e-day-co-developed-by-people-can-fly<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Gears of War: Judgment studio returns for series' latest entry.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > People Can Fly [84 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/people-can-fly">People Can Fly</a>, which served as the lead developer on&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Judgment</em> and a co-development partner on the original <em>Gears of War</em> trilogy, is working with <a title="Companies > The Coalition [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/xbox-game-studios/the-coalition">The Coalition</a> as a co-development partner on <em><a title="Games > Gears of War: E-Day [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gears-of-war-e-day">Gears of War: E-Day</a></em>, the studio <a href="https://peoplecanfly.com/partnership-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. <span id="more-940584"></span></p><p>“Returning to collaborate on the next chapter of this legendary saga is both a privilege and an exciting opportunity to build upon the intense, visceral <a title="Genres > Action [2,444 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and rich storytelling that fans have come to love,” said People Can Fly CEO Sebastian Wojciehowski in a press release. “We are deeply grateful for our partners’ trust and support on this journey.”</p><p>The Coalition studio head Mike Crump added, “<em>Gears of War: E-Day</em> is not just our next major game; it’s a return to what makes <em>Gears of War</em> games special and authentic. We’re pleased to be partnering with the talented folks at People Can Fly who have been a part of our franchise’s legacy for so long.”</p><p>People Can Fly development director Guillaume Barry said, “Our team at People Can Fly, made up of dedicated <em>Gears of War</em> fans, is pouring everything we have into creating an experience that will exceed expectations. While we can’t share more just yet, we’re eager for the day when we can show all the exciting things we’ve been working on.”</p><p><em>Gears of War: E-Day</em> will be available for Xbox Series and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3010850/Gears_of_War_EDay/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and Microsoft Store. A release date has yet to be announced.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos coming to PC in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-coming-to-pc-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-coming-to-pc-in-2025.1092828/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-coming-to-pc-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PlayStation and Switch versions due out on January 28 in the west.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [390 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,204 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a> will release <em><a title="Games > Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos">Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-940579"></span></p><p><em>Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and witch on June 27, 2024 in Japan, and is due out for those platforms on January 28 in the west.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Idea Factory International:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>This dimension is different from Gamindustri…</p><p>A vast number of distinct Dogoos are appearing and threatening to cover the land.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>To escape from this otherworldly realm, a lone rider surveys the mysterious world in search of an exit.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dogoo Day Care</strong> – Choose from six playable characters, scour the land on your trusty bike, and collect as many variants of Dogoos as possible to win! As players progress through 15 Dogoo-filled stages, Uzume must find a way to snap her friends out of their weird fascination with Dogoos!</li><li><strong>The Dogoo Bounty Hunter</strong> – Collecting Dogoos can be a cinch, but stealing Dogoos is a whole ‘notha ball game! Certain characters shine more in close combat, while others excel in long-range attacks. Find the strengths (and weaknesses, of course!) to become a true Dogoo bounty hunter!</li><li><strong>These Dogoos Do Bike Back</strong> – As squishy and adorable as these Dogoos are, some can be quite the menace. Each Dogoo has specific types of behaviors, as well as positive/negative effects when collecting them. By learning the positive and negative effects of the Dogoos, you can use them to your advantage and even throw the nasty ones to your opponent!</li><li><strong>Stunt Your Bike</strong> – Want to show off your ride in the next bike meet? Impress (or scare?) Dogoos by altering the bike’s body, muffler, tires, and other accessories! These customizations can give the Goddesses increased defense, max speed, acceleration, and even maneuverability. These upgrades can ultimately give you the winning edge!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PC Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos | Announcement Trailer | Steam®" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6K3hDTtHNX0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>