<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:40:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Group Corporation and Bandai Namco Holdings sign strategic partnership]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/sony-group-corporation-and-bandai-namco-holdings-sign-strategic-partnership</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-group-corporation-and-bandai-namco-holdings-sign-strategic-partnership.1251792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Sony Group Corporation acquires 2.5 percent of Bandai Namco Holdings.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Group Corporation [1,406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation">Sony Group Corporation</a> and <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> Holdings have signed a strategic business alliance agreement aimed at strengthening engagement among anime and manga fans, which will also see Sony acquire 16 million Bandai Namco shares for 68 billion yen, becoming a shareholder holding approximately 2.5 percent of total issued shares of Bandai Namco, the companies <a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/news/20250724_E.pdf" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-979915"></span></p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Strategic Business Alliance</strong></p><p>Through this business alliance and Sony’s investment in Bandai Namco, as two of the leading Japanese entertainment companies, Bandai Namco and Sony will focus on expanding the fan community for [intellectual property] such as anime and manga around the world and strengthening engagement, particularly in the anime field where rapid market growth is anticipated, while merging their strengths to create new and emotionally moving experiences for fans, and as a result of these efforts maximize the value of [intellectual property].</p><p>Bandai Namco and Sony have historically collaborated on various projects in the fields such as games, anime and music, and they plan to extend this collaboration to a broader range of areas. The two companies intend to implement initiatives including the expansion of works as well as products and services based on [intellectual property] developed by Bandai Namco, leveraging Sony’s strengths in areas such as the production and distribution of anime and other video content, as well as merchandising. They also plan to engage in detailed discussions regarding the joint development and promotion of [intellectual property] such as anime and manga, in addition to planning and technical collaboration on experiential entertainment. Furthermore, the two companies plan to explore opportunities to support creators by jointly developing and operating entertainment-related technologies and services, and to engage in joint investments and business alliances in fan engagement areas.</p><p><strong>■ Comments</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Nobuhiko Momoi, Executive Vice President, Bandai Namco Holdings Inc.</strong></p><p>“The Bandai Namco Group promotes an ‘[intellectual property] axis strategy’ that aims to maximize [intellectual property] value by leveraging the appeal and worldview of [intellectual property], providing the optimal products and services at the optimal timing in the optimal regions. We are filled with excitement about the potential to create new entertainment by combining Sony Group’s strengths and technological capabilities across various entertainment fields with Bandai Namco’s [intellectual property] axis strategy. Through this collaboration, we aim to connect with [intellectual property] fans worldwide, cocreate the future together, and realize our Purpose, ‘Fun for All into the Future,’ and Mid- to Long-term Vision, ‘Connect with Fans.'”</p><p><strong>Toshimoto Mitomo, Chief <a title="Genres > Strategy [267 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">Strategy</a> Officer, Representative Corporate Executive Officer, Sony Group Corporation</strong></p><p>“Through this partnership, we aim to co-create an array of content and experiences that exceed expectations and deliver Kando (emotion) to even more fans, alongside Bandai Namco Group, with its outstanding capacity for multidirectional expansion of diverse [intellectual property] and deep connections with fans at real touchpoints, both domestically and internationally. By combining the strengths of both companies in the field of entertainment and unlocking the potential of compelling [intellectual property], we will further accelerate our efforts to maximize [intellectual property] value and realize Sony’s long-term vision, ‘Creative Entertainment Vision.'”</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/sony-group-corporation-and-bandai-namco-holdings-sign-strategic-partnership]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter details Zeiss characters and places; trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-details-zeiss-characters-and-places-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-details-zeiss-characters-and-places-trailer.1251762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [743 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> has released new footage, information, and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a></em>, introducing Zeiss characters Professor Albert Russell, Kilika Rouran, Major Maximillian Cid, and Maintenance Chief <a title="Companies > Gust [812 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/gust">Gust</a>av, as well several locations. <span id="more-979798"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ Characters</strong></p><p><strong>Professor Albert Russell</strong> (voiced by Jim Meskimen in English, Yoku Shioya in Japanese)</p><ul><li><strong>Age:</strong> 68</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_001.png"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>A genius orbal engineer of the Liberl Kingdom.</p><p>A free-spirited, eccentric orbal engineer.</p><p>Professor Russell is a legendary genius who paved the way in advancing orbal technology. He founded the Zeiss Engineering Factory (now the Zeiss Central Factory), and is credited with inventing the modern-day airship.</p><p>He is also recognized as one of the three great disciples of Professor C. Epstein, the inventor of orbments.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Kilika Rouran</strong> (voiced by Meli Grant in English, Haruka Michii in Japanese)</p><ul><li><strong>Age:</strong> 27</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_005.png"></a></figure><p>A receptionist of the Bracer Guild’s Zeiss branch.</p><p>A woman from the Calvard Republic who serves as the receptionist for the Zeiss branch of the Bracer Guild.</p><p>Always thinking two or three steps ahead and preparing for the worst-case scenario, Kilika possesses remarkable analytical skills that far exceed what would be expected of a guild receptionist.</p><p>She is also said to be well-versed in martial arts, and has known the bracer Zin from the Republic for many years.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_006.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_007.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_008.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Major Maximillian Cid</strong> (voiced by John Patneaude in English, Kengo Takanashi in Japanese)</p><ul><li><strong>Age:</strong> 32</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_009.png"></a></figure><p>The commanding officer of Leiston Fortress.</p><p>Major Cid is a deeply sincere individual who holds military discipline to the highest standard. His <a title="Genres > Action [2,887 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s have earned him the trust and respect of his subordinates.</p><p>As a versatile fighter who excels in both swordsmanship and orbal arts, Cid’s skill ranks among the very top in the entire Royal Army of Liberl.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_010.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_012.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Maintenance Chief Gustav</strong> (voiced by Andrew Kishino in English, Makoto Sahara in Japanese)</p><ul><li><strong>Age:</strong> 48</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_013.png"></a></figure><p>The maintenance chief of the Zeiss Central Factory, easily recognizable by his bandana and unshaven stubble.</p><p>Despite his no-nonsense, hard-working personality, he also possesses a surprisingly easygoing side, showing patience and understanding toward Factory Chief Murdock’s anxieties and Professor Russell’s troublesome tendencies.</p><p>Gustav also works as the chief overseer of the factory ship Leibnitz, the pride of Zeiss. His skills as a mechanic are highly regarded by everyone around him.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_014.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_015.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_016.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Locations</strong></p><p><strong>Industrial City of Zeiss</strong></p><p>The heart of the Kingdom of Liberl’s orbment production industry.</p><p>A city in which innovative technologies such as escalators, elevators, and even lane-changing airship landing ports are all made possible through orbments. <a title="Games > Beneath [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/beneath">Beneath</a> the streets of Zeiss lies an extensive orbal factory, boasting some of the most advanced technology on the continent.</p><p>At the forefront of cutting-edge orbal research and development is the Zeiss Central Factory, which also serves as the city’s administrative hub. Its Factory Chief, Murdock, acts as the mayor of Zeiss.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_017.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_018.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Elmo Village</strong></p><p>Situated near the border with the Republic of Calvard to the east, this village is renowned for its hot springs.</p><p>Though Elmo is a small village with just the Maple Leaf Inn and a single souvenir shop, its open-air baths offer a liberating atmosphere and are highly rated by tourists. Many visitors from abroad return for the relaxing experience.</p><p>A relatively large number of villagers in Elmo have Eastern origins, and the architecture and interior decor reflect a distinctly Eastern aesthetic.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_019.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Leiston Fortress</strong></p><p>Located on the southern shore of Valleria <a title="Games > Lake [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lake">Lake</a>, this fortress serves as the headquarters of Liberl’s Royal Army.</p><p>Several times larger than Haken Gate in northern Bose, Leiston Fortress operates under the vigilant supervision of Major Cid, the garrison’s commanding officer. Here, soldiers diligently train and fulfill their duties.</p><p>Ten years ago, during the Hundred Day War with the Erebonian Empire, this very fortress was the only one that did not fall to Imperial forces. As a result, it served as the base for the Royal Army’s desperate counteroffensive.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_020.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong><a title="Companies > crim [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">Crim</a>son Tower</strong></p><p>Found in the expansive Tratt Plains southeast of Zeiss, this impressive ancient ruin is thought to have been constructed around 1,200 years ago.</p><p>True to its name, the structure seems to symbolize flames and the vibrant hue of carnelia, the fire septium. The tower’s interior is illuminated by flickering torches, and artifacts made of carnelia have been discovered within its walls.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_021.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Notebook System</strong></p><p>In <em><a title="Series > Trails [86 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/trails">Trails</a> in the Sky the 1st</em>, you can use shortcuts to access a variety of notebooks useful on your <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,415 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>, such as the “Bracer Notebook” that automatically documents quest details, the “Battle Notebook” that registers enemy details, and the “<a title="Genres > Cooking [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">Cooking</a> Notebook” useful for making food.</p><p><strong>Bracer Notebook</strong></p><p>Automatically documents details related to quests accepted at the Bracer Guild’s bulletin board, as well as major story-related events. Additionally, when a quest is completed, a quest-specific photo is added alongside a few words from Estelle.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_022.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_023.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_024.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Cooking Notebook</strong></p><p>Documents the dishes that Estelle and company eat on their journey, and enables you to make dishes using the ingredients in your possession. By making dishes, various special effects will occur, such as increasing your party members’ abilities for the first time. By making certain dishes, Estelle and company may even be inspired to come up with their own arrangements…</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_025.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_026.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_027.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Battle Notebook</strong></p><p>Automatically registers enemy information by either “defeating” or “stunning” them in battle. You can check information such as basic stats and weaknesses, dropped items, and so on, allowing you to take on enemies with a strategic advantage.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_028.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Reading Books</strong></p><p>Books obtained in the game, such as the Liberl News or novels, will automatically be added to your list of readable content.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Trails-in-the-Sky-1st-Chapter_2025_07-24-25_029.jpg"></a></figure></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-details-zeiss-characters-and-places-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bounty Sisters for Switch launches December 18 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/bounty-sisters-for-switch-launches-december-18-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bounty-sisters-for-switch-launches-december-18-in-japan.1251741/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC version not dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Bounty Sisters [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bounty-sisters">Bounty Sisters</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on December 18 in Japan for 4,400 yen, developer <a title="Companies > PiXEL [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pixel">PiXEL</a> <a href="https://www.value-press.com/pressrelease/359582/" target="_blank">announced</a>. A PC (Steam) version is also planned, but was not dated. <span id="more-979870"></span></p><p>A 9,900 yen limited edition will also be available, which includes a copy of the game, a mini album containing an arrangement of tracks, three acrylic stand figures, and the art book “Shuzilow.HA Artworks.”</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Bounty-Sisters-Date_07-24-25_LE.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>Bounty Sisters</em> is a fully voiced comedy <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,415 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> / vertical scrolling <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [803 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up</a> in which you pilot the vehicles of three unique sisters, utilizing their main and sub weapons, help from sisters, and special skills (bombs) to progress. Character designs and illustrations were handled by Shuzilow.HA.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch「バウンティシスターズ」予約開始トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FJLnisTLFhU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/bounty-sisters-for-switch-launches-december-18-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You launches July 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-july-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-july-31.1251729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Romance visual novel dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Romance <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you">Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3690420/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 31, developer Operahouse <a href="https://twitter.com/OPERAHOUSE_game/status/1948216630502383904" target="_blank">announced</a>. It will support English, Japanese, Korean, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-979864"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3690420/Dreaming_in_Cherry_Blossoms_I_Fall_in_Love_with_You/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A story where the “memories of cherry blossoms” gently unravel the heart.</p><p>It is a tale of a person encountering “everyday life” once again in a quiet season.​</p><p>A visual novel set in a small town where fantasy and reality intersect, quietly touching the heart.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In the changing scenery, as if searching for something that once certainly existed.​</p><p>Eventually, it becomes a journey to face forgotten emotions once more.​</p><p>Within the game, graphics enveloped in soft light and delicate sounds color the story.</p><p>Multiple “forms of the heart” are depicted based on the player’s choices.​</p><p>Feelings that everyone has experienced at least once but couldn’t express in words—.</p><p>Find the answer within the spring breeze.</p><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li>Cherry (voiced by Rin Kurusu)</li><li>Wathy (voiced by Saku Mizuno)</li><li>Yuri Takai (voicd by Yurina Uchiyama)</li><li>Shoko Ina (voiced by Non Harusaki)</li><li>Yua Orihara (voiced by <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>tsu Murakami)</li><li>Hayato Kusanagi (voiced by Kakeru Hatano)</li><li>And more</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-july-31]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>