<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:49:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Game Catalog and Classics Catalog lineup for September 2025 announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-september-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-september-2025-announced.1293771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Persona 5 Tactica, Fate/Samurai Remnant, Legacy of Kain: Defiance, and more.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,051 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/09/10/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-september-wwe-2k25-persona-5-tactica-green-hell-fate-samurai-remnant-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the September 2025 Game Catalog lineup for Extra and Premium subscribers, and Classics Catalog titles for Premium subscribers. <span id="more-991039"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><p>All titles will be available from September 16.</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Game Catalog</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > CONSCRIPT [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/conscript">CONSCRIPT</a></em></strong> (PS5) –&nbsp;<em>CONSCRIPT</em> is a <a title="Genres > Survival [455 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> horror game inspired by classics of the genre, blending all the punishing mechanics of older <a title="Genres > Horror [703 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror games</a> into a cohesive, tense, and unique experience. Set in 1916 during the Great War, you play as a French soldier searching for his missing-in-<a title="Genres > Action [3,020 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> brother during the Battle of Verdun. Will you be able to search twisted trenches, navigate overrun forts, and cross no-mans-land to find him, and ensure a home goes unbroken? Survive in an intense, harrowing atmosphere boosted by a unique pixel art aesthetic and oppressive sound design. Navigate intricate level design that promotes item <a title="Genres > Management [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> and route planning, whilst solving complex environmental puzzles.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Crow Country [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/crow-country">Crow Country</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;The creators of celebrated <a title="Genres > Point-and-Click [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/point-and-click">point-and-click</a> murder mystery Tangle Tower return with a retro-inspired survival horror set in an abandoned theme park. The year is 1990 and Edward Crow, the owner of the Crow Country theme park, is missing. Two years after he suddenly closed his park, a mysterious young woman called Mara Forest arrives to explore the abandoned property and find its lost owner. Why did Crow really shut down Crow Country and what is Mara Forest’s connection to him?</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Fate/Samurai Remnant [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fate-samurai-remnant">Fate/Samurai Remnant</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;“Your wish shall perish…” A Holy Grail War begins in Edo Japan. The curtain rises on a new <em><a title="Series > Fate [69 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a></em>, an <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,780 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> presented by <a title="Companies > TYPE-MOON [131 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/type-moon">Type-Moon</a> and <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,086 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo Games</a>. The 4th year of the Keian Era, Edo Period. It has been several decades since the end of a turbulent, blood-soaked era. People were enjoying peace and tranquility, but a battle between seven pairs of <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ters and Servants is about to begin as the “Waxing Moon Ritual” unfolds in the shadows. Miyamoto Iori, a young man in Asakusa, finds himself caught in the violence of a Holy Grail War.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Green Hell [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/green-hell">Green Hell</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;<em>Green Hell</em> is an <a title="Genres > Open-World [720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> survival simulator set in the unique and uncharted setting of the Amazonian rainforest. Plunge into the open world survival <a title="Genres > Simulation [825 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> set in the extreme conditions of the unforgiving Amazon jungle. Use real-life survival techniques to craft, hunt, fight, and gather resources. Build a makeshift shelter or raise a fortress, but always remember to tend to your wounds and maintain mental health. Survive on your own, or try your chances in an up-to-four-player online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [325 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> mode.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > The Invincible [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-invincible">The Invincible</a></em></strong> (PS5) –&nbsp;You are a highly qualified, sharp-witted astrobiologist named Yasna. Being entangled in a space race, you and your crew end up on the unexplored planet Regis III. The scientific journey quickly turns into a search mission for lost crewmates. Follow its trail, but be fully aware that every decision you make can bring you closer to danger. On her journey, Yasna will face decisions that will shape the outcome of the story. Help her make difficult choices and witness one of 11 possible endings to the deeply philosophical story.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Persona 5 Tactica [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/persona-5-tactica">Persona 5 Tactica</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) – <em>Persona 5 Tactica</em> is a turn-based <a title="Genres > Strategy [282 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a>, featuring an all-new story, the return of fan-favorite characters and brand-new allies and foes. After a strange incident, the Phantom Thieves wander into a bizarre realm where its citizens are living under tyrannical oppression. Surrounded by a military group named Legionnaires, they find themselves in grave danger until a mysterious revolutionary named Erina rescues them and offers an enticing deal in exchange for their help. What truth lies behind Erina and the deal she offers to the Phantom Thieves? Join the group as they lead an emotional revolution in this thrilling combat <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,539 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > WWE 2K25 [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wwe-2k25">WWE 2K25</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) – “The Wiseman” Paul Heyman hosts The Bloodline’s Dynasty, a new <a title="Companies > 2K [675 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k">2K</a> Showcase celebrating one of the most historic family dynasties in <a title="Genres > Wrestling [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/wrestling">wrestling</a>. Relive legendary showdowns and create dream matches between The Bloodline and WWE Superstars and Legends. Intergender wrestling makes its long-awaited WWE 2K debut, alongside the return of chain wrestling, Underground and Bloodline Rules match types, barricade diving and more. Take control of your Superstar from the women’s or men’s divisions in a singular multi-gender MyRISE storyline where WWE Superstars infiltrate NXT and attempt to take control of the WWE universe. Discover new brawl environments, unlockable arenas, characters, ally storylines and more. (Both <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,334 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,327 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> versions of <em>WWE 2K25</em> will be download only.)</li></ul><p><strong>■ Classics Catalog</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><a title="Platforms > PS2 [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps2">PlayStation 2</a></strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>Legacy of Kain: Defiance</em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;Continue Kain and Raziel’s epic conflict in this faithful emulation of the classic PS2 action-adventure title, Legacy of Kain: Defiance, playable on PS4 and PS5 for the first time. Take control of two powerful and highly evolved vampires: Kain, Emperor of Nosgoth and near-demigod, and Raziel, a wraithlike angel of death. Each equipped with their own legendary sword, Kain &amp; Raziel must battle through a world poisoned by conflict and intrigue as they attempt to unravel their destinies and defeat the dark forces that seek to condemn their world to eternal damnation.</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-september-2025-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yurukill: The Calumniation Games now available for Xbox Series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/yurukill-the-calumniation-games-now-available-for-xbox-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yurukill-the-calumniation-games-now-available-for-xbox-series.1293705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Another surprise release from IzanagiGames.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>An <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,870 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> version of <em><a title="Games > Yurukill: The Calumniation Games [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yurukill-the-calumniation-games">Yurukill: The Calumniation Games</a></em> is now available for Xbox Series via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/yurukill-the-calumniation-games/9nr6j41s2wxw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> for $24.99, publisher <a title="Companies > IzanagiGames [102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/izanagigames">IzanagiGames</a> announced. <span id="more-991051"></span></p><p><em>Yurukill: The Calumniation Games</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch on May 25, 2022 in Japan, followed by July 5, 2022 in North America, and July 8, 2022 in Europe alongside a PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1733840/Yurukill_The_Calumniation_Games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>) version. <!--more--></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via IzanagiGames:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Pardon or kill. Let the madness begin! At the edge of despair, lurks the unsettling past, and an unspeakable truth. What lies hidden in the twisted attractions of the secluded amusement park, Yurukill Land? Who will emerge victorious from its cruel, fiendish games?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><a title="Games > Clea [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clea">Clea</a>r Your Name</strong> – Take on the nerfarious attractions of Yurukill Land for a chance to prove your innocence. Partner up with your Executioner and set your sights on emerging victorious from the Yurukill Games. For the victors, absolution awaits.</li><li><strong>Risk Your Life</strong> – Solve puzzles and uncover hints about the <a title="Companies > crim [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>es you stand accused of, and put it all on the line in Maji-Kill Time—tense life or death cross-examinations. One wrong answer, and all is lost. As you progress, the grim truths of each incident will come to light.</li><li><strong>Take to the (Virtual) Skies</strong> – Pilot your Yurukill Fighter through a series of <a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [201 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">virtual reality</a> challenges. Put your understanding of each case to the test in High-Speed Quizzes: choose the correct lane, and you’ll be rewarded with extra lives. In the Prejudice <a title="Games > Synapse [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/synapse">Synapse</a>, present evidence from your investigations, and destroy your Executioner’s prejudices. Each top-down shoot ‘em up section (courtesy of veteran developer <a title="Companies > G.rev [53 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/g-rev">G.rev</a>!) ends with a nail-biting Prisoner vs Executioner showdown. Whether you’re a shoot ’em up expert or newcomer to the genre, find the perfect challenge to suit your level with a choice of Easy, Normal, and Hell difficulties.</li><li><strong>Run the Gauntlet</strong> – Choose your craft, set the difficulty, buckle up, and blast through shoot ’em up sections from the main game in Score Attack mode. Features global online rankings.</li></ul><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Original Story / Scenario:</strong> Homura Kawamoto / Hikaru Muno</li><li><strong>Director / Producer:</strong> Shinsuke Umeda</li><li><strong>Character Design:</strong> Hiro Kiyohara</li><li><strong>Soundtrack:</strong> Yuko Komiyama</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [814 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">Shoot ‘Em Up</a> Development:</strong> G.rev</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/yurukill-the-calumniation-games-now-available-for-xbox-series]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>