<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:54:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Back to the Dawn for Switch 2, Switch launches March 5, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/back-to-the-dawn-for-switch-2-switch-launches-march-5-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/back-to-the-dawn-for-switch-2-switch-launches-march-5-2026.1332394/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PlayStation 5 release date to be announced at a later time.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [580 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> versions of prison break thriller <a title="Genres > RPG [17,722 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Back to the Dawn [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/back-to-the-dawn">Back to the Dawn</a></em> will launch on March 5, 2026, publishers <a title="Companies > Clouded Leopard Entertainment [112 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/clouded-leopard-entertainment">Clouded Leopard Entertainment</a> and <a title="Companies > Spiral Up Games [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/spiral-up-games">Spiral Up Games</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > Metal Head Games [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/metal-head-games">Metal Head Games</a> announced. Details regarding the release date for the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/back-to-the-dawn-coming-to-ps5-switch-2-and-switch-in-2026">PlayStation 5 version</a>, which is due out in 2026, will be announced at a later time. <span id="more-1001591"></span></p><p><em>Back to the Dawn</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1735700/Back_to_the_Dawn/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on November 3, 2023, followed by a full release for Xbox Series, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1735700/Back_to_the_Dawn/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/back-to-the-dawn/9pkwjsj4nwc7" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on July 18, 2025.</p><p>The PlayStation 5, Switch 2, and Switch release will feature enhanced localization across all subtitle languages, as well as the addition of brand-new Japanese and Chinese voice acting. Thomas the Fox will be voiced in Japanese by Shugo Nakamura, while Bob the Panther will be voiced by Yasuhiro Mamiya. Additional cast members will be revealed in the coming months.</p><p>In Japan and Asia, Clouded Leopard Entertainment will distribute physical editions of <em>Back to the Dawn</em>. Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Standard Edition</strong></p><ul><li>A copy of <em>Back to the Dawn</em> (Switch 2 version ships on a game-key card)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Limited Edition</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Back-to-the-Dawn-Switch-2-Switch_10-23-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>A copy of <em>Back to the Dawn</em> (Switch 2 version ships on a game-key card)</li><li>Original newly illustrated box</li><li>Exclusive acrylic diorama stand – A 3D acrylic stand designed to showcase the charm of five characters illustrated in finely detailed pixel art, set against a prison backdrop. Display it on your desk for a fully immersive game experience!</li><li>Original pins (two types) – Two original pins designed after the game’s two protagonists. Attach them to a bag or accessory and enjoy them as a stylish accent in your outfit.</li><li>Digital art book and digital soundtrack (not planned to be sold separately) – A special application that allows you to view a pixel-art-based art book capturing the game’s atmospheric world, while listening to the hard-boiled soundtrack from the main game.</li><li>Downloadable content: “Supporter Pack” – An all-in-one downloadable content set designed to enhance your gameplay experience, including:<ul><li>The limited skin set “Room Remodeling Design Book”</li><li>Bonus customization items</li><li>Convenience items that help increase affinity with characters more efficiently</li></ul></li><li>Limited Edition-exclusive original downloadable content: “Original Item” (Not planned to be sold separately)</li></ul><p><strong>First-Print Purchase Bonus</strong> (either edition)</p><ul><li>Microfiber cloth – A microfiber cloth featuring the game’s main visual.</li><li>Switch 2 / Switch-exclusive downloadable content: “Prison Skin”</li></ul></blockquote><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Clouded Leopard Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In this prison-escape-themed RPG, <a title="Companies > crim [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">crim</a>e, conspiracy, and hidden traps intertwine, while the relationships between characters grow increasingly complex. Step into the role of an animal inmate, survive the harsh realities of prison life, explore, grow, and plan your escape.</p><p>Stay sharp—fight to prove your innocence, uncover the schemes lurking behind rival factions, and battle not just for your own freedom, but for the future of the city itself.</p><p>Meet a cast of unforgettable characters and experience an epic story in <em>Back to the Dawn</em>.</p><p><strong>A Hardboiled Story Straight Out of the Movies</strong></p><p>In a city of animals torn apart by corruption, play as a wrongfully convicted journalist or an undercover investigator forced into a brutal prison system. With allies working from the outside, gather evidence, follow every lead without leaving a trace, and fight to save yourself—and the city.</p><p><strong>A Fully-Fledged RPG Packed with Content</strong></p><p>Choose between two protagonists, each with a main story exceeding 20 hours of playtime. Encounter three powerful gangs, 47 uniquely crafted inmates, dozens of memorable NPCs, and take on over 100 intricately designed quests. With multiple escape routes, richly branching endings, and a script of over one million characters, this is a one-of-a-kind RPG experience.</p><p><strong>Uncover the Prison’s Hidden Conspiracies</strong></p><p>Though the prison appears orderly, dark secrets lurk beneath. A suspicious figure loiters in the shadows, strange noises echo from the kitchen’s back door, and a locked door at the end of a corridor has never been opened.</p><p>Gather scattered clues, trade information, and sneak out during lights-out to uncover the secrets and conspiracies festering within the prison—before time runs out.</p><p><strong>A Deeply Immersive Virtual <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong></p><p>Blend seamlessly into prison life, follow the rules when you must, and make your mark when opportunity calls. Explore unfamiliar environments and take on a wide range of challenges.</p><p>Will you spend your days as a model prisoner in peace, or cause chaos as a notorious troublemaker? The choice is yours.</p><p><strong>A Colorful Cast</strong></p><p>Meet a colorful cast of inmates in your prison, each with an interesting story to tell. You can either make them your friends or fight, bully and rob them into submission. Will you be part of a gang or a cunning lone wolf? Pick a side!</p><p><strong>Open Character Growth System</strong></p><p>Are you a tough guy who lets his fists do the talking, a thief who hides in the shadows, or perhaps a smooth talker who manipulates the scene? Develop your skills, craft tools to suit your style, and climb your way from “new fish” to “top dog.”</p><p><strong>Plan Your Prison Escape</strong></p><p>In a place built to break you, your sharpest weapon is your creativity and cunning. Every inch of Boulderton Prison might hold the key to your escape, from your prison cell to the infirmary, to the sewers and even the rooftops. Can you break free?</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch 2 and Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Back to the Dawn Release Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kRb-kmy8xsw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『Back to the Dawn ～ブレイク･ザ･アニマル･プリズン～』 発売日アナウンストレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDC9hQu2YOY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『Back to the Dawn ～브레이크 더 애니멀 프리즌～』 발매일 안내 트레일러" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRZ9tQQN_bI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《動物迷城 ～Back to the Dawn～》 發售日期發表影片" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qVeuRpkblr8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《动物迷城 ～Back to the Dawn～》 发售日期发表视频" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cx1wUI5RBu0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/back-to-the-dawn-for-switch-2-switch-launches-march-5-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>