<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 17:23:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Backrooms 1998 launches February 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/the-backrooms-1998-launches-february-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-backrooms-1998-launches-february-20.1112316/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/the-backrooms-1998-launches-february-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>First launched in Early Access in May 2022.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Found footage survival <a title="Genres > Horror [558 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > The Backrooms 1998 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-backrooms-1998">The Backrooms 1998</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,882 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,733 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,786 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,665 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,387 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1985930/The_Backrooms_1998__Found_Footage_Survival_Horror_Game/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 20, publisher <a title="Companies > Feardemic [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bloober-team/feardemic">Feardemic</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Steelkrill Studio [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/steelkrill-studio">Steelkrill Studio</a> announced. <span id="more-944946"></span></p><p>The Early Access version launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1985930/The_Backrooms_1998__Found_Footage_Survival_Horror_Game/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 25, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Feardemic:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>The Backrooms 1998</em> is a first-person found footage psychological horror <a title="Genres > Survival [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival game</a> where it tells the story of a young teen after accidentally falling into the depths of <em>The Backrooms</em> in 1998.</p><p>Roam freely, mark, explore and try to unravel the story—however you are not alone.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Don’t scream.</p><p><strong>Trigger Warning</strong></p><p>This game may be disturbing to some audiences as this game contains real disturbing footage, sounds, fear nature, jump scares, gore, extreme violence, murders, and intense horror that may not be for the faint of heart. Play this game at your own risk.</p><p>Can you escape the backrooms?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Delve Into the Backrooms</strong> – Try to find your way in an unwelcoming maze of the backrooms</li><li><strong>Stamina System</strong> – Don’t lose your breath and keep an eye on your stamina levels. Avoid getting too tired, unless you want the creature to get to you.</li><li><strong>Leave a Trace</strong> – Use your spray gun to mark your path, helping you navigate the backrooms and keep track of the rooms you’ve already explored.</li><li><strong>Stock Up on Goods</strong> – Use the tools scattered around to help you escape this nightmare.</li><li><strong>Limited Chances</strong> – Save yourself by saving your progress in the special ‘safe rooms’. This is your only chance to not be trapped here for eternity.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Backrooms 1998 - Console Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QfB74-wjrO0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MADO MONOGATARI: Fia and the Wondrous Academy coming west in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mado-monogatari-fia-and-the-wondrous-academy-coming-west-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mado-monogatari-fia-and-the-wondrous-academy-coming-west-in-2025.1112271/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mado-monogatari-fia-and-the-wondrous-academy-coming-west-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Join Fia on her journey to achieve Great Mage status at The Ancient Magic Academy.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [394 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a> will release dungeon crawling <a title="Genres > RPG [16,997 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > MADO MONOGATARI: Fia and the Wondrous Academy [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mado-monogatari-fia-and-the-wondrous-academy">MADO MONOGATARI: Fia and the Wondrous Academy</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,882 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,665 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> in the west in 2025, the publisher announced. It will feature English and French subtitles with Japanese voice-overs. <span id="more-944914"></span></p><p><em>MADO MONOGATARI: Fia and the Wondrous Academy</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch on November 28, 2024 in Japan.</p><p>In the west, the game will be available both physically and digitally. Users can wishlist both the <a href="https://ifi.store/products/Mado-Monogatari-SE" target="_blank">standard</a> and <a href="https://ifi.store/products/Mado-Monogatari-LE" target="_blank">limited editions</a> via the Idea Factory International Online Store today. Details on the limited edition will be announced at a later date.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/MADO-MONOGATARI-Ann_02-18-25_Package.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Idea Factory International:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The Ancient Magic Academy.​</p><p>An academy with a long, storied past, known as the place where The Great Mage learned and graduated. Students study here to become Mages themselves.</p><p>A girl named Fia, wanting to enroll in the Academy, makes a long arduous journey from her hometown, and manages to get in through her own luck.</p><p>She now tries her best to get through the many challenges of schoolwork, strict professors, and mysterious happenings, all in pursuit of her goal to become a Great Mage herself, while also making friends with other students in her class.</p><p>Embark on an adventure with Fia and her classmates as they explore the mysteries of the Ancient Magic Academy and uncover the legends of The Great Mage.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_944924"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Conquer Dynamic Dungeons and Help Fia Become A Great Mage!</strong> – Crawl through randomly generated dungeons and engage in real-time, turn-based battles to help Fia level up. Use Magic Artes and collect Elemental Orbs to fill up your gauge and unleash Great Magic Artes. <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge your inventory and stats as you traverse floor after floor of wondrous treasures and magical monsters—including Puyo, Skeleton T, and others!</li><li><strong>Keep your Grimoire Handy!</strong> – Keep track of unlocked abilities with the Grimoire, which logs Fia’s Magic Artes. Complete Assignments, Help <a title="Platforms > Quest [130 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s, and earn Learning Points that can be used to unlock nodes in the Grimoire for Fia to learn new Magic Artes.</li><li><strong>Fia is Mad About Town!</strong> – Take a break from dungeon crawling and explore the school grounds where Fia can check out the Bulletin Board for unlocked mini-games, interact with classmates, grow ingredients, cook curry for in-dungeon boosts, and more! Find out what other goings on await Fia along her journey!</li><li><strong>Swords, Shields, and Shiny Armor with Synthesis in the Storage Room</strong> – In the Storage Room of the school grounds, use items found in dungeons to synthesize into new equipment for Fia. Better synthesis items can later be unlocked via the Grimoire.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/mado-monogatari-fia-and-the-wondrous-academy/february-18-2025/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://ifi.games/madomonogatari/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MADO MONOGATARI: Fia and the Wondrous Academy | Announcement Trailer (NA) | PS4®, PS5®, and Switch™" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ssV0H0rXIK0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skater Tyshawn Jones claims to be in upcoming Tony Hawk game remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/skater-tyshawn-jones-claims-to-be-in-upcoming-tony-hawk-game-remaster</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skater-tyshawn-jones-claims-to-be-in-upcoming-tony-hawk-game-remaster.1112223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/skater-tyshawn-jones-claims-to-be-in-upcoming-tony-hawk-game-remaster<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>The revival of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4?</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Professional skateboarder Tyshawn Jones is in an upcoming <em>Tony Hawk</em> video game remaster, he told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3umK3xG7Ly4&amp;t=1314" target="_blank">Power 105.1 FM’s The Breakfast Club</a> in an interview today. <span id="more-944905"></span></p><p>When discussing new skateboarding video games, Jones said, “I’m in a <em>Tony Hawk</em> coming out, so that’s cool—they got a new one they’re remastering, so that’s about to come out. I was [also] in the last one [<em><a title="Games > Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 1 + 2 [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2">Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 + 2</a></em>].”</p><p>The latest entry in the <em>Tony Hawk</em> video game series, <em>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 + 2</em>, launched for <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,786 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,387 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-and-2" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on September 4, 2020, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,882 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,733 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> on March 26, 2021, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,665 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on June 25, 2021, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2395210/Tony_Hawks_Pro_Skater_1__2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 3, 2023.</p><p>Back in June 2022, Tony Hawk <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2022/06/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-plans-shelved-after-blizzard-entertainment-absorbed-vicarious-visions-says-tony-hawk">said</a> that a <em>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4</em> was planned after <em>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 + 2</em>, but plans were shelved after developer <a title="Companies > Vicarious Visions [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blizzard-entertainment/vicarious-visions">Vicarious Visions</a> was absorbed by <a title="Companies > Blizzard Entertainment [150 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blizzard-entertainment">Blizzard Entertainment</a>. At the time, Hawk said, “I wish there was someway to bring it back. I mean, who knows? Maybe when all the dust settles, we’ll figure it out.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relic Entertainment announces turn-based strategy game Earth vs Mars for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/relic-entertainment-announces-turn-based-strategy-game-earth-vs-mars-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/relic-entertainment-announces-turn-based-strategy-game-earth-vs-mars-for-pc.1112181/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/relic-entertainment-announces-turn-based-strategy-game-earth-vs-mars-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out this summer as first game in smaller-scale Relic Labs initiative.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Company of Heroes</em> developer <a title="Companies > Relic Entertainment [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/relic-entertainment">Relic Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3269230/view/741507988083180258" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Earth vs Mars" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/earth-vs-mars">Earth vs Mars</a></em>, a turn-based strategy game that pits Earth’s forces against a Martian invasion. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,387 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3269230/Earth_vs_Mars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> this summer. <span id="more-944900"></span></p><p><em>Earth vs Mars</em> is the first smaller-scale “indie-style” game from Relic Entertainment’s new initiative Relic Labs, which will differ from its traditional, bigger <a title="Genres > Real-Time Strategy [119 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/real-time-strategy">real-time strategy games</a>. The Relic Labs initiative will allow the studio te explore new sub-genres, experiment, and release games more frequently.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3269230/Earth_vs_Mars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Martians have been visiting Earth for decades, abducting animals and humans and harvesting their atomic essence to create bizarre Martian-creature hybrids. This time they’re here to claim our planet.</p><p>In this turn-based strategy game, an unlikely group of commanders will lead Earth’s military as they face an overwhelming Martian invasion. Fight high-tech saucers, grav-tanks and elite alien warriors in a battle for the planet’s <a title="Genres > Survival [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Your secret weapon is the “Splice-O-Tron.” With it, you can combine human “volunteers” with Earth creatures to create powerful hybrid supersoldiers to fight alongside Earth’s regular military.</p><p>Rain acid from the skies with the fast-moving cheetah-fly. Charge through enemy lines with devastating human-rhino hybrids. Or strike from the forests with your deadly squirrel-cow infantry.</p><p>As the campaign progresses, you’ll unlock new types of creature, powerful unit upgrades and game-changing commander abilities. But as your army evolves, so will your enemy’s, and you’ll face everything from the sentient organic weapon known only as “The Creep” to the Martian’s own mutant creations.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><p>More information on each key feature will be released in the coming months, but for now, here is a short summary.</p><ul><li><strong>Single-Player Campaign</strong> – <em>Earth vs Mars</em> will feature an expansive narrative focused campaign composed of over 30 hand-crafted missions.</li><li><strong>Online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [446 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a></strong> – Battle against other commanders, either as the armies of Earth or as the forces of the Martian Invaders. Lots more information to come!</li><li><strong>VS Mode</strong> – Battle against the AI on custom maps giving lots of replayability to single-player fans.</li><li><strong>Map Editor</strong> – Fully featured Map Editor allows you to create custom maps and scenarios. Again, more information to come in time!</li><li><strong>Splice-o-tron</strong> – Bringing some old-school Relic flavor to this genre, the Splice-o-Tron will be a key mechanic in the game. Combining creatures with human “volunteers” will allow you to field an array of exciting and powerful hybrid units.</li><li><strong>Unit Abilities</strong> – Many of the Units in <em>Earth vs Mars</em> will have their own unique abilities, adding new strategies and gameplay depth to this style of game.</li><li><strong>Commanders</strong> – There will be multiple commanders in the game, each bringing passive and active abilities that enhance the way you play.</li><li><strong>Beautifully Realized 3D World</strong> – We’re excited to bring 3D units, tilesets, and stunning effects to turn and tile-based players in <em>Earth vs Mars</em>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>And here is a FAQ containing additional information:</p><blockquote><p><strong>When is <em>Earth vs Mars</em> coming out?</strong></p><p>We are targeting a summer 2025 release for <em>Earth vs Mars</em>.</p><p><strong>Will <em>Earth vs Mars</em> be coming to any other platforms?</strong></p><p>For launch, we are focused on releasing <em>Earth vs Mars</em> on Steam (PC), however based on the game’s reception, we may consider other platforms in the future.</p><p><strong>How much will <em>Earth vs Mars</em> cost?</strong></p><p>We don’t have a final price just yet, but we’re looking at other similar games in the genre to help inform that decision.</p><p><strong>What languages will <em>Earth vs Mars</em> support?</strong></p><p>We’ll have more news on all the language options for <em>Earth vs Mars</em> closer to its release date.</p><p><strong>Will <em>Earth vs Mars</em> be Steam Deck compatible?</strong></p><p><em>Earth vs Mars</em> will not be Steam Deck compatible at launch, but it is top of mind for the development team.</p><p><strong>When will you share more information about the story, characters, units, Splice-O-Tron and more?</strong></p><p>Over the coming months we will have lots more to share from the development team in blogs, videos, and livestreams. Join the official Relic Entertainment Discord server to stay up to date on the latest.</p><p><strong>This game and genre are very different from what Relic Entertainment has done in the past. Should I be worried?</strong></p><p>No! <em>Earth vs Mars</em> is the first of our Relic Labs games, which allows us to have some fun, be experimental, and try new ideas with smaller games. We will still be working on big classic real-time-<a title="Genres > Strategy [218 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy games</a> now and moving forward. You can read more about our new development strategy here and here.</p><p><strong>Will <em>Earth vs Mars</em> have any post-launch downloadable content or expansions?</strong></p><p>For launch, we are focused on the core <em>Earth vs Mars</em> game itself. If players love the experience, we would be eager to work on additional content for the game.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Earth vs. Mars - Exclusive Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H1fcAfm_gLM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>