<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 15:20:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[La Quimera launches April 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/la-quimera-launches-april-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/la-quimera-launches-april-25.1157181/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/la-quimera-launches-april-25<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>24-hour closed beta test set for April 12.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Narrative-driven first-person-<a title="Genres > Shooter [4,058 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > La Quimera [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/la-quimera">La Quimera</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,811 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2282350/La_Quimera/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 25 for $29.99 / €29.99, developer <a title="Companies > Reburn [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/reburn">Reburn</a> announced. A limited-entry closed beta test will be available for 24 hours starting <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250412T1400" target="_blank">April 12 at 7:00 a.m. PT / 10:00 a.m. ET</a>, allowing users to play part of a pivotal mid-game mission in solo or <a title="Genres > Co-Op [252 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play. <span id="more-956266"></span></p><p>“Our Reburn team can’t wait to finally share our hard work and vision for <em>La Quimera</em> with players on April 25,” said Reburn co-founder and CEO Dmytro Lymar in a press release. “Ahead of our release, we invite players to join us in our closed beta to get an early look at the co-op experience for our vision of Nuevo Caracas and far beyond.”</p><p>Lymar continued, “As a development studio operating out of Ukraine, the last several years have been extremely challenging in terms of bringing any artistic creation to life while contending with the realities of war and dramatic shifts in the games industry. Through it all, we stayed focused on what we love: Creating immersive, story-driven experiences. Our work wouldn’t be possible without the bravery and sacrifice of those defending Ukraine, and we’re profoundly grateful for their strength and resilience. We’re also truly thankful to everyone who supported and believed in us along the way.”</p><div id="carousel_956268"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Reburn:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>La Quimera</em> is a story-driven <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,644 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> set in dystopian future Latin America. In a fractured world where microstates rely on mercenary forces, you are an operative caught in a web of lies and deception. Play alone or with up to two friends geared with futuristic weapons, exoskeletons and combat abilities.</p><p>Year 2064. The majority of nation states have become extinct. A series of natural and human-caused catastrophes in the 2030s and 2040s triggered the collapse of global systems, led to the fragmentation of human communities. The political entities in this new world are microstates and even amidst the current inter-state and corporate conflicts, typically see no point in maintaining their own armies, having to rely on mercenary<br>forces—the “golden age” of private military companies, so called PMCs, has arrived.</p><p>As PMC operatives, you’ll take on intense high-risk campaign in a dystopian world of future Latin America across a breathtaking megalopolis and lush jungle combining highly advanced weaponry and technology battling against rival factions.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Explore Together</strong> – An engaging story-driven atmospheric shooter experience regardless if you play alone or as a part of the cooperating team. Team up with fellow mercenaries to coordinate tactics, combine firepower with combat abilities and share resources.</li><li><strong>Build Your Perfect Arsenal</strong> – Acquiring the right tools is crucial in this unforgiving world. Choose from a selection of distinct weapons. Customize your exoskeleton with a range of parts. Every weapon, ability, exoskeleton will allow you to craft the perfect combination for desired play style and enemy type.</li><li><strong>Fight Through the Hostile Factions</strong> – Face off against factions in intense battles, each with their own specifics—lightly armed charging bandits, <a title="Genres > Stealth [80 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>y long-range sharpshooters or heavy shielded and armed elite fighters.</li><li><strong>Battle the Robotic Enemies</strong> – With resistance to conventional weapons, and their ability to fly, crawl on ceilings, and scale walls makes these robotic foes tough, unpredictable and deadly. Some of the more advanced military models require you to discover unique tactics to bring them down for good.</li><li><strong>Take Advantage Through Technology</strong> – A personal combat AI assistant will guide you with tactical information in danger, and serve as a guide in the quieter locations.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new gameplay trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/la-quimera/april-7-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Long Version</strong></p><p><iframe title="La Quimera - Gameplay Trailer (Long Version)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BRsNxTSydoY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Short Version</strong></p><p><iframe title="La Quimera - Gameplay Trailer (Short Version)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XvQMxdU5n7U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Truckful to be published by Pocketpair Publishing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/truckful-to-be-published-by-pocketpair-publishing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/truckful-to-be-published-by-pocketpair-publishing.1157139/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/truckful-to-be-published-by-pocketpair-publishing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A single-player car delivery adventure game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Single-player car delivery <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,186 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Truckful [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/truckful">Truckful</a></em> from Polish studio <a title="Companies > MythicOwl [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mythicowl">MythicOwl</a> will be the first game published by <a title="Companies > Pocketpair Publishing [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pocketpair/pocketpair-publishing">Pocketpair Publishing</a>, the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/pocketpair-establishes-pocketpair-publishing-announces-first-title-with-surgent-studios">recently established</a> publishing venture from <em><a title="Games > Palworld [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Pocketpair [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pocketpair">Pocketpair</a>, the company announced. <span id="more-956307"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Pocketpair Publishing:</p><blockquote><p><em>Truckful</em> is a single-player car delivery adventure game based around completing errands and quests for villagers and uncovering the ancient mystery that surrounds the nearby old forest.</p><p><em>Truckful</em> puts you behind the wheel of your reliable truck, tasked with delivering a range of goods to the townsfolk who call this scenic countryside home. Navigate winding roads, dusty lowlands, and charming towns, all while soaking in the beautiful landscapes that surround you. But don’t be fooled by the tranquility—the road less travelled often holds hidden secrets just waiting to be discovered…</p><p>This seemingly idyllic countryside hides its fair share of mysteries, though. The ancient forest on the outskirts whispers through local legends and folklore, its dense canopy creating an unsettling atmosphere, with something lurking in the shadows… Explore hidden paths, navigate misty wetlands, and brave treacherous marshes and quicksands to uncover the truth beneath the branches.</p></blockquote><p><em>Truckful</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,811 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3090810/Truckful/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MythicOwl x Pocketpair - Truckful Publishing Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rZDY-AFvTvU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening ‘Anime’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-anime-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-%E2%80%98anime%E2%80%99-trailer.1157136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening-anime-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Latest look at the side-scrolling action platformer.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Microids [203 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microids">Microids</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Magic Pockets [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/magic-pockets">Magic Pockets</a> have released a new trailer for <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [953 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> action <a title="Genres > Platformer [656 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/space-adventure-cobra-the-awakening">Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening</a></em>, dubbed the “<a title="Platforms > Anime [322 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a>” trailer. <span id="more-956310"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Microids:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Immerse yourself in a thrilling action platform game and harness the unique abilities of an iconic <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,186 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r.</p><p>Play as Cobra, the space pirate, in an action platformer. Along with Lady Armaroid, your loyal partner, and equipped with your iconic Psychogun, you must solve a mystery that could threaten the entire universe.</p><p>Travel from planet to planet to save three enigmatic sisters, whose fate is tied up with a fabulous treasure sought by the dreaded Space Pirate Guild.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You will need to shrewdly use Cobra’s weapons and gadgets to defeat your enemies and complete the levels filled with obstacles and traps, which won’t be an easy feat for our space rogue.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>An <a title="Genres > Action [2,637 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> and Platform Crossover</strong> – Visit a multitude of exotic planets across levels filled with traps testing your skills to the limit. With Cobra’s superhuman abilities, you will need to relentlessly run, jump and climb, and make sure you use all the means at your disposal to take out your enemies.</li><li><strong>Equipped to the Nines</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter Cobra’s iconic weapons, such as the awesome psychogun and the Colt Python 77, to destroy the opponents on your heels, as well as his famous gadgets like the cigar and the grappling hook. You will need all of your arsenal to defeat the powerful bosses standing in your way.</li><li><strong>Solo and <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> Modes</strong> – Explore story mode by choosing from the three difficulty levels, allowing veterans of the genre to take on a real test worthy of their skills, while those looking for less of a challenge to enjoy the story. You can also try to escape your enemies in a two-player <a title="Genres > Co-Op [252 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> mode.</li><li><strong>A Thrilling <a title="Genres > Science-Fiction [77 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/science-fiction">Science-Fiction</a> World</strong> – Immerse yourself in this amazing space opera world as you embark on your adventure as a fearsome, charismatic hero. Over the course of this epic journey, you will cross paths with colorful characters like the Royal Sisters and the terrifying Crystal Bowie—Cobra’s nemesis.</li><li><strong>A Faithful Adaptation</strong> – <em>Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening</em> is the first video-game adaptation of <em>Cobra</em> on modern platforms. It covers the first 12 episodes of the famous anime series, remaining true to its spirit with the moments of bravery and humor that made it so special.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Space Adventure Cobra: The Awakening</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,000 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,916 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,811 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2878220/Space_Adventure_Cobra__The_Awakening/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a title="Companies > Epic Games [349 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/space_adventure_cobra_the_awakening" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on August 26.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Anime Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Space Adventure Cobra – The Awakening – Anime Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ww6wcNR388k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>