<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:51:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tokyo Xtreme Racer launches September 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/tokyo-xtreme-racer-launches-september-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tokyo-xtreme-racer-launches-september-25.1289727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently in Early Access.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Future Tokyo-set <a title="Genres > Racing [273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> game <em><a title="Games > Tokyo Xtreme Racer (2025) [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tokyo-xtreme-racer-2025">Tokyo Xtreme Racer</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,169 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2634950/Tokyo_Xtreme_Racer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on September 25 for $49.99 / 6,600 yen, developer <a title="Companies > Genki [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/genki">Genki</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000012.000145415.html" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-988916"></span></p><p><em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</em> first launched in Early Access on January 23.</p><p>Here is the <a href="https://twitter.com/Tokyo_Xtreme/status/1963863982290399396" target="_blank">producer letter</a> detailing the full release:</p><blockquote><p>Thank you very much to all the players and fans for all the feedback and requests during the Early Access period. The development team is excited to announce that <em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</em> is now ready for its full release. Throughout the Early Access period, we’ve received an incredible amount of feedback and requests from players around the world. Your voices have been instrumental in shaping the game, and we are deeply grateful for your support.</p><p><strong>Full Release Details</strong></p><ul><li>Release date: September 25, 2025 (JST)</li><li>SRP: $49.99 USD / 6,600 JPY</li><li>Platform: Steam</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>What’s New in the Official Full Release</strong></p><ul><li>Addition of new car models and car parts</li><li>Addition of a new chapter and new rivals</li><li>Game balancing and adjustments based on feedback from players</li></ul><p>We would also like to provide some feature updates.</p><p>We have decided to postpone the implementation of the “Replay Feature” and prioritize additional game volume such as additional story content. We sincerely apologize to everyone who was looking forward to this feature. We will do our best to add the feature, polished and ready in future game updates.</p><p>After careful consideration, we have also decided not to implement “Steam Record Ranking” due to insufficient cheat prevention measures. We believe introducing the feature without being able to provide a fair playing field for all players would negatively impact the player experience.</p><p>The passion, feedback and support from the fans has been invaluable to the development team.</p><p>We are very excited to finally deliver the complete experience and hope everyone will have a great time playing <em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</em>.</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/tokyo-xtreme-racer-launches-september-25]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>