<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:16:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth Must Die launches January 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/earth-must-die-launches-january-27</link>
            <guid>1406032</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Point-and-click adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Point-and-Click [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/point-and-click">Point-and-click adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Earth Must Die [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/earth-must-die">Earth Must Die</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3639780/Earth_Must_Die/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on January 27, publisher <a title="Companies > No More Robots [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/no-more-robots">No More Robots</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Size Five [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/size-five">Size Five</a> announced. A new demo is available now. <span id="more-1019045"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via No More Robots:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the desk of VValak Lizardtongue, Grand Shepherd of the <a title="Games > Tyr" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tyr">Tyr</a>ythian Empire:</p><p>Well this is just complete and utter bullshit.</p><p>Those idiotic, moronic Terranoids think they can just roll in here and take over my beautiful Tyrythian kingdom? The kingdom that I built from the ground up with my bare hands, and only sort of inherited from my dear, sweet, extremely dead father?</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Did I mention that this is bullshit?</p><p>It’s fine though, because what they don’t realize is that I am going to make them very, very dead. Along with my trusty sidekick and childhood nursing bot Milky—please do not ask me questions about that—I will whiz over to Earth, turn it into a stinking pile of rubble, and be back home in time for a warm glass of milk before bed.</p><p><em>Earth Must Die</em> is the story of my glorious rise to power (off the back of my adored father’s passing), my subsequent accidental surrender to the Terranoids, and my infamous revenge against Earth and everything it stands for.</p><p>Apparently the story is retold in the form of one of those old point and click <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,813 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure games</a> that people gave a shit about in the 1990s, I wanna say? But in 2025. Doesn’t sound like a good idea to me, but what do I know—I’m just a benevolent, terrifying leader of worlds who everyone loves and also super respects.</p><p>I’m also not sure what the phrase “British comedy royalty” is supposed to mean, but I guess they got a bunch of “funny” fuckwits to dub over my glorious voyage to feed the Terranoids their own arseholes? Let me just copy/paste the list here so I don’t have to give them any more time and effort than they deserve:</p><ul><li>Joel Fry – Vvalak Lizardtongue</li><li>Martha Howe-Douglas – Milky</li><li>Alex Horne – Major Haskit, Bentik</li><li>Ben Starr – Krall, Danzan</li><li>Tamsin Greig – Rena, Blorr, Spiffy</li><li>Matthew Holness – Phelonius Skwid</li><li>Mike Wozniak – Willip, Jobson, Druce</li><li>Don Warrington – Quintarian</li><li>Stevie Martin – Skwidbot</li><li>Sophie Duker – Meebap</li><li>Emma Fryer – Parrach, Betsy</li><li>Alasdair Beckett-King – Oogles, Toilet, Vacuum, Village Elder</li><li>Rosie Holt – Chizz, Zarlaph, Karton</li><li>Jon Blyth – Fnaaaarglurp, Olkus</li><li>Julie Nolke – Grace Flufton</li><li>Sam O’Leary – Ian Gard, Ripper</li><li>Tom Lawrinson – Tree, Needledick</li><li><a title="Games > Sally [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sally">Sally</a> Beaumont – Glushh, Big Snake</li><li>David Monteith – Allus, Pfysus, Marvap, Altican, Commandant</li><li>Inel Tomlinson – Cecil, Zertan, Robert Droid, Skwid Guards</li><li>Theo Leslie – Dinny</li></ul><p>How do I not have someone to do this for me? Anyway, apparently my magnificent story is told over a series of many hours, and you click a bunch and things happen and really I don’t care about any of this, I’m just here for the glory.</p><p>You’ll be able to experience my unbelievably cool story through something called “Steam,” which is apparently how you access experiences like this back in 2025. Sounds primitive, but I guess every civilization has to start as gross slugs crawling their way onto the banks of the future.</p><p>VValak signing off.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Earth Must Die is launching January 27th on Steam! Play the demo NOW!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nr0mqovgrHA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/earth-must-die-launches-january-27]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>