<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 13:17:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steel Seed ‘Extended Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/steel-seed-extended-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steel-seed-%E2%80%98extended-gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.1146198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/steel-seed-extended-gameplay-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>15 minutes of new footage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > ESDigital Games [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/esdigital-games">ESDigital Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Storm in a Teacup [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/storm-in-a-teacup">Storm in a Teacup</a> have released a 15-minute extended gameplay trailer for <a title="Genres > Stealth [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,603 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,152 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Steel Seed [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/steel-seed">Steel Seed</a></em>. <span id="more-952784"></span></p><p>The trailer provides an in-depth look at protagonist Zoe and her flying drone companion, KOBY, at the start of their journey in a hostile underground facility filled with secrets and danger.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via ESDigital Games:</p><blockquote><p><em>Steel Seed</em> is a gripping action-adventure game from the visionary team behind the critically acclaimed Close to the Sun set in a dark sci-fi world where humanity stands on the brink of extinction. Join Zoe and her flying drone companion KOBY as they investigate the depths of a hostile underground facility in search of answers and the key to mankind’s <a title="Genres > Survival [398 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>.</p><p>From towering industrial landscapes to eerie biodomes, the world of <em>Steel Seed</em> is as haunting as it is immersive, with a story revised and edited by BAFTA-winning Martin Korda. Players can adapt their playstyle with a unique blend of stealth-action gameplay, three distinct skill trees, and over 40 upgradable abilities.</p></blockquote><p><em>Steel Seed</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,142 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,948 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/458430/Steel_Seed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/steel-seed-cdc5d9" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on April 10. A physical edition will be available for PlayStation 5 on May 23.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Extended Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Steel Seed | Extended Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TADHqpf2Sds?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Backyard Baseball ’97 now available for iOS, Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/backyard-baseball-97-now-available-for-ios-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/backyard-baseball-%E2%80%9997-now-available-for-ios-android.1146162/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/backyard-baseball-97-now-available-for-ios-android<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Console versions seemingly coming next.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Backyard Baseball '97 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/backyard-baseball-97">Backyard Baseball ’97</a></em> is now available for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/backyard-baseball-97/id6740349666" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pgp.bybb97" target="_blank">Google Play</a> for $4.99, publisher <a title="Companies > Playground Productions [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playground-productions">Playground Productions</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Mega Cat Studios [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mega-cat-studios">Mega Cat Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-952443"></span></p><p>The re-release of the 1997 <a title="Genres > Sports [603 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">sports game</a> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3170540/Backyard_Baseball_97/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 10, 2024.</p><p>A <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10014585" target="_blank">PlayStation Store page</a> for PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 versions also <a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Backyard-Baseball-97_03-27-25_PlayStation-Store.jpg" target="_blank">went live for wishlisting</a> earlier this week before being taken down today. Despite the text—“The award winning classic is now available on PlayStation 4 &amp; 5!”—a representative for the publisher told <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a>, “The team is naturally exploring other platforms for the <em><a title="Games > Backyard Sports [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/backyard-sports">Backyard Sports</a></em> re-releases. Right now, no additional platforms have been confirmed or announced for <em>Backyard Baseball ’97</em> beyond Steam, with iOS and Android being announced (and launching) [today]. The PlayStation Store listing was simply a placeholder.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Relive the game that started it all! The original Backyard Baseball ’97, now enhanced to run on Steam. Whether you’re picking your dream team, hitting home runs, or just here for the witty banter, step back into the backyard and experience the game that made baseball fun for everyone!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Play pick-up games, practice batting, keep track of stats, compete in single games or a whole season – you can even set the rules! Backyard Baseball ‘97 features all of the realism and statistics of adult baseball games but with simple, intuitive controls that anyone can master.</p><p><strong>Batter Up, Playground Style</strong></p><p>The rules for Backyard Baseball are a hybrid of Major and Little League rules:</p><ul><li>No leading off</li><li>No Injuries</li><li>Bunting is allowed</li><li>Tagging up is allowed</li><li>You can also practice batting</li></ul><p>To get into the swing of things, choose a batter and face Mr. Clanky for some batting practice. This is where you’ll learn just when to click to make your chosen batter hit that ball!</p><p><strong>One Nation Under Pablo</strong></p><p>For many fans, this is the game that debuted one of the most iconic video game characters of the 90s or any era—the legend himself, Pablo Sanchez. Build a roster from a cast of 30 hilarious child athletes who made Backyard Baseball a cult classic.</p><p><strong>Game Modes</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Random Pick-Up</strong> – A quick way to jump right in! The computer chooses a random team for you and itself, and the game starts immediately.</li><li><strong>Single Game</strong> – You take turns with the computer, choosing players from a random pool of characters.</li><li><strong>Season</strong> – You create a team and manage the team through a 14 game series. The opposing teams are computer generated. At the end of the season the best two teams advance to the BBL playoffs (best of three). The playoffs winner advances to the championship series which consists of the Super Entire Nation Tournament (best of three) and then the Ultra Grand Championship of the Universe Series (best of five)!</li></ul><p><strong>Global Leaderboard</strong></p><p>Compete globally! Steam’s Leaderboard system lets you compete with friends and players around the world. Track your home runs, strike-outs, grand slams, season wins and more in real-time. See how you stack up and strive to reach the top!</p><p>At our core, we are fans first–not just of video games but of the Backyard Sports franchise. Fans have asked for accessible and legal ways to play their original Backyard titles for years, and we are excited to deliver.</p><p>Without having access to the source code, there are hard limitations on the experience we can create. As an example, we can’t support gamepads, nor the Steam deck, in these original titles. We can’t use the original 32bit code to support modern macOS, as even with an incredibly clever wrapper, macOS can’t execute the binaries.</p><p>We can make the game run buttery smooth, stack it with Steam achievements to test your mettle and give you a chance to batter up to compete in the Steam Global Leaderboards for Home Runs. Baseball 1997 runs well, looks better than ever, and creates a new installation for digital preservation within the Backyard Sports catalog that allows the next generation of fans to fall in love with the title that started it all.</p><p><strong>Development</strong></p><p>With the original source code lost in the years since the 1997 release, Playground Productions has teamed up with Mega Cat Studios to remaster the original titles and bring them to modern devices. Forming a team of avid gamers and <em>Backyard Sports</em> enthusiasts, Mega Cat accomplished a near-impossible feat by hacking the original CD-ROM and developing new game builds to be compatible with current generation PCs. It was a meticulous process that took a considerable amount of time and effort to revitalize the game. Given the intricacies involved in this remaster, <em>Backyard Baseball ’97</em> is only compatible with PC devices at this time, but both Mega Cat and Playground Productions are working diligently to ensure <em>Backyard Sports</em> becomes available on multiple platforms moving forward.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>