<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:37:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shine Post: Be Your Idol! platform changed from mobile to console]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/shine-post-be-your-idol-platform-changed-from-mobile-to-console</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shine-post-be-your-idol-platform-changed-from-mobile-to-console.1076352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/shine-post-be-your-idol-platform-changed-from-mobile-to-console<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Specific platform(s) to be announced at a later date.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Shine Post: Be Your Idol!" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shine-post-be-your-idol">Shine Post: Be Your Idol!</a></em>, which was first announced in October 2021 as an iOS and Android game based on the idol mixed media series <em>Shine Post</em>, has changed its supported platforms to from mobile to console, <a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,096 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/SHINEPOST_PJ/status/1876554370164351019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. Specific platform(s) will be announced at a later date. <span id="more-937198"></span></p><p>Here is the full message from the development team:</p><blockquote><p><strong><em>Shine Post: Be Your Idol!</em> Platform Change Announcement</strong></p><p>Thank you for your continued support despite the long wait for <em>Shine Post: Be Your Idol!</em> The reason for the delay is that we were considering how to best deliver <em>Shine Post</em>‘s game content. After carefully considering every option and repeated discussions, we have decided to change the supported platform.</p><p>The fragmented updates we have provided up until now will reset, and rather than a game design centered around mobile operations, we will rebuild the game with goal-oriented gameplay characteristic of console games.</p><p><em>Shine Post</em> is a story about idols who, while sometimes lost or discouraged, run with all their might toward their dreams. After thinking about how to properly depict these idols’ pursuit of their dreams, we came to the conclusion that offering the game on a platform other than mobile would be the best approach.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In the original story, a talented manager works behind the scenes to help the idols’ dreams come true, but in this game, players will take on the role of someone who works both behind the scenes and in the spotlight to help the idols achieve their dreams. Whether their dreams come true or not will depend entirely on the player’s thoughts and decisions. We are putting all our efforts into creating something that everyone will enjoy.</p><p>That said, in order to avoid sharing uncertain information and letting everyone down, we will announce the specific platform(s) and game content, along with the release timing, at a later date. You will have to wait a little longer, but we hope to provide as many details as possible when we are able to share more. We would appreciate it if you could bear with us just a little longer.</p><p>—The <em>Shine Post: Be Your Idol!</em> Development Team</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Tale of Bistun coming to PS5, PS4, and Switch on January 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/the-tale-of-bistun-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-january-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-tale-of-bistun-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-january-21.1076289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/the-tale-of-bistun-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-january-21<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox One and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > IMGN.PRO [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/imgn-pro">IMGN.PRO</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Black Cube Games [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/black-cube-games">Black Cube Games</a> will release <a title="Genres > Action [2,400 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,976 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > The Tale of Bistun [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-tale-of-bistun">The Tale of Bistun</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,624 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,569 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,483 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on January 21 for $17.99 / £13.99 / €14.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-937094"></span></p><p><em>The Tale of Bistun</em> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2022/06/the-tale-of-bistun-launches-july-13">first launched</a> for Xbox One and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/916140/The_Tale_of_Bistun/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/the-tale-of-bistun-9d6c5f" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/the_tale_of_bistun" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on July 13, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via IMGN.PRO:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>The Tale of Bistun</em> follows an amnesiac stone-carver on his journey up the slopes of the intimidating Mount Bistun. He’ll have to battle legions of monstrous foes using fast-paced, melee combat and powerful magical abilities as he explores the real world and the mysterious place of forgotten memories, known as the Revelations Realm, in search of answers. A mysterious voice encourages him to keep going, recounting his every step and keeping close tabs on his quest through these beautiful but blight-infested lands.</p><p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>A Re-telling of a Persian Legend</strong> – Based on an epic romantic poem from the 12th century, “Khosrow and Shirin,” <em>The Tale of Bistun</em> is a tale of love, loss, and adventure through a land where magic and bravery collide.</li><li><strong>A Stunning Land of Myth and Magic</strong> – Ascend the deadly slopes of Mount Bistun and battle through a gorgeous world that brings the ancient lands of Mesopotamia to life.</li><li><strong>Hack, Slash, and Blast</strong> – Battle hordes of dangerous foes using fast-paced tactical melee combat and ferocious magical abilities</li><li><strong>Carve Out Your Tale</strong> – King Darius, eat your heart out! Create your Behistun Inscription and etch out beautiful engravings to tell the world your story.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,705 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Tale of Bistun - Official PlayStation Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GhifGbCY4AQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Switch Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p>h0tXjFIYZc8</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>