<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:22:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yooka-Replaylee – one hour of gameplay with developer commentary]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/yooka-replaylee-one-hour-of-gameplay-with-developer-commentary</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yooka-replaylee-%E2%80%93-one-hour-of-gameplay-with-developer-commentary.1053945/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/yooka-replaylee-one-hour-of-gameplay-with-developer-commentary<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New features and more changes revealed.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Playtonic has released a one-hour gameplay walkthrough of <em>Yooka-Laylee</em> remake <em><a title="Games > Yooka-Replaylee [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yooka-replaylee">Yooka-Replaylee</a></em> with commentary from senior community manager Steve James and studio and game director Gavin Price. <span id="more-931916"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of what you will see:</p><blockquote><p><strong>What’s New? What’s Changed?</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Coinelius’ Coins’ New Color</strong> – Coinelius, the helpful piggy bank and new character edition to <em>Yooka-Replaylee</em> has already undergone a change with his beautiful platinum coins having stolen the golden hues of the Quill because…</li><li><strong>Level-Specific Quills</strong> – Having given up their golden coat to Coinelius’ coins, Quills now come in a variety of colours as they become specific to the level the player is currently in. Why is this? Because our crafty salesman Trowzer has gotten pickier over the years.</li><li><strong>Trowzer’s New Wares</strong> – The role of Trowzer is fundamentally changing in <em>Yooka-Replaylee</em> with a whole new set of wares to sell. What these wares are we are not ready to reveal quite yet.</li><li><strong>All Moves From the Beginning</strong> – In one of the bigger changes to the game, and why the role of our beloved salesman has changed, is that players will have access to the full arsenal of Yooka and Laylee’s moves from the start of the game.</li><li><strong>New Pagie Pieces Collectible</strong> – A new collectible has joined the roster in the form of Pagie pieces. Collecting these will unlock additional bonuses.</li><li><strong>Levels Available in Their “Expanded” Stage From the Start</strong> – In another change to the original <em>Yooka-Laylee</em>, levels will now be available in their entirety from the very start.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Yooka-Replaylee</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,430 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, “<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/yooka-replaylee-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-nintendo-consoles">Nintendo consoles</a>,” and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,853 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2448020/YookaReplaylee/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch the footage below.</p><h2><span>One Hour of Gameplay with Developer Commentary</span></h2><p><iframe title="Yooka-Replaylee Demo - Developer Commentary!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_tP6kgRV-0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reuters: Ubisoft shareholders in talks over possible buyout terms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/reuters-ubisoft-shareholders-in-talks-over-possible-buyout-terms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reuters-ubisoft-shareholders-in-talks-over-possible-buyout-terms.1053900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/reuters-ubisoft-shareholders-in-talks-over-possible-buyout-terms<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>The Guillemot family reportedly looking to Tencent to remain in control.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Ubisoft [1,286 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ubisoft">Ubisoft</a> shareholders are considering how to structure a possible buyout, two people familiar with the matter told <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/ubisoft-shareholders-talks-over-possible-buyout-terms-sources-say-2024-12-06/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Reuters</a>. <span id="more-931905"></span></p><p>The Guillemot family, which is the largest and founding shareholder of Ubisoft, has reportedly been in talks with <a title="Companies > Tencent [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent">Tencent</a>, which owns a 10 percent stake in the company, and other shareholders in recent weeks about funding a <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a>-led buyout.</p><p>The people said that the Guillemot family would like to retain control over the company, but Tencent has not decided whether it will participate in a buyout and increase its stake in the company. Tencent is said to have asked for a greater say on future board decisions in return, which the Guillemot family has not agreed to.</p><p>Discussions are reportedly ongoing as Tencent would like to prevent a hostile takeover of Ubisoft by other investors. One person said Tencent’s plan is to remain patient and wait for the Guillemot family to agree to a deal.</p><p>Both Tencent and the Guillemot family declined to comment, but a representative for Ubisoft said, “We remain committed to making decisions in the best interests of all of our stakeholders. In this context, as we have already indicated, the Company is also reviewing all its strategic options.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>