<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:35:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shuffle Tactics launches June 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/shuffle-tactics-launches-june-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shuffle-tactics-launches-june-24.1188927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/shuffle-tactics-launches-june-24<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dark fantasy tactical deckbuilding RPG gets new demo.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Dark fantasy tactical deckbuilding <a title="Genres > RPG [17,246 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Shuffle Tactics" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shuffle-tactics">Shuffle Tactics</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2186580/Shuffle_Tactics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on June 24, publisher <a title="Companies > The Arcade Crew [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-arcade-crew">The Arcade Crew</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Club Sandwich" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/club-sandwich">Club Sandwich</a> announced. An expanded demo is now available. <span id="more-964874"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the demo’s new content and features, via The Arcade Crew:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong>All-New Content</strong><ul><li>A brand new playable hero, Fletch:<ul><li>Unshakably proud of his peasant roots and humble hometown, Fletch has no reservations in challenging the king’s authority, standing firm in battle behind defensive structures he crafts with his own hands.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li>Encounter four total bosses, featuring two brand-new bosses (two boss fights per run, randomly selected for each biome)</li><li>The debut of two powerful sidekicks—these allies wield unique abilities that can turn a nigh impossible skirmish into a fair fight<ul><li>Each sidekick is skilled in a different area such as healing, magic, and archery. Choose the best sidekicks to complement your playstyle, but be mindful of your decisions—only two sidekicks can be hired during a run.</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Explore the Engrossing Tactical Depth of <em>Shuffle Tactics</em></strong><ul><li>Play as the fierce Doberknight, a sword-hurling powerhouse that can kick foes into optimal positions. Cunning fighters can also unlock an alternate kit of abilities tailored to spread corrupting fire across tiles on the grid-based map, adding another layer to the Doberknight’s deep strategic potential.</li><li>Build winning strategies utilizing <em>Shuffle Tactics</em>‘ cards, charms and relics; the demo offers one third of the full game’s itemset.</li><li>Ally with a roster of five total sidekicks, each with different abilities to aid you in battle.</li><li>Forge your path across two biomes: the dilapidated outskirts of a Capital known as The Deluge, and The Snarl, a lush forest teeming with menacing creatures.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>And here is a brief overview of the game:</p><blockquote><p>In <em>Shuffle Tactics</em>‘ medieval world of Asteria, King Ogma has cursed the land while attempting to revive his beloved queen. Instead of returning his true love to her kingdom, King Ogma has inflicted Glimmer upon the world. This mysterious force has corrupted the inhabitants of Asteria and the King himself, while also imbuing <em>Shuffle Tactics</em>‘ starring heroes with special powers. Discover the secret behind the curse that repeatedly revives these warriors after they fall in battle, all while fighting to bring down the corrupted King Ogma to restore peace to the realm of Asteria.</p><p>Admire <em>Shuffle Tactics</em>‘ weaving of 2D pixel art with 3D environments as you strategize your path to victory, and claim your rightful place as Asteria’s new King. Tacticians must navigate sprawling 3D battlefields, where every angle and elevation can mean the difference between victory and defeat, emphasizing the critical importance of positioning. For warlords with a competitive edge, medals will be awarded to players with the fastest run, lowest damage received during a run, and biggest single attack damage.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Shuffle Tactics | Release Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_UycdxFWlw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>