<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:07:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homura: The Crimson Warriors coming west in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/homura-the-crimson-warriors-coming-west-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/homura-the-crimson-warriors-coming-west-in-2026.1299369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Otome visual novel released as Kurenai no Homura: Sanada Ninpouchou in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [418 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a> will release <a title="Genres > Otome [116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/otome">otome visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Homura: The Crimson Warriors [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/homura-the-crimson-warriors">Homura: The Crimson Warriors</a></em> for Switch in 2026 in the west, the publisher announced. <span id="more-992841"></span></p><p><em>Houra: The <a title="Companies > crim [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">Crim</a>son Warriors</em> first launched for PS Vita on June 28, 2018 in Japan under the title <em>Kurenai no Homura: Sanada Ninpouchou</em>. A Switch version followed on February 15, 2024.</p><p>Wishlisting for the standard edition is available now via <a href="https://ifi.store/products/homura" target="_blank">IFI’s Online Store</a>.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Homura-Crimson-Warriors_09-16-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Idea Factory International:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Fourteen years have passed since the Battle of Sekigahara split Japan in two.</p><p>Now firmly in control, the Tokugawa shogunate is scheming to eliminate the Toyotomi clan, a long-standing thorn in its side.</p><p>In response, the Toyotomi clan has decided to confront the Tokugawa head-on, using Osaka Castle as their stronghold. Calls for support were sent to daimyo throughout the nation and a mere few answered the call. One of these brave warriors was Nobushige Sanada, the second son of the Sanada family who was cast away to Mt. Kudo on house arrest after the Battle of Sekigahara.</p><p>Alongside Nobushige on his escape from Mt. Kudo are the Sanada Ten Braves, ten ninjas who serve him even after their exile. Standing in their way are the Ura Yagyu, a group comprised of assassins who have carried out many killings under orders from the shogunate, mysterious swordsmen, and mighty warriors.</p><p>This is the final chapter of the Warring States period. It is a tale of the bonds and way of life shared by the Nobushige Sanada and the Ten Braves who gather at Osaka Castle.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Amongst the Fire and Ashes, Love Will Prevail</strong> – Previously released in Japan on PS Vita in 2018, Western fans can experience the historical fantasy otome as the protagonist Mutsumi Mochizuki fights alongside the Crimson Warriors. Accompanied with multiple endings and CGs, this legendary battle of love tangled with iconic historical events and original characters in the Warring States period is sure to capture the hearts of history otome lovers!</li><li><strong>Maintain Peak Performance With Energy Reading</strong> – Use Energy Reading to detect the affection level and Ring status of love interests. Mutsumi has the special ability to adjust the love interests’ Rings. When sped up, it allows them to utilize unique powers at the cost of their physical health. Make sure to keep their Rings balanced! If their health deteriorates too much, the consequences could be dire…</li><li><strong>Ninja Guidance</strong> – Use your ninja scrolls to keep track of where you are in the story and revisit moments of the past if you seek a different outcome of the path you’ve chosen. Adjust both your affection and ring levels with each warrior when you select previously viewed events to change the course of history!</li><li><strong>Path of the Samurai</strong> – Throughout the story, you can level up your ninja rank to keep up with the Crimson Warriors during battle. Take your ninja skills to the next level and make it your mission to reach <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter rank and ensure victory against the Ura Yagyu!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://ifi.games/homura/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Homura: The Crimson Warriors | Announcement Trailer | Nintendo Switch™" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/emm5V2PiQJo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/homura-the-crimson-warriors-coming-west-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei ‘One Thousand Blades’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/ghost-of-yotei-one-thousand-blades-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-%E2%80%98one-thousand-blades%E2%80%99-trailer.1299363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The story of a warrior in Japan on a mission of vengeance.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,053 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sucker Punch Productions [155 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/sucker-punch-productions">Sucker Punch Productions</a> have released a new trailer for <em><a title="Games > Ghost of Yotei [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a></em> dubbed “One Thousand Blades.” <span id="more-992846"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Sony Interactive Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Become a different kind of ghost and witness a bold new story set against the stunning backdrop of northern Japan’s rugged landscapes.</p><p>Taking place 300 years after the critically acclaimed <em><a title="Games > Ghost of Tsushima [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a></em>, this standalone experience follows a haunted, lone mercenary named Atsu in the 1600s. Thirsty for revenge, she sets out to hunt down those who killed her family many years prior.</p><p>Her quest across Ezo will take her to unexplored lands as she seeks out a gang of six outlaws. Along the way, she’ll encounter far more than she could have wagered for at the journey’s outset. Help her find unlikely allies, forge lasting bonds and build a path towards healing and redemption.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Feel the thrill of combat—the haptic feedback of the DualSense wireless controller brings Atsu’s katana combat to your fingertips.</li><li><a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter the bow and arrow or grappling hook, experience the excitement of battle, and explore various types of terrain—all accentuated by the DualSense wireless controller’s adaptive triggers.</li><li>Appreciate the power of the <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,368 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> console with lightning-fast load times rapidly transporting you to the beautiful surroundings of northern Japan.</li><li>Explore lush, vibrant environments rendered with stunning visuals, as Atsu travels through snowy ridges, fields of wildflowers and rocky terrain—amongst others.</li><li>Tempest 3D AudioTech: Immerse yourself in 1600s Japan as 3D spatial audio creates unique soundscapes all around you.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Ghost of Yotei</em> is due out for PlayStation 5 on October 2.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>One Thousand Blades Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - One Thousand Blades Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R-8v2fm2WkQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/ghost-of-yotei-one-thousand-blades-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>