<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:09:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Mobile closed alpha test set for December]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/palworld-mobile-closed-alpha-test-set-for-december</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-mobile-closed-alpha-test-set-for-december.1352113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Registration now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > KRAFTON [71 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krafton">KRAFTON</a> will host a closed alpha test for <em><a title="Games > Palworld Mobile [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/palworld-mobile">Palworld Mobile</a></em> in December, the company announced. Sign-ups are available now via the game’s <a href="https://palworldm.com/alpha-test" target="_blank">official website</a> until November 26. <span id="more-1006622"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via KRAFTON:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><a title="Genres > Action [3,198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,696 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> with Pals! Be the first to make history!</p><p><em>Palworld Mobile</em> is a mobile adaptation of the <em><a title="Games > Palworld [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/palworld">Palworld</a></em> intellectual property, reimagining the world and core gameplay of the global hit for mobile platforms. Embark on a new adventure with mysterious creatures called Pals—explore vast open fields, survive harsh environments, craft tools and items, and engage in dynamic combat.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Survival [480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a></strong> – Survive the dangers of starvation, the cold, and formidable foes alongside mysterious creatures called “Pals” while exploring a vast world filled with them. Pals you capture in the field can become your loyal allies in battle, but in dire times, they might also just end up on your dinner table.</li><li><strong>Combat</strong> – <a title="Companies > Aiming [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/aiming">Aiming</a> and pulling the trigger is your job, but changing the tide of battle is up to power of Pals who’ve been thrown into the fight. From devastating firepower to life-saving healing when you need it most—Pals don’t have to be your battle companions. Survival is all that matters, whether Pals serve as weapons or healing potions.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Crafting [47 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">Crafting</a></strong> – Gather materials to craft tools and buildings essential for your survival. From wooden clubs to guns, and from Primitive Workbenches to large factories—your precious Pals who once lent you a helping hand (or paw) in building your first humble base will soon become part of your much greater “labor force.”</li><li><strong>Together</strong> – Breed and hatch Pals in the Plaza, battle against other players, and challenge mighty bosses. “United we stand,” is how the saying goes, but… there are always those who just want to watch the world burn.</li></ul></blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/palworld-mobile/november-12-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1006625"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/palworld-mobile-closed-alpha-test-set-for-december]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSOFT announces MMORPG Horizon Steel Frontiers for PC, iOS, and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/ncsoft-announces-mmorpg-horizon-steel-frontiers-for-pc-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft-announces-mmorpg-horizon-steel-frontiers-for-pc-ios-and-android.1352092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>And here are some comments from NCSOFT chief corporate officer Taekjin Kim, Guerrilla Games studio director Jan-Bart van Beek, and NCSOFT executive producer Sung-Gu Lee, via the announcement video:</p><div><p><strong>Taekjin Kim, NCSOFT Chief Corporate Officer</strong></p><p>“When I fist experienced <em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em> in 2017, I was instantly drawn into its vibrant and captivating world. The battles against colossal machine lifeforms were exhilarating and the mysterious narrative sparked my curiosity, urging me to explore every corner of that universe. Yet I couldn’t help but feel a little wistful that such an incredible world had to be experienced alone. I imagined how thrilling it would be to meet others, to team up and face these massive machines together.</p><p>“From the beginning, I was convinced: battling machine lifeforms would be far more exciting than facing any fantasy monster. That vision inspired us to create an MMO set in this extraordinary universe. And today, I’m proud to present <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em>—a dream realized. <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> represents a new challenge for NC, and the start of an exciting journey ahead. We hope you look forward to this new <em>Horizon</em> born from the collaboration between NC and Guerrilla.”</p><p><strong>Jan-Bart van Beek, Guerrilla Games Studio Director</strong></p><p>“I was the one who originally came up with the concept of the <em>Horizon</em> franchise. The <em>Horizon</em> franchise is incredibly special to me and to everyone at Guerrilla. It’s a world we’ve poured our hearts and souls into. It’s a place where humanity, nature, and technology are constantly colliding. It’s become a vibrant and living world full of stories, tribal cultures, and of course, those incredible animal-like machines that rule the land.</p><p>“From the very beginning of creating this franchise, we’ve imagined the <em>Horizon</em> universe as one that could be experienced in many different ways. <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> is a full-fledged MMORPG that NCSOFT has built specifically for mobile. With <em>Steel Frontiers</em>, you can step into this world, anywhere, anytime.</p><p>“Players take on the role of machine hunters, chasing opportunity in a region called the Deadlands, which is inspired by Arizona and New Mexico. You’re sharing the frontier with thousands of other players, sometimes working together to take down machines, and other times competing with rival tribes or fighting over resources. And that mix of cooperation and competition creates moments you could never script.</p><p>“At the heart of the <em>Horizon</em> story is the search for the balance between humanity, nature, and technology. Sometimes that’s harmony, sometimes that’s conflict. But it always creates a world filled with mystery and beauty. What we want players to feel is the world’s resilience and its hope. And that even when everything seems overwhelming, humanity can adapt, can survive, and find meaning in the world.</p><p>“We already had groups at Guerrilla playing <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> together at the office, and it’s really amazing. Whenever I get a chance to jump in on an early gameplay test, what really stands out is <em>Steel Frontiers</em>‘ distinct tone and atmosphere. It has a unique identity of its own, and has been brought to life by NCSOFT’s developers. But it fits perfectly with the Horizon universe, and that balance with the essence of <em>Horizon</em> and something fresh is what really excites me about this project.”</p><p><strong>Sung-Gu Lee, NCSOFT Executive Producer</strong></p><p>“I’m a bit nervous to present this project to the world for the first time, but at the same time, I’m extremely excited. The core concept of <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> can be summed up in one phrase: the thrill of taking down colossal machines. Hunting massive machines was one of the greatest appeals of the original&nbsp;<em>Horizon</em> series. And now, we’re expanding that experience into the world of MMORPGs.</p><p>“Our main focus is designing a new combat experience tailored for an MMORPG. In <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em>, we’ve added unique, original gameplay elements to the process of taking down giant machines. For example, after destroying a specific part of a machine, you can quickly approach and climb onto it using a Pullcaster, set traps on the damaged part, and inflict status effects. During battle, you can even pick up weapons dropped by the machine, carry them on your mount, and use them in subsequent fights. At the heart of giant machine hunts are two core values. cooperation and strategy. Players must take on their roles, act strategically, and work together seamlessly. These combat mechanics truly shine in large-scale battles, offering the scale and dynamism that only an MMORPG can provide.</p><p>“In <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em>, every player is a hero. We’ve put great care into customization, allowing you to fully express your individuality—even down to the smallest details. During character creation, we’ve incorporated the tribes from the original <em>Horizon</em> world. You can choose from diverse tribes such as Nora, Tenakth, Utaru, or Oseram, and create your character based on your preferred tribe. Our system provides a high degree of freedom, so you can design your character exactly as you envision—from facial features, body type, and hair, to makeup and finer details. The characters you create can be shared with other players, allowing you not only to show off your own style, but also draw inspiration from others to further customize your hero. Step into <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em> as a truly unique machine hunter, crafted entirely by you, and explore a world where your individuality matters.</p><p>“In the world of <em>Horizon Steel Frontiers</em>, you’ll be able to develop your own character, team up with friends to hunt colossal machines, and live the story of a machine hunter in the Deadlands. We can’t wait to see you all become the heroes of this adventure, and we’re doing our best to make that day come as soon as possible.”</p></div><p>Watch the announcement video and gameplay trailer below.</p></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/ncsoft-announces-mmorpg-horizon-steel-frontiers-for-pc-ios-and-android]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding Isolations animated series announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/death-stranding-isolations-animated-series-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-isolations-animated-series-announced.1352089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Streaming exclusively on Disney+ in 2027.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Kojima Productions [564 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kojima-productions">Kojima Productions</a> has <a href="https://www.kojimaproductions.jp/deathstranding-animation-series-announcement" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Death Stranding [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-stranding">Death Stranding</a> Isolations</em> (working title), an animated series project produced by E&amp;H production. It will stream exclusively on Disney+ in 2027. <span id="more-1006601"></span></p><p>The series will tell a new story that follows a young man and woman as they set out on an <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,696 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. It follows in the footsteps of the <em>Death Stranding</em> video game in spirit and ideas, and depicts the world through a “bold and yet subtle touch and top-class hand-drawn animation.”</p><p>Here is the story synopsis and staff list:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Story Synopsis</strong></p><p>Once, there was an explosion…</p><p>Lonesome souls of the dead manifest in the physical world, reaching in search of the living. However, the connection they create triggers a massive explosion that eradicates anything of this world—a phenomenon referred to as the Death Stranding. These events wipe out nations as well as civilization itself. People who remain are now isolated, withdrawn, and without connections. As humanity stands at the brink a legendary porter set out to transport both cargo and wishes of its senders, reconnecting people in the hope that they might still be saved.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Based on the video game born out of the mind of legendary game creator, <a title="People > Hideo Kojima [145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/people/hideo-kojima">Hideo Kojima</a>, comes a new animation series headed by Japan’s up-and-coming animation studio E&amp;H production. Helmed by E&amp;H’s Takayuki Sano, it follows in the footsteps of the original in spirit and ideas and depict the world of Death Stranding through a bold and yet subtle touch and top-class hand-drawn animation.</p><p>Somewhere in North America, just as Sam Bridges walks through the continent in order to save America, the someones are also trying to deal with their isolation in their own way. An old man trying to realize salvation through ways outside of the connection advocated by Bridges. A female warrior who tries to kickstart a world of constant fighting. A boy with a grudge against Bridges. A girl who embraces loneliness.</p><p>On the precipice of the end of humanity and the world, their fates and hopes converge, as another story of Death Stranding begins.</p><p>And now, comes another explosion…</p><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Executive Producer:</strong> Hideo Kojima</li><li><strong>Director:</strong> Takayuki Sano</li><li><strong>Original Character Design:</strong> Ilya Kuvshinov</li><li><strong>Animation Production:</strong> E&amp;H production</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/death-stranding-isolations-animated-series-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SANABI free DLC ‘A Haunted Day’ launches November 27 for PC, later for Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/sanabi-free-dlc-a-haunted-day-launches-november-27-for-pc-later-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sanabi-free-dlc-%E2%80%98a-haunted-day%E2%80%99-launches-november-27-for-pc-later-for-switch.1352026/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Story set 13 years prior to the events of the main game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > SANABI [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sanabi">SANABI</a></em> free downloadable content expansion “A Haunted Day” will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3996620/SANABI_A_Haunted_Day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on November 27, followed by <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,976 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> at a later date, publisher <a title="Companies > NEOWIZ [90 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neowiz">NEOWIZ</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Wonder Potion [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wonder-potion">Wonder Potion</a> announced. <span id="more-1006520"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via NEOWIZ:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>“A Haunted Day” takes place prior to the events of the base game and centers on Major Song during her time at Uigeumbu No. 12 as she follows a lead into a treacherous scrapyard. Unlike the grappling mechanics in the base game, the downloadable content’s combat gameplay combines recoverable jumps with the raw power of Song’s shotgun for spectacular aerial maneuvers.</p><p>The first spin-off downloadable content of <em>SANABI</em>, packed with thrilling action expanding on the main story.</p><p>The downloadable content includes eight new stages and two boss fights.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>13 years ago, under an unreasonable order from her superior, Major Song headed to a suspicious scrapyard outside of Hanyang.</p><p>What awaited her there was a hail of bullets, explosions… and a general with a steel tiger?</p><p><strong>The New Playable Character: Major Song</strong></p><p>The playable character of this spin-off is Major Song, during her time serving in Uigeumbu No.12, before she met the General.</p><p><strong>Stylish and Agile “Aerial <a title="Genres > Action [3,198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>” <a title="Genres > Platformer [783 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">Platformer</a></strong></p><p>Major Song can perform agile aerial maneuvers with precision. Combined with her unique abilities—a recoverable mid-air jump and expert use of a shotgun—she becomes a formidable opponent, even against a General.</p><p>From Burst Mode, which defends against enemy attacks and boosts the power of all actions, to the enhanced shotgun that deals massive damage…</p><p>Play as Major Song, who is the youngest to ever pass the martial exam, a government-certified living weapon!</p><p><strong>Spin-Off Scenario: A Haunted Day</strong></p><p>Operation 3 was issued at an assault robot scrapyard, outside of Hanyang.</p><p>Major Song found a clue to the treason. She dives into this massive scrapyard with confidence, but something about this place feels… off.</p><p>There are maniacally aggressive robots and a disturbingly ominous signaling device.</p><p>A superior giving unreasonable orders, a scrapyard plagued by strange phenomena, and… a general with a steel tiger?</p><p>Today, it feels like haunted or something</p><p>What’s happening in this scrapyard?</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Free Expansion “A Haunted Day” Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="[SANABI: A Haunted Day] |​ Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ontZGBpnJlU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="귀신 씌인 날 |​ 출시일 공개 트레일러" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_GlLytImBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="《闪避刺客: 离奇的一天》 |​公开上线日期预告片" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g4v5SwIR8Hw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/sanabi-free-dlc-a-haunted-day-launches-november-27-for-pc-later-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>