<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:39:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magical Nut Ikuno launches May 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/magical-nut-ikuno-launches-may-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magical-nut-ikuno-launches-may-22.1183830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/magical-nut-ikuno-launches-may-22<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Nut-collecting action game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Nut-collecting <a title="Genres > Action [2,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Magical Nut Ikuno" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/magical-nut-ikuno">Magical Nut Ikuno</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,054 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,086 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3388890/Magical_Nut_Ikuno/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 22 for $14.99 / 1,980 yen, publisher and developer <a title="Companies > qureate [45 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/qureate">qureate</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Shochiku [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shochiku">Shochiku</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > Orgesta [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/orgesta">Orgesta</a> announced. It will support English, Japanese, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-963796"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://qureate.co.jp/ikuno/en/" target="_blank">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ About</strong></p><p>The battle of the Radiant fighters in search of the Crysnuts begins.</p><p>This is an action game where you will defeat the stage by collecting Crysnuts that are on the map without bumping into any enemies. Will radiant Fighters Ikuno Hinata and Anami Tsukine be able to destroy the ambitions of the evil empress Hamester!?</p><p><strong>■ Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Ikuno Hinata and Anami Tsukine are ordinary female college students! One day, they met the Crysnut Fairies, Sen and Rizu, who plan to restore world peace, and get asked to protect the world from the evil empress Hamester!</p><p>It seems as though Ikuno and Anami have the potential to become Radiant Fighters and fight against evil, but… Hamester attacks the city and things get dicey! After deciding to protect all that’s important and fight… They transform into Radiant Fighters!</p><p>To protect world peace and each other, the two rise! But Hamester becomes more powerful with the Crysnuts…</p><p>What will happen to world peace!? Fight for what’s right, Ikuno, Anami!</p><p><strong>■ Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Ikuno Hinata</strong> (voiced by Akiho Suzumoto) – She was attending college as an ordinary student, but after meeting the Crysnut fairy Sen, her life turns into a battle to save the world. She has a straightforward personality and does her best to treat everyone equally. She watches the kid’ anime and never misses an episode that she’s been watching since childhood. On top of that, she has learned dance from a young age, making her agile.</li><li><strong>Anami Tsukine</strong> (voiced by Saho Shirasu) – Best friends with Ikuno since childhood. Polite and gracious, but sometimes shows a surprisingly clumsy side. After meeting Rizu, a Crysnut Fairy, begins her quest with Ikuno. She has high academic skills and is good at studying. She is quick-witted, but her laid-back personality makes it difficult to tell.</li><li><strong>Sen</strong> (voiced by Saima nakano) – A Crysnut Fairy. Ikuno tripped and squashed him, and he became one with her as a result of this. He is confident and loved to be praised, loving himself more than he does others. However, he is just as much of a clumsy troublemaker.</li><li><strong>Rizu</strong> (voiced by Sachie Hirai) – The other Crysnut Spirit. Becomes one with Anami after being crushed by her. He has a serious personality and can’t feel rested unless rules are followed. Because of this, he can feel hard to work with, but he has developed a strong bond with Anami.</li><li><strong>Hamester</strong> (voiced by Rika Kinugawa)</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_963797"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>■ System</strong></p><p><strong>Retrieve the Crysnuts!</strong></p><p>Obtain all Crysnuts scattered throughout the map whilst avoiding the Hameham,</p><p>Hamester’s underlings to clear the stage.</p><p>Throughout the map are items, such as “Nut soda” that heals your health, and “<a title="Companies > Hamster Corporation [54 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hamster-corporation">Hamster</a> wheel” that will make you invincible against the Hamehams. Use these to conquer the stage! But watch out for traps that slow you down and stop your movement!</p><p><strong>Stuff the Cheeks With Crysnuts to Increase Volume!</strong></p><p>Collected Crysnuts will make “Sen” and “Rizu”‘s cheeks puff up who are attached to their chests.</p><p>The more Crysnuts that you collect, the biggest “Sen” and “Rizu”‘s cheeks will get!</p><p>Don’t get it mixed up…! Their chests aren’t getting bigger, their cheeks are just puffing up!</p><p>The more Crysnuts you collect, the bigger the cheek pouches grow!</p><p><strong>We Will Protect the Maidens’ Sanctuaries and Your Account!</strong></p><p>There is a mode that hides the girls’ parts that shouldn’t be seen with a “Light Curtain”! This will help avoid social media account bans… Maybe. The Light Curtain has its work cut out needing to both “protect maidens’ sanctuaries” and “protect gentlemen’s accounts”.</p><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Character Design:</strong> Waon Inui</li><li><strong>Scenario:</strong> Linkedbrain Inc.</li><li><strong>Producer:</strong> Yujiro Usuda</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a gameplay video below. View a set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/magical-nut-ikuno/may-8-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>PC Gameplay</span></h2><p><iframe title="Magical Nut Ikuno - PC Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l17dyn59_LI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>