<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:54:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles ‘Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-%E2%80%98gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.1275633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Lead your units to victory on grid-based maps.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> has released a new gameplay trailer for <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [444 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">strategy RPG</a> remaster <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles">Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</a></em>. <span id="more-986469"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Square Enix:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The dramatic tale of ambition, betrayal, and honor will come to life with an updated and enriched script with fully voiced dialogue, alongside improved graphics that bring a new level of immersion and playability to the battlefield. Additionally, the enhanced version brings quality-of-life updates like new difficulties, a revamped UI, auto save, and more that make the game more accessible to newcomers. The game features strategic, turn-based combat and an elaborate character progression system that makes every battle exhilarating and filled with unexpected twists.</p><p>Hailed as one of gaming’s greatest stories, in this standalone game, players will step into the Kingdom of Ivalice—a medieval world steeped in political conflict—in which players uncover the truth behind the young noble Ramza Beoulve, whose role on history’s stage has been buried from view.</p><p>The new key art of Ramza and Delita, the two heroes of this story, is drawn by Akihiko Yoshida. The art depicts the complex relationship of the two individuals—whether they stand together to protect one another, or the start of a departure as they walk divergent paths. Above them, Ovelia and Alma, both of whom have strong ties to Ramza and Delita, solemnly look into the distance, foreshadowing the direction that fate will lead them.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Legendary developers from the original game will make their return in <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em>, including Kazutoyo Maehiro (director), Hiroshi Minagawa (art director), and Yasumi Matsuno (original script, scenario writer and editor).</p><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> will include both enhanced and classic versions of the game. The enhanced version features modern upgrades and quality-of-life changes, including fully voiced characters, a ground-up graphical overhaul and an updated user interface that make <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> the perfect entry point to the tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [17,524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> classic for new players. The classic version is a nostalgic recreation of the game, developed for players who want to experience the original <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy Tactics [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-tactics">Final Fantasy Tactics</a></em> from 1997.</p><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em>‘ voice cast featuring an all-star lineup of new and returning <em><a title="Series > Final Fantasy [141 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a></em> cast members, including Joe Pitts (Ramza), Gregg Lowe (Delita), <a title="Games > Hannah" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hannah">Hannah</a> Melbourn (Agrias), Timothy Watson (Cidolfus), Harry McEntire (Mustadio), Ben Starr (Dycedarg), and cameos by Cody Christian (Cloud Strife from <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy VII Remake [107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-remake">Final Fantasy VII Remake</a></em> series) and Briana White (Aerith Gainsborough from <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> series).</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Challenging, Tactical Turn-Based Battles</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the addictive tactical turn-based combat and deep character progression system that made the game an instant tactical RPG classic. Players will test their battle acumen against a host of powerful enemies, and use the various terrains, characters and customizations, as well as their strategic thinking, to achieve victory.</li><li><strong>Customizable Job System with Dynamic Character Progression</strong> – Players can master a robust roster of over 20 jobs—including black mage, dragoon, geomancer (who can use the environment against foes), summoner (who can call forth the iconic <em>Final Fantasy</em> moogle and other espers), time mage (who uses time magick), thief, and more—and over 300 character abilities to strategically build endless party combinations.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Enhance [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d Gameplay Features and a Faithful Classic Version</strong> – The enhanced version features a revised script and fully voiced dialogue, offering a new level of enjoyment to this classic story. Additionally, a brand-new user interface, improved graphics, as well as additional character conversations and dialogue create a new level of immersion. Additionally, many new features have been added to make the game even more approachable including the ability to confirm unit turn order with the press of a button, scout the battlefield from afar with the tactical view feature, speed up battles with fast forward, auto save during battles, adjust game difficulty to match your play style, and more. The classic version faithfully recreates the 1997 release of <em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em> alongside the acclaimed War of the Lions translation—perfect for fans who wish to relive the original experience.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [345 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,270 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,978 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1004640/Final_Fantasy_Tactics__The_Ivalice_Chronicles/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 30.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY TACTICS - The Ivalice Chronicles | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wVCaeyucLTE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-gameplay-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triangle Strategy now available for PS5, Xbox Series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/triangle-strategy-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/triangle-strategy-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series.1275585/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Strategy RPG gets a surprise release on new platforms.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Artdink Corporation [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/artdink-corporation">Artdink Corporation</a> have released turn-based <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [444 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">strategy RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Triangle Strategy [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/triangle-strategy">Triangle Strategy</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,725 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> for a limited time launch price of $41.99, the companies announced. After September 4, the price will change to $59.99. The PC versions is also now available via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/game/9N0TCG0Z1NG4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>. <span id="more-937042"></span></p><p><em>Triangle Strategy</em> first launched for Switch on March 4, 2022, followed by PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1850510/TRIANGLE_STRATEGY/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on October 13, 2022, and Quest 2 and Quest 3 on October 31, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Square Enix:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A brand-new tactical RPG from the team behind the <em>Bravely</em> and <em><a title="Games > Octopath Traveler [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/octopath-traveler">Octopath Traveler</a></em> series. <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the dramatic story of war-torn Norzelia from different perspectives in stunning <a title="Series > HD-2D [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/hd-2d">HD-2D</a>, with a complex turn-based battle system.</p><p><strong>The World</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In the land of Norzelia, the Holy State of Hyzante controls the realm’s supply of salt; the snowswept Grand Duchy of Aesfrost, its veins of iron; and between the two lies the Kingdom of Glenbrook, a land of verdant forests and rivers. These nations waged what came to be known as the Saltiron War. After the war ended, the three nations maintained a tenuous peace. Yet a looming event threatens to destroy that balance…</p><p><strong>Multiple Stories, Multiple Endings</strong></p><ul><li>A tale that will challenge your convictions – You will face many difficult choices as the three nations conspire against each other. Making value judgments and decisions based on the ideals of Utility, Morality, and Liberty will determine your Conviction. These parameters will affect how the story branches, and which companions join your party.</li><li>Voting affects your fate – Important decisions affecting the fate of the protagonists are made through a voting process employing the Scales of Conviction. You must persuade allies, each with their own values and opinions, to cast their coin upon the scales to see your desired goals achieved.<br>Where will your convictions lead you?</li></ul><p><strong>Tactical Battles</strong></p><p>Make use of the terrain and field elevation, coordinate attacks between your units, surround your foes on both sides to perform follow-up attacks, and more. Create a party from 30 different characters with diverse skills to take on complex battles and emerge victorious.</p><p><strong>The Latest HD-2D Graphics</strong></p><p>Advanced pixel graphics as previously featured in the <em>Octopath Traveler</em> series, <em><a title="Games > Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a></em>, and <em><a title="Games > LIVE A LIVE (2022) [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/live-a-live-2022">LIVE A LIVE</a></em> bring the story to life in beautiful HD-2D. 3DCG image effects are added to retro graphics to create an immersive world full of character and delightful detail.</p><p><strong>To Fans of Tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [17,524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPGs</a></strong></p><p>Square Enix presents a brand-new tactical RPG to fans of games like <em>Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together</em>, <em><a title="Games > Tactics Ogre: Reborn [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tactics-ogre-reborn">Tactics Ogre: Reborn</a></em>, and Final <em>Fantasy Tactics: The War of the Lions</em>.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="TRIANGLE STRATEGY | PS5 and Xbox Series X|S Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WLWGABIipNQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="PS5版/Xbox版/Windows版『トライアングルストラテジー』アナウンストレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zGqhKI5sLzI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/triangle-strategy-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X launch October 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/rog-xbox-ally-and-rog-xbox-ally-x-launch-october-16</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rog-xbox-ally-and-rog-xbox-ally-x-launch-october-16.1275540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Playable at Gamescom 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a href="https://us.asus.click/ROGXboxAllyPR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ROG Xbox Ally</a> and <a href="https://us.asus.click/ROGXboxAllyXPR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ROG Xbox Ally X</a> handheld devices will launch on October 16 in Australia, Belgium, Canada, Czech Republic, China (<a title="Platforms > Xbox [26,484 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Ally X only), Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Hong Kong, Italy, Ireland, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Philippines, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Saudi Arabia, Singapore, South Korea, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Taiwan, Turkey, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, United States, and Vietnam, Microsoft Gaming and ASUS <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/20/rog-xbox-ally-handheld-release-date-october-features/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. Other markets where ROG Ally series products are sold, including Brazil, India, Indonesia and Thailand, will follow in early 2026. More information about pricing and pre-orders will be announced in the coming weeks. <span id="more-986421"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Ready for Launch</strong></p><p>Able On October 16, ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X will be available in the United States and across key international markets, spanning Europe, Asia, and the Middle East. Availability will expand to additional regions where the ROG Ally series is already sold today. Pricing and pre-order details will follow in the coming weeks.</p><p>ROG and Xbox co-developed the ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X to give gamers the freedom to play their way, anytime and anywhere. The ROG Xbox Ally is powered by an AMD Ryzen Z2 A processor featuring four Zen 2 cores with eight threads and eight RDNA 2 GPU cores. This offers ultra-efficient performance, paired with 16GB of LPDDR5X‑6400 RAM and a 512GB M.2 SSD, and all backed by a 60Wh battery for extended play.</p><p>The premium, high-performance ROG Xbox Ally X ups the ante with an AMD Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme, a new 8‑core/16‑thread Zen 5 APU with 16 RDNA 3.5 GPU cores and an integrated 50 TOPS NPU. The ROG Xbox Ally X also features 24GB of LPDDR5X‑8000 memory, a 1TB M.2 SSD, and boasts a larger 80Wh battery for longer playtime.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Optimized for Handheld</strong></p><p>The team at Xbox has been hard at work behind the scenes partnering with game studios to test and optimize thousands of <a title="Platforms > PC [23,978 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> titles for handheld compatibility. This new Handheld Compatibility Program ensures day-one users have the best experience possible on their ROG Xbox Ally handhelds. At launch, compatible games in the game library will sport Handheld Optimized or Mostly Compatible badges.</p><p>Handheld Optimized means that the game is ready to go—with default controller inputs, an intuitive text input method, accurate iconography, clear text legibility, and appropriate resolution in full-screen mode. Mostly Compatible means that the game may require minor in-game setting changes for an optimal experience on handheld.</p><p>The Xbox team is also bringing advanced shader delivery to the ROG Xbox Ally. This allows the Xbox app to preload a game’s shaders during download, so supported games will launch up to 10x faster, run more smoothly, and use less battery on first play. Xbox is working on adding this feature to even more games over time.</p><p>The ROG Xbox Ally X also features AMD’s cutting-edge Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme processor with a built-in NPU, that unlocks upcoming AI powered features starting early next year—with more to come. These features include:</p><ul><li><strong>Automatic Super Resolution (Auto SR)</strong> – a system-level feature that uses the power of the NPU to upscale games running at lower resolutions. This delivers high-resolution visuals and smooth framerates across a wide range of games, with no additional changes required from game developers.</li><li><strong>Highlight Reels</strong> – AI captures standout gameplay moments—like epic boss battles or victories—and generates short replay clips to share with friends or on social channels.</li></ul><p><strong>See the New ROG Ally Lineup in <a title="Genres > Action [2,951 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong></p><p>The ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X will make their fully playable debut at Gamescom 2025, joined by ROG’s complete 2025 laptop lineup powered by the latest NVIDIA GeForce RTX 50 Series GPUs. Visitors can test-drive the handhelds with a curated game selection including <em><a title="Games > Gears of War: Reloaded [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gears-of-war-reloaded">Gears of War: Reloaded</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > DOOM: The Dark Ages [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages">DOOM: The Dark Ages</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Hogwarts Legacy [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Lies of P [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lies-of-p">Lies of P</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Balatro [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/balatro">Balatro</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></em>, and <em><a title="Games > Roblox [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a></em> experiences such as <em>99 Nights in the Forest</em>, <em>Grow a Garden</em>, and <em>Rivals</em>.</p><p><strong>Meet and Greet Two Amazing Actors</strong></p><p>To celebrate the upcoming launch of the ROG Xbox Ally and Ally X, ROG is reuniting <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> actors Ned Luke and Shawn Fonteno for the latest installment of its ROG Travel campaign. Ned reprises his role as ROG Travel’s witty supervisor, while Shawn joins the cast as a new recruit bringing fresh ideas to the table. Both stars will appear live at the ROG booth, giving fans the chance to meet one of gaming’s most iconic duos in person.</p><p><strong>Specifications</strong></p><table><thead><tr><th></th><th>ROG Xbox Ally X</th><th>ROG Xbox Ally</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Operating System</td><td colspan="2">Windows 11 Home</td></tr><tr><td>Processor (APU)</td><td>AMD Ryzen AI Z2 Extreme Processor (50 TOPS NPU)</td><td>AMD Ryzen Z2 A Processor</td></tr><tr><td>Memory</td><td>24GB LPDDR5X-8000</td><td>16GB LPDDR5X-6400</td></tr><tr><td>Storage</td><td>1TB M.2 2280 SSD (upgradable)</td><td>512GB M.2 2280 SSD (upgradable)</td></tr><tr><td>Display</td><td colspan="2">7” FHD (1080p) IPS, 500 nits, 16:9<br>120Hz refresh rate<br>FreeSync Premium<br>Corning Gorilla Glass Victus + DXC Anti-Reflection</td></tr><tr><td>I/O</td><td>1x USB4 Type-C with DisplayPort 2.1 / Power Delivery 3.0, Thunderbolt 4 compatible<br>1x USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-C with DisplayPort 2.1 / Power Delivery 3.0<br>1x UHS-II microSD card reader (supports SD, SDXC and SDHC; UHS-I with DDR200 mode)<br>1x 3.5mm Combo Audio Jack</td><td>2x USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-C with DisplayPort 1.4 / Power Delivery 3.0<br>1x UHS-II microSD card reader (supports SD, SDXC and SDHC)<br>1x 3.5mm Combo Audio Jack</td></tr><tr><td>Network</td><td colspan="2">Wi-Fi 6E (2 x 2) + Bluetooth 5.4</td></tr><tr><td>Dimensions</td><td>11.45″ × 4.78″ × 2.00″ in (290.8*121.5*50.7mm)</td><td>11.45″ × 4.78″ × 2.00″ in (290.8*121.5*50.7mm)</td></tr><tr><td>Weight</td><td>1.58lb (715g)</td><td>1.48lb (670g)</td></tr><tr><td>Battery</td><td>80Wh</td><td>60Wh</td></tr><tr><td>Included Accessories</td><td colspan="2">65W charger stand</td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Introducing Handheld Compatibility</span></h2><p><iframe title="Introducing Handheld Compatibility" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uQiwumMYsGA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Inside the ROG Xbox Ally: Game Access and Compatibility</span></h2><p><iframe title="Inside the ROG Xbox Ally: Game Access and Compatibility" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VTaboYwSyuc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/rog-xbox-ally-and-rog-xbox-ally-x-launch-october-16]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>