<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:41:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ys vs. Trails in the Sky: Alternative Saga launches this summer in the west]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/ys-vs-trails-in-the-sky-alternative-saga-launches-this-summer-in-the-west</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ys-vs-trails-in-the-sky-alternative-saga-launches-this-summer-in-the-west.1197366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/ys-vs-trails-in-the-sky-alternative-saga-launches-this-summer-in-the-west<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Crossover fighting game includes rollback netcode.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Crossover fighting game <em><a title="Games > Ys vs. Trails in the Sky: Alternative Saga [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ys-vs-trails-in-the-sky-alternative-saga">Ys vs. Trails in the Sky: Alternative Saga</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,523 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,017 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1794880/Ys_vs_Trails_in_the_Sky_Alternative_Saga/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a title="Companies > Epic Games [349 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/ys_vs_trails_in_the_sky_alternative_saga" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> this summer in the west, publisher <a title="Companies > refint/games [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/refint-games">refint/games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [730 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> announced. <span id="more-966927"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Finally, the walls between Falcom’s legendary <a title="Genres > RPG [17,270 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> series, <em>Ys</em> and <em><a title="Series > Trails [76 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/trails">Trails</a></em>, are broken for the ultimate dream match up! Fan-favorite heroes and rivals clash in battles once thought impossible, with support from beloved characters across Falcom’s classic titles to aid you in the fight!</p><p><strong>Maximum Thrill! High-Speed Battle <a title="Genres > Action [2,739 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>!</strong></p><p>The fast-paced action that earned acclaim in <em>Ys SEVEN</em> is back and better than ever! With the ability to jump adding a whole new layer of speed and strategy, you’ll soar across vast battlefields while unleashing thrilling combos that take the excitement to the next level.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Familiar characters from the <em>Trails in the Sky</em> series showcase their mastery of diverse crafts, delivering familiar yet dynamic attacks you can only experience in this title!</p><p><strong>Bringing the Story to Life with Full Voice Acting!</strong></p><p>Featuring a stellar cast of voice actors from the <em>Ys</em> and <em>Trails</em> series, every scene comes to life with full voice acting. Their powerful performances heighten the drama of battles and cutscenes.</p><p><strong>Falcom All-Stars! A Cast of Beloved Characters!</strong></p><p>In addition to the playable characters, many fan-favorite characters from various titles join as support characters! These allies provide powerful backup in heated battles, which will assist you in achieving victory. Let their guidance lead you to triumph!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Beautifully remastered graphics for display in HD and 4K screens, as well as 60 frames per second support.</li><li>Featuring couch and online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [502 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> for the first time.</li><li>Includes English voice acting from a familiar cast from the <em>Ys</em> and <em>Trails</em> series.</li><li>A vast Material Collection of wallpapers and soundtracks from various Falcom titles to unlock.</li><li>PC-centric features including mouse and keyboard support, arbitrary aspect ratio (up to 5:4 and 21:9), and more!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Characters Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ys vs. Trails in the Sky: Alternative Saga - Character Trailer (PS4, PS5, Nintendo Switch)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/faYDxtmsx2A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake update now available, adds traversal improvements, ‘short-cut’ feature, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-update-now-available-adds-traversal-improvements-short-cut-feature-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-update-now-available-adds-traversal-improvements-%E2%80%98short-cut%E2%80%99-feature-and-more.1197363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-update-now-available-adds-traversal-improvements-short-cut-feature-and-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Assign spells and abilities to specific buttons.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publsher <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,347 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Artdink Corporation [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/artdink-corporation">Artdink</a> have <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-update-notice" target="_blank">released</a> the version 1.1.0.0 update for <em><a title="Games > Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a></em> on <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,523 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,236 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and the version 1.2.0.0 update on <a title="Platforms > PC [23,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, which adds traversal improvements, a new “short-cut button” for spells and abilities, and various battle adjustments. <span id="more-966920"></span></p><p>Here are the patch notes:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Traversal</strong></p><ul><li>The movement speed when travelling by boat or using Ramia has been increased.</li><li>Adjustments have been made to avoid boat travel speed being reset by opening the menu or getting into a battle while travelling by boat.</li><li>A feature has been added whereby pressing the menu button while flying with Ramia allows the player to switch between automatic and manual flight modes.</li></ul><p><strong>Vocations</strong></p><ul><li>Critical hit rates for the Hero and Martial Artist have been increased.</li><li>The Hero’s Falcon Slash and Gigaslash abilities have been made more powerful.</li><li>The Warrior’s Cutting Edge ability has been made more powerful.</li><li>The Priest can now equip the Duplic Hat.</li><li>The Monster Wrangler’s Monster Pile-On ability has been changed to have reduced power until all friendly monsters have been found, and to carry out a random number of attacks between 3 and 5.</li><li>The amount of MP used by the Monster Wrangler ability Wild Side has been changed to 30.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Battle</strong></p><ul><li>A limit has been placed on the number of times that some monsters can perform certain <a title="Genres > Action [2,739 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s within one turn.</li><li>Some monsters have been adjusted so that they no longer use Defending Champion in the next turn after they become the last remaining monster.</li><li>The status-ailment resistance of boss monsters has been increased for Draconian <a title="Platforms > Quest [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a> difficulty.</li><li>Adjustments have been made to make it more difficult for both enemies and party members to be successively afflicted with the same status ailments.</li><li>Some monsters (<a title="Platforms > Meta [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>l Chimaera and Hardy Hand) now yield more experience points when defeated.</li><li>Defense has been lowered for all monsters except for metal monsters.</li><li>Minor adjustments have been made to the way that damage is dealt.</li></ul><p><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul><li>Once the Mini Medal Manor has been visited, it will be added to the list of Zoom destinations.</li><li>A new “short-cut button” feature has been added that allows spells and abilities to be assigned to specific buttons. For more information, please refer to Traveller’s Tips in-game.</li><li>In the Temple of Trials, the number of Elfin Elixirs required to be handed over to the guard has been changed to 10.</li><li>A treasure chest has been added to the Temple of Trials, allowing players to acquire one more Gringham Whip.</li><li>Fixed a bug whereby levelling up after using the Seed of Life or Seed of Magic items would cause the status increase value to be calculated twice.</li><li>Adjustments have been made so that if trophies and achievements have not been acquired correctly, selecting Misc. &gt; Info in the menu allows some of them to be reacquired.</li><li>Miscellaneous fixes for minor bugs.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> is available now for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2701660/DRAGON_QUEST_III_HD2D_Remake/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake/9n80pq2dsbp1" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero version 2.0 update ‘Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn’ launches June 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-0-update-where-clouds-embrace-the-dawn-launches-june-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-0-update-%E2%80%98where-clouds-embrace-the-dawn%E2%80%99-launches-june-6.1197342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/zenless-zone-zero-version-2-0-update-where-clouds-embrace-the-dawn-launches-june-6<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Season 2 begins alongside Xbox Series release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The version 2.0 update for <em><a title="Games > Zenless Zone Zero [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zenless-zone-zero">Zenless Zone Zero</a></em>, dubbed “Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn,” will launch on June 6, developer <a title="Companies > miHoYo [196 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> announced. As <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/zenless-zone-zero-for-xbox-series-launches-in-june-alongside-version-2-0-update">previously announced</a>, the <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,236 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> versions will launch alongside version 2.0. <span id="more-966809"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via miHoYo:</p><blockquote><p>In this expansive update, Proxies will venture into the all-new Waifei Peninsula alongside trusted allies such as Yixuan from Yunkui Summit, revitalize the Suibian Temple nestled within the bustling Failume Heights, and take on more challenging Hollow combat in a more open and spacious environment. To commemorate the game’s first anniversary, Version 2.0 will bring a wide array of celebration rewards including a free S-Rank Agent, a free S-Rank W-Engine, 1,600 Polychromes and 20 Encrypted Master Tapes.</p><p>Following the resolution of the Sacrifice crisis in previous chapters, players will embark on an exhilarating new journey in Waifei Peninsula, a remote yet vibrant district of New Eridu. Guided by Yi Xuan, the High Preceptor of Yunkui Summit, Proxies will further uncover the hidden secrets of Phaethon and experience new Hollow exploration gameplay that harnesses the forces of Ether. The region’s main city Failume Heights thrives near the Lemnian Hollow, renowned for the rare resource Porcelume. It offers distinctive tea houses, pawnshops, and dessert stalls, inviting Proxies to immerse themselves in the local atmosphere. Meanwhile, Proxies will take on management of their very own Suibian Temple, upgrade the temple’s facilities and earn in-game rewards by dispatching Bangboos, completing commissions, and collecting resources from the Hollows.</p><p>The Lemnian Hollow is an area rich in resources, yet fraught with danger. Due to the perilous Miasma widespread in the Hollow, formidable foes will enter the Miasmic Field state under certain conditions, gaining shields and enhanced abilities. To counter this, several powerful allies will join the roster. Yixuan, also known as the Grandmaster, will join the combat as an S-Rank Agent. With her unique Attribute Auric Ink and Specialty Rupture, Yixuan ignores enemies’ Defense and deals all damage based on her Sheer Force, which can be increased according to her Attack and Max HP. She also utilizes a special mechanic called Adrenaline instead of just regular Energy, and possesses 2 distinct Ultimate modes for varied combat scenarios, bringing Void Hunter-level prowess to the team. Joining Yixuan is Ju Fufu, the senior disciple of Yunkui Summit, who will debut as an S-Rank Fire Stun Agent. Ju Fufu and her mighty weapon Hu Wei can accumulate Might and Momentum points to deal both Physical and Fire damage. Her Chain Attack grants the entire team the Tiger’s Roar effect, boosting the squad’s CRIT DMG as well as the damage of Chain Attacks and Ultimates.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_966810"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>Also stepping into the spotlight is Pan Yinhu, Yunkui Summit’s A-Rank Physical Defense Agent, who proves that even a kitchen-savvy panda can be a force to reckon with. Completing the squad is Belion, an S-Rank Bangboo from Yunkui Summit. Meanwhile, the S-Rank Ether Support Astra Yao and the S-Rank Physical Defense Caesar will return to the Version 2.0 banners.</p><p>Apart from new narrative and characters, Hollow Zero: Lost Void will also be updated with new commissions and the possibility to equip multiple Gears to different Agents, adding more strategic options to battles. In Version 2.0, Proxies will be able to enter the cinema in Lumina Square to enjoy movies with different characters during the Gravitational Attraction event and obtain exclusive rewards by completing certain tasks, including an A-Rank W-Engine Reel Projector. In the Soul of Steel: Golden Bond event, Proxies can pilot sleek mechs into the Hollows, take on a variety of challenges, and earn abundant rewards.</p><p>To support more convenient exploration across the expanded New Eridu and Hollows, Version 2.0 will introduce a brand-new 3D map and enhanced navigation features. The newly implemented Fissure Beacons will allow Proxies to restore HP, revive Agents, and teleport, allowing Proxies to resume combat more efficiently. Furthermore, new players who complete Season 1 Chapter 2 Interlude can directly unlock and switch to Season 2’s main storyline.</p><p>Beyond new content and optimizations, Version 2.0 will deliver generous anniversary rewards in appreciation of the players’ continued support. Proxies will be able to choose one S-Rank Agent and one S-Rank W-Engine from the Stable Channel for free, along with receiving 1,600 Polychromes, as well as an anniversary-exclusive title and avatar upon the Version 2.0 release. Furthermore, players can also obtain a variety of in-game rewards, including 20 Encrypted Master Tapes, 10 Boopons, and new Outfits for the protagonists by completing specific challenges and event commissions.</p></blockquote><p><em>Zenless Zone Zero</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,523 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10009763" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [23,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">client download</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/zenless-zone-zero-c7c151" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/zenless-zone-zero/id1606356401" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.HoYoverse.Nap&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>. An Xbox Series versions is also planned.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers and the version 2.0 special program below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/zenless-zone-zero/may-22-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Version 2.0 Update “Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn” Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Version 2.0 Teaser &quot;Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn&quot; | Zenless Zone Zero" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u8cwFGkNO1w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="Ver.2.0 PV「雲霞の行き着く処」｜ゼンレスゾーンゼロ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bHLmYnMK8r4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="2.0 버전 PV 「구름과 노을이 만나는 곳」 | 젠레스 존 제로" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2NZtwi5hFiQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《絕區零》2.0版本PV｜雲霞同歸處" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nmpk_ilmjxw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>First Anniversary Replay: Hollow Wandering 2024</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="First Anniversary Replay - Hollow Wandering 2024 | Zenless Zone Zero" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pwYb5RSC0HY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="2024年ホロウの旅 1周年記念プレイバック | ゼンレスゾーンゼロ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jr5qH52shyo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="1주년 기념 리플레이 「2024 공동 오디세이」 | 젠레스 존 제로" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/imDa3pw4HdY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《絕區零》一週年紀念回放｜2024空洞漫遊" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Np_PpjFKws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Frank Burger Collaboration Preview Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="프랭크버거 콜라보 예고 PV | 젠레스 존 제로" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gLnMyGw_RBc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 2.0 Update “Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn” Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Zenless Zone Zero Version 2.0 &quot;Where Clouds Embrace the Dawn&quot; Special Program" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ACjLWP_zviU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『ゼンレスゾーンゼロ』Ver.2.0「雲霞の行き着く処」予告番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w0w_HQ21KJ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="〈젠레스 존 제로〉 시즌 2 출발!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BdvNnTDAkzw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《絕區零》第二季啟程！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wumZT6F0Xp8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>