<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 08:29:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A-RED Walking Robot launches July 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/a-red-walking-robot-launches-july-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-red-walking-robot-launches-july-17.1220190/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/a-red-walking-robot-launches-july-17<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Toy robot puzzle platformer dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Toy robot puzzle <a title="Genres > Platformer [698 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > A-RED Walking Robot [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/a-red-walking-robot">A-RED Walking Robot</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,752 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,095 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,523 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2659840/ARED_Walking_Robot/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Dojo System [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dojo-system">Dojo System</a> and developer <a title="Companies > JOOKITOOZ [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/jookitooz">JOOKITOOZ</a> announced. <span id="more-974355"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Dojo System:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>A-RED Walking Robot</em>&nbsp;is a captivating toy robot simulator combines realistic physics with innovative mechanics in a world full of challenges and fun. In <em>A-RED Walking Robot</em>, you’ll take control of A-RED, an adorable wind-up robot, as you explore a workshop filled with obstacles and enemies. Each challenge has been carefully designed by its creator to test your strategic and dexterity skills, providing a unique experience for players of all ages.</p><p>With realistic physics and incredibly precise control, <em>A-RED Walking Robot</em> will challenge you with a variety of situations that will test your skill with the controller. Get ready to navigate intricate mazes, push objects with A-RED’s tiny robotic hands, and shoot lasers to move obstacles or defeat enemies like lurking tyrannosaurs and mechanical spiders. Want more? Equip your jetpack to cross vast distances and use electricity to activate switches and unlock new paths.</p><p>A-RED’s vital energy comes from its wind-up mechanism, and your mission is to keep it running by collecting golden keys scattered around the workshop. Each wind-up key you find will recharge the mechanism and save your progress, giving you more time to tackle the demanding game maps. Take good care of A-RED, or you’ll hear one of its over 300 cybernetic howls of anger and despair!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>A-RED Walking Robot</em> isn’t just a skill game; it’s a unique experience that combines the charm of classic toys with realistic graphics and advanced physics technology, offering hours of fun and challenges for players of all ages.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Dare to control the charismatic A-RED! Move on land or fly with its jetpack to uncover all the hidden surprises in the huge, chaotic workshop.</li><li>Eliminate obstacles, shoot enemies and clear the way to the next checkpoint!</li><li>Collect wind-up keys scattered around the workshop to save your progress and gain time. Move forward steadily, as A-RED’s vital energy depends on its wind-up mechanism!</li><li>A-RED is equipped with a powerful emotional processor that displays joy, neutrality, or anger. Over 300 different expressions!</li><li>Explore the intricate levels of the workshop accompanied by the vibrant soundtrack of Atsushi Moriya (DJ Guinzy). Authentic Japanese atmosphere guaranteed!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Trailer ARED Release 17/07" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b_603wanLNs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DORONKO WANKO for Switch launches July 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/doronko-wanko-for-switch-launches-july-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doronko-wanko-for-switch-launches-july-24.1220154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/06/doronko-wanko-for-switch-launches-july-24<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,242 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of mess-making dog <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > DORONKO WANKO [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/doronko-wanko">DORONKO WANKO</a></em> will launch on July 24 for 500 yen, publisher <a title="Companies > Phoenixx [67 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/phoenixx">Phoenixx</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Studios [114 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment/bandai-namco-studios">Bandai Namco Studios</a> and <a title="Companies > GYAAR Studio [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment/bandai-namco-studios/gyaar-studio">GYAAR Studio</a>s <a href="https://phoenixx.ne.jp/doronkowanko250617/" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-974357"></span></p><p><em>DORONKO WANKO</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2512840/DORONKO_WANKO/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 26 as a free download. The Switch version will feature a litter of new playable dog breeds, which will be available as paid downloadable content for the PC version.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Phoenixx:</p><blockquote><p>Mom keeps her house so pristine! It would be a shame if… newly-added furry friends… made a heckin’ mess all over the place! Alongside <em>DORONKO WANKO</em>‘s playful Pomeranian protagonist, unleash the rascal within as three new breeds are added to the mix of playable puppers. </p><p>How much will it cost to clean this up? As much as possible! Roll around in nearby puddles, tippy-tap into clean areas of the house, then shake-shake-shake to splatter muddy mayhem in every direction and rack up a six-figure housekeeping bill. Don’t worry, master could never be mad at such a cute, smol doggo, right?</p><p>Hop onto kitchen countertops, run across shelves, and into various rooms to paint a multicolored messterpiece by knocking over nearby staining liquids like tomato juice, wine, coffee, ink, and paint. Explore the entire house to find special rooms in which to wreak even more havoc prior to discovery.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Snoot-boop power buttons of nearby appliances—like robot vacuums and fans—that can fling muck even further than any floofer’s tiny toe beans could ever touch. Don dirt-spreading wearables like miniature mess cannons and sludge-spouting whales to dishevel rooms at a devious pace. Pick up misplaced items like mugs and toys, then return them to the right spot to solve bamboozling puzzles that unlock special gifts.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="【Nintendo Switch】DORONKO WANKO PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g9-CYrUcn3k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【Nintendo Switch™版】DORONKO WANKO PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FV9CtVKlC64?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>