<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 11:08:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[hololive Treasure Mountain MegaPack coming to Switch on June 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hololive-treasure-mountain-megapack-coming-to-switch-on-june-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hololive-treasure-mountain-megapack-coming-to-switch-on-june-18.1201287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hololive-treasure-mountain-megapack-coming-to-switch-on-june-18<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes the base game and all downloadable content.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > holo Indie [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/holo-indie">holo Indie</a> and developer <a title="Companies > BeXide [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bexide">BeXide</a> will release 3D puzzle game <em><a title="Games > hololive Treasure Mountain [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hololive-treasure-mountain">hololive Treasure Mountain MegaPack</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,136 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/hololive-treasure-mountain-megapack-switch/" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a> on June 18 for $19.99, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/holoindie_ccmc/status/1927930648183882064" target="_blank">announced</a>. It includes the base game and all downloadable content. A demo is available now. <span id="more-968056"></span></p><p><em>hololive <a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a> Mountain</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2972990/hololive_Treasure_Mountain/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 31, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2972990/hololive_Treasure_Mountain/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Stack the love of Captain Marin! A simple yet exciting 3D physics puzzle game!</p><p><strong>Stack the Love of Captain Marin</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Hololive members transform into adorable treasures!</p><p>Stack the 3D Hololive characters without letting them overflow to create your very own mountain in this must-play 3D puzzle game for Hololive fans!</p><p><strong>How to Play</strong></p><p>Just toss the treasures and stack them on the island! Combine identical treasures to transform them into larger ones! The game ends when a treasure falls off the island!</p><p>Create bigger treasures and make consecutive combinations to boost your score through chain reactions! And when you create the largest treasure, something amazing happens…!?</p><p><strong>Treasure Exchange</strong></p><p>The treasures that appear in the game can be swapped with other members! Customize to your liking and create your own unique mountain of favorite characters!</p><p><strong>Rankings</strong></p><p>Compete with players from around the world and test your skills. Aim for the high score and keep challenging yourself!</p></blockquote><h2><span><em>MegaPack</em> (Switch) Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="【holo Indie】hololive Treasure Mountain MegaPack Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8CnvahizB_I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【holo Indie】ホロライブお宝マウンテン てんこ盛りVer Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aWdar-VP670?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HoloParade: Deluxe Edition coming to Switch on June 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/holoparade-deluxe-edition-coming-to-switch-on-june-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/holoparade-deluxe-edition-coming-to-switch-on-june-18.1201284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/holoparade-deluxe-edition-coming-to-switch-on-june-18<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes the base game and all downloadable content.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > holo Indie [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/holo-indie">holo Indie</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Roboqlo" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/roboqlo">Roboqlo</a> will release <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,002 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Tower Defense [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/tower-defense">tower defense game</a> <em><a title="Games > HoloParade [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/holoparade">HoloParade: Deluxe Edition</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,136 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/holoparade-deluxe-edition-switch/" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a> on June 18 for $10, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/holoindie_ccmc/status/1927930648183882064" target="_blank">announced</a>. It includes the base game and all downloadable content. <span id="more-968055"></span></p><p><em>HoloParade</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2647230/HoloParade/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 1, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2647230/HoloParade/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Collect your favorite characters, nurture them, and have fun just watching in this hololive fan game! It’s a 2D tower defense game that offers depth for dedicated players, strategic elements, and easy enjoyment for casual players.</p><p><strong>A Lively Parade With hololive VTubers and <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>cot Characters!</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>HoloParade</em> is a fan game of hololive and the first title to serve as a test case for holo Indie. Collect, nurture, and enjoy watching your favorite characters! It’s a 2D tower defense game that offers depth, strategy, and can also be enjoyed casually.</p><p>To hololive fans:</p><p>This game is designed for players who enjoy strategy and trial and error, and involves exploring various formations and play styles suited to each stage. With stages featuring a variety of characteristics and characters having their specific strengths and weaknesses, please note that you cannot easily clear all stages with just your favorite characters. With careful character development and strategic gameplay, you can clear stages up to the end credits with a favorite formation, but subsequent high-difficulty stages will require formations tailored to the enemies.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Simple Yet Deep, Lively Battles</strong><ul><li>The basic system is a classic 2D tower defense game where you summon characters from your base and march them forward to destroy the enemy’s base to win. While the controls are simple, the gameplay is profoundly deep. With over 65 characters, each possessing a variety of abilities like ally healing support and self-destruct attacks, skillful combination and flexible formation are key to enjoying the game.</li><li>Additionally, there’s an element inspired by parades called the “Symphony Effect,” where various effects are activated based on the musical instruments played by the characters in march. This adds further strategic depth to the formation of your parade squad and the order of their summoning.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Comprehensive Development Elements</strong><ul><li>In addition to leveling up and limit breaking, there is a “Skill” system that allows you to add special abilities not available through regular development. Since you can add up to three types of skills to each character and select them carefully, you can enjoy a unique development process! Furthermore, since you can reset levels and get a full refund of the coins spent, it allows for more freedom in restructuring formations and character development.</li></ul></li><li><strong>No <a title="Genres > Gacha" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/gacha">Gacha</a> Purchases, No Stamina System</strong><ul><li>The scout gacha, which allows you to acquire characters, can be used by consuming tickets obtained within the game, with no additional purchases required. Also, as there is no stamina system, you are not bound by time and can play as much as you like, whenever you like.</li><li>Moreover, the scout gacha allows you to choose from two randomly selected character candidates, enabling players to make selections based on their strategy or preference rather than leaving it entirely to chance.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Take a Break with Various Talents and Mini-Games in the Office</strong><ul><li>When you return to the office, the home screen, you’ll be greeted by newly recorded voice lines from Harusaki Nodoka, a staff member of hololive. In the office, talents from hololive may also make appearances, and you might witness some unexpected interactions.</li><li>Additionally, mini-games with gameplay entirely different from the main story have been implemented. These games allow you to collect coins necessary for character strengthening. For now, the mini-games titled “Hurry Up! Miko-Chi!” and “Dancing Subaru” are available. In “Hurry Up! Miko-Chi!”, Sakura Miko (a VTuber affiliated with Hololive), who has overslept, dashes at full speed towards her destination while avoiding obstacles.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><em>Deluxe Edition</em> (Switch) Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="【holo Indie】HoloParade: Deluxe Edition Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7XPdlc_sOHs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【holo Indie】ホロパレード デラックス版 Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xhIs0L9AszI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LAPIN for Switch launches October 9]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/lapin-for-switch-launches-october-9</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lapin-for-switch-launches-october-9.1201257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/lapin-for-switch-launches-october-9<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available both physically and digitally in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,136 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,002 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [685 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > LAPIN [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lapin">LAPIN</a></em> will launch on October 9, publisher <a title="Companies > CFK [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cfk">CFK</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Studio Doodal [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/studio-doodal">Studio Doodal</a> announced. <span id="more-967921"></span></p><p>In Japan, the game will be available both physically and digitally. The standard edition will cost 4,378 yen, while the first-print run limited edition will cost 7,678 yen. The latter includes a special box, art book, 33-track original soundtrack, and a special diorama acrylic stand.</p><p><em>LAPIN</em> first launched in Early Access for Xbox Series, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1454540/LAPIN/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/lapin-game-preview/9nbqhm0gm30n" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on November 17, 2022, followed by a full release on August 30, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via CFK:</p><blockquote><p>The rabbits who lived underneath a park have to leave for a new home, as the humans started a renovation. Liebe, a white rabbit, goes on an adventure with Captain, Bianca, José, and Montblanc. What will happen to these five rabbits on their adventure?</p><p>Join the rabbits on their adventure full of new friends, rabbit-threatening dangers, and last but not least, beautiful scenery!</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch |『LAPIN（ラパン）勇敢なウサギ探検隊の冒険』公式プロモーションムービー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W89NG5om9DQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV ‘Overview’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv-overview-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-mario-party-jamboree-%E2%80%93-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv-%E2%80%98overview%E2%80%99-trailer.1201239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv-overview-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Throw an even bigger bash with <em>Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em>.</p><p><strong>Camera at the Ready!</strong></p><p>Connect the <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,136 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> 2 camera accessory or other compatible USB-C camera (sold separately) and bring everyone into the game.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Put Yourself in the Game With Cameraplay</strong></p><p>CameraPlay puts players’ faces into the <a title="Genres > Action [2,754 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> during minigames and when viewing the game board. Plus, it can capture player movements to enable full-body motion controls in select minigames!</p><ul><li>See everyone’s faces on the game board.</li><li>Move your body to take on minigames.</li></ul><p><strong>Smoooooth Mouse Controls</strong></p><p>Place the Joy-Con 2 controller on its side to use it like a mouse in compatible modes. Slide and click with ease! Plus, with HD rumble 2, you can feel even more realistic feedback through the controller.</p><p>Attach the Joy-Con 2 strap and hold the controller firmly when using mouse controls.</p><p><strong>Shout into the Mic!</strong></p><p>Using the Nintendo Switch 2 system’s built-in microphone, you can clap your hands or use your voice to control the action in certain modes.</p><p><strong>You’re the Contestant on <em>Jamboree TV</em>!</strong></p><p><em>Jamboree TV</em> is a new way to play that’s all about audience participation! Take on a variety of challenges along with Mario and friends.</p><p><strong>Let the Games Begin! </strong><strong>Mario <a title="Genres > Party [96 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a></strong></p><p>Roll the dice to race others around the game board to collect the most Stars. Each of the seen boards has its own personality! New rules for <em>Jamboree TV</em> include two-on-two team matches and more. Plus, if you connect a compatible USB-C camera, your face can appear directly in the game.</p><ul><li>Roll the dice and shoot for the Stars.</li><li>Compete in minigames to earn coins.</li><li>See if you can flip the script when you land on a Chance Time Space!</li></ul><p><strong>Get Loud and Excited… or Face Punishment! Bowser Live</strong></p><p>Oh dear—Bowser is hosting a performance, and you’re the main act! Two teams compete in a variety of fun minigames controlled by sound and movement. It’s about to get wild! Connect a compatible USB-C camera to project you and your buddies into the in-game venue.</p><ul><li>Collect coins by bashing? Blocks.</li><li>Shout to push forward in “Go! Go! Chicken Race.”</li><li>Go back and forth with Bowser in “Call and Response.”</li></ul><p>Be aware of your surroundings. Wear wrist straps and allow adequate room around you during gameplay.</p><p><strong>A Thrill Ride Full of Bad Guys?! Carnival Coaster</strong></p><p>Lock in and go on this <a title="Genres > Co-Op [271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> coaster! Once through the pipe, use Joy-Con 2 mouse controls to aim at flying baddies and try to knock ’em down. Work together to improve your score!</p><ul><li>Lower the safety bar firmly with your hands.</li><li>Throw balls to knock away enemies.</li><li>Drop in and feel the experience.</li></ul><p><strong>Even MORE Minigames!</strong></p><p>Enjoy 20 new minigames using Joy-Con 2 mouse controls, HD rumble 2, and the system’s built-in microphone. Some minigames can be played by plugging in a compatible USB-C camera.</p><p>You can also play 78 minigames previously included with the <a title="Games > Super Mario Party Jamboree [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-mario-party-jamboree">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a> game, too—in greater detail!</p><p>Some minigames cannot be played in the <em>Jamboree TV</em> mode. Select the Super Mario Party Jamboree option from the title screen to play the base game.</p><p><strong>All Together, Anytime, Anywhere</strong></p><p>Play like you’re all in the same room using GameChat, no matter the distance. Plug in a compatible USB-C camera to use video chat and CameraPlay features.</p><p><strong>GameShare with Friends</strong></p><p>If you have the Nintendo Switch 2 system and the <em>Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em> game, you can share part of the game with anyone who has a Nintendo Switch or Nintendo Switch 2 system using GameShare.</p><p>With one game, up to four people can play the Mega Wiggler’s Tree Party board in Mario Party mode.</p><p><em>Only Party Rules and 30 select minigames are available with GameShare. Not compatible with GameShare through GameChat. Only playable in handheld mode.</em></p><p><strong>The Party Has Never Looked Better</strong></p><p>The <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em> supports up to WQHD (1440p) resolution* in TV mode and Full HD (1080p) resolution in handheld and tabletop modes. Enjoy the world of Mario Party with greater detail and fluidity!</p><p><em>*Jamboree TV only. Compatible display required.</em></p><p><strong>Only for Nintendo Switch 2</strong></p><p>In addition to the full <em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em> game, the <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em> includes the new <em>Jamboree TV</em> mode, as well as new features that use Joy-Con 2 mouse controls and HD rumble 2, the system’s built-in microphone, and a compatible USB-C camera accessory.</p><p>If you already have <em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em> for Nintendo Switch, you can purchase the upgrade pack separately to play the <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em> on Nintendo Switch 2.</p></div><p><em>Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [151 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> on July 24.</p><p>Watch the trailer and commercials below.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>