<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:20:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia – 2025 updates roadmap announced, sales top two million on consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/phasmophobia-2025-updates-roadmap-announced-sales-top-two-million-on-consoles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobia-%E2%80%93-2025-updates-roadmap-announced-sales-top-two-million-on-consoles.1105005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/phasmophobia-2025-updates-roadmap-announced-sales-top-two-million-on-consoles<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PS VR2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Major reworks, new ghost-hunting tools, seasonal events, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Kinetic Games [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kinetic-games">Kinetic Games</a> has announced the 2025 roadmap for four-player <a title="Genres > Co-Op [230 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> psychological <a title="Genres > Horror [553 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Phasmophobia [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/phasmophobia">Phasmophobia</a></em>, including major reworks, new ghost-hunting tools, seasonal events, and a new map. The Early Access version of the game has also sold over two million units across <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,803 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS VR2 [227 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PlayStation VR2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,671 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, 104 days after its console launch. <span id="more-942984"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the upcoming updates, via Kinetic Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>First Major Update: “Chronicle”</strong></p><p>The first major update, “Chronicle,” will bring changes to the journal and rework the way in which Ghost Hunters can capture evidence. The Photos tab will be replaced with a Media tab featuring three new sections—Photos, Videos, and Sound Recordings—with any photographic, audio, or visual evidence logged in the corresponding pages. </p><p>The game’s media quality system is being replaced too, with a players’ first “capture” of any media type labelled as “Unique.” These will reward lots of cash and XP at the end of a contract, while “duplicates” will reward much less.</p><p>Chronicle will also introduce the Sound Recorder, a brand new piece of equipment designed to record unique paranormal sounds. Players brave enough to do so will be able to listen back to their recordings in the updated journal, letting them discover helpful clues that may previously have been drowned out by terrified screams.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Phasmophobia-Updates_02-10-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Map Reworks</strong></p><p>Outdoorsy hunters will be pleased to know there are two map reworks on the way this year: Bleasdale Farmhouse will receive a complete overhaul, with visual enhancements and a complete redesign of the layout, including new locations for ghosts to haunt. Players will be able to explore a garden just outside the main living room, complete with ghost rooms, as well as revamped areas to explore. Grafton Farmhouse will also receive an update later this year.</p><p><strong>More to Come</strong></p><p>There’s even more to come, with a player character overhaul, new small map, and updates for the Easter, Halloween and Holiday seasons set to arrive in 2025. Plans for 2026 are already underway too, with house map reworks, even more new maps, and Horror 2.0 in the works.</p></blockquote><p>“We’re beyond excited for the new updates and reworks coming to <em>Phasmophobia</em> this year,” said Kinetic Games director and <em>Phasmophobia</em> lead developer Daniel Knight in a press release. “Our early access period so far has given us a fantastic opportunity to listen to our players, and the big changes we’re making are a direct reflection of the feedback we’re seeing. We’re really proud of the direction <em>Phasmophobia</em> is going in, thanks in no small part to our amazing community, and we can’t wait to see what everyone thinks of some of the surprises in store for 2025.”</p><p><em>Phasmophobia</em> is available now in Early Access for PlayStation 5, PlayStation VR2, Xbox Series, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/739630/Phasmophobia/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bubble Ghost Remake launches March 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27.1104906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Guide a little ghost and his bubble through an enchanted mansion.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Platformer [609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> remake <em><a title="Games > Bubble Ghost Remake" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bubble-ghost-remake">Bubble Ghost Remake</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2412240/Bubble_Ghost_Remake/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Selecta Play [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/selecta-play">Selecta Play</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nakama Game Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nakama-game-studio">Nakama Game Studio</a> announced. A physical standard edition for North America and Europe, as well as a Collector’s Edition for Europe, will also be available at participating retailers. <span id="more-942957"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Selecta Play:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In the old castle of the renowned inventor Heinrich Von Schinker, in northern England, Heinrich’s spirit returns as a small ghost.</p><p>Alongside a mysterious bubble that he can move with gentle blows, he must face his own out-of-control inventions and fierce wild animals.</p><p>Guiding the bubble to freedom is his only goal.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Challenge Your Skills</strong> – Overcome levels filled with dangers and puzzles that will test your abilities. With addictive gameplay and devilish difficulty, your only goal is to protect the bubble at all costs.</li><li><strong>Defeat Epic Bosses</strong> – Face fierce bosses that will make you sweat. Only the most skilled will emerge victorious.</li><li><strong>Relive the Original Classic</strong> – Enjoy the full remaster of the 90s game, with 36 original levels recreated with completely renewed art.</li><li><strong>Compete for Glory</strong> – Perfect your times in speedrun mode and submit your results online to secure your place in the prestigious Hall of Fame.</li></ul><p><strong>More Features</strong></p><ul><li>Enjoy an <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,031 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with over 40 levels filled with skill and clever puzzles.</li><li>Three difficulty levels tailored to your playstyle.</li><li>Completely revamped graphics and sound that bring the magical world of the castle to life.</li><li>Dive deep into Heinrich’s story by finding hidden collectibles throughout the castle chambers.</li><li>Upload your scores and compare them with the best players worldwide in the online ranking.</li><li>Discover secret rooms, alternative endings, and unlock challenging in-game achievements.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Bubble Ghost - Official launch date trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YyKfdHMryC8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>