<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 17:09:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BlazBlue: Entropy Effect coming to iOS, Android on July 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/blazblue-entropy-effect-coming-to-ios-android-on-july-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blazblue-entropy-effect-coming-to-ios-android-on-july-22.1238454/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > 91Act [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/91act">91Act</a> will release <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,039 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Roguelike [343 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > BlazBlue: Entropy Effect [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/blazblue-entropy-effect">BlazBlue: Entropy Effect</a></em> for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/blazblue-entropy-effect/id6742527094" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.actgames.bbee.gl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a> on July 22, the developer announced. <span id="more-978052"></span></p><p><em>BlazBlue: Entropy Effect</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2273430/_/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 15, 2023, followed by a full release on January 31, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Ultimate 2D <a title="Genres > Roguelite [264 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> action experience!</p><p><em>BlazBlue: Entropy Effect</em> delivers an unparalleled action gaming experience. Dive into combat where you’ll continuously evolve and enhance your combo builds, leading to an exhilarating, deeply satisfying flow of battle beyond your expectations.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Choose from 14 captivating characters, each with unique fighting styles. Mix and match their abilities to continuously alter combat mechanics mid-fight, gradually <a title="Genres > Crafting [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> a personalized fighting experience that’s truly your own.</p><p>Every end is a new beginning, and every finish line is a starting point. After continuous content updates on PC, <em>BlazBlue: Entropy Effect</em> now arrives on mobile with stellar reviews, even richer content, and multiple international awards!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Dozens of move variations for each character.</li><li>Full gamepad support for precision control.</li><li>Freely customize your touchscreen button layout.</li><li>Optimized controls specifically for iPhone &amp; iPad.</li><li>Carefully designed difficulty options to suit both action game newcomers and veterans.</li><li>Supports local <a title="Genres > Co-Op [302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative multiplayer</a> via LAN, letting you team up with a friend.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>iOS and Android Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="BlazBlue Entropy Effect Mobile: Launching July 22nd Worldwide!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/McDIAfF9HWs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/blazblue-entropy-effect-coming-to-ios-android-on-july-22]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Endzone 2 launches July 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/endzone-2-launches-july-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/endzone-2-launches-july-24.1238406/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently in Early Access.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Survival [434 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> <a title="Genres > Simulation [786 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Endzone 2 [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/endzone-2">Endzone 2</a></em> will leave early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,632 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2144640/Endzone_2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/endzone_2" target="_blank">GOG</a> on July 24, publisher <a title="Companies > Assemble Entertainment [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/assemble-entertainment">Assemble Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gentlymad Studios [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gentlymad-studios">Gentlymad Studios</a>  announced. <span id="more-978043"></span></p><p><em>Endzone 2</em> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/endzone-2-launches-in-early-access-on-august-26">first launched</a> in Early Access on August 26, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Endzone 2</em> is a post-apocalyptic survival colony builder, where you embark to secure humanities survival after a cataclysmic disaster. Discover and repopulate the last habitable grounds, while the survival of your people hinges on your wits, foresight, and resilience in a harsh and unforgiving world.</p><p>Survivors,</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The time has come to surpass the confining limits of these lands. Our brightest minds have constructed machinery that allow us to break free and venture beyond our borders!</p><p>Let there be no doubt—even after centuries, Mother Nature’s anger remains unbroken. She is the same untamed beast she was when our ancestors stepped out of the Endzone. Our way will be filled with obstacles, misery, and death. Yet, we are pioneers, born with a unwavering curiosity to expand, rebuild, and thrive. Together, we will rekindle humanity.</p><p><em>—Jeremiah Sawchyn, Leader of Expedition 01</em></p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Survive amidst a relentless and ever-changing environment in a world of constant threat.</li><li>It’s your turn to freely choose your starting point by taking direct control of your settlement bus.</li><li>Venture into the treacherous badlands, a terrain riddled with ancient ruins, hidden loot, and daring missions.</li><li>Explore habitable zones full of unique resources and daunting challenges, giving rise to multiple settlements under your command.</li><li>Build, develop, and expand your settlements, forging a remarkable landmark with many buildings and upgrades.</li><li>Secure your economic progress by researching new buildings, technologies, and refined resources as well as optimized production lines.</li><li><a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter your trade skills as you establish and manage trade routes between your zones and traders that are essential for your survival.</li></ul><p><strong>Develop Your Settlement</strong></p><p>Survive in a world of constant threats, including radioactively contaminated ground, droughts, toxic rain, and sandstorms. Grow and expand your settlement, research technologies, refine resources, and manage your economy by building an efficient infrastructure.</p><p><strong>Stabilize Your Legacy</strong></p><p>Nurture your settlement by thoughtfully caring about the needs of your people. Forge trading routes between your zones and traders, facilitating the exchange of vital goods. Transcend mere survival and usher your settlement into an era of flourishing prosperity.</p><p><strong>A Motorized Takeoff</strong></p><p>In <em>Endzone 2</em>, you hit the road with your trusty bus, navigating through the badlands — an uninhabitable and treacherous terrain scattered with ruins, loot, and missions. Yielding to your curiosity and exploring these areas may reward you with special resources, technologies, and new trading partners. However, it can also place you in deadly peril, triggering disasters or jeopardizing the lives of your explorers.</p><p><strong>Discover the Unknown</strong></p><p>As you journey through the badlands, you’ll encounter habitable zones — expansive plots of land ripe for settlement and scarce resource harvesting. Each zone boasts its own unique array of resources, so choose your next settlement location wisely and let your journey flow.</p><p><strong>An Unforgiving World</strong></p><p>In <em>Endzone 2</em>, the landscape and environment are in constant flux, presenting ever-changing challenges just around the corner! Behold as sandstorms ravage the surroundings and droughts deplete your water supplies, leaving your zones parched and transformed into deserts.</p><p><strong>Key Changes and Additions</strong></p><p><em><a title="Games > Endzone: A World Apart [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/endzone-a-world-apart">Endzone: A World Apart</a></em> veterans, please read!</p><ul><li><strong>Zones</strong> – In <em>Endzone: A World Apart</em>, you played on one vast map where you could build a global settlement. But in <em>Endzone 2</em>, the world expands as you uncover different zones, each offering exclusive resources to plunder. <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge multiple settlements and unlock a vast amount of possibilities.</li><li><strong>New Settler Behavior</strong> – We’ve tackled and refactored settler paths and job distribution issues from the ground up. Embrace the new and improved system, now more comprehensible and balanced, supporting thriving settlements with thousands of inhabitants.</li><li><strong>Vehicles</strong> – Your wish for vehicles back in <em>Endzone: A World Apart</em> has been heard! Now, you can freely choose your starting location by moving your settlement bus. As the game progresses, you’ll have the opportunity to construct additional vehicles, perfect for establishing trade routes or venturing into the treacherous badlands.</li><li><strong>Expedition System Overhaul</strong> – Exciting changes! The updated expeditions system introduces detailed ruins waiting to be explored by directly controlling and guiding your explorers. They consist of less text and more <a title="Genres > Action [2,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>! Uncover clues, unlock secrets, and discover valuable loot on your journeys.</li><li><strong>New Graphics</strong> – Our rendering system has undergone a complete overhaul, bringing you a more detailed and visually stunning environment. The animations have received a makeover too, resulting in breathtaking graphics that will immerse you like never before.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Endzone 2 - Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LNVW4ckpOoc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/endzone-2-launches-july-24]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time Flies launches July 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/time-flies-launches-july-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/time-flies-launches-july-31.1238403/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A short adventure about our limited time in this world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Hand-drawn <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,387 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Time Flies [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/time-flies">Time Flies</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,867 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,319 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,632 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2000120/Time_Flies/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 13 for $14.99, with a 10 percent-off limited launch discount, publisher <a title="Companies > Panic [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/panic">Panic</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Playables" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playables">Playables</a> announced. <span id="more-977992"></span></p><p>“Flies are pretty annoying, and we’ve been listening to one every day for the past four years of game development,” said Playables developer Michael Frei in a press release. “Please do your part and Wishlist the game now, I really need therapy.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Panic:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A short adventure about our limited time in this world.</p><p>In <em>Time Flies</em>, you’re a fly—your life is short, but your bucket list is long! Learn an instrument, read a book, become rich, get drunk, or make someone smile. And if you don’t feel like pursuing your goals, you can just relax, clean your wings, and listen to music. Make the best of the time you have left, because we’re all going to die.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Explore a painstakingly hand-drawn, densely detailed world.</li><li>Dozens of unique and obscure goals to accomplish.</li><li>Numerous intriguing ways to die.</li><li>Grimly variable life expectancy based on player location.</li><li>Delightfully accurate fly physics.</li><li>The most expansive game yet from the mind behind <em>KIDS</em> and <em>Plug &amp; Play</em>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Time Flies - Release Date Trailer - Coming July 31st" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FzAwgAIXn28?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/time-flies-launches-july-31]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II Remastered ‘Chronological’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-chronological-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-%E2%80%98chronological%E2%80%99-update-now-available.1238349/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Experience Ellie and Abby's story chronologically.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,021 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Naughty Dog [312 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a> have released a free update for <em><a title="Games > The Last of Us Part II Remastered [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered">The Last of Us Part II Remastered</a></em> today that lets players experience the story chronologically, the companies <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/07/08/introducing-the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-chronological-experience-out-today/" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-978036"></span></p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p>Available for players as part of a downloadable update today, we’ve introduced a new way to play the story of <em><a title="Games > The Last of Us Part I [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-i">The Last of Us Part I</a>I</em> like never before—chronologically.</p><p>Those who have already played will know its story is told non-linearly, as Ellie and Abby’s motivations, realizations, and emotional stakes unfold across myriad flashbacks and present-day storylines. While this structure is very intentional and core to how our studio wanted <em>Part II</em>‘s themes and narrative beats to impact players, we always wondered what it would be like to experience this story chronologically. And now finally, we can answer that question.</p><p>Through the new Chronological mode, we believe players will gain even deeper insight into <em>Part II</em>‘s narrative. Players will be able to see how Ellie being gifted a guitar flows so neatly into her learning to play, for example, while the journey through Seattle will showcase the fascinating parallels between Ellie and Abby’s crisscrossing journeys. You’ll see just how close they come into running into each other, how their <a title="Genres > Action [2,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s impact each other, and more.</p><p>It was no small feat to bring <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>‘s story chronologically together, given that <em>Part II</em>‘s story is so meticulously put together. We’re grateful to the developers both at Naughty Dog and our partners at Nixxes to make the Chronological mode as smooth as possible. And while we of course recommend players still new to the game to play through <em>Part II</em>‘s story as was originally developed, the team’s hard work has paid off with a fascinating new way to enjoy this chapter.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>And we also wanted to reward players for jumping into this new, transformative approach to our story. In addition to new trophies tied to completing the narrative experience in chronological order, doing so will also unlock two new, perhaps surprisingly familiar skins…</p><p>Yes, that’s right, play as Joel dressed as Nathan Drake and Tommy as Sam Drake in No Return. Particularly as we celebrate Naughty Dog’s 40th anniversary this year, we love getting the chance to spotlight and share in the history of our studio that we love as much as we know you do. These skins will be unlocked for completing the narrative in Chronological, and will be usable in No Return, <em>Part II Remastered</em>‘s thrilling <a title="Genres > Roguelike [343 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Survival [434 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> mode.</p><p>A new update for <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> is available today on both <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,867 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> (via Patch 2.1.0) and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,632 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam and the <a title="Companies > Epic Games [352 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store (via Patch 1.5), bringing with it the Chronological mode, as well as a host of additional bug fixes and performance improvements.</p><p>We here at Naughty Dog are so grateful for all the love and support we’ve seen from <em>The Last of Us</em> fans these last few months. From the launch of <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> on PC, to <em>The Last of Us Complete</em> on PlayStation 5, to seeing your weekly reactions to season 2 of the television series, it’s been such a pleasure to celebrate this moment with you.</p></blockquote><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> is available now for PlayStation 5 and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2531310/The_Last_of_Us_Part_II_Remastered/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-chronological-update-now-available]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SOMA for Switch launches July 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/soma-for-switch-launches-july-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/soma-for-switch-launches-july-24.1238346/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Sci-fi horror game set deep beneath the surface of the Atlantic Ocean.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The Switch version of <a title="Genres > Horror [658 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em>SOMA</em> will launch on July 24, <a title="Companies > Abylight Studios [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/abylight-studios">Abylight Studios</a> and <a title="Companies > Frictional Games [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/frictional-games">Frictional Games</a> announced. <span id="more-978034"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Abylight Studios:</p><blockquote><p>Originally developed by the masterminds at Frictional Games, this critically acclaimed science-fiction horror masterpiece is making its way to <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [22,273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>‘s hybrid console, meticulously optimized to deliver an uncompromised experience. Get ready to question reality and survive a nightmare unlike any other.</p><p>Dive headfirst into PATHOS-II, a desolate underwater research facility where the lines between human and machine blur. As you explore the eerie, submerged corridors under the Atlantic Ocean, you’ll be thrust into a fight for <a title="Genres > Survival [434 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> against a hostile world that forces you to confront the very nature of consciousness and what it truly means to be human. <em>SOMA</em> is renowned for its profound narrative and unsettling atmosphere, earning a formidable <a title="Platforms > Meta [147 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>critic score of 84 and cementing its place as a genre-defining psychological thriller.</p><p>Abylight Studios has worked  to ensure that this <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,319 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> version of <em>SOMA</em> is a full, faithful adaptation. <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the terrifying world of <em>SOMA</em> with optimized performance, stunning visuals, and the immersive sound design that made the original a sensation, now playable wherever you go. <em>SOMA</em> will be compatible with Switch 2.</p></blockquote><p><em>SOMA</em> is currently available for PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/282140/SOMA/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/soma" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/soma" target="_blank">GOG</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SOMA Nintendo Switch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRzE3yE_oX0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/soma-for-switch-launches-july-24]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>