<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 03:54:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operation Night Strikers launches August 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/operation-night-strikers-launches-august-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/operation-night-strikers-launches-august-7.1134273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/operation-night-strikers-launches-august-7<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Special Edition includes download code for early access to  NIGHT STRIKER GEAR.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Operation Night Strikers [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/operation-night-strikers">Operation Night Strikers</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,788 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3099790/Operation_Night_Strikers/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 7, publisher <a title="Companies > TAITO [137 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/taito">TAITO</a> and developer <a title="Companies > M2 [87 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/m2">M2</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/TAITO_Apps/status/1900351432152539299" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. <span id="more-950086"></span></p><p>The game will be available in the <a href="https://twitter.com/TAITO_Apps/status/1900352036388167965" target="_blank">following editions</a>:</p><ul><li><strong>Switch Physical Edition</strong> (7,480 yen)<ul><li>Included Titles and Versions (<em>Operation Wolf</em>, <em>Operation Thunderbolt</em>, <em>Night Striker</em>, <em>Space Gun)</em><ul><li><a title="Genres > Arcade [72 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">Arcade</a> Versions</li><li>Console Port Versions</li></ul></li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><strong>Switch and PC Digital Editions</strong> (4,730 yen)<ul><li>Included Titles and Versions (<em>Operation Wolf</em>, <em>Operation Thunderbolt</em>, <em>Night Striker</em>, <em>Space Gun)</em><ul><li>Arcade Versions</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Switch and PC Downloadable Content “Operation Night Strikers CS”</strong> (2,750 yen)<ul><li>Included Titles and Versions (<em>Operation Wolf</em>, <em>Operation Thunderbolt</em>, <em>Night Striker</em>, <em>Space Gun)</em><ul><li>Console Versions</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>And here is a breakdown of <a href="https://twitter.com/TAITO_Apps/status/1900352125747789953" target="_blank">all the versions</a> for each title:</p><ul><li><strong><em>Operation Wolf</em></strong><ul><li>Arcade Versions<ul><li>JP</li><li>JP Easy</li><li>US</li><li>US Easy</li></ul></li><li>Console Versions<ul><li>FC</li><li>NE</li><li><a title="Companies > SEGA [2,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter System</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong><em>Operation Thunderbolt</em></strong><ul><li>Arcade Versions<ul><li>JP</li><li>JP Easy</li><li>US</li><li>US Easy</li><li>US Mini</li></ul></li><li>Console Versions<ul><li>SN</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong><em>Night Striker</em></strong><ul><li>Arcade Versions<ul><li>JP</li><li>World</li><li>EU</li></ul></li><li>Console Versions<ul><li>MEGA-CD</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong><em>Space Gun</em></strong><ul><li>Arcade Versions<ul><li>JP</li><li>JP Easy</li><li>US</li><li>US Easy</li></ul></li><li>Console Versions<ul><li>SEGA Master System</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>A physical Special Edition (pictured) will also be available for Switch, which among other bonuses, includes a download code to play M2’s upcoming&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > NIGHT STRIKER GEAR [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/night-striker-gear">NIGHT STRIKER GEAR</a></em> ahead of its official release.</p><p>Here is an overview of the collection, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3099790/Operation_Night_Strikers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Operation Wolf</em> and <em>Night Striker</em>, two milestones of the 80s arcade movement in one action-packed compilation! Relieve all the high-speed arcade thrills and explosive spills!</p><p><strong>Title Lineup</strong></p><ul><li><em>Operation</em> Wolf (Versions: Arcade, <a title="Platforms > NES [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/nes">Famicom</a>, NES, SEGA Master System)</li><li><em>Operation Thunderbolt</em> (Versions: Arcade, <a title="Platforms > SNES" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/snes">SNES</a>)</li><li><em>Night Striker</em> (Versions: Arcade, Mega CD)</li><li><em>Space Gun</em> (Versions: Arcade, SEGA Master System)</li></ul><p><strong><em>Operation Wolf</em></strong></p><p>Using only a machine gun and rocket-propelled grenades, you alone must infiltrate enemy territory, secure the hostages, then get them safely to the extraction point! The mission code is Operation Wolf.</p><p><strong><em>Operation Thunderbolt</em></strong></p><p>A hostage rescue mission in Africa and only one man can help! Roy Adams, hero of Operation Wolf is back, and this time his former green beret team-mate, Hardy Jones joins the fight. Your mission code is Operation Thunderbolt. <a title="Companies > Impossible [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/impossible">Impossible</a> odds are nothing to these men!</p><p><strong><em>Night Striker</em></strong></p><p>Become a member of the United Nations Special <a title="Genres > Action [2,563 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Force, a.k.a. Night Striker, and destroy the enemy terrorist organization with in your high-speed combat hovercraft: Intergray!</p><p><strong><em>Space Gun</em></strong></p><p>2039 AD: an age of space exploration. On their way to investigate an unexplained incident on a space station, a team of space marines receive a distress call from a cargo ship, but what could prepare them for the <a title="Genres > Horror [571 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s onboard?! Use your multi-purpose rifle to slay the monsters and rescue the hostages!</p><p>Four faithful ports, complete with various gadgets, replay functions, and other useful features to enhance the originals!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Apply filters to simulate actual arcade monitors.</li><li>New gadgets to display various useful information.</li><li>Includes multiple arcade versions of each title.</li><li>Save / load anytime during play.</li><li>Upload your own play data, or download and view top ranking players’ data.</li><li>Compatible with the Cyber Stick intelligent controller.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f confirmed for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC; reveal trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/silent-hill-f-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-reveal-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-reveal-trailer.1134213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/silent-hill-f-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-reveal-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Navigate the twisted paths of Ebisugaoka.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Silent Hill f [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a></em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,878 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2947440/SILENT_HILL_f/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/silent-hill-f-714aed" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/silent-hill-f/9n5nfrqv2hqq" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> when it launches, publisher <a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,109 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a> and developer <a title="Companies > NeoBards Entertainment [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neobards-entertainment">NeoBards Entertainment</a> announced. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-943432"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Konami:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In 1960s Japan, Shimizu Hinako’s secluded town of Ebisugaoka is consumed by a sudden fog, transforming her home into a haunting nightmare.</p><p>As the town falls silent and the fog thickens, Hinako must navigate the twisted paths of Ebisugaoka, solving complex puzzles and confronting grotesque monsters to survive.</p><p>Immerse yourself into Hinako’s world imagined by renowned author Ryukishi07, with entrancing music, including pieces by Akira Yamaoka, and beautiful visuals in a gripping tale of doubt, regret, and inescapable choices. Will Hinako embrace the beauty hidden within terror, or succumb to the madness that lies ahead?</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Discover a new chapter in the <em><a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nt Hill</em> series, blending psychological horror with a haunting Japanese setting.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_950013"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>In 1960s Japan, teenager Shimizu Hinako lives in the small, remote town of Ebisugaoka, nestled in a mountain pass. An average teen, she passes the time with nothing particularly special about her life.</p><p>Until, that is, a deep fog descends on Ebisugaoka, and everything Hinako knows crumbles as she finds her once-familiar home infested with spreading danger, the town empty except for the <a title="Genres > Horror [571 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s teeming in the fog.</p><p>Now, as she navigates the twisting paths of Ebisugaoka, Hinako must solve puzzles and fight for her life in her struggle to survive.</p><p>Her struggle to reach the inevitable decision that must be made. And her struggle to put an end to that which must be slain.</p><p>Will she choose to embrace elegance and beauty? Or will her path lead her to madness and horror…</p><p>A story of impossible decisions, of the beauty in terror, and terror from beauty.</p><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Shimizu Hinako</strong> – The game’s main character. A teenage girl struggling under the pressure of expectations from her friends, family, and society. Cheerful and energetic as a child, she’s grown to become much more restrained, and now hardly smiles.</li></ul><p><strong>Staff Comments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Scriptwriter <a href="https://twitter.com/07th_official" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ryukishi07</a></strong> – “To this day, I remember the feeling of my first encounter with the suffocating and oppressive atmosphere of <em>Silent Hill</em>. It still deeply haunts me, and it still utterly fascinates me. It’s an honor to find myself involved with a series I have so many memories with. I’ve poured all my efforts into this story, so much so that I don’t think I would mind if it was the last thing I ever wrote. To me, the <em>Silent Hill</em> series is more than just a collection of stories, it’s a medium; an amazing, phenomenal way of exploring and experiencing a person’s heart and mind. It’s my hope that players out there will come to appreciate it in the same way. And to all of our overseas friends, I hope you’ll enjoy a look at what <em>Silent Hill</em> might be like if set somewhere a little different, like Japan.”</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Creature [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a> and Character Designer <a href="https://twitter.com/kera_2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kera</a></strong> – “I love the <em>Silent Hill</em> series, and it’s been a big influence on me. In particular, I am constantly remembering <em><a title="Games > Silent Hill 2 (2024) [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-2-2024">Silent Hill 2</a></em>, and the messages on the walls, the music, and the monster designs. So, when it came to <em>Silent Hill f</em>, and bringing the setting to Japan, we had to come up with something that felt just a little different, and I had to really think about how to get that feeling. The monster designs were the hardest. I had to consider everything that’s come in <em>Silent Hill</em> before, and figure out how to take this game in a different direction, but still be <em>Silent Hill</em>. It might not be the exact same blood-smeared, rusting scenery, but I sincerely hope you’ll enjoy our vision and the world we’ve created.”</li><li><strong>Composer <a href="https://twitter.com/akirayamaoka" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Akira Yamaoka</a></strong>&nbsp;– “Although this is set in Japan, we focused on portraying it in a way that is based solely on the conception of <em>Silent Hill</em>. While incorporating plenty of Japan’s unique identity, we sublimated it as fiction and expressed this unique culture as entertainment. By doing so, we believe we were able to blend the charm of Japan in a new way into the unique worldview of <em>Silent Hill</em>. We hope that through this game, you will enjoy the look and feel of what makes this title truly <em>Silent Hill</em>.”</li><li><strong>Composer <a href="https://twitter.com/ken_inage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kensuke Inage</a></strong> – “The first time I played <em>Silent Hill</em> was about 20 years back. I’m extremely honored to have been offered such a great opportunity for a series with a rich history. I was in charge of composing the music for the Otherworld, known in this game as the ‘Dark Shrine.’ I have composed music for an unsettling yet beautiful world that uses imagery from shrines, blending ancient Japanese court music with ambient echoes. I wove in various techniques that will connect the player to the protagonist’s agony, internal conflict, fear, and other emotions. I hope you get to experience it for yourself in the game.”</li></ul><p>*Other composers include&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/higu_dai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dai</a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://twitter.com/xaki_k_sakita" target="_blank" rel="noopener">xaki</a>.</p><p><strong>Disclaimer</strong></p><p>This game contains depictions of gender discrimination, child abuse, bullying, drug-induced hallucinations, torture, and graphic violence.</p><p>This game is set in Japan in the 1960s and contains depictions based on the customs and culture of that time. These depictions do not reflect the opinions or values of the developers or any individuals involved.</p><p>If you feel uncomfortable at any point while playing, please take a break from playing or speak to someone you trust.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the reveal trailer and an archive of today’s <em>Silent Hill</em> Transmission below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/silent-hill-f/march-13-2025/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/silenthill/f/us/en/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="SILENT HILL f | Official Reveal Trailer (4K: EN/ESRB) | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_qFEyq8quhA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="SILENT HILL f | Official Reveal Trailer (4K: JA/CERO) | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ONp_2FNYqvM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span><em>Silent Hill</em> Transmission: March 13, 2025</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="SILENT HILL Transmission (EN) with subtitles | March 13, 2025 | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0pPKJevpvZI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="SILENT HILL Transmission (JP) 字幕付き | 2025.3.14 | KONAMI" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IWvyPjr0YSo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>