<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:06:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Game Catalog and Classics Catalog lineup for January 2025 announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-january-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-january-2025-announced.1083033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/playstation-plus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-lineup-for-january-2025-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>God of War Ragnarok, Like a Dragon: The Man Who Erased His Name, MediEvil II, and more.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,941 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/15/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-january-god-of-war-ragnarok-like-a-dragon-gaiden-the-man-who-erased-his-name-atlas-fallen-reign-of-sand-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the January 2025 Game Catalog lineup for Extra and Premium subscribers, and Classics Catalog titles for Premium subscribers. <span id="more-938606"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><p>All titles will be available from January 21.</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Game Catalog</strong></p><ul><li><strong><em><a title="Games > ANNO: Mutationem [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/anno-mutationem">ANNO: Mutationem</a></em></strong> (<a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,588 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a>) –&nbsp;Welcome to the neon-covered, 2D-meets-3D Cyberpunk world of <em>ANNO: Mutationem</em>. In this <a title="Genres > Action [2,416 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> with <a title="Genres > RPG [16,924 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> elements, you become Ann: a highly-skilled combat-trained lone wolf on a personal mission in a giant Metropolis, full of sinister mega-corporations, mysterious fringe groups and creatures more bizarre than words can express.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Atlas Fallen [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/atlas-fallen">Atlas Fallen</a>: Reign Of Sand</em></strong> (PS5) –&nbsp;In this <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,465 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a>, master the sands and explore a unique fantasy land teeming with secrets and dangers alone or in online two-player <a title="Genres > Co-Op [227 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, as you hunt colossal legendary creatures in spectacular combat. <em>Reign of Sand</em> is the ultimate version of <em>Atlas Fallen</em>: an expanded world, new enemies and challenges, revamped progression, new quests, reworked voice acting, additional difficulty mode and “New Game+” modes!</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Citizen Sleeper [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/citizen-sleeper">Citizen Sleeper</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;You are a sleeper, a digitized human consciousness in an artificial body, owned by a corporation that wants you back. Inspired by Tabletop Roleplaying games, Citizen Sleeper uses Dice, Clocks and Drives to create a player-led experience, where you choose your path in a rich and responsive world. Thrust amongst the unfamiliar and colorful inhabitants of the Eye, you need to build friendships, earn your keep, and navigate the factions of this strange metropolis, if you hope to survive to see the next cycle.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > God of War Ragnarok [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War Ragnarok</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;From <a title="Companies > Santa Monica Studio [188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/santa-monica-studio">Santa Monica Studio</a> comes the sequel to the critically acclaimed <em><a title="Games > God of War (2018) [175 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/god-of-war-2018">God of War</a></em> (2018). Embark on an epic and heartfelt journey as Kratos and Atreus struggle with holding on and letting go. Fimbulwinter is well underway. Kratos and Atreus must journey to each of the Nine Realms in search of answers as Asgardian forces prepare for a prophesied battle that will end the world. Along the way they will explore stunning, mythical landscapes, and face fearsome enemies in the form of <a title="Games > Norse [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/norse">Norse</a> gods and monsters. As the threat of Ragnarök grows ever closer, Kratos and Atreus must choose between their own safety and the safety of the realms.</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > Like a Dragon Gaiden: The Man Who Erased His Name [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/like-a-dragon-gaiden-the-man-who-erased-his-name">Like a Dragon Gaiden: The Man Who Erased His Name</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) – Once a legendary yakuza, Kazuma Kiryu faked his own death and abandoned his name for the sake of protecting his family. Now, he is thrust into conflict by a mysterious figure attempting to drive him out of hiding. Under the codename “Joryu,” Kiryu embarks on a gripping action narrative with bone-shattering combat in vibrant locations filled with exciting characters and activities.</li><li><strong><em>Orcs Must Die! 3</em></strong> (PS5, PS4) – <em>Orcs Must Die! 3</em> ushers orc-slaying mayhem to a previously unimaginable scale. Solo or with a friend by your side, arm yourself with a massive arsenal of traps and weapons. Slice, burn, toss and zap hordes of repugnant orcs in this long-awaited successor to the award-winning series. It’s everything fans loved about the first two games and more. More orcs, more traps, more weapons, more upgrades and even better looking. It’s cranked up to at least eleven.</li><li><strong><em>Poker Club</em></strong> (PS4) –&nbsp;Welcome to <em>Poker Club</em>. Live the life of a poker pro in the most immersive poker <a title="Genres > Simulation [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> ever seen, with ultra HD 4K visuals and breath-taking ray tracing. Join a community of online players on their way to the top and track your progress in more than 10 Texas Hold’em tournament modes including freezeouts, shootouts, super-turbos, bounties and more. Whether you’re a seasoned poker pro or brand new to the table, perfect your play style for the chance to win big.</li><li><strong><em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em></strong> (PS4) –&nbsp;<em>Sayonara Wild Hearts</em> is a dreamy <a title="Genres > Arcade [67 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade game</a> about riding motorcycles, skateboarding, dance battling, shooting lasers, wielding swords, and breaking hearts at 200 mph. As the heart of a young woman breaks, the balance of the universe is disturbed. A diamond butterfly appears in her dreams and leads her through a highway in the sky, where she finds her other self: the masked biker called The Fool. Journey through a custom-written pop soundtrack, chase scores, and set out to find the harmony of the universe, hidden away in the hearts of Little Death and her star-crossed allies: Dancing Devils, <a title="Games > Howl [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/howl">Howl</a>ing Moons, Stereo Lovers and Hermit 64. Let’s Pop!</li><li><strong><em><a title="Games > SD Gundam Battle Alliance [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sd-gundam-battle-alliance">SD Gundam Battle Alliance</a></em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;<a title="Platforms > Mobile [2,683 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">Mobile</a> Suits and characters from across <em>Mobile Suit Gundam</em> history take center stage in this all-new action RPG. The story takes place in G: Universe, a world where <em>Gundam</em> canon twists and turns in ways no one can predict. To correct this world’s distorted history, you lead a three-unit squadron consisting of Mobile Suits and pilots from across <em>Gundam</em> history—a true Battle Alliance. <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> <em>Gundam</em> history’s most famous scenes as you develop new Mobile Suits to add to your arsenal. In <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>, you can play through the game with up to two other players in a three-person team. Enjoy this new <em>SD Gundam</em> action RPG solo, or with friends.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Classics Catalog</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,736 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a></strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>Medievil II</em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;The sequel to <em><a title="Games > MediEvil (2019) [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/medievil-2019">MediEvil</a></em> released on <a title="Platforms > PS1 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps1">the original PlayStation</a> in 2000. In this new and improved version, featuring up-rendering, rewind, quick save, and custom video filters, you’ll have to challenge the powers of darkness and untold magic as Sir Daniel Fortesque returns from the grave to thwart an evil sorcerer’s plans. Arm yourself with a mighty arsenal of weapons, including swords, daggers, crossbows, hammers, and even the occasional chicken drumstick. Solve fiendish puzzles and riddles, face ghoulish enemies that will strike fear into the bravest of souls, all of it set to a spine-tingling soundtrack.</li></ul><p><strong><a title="Platforms > PS2 [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps2">PlayStation 2</a></strong></p><ul><li><strong><em>Indiana Jones and the Staff of Kings</em></strong> (PS5, PS4) –&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones and the Staff of Kings</em>, originally released in 2009 on PlayStation 2, takes you on a perilous, around-the-world quest for the staff of Moses. This classic third-person action adventure has been enhanced with up-rendering, rewind, quick save, and custom video filters. Grab your whip and get ready for a thrilling journey in true Indiana Jones tradition.</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Age of Empires, Borderlands, and BioShock developers announce real-time tactical roguelite game Wartorn for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/former-age-of-empires-borderlands-and-bioshock-developers-announce-real-time-tactical-roguelite-game-wartorn-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-age-of-empires-borderlands-and-bioshock-developers-announce-real-time-tactical-roguelite-game-wartorn-for-pc.1083030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/former-age-of-empires-borderlands-and-bioshock-developers-announce-real-time-tactical-roguelite-game-wartorn-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in Early Access this spring.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Stray Kite Studios" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stray-kite-studios">Stray Kite Studios</a>, a studio comprised of former <em>Age of Empires</em>, <em><a title="Series > Borderlands [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/borderlands">Borderlands</a></em>, and <em>BioShock</em> developers, has announced <em><a title="Games > Wartorn [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wartorn">Wartorn</a></em>, a real-time tactical <a title="Genres > Roguelite [209 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite game</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [22,125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1296660/Wartorn/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [347 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store. It will launch in Early Access this spring. <span id="more-938587"></span></p><p>“Our vision for <em>Wartorn</em> is a game that seamlessly blends artistic expression, tactical depth, and emotional resonance,” said Stray Kite Studios CEO and co-founder Shovaen Patel in a press release. “We want players to feel like every choice matters, both on the battlefield and in the story.”</p><p>Creative director and Stray Kite Studios co-founder Paul Hellquist added, “<em>Wartorn</em> challenges players to navigate the chaos of a divided world while finding purpose and joy in selflessness. We’ve poured our hearts into creating a game that not only entertains but also makes players think deeply about sacrifice, <a title="Genres > Survival [367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>, and the bonds that unite us.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1296660/Wartorn/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Wartorn</em> is a single-player, squad-based, roguelite campaign experience where players play as Yara and Elani, sisters who have been driven from their home and must traverse the wartorn Isles of Talaur to reach the safety of Beynun, their ancestral fortress.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Harness the elements in fierce real-time battles while gathering and upgrading a crew of fantasy creatures in this roguelite adventure across a world torn apart by war.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_938591"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Systemic Elemental System</strong> – <em>Wartorn</em> features a systemic, emergent gameplay system using the elements of fire, water, tar, plant, and lightning. Strategically choose your squads to master the elements and environment against hordes of enemies. Water extinguishes fire, tar amplifies fire, electricity crackles across the ranks in wet conditions, and water can heal plant-based units. And that’s just scratching the surface!</li><li><strong>Squad-Based Combat</strong> – Build out your Caravan by recruiting squads of fantasy creatures including goblins, elves, demons, treefolk, (and more!) as you travel the world. Each squad adds new strategic options to your caravan through their different characteristics and unique abilities. Mix and match what squads you bring into battle to truly master a run. Battlefield positioning, squad combos, and skillful usage of abilities can win the day, but be careful, losses cost you morale, and if your caravan loses hope it’s game over.</li><li><strong>Strategic Replayability</strong> – The game’s blend of strategic and roguelite elements offer deep replayability, with each run feeling fresh thanks to emergent gameplay, dynamic squad <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a>, and unpredictable narrative events that can save your struggling band or cost them their lives.</li><li><strong>Locating Your Lost Family</strong> – Search the Isles of Talaur to meet Yara and Elani’s family, who reveal pieces of the game’s story and grant the player heirlooms that bring with them new advantages and abilities for future runs.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/wartorn/january-15-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Wartorn - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XoqMFJs4wvw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doraemon Dorayaki Shop Story coming to PS4, Xbox Series, and Xbox One on January 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16.1082928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/doraemon-dorayaki-shop-story-coming-to-ps4-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-on-january-16<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><em>Doraemon Dorayaki Shop Story</em> first launched for Switch on August 27, 2024, followed by iOS and Android on September 23, 2024, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2934180/Doraemon_Dorayaki_Shop_Story/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 9, 2024.</p><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A game where you run a sweets shop with the popular manga character Doraemon.</p><p>Let’s make Doraemon’s favorite dorayaki and create a store that will be the talk of the town.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>First, make the sweets, set up the shelves, prepare the tables, and get ready to run the shop!</p><p>In addition, various characters from Fujiko・F・Fujio’s works will appear as customers!</p><p>Many characters will come, including T・P BON and Kiteretsu Encyclopedia.</p><p>During your <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> to find ingredients, you will encounter many difficulties. Even in such a situation, Doraemon’s secret gadgets will help you solve difficult problems without any difficulty!</p><p>A management game created by Kairosoft, a company popular for its <a title="Genres > Simulation [626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation games</a>.</p><p>Enjoy Doraemon’s unique adventures.</p><p><strong>Game Flow</strong></p><p>First, let’s make a dorayaki.</p><p>Set up seats and shelves of sweets inside the shop and open it.</p><p>As you discover different sweets while making them, you will attract more customers.</p><p>Occasionally, you will fulfill your customers’ requests and make your dorayaki shop famous and known throughout the country.</p><p><strong>Doraemon and Friends</strong></p><p>Five friends will become shop staff and help out in the shop. Shop staff have two parameters.</p><ul><li><strong>Exploration</strong> – Helps you find ingredients and get rid of obstacles.</li><li><strong>Skill</strong> – Helps you make sweets in the kitchen and improve sweets in the prototype room.</li></ul><p><strong>Let’s Make Sweets!</strong></p><p>Making many new sweets will lead to the development of the shop. Let’s collect ingredients by searching for ingredients and make them as you go.</p><p>You can make sweets by looking at hints on combinations, but there are also rare sweets that don’t have any hints.</p><p><strong>Be Particular About the Decorations</strong></p><p>You can decorate your sweets. Basically, it’s best to choose freely based on your preference for appearance. The decorations you choose will improve the quality and reputation of the sweets at the tasting event. It will also have a positive effect when you improve the sweets.</p><p>The decorations may go well with the staff who puts the finishing touches on them.</p><p><strong>Let’s Search for Ingredients</strong></p><p>Go find ingredients in various places. When you discover ingredients, you will be able to make new sweets.</p><p>When searching for ingredients, the staff’s exploration parameters are important. If the numbers are high, it will be easier to meet new characters and discover items. The staff’s exploration ability also affects the rank of books that can be used to improve sweets.</p><p><strong>Build a Facility</strong></p><p>Installing facilities is important for the development of your shop.</p><p><strong>Facility Parameters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Charm</strong> – The higher it is, the higher the satisfaction will be and the more points you will receive.</li><li><strong>Genre</strong> – There are types such as wabisabi or retro, and building facilities of the same genre nearby will generate area bonuses.</li></ul><p><strong>Aim to Rank Up</strong></p><p>As you rank up, you’ll be able to manage your shop more advantageously, and the number of things you can do and the facilities you can build will increase.</p><p>You’ll also be able to use the Lander-Expander more times, which will allow you to expand your space.</p><p>Meet the conditions to reach the highest rank.</p><p><strong>About the Ending</strong></p><p>The game will end 1 year after you start at the end of the fourth week of March, but you can continue to play the game after that.</p><p>If you start a new game after reaching the ending and use the “New Game+” data, you can start the game with some of the data you cleared, which can give you an advantage in running your business.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>