<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 16:30:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SHUTEN ORDER interview with Kazutaka Kodaka, Takumi Nakazawa, and Masafumi Takada – cults, mysteries, and multiple genres]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/shuten-order-interview-with-kazutaka-kodaka-takumi-nakazawa-and-masafumi-takada-cults-mysteries-and-multiple-genres</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shuten-order-interview-with-kazutaka-kodaka-takumi-nakazawa-and-masafumi-takada-%E2%80%93-cults-mysteries-and-multiple-genres.1304511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > SHUTEN ORDER [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shuten-order">SHUTEN ORDER</a></em> launched for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3216500/SHUTEN_ORDER/" target="_blank">Steam</a> earlier this month, and <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> sat down for a brief chat with game creator, planner, and scenario writer Kazutaka Kodaka; director and scenario writer Takumi Nakazawa; and composer and sound director <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>afumi Takada to dive a bit deeper into the multi-genre mystery game’s creation. <span id="more-993333"></span></p><p>Get the full interview below.</p><p><strong>What made you want to create a game based around a religious cult? Were there any real-life inspirations in designing the cult?</strong></p><p><strong>Kazutaka Kodaka, Creator, Planner, and Scenario Writer:</strong> “Originally, I wanted an indie game idea, tackling an edgy theme that wouldn’t be possible with a big budget, so I chose to focus on cults and dismemberment murder.</p><p>“Later, I came up with a trick that really fit that theme, but to pull it off the game’s scale ended up becoming too large, so I put it on hold for a while.</p><p>“When I got to know <a title="Companies > DMM Games [91 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/exnoa/dmm-games">DMM GAMES</a>, I showed them a plot that incorporated this idea. Despite the extreme theme, they agreed to work on it together, and that’s how this title came to life.”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><em>SHUTEN ORDER</em>‘s religion forbids violence, yet the story revolves around murder. How did you balance that without breaking the cult’s rules?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “As a cult, they have their own unique values ​​and rules. That’s why they wish for the end of the world. Everything ties back to a single, overarching mystery, the dismemberment murder of their leader. I constructed the story and setting specifically to lead to that conclusion. <a title="Series > Persona [91 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>lly, I think it’s one of my best works, so I hope you’ll see for yourself.”</p><p><strong>Each Minister’s route uses a different genre. How did you keep them feeling like one game, versus a collection of several smaller games?</strong></p><p><strong>Takumi Nakazawa, Director and Scenario Writer:</strong> “There are two key points.</p><p>“The first is to stick to the main theme. In every route, we made sure to organically weave the story into the scenario of each route, so as not to lose sight of the core of the story, which is the murder of the cult leader, and the protagonist’s goal of finding the killer.</p><p>“The second is to maintain a consistent tone. When developing the game systems for each genre, we were careful not to stray from the setting of <em>SHUTEN ORDER</em>.”</p><p><strong>When designing the Ministers, did you start with their character archetypes and then match genres to fit them, or did you first decide on the genres and build the characters around that? Can you talk a bit about that process?</strong></p><p><strong>Nakazawa:</strong> “I heard from Kodaka that both were decided on almost simultaneously, but the genre came slightly ahead. For example, it was broadly decided that one of the routes would be a mystery adventure. Since that seemed like a good place for a detective character to play an active role, we constructed the image for Kishiru Inugami around Sherlock Holmes. The scenario’s plot was then built around that idea. After that, the details of the character were solidified as the scenario was written.</p><p>“On the other hand, for the Ministry of Science route, there were times when the genre was reconsidered after the character had already been decided. It’s not like we decided completely on one element and then solidified the other.”</p><p><strong>The routes range from <a title="Genres > Horror [713 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> to romance. How did you approach creating the soundtrack so that it fits all these different genres?</strong></p><p><strong>Masafumi Takada, Composer and Sound Director:</strong> “To evoke the culture of Shuten Order, I first created several thematic motifs shared across the entire game, and then arranged them to match each route, thereby shaping the soundtrack’s sense of world.</p><p>“In other words, if the motifs are like ‘words,’ the arrangements can be seen as the ‘rhythm and harmony’ of each genre’s language.</p><p>“By doing so, the soundtrack transforms with each route, yet throughout the game the world of <em>SHUTEN ORDER</em> lingers like a scent, remaining with players as a lasting part of their experience.”</p><p><strong>The protagonist Rei only has four days to live. Why four? How did you decide on that time limit for the story? And how did that limit change your approach to pacing?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “The four-day rule is something shared across all of the routes. I decided on it by looking at the balance within each route.</p><p>“Depending on the route, it turned out to be quite a tough restriction, but I think we somehow managed to pull it off.”</p><p><strong>You’ve previously said <em>SHUTEN ORDER</em> is influenced by every <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [605 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> you’ve loved. Can you share a couple of direct examples?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “<em>Cross Tantei Monogatari</em>, <em>Machi</em>, <em>Princess Tomato in the Salad Kingdom</em>, <em>Cross Channel</em>, <em><a title="Games > Clock Tower: Rewind [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clock-tower-rewind">Clock Tower</a></em>, <em>428: Shibuya Scramble</em>,<br><em>The Portopia Serial Murder Case</em>, <em>Zero Escape</em>, <em>Ever 17</em>, <em>Ace Attorney</em>, <em>Higurashi When They Cry</em>, and <em>The Song of Saya</em>.”</p><p><strong>Most of Mr. Kodaka’s past works revolve around investigating murders. What keeps drawing you back to that theme, and what feels new about it this time?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “I’ve always loved mysteries, and I think it’s one of my strengths as a creator.</p><p>“Right now, whether you look at Japan or overseas, there really aren’t many game developers focusing primarily on mysteries, so I want to keep exploring that space. Of course, I enjoy working on other genres too.”</p><p><strong>The story is about pursuing the truth, but also making sacrifices. Can you talk more about the nature of these sacrifices, and how they affect the player?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “I can’t go into detail without spoilers, but the truth doesn’t always lead to a happy outcome. It can also reveal hardships.”</p><p><strong>How do you hope this game stands out from other mystery or <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,573 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure games</a>? What do you hope sticks with the player after the story is complete?</strong></p><p><strong>Nakazawa:</strong> “There are two points that stand out.</p><p>“The first is that it’s a mystery that unfolds within the context of religion, a world where values differ from common sense. There are original tricks that are not found (and would not work) in other works.</p><p>“The second point is that the secrets hidden in the story can be revealed in any order. These secrets are spread across five routes. Players can choose to play through the routes in any order, so the order in which the secrets are revealed will be different for each player. This creates an experience that is unique for each player.</p><p>“After finishing the story, players will experience a distinct feeling that comes from this work, and at the same time, realize that it was a special experience that only they could have. That’s the way I see it.”</p><p><strong><em>SHUTEN ORDER</em> is currently only available for for Switch and PC. Is there any possibility we’ll see the game on PlayStation or Xbox in the future?</strong></p><p><strong>Kodaka:</strong> “DMM Games owns the property, so ultimately it’s up to them.”</p><p><strong>Thank you for your time, everyone!</strong></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/shuten-order-interview-with-kazutaka-kodaka-takumi-nakazawa-and-masafumi-takada-cults-mysteries-and-multiple-genres]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcade pinball game XENOTILT now available for PS5; coming to Xbox Series and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/arcade-pinball-game-xenotilt-now-available-for-ps5-coming-to-xbox-series-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcade-pinball-game-xenotilt-now-available-for-ps5-coming-to-xbox-series-and-switch.1304508/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The sequel to DEMON'S TILT.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher and developer <a title="Companies > FLARB" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/flarb">FLARB</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > WIZNWAR" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wiznwar">WIZNWAR</a> have released <em><a title="Games > XENOTILT" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/xenotilt">XENOTILT</a></em>, the <a title="Genres > Arcade [92 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> pinball sequel to <em>DEMON’S TILT</em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,416 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> for $19.99. <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,941 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> versions will follow at a later date. <span id="more-994268"></span></p><p><em>XENOTILT</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2008980/XENOTILT_HOSTILE_PINBALL_ACTION/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 18, 2023, followed by a full release on November 12, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via FLARB:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>XENOTILT</em>, the sequel to the cult hit, <em>DEMON’S TILT</em>. Get ready for another pinball fantasy. <em>XENOTILT</em> shreds the envelope with face-melting gameplay and graphics.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>An expansive three-story table.</li><li>Nightmarish new bosses.</li><li>New lighting system.</li><li>Nine-ball multiball matrix.</li><li>Big numbers, bullet hell.</li><li><a title="Companies > CAVE Interactive [60 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cave-interactive">Cave</a>rnously deep mechanics.</li><li>A mega-driven soundtrack by EC2151.</li></ul><p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Three-Tier Playfield</strong> – Welcome to the Samaritan, a derelict ship turned hostile, has anyone survived?</li><li><strong>Xenophage Swarm</strong> – A vicious infestation that plagues the Samaritan.</li><li><strong>The Turret System</strong> – Big bullets chew up baddies and smash enemy volleys.</li><li><strong>The Perk System</strong> – Upgrade your weapons, defense, and scoring power with nine unique perks.</li><li><strong>The Multiball Matrix</strong> – Holds nine balls, activates perks, and creates multiball opportunities.</li><li><strong>Crisis Mode</strong> – Time attack, with a multiball twist. Die n’ retry.</li><li><strong>Hardcore</strong> – One ball, maxxed firepower.</li></ul><p><strong>The Xenophage</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Hera the Rogue Pirate A.I.</strong> – A sentient Malware has taken over the Samaritan. Cosmic pirate queen.</li><li><strong>Chrysalis</strong> – A bruiser of a Xenophage bug, swarm protector.</li><li><strong>Tiger Supreme</strong> – The Samaritan’s security measure.</li><li><strong>Star Pilot</strong> – Addicted to life support he functions now as the undead navigator.</li><li><strong>Mecha-Neko</strong> – Weaponized blackjack dealer. Press your luck for big points!</li><li><strong>Olmech</strong> – Stone god grafted with cybernetic enhancements.</li><li><strong>Brood Mother</strong> – Hive mother to the Xenophage swarm. Don’t touch her babies!</li></ul><p><strong>Visuals and Sound</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Graphics</strong> – “Hi-Bit,” massive colorful <a title="Companies > sprite [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sprite">sprite</a>s inspired by the 16 and 32-bit era. Scaling, rotation, camera zooms… No “blast processor” required!</li><li><strong>Music</strong> – A mega-driven soundtrack: an all-new original soundtrack true to the guttural sound of the 16-bit era, composed by E.C.2151</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/arcade-pinball-game-xenotilt-now-available-for-ps5-coming-to-xbox-series-and-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genokids launches in Early Access on October 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/genokids-launches-in-early-access-on-october-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genokids-launches-in-early-access-on-october-2.1304445/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Expected to remain in Early Access for two years.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Genokids [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/genokids">Genokids</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1239360/Genokids/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 2, developer <a title="Companies > Nukefist [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nukefist">Nukefist</a> announced. <span id="more-994383"></span></p><p>The Early Access version will feature the game’s first of three acts, with the full release planned to add two more chapters, including new levels, secrets, abilities, power-ups, enemies, bosses, weapons, and two additional movesets for the remaining main characters yet to appear.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1239360/Genokids/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><em>Genokids</em> is a game about MOTIVATION, a fast-paced <a title="Genres > Hack-and-Slash [61 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/hack-and-slash">hack-and-slash</a> where a band of musicians take down an alien invasion!</p><ul><li>Play as&nbsp; four characters at the same time, each with their own moveset!</li><li>Smoothly navigate through the ruins of Las Divas using slick parkour moves.</li><li>Style your way through waves of enemies, what’s the point of saving the world if you don’t look cool doing it?</li><li>Follow the bombastic tale of this band of misfits as they make the impossible, possible.</li></ul><p>A bizarre music band named Genokids is rocking one of their best concerts to date when The Infinite Empire of Zenodia decides to invade Earth and assimilate mankind, landing right on top of the band and ruining both their concert and mood.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Seamlessly swap between all four characters in the middle of a fight. Execute multiple actions at the same time!</p><p>Go beyond your limits and enter HYPER MODE!</p><p>MOTIVATION IS MANKIND’S GREATEST WEAPON!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GENOKIDS - ACT1 Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O3YbRnsIdGQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/genokids-launches-in-early-access-on-october-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 ‘Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-gameplay-reveal-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-%E2%80%98multiplayer-gameplay-reveal%E2%80%99-trailer.1304442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Plus a deep dive into everything multiplayer.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Activision [70 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/activision">Activision</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Treyarch [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/activision/treyarch">Treyarch</a> and <a title="Companies > Raven Software [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/activision/raven-software">Raven Software</a> have released the <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [603 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer game</a>play reveal trailer for <em><a title="Games > Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a></em>, as well as published a new <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/09/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-deep-dive" target="_blank">multiplayer deep dive</a> detailing everything from new modes to maps, weapons, Perks, Field Upgrades, and more. <span id="more-994379"></span></p><p><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,416 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,941 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,363 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1938090/Call_of_Duty/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/9plbm5790l94" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>, and <a href="https://us.shop.battle.net/en-us/product/call-of-duty-black-ops-7" target="_blank">Battle.net</a> on November 14. It will also be available via Game Pass.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 | Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGFYtZD53ZA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-gameplay-reveal-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>