<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 18:58:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LightSpeed Studios unveils original IP strategy, including new AAA action game by Hideaki Itsuno]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/lightspeed-studios-unveils-original-ip-strategy-including-new-aaa-action-game-by-hideaki-itsuno</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lightspeed-studios-unveils-original-ip-strategy-including-new-aaa-action-game-by-hideaki-itsuno.1140327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/lightspeed-studios-unveils-original-ip-strategy-including-new-aaa-action-game-by-hideaki-itsuno<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><a title="Companies > LightSpeed Studios [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent/tencent-games/lightspeed-studios">LightSpeed Studios</a> has revealed its “Original IP Initiative,” a new strategic focus centered on developing original titles, including an AAA original <a title="Genres > Action [2,583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> by Hideaki Itsuno. <span id="more-949448"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>LightSpeed Studios Commits to Development of Original Game Intellectual Property</strong></p><p>Recognizing that innovation drives player engagement, LightSpeed Studios is sharpening its approach and announcing its commitment to empowering a network of self-sustained, independently run regional studios that will be focused entirely on developing original, cross-platform game titles.</p><p>LightSpeed Studios, best known for its work with established game title <em>PUBG <a title="Platforms > Mobile [2,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">MOBILE</a></em> (co-developed with <a title="Companies > KRAFTON [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krafton">KRAFTON</a>), is strategically expanding and building state-of-the-art development facilities around the world to support original game development.</p><p>This strategy enables its development studios, which notably includes LightSpeed LA, the newly established <a title="Companies > LightSpeed Japan Studio [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent/tencent-games/lightspeed-studios/lightspeed-japan-studio">LightSpeed Japan Studio</a>, along with teams across the world, a direct pipeline to LightSpeed Studios’ centralized technical resources. This consists of LightSpeed Studios’ latest research and development breakthroughs, which push the boundaries of graphics and performance to enhance in-game realism, as showcased in workshops during GDC 2025.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>LightSpeed Studios Sets the Stage for a New Era for LightSpeed Japan Studio</strong></p><p>Building on this approach, legendary game director and head of LightSpeed Japan Studio, Hideaki Itsuno, is revealing at GDC 2025 that he’s entering the arena and embarked on the early stages of bringing his own visionary AAA game title to life. Drawing on his extensive experience directing games and building incredible teams at <a title="Companies > Capcom [2,570 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> that drove the remarkable successes of <em>Devil May Cry</em>, the Capcom <em>Alpha</em> series, <em>Capcom VS. <a title="Companies > SNK Corporation [412 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/snk">SNK</a></em>, and many more iconic game titles, Itsuno is ready to apply the same principles of creative freedom, efficiency, and humility to assemble an outstanding team and create something truly groundbreaking.</p><p>“We’re building a creative environment that combines diverse cultural perspectives with cutting-edge technology,” said LightSpeed Japan Studio general manager Hideaki Itsuno. “Our focus is on developing gameplay elements that offer players entirely new experiences—the kind of innovations that make players say I’ve never seen that in a game before.”</p><p><strong>Leveraging Global Talent and Nurturing Creative Freedom</strong></p><p>Additionally, to foster fresh perspectives in original game development, LightSpeed Studios is adopting a model that enables each studio to shape its own culture, advocating for original thinking within teams. Bringing to the table Eastern and Western game philosophies, LightSpeed Studios is positioned to encourage regional teams to exchange ideas, blend cultural influences, and unite under a shared vision—creating truly global gaming experiences.</p><p>A standout example of this approach is being led by the vice president of LightSpeed Studios, Steve C. Martin, known for his commitment to five-year development cycles. Focused on bringing his original AAA open world action title, Last Sentinel, to life, Steve has assembled a world-class, global team. Despite talent from prestigious studios like Rockstar Games, Meta and EA Games, LightSpeed LA has fostered not only a culture of creative freedom but ensures product efficiency, thanks to Steve’s emphasis on humility and a willingness to embrace constructive feedback.</p><p>“Any game studio’s ambition lies with developing original games,” said Martin. “The creative freedom of creating your own lore from scratch, building a compelling narrative, and all the upsides from this is the dream of any studio, and that’s why LightSpeed Studios is the place to be.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part II Remastered for PC to launch alongside new playable characters and maps for ‘No Return’ mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-for-pc-to-launch-alongside-new-playable-characters-and-maps-for-no-return-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-for-pc-to-launch-alongside-new-playable-characters-and-maps-for-%E2%80%98no-return%E2%80%99-mode.1140270/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-for-pc-to-launch-alongside-new-playable-characters-and-maps-for-no-return-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>Two New Characters</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/TLoU2_03-20-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><p>Two new characters are being introduced for the mode—<em><a title="Games > The Last of Us Part I [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-i">The Last of Us Part I</a></em>‘s Bill and Marlene. Like with each No Return combatant, these characters offer their own unique playstyles, and should offer both new and returning fans an exciting new opportunity to test their mettle.</p><ul><li><strong>Bill</strong> is a “Smuggler” playstyle who can access a custom pump shotgun from dead drops, and receives double rewards from drops as well. He’s stronger against melee attacks but can’t dodge.</li><li><strong>Marlene</strong>, meanwhile, features a “Risk Taker” playstyle that includes a Custom Assault Rifle, “All or Nothing” gambits, can reroute her No Return path once per run, and more.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Four New Maps</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/TLoU2_03-20-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Four new maps have also been added to No Return.</p><ul><li><strong>Overlook</strong>, which is set high above the city of Seattle and features plenty of verticality, is the memorable site of a Seraphites encounter in the campaign.</li><li><strong>School</strong> is, during the campaign, the abandoned elementary school in which Ellie and Dina face off against the W.L.F.</li><li><strong>Streets</strong> is set in the overgrown Seattle neighborhood of Hillcrest.</li><li><strong>Nest</strong> will be familiar to players who have played as Abby through an Infected-infested building.</li></ul><p><strong>PlayStation 5 Update</strong></p><p>This new No Return content, as well as accompanying new Trophies and additional bug fixes – will be available day-and-date with the PC launch via a free downloadable 2.0.0 patch.6</p><p><strong><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [47,191 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Network Log-In Bonuses</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/TLoU2_03-20-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> on PC will support PlayStation overlay and PSN Trophies with an optional account for PlayStation Network log-in.</p><p>While not required, those on PC who do sign in with their account for PlayStation Network will also gain access to 50 in-game points to activate bonus features, as well as a new skin for Ellie featuring Jordan A. Mun’s jacket from our new game in development for PlayStation 5, <em><a title="Games > Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a></em>.</p><p><strong>PC Features</strong></p><p>The PC version of <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> brings with it all the improvements and new features added in the PlayStation 5 version released in 2024, such as the <a title="Genres > Roguelike [306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Survival [393 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> mode No Return, Guitar Free Play, and hours of developer commentary.</p><p>And in partnership with our friends at Nixxes Software and <a title="Companies > Iron Galaxy [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/iron-galaxy">Iron Galaxy</a>, <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> has been brought to PC with plenty of PC-centric quality-of-life features that further bring the snow-covered mountains of Jackson, Wyoming, and the rainswept streets of Seattle, Washington to beautiful life.</p><p>This version of <em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> is optimized for PC with:</p><ul><li>Nvidia DLSS 3 Super Resolution support1</li><li>AMD FSR 3.1 and AMD FSR 4 support with upscaling and frame generation1</li><li>VSync and framerate cap options, including an uncapped framerate option2</li><li>DirectStorage support, and more.</li></ul><p>It has been developed with features designed specifically for PC, including:</p><ul><li>Adjustable Texture Quality</li><li>LOD <a title="Games > Distance [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/distance">Distance</a> Range</li><li>Volumetric Quality</li><li>Shadow Quality</li><li>Ambient Occlusion</li><li>Reflections Quality</li><li>And more</li></ul><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> on PC will feature support for Ultrawide monitors, so players will be able to take in the stunning vistas of Jackson and the harsh streets of Seattle with gameplay supported in 21:9 ultra-wide, 32:9 super ultra-wide and even 48:9 resolutions with compatibility for triple-monitor setups.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/TLoU2_03-20-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><p>And take in every chapter of Ellie and Abby’s journeys in stunning 4K resolution while playing either via various supported controllers as well as keyboard and mouse controls. And immerse yourself in the story with 3D audio surrounding you in every tense moment of <a title="Genres > Action [2,583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and each quiet scene of exploration.</p><p>Keyboard and mouse control support includes a host of new control customization options, like full control remapping, primary and secondary bindings for keyboard and mouse control, an adaptive mode that allows players to combine keyboard and controller inputs, and more. Part II Remastered on PC will feature full gamepad support, while DualSense controllers are supported and feature full haptic feedback5.</p><p>As our team and partners have been hard at work on this version, we’ll also be introducing a host of bug fixes and various improvements to offer as smooth a play experience as possible.</p><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> on PC offers a wide range of graphics settings and presets, to ensure the best possible experience on hardware ranging from high-end PCs to handheld gaming devices. Below you’ll find an overview of recommended specifications for a variety of graphics presets.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/TLoU2_03-20-25_005.jpg"></a></figure></div><p><em>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</em> first launched for PlayStation 5 on January 19, 2024.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic Dream Team ‘Shadow Levels’ update now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/sonic-dream-team-shadow-levels-update-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-dream-team-%E2%80%98shadow-levels%E2%80%99-update-now-available.1140231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/sonic-dream-team-shadow-levels-update-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New stages, new mission, and more.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,653 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> and developer <a title="Companies > HARDlight [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/hardlight">HARDlight</a> have released a free update for <a title="Genres > Action [2,583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [637 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Sonic Dream Team [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sonic-dream-team">Sonic Dream Team</a></em>, which adds three new levels playable by Shadow, a new mission, new interactable gameplay toys, and various other improvements. <span id="more-951426"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Three Brand-New Levels</strong><ul><li>Scrambled Shores, Dream Factory and Nightmare Maze each have a new Act playable only as Shadow.</li><li>Unlock them through the Shadow reward track, then explore these corrupted environments in <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,139 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a>!</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Mission</strong><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Nightmares are spreading through the Dreamworld, sprouting strange nodes of corrupted Magination.</li><li>Traverse these twisted environments, cleaning up outbreaks before exposing the nightmare’s weak points and destroying them for good!</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Interactable Gameplay Toys</strong><ul><li>Trampolines and tightrope springs help players bound over chasms and up impassible walls.</li><li>Phase platforms flicker in and out of reality – lock them into position with Chaos Control.</li><li>Sequenced jump panels let players blast over vast distances with ease!</li></ul></li><li><strong>A Handful of Small Improvements</strong><ul><li>Many players have been asking if they can replay the tutorials, so these have now been moved to their own section in the Act select. Have fun!</li><li>Fixed an issue that stopped players from listening to certain music tracks during their adventures.</li><li>New SFX for Perfect Boost and Perfect Jump.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/sonic-dream-team/march-20-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Shadow Levels Update Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sonic Dram Team - Shadow Levels Update Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fsETxI5tMjo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_951427"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side-scrolling action platformer Knuckle Jet announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/side-scrolling-action-platformer-knuckle-jet-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/side-scrolling-action-platformer-knuckle-jet-announced-for-pc.1140213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/side-scrolling-action-platformer-knuckle-jet-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From Teslagrad series developer Rain Games.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Teslagrad</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Rain Games [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rain-games">Rain Games</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Knuckle Jet [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/knuckle-jet">Knuckle Jet</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [937 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> action <a title="Genres > Platformer [637 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [22,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3199470/Knuckle_Jet/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced, but the game is described as in “early development.” <span id="more-951390"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3199470/Knuckle_Jet/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>What’s this? An off-the-wall, riveting jetpunk nose-breaking ricochet action platformer, lovingly crafted by the oddballs behind the <em>Teslagrad</em> series?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Jet-Fueled Knuckle Acrobatics</strong> – Scientifically inaccurate flight action that rewards high-speed momentum and precision. Feel free to completely ignore G-force in the name of awesomeness, and keep smashing, crashing and crushing to stay in the flow!</li><li><strong>Non-Stop <a title="Platforms > Arcade [376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">Arcade</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong> – Tons of standalone levels (How many? we don’t know yet, we’re still making them! but there will be plenty!) packed with fresh things to punch, easily navigable through a revolutionary new innovation we call a “map screen”. Utilize the environment, find rewards, and chase perfection!</li><li><strong>Hoard Equipment for the Challenges Ahead</strong> – Collect and upgrade a large array of gear that offers drastic gameplay changes. Ignore all fashion sense and pick item combinations that suit your playstyle, specialize in optimized builds for each challenge, or go for stylish matching gear—it’s all good.</li><li><strong>A Rogues Gallery of Despicable Villains</strong> – From high-rise clockwork cities to soot black forests, each biome in Motorland is under the grip of the scheming business partners of power-hungry industrialist Baron Tychoon. They’ve kidnapped a whole orphanage and put the little ragamuffins to work among the crushing pistons and spinning cogs of their robotic death machines, and it’s up to you to save the kids. Crush this cadre of conniving crooks before facing the ultimate foe!</li><li><strong>Drop Into Battle Together With a Friend</strong> – It is nice to have friends. It’s even better when they can join you in battle! Fight together across the main campaign, or beat the snot out of each other in a friendly game of Knuckleball.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the announcement teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Knuckle Jet - Announce Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sHYcNbS8IPQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>