<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:52:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition delayed to early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-nintendo-switch-2-edition-delayed-to-early-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-%E2%80%93-nintendo-switch-2-edition-delayed-to-early-2026.1353442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Physical release and Switch 2-exclusive "Gun Shooting Mode" planned.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Dragami Games [45 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/extreme/dragami-games">Dragami Games</a> has delayed <em><a title="Games > Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lollipop-chainsaw-repop">Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a></em> from its previously planned November 2025 release window to early 2026, the company announced. The additional time will enable the simultaneous release of a physical edition, as well as the implementation of a Switch 2-exclusive “Gun Shooting Mode.” <span id="more-1006931"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Notice and Apology for the Delay</strong></p><p>Initially, the game was planned for release as a digital-only title. However, following the announcement, we have carefully considered the possibility of releasing a physical edition. Thanks to the cooperation of several publishing partners, we are now preparing to release physical package editions for multiple regions.</p><p>To unify the release dates for both the digital and physical versions, we have decided to delay the launch. We sincerely apologize to everyone who has been looking forward to the game, and we kindly ask for your understanding as we work to deliver the best possible experience.</p><p><strong><a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> Edition Exclusive “Gun Shooting Mode” Revealed</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Lollipop-Chainsaw-Switch-2_11-13-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>We are also pleased to announce a brand-new mode exclusive to the <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em>—the “Gun Shooting Mode.”</p><p>In this mode, Juliet, the game’s protagonist, is equipped with her Chainsaw Blaster at all times and takes on zombie hunting using only gunfire. Each stage features “WAVE” sections where hordes of zombies surge in, allowing players to enjoy a new gameplay experience as they aim and shoot from an over-the-shoulder perspective.</p><p>Additionally, this mode incorporates ride-<a title="Genres > Rail Shooter [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/rail-shooter">rail shooter</a> elements, where players progress through stages a long a set path, offering a fresh and thrilling experience distinct from the traditional gameplay style.</p><p>This mode also supports mouse-style controls using the Nintendo Switch 2’s Joy-Con 2, providing a more intuitive gameplay experience. It is unlocked a nd becomes playable upon completing either Original Mode or RePOP Mode.</p><p><strong>Looking Ahead</strong></p><p>Dragami Games remains committed to delivering an even more fulfilling gameplay experience. We will continue to refine and prepare the title for release, and we ask fo r your continued patience and support until launch.</p></blockquote><p><em>Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2658450/LOLLIPOP_CHAINSAW_RePOP/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on September 12, 2024, followed by PlayStation 4 and Xbox One on December 2, 2024. Total sales <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-sales-top-300000">surpassed 300,000 units</a> on August 12, 2025.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-nintendo-switch-2-edition-delayed-to-early-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hi-Fi RUSH publishing transferred to KRAFTON]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/hi-fi-rush-publishing-transferred-to-krafton</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hi-fi-rush-publishing-transferred-to-krafton.1353412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Patch reflecting the change in-game scheduled for December 4.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publishing of <em><a title="Games > Hi-Fi RUSH [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hi-fi-rush">Hi-Fi RUSH</a></em> has moved from <a title="Companies > Bethesda Softworks [801 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/bethesda-softworks">Bethesda Softworks</a> to <a title="Companies > KRAFTON [72 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krafton">KRAFTON</a>, the parent company of developer <a title="Companies > Tango Gameworks [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/krafton/tango-gameworks">Tango Gameworks</a> and owner of the <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> intellectual property <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/krafton-acquires-tango-gameworks-hi-fi-rush-ip">as of August 2024</a>, the company announced. <span id="more-1006951"></span></p><p>Digital storefronts will gradually be updated to reflect KRAFTON as the publisher, and in-game elements reflecting these changes will be updated through a patch scheduled for release on December 4.</p><p><em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> is available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,281 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,793 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1817230/HiFi_RUSH/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/hi-fi-rush" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/hi-fi-rush/9nftc552k3gj" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>.</p><p>Get the full <a href="https://support.krafton.com/hc/en-us/articles/52410315858201--Notice-Change-in-Service-Operator-for-Hi-Fi-RUSH" target="_blank">announcement</a> and <a href="https://support.krafton.com/hc/en-us/articles/52369347459737-Hi-Fi-RUSH-Service-Transfer-to-KRAFTON" target="_blank">FAQ</a> below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Notice of Change in Service Operator</strong></p><p>Dear <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> fans,</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>We would like to inform you that the service operator of <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> will be changing from Bethesda Softworks to KRAFTON. This transition will begin on November 14, 2025, at 9:00 a.m. (KST).</p><ol><li><strong>Details and Schedule of the Transition</strong><ul><li><strong>Start of Service Transition</strong> – Starting from November 14, 2025, at 9:00 a.m. (KST), the official service operation of <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> will be transferred to KRAFTON. Accordingly, store page contents (such as images, videos, and descriptions) will gradually be updated to reflect KRAFTON ownership.</li><li><strong>In-Game Update Schedule</strong> – In-game elements reflecting this change will be updated through a patch scheduled for December 4, 2025, at 11:00 a.m. (KST). Please note that this transition will not affect gameplay content, and you will be able to continue enjoying Hi-Fi RUSH just as before.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Possible Issues During the Transition</strong><ul><li>Until the scheduled patch is applied, the Bethesda.net connection feature within the game will be disabled, which may result in certain error messages being displayed. Other unexpected issues may also occur during this period. We kindly ask for your understanding, and if you encounter any problems, please contact KRAFTON Customer Support for prompt assistance.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Player Data</strong><ul><li>Please rest assured that this transition will not affect your save data, game progress, achievements, or any other player information. You can continue playing <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> without interruption.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Contact Information</strong><ul><li>If you experience any issues or have questions related to the game, please reach out to KRAFTON’s customer support.</li></ul></li></ol><p>KRAFTON is committed to providing a smooth transition and continuing to deliver an enjoyable <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> experience to all players.</p><p>Thank you for your continued support.</p><p><strong>Frequently Asked <a title="Companies > Question [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/question">Question</a>s</strong></p><ol><li><strong>Will my existing game data be retained after the transfer?</strong><ul><li>Yes. All save data, purchases, downloadable content, and achievements will remain intact.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Do I need to reinstall the game?</strong><ul><li>No. You can continue using the existing installation. However, an automatic update may occur the first time you launch the game after the transfer.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Will my Steam Cloud saves remain available?</strong><ul><li>Yes. The Steam Cloud save function will remain available. Please note that it may be temporarily disabled during the transition period, so we recommend backing up your local save files as a precaution.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Will there be any changes to downloadable content or additional content?</strong><ul><li>No. All downloadable content, soundtracks, and additional content purchased through Steam will remain available after the transfer.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Where should I contact for customer support?</strong><ul><li>Before November 13, 2025: Bethesda Customer Support.</li><li>After November 14, 2025: KRAFTON Customer Support.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Will my language or region settings change?</strong><ul><li>No. Your current language (Korean, English, Japanese, etc.) and region settings will remain the same.</li></ul></li><li><strong>How will future updates and events be managed?</strong><ul><li>After the transfer, KRAFTON will serve as the publisher and handle all game updates, maintenance, and future events. Information regarding updates and events will be shared via KRAFTON’s official channels.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Where should I request a refund or billing assistance?</strong><ul><li>Payments before November 13, 2025: Bethesda Customer Support.</li><li>Payments after November 14, 2025: KRAFTON Customer Support.</li><li>Refunds for Steam purchases will continue to be handled directly by Steam Support.</li></ul></li><li><strong>I get a network error when clicking on “Bethesda.net” in the menu.</strong><ul><li>The Bethesda.net connection feature in <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> has been disabled. For more details, please refer to the announcements on the KRAFTON Support website.</li></ul></li><li><strong>What happens to my game now that Bethesda is no longer the publisher?</strong><ul><li>You can continue to play <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> on your existing Steam account without any issues.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Will my save data or achievements be affected by the publisher change?</strong><ul><li>No. Your save data and achievements will remain unaffected.</li></ul></li><li><strong>I’m playing <em>Hi-Fi RUSH</em> through Game Pass. Will this change affect me?</strong><ul><li>No. Players who own the game through Game Pass can continue to play without interruption. However, you may encounter an error message when attempting to connect to Bethesda.net within the game.</li></ul></li><li><strong>What happens if I don’t install the December 4 update?</strong><ul><li>To ensure smooth gameplay, we recommend installing the December 4 update. Failure to update may result in certain features not functioning properly.</li></ul></li></ol></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/hi-fi-rush-publishing-transferred-to-krafton]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ys X: Proud Nordics for PS5 launches February 19, 2026 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/ys-x-proud-nordics-for-ps5-launches-february-19-2026-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ys-x-proud-nordics-for-ps5-launches-february-19-2026-in-japan.1353397/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-orders live at Japanese retailers.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [761 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> will release <em><a title="Games > Ys X: Proud Nordics [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ys-x-proud-nordics">Ys X: Proud Nordics</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> on February 19, 2026 in Japan for 8,580 yen, the company announced. It <a href="https://twitter.com/nihonfalcom/status/1989211696670666778" target="_blank">will support</a> 4K resolution at 120 frames per second <span id="more-1006650"></span></p><p>First-print copies of the physical edition will include the “<em>Ys X: Proud Nordics</em> Complete Additional Songs Collection (Reprint),” a music CD featuring the 12 new tracks from the game.</p><p><em>Ys X: Proud Nordics</em> first launched for Switch 2 on July 31, 2025 in Japan, followed by both Switch 2 and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3821790/Ys_X_Proud_Nordics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on August 21, 2025 in Asia.</p><p><a title="Companies > NIS America [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-ichi-software/nis-america">NIS America</a> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/ys-x-proud-nordics-coming-west-in-early-2026-for-switch-2-pc">previously announced</a> it will release both the Switch 2 and PC versions in the west in early 2026, and Falcom <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/ys-x-proud-nordics-coming-to-ps5-in-2026">recently confirmed</a> that the western release will also include the PlayStation 5 version.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via NIS America:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> Adol and Karja’s unforgettable journey across Obelia Gulf with new quality of life improvements, then discover the new story centering around Oland Island, and the mysterious newcomers Canute and Astrid. And once you’re ready, challenge yourself in the devious, time-trial dungeon of Muspelheim, where every second counts. Your new adventure awaits!</p><p>As the definitive edition of this critically acclaimed entry in the <em>Ys</em> series, <em>Ys X: Proud Nordics</em> offers all of the fast-paced combat and enthralling narrative of the original release, with new mechanics, a high-difficulty dungeon, and a brand-new storyline seamlessly integrated throughout the game.</p><p>After a tense encounter at sea, the young red-haired adventurer Adol and the proud Norman Karja find themselves bound together by shackles of <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>, and by the looming threat of an undying horde known as the Griegr, who seek to pillage the vibrant Obelia Gulf. Aboard their ship, the Sandras, Adol and Karja gather a trusty crew of friends and allies as they go head-to-head with the Griegr in one unforgettable journey!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Adventure [2,699 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> Anew</strong> – The spectacular adventure of <em><a title="Games > Ys X: Nordics [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ys-x-nordics">Ys X: Nordics</a></em> is back and better than ever, with improved graphical performance and quality of life updates that make this the definitive way to experience <em>Ys X</em>.</li><li><strong>Isle of <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>ery</strong> – Arrive at Oland Island and take part in a brand-new adventure! With Shield Siblings Canute and Astrid by your side, dig deep into the mystery surrounding this island in a story that’s been seamlessly integrated into the original.</li><li><strong>An Ocean of Experiences Awaits</strong> – New mechanics and content abound in <em>Ys X: Proud Nordics</em>! Use the new Mana Hold ability to manipulate the world around you, try your hand at new challenges on Oland Island, and prepare yourself for Muspelheim, a timed dungeon of diabolical difficulty.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new set of web commercials below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/ys-x-proud-nordics/november-14-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Web Commercial #1</span></h2><p><iframe title="PS5『イースⅩ -Proud NORDICS-』WebCM #YSX" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1maeNYA-KJs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Web Commercial #2</span></h2><p><iframe title="PS5『イースⅩ -Proud NORDICS-』WebCM #YSX" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2chb8BatxRc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1006890"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/ys-x-proud-nordics-for-ps5-launches-february-19-2026-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shiren the Wanderer: The Mystery Dungeon of Serpentcoil Island Plus coming to iOS, Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/shiren-the-wanderer-the-mystery-dungeon-of-serpentcoil-island-plus-coming-to-ios-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shiren-the-wanderer-the-mystery-dungeon-of-serpentcoil-island-plus-coming-to-ios-android.1353385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes all paid and</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Spike Chunsoft [897 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/spike-chunsoft">Spike Chunsoft</a> will release <a title="Genres > Dungeon RPG [84 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/dungeon-rpg">dungeon RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Shiren the Wanderer: The Mystery Dungeon of Serpentcoil Island [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shiren-the-wanderer-the-mystery-dungeon-of-serpentcoil-island">Shiren the Wanderer: The Mystery Dungeon of Serpentcoil Island Plus</a></em> for iOS and Android for 3,500 yen, the company announced. A release date was not announced, and it is currently unclear whether the mobile versions are planned for release outside Japan. <span id="more-1006925"></span></p><p><em>Shiren the <a title="Games > Wanderer [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wanderer">Wanderer</a>: The <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>ery Dungeon of Serpentcoil Island</em> first launched for Switch on January 25, 2024 in Japan and February 27, 2024 worldwide, followed by PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2178480/Shiren_the_Wanderer_The_Mystery_Dungeon_of_Serpentcoil_Island/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 11, 2024.</p><p>As the “Plus” in its name implies, the iOS and Android release will include all of the free and paid downloadable content previously released for the Switch and PC versions, including the “Plus Pack” expansion.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/shiren_spchun/status/1989169287672799376" target="_blank">According to Spike Chunsoft</a>, the company has even more things to announce in commemoration of <em>Shiren the Wanderer</em>‘s 30th anniversary, which it will celebrate on December 1.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>iOS and Android Announce Trailer</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Android/iOS『不思議のダンジョン　風来のシレン６ とぐろ島探検録』アナウンストレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U4HlOdhbN6U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/shiren-the-wanderer-the-mystery-dungeon-of-serpentcoil-island-plus-coming-to-ios-android]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GigaBash DLC ‘GAMERA: Rebirth’ now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/gigabash-dlc-gamera-rebirth-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gigabash-dlc-%E2%80%98gamera-rebirth%E2%80%99-now-available.1353382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Gamera and Guiron join the fray.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > GigaBash [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gigabash">GigaBash</a></em> downloadable content “<em>GAMERA: Rebirth</em>,” which adds new playable characters Gamera and Guiron in their <em>GAMERA: Rebirth</em> incarnations, is now available, developer <a title="Companies > Passion Republic Games [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/passion-republic-games">Passion Republic Games</a> announced. <span id="more-1006528"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the downloadable content, via Passion Republic Games:</p><blockquote><p>This downloadable content adds two new playable characters Gamera and Guiron in their <em>GAMERA: Rebirth</em> incarnations into the game, featuring their own unique skillsets and moves brought to life! From the silver screen to your screens, these legends of kaiju cinema are here to fight.</p><ul><li><strong>Gamera</strong> – Gamera emerges to protect those it was made to destroy. Gamera shows that defense and offense go hand-in-hand, with plasma jets to close the distance and flaming projectiles to engage at range. Its thick armored shell ensures no attack gets through. The guardian kaiju is devastating and dangerous at any distance.</li><li><strong>Guiron</strong> – Slicing through at lightning speed, Guiron launches into the fray! With unmatched agility, Guiron wields its iconic bladed head to drive destruction into any who stand in the way. Its razor-sharp plasma Scale Shots threaten those who try to escape. This kaiju is a living weapon in name and purpose.</li></ul><p>With this latest downloadable content, alongside previous crossover characters from other legendary kaiju and Tokusatsu franchises, <em>GigaBash</em> now features a massive lineup of 26 playable characters. Will you embody the cutting edge of Guiron and strike terror upon the world? Or will you don the shell of Gamera to purify and protect your allies?</p></blockquote><p><em>GigaBash</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,281 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,307 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,793 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1546400/GigaBash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/gigabash" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/gigabash/november-13-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>DLC “<em>GAMERA: Rebirth</em>” Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GigaBash - GAMERA -Rebirth- DLC - Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e4926tlZCj4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1006531"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/gigabash-dlc-gamera-rebirth-now-available]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>