<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gematsu_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gematsu_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gematsu_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 02:37:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infinity Nikki launches December 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/infinity-nikki-launches-december-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/infinity-nikki-launches-december-5.1035384/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/infinity-nikki-launches-december-5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Cozy open-world adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [333 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> <a title="Genres > Open-World [512 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> dress-up <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,864 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Infinity Nikki [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/infinity-nikki">Infinity Nikki</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,357 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [21,695 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via client download and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/infinity-nikki-71fc64?lang=en-US" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/infinity-nikki/id6502622570" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.infoldgames.infinitynikkien" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a> on December 5, publisher <a title="Companies > Infold Games [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/papergames/infold-games">Infold Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Papergames [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/papergames">Papergames</a> announced. <span id="more-925984"></span></p><p>A pre-order-exclusive bundle is currently available to pre-order via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10004842" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a> for $9.99 / £7.99 / €9.99 / ¥1,540, which includes the following bonus content:</p><ul><li>In-game item for Resonance: “Resonite Crystal” x3</li><li>In-game currency: “Bling” x20,000</li><li><a title="Genres > Crafting [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">Crafting</a> materials for Outfits: “Thread of Purity” x50</li><li>Growth materials for Outfits: “Shiny Bubble” x10</li><li>Growth materials for Eurekas: “Shining Particle” x2</li></ul><p>Here is a <a href="https://twitter.com/InfinityNikkiEN/status/1856879641157669219" rel="noopener" target="_blank">message from producer Runhao Yao</a> on the game’s release:</p><blockquote><p>Dear Stylist,</p><p>Hello, everyone. I’m Runhao Yao, producer of the <em>Nikki</em> series. I want to personally thank each of you for your continued support and patience. Today, we’re thrilled to announce that <em>Infinity Nikki</em> will officially release across multiple platforms on December 5—a date that holds special meaning for us. Twelve years ago, on this very day, we released our first game in the beloved <em>Nikki</em> series, <em>Nikki Up2U: A Dressing Story</em>. Now, our fifth <em>Nikki</em> game is finally ready to meet you.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The first <em>Nikki</em> game was created by just a few of us, but today, the <em>Infinity Nikki</em> team has grown to more than one thousand people. Bringing this “one-of-a-kind” project to life has been challenging, with far more complexity in development and <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> than we ever anticipated. It’s been tough, but our determination carried us through. Our team has always believed in taking on the impossible, and because this was a <em>Nikki</em> project, we were even more motivated and inspired to pursue “infinity” with everything we had.</p><p>These last 12 years have been a long but precious journey for both the <em>Nikki</em> series and our team. Thank you to everyone who has played Nikki in the past, those who enjoy it now, and those who will join us in the future. If you’re planning to try <em>Infinity Nikki</em>, we hope it brings you joy.</p><p>—Runhao Yao, Producer</p></blockquote><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Infold Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Infinity Nikki</em> is the fifth installment in the beloved <em>Nikki</em> series developed by Infold Games. Utilizing Unreal Engine 5, this multi-platform, open-world dress-up adventure seamlessly blends the series’ core dress-up mechanics with open-world exploration elements. It also offers platforming, puzzle-solving, and many other gameplay elements to create a unique and rich experience.</p><p>In this game, Nikki and Momo embark on a new adventure to travel across the fantastical nations of Miraland, each with its own unique culture and environment. Players will encounter many characters and whimsical creatures while collecting stunning outfits of various styles. Some of these outfits possess magical abilities that are crucial for exploration.</p><p><strong>Whimsical Adventure with Endless Fun</strong></p><p>Harnessing the power of Whim that’s hidden within outfits, Nikki has the tools to help her overcome difficult trials. Her courage and determination know no bounds.</p><p>The Floating Outfit allows Nikki to hover gracefully, the Gliding Outfit summons a giant flower for high-altitude flights, and the Shrinking Outfit lets her sit on Momo’s head as he navigates through small spaces. These Ability Outfits open up many possibilities for adventure and thus offer an endless amount of fun!</p><p>In this vast, fantastical world, master techniques such as floating, running, and plunging to freely explore the land as well as tackle cleverly designed puzzles and levels. The joy of 3D platforming is interwoven throughout the game’s open-world exploration. Each unique scenery is vibrant and charming. Soaring paper cranes, speeding wine cellar minecarts, mysterious ghost trains—new mysteries are waiting to be unraveled!</p><p><strong>Wonderful Moments with Endless Immersion</strong></p><p>Miraland is also a fantastic place for you to relax and appreciate life.</p><p>With sunrises, sunsets, and the ever-changing weather, the creatures of Miraland have their own lives. Remember their daily routines and try to find them! Wear outfits with special abilities to fish by the river or catch bugs with a net. The game features an in-depth gathering system where the items Nikki collects become great clothing materials.</p><p>Stroll through flower fields and meadows, walk along mountain streams, and encounter merchants offering special outfits. Let your inspiration rise with the paper cranes on the streets. Use Momo’s Camera and dress Nikki up in your favorite outfits. You can choose the perfect backgrounds and frames to take pictures of her, capturing every heartwarming moment of your journey anytime, anywhere.</p><p><strong>It’s Glam Time Any Time!</strong></p><p>Thank you for being interested in <em>Infinity Nikki</em>. We look forward to meeting you in Miraland!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Infinity Nikki Official Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ja4dbzntYMY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="インフィニティニキ グローバルリリース決定 記念PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xyt8yKhZyC4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="《無限暖暖》全球公測定檔12月5日！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x6DLW7obwIA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MONGIL: STAR DIVE G-Star 2024 trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mongil-star-dive-g-star-2024-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mongil-star-dive-g-star-2024-trailer.1035372/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mongil-star-dive-g-star-2024-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Another look at the upcoming action RPG.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Netmarble [32 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble">Netmarble</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Netmarble Monster" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble/netmarble-monster">Netmarble Monster</a> have released the G-Star 2024 trailer for <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,396 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > MONGIL: STAR DIVE [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mongil-star-dive">MONGIL: STAR DIVE</a></em>. <span id="more-927534"></span></p><p><em>MONGIL: STAR DIVE</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,695 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, iOS, and Android in the second half of 2025 worldwide. If you missed it earlier, watch an additional trailer <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mongil-star-dive-ready-set-action-trailer-netmarble-action-rpg-for-pc-ios-and-android">here</a>.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>G-Star 2024 Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="[몬길: STAR DIVE] 2024 지스타 PV 공개!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n0YXqHSI25k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Idol Maker VR announced for PS VR2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/idol-maker-vr-announced-for-ps-vr2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/idol-maker-vr-announced-for-ps-vr2.1035366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/idol-maker-vr-announced-for-ps-vr2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PS VR2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on November 21.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > CFK [71 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cfk">CFK</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Yeda Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/yeda-entertainment">Yeda Entertainment</a> have announced <a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [169 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">virtual reality</a> raising <a title="Genres > Simulation [600 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Idol Maker VR" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/idol-maker-vr">Idol Maker VR</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS VR2 [217 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PlayStation VR2</a>. It will launch via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10010125" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a> on November 21 for $14.99 / 1,490 yen with English, Japanese, Korean, and Traditional Chinese language support. <span id="more-927508"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via CFK:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Here you have a girl who dreams to become a superstar. You, a rookie guardian angel, have descended to the human world in order to help a girl achieve her earnest dream.</p><p>Which paths will your choices lead her down? As her guardian angel, guide her to become the superstar everyone dreams of becoming.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Duties as Guardian Angel</strong> – You have five years until the girl becomes an adult. Through your coaching as guardian angel, raise the girl to get all eyes on her and turn her into a star. Develop her idol talents through various experiences and training methods. All sorts of futures await depending on your guidance.</li><li><strong>For the Greatest Debut</strong> – Show off the results of your persistent training at your audition! Take part in regular auditions to show the judges all the talents you’ve honed thus far. Who knows what good things lie in store if you don’t give up and keep at it?</li><li><strong>Rearing is Important Into Adulthood!</strong> – It’s good to achieve these big dreams, but it’s also important to help raise a healthy adult. Check and utilize her condition stats to balance training and a healthy lifestyle. Create a systematic development plan for the girl’s future.</li></ul></blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/idol-maker-vr/november-13-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_927516"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 2 remake for iPhone, iPad, and Mac launches December 10]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10.1035267/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free to try, with an in-app purchase to unlock the full game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The iPhone, iPad, and Mac versions of the <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil 2 (2019) [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-2-2019">Resident Evil 2</a></em> remake will launch via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/resident-evil-2/id1640632432" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a> on December 10, <a title="Companies > Capcom [2,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> announced. It will be compatible with all iPhone 16 models, iPhone 15 Pro models, and every iPad and Mac with the M1 chip or later. <span id="more-927482"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>Players are invited to try a portion of the gripping story with a free download before purchasing the full experience. <em>Resident Evil 2</em> includes support for Universal Purchase and cross-progression, enabling players to enjoy Leon and Claire’s journey through Raccoon City across iPhone, iPad, and Mac and transfer save data between devices.</p><p><em>Resident Evil 2</em> on iPhone and iPad includes enhanced controls along with a new Auto Fire feature, giving players the option to automatically fire weapons after aiming at enemies for a short time. The title also supports a range of compatible controllers on iPhone, iPad, and Mac.</p></blockquote><p>The <em>Resident Evil 2</em> remake is currently available for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/883710/Resident_Evil_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, as well as for Switch via cloud streaming.</p><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/resident-evil-2-2019/november-13-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_927484"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>