<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:38:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Console Exclusive Stalker 2 Is Set to Leave Game Pass in November and Some Subscribers Do Not Like That One Bit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-console-exclusive-stalker-2-is-set-to-leave-game-pass-in-november-and-some-subscribers-do-not-like-that-one-bit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-console-exclusive-stalker-2-is-set-to-leave-game-pass-in-november-and-some-subscribers-do-not-like-that-one-bit.1341937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft has confirmed the next batch of games set to leave Xbox Game Pass, and one in particular has caused a degree of frustration with subscribers: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl">Stalker 2</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC Game World’s Stalker 2 launched as an Xbox console exclusive last year alongside backing from Microsoft. While it is not an Xbox Game Studios-published video game, Microsoft played a key role in its marketing ahead of its much-delayed release date in November 2024. It even worked with the Ukrainian studio on a 90-minute documentary that revealed the difficulty the developers faced building the game amid Russia’s full-scale invasion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As confirmed by the Xbox app, Stalker 2 is set to leave Game Pass on November 16, 2025, alongside four other games detailed below.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/03/screenshot-2025-11-03-093646-1762165019350.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Stalker 2 is set to leave Game Pass this month.</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Games set to leave Xbox Game Pass on November 16, 2025:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl">Stalker 2</a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/football-manager-2024">Football Manager 2024</a> / <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/football-manager-2024-console">Football Manager 2024 Console</a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blacksmith-master">Blacksmith Master</a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/frostpunk">Frostpunk</a></li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/spirittea">Spirittea</a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s Stalker 2’s exit that has caused the most kerfuffle, with some Game Pass subscribers criticizing the move a year after launch, and just ahead of the game’s release on PlayStation 5 on November 20.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Microsoft backed GSC through all the delays and even the invasion, so it’s surprising they weren’t able to secure a better deal,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/stalker/comments/1omgg67/stalker_2_is_about_to_leave_game_pass/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said redditor JBishie</a>. “I think it’s a matter of principle: the game was incomplete at launch and is only now starting to resemble a finished product, yet it’s being removed from the service just as the 1.7 update approaches, and with the PS5 release coming up, the timing looks especially poor.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, the fact Stalker 2 launched first on Xbox and PC with quite a few problems, which are only now ironed out in time for the PS5 launch, is being highlighted by those who believe the game should remain on Game Pass for a while longer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's been a year, which is a pretty standard time for non MiS games,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/stalker/comments/1omgg67/comment/nmpb4mf/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said VickyCriesALot</a>. “I'm not sure why this is such a shock to people like it's unprecedented. Lmao.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Because the game just got to a decent state in that year's time?” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/stalker/comments/1omgg67/comment/nmpf7xt/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">countered davepars77</a>. “It’s going to take another year to get everything sorted, not even talking about DLC yet. It's been in early access not a finished product so now’s a great time to rip it off the service.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I think it’s a really bad precedent that a game stays shorter in Game Pass than we had to wait for it to launch, beyond waiting MONTHS to become properly playable patch after patch,” <a href="https://x.com/ZakkenKloot/status/1984925333204689052" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">complained X / Twitter user @ZakkenKloot</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's bad that Stalker is going,” <a href="https://x.com/Matty_Cs_World/status/1984936078235598902" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">added @Matty_Cs_World</a>. “It was good but basically released very buggy. I don't like that a premium subscription is just used as a beta testing area for devs. I did want to go back to the game. But I guess that ship has sailed.”</p><div id="xbox-games-series-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Xbox Games Series Tier List</h3><h3>Xbox Games Series Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“Xbox has to stop funding unfinished early access games essentially for Game Pass day one titles,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1omxb7y/xbox_has_to_stop_funding_unfinished_early_access/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said Minute-Use-8489</a>. “Two games that come to mind Stalker 2 &amp; Payday 3 came out very unfinished and took a year for them to fix and update each game than once their good to play they get removed from Game Pass feels like a scam to the subscribers imo.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting most of the games on this list are available with a discount of at least 20% until they leave Xbox Game Pass in early November.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It doesn’t help that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cancellations-anger-and-frantic-subscription-stacking-the-internet-reacts-to-microsofts-xbox-game-pass-price-hike">Microsoft recently sparked a significant backlash by hiking the price of Game Pass</a>. In the case of Ultimate, it went up a whopping 50% to $29.99 a month. That amounts to an extra $120 a year. To justify the price hike, Microsoft upped the number of day one releases per year to 75, and added Fortnite Crew and Ubisoft+ Classics for the first time ever. There were also upgrades to Xbox Cloud Gaming streaming quality.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Stalker 2 on PS5, it launches on Sony’s console with full support for the DualSense controller’s features, including haptic feedback and adaptive triggers. Further technical enhancements for the PS5 Pro are also in development.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-console-exclusive-stalker-2-is-set-to-leave-game-pass-in-november-and-some-subscribers-do-not-like-that-one-bit]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>