<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 06:59:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Awesome Board Game and LEGO Mash Up Is Steeply Discounted for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-awesome-board-game-and-lego-mash-up-is-steeply-discounted-for-prime-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-awesome-board-game-and-lego-mash-up-is-steeply-discounted-for-prime-day.1240047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next" tabindex="-1"><header></header><main data-cy="page-main-content" id="main-content"><div data-cy="commerce-disclosure-container"><p>If you buy through our links, IGN may earn an affiliate commission.</p><!-- --> <p><a data-cy="terms-of-use-link" href="https://www.ziffdavis.com/terms-of-use#endorsement">Learn more</a>.</p></div><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This deal is bananas. </h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Prime Day has no shortage of great deals on both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-lego-set-deals-for-prime-day-2025">LEGO sets</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-game-deals-prime-day-2025">popular board games</a>. But what if I told you you can get both in one? Monkey Palace: A LEGO Board Game is currently discounted down to $14.99, which is a nice 63% off the original price of $39.99. This is also its lowest price we've seen in the last 30 days on this tabletop mash up.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Monkey Palace: A LEGO Board Deal for Prime Day</h2><div catalogid="d2d1b785-5837-4d9e-a198-87e12f294a3b" id="224866"><div id="224866" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monkey Palace: A LEGO Board Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Monkey Palace is a hybrid LEGO set/board game for two to four players, ages 10+. In it, each player has to work together to rebuild the titular Monkey Palace using LEGO bricks. You'll earn Banana Points by placing certain bricks of a specific color onto other color-distinguished spaces, which will then determine the amount of Banana Points you receive. Once all of the bricks are used and the Monkey Palace is complete, the game is over. Then, players add up their Banana Points, and the player with the most wins the game. It's pretty straightforward, but its simplicity makes it a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-family-board-games">good option for family game night</a> or for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-kids">kids new to board games</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The way the game is designed, no two sessions will have the same Palace build outcome, so there's plenty of replayability potential and avenues to find new strategies. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Prime Day Board Game Deals</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The board game selection for Prime Day isn't bad. You can find some childhood classics like Guess Who? and even some <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-based-on-video-games">board games based on video games</a>, like Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City. The board game discounts are steep enough, with some being offered for up to 52% off. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Great Deals on LEGO Sets During Prime Day</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Some of the coolest LEGO sets are discounted, as well. You can save anywhere between 20% and 54% on certain sets, and if you're a big <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-star-wars-sets-on-sale-for-prime-day-2025">LEGO Star Wars fan</a>, plenty of their 25th Anniversary sets are included, such as the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazons-best-lego-deal-for-prime-day-is-this-massive-star-wars-ship">Imperial Star Destroyer</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Myles Obenza is a freelance writer for IGN. Follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mylesobenza.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mylesobenza.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 10, 2025 4:45 am</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></main></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-awesome-board-game-and-lego-mash-up-is-steeply-discounted-for-prime-day]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Azul Board Game Deal for Prime Day Is an Easy Recommendation to Make]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-azul-board-game-deal-for-prime-day-is-an-easy-recommendation-to-make</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-azul-board-game-deal-for-prime-day-is-an-easy-recommendation-to-make.1239993/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Laying tiles has never been so fun.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the standouts during this year’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-2025-sale-top-deals-live">Prime Day</a> sale has been board games, and one of the best is Azul from Asmodee, on sale for $20.99 and is part of the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBg28E?object_uuid=25a0111e-bcb7-4d29-9aec-24485ce7a31b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">limited time offer</a> where if you spend $40 you save $10 off your order too. With colorful mosaic tiles, 2-4 players take turns picking out designs that will fill out spaces on their board to earn points. It’s one of those games that fits the “easy to learn, tough to master” category, and is one of my favorite games to introduce to folks that are both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-beginner-board-games">new to the board gaming hobby</a> and also to those that already have a sizable collection themselves. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Azul Board Game Deals at Amazon Today</h2><div id="224829" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cf181ccb-1e1a-4197-b57b-21ac5b94279d"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Azul</h3></p></div><div id="224830" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cf181ccb-1e1a-4197-b57b-21ac5b94279d"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Azul Stained Glass of Sintra</h3></p></div><div catalogid="cf181ccb-1e1a-4197-b57b-21ac5b94279d" id="224831"><div id="224831" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Azul Summer Pavilion</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">With its colorful plastic tiles, playing a game of Azul looks as lovely looking as it is to play, and thanks to its alternate versions (also on sale), you can pick whatever theme speaks more to you and your game group. Is stained glass more your style? Then maybe Azul: Stained Glass of Sintra and its window panes may be for you, or Azul: Summer Pavilion if bright summery tiles are more alluring to you. Each version may have slight tweaks or additional mechanics to it, but the core game system is similar regardless of the version you get.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Summertime makes me think of spending time outside with friends and family, whether at the park, a beach, or enjoying a cold one at a local brewery, and Azul is the perfect game to take with you and set up on a warm summer evening. Set up takes minutes, and games only take about half an hour. Look no further than Azul if you’re looking for a chill new game to play with your friends.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a complete look at what different versions and expansions there are, make sure to check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/azul-board-game-buying-guide">Azul buying guide</a> for all that info. We've also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/azul-board-game-review">reviewed this board game</a> if you want a more in-depth look at gameplay.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Board Game Deals</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"> For more board game deals, check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-game-deals-prime-day-2025">full list of Prime Day Board Game sales</a> or dive into some of the top picks below</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em> Scott White is a freelance contributor to IGN, assisting with tabletop games and guide coverage. Follow him on </em><a href="https://x.com/ProfessorRPG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>X/Twitter</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/professorrpg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 10, 2025 12:35 am</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-azul-board-game-deal-for-prime-day-is-an-easy-recommendation-to-make]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Has Some Irresistible Legend of Zelda Gifts in Its Prime Day Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-legend-of-zelda-merch-deals-prime-day-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-has-some-irresistible-legend-of-zelda-gifts-in-its-prime-day-sale.1239936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's dangerous to go alone, take these!</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Prime Day is still going on until this Friday, July 11, and there are countless great deals available in a wide variety of categories. There happens to be a significant amount of Legend of Zelda-related items in these sales, so I've gathered some of the best and put together a little Prime Day gift guide for that Zelda fan in your life. Amazon has everything from games, books, and apparel on sale, so Hyrule is your oyster. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If the Prime Day deals don't quite have what you're looking for, be sure to check out the <a href="https://store.ign.com/collections/the-legend-of-zelda" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store for more awesome Legend of Zelda gift ideas</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Some of the Best Legend of Zelda Gifts to Grab During Prime Day</h2><p id="video-games"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Video Games">Legend of Zelda Video Games</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, the Legend of Zelda video games are the bread and butter, and we wouldn't have any of these other snazzy gifts without them. While the discounts on these aren't as steep as I'd like, it's never a bad time to experience Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom for the first time. The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom is the highest discounted of the bunch at 15% off, and I highly recommend it if you enjoy the classic top-down 2D style like I do. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Breath of the Wild and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom/Everything_New_In_Zelda:_Tears_of_the_Kingdom_Switch_2">Tears of the Kingdom both have Nintendo Switch 2 upgrades available</a>, so if it's your first time dipping your toes into these masterpieces and you have the snazzy new handheld-hybrid console, you won't be disappointed. There are also quite a few <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-amazon-prime-day-switch-game-deals-2025">other Switch games on sale</a> if you're looking outside of Hyrule for games to play.</p><p id="books"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Books">Legend of Zelda Books</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Part of Prime Day is a buy 2, get 1 free promotion on dozens of physical media. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-books-are-heavily-discounted-for-prime-day">A handful of Zelda books are included in this at a discount</a>, so if you've had your eye on these, you can bundle and save for some great coffee table books. Of note, while the Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia is sitting at 55% off, it isn't included in the buy 2, get 1 free sale like Hyrule Historia and Art &amp; Artifacts. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then you have the Legend of Zelda manga series, covering the stories from most of the games like Twilight Princess and Ocarina of Time. Another odd selection of these is included in buy 2, get 1 free, but the box sets of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-legend-of-zelda-books-and-manga">entire library of Zelda manga</a> is still discounted for Prime Day. Check them out below.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Legend of Zelda Manga Box Sets</h3><h3 data-cy="title3">Buy 2 Legend of Zelda Books, Get 1 Free</h3><h2 data-cy="title2">The Legend of Zelda Animated Series</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">You're likely familiar with the "well excuuuuuuse me, Princess" meme at this point. It originated in the incredibly cheesy and campy animated series from the 80's. Luckily for us, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-complete-legend-of-zelda-animated-series-is-super-cheap-for-prime-day">complete series on DVD is on sale during Prime Day</a> and qualifies for the buy 2, get 1 free promotion. You can save an additional 10% off the already discounted 43% with the attached coupon. </p><div id="224816" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="c8b15a1e-0046-45e0-9af2-fe6f733c05d1"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Legend of Zelda - The Complete Series (DVD)</h3></p></div><p id="apparel"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Apparel">The Legend of Zelda Apparel</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">We all love a good graphic tee, and the Legend of Zelda selection is pretty good. There are countless styles, sizes, and colors available and discounted for Prime Day, but here are some of my favorites. The Retro Kanji Link Portrait is an awesome recreation of the classic Link design and goes with any style. These are all 30% off, so if you've been looking to upgrade your wardrobe with awesome nerdy shirts Prime Day has you covered. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Other Great The Legend of Zelda Gifts</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are countless cool gifts to pick from, it really was hard to narrow down this list without making it too extensive. Below are some more of my favorite things I'd actually get for my home office, light the heart container light and the Majora's Mask LED neon sign. The ceramic ocarina actually works and comes with a song book with music from the games, as well as an easy explainer for how to play it. These are going for between 20% to 42% off for certain items and make great additions to bookshelves, desks, what have you. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Myles Obenza is a freelance writer for IGN. Follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mylesobenza.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mylesobenza.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 9, 2025 9:18 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-legend-of-zelda-merch-deals-prime-day-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>