<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:32:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws Patch Cuts Stealth Objectives, Improves AI, and More in Huge Title Update 1.4.0]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-patch-cuts-stealth-objectives-improves-ai-and-more-in-huge-title-update-140</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-patch-cuts-stealth-objectives-improves-ai-and-more-in-huge-title-update-1-4-0.1041603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-patch-cuts-stealth-objectives-improves-ai-and-more-in-huge-title-update-140<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft has released the huge and highly anticipated Title Update 1.4.0 for Star Wars Outlaws on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC, which, perhaps most notably, cuts stealth requirements from almost the entire game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/star-wars/outlaws/news-updates/1sXCR6GmB3Kn7OrKiy8DPO/star-wars-outlaws-title-update-140" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post</a> detailed the patch notes, which are available below, and confirmed the removal of forced stealth (meaning players will no longer have to return to a checkpoint when triggering "do not raise the alarm" or "do not get caught" objectives) alongside improvements to enemy AI and detection, facial expressions and animations, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This Title Update brings changes to combat and stealth allowing for greater player choice, the ability to now keep pick-up weapons in more situations, visual options to allow for a sharper image and much more to improve your journey across the galaxy," Ubisoft said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It doesn't address the issues affecting some PC players who updated to Windows 11 24H2, however, but Ubisoft said it is "working hard to deploy a permanent fix" as soon as possible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Star Wars Outlaws creative director Drew Rechner promised to make big changes to "elevate the game experience to better meet" player expectations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sentiments such as these are often seen in the wake of disastrous game launches but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">Star Wars Outlaws debuted to positive reviews</a>. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-admits-star-wars-outlaws-underperformed">Poor sales shook a struggling Ubisoft</a>, however, and it is now working to improve the game ahead of what it hopes will be a sales bump alongside <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-unveils-roadmap-leading-up-to-november-steam-release">its Steam launch</a> and the holiday period.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Star Wars Outlaws Title Update 1.4.0 Patch Notes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>General Gameplay</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where players could get stuck by not being able to take off using the Trailblazer after certain missions</li><li>Kay now holsters a two-handed weapon in more situations such as when climbing, grappling or using the speeder</li><li>Improved AI speeder usage</li><li>Improved enemy detection</li><li>Improved enemy tactical decision-making in combat to encourage more active management of their positioning</li><li>Decreased enemy damage per shot while increasing the damage cadence increase over time</li><li>Improved detection signs and feedback of cameras</li><li>Player state (crouched, standing) is now kept after traversal actions</li><li>Fixed an issue where only one NPC would be alerted when whistling</li><li>Fixed an issue where the player could remain undetected in high grass while performing aggressive actions</li><li>Enabled the use of combat in parts of syndicate districts</li><li>Added weak points to various enemies</li><li>Adjusted weapon aiming (spread, recoil, etc.) to allow for more precision and management</li><li>Updated weapon damage values for Kay for all weapons</li><li>Increased headshot damage when hitting enemies</li><li>Improved blaster module usage (Ion and Power)</li><li>Removed player blast damage from the Power module</li><li>Added enemy stagger to explosions</li><li>Added body part-specific death animations to improve combat satisfaction</li><li>Improved NPC cover usage during combat</li><li>Fixed an issue where Kay would put away the holotracker when crouching</li><li>Fixed an issue where hostile NPCs were sometimes marked as friendly and could not be damaged by blaster fire</li><li>Adjusted jumping to give more control in the air of where you will land</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UI, HUD and Settings</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added visual indication of when an NPC starts detecting the player</li><li>Added text highlighting which blaster module should be used when aiming at heavy guards, droids and cameras</li><li>Prompt to ping the tracked objective is now more prominent and affected by HUD visibility settings</li><li>Added icons to environmental objects that require unlockable abilities</li><li>Improved Nix quick action icon by highlighting button when having an active target</li><li>Made it clearer whether a takedown could trigger combat</li><li>Added NPC tags above their heads (works with existing colorblindness settings)<ul data-cy="list"><li>White - Neutral</li><li>Orange - Aware</li><li>Red - In Combat</li></ul></li><li>Adjusted Adrenaline Rush cost based on difficulty<ul data-cy="list"><li>Story mode - 100% (unchanged)</li><li>Normal - 110%</li><li>Challenging/Hard -150%</li></ul></li><li>Improved wanted system messaging and display</li><li>Fixed an issue where some gear effect icons were not showing correctly</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Audio</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved enemy dialogue when they are going in and out of cover</li><li>Fixed an issue where sound wouldn't play through the DualSense controller on PS5</li><li>Fixed an issue where arcade games would be missing music after starting a new game</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cinematics</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added facial animations to gameplay dialogue scenes and vendors</li><li>Improved animations and visuals of some dialogue scenes</li><li>Fixed an issue where ND-5 would be missing from the passenger seat when landing/taking off from Renpalli or Achra stations</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Camera</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved camera when shooting, aiming down sights, and moving aim</li><li>Improved cover camera, including the ability to manually shoulder swap when aiming</li><li>Improved the camera by showcasing a better view of each shop when interacting with a vendor</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Worlds, Fauna, and Flora</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue with destructible flora</li><li>Fixed an issue where the visual effects created by waterfalls were broken</li><li>Increased the distance at which lights can be seen in the world</li><li>Improved the visuals of some grass textures and mud, especially at distance</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Photo Mode</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>A new clean lens has been added</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Accessibility</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added a Custom Controller Preset to allow remapping of individual buttons. You can choose separate sets of button swaps for Kay, the speeder, and the Trailblazer.</li><li>Added a new 'strong' aim assist setting</li><li>Added a new auto-transfer option for climbing, which lets you automatically hop between climbable objects by moving towards them instead of having to press a button</li><li>Added setting to change how large and clear the effect showing the security camera detection area is</li><li>Sound effects slider split into two separate sliders, for gameplay sounds and background sounds</li><li>Faster menu narration, settings now go up to 400% speed.</li><li>Menu narration now reads lockpicking and slicing minigames, objective hints, and which Sabacc card is currently highlighted in your hand and while drawing/discarding</li><li>Option added to toggle the Cinematic Lens (distortion, fringing, and vignetting effects) off for gameplay</li><li>'Fill screen' is now the default screen ratio, meaning larger text size for the initial menus before you reach the ratio setting screen</li><li>'Remove all' hold input for map markers added to 'change holds to presses' setting</li><li>Descriptions of accessibility settings reworded for improved clarity</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where destroying a ship by ramming it would not count towards the 'Never tell me the odds' trophy/achievement</li><li>Fixed an issue where the 'Shoot First' achievement/trophy and 'The Better' ability could not be unlocked at the same time</li><li>Fixed an issue where defeating Death Troopers during certain missions would not count towards the 'Defying Death' Ubisoft Connect Challenge</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>MAIN &amp; SIDE QUESTS</strong> <em>(beware of spoilers)</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Toshara</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Rejected<ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where Kay can't listen at the bar to progress the intel quest</li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Tatooine</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The Veteran<ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the quest line would not start if travelling to Akiva before the dialogue finishes</li></ul></li><li>Partners<ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the cinematic would not trigger if using Adrenaline Rush as the Rancor hits the hangar doors</li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Akiva</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Revelator<ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where ND-5 could spot Kay when going from crouched to standing while on a steam vent</li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Bug Reporter</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">We're pleased to announce that reporting issues will now be easier- introducing the <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/star-wars/outlaws/bug-reporter/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Star Wars™ Outlaws Bug Reporter</a>. This website functions the same way as on other Ubisoft titles; it's your direct channel to view issues reported by other players and to directly report any issues you encounter to our team. We will actively update this board so you will be aware when issues are being investigated, and when fixes and improvements will be rolled out in an upcoming update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CD Projekt Rules Out Cyberpunk 2077 PS5 Pro Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-rules-out-cyberpunk-2077-ps5-pro-patch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cd-projekt-rules-out-cyberpunk-2077-ps5-pro-patch.1041600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-rules-out-cyberpunk-2077-ps5-pro-patch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">CD Projekt has ruled out a PlayStation 5 Pro patch for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://x.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1859151714747552122" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a> responding to a fan calling for an update to take advantage of Sony’s $700 mid-gen console upgrade, CD Projekt delivered the news: “We currently have no plans for PS5 Pro patch.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some Cyberpunk 2077 fans had hoped to see the four-year-old adventure updated for PS5 Pro given it’s a graphics showcase and has endured high-profile performance issues. But it seems CD Projekt is focused on other things.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">What other things? It has Witcher 4 (the first game in a new trilogy set in The Witcher universe), the sequel to Cyberpunk, a new multiplayer The Witcher game, and a brand new original IP in the works, on top of supervising a remake of the original The Witcher. That’s a lot!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's worth bearing in mind that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-xbox-series-xs-next-gen-update-game-pass-release-date">Cyberpunk 2077 received a free next-gen update</a> for both PS5 and Xbox Series X in February 2022. This update let PS5 and Xbox Series X players select a performance mode that targets 60 frames per second and 4K resolution, or a ray tracing mode that runs at 30fps.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PS5 Pro, meanwhile, has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-callisto-protocol-gets-mammoth-8k-30fps-update-for-ps5-pro">boosted a number existing PS4 and PS5 games in impressive ways</a>, but has caused unexpected issues for others, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-star-wars-jedi-survivor-among-several-games-with-ps5-pro-issues">such as the Silent Hill 2 remake and Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 Launches Big on Steam as Dev Promises Fixes for ‘Rough Edges’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-launches-big-on-steam-as-dev-promises-fixes-for-rough-edges</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/s-t-a-l-k-e-r-2-launches-big-on-steam-as-dev-promises-fixes-for-%E2%80%98rough-edges%E2%80%99.1041531/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-launches-big-on-steam-as-dev-promises-fixes-for-rough-edges<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We literally haven't released anything of this scale before."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl">S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a> has enjoyed a big launch on Steam, becoming one of the most-played games on Valve’s platform on release day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ukrainian developer GSC Game World’s post-apocalyptic horror shooter saw a peak concurrent player count of 113,587 on Steam, a number that was enough to place S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 in the platform’s top 10 most-played games list. That dwarfs the Steam peak concurrent player count of all the other S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games, including 2007’s S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 also launched on Xbox Series X and S and straight into Game Pass, so its combined peak concurrent player count will be much larger than what we’ve seen on Steam (Microsoft does not make its player numbers public). The expectation is that its player count will continue to grow as S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 heads into its first weekend on sale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also has a ‘very positive’ user review rating on Steam, despite suffering from various bugs detailed in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-review">IGN’s S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl Review in Progress</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC Game World has told fans it plans to address these bugs with a series of patches. “S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 is a massive game,” the developer said. “We understand that in such a game, there may still be rough edges: we literally haven't released anything of this scale before. We’re absolutely committed to being here, monitoring your feedback, and quickly fixing any issues that need our attention.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“In the first days after release, we’ll be working with hotfixes, rolling them out as precisely as possible, but as frequently as we can. Then, we’ll switch to larger updates that include constant improvements.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Free in-game content is also coming to the game. Expect more on that when GSC Game World shares its roadmap later in December. “We have big plans for the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. universe,” the developer added. “In a way, today is both a return and the beginning of a grand new journey.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help you survive in the Zone, we've got a list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks">Essential Stalker 2 Tips and Tricks</a>, plus a guide on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Things_to_Do_First_in_Stalker_2">Things to Do First in Stalker 2</a> to help you through the early game, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Things_Stalker_2_Doesn%27t_Tell_You">Things Stalker 2 Doesn't Tell You</a> - everything we wish we knew before we started playing. Save time scouring the wasteland with our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Artifacts_List_and_Locations">Artifacts checklist and locations guide</a>, and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Stash_Locations_and_Rewards">Stash location</a> we've found so far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 has suffered a number of understandable delays, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-delayed-again-this-time-by-2-months-so-the-dev-can-fix-more-unexpected-anomalies"><u>most recently in July</u></a> when the game was due out in September. GSC Game World said at the time that the extra two months would give the developers the chance to fix "unexpected anomalies," aka bugs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC Game World has also been vocal about the challenges the studio faced getting S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2 up to scratch after a mixed reaction to its debut public showing last year. At gamescom 2023, GSC Game World addressed what some had called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-devs-discuss-imperfect-gamescom-2023-demo-address-downgrade-debate"><u>a “downgrade” sparked by S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2’s then latest gameplay trailer</u></a>. At the time, GSC Game World told IGN it was still targeting a visual quality and level of polish suggested by S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2’s eye-catching 2021 trailer despite <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-stalker-2-developers-say-the-war-in-ukraine-russian-hackers-and-death-threats-wont-break-them"><u>the horrendous conditions suffered by the staff amid the war with Russia</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>