<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Payday 3 Players React to Developer Starbreeze Saying It Will Make a ‘Significantly Lower Level of Investment’ in Year 2 Content]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-players-react-to-developer-starbreeze-saying-it-will-make-a-significantly-lower-level-of-investment-in-year-2-content</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/payday-3-players-react-to-developer-starbreeze-saying-it-will-make-a-%E2%80%98significantly-lower-level-of-investment%E2%80%99-in-year-2-content.1038294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-players-react-to-developer-starbreeze-saying-it-will-make-a-significantly-lower-level-of-investment-in-year-2-content<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/payday-3">Payday 3</a> developer Starbreeze has sparked backlash after confirming plans to make a “significantly lower level of investment” in the game’s second year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Starbreeze’s struggle with Payday 3 after last year’s disastrous launch is well-documented, but its recent series of year one anniversary updates were well-received by players who had hoped for similarly significant updates during the co-op shooter's second year. Indeed, Payday 3’s recent Steam user reviews are on ‘mostly positive’, with all reviews on ‘mixed.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, that goodwill may now be under threat after comments from Starbreeze acting CEO Mats Juhl in a <a href="https://www.inderes.dk/releases/starbreeze-ab-publ-interim-report-january-september-2024" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">financial report</a> caused some Payday 3 players to express concern that the studio was now prioritizing its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-developer-starbreeze-announces-dungeons-dragons-co-op-multiplayer-game">Dungeons &amp; Dragons game</a> instead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The backlash revolves around Juhl’s comment on Payday 3’s level of investment for year two versus year one. It is below, reproduced in its entirety.</p><blockquote>During the quarter, both the third and fourth DLCs for Payday 3 – “Chapter 3: Houston Breakout” and “Chapter 4: Fear &amp; Greed” were released. In conjunction with both launches, a lot of free content was also released to all players, including a new free heist. Both DLCs received a very positive reception from the player base and the game's rating on Steam, among others, has taken significant steps upwards. The game's MAU (monthly active players) is holding steady considering that we in September left Xbox GamePass. The level of investment during Payday 3's first year on the market, both through launched DLCs and "Operation Medic Bag", has been at an elevated level. Ahead of year two, we are confident in being able to continue delivering amounts of value to our players with a significantly lower level of investment.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">That last line (“significantly lower level of investment”) is the one causing all the damage here, and players are blaming it on Starbreeze shifting focus onto Project Baxter, its in-development Dungeons &amp; Dragons game. Elsewhere in the financial report, Juhl said production on Project Baxter had ramped up (along with the payment of licensing fees to Wizards of the Coast), and that as Payday 3’s game-saving Operation Medic Bag updates ramp down, the game will enter year two “with a smaller team focused on continuously updating the game with new content.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Disgruntled players have taken to Steam reviews to let their feelings about this be known. “Dead game,” reads one negative review, “like this time for real.” “Dropping this game as soon as it started to show promise is insane,” said another. “Significantly lower,” another review reads. "I've tried defending this game for so long, but it is really frustrating seeing the company executives kill this game before it has a chance to fully recover just to fund their next project that will more than likely flop, just like Payday 3," another reviewer said. "Save your money and the headache; Payday 3's future is genuinely grim."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a similar outcry over on the Payday subreddit, where fans are already hitting out at Starbreeze and Project Baxter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite this, Starbreeze sounds like it still believes in Payday 3, even if some of its players do not. “Starbreeze remains financially strong, with a healthy balance sheet almost free of debt and a cash position to execute our strategy,” Juhl said. “Sales of Payday 3 still have great potential to improve, which is offset somewhat by continued relatively stable sales of Payday 2 and third-party publishing of, among other things, Roboquest. During the same period last year, we booked the revenue attributable to Payday 3's launch, which makes the revenue in the comparison period uniquely high.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of Payday 2, significantly more people are playing that game on Steam (27,553 24 hour peak) than Payday 3 (1,314 24 hour peak), despite the former being over a decade old. In September, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-director-steps-down-after-disastrous-first-year">Payday 3 director Miodrag Kovačević stepped down to work as a designer instead</a>. Lead producer Andreas Penninger and global brand director Almir Listo were put in place to act as the "creative force" behind the game "in the interim."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Starbreeze is still hiring for Project Baxter, meanwhile, as work on the game “continues at full speed.” “Internally, we have weekly playtests of Baxter, and active discussions with a number of industry-leading players regarding potential collaborations around Baxter's development and launch,” Juhl said. Starbreeze said it has 191 total employees, most of which are based at its head office in Stockholm, Sweden.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Siege Finally Gets Full Crossplay With Year 9 Season 4 — and Ubisoft Has a Plan to Protect Console Players From PC Cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rainbow-six-siege-finally-gets-full-crossplay-with-year-9-season-4-and-ubisoft-has-a-plan-to-protect-console-players-from-pc-cheaters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rainbow-six-siege-finally-gets-full-crossplay-with-year-9-season-4-%E2%80%94-and-ubisoft-has-a-plan-to-protect-console-players-from-pc-cheaters.1038201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/rainbow-six-siege-finally-gets-full-crossplay-with-year-9-season-4-and-ubisoft-has-a-plan-to-protect-console-players-from-pc-cheaters<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rainbow Six Siege’s next update finally adds PC and console crossplay to the competitive multiplayer shooter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Year 9 Season 4 update, dubbed Operation Collision Point, launches on December 3 and also makes changes to anticheat, remasters an Operator, adds Siege Cup, and tweaks gameplay balance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite approaching its ninth birthday, Siege remains one of the most popular competitive multiplayer games across PC and console, and is a mainstay of Steam’s top 100 most-played games. For embattled publisher Ubisoft, it is a reliable earner <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisofts-founding-guillemot-family-and-tencent-reportedly-considering-taking-the-company-private-amid-high-profile-flops-and-share-price-collapse">at a time when new releases such as Star Wars: Outlaws and Call of Duty competitor XDefiant have struggled</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The addition of crossplay means players will be able to play with friends from other platforms seamlessly, with console players able to join the PC player pool. Squads including a PC player will be automatically moved to the PC-matchmaking pool. However, PC players will not have the option to join the console matchmaking pool. Console players who play Ranked playlists with crossplay active will maintain a PC rank that is separate from their console rank, Ubisoft explained.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The anticheat updates include improved cheater detection to ensure fairness, Ubisoft said. With the arrival of PC and console crossplay, players with a Mousetrap Penalty will be forced into the PC matchmaking pool for 90 days. If crossplay is turned off, these players will be unable to join matchmaking until the option is turned back on. Additionally, matches with a detected cheater will be automatically canceled with no impact on MMR. “These changes reflect Rainbow Six Siege’s ongoing commitment to player protection,” Ubisoft added.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Related, Ubisoft has overhauled the Reputation Center to provide a clearer overview of how different actions affect player standing and thresholds for receiving warnings or penalties. Account-related information such as rank, reputation, and match replays will be concentrated in the new Career hub, with account stats coming soon, Ubisoft clarified.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Blackbeard now has an upgraded Adaptable Shield gadget, and the Siege Cup beta is available to all players above Clearance Level 50. Siege Cup is Siege’s most competitive playlist, where five-player squads compete in skill-based ladder tournaments for Competitive Coins that can be used to unlock exclusive skin collections every two weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And finally, Season 4 makes changes to Ballistic Shields and balancing updates for Attacking Operators Ying and Sens. The number of bullets needed to suppress Shield Operators have been reduced to add value to suppressive fire and improve Shield Operator counterplay. This allows suppression to occur sooner and last for a longer duration, Ubisoft explained. Operators will not take damage from melee attacks while shielded, but guard break intensity from melee attacks will remain the same. Ying’s rush has been changed "to encourage more precise gameplay" in addition to Sens’ R.O.U. Projectors update "that allows for more flexible and creative play."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life 2 Hits Highest Steam Concurrent Player Count Since Records Began]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-2-hits-highest-steam-concurrent-player-count-since-records-began</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-2-hits-highest-steam-concurrent-player-count-since-records-began.1038195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-2-hits-highest-steam-concurrent-player-count-since-records-began<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It helps that it’s free, man.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-2-20th-anniversary-update-includes-developer-commentary-improved-graphics-and-a-2-hour-documentary">Half-Life 2’s 20th Anniversary update</a> has sparked a new concurrent player count record on Steam.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Valve’s influential shooter hit a peak concurrent player count of 64,222 over the weekend after the studio released an upgraded experience with new features alongside a documentary <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/never-before-seen-half-life-2-episode-3-gameplay-footage-and-ice-gun-revealed-in-new-documentary">that revealed gameplay of the canceled Episode 3</a>. It helps that Half-Life 2 also went ‘free to keep’ until today, November 18.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/half-life-2">Half-Life 2</a> launched on November 16, 2004, a year after Steam itself. Public records for the game’s concurrent player count only begin in September 2008, according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/220/charts/#max" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SteamDB</a>, so we don’t know how many played Half-Life 2 at launch 20 years ago. But we do know that at no point since September 2008 has Half-Life 2 been as popular on Steam as it is now. Half-Life 2's previous recorded best was 16,101 in August 2021 after a community event sparked a resurgence of interest.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The anniversary update means Half-Life 2 now includes the complete Episode One and Episode Two expansions along with the base game. They’re accessible from the main menu, and you automatically advance to the next expansion after completing each one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also a new Developers Commentary for the Half-Life 2 base game, after Valve got the team back to record three-and-a-half hours of new behind-the-scenes commentary.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps most exciting is integrated Steam Workshop support, which lets players browse, install, and play user-created content for Half-Life 2 without ever leaving the game. Meanwhile, there are bug fixes and new graphics options that let players push the visual fidelity of Half-Life 2 further than was allowed in the original release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All these updates, the documentary and its associated headlines, and the ‘free to keep’ offer have combined to boost interest in all things Half-Life 2, and send thousands of players into City 17 to fight back against the Combine.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The question now is, will Valve finally follow it up with Half-Life 3?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix: 'We Will Not Cheat' With Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3's Airship]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-we-will-not-cheat-with-final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-airship</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-we-will-not-cheat-with-final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-airship.1038192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-we-will-not-cheat-with-final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-airship<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Square Enix has promised it won't "cheat" when it comes to Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3’s airship.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans of the original Final Fantasy 7 will know that the Highwind is an airship from the original Final Fantasy 7 that Cloud and the crew unlock in Act 3. It lets the part swiftly and seamlessly travel around the world, even interrupting the imposing Weapons as they potter about the map.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The airship is set to star in the third and final part of Square Enix’s Final Fantasy 7 remake trilogy, but some fans had wondered whether the original airship system would be replicated in the upcoming game, given its expanded detail and scope. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/17/05-ff7r-art-1117-2-q570dxz0p-1731880505496.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Aerith and the Highwind airship in Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth. Image credit: Square Enix.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As reported by <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/638/G063881/20241115058/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4gamer</a> and translated by <a href="https://www.siliconera.com/square-enix-will-focus-on-the-airship-for-ffvii-remake-part-3/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Siliconera</a>, producer Yoshinori Kitase and director Naoki Hamaguchi told an audience of fans at the Korean G-STAR 2024 gaming conference that the airship’s introduction in Part 3 means the world needs to be experienced from a higher perspective.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We will not cheat with the airship system (in Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3) but take the challenge head-on so that it can freely fly all over the game map,” Hamaguchi confirmed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While that will come as some reassurance to fans, questions remain. How low or high will the Highwind be able to fly over the game map? Will you be able to land and pop out at any location? Will airship travel be seamless across the entire planet, with no loading? Will Part 3 represent the game map in a different way to accommodate airship traversal?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It may be some time before we find out. In April, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-hoping-to-release-final-fantasy-7-remake-trilogys-finale-by-2027">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3’s main story was said to be finished</a>, with voice recording set to start shortly after. A 2027 release window was suggested, too (the original Final Fantasy 7 launched in 1997).</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-remake">Final Fantasy 7 Remake</a> came out in 2020, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Rebirth</a> launching in February this year. In September, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-admits-final-fantasy-16-and-7-rebirth-profits-did-not-meet-our-expectations">Square Enix made public its dissatisfaction with Final Fantasy 16 and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth’s commercial performance</a>, admitting neither game met profit expectations. Final Fantasy 16 producer Naoki Yoshida has said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-16-producer-naoki-yoshida-says-it-may-be-time-for-the-younger-generation-to-handle-final-fantasy-17"><u>it might be time for a younger generation to lead the franchise and helm Final Fantasy 17</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-ending-explained"><u>our Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth ending explained</u></a> to find out where things left off.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>