<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:31:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tony Hawk's Pro Skater Announcement Teased as Fans Spot Easter Egg in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-announcement-teased-as-fans-spot-easter-egg-in-call-of-duty-black-ops-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tony-hawks-pro-skater-announcement-teased-as-fans-spot-easter-egg-in-call-of-duty-black-ops-6.1114821/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-announcement-teased-as-fans-spot-easter-egg-in-call-of-duty-black-ops-6<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision may finally be ready to start talking about its next Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater game, and it seems to be using a sneaky <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> Easter Egg to get the conversation started.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty outlet <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1892621320598208577" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CharlieIntel</a> spotted and shared references to the publisher’s legendary skateboarding video game franchise in a peculiar place after the Black Ops 6 Season 2 Reloaded update went live today. Included with an ammo chest of new features, weapons, and more content was the return of the fan-favorite skate-themed map, Grind. The skatepark arena has been brought back mostly as fans remember it, with one exception being a giant, in-game TV screen featuring a very Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater-looking logo and a date of March 4, 2025.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Looks like a teaser for something related to Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater has been found in Black Ops 6’s Grind MP map!</p><p>Announcement on March 4. 👀 <a href="https://t.co/8efl6Qansl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/8efl6Qansl</a></p></div>— CharlieIntel (@charlieINTEL) <a href="https://twitter.com/charlieINTEL/status/1892621320598208577?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 20, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It stops short of being in-your-face but is still undeniably an eyebrow-raising reference for fans who have been on the lookout for another entry in the Pro Skater series. Rumors that another installment could soon be announced began earlier this week when fellow skater Tyshawn Jones let it slip that he would soon be featured in an upcoming Tony Hawk video game (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-skater-claims-hes-in-a-new-tony-hawk-remaster-about-to-come-out/#google_vignette" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>VGC</u></a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I’m in a Tony Hawk coming out, so that’s cool,” Jones said during a conversation on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3umK3xG7Ly4&amp;t=1s" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>The Breakfast Club podcast</u></a>. “They got a new one they remastering so that’s about to come out. I was in the last one.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was a curious comment that had fans excited, with today’s newly revealed Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater Black Ops 6 Easter Egg letting them know when they can expect to learn more. Unfortunately, there’s no telling what exactly that March date has in store.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision tried to breathe life into the franchise with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-5">Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 5</a> back in 2015 but has yet to release another new numbered entry since. However, in 2020, fans received the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2">Pro Skater 1 + 2 remakes</a> from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-developer-vicarious-visions-blizzard-entertainment">Vicarious Visions</a>. That means it’s been five years since a Tony Hawk game hit store shelves. With so much evidence lining up for a big reveal next month, it seems the wait may soon be over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we wait to see what that March 4 reveal has lined up, you can read up on a few of the other skateboarding-themed inclusions in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 2 Reloaded, including a pack of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activisions-costly-call-of-duty-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-crossover-has-some-players-saying-black-ops-6-should-just-go-free-to-play-at-this-point">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle cosmetics that have some fans upset</a>. You can also see Tony Hawk himself confirm that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tony-hawk-teases-pro-skater-anniversary-plans-it-will-be-something-the-fans-will-truly-appreciate">he was working with Actvision again as of last year</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>