<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:37:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROUTINE: The Final Preview – IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/routine-the-final-preview-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/routine-the-final-preview-%E2%80%93-ign-first.1350118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/10/ignfirst-routine-3-finalpreview-banner-1762810914943.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">As a lover of puzzle games, what can elevate my puzzle-solving experience more than having horrifying monsters breathing down my neck and ready to snap said neck if I fail to solve their puzzle in time? I love these types of games that keep me on edge for hours on end, so Routine is exactly the type of aesthetically pleasing and brutally tense kinds of horror experience I’m always on the lookout for. And with a deeply cool 80’s-tech lunar setting and the beginnings of a story that has me interested in seeing more, I’m willing to overlook some of the things I was less impressed by during the roughly 90-minute demo, like the fact that the monsters searching for me were about as bright as the desks I hid behind and underneath. It remains to be seen if the story will pay off as much as its promising setting and compelling vibe might imply, but I’ll definitely be diving deeper in the future to see how it shakes out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Routine is one of those horror games where you’re forced to run around solving little puzzles while absolutely horrifying monsters stalk the halls, ready to kill you on sight if you fail to avoid their notice – you know, in the same vein as something like Alien: Isolation or My Friendly Neighborhood. That comes with  all the same pros and cons as its genre peers, where you have these really tense moments as you manage to solve a puzzle and rush through a door just before the bad guy you can’t possibly hope to kill catches up with you. But you then also have plenty of instances where you’re stuck in a room waiting for the dumb bad guy to turn around and walk away, leading to lots of moments where the tension sours into a monotonous waiting game. I tend to really enjoy these kinds of protracted hide and seek sequences, even if they do occasionally involve a bit of waiting, so this was right up my alley.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In this particular case, I found myself on a moon base that had been taken over by killer humanoid robots, whose lidless, unblinking eyes searched for me as I repaired various broken electrical systems and tried to get through each area unnoticed. The ambience of this dilapidated lunar base with an ‘80’s tech aesthetic really worked for me, clearly drawing inspiration from fellow retro-tech science fiction worlds like Alien. But Routine also brings with it a unique sense of humor, with silly arcade games to play in between sweat-inducing horror sequences and cheeky, non-murderous robot helpers to find along the way. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Routine's immaculately creepy vibes, unique retro aesthetic, and tongue-in-cheek jokes in between bouts of utter terror, all coalesce in a way I haven’t seen before.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This is one of the biggest ways in which Routine sets itself apart, as its immaculately creepy vibes, unique retro aesthetic, and tongue-in-cheek jokes in between bouts of utter terror, all coalesce in a way I haven’t seen before. I didn’t get a very strong sense of whether or not the story will deliver something worth all the stress and jump scares along the way, but hopefully all this neat worldbuilding will translate into something as awesome as the setting. With some solid environmental storytelling and hints at some kind of mysterious viral disease at work, it has certainly piqued my curiosity.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The areas I explored ranged from= fairly unremarkable metallic hallways filled with busted droids and signs of something catastrophic having happened recently to really neat areas like an abandoned arcade with janky retro games to play and a shopping mall littered with debris. And, of course, since the whole thing takes place on a base on the moon, they take every opportunity to give you a nice view of the beautiful majesty of good ol’ Selene. Gotta love that. I’m a tad skeptical that they can manage to keep things interesting when you’re stranded on a fairly generic space station on a barren rock in outer space, but hey, so far so good.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although much of the demo I played featured some fairly by-the-numbers puzzles, like finding codes around the world to enter into a keypad to unlock a door, it also had some neat mechanics built around the C.A.T device you’re given early in the story. This tool is basically just a handheld camcorder that can also do things like fire an electrical bolt at targets in your path. What’s cool, though, is that it evolved as I progressed, like when I unlocked an ultraviolet mode called the Ultraview Module that allowed me to see trace substances like bloodstains that helped me solve some of the space station’s more unintuitive riddles. I only unlocked two modes in my time with it, but it’s clear that upgrading this bad boy is going to be the primary way in which you power up, and so far I like that idea quite a bit. It’ll be interesting to see what clever new uses they find for it.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While you upgrade your C.A.T., read snippets of lore around the space station, and solve puzzles, you’ll find yourself almost constantly hunted by extremely violent robots that chase after you on sight with intent to kill. Naturally, that makes even the most simple brain teasers that much more stressful, as you spend every other second double-checking over your shoulder, or wincing when you hear a robotic sound come from somewhere nearby. It’s not exactly an original premise, but it’s certainly the classic type of horror gameplay I’ve come to know and love over the years – and something we could definitely use more of.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One thing that was a bit disappointing, at least during my extremely early time with the story, is just how easy it was to outsmart the fairly dim robots hunting for me, to the point where I never actually was killed during my time playing. They make a ton of noise as they march around electronically, give up the chase as soon as you start running away since they can’t hope to compete with your speed, and don’t do a very thorough job searching for you if you’re hidden in an obvious corner they haven’t bothered exploring yet. What’s more, one of the abilities you unlock for your C.A.T. early on, is a mode where you can tase the robots chasing you, shorting them out for a second or two to buy valuable time you need to get away, as if it weren’t already easy enough as-is. But that doesn’t mean they aren’t still as intimidating as hell – the robotic shrieks they make every once in a while made my skin crawl, and the few times where they were able to get close without me noticing sent me screaming in the opposite direction. They may not actually be very deadly killers (at least early on), but they’re still pretty damn stressful to be around nonetheless.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/routine-the-final-preview-ign-first]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Claim Broken Promises After $70 Pokémon Pokopia Confirmed as First Nintendo-Published Game-Key Card Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-pokopia-looks-to-be-a-70-game-key-card-release-but-no-nintendo-hasnt-broken-its-promise-around-games-it-develops</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fans-claim-broken-promises-after-70-pok%C3%A9mon-pokopia-confirmed-as-first-nintendo-published-game-key-card-release.1350115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-pokopia">Pokémon Pokopia</a> will cost $70 and only be available physically as a Game-Key Card, it appears — something that has stunned some Nintendo fans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-pokopia-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-confirmed">confirmation of the game's March 5, 2026 release date</a> earlier today, store pages for the highly-anticipated Pokémon life simulation have now gone live, detailing its price and status as a Game-Key card game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the U.S., Pokopia is <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/pokemon-pokopia-switch-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available</a> to pre-order now for $69.99. In Japan, meanwhile, Pokopia costs 8,980 yen — the same price point as Mario Kart World ($80 in the U.S.), and more than other Nintendo-published titles such as Donkey Kong Bananza and even Pokémon Legends: Z-A.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo's Japanese <a href="https://www.pokemon.co.jp/ex/pocoapokemon/ja/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website</a> specifically lists Pokopia's physical edition as a Game-Key card, and while the same information isn't shown in the U.S., Nintendo has simulataneously published a YouTube <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5ldQYMwzWrY&amp;t=15s" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> instructing users on how "Game-Key Cards on Nintendo Switch 2" work — which uses Pokémon Pokopia as an example. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Game-Key Cards have proven controversial among Nintendo fans who dislike the fact that the cartridges only contain a prompt to download the game, rather than its full game data. That means you do need to connect your Switch 2 online after buying the game, and then also need to wait while it downloads. However, Game-Key Cards differ from digital downloads as they can still be re-sold or shared with others — just like a regular game cartridge.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo previously <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/nintendo-has-no-plans-to-use-game-key-cards-for-first-party-developed-titles" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stated</a> that it had "no plans to use Game-Key Cards for Nintendo-developed titles" — something some fans today have pointed to as a broken promise. But, of course, Pokémon is not a solely Nintendo-owned franchise and Nintendo does not develop Pokémon games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, Nintendo <em>is</em> publishing Pokémon Pokopia, and this does appear to be the first Nintendo-published game offered on a Game-Key Card. But this is also a game developed by Koei Tecmo — which, last time we checked, was not a Nintendo development studio.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier today, Nintendo announced a new trailer for Pokémon Pokopia will debut later this week on Thursday, November 13 at 6am Pacific, 9am Eastern, or 2pm UK. Eagle-eyed fans believe the video will feature over 10 minutes of gameplay — suggesting Nintendo is confident in what it has to show.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-pokopia-looks-to-be-a-70-game-key-card-release-but-no-nintendo-hasnt-broken-its-promise-around-games-it-develops]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition Sparks Backlash as Disgruntled Fans Use Steam Reviews to Express Their Disappointment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-sparks-backlash-as-disgruntled-fans-use-steam-reviews-to-express-their-disappointment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-sparks-backlash-as-disgruntled-fans-use-steam-reviews-to-express-their-disappointment.1350004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-4-anniversary-edition">Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</a> was meant to act as a celebration of Bethesda’s post-apocalyptic role-playing game on its tenth birthday. But it turns out that things haven’t exactly gone to plan as the update was met with a backlash on Steam.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The $59.99 Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition includes the six official Fallout 4 expansions and over 150 Creation Club items (paid mods). But there’s also a Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition upgrade Bethesda is selling to existing owners of the base game, priced $39.99.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Bethesda points out that this upgrade offers a discount on all the items sold separately, fans have hit out at the pricing for the Anniversary Edition, especially in the context of Fallout 4 itself being a decade old and what the Anniversary Edition actually gets you. It’s worth noting that the Fallout 4 base game is currently $19.99 on Steam (it launched at $59.99), and the Fallout 4 Game of the Year Edition, which includes the base game and all the six official expansions, costs $39.99.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Fallout 4 - Creations Bundle, which includes the 150 paid mods released as part of the Anniversary Edition, costs $19.99 on its own. And it’s the Steam store page for this bundle that has born the brunt of the backlash, with a ‘mostly negative’ user review rating.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Complaints there report crashing issues, glitches, and even a problem with getting the new mods to work. Meanwhile, it sounds like the Anniversary Edition is breaking prior mods, although <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-issues-fallout-4-mod-warning-ahead-of-anniversary-edition-release-patch-will-make-gameplay-and-performance-improvements-as-well-as-add-new-creations-menu">Bethesda warned this would happen when it came to mods that affect the new Creation Club menu</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Be a gamer in 2025,” reads the most helpful review, according to Steam. “You purchase the content. You don't get the content in game. Bethesda's update causes even more crashes. Trying to quit the game causes it to crash. GG.”</p><div id="fallout-4-perks-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Fallout 4 Perks Tier List</h3><h3>Fallout 4 Perks Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“It is bugging out like crazy and not giving out all of the creations that are mentioned in the bundle,” another review reports. “Game absolutely refuses to let you attempt to install anything involving the Creation Club and freezes upon launching and quitting the game to the point where you can’t even use task manager or Steam to force close. For the love of god Bethesda, this is worse than Skyrim's anniversary launch. Fix your game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The reaction on the Fallout subreddit features a similar sentiment, and yes, the memes have begun.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The backlash has also spilled over into Steam reviews for the Fallout 4 base game, where negative reviews have flooded in following the Anniversary Edition’s release, causing recent reviews to plummet to ‘mixed.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“They just killed the game with this Anniversary update,” reads one negative review on the Fallout 4 base game. “Not going to sort my 400+ mods as it would take days. Goodbye Fallout, I would like to say I will miss you but I won't.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a disappointing start for Fallout’s big push ahead of the hotly anticipated December launch of Fallout Season 2 on Prime Video. A new Fallout: New Vegas bundle is also due out, with a Fallout TV show-themed update to Fallout 76 also coming in December. Hopefully Bethesda can sort these issues out sooner rather than later.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Fallout 4 - Creations Menu Update November 10 patch notes:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Creations Menu</strong>: A new in-game Creations menu has been added, making it easier than ever to discover, download and enjoy content from professional developers and passionate enthusiasts alike.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Gameplay &amp; Performance</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>VATS Accuracy:</strong> VATS hit chances are now consistent across platforms and no longer drop to 0% or show incorrect values. Targeting enemies through walls without the Penetrator perk is no longer possible.</li><li><strong>NPC Visual Creations:</strong> Fixed stuttering and hitching caused by Creations that edit NPC visuals. Performance is improved when using such Creations.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Stability &amp; Crashes</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>BNET Connectivity:</strong> Better handling when there is a  <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/linkfilter/?u=https%3A%2F%2FBethesda.net" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bethesda.net</a> outage</li><li><strong>Crafting Station Crash:</strong> Interacting with crafting stations or the workshop on ultrawide monitors no longer causes crashes.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ultrawide &amp; Super Ultrawide Support</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>UI &amp; HUD Scaling:</strong> UI elements, HUD backgrounds, and item previews now scale correctly for 21:9 and 32:9 aspect ratios. Menus, quest updates, tutorials, workshops, and inspected objects are no longer stretched or squished.</li><li><strong>Pip-Boy Map:</strong> Players can now place markers, fast travel, and pan the map to the right side in the Pip-Boy when using ultrawide resolutions.</li><li><strong>Save Preview Images:</strong> Save preview images are now letterboxed to avoid looking squished on ultrawide monitors.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Resolution Detection:</strong> Autodetect now sets supported display resolutions, preventing crashes on launch.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-sparks-backlash-as-disgruntled-fans-use-steam-reviews-to-express-their-disappointment]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Pokopia Nintendo Switch 2 Release Date Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-pokopia-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-pokopia-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-confirmed.1349998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has just confirmed a release date for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-pokopia">Pokémon Pokopia</a>, its promising-looking Animal Crossing-style game for Nintendo Switch 2. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Out of the blue, as is Nintendo's whim, we now know that the game will arrive on March 5, 2026. A brand new trailer will also drop this week — though you'll need to wait until Thursday, November 13, for that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Announced back during <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-september-2025-live-updates-everything-announced">Nintendo's big September Direct</a>, Pokémon Pokopia looks set to blend your favorite pocket monsters with gameplay elements from Animal Crossing, Harvest Moon and Dragon Quest Builders. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">By recruiting and befriending different Pokémon species, you'll be able to shape the land, harvest crops and resources, then build homes for you and your Pokémon. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You control a human-form Ditto, so are able to gradually pick up the abilities of other creatures. The Grass-type Bulbasaur, for example, will allow you to gain the ability to grow plants, while learning from Water-type Squirtle will let you water them. You can shape terrain by punching it, learning from Hitmonchan, or build wooden structures by learning construction techniques from Timburr.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We'll have the latest trailer for Pokémon Pokopia for you to watch later this week — at 6am Pacific, 9am Eastern, or 2pm UK on Thursday.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-pokopia-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-confirmed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>