<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 19:18:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: NBA 2K26, Logitech PC Gaming Accessories, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-october-25-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-nba-2k26-logitech-pc-gaming-accessories-and-more.1334905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Make every day game day.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We've rounded up the best deals for Saturday, October 25, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">NBA 2K26 for $49.94</h2><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229883"><div id="229883" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>NBA 2K26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">NBA 2K26 is on sale this weekend for $49.94, just in time for the start of the NBA season. Play kicked off this week with the OKC Thunder and Houston Rockets, and if you haven't yet picked up 2K26, this deal can make every day game day. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nba-2k26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, “Ball Over Everything” is a fitting description for NBA 2K26. The smooth on-court action is better than ever and MyCareer’s excellent started-from-the-bottom journey to the pros story make it so the imperfections are easier to ignore."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save on Xbox Ally X</h2></div><div catalogid="8d82a57c-a009-4132-a2ac-784cb66e516e" id="229852"><div id="229852" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Open Box, Excellent Condition</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>ROG Xbox Ally X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Best Buy has open box models of the ROG Xbox Ally X already on sale, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-xbox-ally-x-drops-in-price-for-the-first-time-when-you-buy-slightly-used">allowing you to save</a> on this brand new device. The Xbox Ally X is an excellent choice if you're looking to take your Xbox experience with you wherever you go, as you can instantly access your library and Xbox Game Pass with the press of a button.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Madden NFL 26 for $49.94</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229884"><div id="229884" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Madden NFL 26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation 5 copies of Madden NFL 26 are available for $49.94 this weekend at Amazon. This latest entry brings new updates that make a noticeable difference, particularly when compared to entries of the last few years. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "There’s always room for improvement, but it’s hard to overstate what a leap Madden NFL 26 feels like both on and off the field."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Apple AirTag 4-Pack for $64.99</h2></div><div catalogid="07bae54a-386a-4ab0-8871-973d4758734d" id="229431"><div id="229431" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirTag 4 Pack</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Apple AirTags are some of the best products out there for numerous reasons. While they aren't necessarily exciting, AirTags can make your life so much easier. Throw one in your luggage, backpack, or even Nintendo Switch 2 case for easy tracking.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Logitech G502 Gaming Mouse for $37.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229885"><div id="229885" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Logitech G502 HERO High Performance Wired Gaming Mouse</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Logitech G502 Gaming Mouse has been around for a long while, but it's still one my <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-gaming-mouse">favorite gaming mice</a> on the market. Some of its best features include a Hero 25K sensor, an adjustable weight system, mechanical switch button tensioning, and a total of 11 customizable buttons. This is an amazing mouse for competitive games, single player games, and even just daily web browsing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save 50% Off the Anker SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Power Station</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229887"><div id="229887" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Portable Power Station</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There is nothing worse than losing power due to a storm or outage at a critical moment. A full backup generator can be very expensive to install, but Anker has a portable solution on sale this weekend for $397.99. The SOLIX C1000 Gen 2 Power Station has a 2,000W power output, which is perfect to set up as a UPS. With 100% battery available in under one hour of charging, this can be a game-changing device to your home.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Logitech G515 Lightspeed Gaming Keyboard for $109.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229886"><div id="229886" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Logitech G515 Lightspeed TKL Low Profile Wireless Gaming Keyboard</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This weekend, you can score the Logitech G515 Lightspeed Gaming Keyboard for $109.99 - that's 31% off the MSRP! This TKL keyboard is quite slim, making it fit into any setup with ease. The Red Linear switches with double-shot PBT caps offer durability and performance, with a 1.3mm actuation distance.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 25, 2025 3:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-october-25-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>