<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 23:04:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Time Wrestling: All or Nothing Board Game Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/all-time-wrestling-all-or-nothing-board-game-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-time-wrestling-all-or-nothing-board-game-review.1182696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/all-time-wrestling-all-or-nothing-board-game-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pile drivers, clotheslines, and – time travel? In the board game All Time Wrestling: All or Nothing, an immensely wealthy wrestling fan from the future uses the power of time travel to bring together some of the most iconic wrestlers from the past, present, and future to compete against one another. The game, designed by Mohamed Al Qadi and Jad Yammine and published by Cation Arts, offers players a fun time, whether or not you're familiar with pro wrestling and its pantheon of characters.</p><div catalogid="d55f387f-9d55-466a-a73e-98f67d3532b9" id="218897"><div id="218897" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>All Time Wrestling: All or Nothing Board Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Anyone who grew up in the ‘90s like I did knows the WWF (as it was called back then, before the World Wildlife Fund won the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WWE#Lawsuit_and_renaming_(2002)" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trademark dispute</a>) was all the rage among kids. So, while I opted to get my spandex fix with Power Rangers, I still had enough folks in my circle to know who the Macho Man and the British Bulldog were. While ATW’s subject matter may not be a big selling point for me, its balancing act of managing your resources and knowing when to push your luck kept me coming back round after round.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In ATW, much like in actual wrestling, players attempt to exhaust and weaken each other, with the end goal being to pin their opponent and take home the win. Each selectable wrestler – including legends like Macho Man Randy Savage and the British Bulldog, alongside ATW original characters – features unique abilities and varying levels of health and stamina, which adds some lovely variety to the game and helps keep matches exciting from one to the next.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Combat plays out with the player holding “initiative” playing cards from their hand and rolling dice to deal damage. Successful hits push the Momentum Track in that player’s favor, replicating the crowd hyping up the wrestler. The higher the momentum, the easier it becomes to land hits and gain other bonuses, which incentivizes continued aggression. Initiative only switches when an attack misses, the defender blocks, the defender uses their once-per-game “Reversal” ability (which instantly stops the combat), or the attacker voluntarily passes to regain some stamina and cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Between the different attack bonuses and the ability to combo cards together, there is a pleasant amount of depth and strategy in ATW without being overly complex. What I found most interesting, though, is how <em>initiative</em> is handled – it's done in a way I haven’t encountered in other games before. I really enjoyed this “press your luck” approach, and it made managing my hand of cards, stamina, and momentum more exciting. It often left me with a tough choice: do I push hard and risk leaving myself in rough shape for a chance to cinch a pin, or do I pass and forfeit the attack to try and weather the next assault, hoping I’ll be in a better position to strike back?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the topic of cards, this is perhaps where my biggest issue with ATW lies. Instead of relying on text, the game heavily uses symbols and icons to denote things like damage, stamina requirements, special attributes, and other modifiers. As a general rule of thumb, if a game <em>can</em> employ icons, it should – so long as they are both readable and not overwhelming. Luckily, I never found there to be too many icons to decode in ATW, but the readability leaves a lot to be desired.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The action cards, which you use the most, feature colorful artwork of various wrestlers performing everything from jabs and punches to German suplexes and signature moves. However, this can make picking up on all the symbols more of a hassle than it should be – especially if you're on the receiving end and viewing them upside down or from a distance. More than a few times I encountered situations where finishers or dice modifiers were missed, or cards were mistaken for others, due to duplicate artwork being used for attacks with different stats. Perhaps it’s because of my long history with games like Magic: The Gathering, but I wish the information was presented atop a slightly opaque background, rather than directly over the art. It’s not a finisher on the game, but it’s certainly a bit of a jab to the chin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The core game box offers players plenty of value and flexibility, providing not only standard 1v1 matches but also a tag-team-based 2v2 mode, a cage match variant with new rules, and a solo <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-campaign-board-games">campaign</a> mode that lets you improve your wrestler as you progress. The automated systems in solo mode are fine, but admittedly, as someone who has never quite gotten into <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-solo-board-games">solo board games</a>, I spent far more time playing against others than diving into ATW’s campaign.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I personally prefer the more intense, head-to-head two-player experience.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As for tag mode, the inclusion of specialty partner abilities and the ability to tag in my friend to continue combos added an extra layer of choice and strategy. Still, it didn’t quite hit as hard as the core 1v1 mode. Even with the new tag mechanic, I couldn’t shake the feeling that this mode simply adds more players at the expense of having more downtime, since only one attacker and one defender are active at any given time, with partners outside the ring. It’s still fun and led to some awesome team-up moments with friends, but I personally prefer the more intense, head-to-head two-player experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those wanting to dive even deeper into the All Time Wrestling universe, the creators continue to release new expansions – fully compatible with existing content – that add legends like Sgt. Slaughter and the Junkyard Dog, alongside new game modes like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-4-players">four-player</a> free-for-alls and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-three-player-board-games">three-player</a>-specific Triple Threat matches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All Time Wrestling is one of those games worth checking out even if the wrestling theme doesn’t grab you. With games clocking in at under 30 minutes for two players and around 45 minutes for tag teams, it's a great filler during game nights or something compact enough to take to a bar. I’d love to see this system adapted for other themes – like a shonen anime (think Dragon Ball Z) or something Power Rangers-inspired. There’s a surprising amount of depth here, while still being approachable for players of varying board game experience – even those coming to it purely for a love of wrestling.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With All Time Wrestling, Cation Arts delivers a dramatic and faithful representation of the wild history of wrestling in a package that will delight fans of head-to-head games, regardless of whether you know what a DDT stands for or not.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where to Buy</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aX2mge?object_uuid=1d3f2b21-42ca-46ea-a29d-eca2d1e54d62&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z1e3g?object_uuid=1d3f2b21-42ca-46ea-a29d-eca2d1e54d62&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Cation Arts</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJpeE?object_uuid=1d3f2b21-42ca-46ea-a29d-eca2d1e54d62&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at The Wrestling Collection</a></li></ul></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 6, 2025 7:15 pm</p></div><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">All Time Wrestling is one of those games worth checking out even if the wrestling theme doesn’t grab you. With games clocking in at under 30 minutes for two players and around 45 minutes for tag teams, it's a great filler during game nights or something compact enough to take to a bar. I’d love to see this system adapted for other themes – like a shonen anime (think Dragon Ball Z) or something Power Rangers-inspired. There’s a surprising amount of depth here, while still being approachable for players of varying board game experience – even those coming to it purely for a love of wrestling. With All Time Wrestling, Cation Arts delivers a dramatic and faithful representation of the wild history of wrestling in a package that will delight fans of head-to-head games, regardless of whether you know what a DDT stands for or not.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Lorcana's Ninth Set - Fabled - to Be Released in September 2025 With A Goofy Movie and the First Iconic and Epic Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-lorcanas-ninth-set-fabled-to-be-released-in-september-2025-with-a-goofy-movie-and-the-first-iconic-and-epic-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-lorcanas-ninth-set-fabled-to-be-released-in-september-2025-with-a-goofy-movie-and-the-first-iconic-and-epic-cards.1182603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-lorcanas-ninth-set-fabled-to-be-released-in-september-2025-with-a-goofy-movie-and-the-first-iconic-and-epic-cards<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Disney Lorcana just revealed a ton of new info for the future of the trading card game, including that the ninth set - Fabled - will be released on September 5, 2025, with the first-ever Iconic and Epic cards and the long-awaited arrival of A Goofy Movie.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside Fabled, more details were shared on Lorcana's eighth set - Reign of Jafar - ahead of its debut on June 6, a new Collection Starter Set was revealed, and details on the Disney Lorcana World Championship were given. Oh, and we can't forget about the tease of Darkwing Duck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A lot of exciting info was unveiled for Disney Lorcana, and we're here to break it down to ensure you don't miss a thing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Fabled Will Add Iconic and Epic Cards, A Goofy Movie, and Rotating Cards for Competitive Play</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/dlc-fabled-a-goofy-movie-image-1746510989873.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">While we still have more to learn about Fabled, the teases given by the Disney Lorcana team are making the wait until pre-release on August 29 and wide release on September 5 just that much harder. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">A Goofy Movie cards will be one of the biggest additions to Disney Lorcana with Fabled, but the team wasn't ready to share exactly which cards will become available. They did share, however, that Mickey and Minnie will be the very first Iconic Cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Iconic Cards will be the rarest cards in all of Lorcana, as only two will appear in each set going forward, and beautiful cards of Mickey and Minnie on a carousel will serve as the Iconic Cards all players will be chasing for their sets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside Iconic Cards will be Epic Cards, which are rarer than Legendary but not as hard to get as Enchanted and Iconic. These cards will also feature special artwork and foil treatments and will give players even more chances to score a special card like a new Elsa (Snow Queen) one. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another big change in Fabled is that it will mark the first time Lorcana will be rotating out certain cards and making them illegal for competitive play. Top-level competitive play is called Core Constructed and will not allow players to use any cards from the first four sets of Lorcana. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Disney Lorcana Fabled Cards and Art</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans of older cards shouldn't worry too much though, as there will be plenty of ways to play your older cards, including in a new format called Infinity Constructed. Furthermore, Fabled will introduce reprinted cards from earlier sets - like Winnie the Pooh (Hunny Wizard) - and those will be fully usable in competitive play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“To keep the competitive game thriving, rotating out older cards to encourage new strategies and fresh deck designs is a really important part of the next chapter,” said Ryan Miller, Brand Manager and Co Designer of <em>Disney Lorcana</em> <em>TCG</em> at Ravensburger. “But because we know there are cards in those early sets that are important to a lot of fans’ deck-building strategies, and we know not everybody got the cards they wanted the first year, we’re re-printing some cards from those first sets in <em>Fabled</em>. Including Enchanted versions of some fan favorites!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you are new to Lorcana and all of these new sets sound enticing and wonderful, the team has announced a new way to jump into this trading card game with the Collection Starter Set. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This set includes four Fabled booster packs, a Tinker Bell (Giant Fairy) "Glimmer Foil" Promo Card, one card portfolio with Mickey Mouse (Brave Little Tailor) on the front, and one collector's guide.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/collection-starter-set-1746511057724.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">Reign of Jafar Offers Aladdin and Bambi Cards Alongside a New Co-Op Adventure</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As we previously mentioned, Reign of Jafar is Lorcana's eighth set and it will be available in pre-release on May 30 and wide release on June 6. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reign of Jafar will continue the ongoing story in Lorcana that stars the Disney villain, and the Lorcana team has given a summary of what fans can expect.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Jafar now possesses the Hexwell Crown and, with it, he has corrupted Archazia’s Island to his wicked will," the official description reads. "Traps and illusions abound in <em>Reign of Jafar</em>, and glimmers like Jasmine – Steady Strategist and Rapunzel – High Climber will need to band together to steal back the crown and defeat the evil vizier."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Disney Lorcana Reign of Jafar Cards and Sets</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside Reign of Jafar, fans will be able to jump into Illumineers' Quest: Palace Heist, which is a new "co-op experience-in-a-box" that will allow four players to team up and take on Jafar and his minion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the cards, fans will be able to try to get Bambi (Prince of the Forest), Flower (Shy Skunk), Thumper (Young Bunny), Jafar (High Sultan of Lorcana), Magic Carpet (Phantom Rug), Aladdin (Vigilant Guard), and much more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Teases of the Future Include Whispers in the Well and Darkwing Duck</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/dlc-whispers-in-the-well-set-art-1746511073170.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">At the end of the presentation, Disney revealed that the set after Fabled will be called Whispers in the Well and it will arrive in Q4 2025. The team didn't share much, but a key art revealed Mickey, Ariel, and the likely addition of Disney Gargoyles into Lorcana. Oh, and that there is a new type of Glimmer abound. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Farther out, the team finally answered many fans' calls for Darkwing Duck to be added to Lorcana as it was confirmed he will be joining the game in 2026.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Get Ready For the Disney Lorcana World Championship</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The competitve scene in Lorcana is heating up as the Disney Lorcana World Championship will take place on June 28 and 29 in Walt Disney World. This major tournament will see players from around the world competing for the envious title of the first annual Disney Lorcana TCG World Champion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans not in attendance will be able to follow along live on Twitch.TV/DisneyLorcana with a team of casters that includes Rebekah (<em>RebekahQuests</em>), Baker (<em>LorcanaVillain</em>), Liam (<em>The Illumiteers</em>), Brandon (<em>Bsquared24</em>), and JD (<em>JDZ Quest</em>). Additionally, there will be a chance to obtain a non-foil 'A Whole New World' promo card during this time, but more details will be given in the future.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/dlc-promo-a-whole-new-world-1746511087140.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-tcgs">what other TCGs alongside Disney Lorcana are worth getting into</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-lorcana-archazias-island-first-impressions-of-the-new-tcg-expansion">our impressions of Lorcana's Archazia's Island expansion.</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Have a tip for us? Want to discuss a possible story? Please send an email to </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/"><em>newstips@ign.com</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Adam Bankhurst is a writer for IGN. You can follow him on X/Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst,</em></a><em> </em><a href="https://www.instagram.com/adambankhurst/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Instagram,</em></a><em> and </em><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@adambankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>TikTok,</em></a><em> and listen to his show, </em><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/talking-disney-magic/id1773431375" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Talking Disney Magic.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>