<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:59:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive First Look at 2025 Pokémon World Championships Merch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-first-look-at-2025-pokemon-world-championships-merch-anaheim-socal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-first-look-at-2025-pok%C3%A9mon-world-championships-merch.1246137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pokémon World Championships in Anaheim, CA are just around the corner in August, and with it comes an exclusive line of cute Pokémon merch, which IGN has an exclusive first look at. Each year, the Pokémon World Championships hosts a special Pokémon Center pop-up shop, and we’re getting <em>three</em> uniquely themed exclusive lines out of the event this time. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-first-look-at-2024-pokemon-world-championships-merch"><u>Last year, we got a tropical, Hawaiian-themed Pokémon line</u></a>. Check out the unique new Pokémon items, including a first-ever Pokémon bodyboard, below. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“In honor of this year’s Anaheim, CA location, Pokémon Center will be releasing three product lines – the Varsity Line, SoCal Beach Skater Line, and Rockabilly Line,” said Cindy Ruppenthal, senior director of Pokémon Center and e-commerce at The Pokémon Company International. “This year’s collection draws inspiration from bright, retro-diner design, blending vibrant colors and nostalgic elements that capture the spirit of our SoCal location.” </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">2025 Pokémon World Championships Exclusive Merch Reveal</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Check out a large selection of the exclusive merch that will be at the Pokémon World Championships in the slideshow above, but keep in mind, this won’t be everything! </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 2025 Worlds Pikachu Plush sporting a varsity jacket, revealed at this year’s North America International Championships in New Orleans, is sure to be a popular item along with the other SoCal-themed plush of Fennekin, Machamp, and Jigglypuff, but there’s a lot more to look forward to. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The standout premiere item this year is the SoCal Bodyboard, which is fully functional for riding waves at the beach, and is priced at $79.99 USD. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ruppenthal “expects strong demand” for the SoCal Bodyboard along with other functional items from the SoCal Beach Skater Line, like the SoCal Beach Towels. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Additionally, following popular reception from Pokémon Worlds in Honolulu, we teamed up with Reyn Spooner to create a Pokémon Aloha shirt, bucket hat, tote, and more to celebrate the event in Anaheim,” Ruppenthal said. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pokemon-center-worlds-2025-3-1752721417421.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A sneak peak of this year's Reyn Spooner shirt, in the front and center. A different design than the 2024 Pokemon Aloha shirts in Honolulu last year. </figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Reyn Spooner Pokémon Aloha shirts from last year were so popular that I witnessed an attendee offer $300 for the shirt off someone’s back, literally, since they had sold out. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I witnessed an attendee offer $300 for the Pokémon Aloha shirt off someone's back last year</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“With this year’s California location, it felt like the perfect moment to reintroduce the</p><p data-cy="paragraph">apparel collaboration as our laid-back, SoCal designs align perfectly with Reyn Spooner’s bright, beach vibe and signature Aloha shirts,” Ruppenthal said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As far as other exclusive apparel goes, there <em>will</em> <strong>be a varsity jacket</strong>, “as well as other standout apparel that matches the various design styles offered this year,” Ruppenthal said. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Most surprising of the designs overall this year is probably the Rockabilly line, featuring Arcanine, Squakabilly, and an edgy Pikachu wearing a leather jacket and sunglasses. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pokemon-center-worlds-2025-rockabilly-1-1752721600256.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Some of the merch from the Rockabilly Line, coming to the Pokémon Center pop-up store at the 2025 Pokémon World Championships.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“We always keep in mind that the Pokémon community has diverse interests and styles, and as such, wanted to introduce a bolder counterpart to the Varsity Line and SoCal Beach Skater Line,” Ruppenthal explained. “The Rockabilly Line features darker tones and edgier styling – all while staying true to the retro-diner theme found throughout the Pokémon Center Pop Up Shop. It complements the store design, which takes fans through a journey (beach to boardwalk to nighttime).” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The theming Ruppenthal describes is important, as the Pokémon Center Pop Up Shop at the Pokémon World Championships each year isn’t just a plain holding room for goods, but more of an immersive experience to explore while shopping, complete with set pieces and unique art. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>...this year, there will be a Pokémon Center special online-only shopping promotion taking place that same week.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Usually, all of the Worlds merch revealed here would be exclusive to the in-person Pokémon Center,  which actually runs an additional two days ahead of the 2025 Pokémon World Championship, from August 13 to August 17. However,  this year, there will be a Pokémon Center special online-only shopping promotion taking place that same week. During this time, the 2025 Pokémon World Championships Coin will be available online. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We don’t know anything else about this online shopping event, like whether any other 2025 World Championship items will be available, but Ruppenthall said, “It’s our way of making sure more fans can take part in the celebration.” </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/map-of-worlds-2025-1752721631366.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A map of the Anaheim Worlds Event Hall, with a huge area in Hall D sectioned off for the Pokémon Center pop-up store. </figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you are attending in person, keep in mind that you usually need to make a separate Pokémon Center pop-up store reservation, but right now, the <a href="https://worlds.pokemon.com/en-us/experience/pokemoncenter/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Anaheim 2025 Pokémon Center page</u></a> says, “More information on how to attend the Pokémon Center pop-up store is coming soon!” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ll be sure to cover the Pokémon Center Pop Up Shop and a lot more during the 2025 Pokémon World Championships from August 15 to August 17 in Anaheim, so stay tuned for updates. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Casey DeFreitas is a deputy editor of guides at IGN. Catch her at the 2025 Pokémon World Championships, or on socials </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/shinycaseyd.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@ShinyCaseyD</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-first-look-at-2025-pokemon-world-championships-merch-anaheim-socal]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jump into Cyberpunk Battle Royale Off The Grid, Available Now on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/jump-into-cyberpunk-battle-royale-off-the-grid-available-now-on-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jump-into-cyberpunk-battle-royale-off-the-grid-available-now-on-steam.1246134/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Community-driven updates make this the most feature rich edition of Off The Grid yet</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Off The Grid</em>, the fast-paced, third-person cyberpunk battle royale from developer Gunzilla Games launches today on Steam, meaning more players can experience the game’s high-octane multiplayer combat and gritty near-future setting. Alongside its PC launch, the release delivers full cross-play support with Xbox, PlayStation and PC, so no player is left behind. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since its initial release, the free-to-play game has steadily built a strong following, thanks to its slick third-person combat, fast-paced gameplay, and a deep looting system. Frequent updates keep things fresh and bring players back for more. One of the game’s most unique features is the cyberlimb system; players can swap out limbs to gain special abilities, adding a layer of unpredictability and strategy to every match. These limbs can be looted, earned through trades, or taken from defeated enemies, offering plenty of ways to customize your loadout and playstyle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Creatively led by film director Neill Blomkamp, writer and director of films <em>District 9, Elysium </em>and <em>Chappie, Off The Grid </em>has become “one of the most dynamic and responsive battle royales on the market” according to Gunzilla Games’ Executive Producer David Nicholson. Recent updates have been made to the game in direct response to community feedback, and it is that “commitment to player-driven development” that will help <em>Off The Grid </em>continue to build momentum as it prepares to roll out even more content. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The launch of <em>Off The Grid </em>on PC opens the door to a larger and broader player base that can become part of the community and continue to improve the game through active engagement. Player feedback continues to be an integral part of <em>Off The Grid </em>with key features such as limbs, weapons and maps all receiving tweaks in response to community involvement. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the game prepares for its next phase, new and active players can expect to see <em>Off The Grid’s </em>packed roadmap unfold over the course of the next few months, including new gameplay elements and community-driven experiences. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Play <em>Off The Grid </em>on Steam by downloading <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3659280/Off_The_Grid" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">here</a>. To stay up to date on new announcements and information, join the active community on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/offthegrid" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Discord</a> or follow the <a href="https://x.com/playoffthegrid" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">X page </a>for future updates. Want to see more, check out the Steam launch trailer <a href="https://otg.gg/SteamTrailer" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">here</a>. </p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/jump-into-cyberpunk-battle-royale-off-the-grid-available-now-on-steam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: Black Bolt and White Flare Preview — Why This Dual Expansion Is Epic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-preview-why-this-dual-expansion-is-epic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-preview-%E2%80%94-why-this-dual-expansion-is-epic.1246131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve been opening packs from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-revealed">Black Bolt and White Flare</a> for the past week, including a White Flare Elite Trainer Box, the Poster Collection, Black Bolt Binder Collection, the Victini Illustration Collection, and a White Flare Booster Bundle. Right away, these don’t feel like typical Scarlet and Violet products. This dual-set format means there are two completely separate card lists, with Black Bolt focusing on Zekrom, Kyurem, and Genesect, while White Flare leans into Reshiram, Samurott, and Keldeo. It’s a clean split that doesn’t feel like filler or overlap. It feels especially fresh considering we've had two sets of trainer Pokémon cards with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-journey-together-preview">Journey Together</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-destined-rivals-preview">Destined Rivals</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is also the final expansion in the Scarlet and Violet era, and I can tell the designers knew it. Pulling cards from both sets, there’s just a lot more to look at and sort through. You’ve got Poké Ball reverse holos, Master Ball reverse holos, Illustration Rares, Special Illustration Rares, and the new Black White Rare cards. Every single Unovan <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-release-full-release-schedule-2025">Pokémon</a> is included across the two sets, which was obvious the moment I started ripping packs, trying to keep track.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pxl-20250714-180207617-1752740669695.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-where-to-buy">Black White Rare cards</a> specifically caught my attention, although I didn't pull Reshiram, Zekrom or Victini. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-where-to-buy">Black Bolt</a>, Zekrom ex has a new monochrome foil treatment, and in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/walmart-members-early-access-preorder-pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-white-flare">White Flare</a>, Reshiram ex has the same look but in pure white. These aren’t just normal secret rares with a different background (although they look fantastic too), They look completely different from anything in their respective sets. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">One thing I appreciate about this setup is how each set feels like it has its own identity. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokmon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-july-14">Black Bolt</a> leans into electric types and edgy designs, while White Flare has a lot more reds and fiery aesthetics. Even the packaging, from the ETBs to the mini tins, reflects that. Sorting the cards felt like two separate collections that just happened to release on the same day.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pxl-20250714-180216169-1752740737783.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">From a collector’s angle, there’s a lot going on here. I noticed pretty quickly that even commons have an Illustration Rare version somewhere in the set. For example, I pulled two different artwork versions of Patrat (one regular and one IR) and it wasn’t just alternate art slapped onto a foil. It felt intentional, with each version telling a different story. That kind of thing keeps me opening packs longer than I probably should.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also helps that I had pretty consistent pulls across all the products I opened. Between the Poster Collection, the Binder Collection, and the Booster Bundle, I pulled several ex cards, a couple of Illustration Rares, and one Master Ball reverse holo that honestly looks better than I expected. It feels like The Pokémon Company made a conscious effort to avoid the rough pull experiences some of the smaller sets had earlier this year.</p><p id="where-to-buy"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Where to buy">Where to Buy</h2></p><p id="unboxing-and-impressions"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Unboxing and impressions">Unboxing and Impressions</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I got my hands on an awesome selection of Black Bolt and White Flare products: a White Flare Elite Trainer Box, Unova Poster Collection, Black Bolt Binder Collection, the Victini Illustration Collection, and a White Flare Booster Bundle.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pokémon TCG: Black Bolt and White Flare - 1</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"> I don’t always open this many different product types when previewing a set, but with the way this dual release is structured, The Pokémon Company wanted to show this large duel-set off. Both sets have their own exclusive promos and packaging styles, which made the whole thing feel like more than just pulling from the same booster packs over and over.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">White Flare Elite Trainer Box</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-63-1752734995575.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I started with the White Flare ETB. Inside were the usual dice, sleeves, and nine booster packs. The promo is an epic Tornadus Illustration Rare. As for the pulls themselves, this ETB wasn’t the wildest I’ve opened, but I did manage to pull a Jellicent ex hyper rare, Whimsicott ex SIR, Accelfor IR, Keldeo ex, then a Mienfoo IR, Woobat Master Ball and Whimsicott ex in one pack! Epic result, but it’s ultimately potluck. Ripping packs of Black Bolt and White Flare open was certainly off to a cracking start.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Unova Poster Collection</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-64-1752735168896.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Unova Poster Collection felt more like a side product. It’s not packed with boosters (just four) but it does come with promos of the Unovan starter common cards from the set and a fold-out poster showing Unova Pokémon featured in both sets on one side, then box art for Black Bolt and White Flare on the other. So there’s two Black Bolt and two White Flare boosters in the Poster Collection. I pulled a Jellicent ex, Venipede IR and a Kyurem ex, which isn’t bad at all for four pack openings.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Black Bolt Binder Collection</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-65-1752735287443.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Binder Collection includes five boosters plus a nine-pocket binder themed around either Black Bolt or White Flare, depending on which version you buy. I got the Black Bolt version and pulled a Drilbur IR, so not a great experience with Black Bolt from the binder collection but the extras will come in handy. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Victini Illustration Collection</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-66-1752735430293.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Out of everything I opened, the Victini Illustration Collection was probably the most surprising. It comes with a Victini promo IR, a giant card of the same and a common Victini Pokéball, plus two Black Bolt and two White Flare. I managed to pull another Keldeo ex, Excadrill ex and a Amoonguss Masterball. The Victini promo’s are worth it on it’s own, but I got some half-decent pulls as well. Fantastic!</p><h3 data-cy="title3">White Flare Booster Bundle</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-67-1752735567011.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, I went through a White Flare Booster Bundle. Six packs, no extra promos or sleeves. This one was all about straight pulls, of which I got one Whimsicott ex, a Patrat IR (my favorite pull of this preview) and Hilda Trainer Full Art in one pack, another Woobat Master Ball. The demi god pack energy in Black Bolt and White Flare is real, and it’s so cool to open one. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I really like Black Bolt and White Flare, with me leaning towards White Flare due to my personal luck with the set. If you’re not pulling IRs and Exs, you’re pulling Pokeball and Masterball rares. I think the ball rares are the new holo and reverse holos for Pokémon TCG, which is a win for everyone in my opinion.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Black Bolt / White Flare: Top Card Pulls</h3><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pokémon TCG: Black Bolt and White Flare - 2</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I can't argue with the amount of pulls from this preview. Out of 27 booster packs I managed to pull four ex's, three Master Ball rares, five Illustration Rares, one Hyper Rare and one Secret Illustration Rare. That's an overall pull rate of over 50%, which isn't bad at all. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We have to consider this isn't a normal set thanks to the amount of Illustration rares and ball rares floating around, but it's an absolute blast to open. Although it's nice to see Pokéball and Master Ball rares coming back to English sets after Prismatic Evolutions, it feels like filling up an already packed set. It would be great to see how many epic pulls trainers could get without the inclusion of Pokéball and Masterball rares.</p><p id="my-favorite-pulls"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="My favorite pulls">My Favorite Black Bolt / White Flare Pulls</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Whimsicott ex Secret Art Rare</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/16/pixel-9-61-1752686302152.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I was lucky enough to pull a Secret Art Rare version of Whimsicott ex, and as usual the artwork is fantastic. Full art cards have a special way of making you love Pokémon you either forgot existed or thought were a bit naff. Whimsicott is one of them and I couldn't be happier with this pull.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Patrat Illustration Rare</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/16/pixel-9-62-1752686685896.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I love these bold Illustration Rares that again make a big fuss about overlooked Pokémon. Patrat is a Pokémon that went straight out of my party as soon as I could catch something to take that sixth spot on my team, yet this is my favorite pull from this preview. Go figure.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Meinfoo Illustration Rare</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-68-1752735782131.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Bringing that Charmander, Charmeleon and Charizard ex 151 vibe, Mienfoo Illustration Rare is a cracking snapshot of a wild Pokémon. We're at that point in Pokémon TCG where these cards are works of art. The pose, backdrop and overall artstyle pops out of the card and I'm here for it.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Hilda Supporter Full Art</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-69-1752736115458.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Supporter Full Arts rarely get much love and often plummit in value unless your a Kanto or Johto mainstay. Personally I love them, and the artwork with Hildas Supporter Full Art is just cool to look at. She's slightly popping into the borders and the subtle movements suggested in the artwork just make it interesting to look at.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Victini Illustration Rare Promo</h3><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/pixel-9-70-1752736289302.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Yes I know it's a guaranteed promo, but I couldn't leave out Victini Illustration Rare. It takes me right back to the launch of Black and White working at Gamestation in the UK (which was owned by Game at the time). We had an event cartridge in an old DS that allowed customers to unlock the Victini event and play through Black and White with this absolute gem of a Mythical Pokémon. Owning Pokémon cards with great memories like this attached to it like this is one of the many reasons why I'm into the TCG, and this artwork is gorgeous. 100% a big preview highlight for me.</p><p id="should-you-buy-these-cards"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Should you buy these cards?">Should You Buy Pokémon TCG: Black Bolt White Flare?</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you haven't secured preorders for Black Bolt and White Flare sealed products, feel free to try your luck at launch at your local brick and mortar or online. Alternatively, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QL8lMP?object_uuid=fef23af1-ba18-495d-8c2e-dde794c8b1a7&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCG Player</a> pricing for presale sealed product is crashing, so I reckon we're seeing the usual price crash post-launch coming earlier.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What do I think of the set? I think it's great and possibly the best opportunity to pull Illustration Rares in the Scarlet and Violet era, it's ending on a high note. Personally I'm not a fan of stuffing the set with Pokéball and Masterball rares, but in terms of quality and presentation they look cool. It would be grand to see Mega Evolution double down on the dual format and loads of Illustration Rares, but this is an encouraging sneek peek into what's next for Pokémon TCG.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-preview-why-this-dual-expansion-is-epic]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Know About James Gunn's DCU Video Game Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-know-about-james-gunn-dcu-video-games-rocksteady-batman-superman</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-know-about-james-gunns-dcu-video-game-plans.1246023/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a bird! It’s a plane! It’s the very first movie in James Gunn’s revamped DC Universe! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that Superman has hit theaters, James Gunn’s DC Universe is fully underway… Or is it? While Gunn has now released a movie, a TV show (Peacemaker), and an animated series (Creature Commandos) under his stewardship, there’s still a missing piece of the DC Universe puzzle: video games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunn told fans back in 2022 that his master plan for an interconnected DC Universe includes video games. But unlike on the movies and TV side of things, there have been no official announcements regarding what the first DC Universe video game will be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An absence of reveals doesn’t mean we don’t have a reasonably clear picture of what to expect, though. Across multiple interviews and press events, Gunn and co-studio head Peter Safran have explained their plans, including the fact that while they don’t technically oversee Warner Bros.’ gaming division, there’s now a much deeper collaboration between WB Games and DC Studios that could dramatically alter the way future DC video games are made. With that in mind, let’s analyze what the future of games will look like in the new DCU era.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gunn Takes Over DC</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The first time we learned that video games factored into Gunn’s DC plans was shortly after he and producer Peter Safran were announced as co-heads of DC Studios on October 25, 2022. While answering fan questions on X, Gunn responded to one user who asked if games would be connected to the DCU alongside films and TV. To this, he <a href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1596921811374964736" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>simply replied, “Yes.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It wouldn’t be until a few months later that <a href="https://www.dc.com/blog/2023/01/31/the-next-generation-of-dc-movies-and-tv-has-arrived" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Gunn revealed</u></a> what movies and shows were in development as part of Chapter 1: Gods and Monsters, which is the DCU’s equivalent of the MCU’s Phase 1. And while video games were conspicuously missing from the Chapter 1 roadmap, Gunn told members of the press, “Television, movies, and games all intertwine within the same universe. We’re going to cast actors who are going to be able to play the characters in [animation and TV], as well as in other things.” This was the first clear indication from Gunn that video games were indeed a part of his plans for the DCU.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Confirmed DCU Projects</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">One important thing to know is that Gunn’s job as head of DC Studios doesn’t include control over any of Warner Bros’ video game studios, which include developers like Avalanche Software (Hogwarts Legacy), NetherRealm Studios (Mortal Kombat), Rocksteady Studios (Batman Arkham), and TT Games (Lego). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Under the current Warner Bros. Discovery corporate structure, Warner Bros. Games exists separately from DC Studios and is overseen by Warner Bros. Discovery's CEO of global streaming and gaming, JB Perrette. But after Gunn and Safran were named DC co-heads in 2022, Perrette appears to be deferring to the new DC bosses when it comes to matters of comic book video games.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>The Walls Break Down Between WB Games and DC Studios</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/warner-bros-video-games-live-services-dc-game-of-thrones-1235888944/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Variety</u></a> in 2024, Perrette revealed, “Frankly, there hasn’t been as close a relationship between the studio and the games business as there should have been. And James [Gunn] is actually a gamer, so having someone who’s passionate about it is super helpful.” Perrette added that the games departments are now “actively working with [Gunn and Safran] on the core franchises within the DC Universe.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Based on this interview, it appears there was once a wall that divided WB’s gaming division from the movie and TV studios. And according to Perrette, it was only after Gunn and Safran took over DC Studios that a newfound sense of collaboration was achieved.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>“Whether it’s NetherRealm or whether it’s Rocksteady, [we] sit with them and talk about characters and stories that we’re interested in and that they’re interested in.”</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This dividing wall was confirmed a year later during a DC Studios Presentation held on February 24, 2025. During the event, James Gunn and Peter Safran confirmed Perrette’s statements regarding the separation between the two WB divisions and how that relationship has changed since they took over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We work incredibly closely with JB Perrette, who runs that division, and it’s really the first time ever it’s been this way at Warner Bros,” Safran confirmed. “It’s been great, and we’ve enjoyed it enormously. Everything had been so siloed, and now that’s completely broken down, and it’s been great. Because it also applies to consumer products and experiences, and everything that DC touches runs up through us now, which is awesome.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“James [Gunn] and I sit with literally the guys that run the studios underneath JB,” Safran added. “Whether it’s NetherRealm or whether it’s Rocksteady, [we] sit with them and talk about characters and stories that we’re interested in and that they’re interested in.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s funny that Safran mentions Rocksteady, as it was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rocksteady-reportedly-working-on-single-player-batman-game-monolith-productions-wonder-woman-in-trouble"><u>reported earlier this year</u></a> that the studio is developing a new single-player Batman game. While it may be too soon to tell, at least according to Gunn and Safran, there will likely be some input from their side of things at DC Studios.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We see designs for the projects in their very earliest stages,” Gunn said at the event. “When they’re talking about what the story might be, we say, ‘Well, maybe you want to go this way because we’re planning on maybe doing something with this character and so forth and so on,’ and help deal with that.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/16/screenshot-2025-07-14-at-12-01-37-pm-1752682573383.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Gunn replies to fans on X. Credit: X.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Does this mean Gunn will be fully in charge of the next Rocksteady Batman game? Not quite. Gunn confirmed that <a href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1597360208824569856" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>“not all”</u></a> games will be connected to the DCU’s overarching story when another fan on X shared their concern about losing standalone experiences like Rocksteady’s Arkham series. So, depending on where Rocksteady wants to take its next single-player Batman game, there’s a chance it could be incorporated into the DCU, or treated as a separate universe like Matt Reeves’ The Batman movies.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Furthermore, Perrette said in the aforementioned Variety interview that WB’s game studios will still be making projects based on what’s best for the studios and gamers, saying, “We’re not going to launch a Superman game purely because we feel obligated. We have to do something that makes sense for the gaming strategy and for fans and for the consumer.”</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How James Gunn’s DCU Is Already Shaping Games</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if DC’s full gaming plans remain a mystery, we’re already seeing Gunn’s unified vision for DC play out in several games right now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our characters can move in and out of animation or jump into a game or onto the big screen, but they will remain consistent throughout: same character, same history, same actor,” Gunn said during the <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/james-gunn-creature-commandos-dc-studios-annecy-1235922754/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>press tour for Creature Commandos</u></a> last year — a couple months after Peacemaker was added to Mortal Kombat 1 as a DLC character on February 28, 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as Gunn said, NetherRealm enlisted John Cena to reprise his TV and movie role as Peacemaker in Mortal Kombat 1. Not only is his likeness and design identical to the version of the character that appears in the HBO series and The Suicide Squad movie, but even his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uO_skSl0MDI" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Victory Pose </u></a>in Mortal Kombat 1 is a direct reference to Peacemaker’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mrr3UNALww" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>glam rock-themed opening credits</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Similarly, this month’s Superman-themed content for Fortnite features skins for Superman, Mr. Terrific, and The Engineer, which are all based on the likenesses of their movie counterparts. So, rather than a comic-book version of these characters, you’re playing as David Corenswet’s Superman, Edi Gathegi’s Mr. Terrific, and Maria Gabriela de Faria’s Engineer. Like Peacemaker, it seems that any appearance by a DCU character in a video game will be identical to their movie and TV counterpart, just as Gunn promised (with the exception of those standalone projects Gunn also promised, of course.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Since taking the reins, our true north has been to bring DC film, TV, animation, and gaming into alignment under a single banner and bring a sense of unity and consistency into the DCU as a whole,” Gunn said ahead of the premiere of Creature Commandos. “This frees us to create a range of products that are diverse and compelling, and deliver great stand-alone entertainment experiences on every medium, while also being part of a larger story that we’re telling within our unified DCU.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s been a rough couple of years for DC games under Warner Bros.. Between the closing of Monolith Software and the cancellation of a Wonder Woman video game, to Rocksteady’s Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League’s lackluster release, the future of DC video games appeared to be in major flux. Warner Bros. even considered<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-wb-discovery-looking-to-sell-off-games-other-divisions-to-prevent-total-breakup" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u> selling off its gaming business entirely.</u></a> </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And while WB Games’ fortunes have changed with the massive success of games like Hogwarts Legacy, there’s still no official word yet on the future of DC video games. But it’s clear based on statements from Gunn, Safran, and Perrette that Warner Bros. Games and DC Studios are collaborating deeply when it comes to any upcoming video game starring DC’s caped heroes. Although the basic expectation is that if a character from DC’s movies and shows appears in a game, it will feature the same actor, the full plans for DC video games, especially from developers like Rocksteady, remain to be seen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out our full list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-dc-movies-and-tv-shows-2025-release-dates-and-beyond">upcoming DC movies and TV shows</a>, as well as our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/superman-2025-review-james-gunn-david-corenswet-rachel-brosnahan-nicholas-hoult">Superman review</a> for our full DC coverage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-know-about-james-gunn-dcu-video-games-rocksteady-batman-superman]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Addresses Concerns Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds Will Be Sold As a Game-Key Card on Nintendo Switch 2, Confirms The 'Full Base Game' Will Be Included]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included-on-the-64gb-cartridge</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included.1246020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sonic-racing-crossworlds"><u>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds </u></a>will be sold as a physical Nintendo Switch game with the "full base game" included on a 64GB cartridge.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 2 Game-Key Cards are physical cards that contain a key to download your chosen game. That means there’s no actual game data on the card you insert into your Switch 2, and you’ll instead need to download the full game once the card is inserted. Every Game-Key Card case should be appropriately labeled on the front of the box, but the practice <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-key-cards-a-little-disheartening-the-thing-remastered-dev-says"><u>has been troubling some gamers</u></a>, especially those who prefer to physically own their games, not just license them digitally.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is particularly good news for Sonic fans because there had been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1lmsid4/sonic_racing_crossworlds_might_be_a_game_key_card/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>confusion and conflicting reports about CrossWorlds in particular</u></a>. Now, however, Sega has removed all doubt, confirming in a new <a href="https://www.sega.com/news/sonic-racing-crossworlds-nintendo-switch-2-faq" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>FAQ</u></a> that "the physical version will feature the full base game on a 64GB cartridge." </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The FAQ also confirmed that crossplay will be available for Nintendo Switch 2 players, progress will carry over from the original Switch to the newer edition, and yes, there will be a $10 upgrade pack for anyone hoping to upgrade to the Switch 2 version in the future. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">By contrast, Square Enix was criticised by fans earlier this week for confirming there would be "no upgrade path" for its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-1-2-hd-2d-remake-first-impressions-classic-dq-has-never-looked-so-good">Dragon Quest 1 &amp; 2 HD-2D Remake</a> on Switch 2, and that its save files would not be compatible across platforms. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega has said CrossWorlds will feature a huge roster of over playable characters, if you include DLC. Characters you’d expect to see, such as Sonic, Dr. Eggman, Knuckles, Shadow, and Tails are present and correct, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-racing-crossworlds-reveals-nickelodeon-collaboration-that-adds-spongebob-squarepants-avatar-and-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-guest-characters"><u>but now you can add the likes of SpongeBob SquarePants, Avatar, and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles into the mix</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">CrossWorlds is, of course, going up against Switch 2 exclusive kart game Mario Kart World, which has so far resisted adding guest characters from outside Nintendo's portfolio. Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is set for release on both the Switch and the Switch 2, so it looks like we’ll be set for some old-fashioned Mario vs. Sonic kart racing rivalry when Sega's effort launches in September.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently went <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-racing-crossworlds-hands-on-preview"><u>hands-on with Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</u></a> and came away impressed. “It’s a vibe,” we said, “and one that I’ve enjoyed and will look forward to drifting through.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included-on-the-64gb-cartridge]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox's New Safety Features Include an AI That Will Guess Your Age Based on a Video Selfie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie.1246017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The company claims new features will help keep teens on platform, where conversations can be moderated.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox has announced a new range of safety features directed specifically at teenagers ages 13-17, including a new age estimation technology that uses AI to guess a user's age based on a video selfie they submit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/07/advancing-safety-on-roblox-with-age-based-communication" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Today's announcement</a> reveals several new features being implemented in Roblox that the company claims will improve teen and child safety on its platform. At the core of the announcement are new features specifically for teens ages 13-17, giving them more freedom on the platform than younger children but still less than adults. Teens will be able to designate "trusted connections" on Roblox, with whom they will be able to chat on the platform without filters. Per Roblox, the goal is to better monitor conversations teens are having on Roblox rather than having them lured to third-party platforms where unmonitored conversations could become inappropriate.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Trusted connections are intended to be set between users who know one another well, and if a teen intends to set someone 18+ as a trusted connection, they can only do so using a QR code scanner or a contact importer.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the past, Roblox has relied on the submission of a government ID verifying that users are 13+ or 18+ to unlock certain platform chat features. However, it is now implementing an alternative verification method. Individuals can submit a "video selfie" to Roblox, and an AI will determine if it believes the person in question is 13+ by analyzing it against "a large, diverse dataset." Google began <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/02/12/google-to-test-using-ai-to-determine-users-ages.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">testing a similar feature earlier this year</a>, as did <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/09/instagram-teen-accounts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meta the year prior</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to these changes, Roblox is also adding new tools such as online status controls, a do not disturb mode, and parental controls for parents who have linked their accounts to a teenage's account.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox has long been in an uncomfortable spotlight regarding its handling of children's safety. In 2018, it made headlines when <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-bans-players-who-gang-raped-a-seven-year-olds-avatar" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a mother reported her seven-year-old daughter's Roblox character was violently sexually assaulted</a> by other players in-game, and separately a six-year-old girl playing Roblox was <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2018/06/05/girl-6-invited-sex-room-playing-childrens-video-game-roblox-7605376/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reportedly invited into a "sex room"</a>. In 2021, People Make Games published a report on the ways in which <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_gXlauRB1EQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Roblox's business model allegedly exploits child labor</a>. In 2022, Roblox faced <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/lawsuit-accuses-roblox-of-enabling-sexual-exploitation" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a San Francisco lawsuit accusing it</a> of enabling the financial and sexual exploitation of a 10-year-old girl. In 2023, it was sued both for <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-accused-of-facilitating-illegal-gambling-ring-for-minors" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">allegedly facilitating</a> "an illegal gambling ecosystem" and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-faces-new-lawsuit-claiming-it-lacks-child-safety-measures" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more generally</a> for having lax child safety protocols that allegedly led to financial loss and children's exposure to adult content. Just last year, Bloomberg published a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">damning report highlighting the prevalence of child predators on the platform</a>. That same year, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-reported-over-13000-incidents-to-the-national-center-for-missing-and-exploited-children-in-2023" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the platform claimed</a> it reported over 13,000 incidents of child exploitation to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children in the year 2023, resulting in the arrest of 24 individuals who allegedly preyed on children through the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Safety has always been foundational to everything we do at Roblox," said Roblox chief safety officer Matt Kaufman in a statement alongside today's new feature news. "Our goal is to lead the world in safety and civility for online gaming. We are dedicated to supporting experiences that are both deeply engaging, and empowering for players of all ages, while continuously innovating how users connect and interact."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala Are the FC 26 Cover Stars — and Fans Are Now Wondering if the 'Madden Curse' Has Spread to Soccer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-%E2%80%94-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer.1246014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s that time of the year again and EA has revealed the cover stars of its next soccer game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ea-sports-fc-26">FC 26</a>. But this go around there’s concern that the infamous 'Madden curse' has spread to EA’s soccer series, after joint cover stars Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala suffered significant injuries that left them facing lengthy spells on the sidelines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It’s really nice to share this moment with Jamal, as a reflection of how far we’ve come,” said Real Madrid and England midfield star Bellingham in a comment accompanying the announcement.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I remember our times rooming together in the England Youth team, we’d play the game all the time. Where I’m from, everyone knows the game, everyone plays it and talks about it so much. I’m grateful to be given the opportunity to be on the cover again.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And here’s a comment from Bayern Munich and Germany forward Musiala: “When I found out I’d be on the cover of FC, it was such a crazy feeling. I thought, how could I tell my little brother? He’s a big fan of the game, so this will be a nice surprise for him. It’s something I always wanted growing up and it’s such a big part of football culture. Who knows, maybe I can still beat Jude at FC.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The problem is, both players are injured and are set to miss a significant chunk of the next season. Let’s start with Bellingham. The 22-year-old just had surgery on a long-standing shoulder injury that’s set to keep him out of the game for up to four months. That means he’s going to miss the start of next season and may not return until November.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worse for Musiala, though. He suffered a horrible injury playing at the Club World Cup that rules him out for between four and five months. After breaking his leg and dislocating his ankle in the same incident, the 22-year-old is set for a long absence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All this means FC 26 launches in September with both its cover stars unable to play the game. One potentially won’t play again until 2026. Hardly ideal for the marketers at EA Sports, who must be wondering whether they are now cursed.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/image001-1752748823131.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala both face lengthy spells on the sidelines. Image credit: EA Sports.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Madden curse fan theory suggests any athlete who appears on the cover of Madden NFL suffers a downturn in their career, either from an injury or generally underperforming. The long-standing Madden curse most recently afflicted Madden NFL 25 cover star Christian McCaffrey of the San Francisco 49ers, who was shifted to the injured reserve list due to calf tightness and achilles tendinitis one month after he graced the cover of the latest American football entry from EA Sports, which arrived August 13, 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.cbssports.com/nfl/news/does-madden-nfl-cover-curse-still-exist-a-look-back-at-25-years-of-covers-after-christian-mccaffrey-nod/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>CBS Sports</u></a> analyzed the history of the Madden curse upon McCaffrey's announcement as 2024's cover star, deeming that, between 2000 and 2024, 58% of players struggled after appearing on the cover.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA’s FIFA series — now FC — has a long way to go before a ‘FIFA curse’ spreads online, but perhaps FC 26 has started something new. FC 26 launches across PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X and S, Xbox One, PC, Amazon Luna, Nintendo Switch, and Nintendo Switch 2 on September 26, 2025, with early access through the Ultimate Edition beginning September 19, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>