<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:47:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Biggest Magic: The Gathering Crashers and Climbers This Week - October 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-magic-the-gathering-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-october-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-biggest-magic-the-gathering-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-october-17.1328098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The Slidey Spideys.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">After a short hiatus, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> Crashers and Climbers are back - and there are some decent drops on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/spider-man-magic-the-gathering-card-reveal-spoiler-spider-verse"><u>Spider-Man</u></a> cards that you may have on your radar.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some fun synergies popping off, too, leading to climbs for cards that came out when I was 8 years old - a poignant reminder that, like death and taxes, Magic is forever.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s get into it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">MTG Crashers This Week</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/crashers-and-climbers-template-1-1760711005285.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that the Spider-Man set is here, a lot of the pre-launch pricing has settled down and that means you can grab some fantastic cards on the (relative) cheap.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QmOnvv?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Gwenom, Remorseless</u></a> is down to just $13 now, and is a 4/4 with deathtouch and lifelink who can play card from the top of your library. The fun thing is that you pay for those cards with life instead of mana, hence why that lifelink keyword is handy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up in Spidey’s baddies, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9l23MO?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Norman Osborn/Green Goblin</u></a> is a 1/1 that can’t be blocked, triggering Connive and giving him the potential to climb in power. Pay the mana cost, and he turns into Green Goblin, able to cheapen spells from the graveyard that you discarded through Connive. He’s $15 now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QdpbNZ?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Anti-Venom, Horrifying Healer</u></a> we’ve already touched on, and he’s now $12 or so. I’m personally planning to pick him up once we get to around the $10 mark I think.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up, the meme-worthy <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBDglJ?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Imposter Syndrome</u></a> has levelled out at around $10. It lets you create a non-legendary copy of a creature that attacked.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, if you wanted to build a five-color Spider-Verse deck, <u>Cosmic Spider-Man</u> is just $10 now. He’s got a ton of keywords that he transfers to other Spider Hero characters, and makes an ideal Commander for anyone looking to drop a ton of them into the same deck</p><h2 data-cy="title2">MTG Climbers This Week</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/crashers-and-climbers-template-2-1760711178228.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Number one on our climbers this week is <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRMn51?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mortuary</u></a>, a card that’s 27 years old and basically bounces creatures from your graveyard straight to the top of your library.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s simple enough, and it’s been a few dollars at most. Now, TCGPlayer has it climbing to around $30 thanks to the emergence of Gwenom, Remorseless, which can pay life to cast cards from the top of your library.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up, when is a Turtle Ninja not a Ninja Turtle? When it’s <a href="https://zdcs.link/akwKJn?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Taeko, the Patient Avalanche</u></a>, of course. Nothing to do with the upcoming TMNT set, this card enters tapped and powers up as cards leave the battlefield without dying. It’s reached $15, having been around $5 just a week or two ago. Turtle power, indeed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up, <a href="https://zdcs.link/aADgqo?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Attunement</u></a> came out in 1998 and works very nicely for turning Norman Osborn into Green Goblin and causing chaos. Did the designers in 1998 ever anticipate that sentence? It’s unlikely, but the card is up to $11 right now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a013g5?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Goryo’s Vengeance</u></a> is a nice bit of graveyard recursion that gets you flinging a big nasty from the graveyard back for one last hurrah, all for just two mana. It’s up to $15.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/av34rx?object_uuid=738dc19d-c127-4416-ae4a-acad309351c8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Entangler</u></a> is a very fun one. It pairs with Anti-Venom, Horrifying Healer (more from him shortly), allowing him to block multiple creatures at once. That’s particularly useful given he ends up negating that damage and powering up with counters in return. After being under a dollar, Entangler is now reaching closer to $10.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.</p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 17, 2025 5:00 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-magic-the-gathering-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-october-17]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox Updates This Weekend: 17-19 Oct Event Roundup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/roblox-weekly-updates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-updates-this-weekend-17-19-oct-event-roundup.1328092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Halloween may still be a couple of weeks away, but that hasn't stopped many of the most popular Roblox experiences from starting their celebrations. This weekend is packed with Roblox updates for the spooky season, so here's a roundup of everything you can expect.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Friday October 17th Roblox Updates:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Several experiences are getting their updates in before the weekend starts, giving you plenty of time to participate in them. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Anime Eternal Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/anime-eternal-roundup-1760708752658.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">First up is Anime Eternal, which is a fighting game that will take you through different anime-inspired worlds as you level up and build your strength to be the strongest player. This experience is planning to release <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/3828468475764671127" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Update 20</a><strong> in three parts</strong>. These are planned to launch today, with the second part due on Sunday, 19th October. The final part will conclude on Wednesday, 22nd October. The new updates are set to add a new island, champions, powers, and overall quality of life improvements.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Adopt Me! Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/adopt-me-roundup-1760708821332.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Following this is Adopt Me! This notoriously adorable experience that lets you collect and trade pets has already launched Halloween content. Today (October 17) <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/5646735073047478830" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halloween will be transformed</a>, and there's a new Cryptid to be adopted. This is a four-in-one pet, which can be changed at the press of a button. There are also <strong>games to</strong> <strong>earn Candy Corn and a Slimingo</strong> you need to track down.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Don't Wake the Brainrots Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/brainrots-wake-roundup-1760708942148.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Don't Wake the Brainrots, which is a game where you sneak around and steal sleeping Brainrots, is launching its<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/772200168546894384" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Huge Halloween Event</a>. The update is expected to add new mutations and new Brainrots as part of this limited-time celebration. There are also special guests reported to be turning up for their admin abuse that will take part on Sunday, 19th October. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Dandy's World Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/dandys-world-roundup-1760708978523.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">It's no surprise that the survival horror experience where you work together to explore the Gardenview Center is making the most of the spooky season. Dandy's World already launched its Halloween content last week, adding new Halloween toons, skins, and a limited-time Halloween floor. You can expect to see <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/8910346076099969655" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">even more skins</a> arrive in today's update.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Looking for </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dandys-world-codes"><strong>Dandy's World codes</strong></a><strong>? Check out our page for newly released codes that coincide with events and any that are still currently active. </strong></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Saturday October 18th Roblox Updates:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Heading into the weekend, you'll see the most-played Roblox experiences launch their usual weekly content. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">99 Nights in the Forest Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/99nights-roundup-1760709020986.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">99 Nights in the Forest has sat near the top of the Roblox charts for months, showing that survival horror isn't just for Halloween. For the unfamiliar, the game involves trying to keep your character fed, warm, and sheltered while you rescue missing children and avoid a dangerous deer-like entity at night. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Naturally, the game is also keen to get into the Halloween spirit. <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/8114024574934057586" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Halloween: Week 1</a> begins in 99 Nights in the Forest on Saturday, October 18th. There isn't much information to go on right now, but from the looks of the picture, I'd expect to see some cultists showing up to trick or treat.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Planning to outrun the deer this weekend? See our </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/99-nights-in-the-forest-codes"><strong>99 Nights in the Forest Codes page</strong></a><strong> for extra gems.</strong></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Grow a Garden Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/gag-roundup-1760709049462.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The gardening simulator, Grow a Garden, has an abundance of seeds, pets, and mutations to discover as you plant, harvest, and sell your crops. It's already launched a <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/9186397504608666231" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halloween event with Ghoul Garden</a>, where you can help the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/grow-a-garden/Ghoul_Garden_Event">witch fill her cauldron</a> and earn Candy Corn to spend at the spooky market. In typical GaG fashion, the event will be extended and continue for a second week. Though it's not clear yet what this will involve, you can always expect new seeds, pets, weather events, and admin abuse before the event starts.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Steal a Brainrot Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/sab-roundup-1760709127161.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Steal a Brainrot is a particularly popular Roblox experience where you'll need to capture Brainrots from a conveyor belt and keep them locked away from other players. You can steal Brainrots and have your Brainrots stolen, so we advise you stick close to that lockdown button if you want to protect your Secret Brainrots. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following on from last week's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/steal-a-brainrot/Witch_Fuse_Update">Witch Fuse event</a>, Steal a Brainrot is launching another update this weekend. Last week, there were new Halloween fusions and themed Brainrots, with La Spooky Grande available to those who collected all four Spooky Brainrots. The details for the <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/8532495578259260020" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">next update</a> haven't been revealed yet, but we're hoping it continues the spooky theme.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Plants vs Brainrots Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/pvbroundupo-1760709173536.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">This experience, which is a fusion of Grow a Garden, Steal a Brainrot, and Plants Vs Zombies, has quickly climbed the Roblox charts and is regularly releasing new content. In this game, you'll plant seeds that attack Brainrots, helping you capture them. As you earn money, you can unlock better plants and take down rarer Brainrots. Last weekend PVB launched the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/plants-vs-brainrots/How_to_Get_Cards">Cards Update</a>, and this weekend will also introduce new content. While no details have been revealed, it's claiming to be an "<a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/854537099309482613" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">epic update</a>", so watch this space. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Grab yourself some money and gear with our </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/plants-vs-brainrots-codes"><strong>Plants Vs Brainrots Codes</strong></a><strong>.</strong></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Fisch Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/fischfright-1760709224673.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The fishing simulator with over 400,000+ variations to collect is also joining in with the seasonal fun and launching <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/2968047596632539696" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FischFright</a>. Considering some of the things that lurk at the bottom of the ocean, there's plenty of opportunity for Fisch to include some truly terrifying specimens.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Sunday October 19th Roblox Updates:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Sunday is a quieter day for Roblox updates. There's just one major update we can see taking place from one of the top experiences, and that's Fish It!</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Fish It! Update</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/fishit-1760709285774.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Who knew that the people playing Roblox were so into fishing? Fish It! is similar to Fisch, but offers a few more variations for you to collect (1,000,000+ to be a bit more exact). If you want a double dose of scary fishing experiences this weekend, then Fish It! rounds off the week with their <a href="https://www.roblox.com/events/8174015307124048435" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halloween Event</a>. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>If you need some extra luck and potions, see our</strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fish-it-codes"><strong> Fish It! Codes Page.</strong></a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">That's everything for Roblox updates this weekend, but there's undoubtedly plenty more Halloween content on the way for the rest of October.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/roblox-weekly-updates]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The PDP Riffmaster Wireless Guitar Controller Now Has a Switch and Switch 2 Version]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-pdp-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-now-has-a-switch-and-switch-2-version</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-pdp-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-now-has-a-switch-and-switch-2-version.1328086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fortnite Festival sure does seem to be bringing guitar controllers back.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://corp.turtlebeach.com/news/news-details/2025/TURTLE-BEACH-LAUNCHES-THE-OFFICIALLY-LICENSED-RIFFMASTER-WIRELESS-GUITAR-CONTROLLER-FOR-NINTENDO-SWITCH--NINTENDO-SWITCH-2-2025-GEbX0SETYJ/default.aspx" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Turtle Beach has released</a> an updated version of the <a href="https://www.turtlebeach.com/products/riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller?Platform=Nintendo+Switch" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PDP Riffmaster Wireless Guitar Controller</a> that works with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/09/27/nintendo-switch-review-2018">Nintendo Switch</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-review">Switch 2</a>. For those not familiar, PDP released the same guitar for Xbox and PlayStation consoles previously – <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pdp-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-review">IGN gave a great review</a> to the PlayStation version, in fact. Like those controllers, this one costs $149.99.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new controller can hold a connection up to 30 feet from a Switch or Switch 2, and gets up to 36 hours of play time on a charge. (It's rechargeable via USB-C.) Like the other iterations of this controller, it's collapsible and ships with a shoulder strap. The Riffmaster has an analog stick, strum bar, whammy bar, and 10 fretboard buttons – five at the top of the neck and five more near the body for all those sick shreds you'll be doing. On the pickguard – that's the part that holds the strum and whammy bars – there's also a Home button, plus and minus button, capture button, and d-pad. Alas, there is no GameChat button.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">PDP Riffmaster Guitar for Switch and Switch 2</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But wait, where are you going to do all that shredding? Yeah, so, if you weren't aware of <em>Fortnite Festival</em>, it's essentially a <em>Rock Band</em> mode inside <em>Fortnite</em>, created by the folks at the Epic-owned Harmonix, who were behind those classic rhythm games. As <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-festival-review">IGN's review</a> found, though, the game didn't quite reach the heights of those hallowed titles at launch. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Turtle Beach isn't the only one out there releasing guitar-shaped controllers lately. CRKD also put out a pair of officially-licensed Gibson Les Paul controllers, which <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crkd-gibson-les-paul-guitar-controllers-review">IGN's Jacqueline Thomas found</a> were great, partially because they had advanced the formula a bit with features like haptics in the strum bar and mechanical buttons, at least in the Pro Edition. Plus, it's a cheaper controller, <a href="https://crkd.gg/products/lp-black-tribal-multi-platform" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">starting at $114.99</a> for the multi-platform (read: Switch-compatible) Encore Edition. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PDP Riffmaster Wireless Guitar Controller for the Switch and Switch 2 is available now at Turtle Beach's website or on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Riffmaster-Wireless-Controller-Nintendo-Gaming-Console/dp/B0FTZV2JHG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon</a> for $149.99.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wes is a freelance writer (Freelance Wes, they call him) who has covered technology, gaming, and entertainment steadily since 2020 at Gizmodo, Tom's Hardware, Hardcore Gamer, and most recently, The Verge. Inside of him there are two wolves: one that thinks it wouldn't be so bad to start collecting game consoles again, and the other who also thinks this, but more strongly.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-pdp-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-now-has-a-switch-and-switch-2-version]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>