<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 17:07:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Armored Core 6 for PS5 Drops to $20 in Amazon and Best Buy’s Presidents’ Day Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/armored-core-6-for-ps5-drops-to-20-in-amazon-and-best-buys-presidents-day-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/armored-core-6-for-ps5-drops-to-20-in-amazon-and-best-buy%E2%80%99s-presidents%E2%80%99-day-sales.1111479/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/armored-core-6-for-ps5-drops-to-20-in-amazon-and-best-buys-presidents-day-sales<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Don't miss out on this excellent Presidents' Day deal.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Presidents' Day marks one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/presidents-day-sales-2025">first big sale events of the year</a>, and if you've been looking to save on video games there's been a fantastic variety on sale to look through. One of our favorite video game deals at the moment is on Armored Core 6: Fires of Rubicon for PS5, which is down to just $20 at <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6oxAR?object_uuid=b334e10f-f36a-438b-993d-6f7c2c5c2c2b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0BX4KZ5PJ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpX2vY?object_uuid=b334e10f-f36a-438b-993d-6f7c2c5c2c2b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Best Buy</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This marks a 67% price drop from its $59.99 list price and a return to its lowest price yet, according to price tracker <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0BX4KZ5PJ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">camelcamelcamel</a>. If you've been hoping to dive into its masterful world of mechs, now's your chance to do it and save some cash in the process.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Armored Core 6: Fires of Rubicon for $20</h2><div catalogid="67dfd403-1dd4-42da-b995-af653e5dc840" id="215405"><div id="215405" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>BANDAI NAMCO Entertainment Armored Core VI Fires of Rubicon - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're still on the fence about adding this game to your collection, it's worth noting that we had a lot of praise for it in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/armored-core-6-fires-of-rubicon-review">review</a>. IGN's Mitchell Saltzman said, "Armored Core 6 doesn’t look to reinvent the bipedal legs of the mech action genre, but it does update, refine, and polish them to an aggressive shine." He also mentions that it's "a welcome return of a classic mecha series."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for even more game deals available during this sale event, have a look through our roundup of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/video-game-deals-presidents-day-sale-2025">best video game deals to shop during Presidents' Day sales</a>. Right now some of the best offerings can be found at <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-presidents-day-sale-2025">Best Buy</a>, including discounts on big releases like Metaphor: ReFantazio, Dragon Age: The Veilguard, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To see even more gaming deals, make sure to check out our individual roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PlayStation deals</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo Switch deals</a> to see the latest and greatest discounts for each platform. For an overall look at the highlights for each console, have a look at our breakdown of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-game-deals">best video game deals</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Feb 17, 2025 3:02 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why You Should Play Monster Hunter: World Before Wilds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/why-you-should-play-monster-hunter-world-before-wilds</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-you-should-play-monster-hunter-world-before-wilds.1111473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/why-you-should-play-monster-hunter-world-before-wilds<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As one of Steam’s most pre-ordered games right now, we know <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is going to be massive. We also know that Wilds will be some people’s first Monster Hunter game. While we’re sure it will have a solid enough tutorial for newcomers, the series is undeniably dense and complex, and so if Wilds is your first go at hunting monsters you may find value in trying one of the previous games first. So before hopping into the vast and dangerous expanse of Monster Hunter Wilds, there’s one game we really recommend you check out: 2018’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-world">Monster Hunter: World</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We don’t recommend Wold because of some big narrative tie-in or cliffhanger ending that will leave you lost and confused when you embark on Wild's central plotline. We suggest it simply because Monster Hunter: World is the game that most closely resembles Wilds’ style and structure. Playing World is a great way to onboard yourself and prepare for the sometimes obtuse systems and gameplay loop the series lives and thrives on.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2022/11/08/monsterhunterworld-blogroll-1516867463450-1667927878979.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Monster Hunter: World shares much in common with the upcoming Monster Hunter Wilds. | Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Monster Hunter: World?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve kept up with Capcom’s recent releases, you might already be asking, “Should I not play <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-rise">Monster Hunter Rise</a>, the most recent game in the series, rather than go back to Monster Hunter: World?” It’s a valid question. But while Rise is the most recent Monster Hunter (and a very good game!), it's clear that Monster Hunter Wilds is a direct successor to 2018’s World rather than 2021’s Rise. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rise may have refined the series’ signature gameplay with rideable mounts, the high-flying Wirebug grapple mechanic, and a few other flashy tricks, but they arrived at the expense of some of the larger and more layered seamless zones that World boasted. You see, while Rise is available on every platform these days, it was originally built for the Nintendo Switch, and that console’s more modest specs informed several of the creative decisions. This resulted in an emphasis on speed and smaller scale zones, which expedited the hunt-upgrade-hunt gameplay loop but lost some of the larger scale and fascinating friction of World. It is those elements that Rise dropped that Wilds seems to be trying to recapture and build upon. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>World feels like the blueprint that Wilds’ much larger open areas are drawing from. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter: World features large zones and an emphasis on tracking monsters and other living beings through a detailed ecosystem, and so World feels like the blueprint that Wilds’ much larger open areas are drawing from. This is why we believe World is the perfect game to prepare you for what’s to come. Those more open zones, which act as stages for long, thrilling hunts stretched across wide swathes of varied terrain, is where modern Monster Hunter shines. We expect Wilds to deliver on all that, but why wait when you can get an early, informative taste of it in World?  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite seeming like a direct successor, it’s important to note that Monster Hunter Wilds’ story isn't a continuation of the tale told in World. However, World’s approach to story and campaign structure will set your expectations appropriately for the direction of Wilds’ story. You’ll meet staple organizations like the Hunter’s Guild governing body, as well as your adorable feline sidekicks, the Palicos, all of which will be present in Wilds. However, these elements will be wholly unconnected from previous (and, most likely, future) entries. Think of all this as being like the Final Fantasy series, in which each entry is known to feature your bearded friend Cid, a massive Behemoth, bright yellow Chocobos, and other defining monsters roaming throughout the land, but all the games are distinct and unconnected, which allows every entry to put its own stamp on classic ideas.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Practice, Practice, Practice</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Above and beyond getting a preliminary understanding of the Monster Hunter universe and how the Wilds’ campaign will be structured, the strongest case for playing Monster Hunter: World first lies in the game's challenging combat. Monster Hunter Wilds’ action is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/monster-hunter-wilds/Weapons">built around 14 weapons</a>, each with their own playstyle and strategies. All 14 of them are also present in Monster Hunter: World, which means you can get a headstart on becoming comfortable with the eclectic systems that govern this series’ genuinely one-of-a-kind combat. Diving into World is a great way to familiarize yourself with each weapon’s techniques and decide which one suits your personal tastes and playstyle the best. Whether it's the quick and flashy dual-blades or the hulking greatsword, each weapon in Monster Hunter is distinct and demands focus to master. So consider Monster Hunter: World a training ground where you can learn weapon basics and build up proficiency. By the time you get to Wilds, you’ll be well on your way to becoming a master of your craft. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets1.ignimgs.com/2017/10/31/monster-hunter-world-pgw-01-26267147179-o-1509411295879.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Learning the intricacies of bows, swords, and switch axes is a big part of Monster Hunter. | Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the Monster Hunter series your weapon is everything. You don't level up and gain skill points through experience or other traditional RPG mechanics. Instead, all of your abilities and stats are delivered through your weapon. Think of your weapon like a character class or job in a more traditional action RPG – each one dictates your role on the battlefield and how you approach each and every hunt. Playing World will teach you how these weapons can be leveled up using parts collected from slain monsters, and how to build toward the higher-level weapons on your weapon tree.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Furthermore, World teaches you early on that you can't just mash your attack button through most situations. The positioning of your character and angle of your attacks are the key to victory, rather than raw damage output. Knowledge of where on a monster’s body your weapon can have the most impact is half the battle. The Longsword is great for slicing off monsters' tails or long appendages, for instance, while the hammer is great for knocking enemies over by bonking them on the head hard enough. Knowing how best to utilize a specific weapon can turn the tide of any battle and set you up for success, so it's certainly worth hopping into Monster Hunter: World and getting familiar with where you can deal devastating damage to your enemies. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Having a solid understanding of the tempo of each hunt will be a huge advantage going into Wilds. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Your weapon is only one piece of World’s equation though. The Slinger is a tool attached to your hunter's left arm that allows you to use special gadgets and ammunition in a fight. Learning when to shoot a Flash Pod to blind an enemy monster or toss out some poison knives for chip damage can make or break a fight. The Slinger returns in Wilds, and knowing how to pepper in shots throughout a fight will take your game to the next level. You'll need to craft Slinger ammo from ingredients gathered from the environment, so having some familiarity with World’s crafting menus and recipes will go a long way when you start using Wilds’ own versions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Once you've got to grips with World’s weapons and tools you'll begin to peel back the Monster Hunter series’ other recurring layers. Your general gameplay loop begins with following monster tracks, hoping to uncover the whereabouts of the beast in question. Along the way you'll use your pickaxe to mine ore, gather some honey for potion crafting, and grab whatever other materials you find along the way to the monster's location. It all becomes second-nature after a while, and having a solid understanding of the tempo of each hunt will be a huge advantage going into Wilds. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">A hunt is not about rushing in, getting a quick kill, and moving on. Each expedition is designed to take some time, especially on the first go around. Learning how to dance with the fire-breathing Anjanath is leagues away from understanding the best equipment to prepare against something like the bomb-dropping Bazelgeuse, but understanding all of the different facets of these creatures builds foundational knowledge. And with Monster Hunter Wilds looking to capture the scope and scale of these adventures in a similar way to how World revels in the spectacle, it means the 2018 entry is the ideal training ground. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Plus, if you need yet another reason to check out Monster Hunter World ahead of Wilds’ release, you can get some free Palico armor if you import save data from World into Wilds, and an additional set of armor if you have data from World’s massive Iceborne expansion. It's a small thing, but dressing up your Palico never gets old. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While you never need to play a prior Monster Hunter game before starting a new one, Capcom’s RPG is a distinctly different animal than any other game out there. While the developer has been working hard to make the learning curve easier with each new game, there are so many unique systems that really the only way to truly prepare for Monster Hunter is by playing Monster Hunter. While there will be many who will find joy jumping right into the new game blind, there's never been a better time to try out Monster Hunter: World and familiarize yourself with the vernacular and community ahead of Wilds’ launch on February 28, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jesse Vitelli is a freelance writer and published author. A former associate editor at Prima Games, he also has bylines at Kotaku, Inverse, Game Informer, and more. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Dev Blizzard Welcomes Marvel Rivals Competition, Says It’s Never Faced Another Game ‘So Similar to the One We've Created’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-dev-blizzard-welcomes-marvel-rivals-competition-says-its-never-faced-another-game-so-similar-to-the-one-weve-created</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-dev-blizzard-welcomes-marvel-rivals-competition-says-it%E2%80%99s-never-faced-another-game-%E2%80%98so-similar-to-the-one-weve-created%E2%80%99.1111380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-dev-blizzard-welcomes-marvel-rivals-competition-says-its-never-faced-another-game-so-similar-to-the-one-weve-created<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a> was, from the moment it was revealed, compared to Overwatch. Taken at face value, Marvel Rivals is remarkably similar to Blizzard’s game; while Marvel Rivals uses Marvel heroes and villains for its playable characters, it is, like Overwatch, a competitive multiplayer hero shooter with some remarkably similar mechanics and gameplay systems. Both Marvel Heroes and Overwatch 2 are free-to-play, monetized as live services, and lean on the addition of new characters to keep things feeling fresh.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-is-a-smash-hit-with-10-million-players-in-just-3-days">Marvel Rivals has enjoyed explosive popularity</a> since launching in December, and it is speculated that this has come at the cost of interest in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/overwatch-2">Overwatch 2</a>. Blizzard’s game, according to the current narrative, is dwindling as NetEase’s Marvel Rivals gobbles up its players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fps/overwatch-2-director-welcomes-competition-from-marvel-rivals-as-the-team-have-never-really-had-another-game-thats-so-similar-to-the-one-that-weve-created/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GamesRadar</a>, Overwatch 2 director Aaron Keller discussed the new reality Blizzard finds itself in, with Marvel Rivals now out in the wild and attracting tens of millions of players.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Overwatch 2 Perks</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We're obviously in a new competitive landscape that I think, for Overwatch, we've never really been in before, to this extent where there's another game that's so similar to the one that we've created," Keller said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’d think this would be a bad thing for Overwatch, then, but Keller called the situation “exciting,” and even said it was “really great” to see Marvel Rivals take ideas established by Overwatch in a “different direction.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, Keller admitted Marvel Rivals’ success had forced a change in attitude within Blizzard when it comes to Overwatch 2, saying: “this is no longer about playing it safe."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To that end, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/blizzard-reveals-radical-overhaul-of-overwatch-2-including-return-of-loot-boxes-perks-and-third-person-mode">Blizzard has announced radical changes coming to Overwatch 2 in 2025</a>. While the roadmap ahead includes much of what you'd expect to see in terms of new content, the core gameplay itself will see a seismic shift, including the additions of hero perks and the return of loot boxes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All eyes will be on Overwatch 2 to see if these changes spark a resurgence in interest. We're now nearly nine years out from the debut of Overwatch in 2016, and two-and-a-half from the launch of Overwatch 2. And while Blizzard does not make Overwatch player numbers public, we can see concurrent player numbers on Steam are as low as they’ve ever been since Overwatch 2 launched on Valve’s platform in 2023, with a 37,046 concurrent player peak over the last 24 hours.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marvel Rivals, meanwhile, remains a top 10 most-played game on Steam, with a 310,287 concurrent player peak over the last 24 hours.</p><div id="marvel-rivals-tier-list-best-heroes" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Marvel Rivals Tier List: Best Heroes</h3><h3>Marvel Rivals Tier List: Best Heroes</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Overwatch 2 still has a ‘mostly negative’ user review rating on Steam. Indeed, in August 2023, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-becomes-worst-user-reviewed-game-on-steam-ever-even-as-tens-of-thousands-turn-up-to-play">Overwatch 2 became the worst user-reviewed game on Steam ever</a>. Most of the negative reviews focused on monetization after Blizzard was heavily-criticised for forcing its premium predecessor to update into a free-to-play sequel, rendering the original Overwatch unplayable, back in 2022. Overwatch 2 subsequently endured a number of controversies including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-pve-hero-mode-canceled-a-difficult-choice"><u>the cancellation of its long-awaited PvE Hero mode</u></a> — the one feature, players said, that justified the sequel's existence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has loads more on Marvel Rivals, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-says-theyre-not-trolling-dataminers-wed-rather-spend-our-time-developing-the-game">the developer's clarification on datamining</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-developer-is-open-to-potential-future-release-on-nintendo-switch-2">thoughts on the possibility of a Nintendo Switch 2 version</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>