<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:25:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Biggest Pokémon Card Crashers And Climbers This Week - August 28]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-august-28</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-biggest-pok%C3%A9mon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-august-28.1283175/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Crown Zenith market has been sending some mixed signals this month. While some Galarian Gallery Ultra Rares are dipping in value, Secret Rares are heating up thanks to collector demand and limited availability. Mid-tier fan-favorites like <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7NAR?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Leafeon VSTAR</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z1y0V?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Suicune V</a> are seeing downward pressure, while the golden Secret Rares – particularly <a href="https://zdcs.link/aMJk3k?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Giratina VSTAR</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJgB5n?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Arceus VSTAR</a> – continue to climb. Crown Zenith’s overall collector appeal remains high, but the card-to-card movement tells a more nuanced story.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Crashers and Climbers This Week</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the climber side, I’ve seen <a href="https://zdcs.link/aMJk3k?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Giratina VSTAR (Secret)</a> make a strong move from around $152 in July to as high as $180 recently. That’s a healthy 18% jump, and it tracks with what I’m seeing in collector circles: people are still chasing the big four gold cards, and Giratina seems to be the crown jewel. <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qqwlvp?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mewtwo VSTAR</a> has also caught some upward momentum lately, jumping from around $102 to nearly $127. It’s not just about nostalgia with this one – <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAvMk?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">its twin art featuring the Charizard faceoff</a> is iconic and playable decks still find room for it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the flipside, <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7NAR?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Leafeon VSTAR</a> has slipped from its February peak of $49.87 down to about $45.54. That’s not a dramatic crash, but it’s enough to suggest the hype has faded a bit. <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qr2DoN?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Deoxys VMAX</a> is feeling a sharper drop, now sitting around $36 after once approaching $45. These cards were never unplayable, but they’re not commanding the same attention in the meta or from collectors.</p><p id="pokmon-card-crashers"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Card Crashers">Pokémon Card Crashers</h2></p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/28/feature-image-5-1756393956460.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7NAR?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Leafeon VSTAR</a> was riding high earlier this year, mostly on the strength of its gorgeous Galarian Gallery artwork and the general hype around Eeveelutions. But lately, it’s slipped about 9% in value. I think this one’s a mix of over-saturation and fading competitive relevance. Ivy Star is a solid switch ability, and Leaf Guard can wall a bit of damage, but the format’s gotten faster and more aggressive, and Leafeon just isn’t keeping up. It’s still a nice display piece, but with more copies floating around and other Secret Rares taking the spotlight, it’s drifting down.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/znxm48?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Glaceon VSTAR</a> is in a similar boat. It’s down about 10% from its February highs, currently sitting around $43. Crystal Star offers decent protection, and Icicle Shot has some control value, but let’s be honest – no one’s building their deck around this card anymore. Like Leafeon, its value was inflated by early demand from collectors chasing the full Eeveelution spread, but that moment seems to have passed. It’s still a strong artwork, but in today’s market, that’s not enough.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qr2DoN?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Deoxys VMAX</a> has dropped nearly 20% since February, and I’m not surprised. Protective DNA is a cool ability on paper, reducing damage from opposing VSTARs, but it’s a little too niche in practice. Max Drain heals and hits for 160, which was decent a few metas ago, but now it feels underpowered. Players aren’t reaching for it, and collectors are more focused on the cleaner, flashier Secret Rares.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z1y0V?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Suicune V</a> has taken a heavier hit, dropping around 24% since May. This one hurts a little because I still think Blizzard Rondo and Fleet-Footed give it solid play value. But it’s been power-crept hard, and its role in decks has diminished. The artwork is still clean, and there’s nostalgia here, but in the context of the Galarian Gallery, it’s getting outshined. With so many cards in the set, not every V is going to hold long-term value.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9l3W5R?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Raikou V</a> has followed a similar path, slipping about 22% since March. It’s basically Suicune V’s Lightning-type twin, with the same draw ability and scalable damage based on benched Pokémon. Again, decent in a vacuum, but there are just better, more dynamic options now. This feels like a victim of set fatigue – there are too many similar cards in Crown Zenith, and only the top-tier ones are holding collector or player attention.</p><p id="pokmon-card-climbers"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Card Climbers">Pokémon Card Climbers</h2></p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/28/feature-image-4-1756393853900.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: Christian Wait / The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aMJk3k?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Giratina VSTAR (Secret)</a> is having a real moment. It’s jumped nearly 18% in the last month, and honestly, I think it still has more room to grow. Lost Impact and Star Requiem are both game-ending tools in the right deck, and the alt-art gold treatment puts it near the top of many collectors’ wishlists. If you’re looking for a high-end Crown Zenith card to hold, this one feels as stable as it gets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qqwlvp?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mewtwo VSTAR</a> has quietly surged too, climbing around 24% since June. Star Raid and Psy Purge both offer serious utility, especially in matchups where you want to punish your opponent for loading their board with Vs. But let’s be real – this one’s rising just as much for the art as the gameplay. That Charizard vs. Mewtwo scene is one of the most memorable alt-arts in the set, and people are starting to grab it before prices push any higher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/zJgB5n?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Arceus VSTAR (Secret)</a> has seen a solid 14% boost, and it’s one of those cards that straddles playability and collectibility perfectly. Starbirth is still one of the strongest consistency abilities in the game, letting you grab any two cards from your deck. Trinity Nova helps ramp energy quickly, which is never out of style. The gold art has a premium feel, and with Arceus being such a central figure in the franchise, it’s an easy card to like long-term.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QL8g4b?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Origin Forme Dialga VSTAR (Secret)</a> is up 16% since July, and I think people are finally waking up to just how powerful Star Chronos can be. Taking an extra turn is one of the rarest effects in the game, and when paired with the right energy acceleration, it’s absolutely devastating. Metal Blast scales well too. From a collector standpoint, the gear-and-time themed art is eye-catching, and scarcity is keeping demand high.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbbwgx?object_uuid=623c07dd-632c-4e1d-9534-a9037a2d8749&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Finally, Origin Forme Palkia VSTAR (Secret)</a> has climbed around 13%. Star Portal remains one of the best ways to recycle Water Energy, and Subspace Swell scales nicely with full benches, which are common in current lists. The art has a dynamic, aquatic style that’s really grown on people. It may not be as flashy as Giratina, but it’s a steady riser, and I wouldn’t be surprised to see it break the $70 mark soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-august-28]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Year 2 Roadmap Reveals Content Plan for Patch 10 Right Up to 2026's Patch 15, Including New Weapons, a New Class, and]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-year-2-roadmap-reveals-content-plan-for-patch-10-right-up-to-2026s-patch-15-including-new-weapons-a-new-class-and-much-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-year-2-roadmap-reveals-content-plan-for-patch-10-right-up-to-2026s-patch-15-including-new-weapons-a-new-class-and.1283172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Xenos spotted.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> publisher Focus Entertainment has lifted the lid on the game’s second year of DLC, confirming patches 10 all the way up to 15.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 is set for a hefty Anniversary Update on September 4, when patch 10 will add a playable Helbrute in PvP, three new weapons, the Chaos Spawn enemy, and the Black Templars Champion Pack.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But we also have content confirmation for patches 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15, which takes us up to the end of the second quarter of next year (June 2026). There’s plenty to note in here for fans, but highlights include the new Techmarine class, now set for release during the first quarter of 2026, a new Battle Barge expansion during the same period, and a new Siege map coming Q2 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The trailer, below, reveals a first look at some of this new content, including the Chaos Spawn and the Mutalith Vortex Beast, and new weapons the Pyreblaster, Pyrecannon, Power Axe, Combi Melta, and the Xenophase Blade. The latter is a Power Sword-like melee weapon created with alien (we think Necron) tech and used by warriors of the Deathwatch Chapter.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Year 2 content:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Four new Operations and a new Siege map</li><li>Two new Eternal War arenas</li><li>New Stratagems (PvE) and Helbrute Onslaught (PvP) game modes</li><li>New playable class: The Techmarine</li><li>New weapons and free unlockable weapon variants for existing weapons</li><li>New enemies and bosses</li><li>New Progression mechanics</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Black Templars Champion Pack and Imperial Fists Cosmetic Pack</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The September 4 Anniversary Update also comes with the release of Space Marine 2’s second Season Pass and its first two DLCs: the Black Templars Champion Pack and Imperial Fists Cosmetic Pack, including a new Champion skin for the Bulwark class and Power Sword skin for the former, and over 40 new cosmetics celebrating seven of the Imperial Fists’ Successor Chapters for the latter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Year 2 roadmap image, below, mentions the new Omnissiah Axe coming alongside the Techmarine. This is a potentially different weapon than the Power Axe shown off in the trailer, so the hope is it functions in a fresh way as well as looks unique.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Throughout the year, the Season Pass II will grant players nine new DLCs, with new Champion skins, armour pieces, and heraldry markings. While existing Chapters like the Blood Angels and Salamanders are to receive new cosmetics, fan-favorite Chapters like the Raptors, Iron Hands, and Carcharodons will get their due time in the spotlight.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/28/unnamed-12-1756393367664.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Space Marine 2 Year 2 DLC roadmap. Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, developer Saber Interactive is also working on Space Marine 3 while continuing to support the hugely successful Space Marine 2. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/with-the-inquisition-watching-tight-lipped-saber-chief-wont-say-much-about-warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-but-he-has-revealed-games-workshop-is-offering-up-some-ideas-that-are-amazing">IGN recently interviewed Saber development chief Tim Willits to try to prize out Space Marine 3 info</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-year-2-roadmap-reveals-content-plan-for-patch-10-right-up-to-2026s-patch-15-including-new-weapons-a-new-class-and-much-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Learnt from the Arknights: Endfield gamescom Booth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-learnt-from-the-arknights-endfield-gamescom-booth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-learnt-from-the-arknights-endfield-gamescom-booth.1283055/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Are you ready, Endministrator?</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">You may have spotted the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/arknights-endfield-official-trailer-gamescom-2025">brand new trailer</a> for GRYPHLINE's upcoming game Arknights: Endfield, a real-time 3D RPG with strategic gameplay elements, during Opening Night Live, but there was certainly no missing the game's presence on the show floor at gamescom. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As one of the leading game companies from China making a strong push onto the global stage, GRYPHLINE came prepared. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/27/corridor-banner-1756286773472.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption"><strong>Even before reaching Hall 8, visitors walking through gamescom's main corridor were greeted by a 50-meter-long banner for Arknights: Endfield—setting the tone for what awaited inside.</strong></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Arknights: Endfield booth in Hall 8, was a sight to behold. From the three giant LED screens to the towering installation facing the main hallway, the message was clear: this is a world they want you to step into. And judging by the crowds gathered, it worked.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GRYPHLINE  recreated one of the key locations in the game, which will be released on PlayStation, PC, and mobile – an Automated Industry Complex (AIC) – in impressive detail, so that visitors could step inside the world of Endfield Industries and their expansion of the frontiers of the planet Talos-II.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/20/img-9572-1755694152516.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Just like in the game, which was nominated for Best Mobile Game at the 2025 gamescom award, the booth casts you as an 'Endministrator' or Endmin, a guardian who has protected the people of Talos-II and saved the planet from multiple disasters in recent years. You have a unique mastery over the planet's most valuable resource, Originium, and have worked with Endfield Industries to provide pioneering industrial technologies and services that harness its power, in order to forge a future for the budding civilisation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But as well as driving innovation and progress, Endfield also faces threats posed by hostile entities the Aggeloi and The Blight – a mysterious dimensional anomaly that infects and taints any matter it comes into contact with.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Arknights: Endfield gamescom Booth</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Arknights: Endfield's AIC is crucial to establishing the new world on Talos-II and defending its people from these dangers. A form of miniaturised and modularised industrial production line, they process gathered raw materials to generate gear, medicines, food, explosives and more at scale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The gamescom booth featured an AIC's central PAC (Protocol Automation-Core), which towered above a recreation of the Grinding Unit, the Filling Unit, and the Shredding Unit, alongside their input and output crates. Thanks to clever use of magnetic levitation, these crates hover above their winding transport belts, vividly recreating the scene from the game. As they pass through these factory facilities, they transform and reveal their contents in a newly refined state, just like how materials turn into products in the game. Overhead, beams of light and glowing tethers linked electric pylons to the core, adding an additional layer of immersive realism. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/27/2-1756287206192.JPG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption"><strong>The stage also featured appearances by four of Germany's top influencers—Bonjwa, RvNxMango, KingChris, and HoneyPuu—showcasing the Arknights: Endfield gameplay and drawing additional buzz on the show floor.</strong></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Standing beneath the towering Protocol Automation-Core and its intricate production network, it felt as though you’d stepped onto the Automated Industry Complex on Talos-II itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also, during the event, eight cosplayers could be found at the Arknights: Endfield booth, representing a selection of the Operator characters from the game.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/27/jze-0259-1756287381511.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">As well as multiple stations to play Arknights: Endfield on PC, the booth also featured a special event composed of four IRL mini missions, each of which awarded visitors with game merch upon completion. Those who worked through all four could enter a daily raffle for an RTX 5080 graphic card, €500 Amazon gift card, or a deluxe Arknights: Endfield merch bundle.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/27/3-1756287426976.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">At a show full of spectacle, Arknights: Endfield carved out a space that left an impression, bringing its world to life on the show floor. If you're keeping up with our gamescom coverage from afar, there’s still plenty more to discover about  <a href="https://endfield.gryphline.com/en-us/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Arknights: Endfield </a>— stay tuned for what’s next.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-learnt-from-the-arknights-endfield-gamescom-booth]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Big Dawn of War 4 Interview: How a New Developer Took On Warhammer 40,000's Flagship RTS, Why It Returns to Kronus, and Why Chaos Isn't Here… Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-dawn-of-war-4-interview-how-a-new-developer-took-on-warhammer-40000s-flagship-rts-why-it-returns-to-kronus-and-why-chaos-isnt-here-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-big-dawn-of-war-4-interview-how-a-new-developer-took-on-warhammer-40-000s-flagship-rts-why-it-returns-to-kronus-and-why-chaos-isnt-here%E2%80%A6-yet.1283049/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Gamescom’s Opening Night Live is, by its very nature, a show that thrives on big surprises, but few would have tuned in expecting to see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-iv">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War 4</a>. After all, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition">a remaster of the original game</a> had only just arrived days prior, and developer Relic Entertainment – now independent after a decade-plus of being owned by Sega – didn’t seem ready to deliver a massive new Warhammer RTS anytime soon. Not that it needed to be ready, of course. This was a double-hit surprise: not only is Dawn of War 4 real, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-4-is-finally-a-reality-but-its-developer-may-surprise-you">it is being developed by a completely different studio</a> from the rest of the series, King Art Games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">How did this happen? And why, in the lavish new CGI trailer, is there no sign of Gabriel Angelos, the Space Marine poster child of the Dawn of War series? Oh, and where are all the Chaos Marines? And why are the Blood Ravens back on Kronus? These are all the questions I had for Jan Theysen, the co-founder of King Art Games and Dawn of War 4’s creative director, when I met with him on the Gamescom show floor. It all started, he explained, when Games Workshop took an interest in his studio’s previous, Relic-inspired strategy game…  </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: How did you become involved with the project? Was it pitched to you? Or did you pitch it to Games Workshop?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Jan Theysen: </strong>So a couple of years ago we developed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/iron-harvest">Iron Harvest</a>, which was a Kickstarter RTS. And we were very open about the production, so we basically shared a lot of our technology and what we can do and so on. Someone at Games Workshop saw that and they basically came to us and said, ‘Let's say if we were to do Dawn of War 4, what would you guys do with it?’ And so we made a concept and we presented it, and we assumed that they probably asked a bunch of [other] people, so we were not really expecting anything to come out of it. But then Iron Harvest was released and was successful, and so [Games Workshop] came back and basically said, ‘Okay, do you want to talk some more?’ And we asked our Iron Harvest publisher, Deep Silver, if they were interested, and of course they were. And so miraculously the three of us came together and now we’re a Dawn of War developer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: So what was that pitch?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>It's basically what we're doing now. While we were working on Iron Harvest, we did a lot of surveys and we were very close to the community and talked to a lot of people. And what basically came out is that a lot of people felt it would be great if there would be more emphasis on campaigns and single player and maybe co-op, and not that much on competitive. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And so we said, ‘Okay, we have a narrative background. We like to do campaigns and we like to do single player stuff. So actually let's do that.’ And we pitched this game where we said, ‘Okay, let's have four factions, but let's have a big campaign for each of the factions instead of a Space Marine campaign where maybe every now and then someone joins in or something.’ That was one of the building blocks. And we also pitched in general this idea of ‘Let's go back to Dawn of War 1’, because we asked a lot of people what they like, and many people asked ‘Couldn't there be more base building and research and upgrades and all of that stuff?’ Big armies and all of that felt very much [like] Dawn of War 1. And so we said, ‘Okay, what we want to do is sort of a new interpretation or an evolution of Dawn of War 1, with a big fat campaign.’ </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Who decides what those factions are? Did Games Workshop suggest you might want to use some factions? </strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>Well, it's a conversation, but it's also, there's so many great factions. So it's more like, ‘Okay, what <em>can't</em> we do?’ And what are the factions that for some reason we feel strongly about? And basically, if you do a Dawn of War, you want the Blood Ravens. That's basically a must have. If you want to do a sort of spiritual successor of the first Dawn of War, you need the Orks, really. Then the Necrons. Necrons were kind of promised or teased for the third game and never came out. So we felt that's maybe a nice thing to do, to basically say, ‘Okay, eventually, here they are, you can play the Necrons now.’ </p><p data-cy="paragraph">[This] basically left us with just one empty slot. And we said, ‘Okay, is there a faction that was never part of Dawn of War before? Something really new for everyone?’ And there are not that many factions, actually, but one that really jumped out is Adeptus Mechanicus. It's a big faction in the lore, everybody knows about them, but they have never been part of Dawn of War. So we said, ‘Okay, AdMec it is.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: And historically, at the time when those Dawn of War games were coming out, AdMec as a faction didn't have as many miniatures. They were more lore rather than a tabletop faction.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>Absolutely. But that changed, obviously, because we're now 20 years later and a lot of things change. I mean, even the Necrons from the first Dawn of War, from Dark Crusade, are very different Necrons from the Necrons of today.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: In terms of the scales of your units, obviously Warhammer goes from tiny Imperial Guardsmen to massive Titan mechs. What is the extent of your scale?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>It's from Scarabs up to Imperial Knights, or to Monoliths, or whatever there is in there. One of the big things is that buildings and RTS camps are always a little bit weird, right? Because they're way too small, obviously. And ours, it's still not a realistic size, but our buildings are a lot bigger than normal in RTS games, because we felt like it just helps with the epicness and all. Everything should be big in Warhammer, I think. But yeah, we have from 40 centimeters to 40 meters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Obviously this series started with Relic. Have you had any conversations with Relic to learn what the important aspects of the character of Dawn of War was so that you could carry that legacy on?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>Well, we didn't call them or talk to them directly. Basically what we did is we went back to all the games, but then specifically Dawn of War 1. We tried to figure out what makes this game tick. The first question was, are we going with Dawn of War 1 or 2? Because both of them are great games, but very different. And we said, ‘Okay, Dawn of War 1 it is.’ And then the question is, ‘Okay, what makes Dawn of War 1, Dawn of War 1?’ It's actually even more complicated because you can't just go back to that game, take a feature, and put it in your game and expect that it still works or that it evokes the same feelings and emotions, because it's 20 years old and stuff changes. And so basically what we really try to do is figure out how you felt 20 years ago when you played the game, and how can we make sure that it feels like that again. And so yeah, we did that a lot and figured out, what is our version of something that they did 20 years ago?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Generally when Relic launched its games, it told a short story in the CGI trailer, whereas yours is a montage of all of these many things. Is it because you wanted a montage, or is that a montage of cinematics from the game?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>It's a little bit of both. We have four CGI [cinematics], so one CGI for each of the campaigns and each of the characters. And then inside the campaigns we have something like 40 minutes of 3D cutscenes. Basically what the trailer is showing is shots from the different CGI intros with this little bit of the framework story, the outline.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Games Workshop is quite protective of its IP. Have you had any conversations where they were like, “Oh, that animation you've done doesn't quite work?”</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>I think first of all, we are totally aligned with them, that we say the game should feel like Warhammer, right? So the look and feel is very important, and it's Warhammer but it’s also Dawn of War, right? So we basically said, ‘Okay, we definitely want to make sure that it feels right.’ </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And then of course the whole IP is so complex, and there's so much stuff in there that even if you're a big fan, you don't know everything. And so what happens a lot is basically we ask them about this weapon: ‘Lore wise it says this, but in this game it looks like this. What colour is the beam supposed to be?’ Or whatever it is. And with that stuff they're great, because then they basically run into the archive and then send the references. And of course in the end they look over everything, they look over all the assets and so on, and make sure that they actually look on form and meet their expectations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: In the press release, it says Dawn of War 4 is set many years after the events of Dark Crusade. Are the narratives of Dawn of War 2 and 3 being acknowledged, or are you doing a soft reboot?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>I think our approach was more that we wanted these campaigns to be kind of nonlinear, so that you sometimes can pick between different missions and so on. And for that we needed a planet. So we said, ‘Okay, we want a world map where you can basically select different missions and so on, and also where there can be world map dialogues from Dawn of War 2.’ And so we basically thought about what we could do. And that was actually something that Games Workshop suggested: ‘Why not go back to [the Dark Crusade setting of] Kronus? Wouldn't that be an interesting thing?’ Well, yeah, that would be cool, because Kronus is basically on the wrong side of the Great Rift. That also feels great for our story because the Blood Ravens are now scattered in the Nhilus Sector, and it's basically they go back to this planet that is kind of connected to them in the hope of maybe finding recruits, or finding brothers that made their way back to the planet as well. But then it’s 40k, and of course everything goes totally wrong, but we felt it's a nice idea to go back there. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And in terms of connections to the previous games, we assume that the Space Marines won the Dark Crusade, so that is now our canon. And the other stuff [from Dawn of War 2 and 3] happened, but it's not really a big part of the story we tell, because now we tell four different stories from four different perspectives. They all have this overarching narrative, but it's not all about the Blood Ravens. And so it's more about what happens now on this planet, and why is everybody on the planet, and all that stuff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I think everybody's going to be asking where the hell is Gabriel Angelos? Where is he?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>That was actually one of the decisions we made relatively early. We don't want Gabriel Angelos in the game. Because for us, he felt a little bit overpowered, and it's a little bit weird to have either this slightly overpowered character from the beginning of the game, which is a little bit off, or you have to do, ‘Oh, well, he lost his memory and he lost all his power,’ which is also a weird trope. And so we basically said we want more “normal” heroes. So we have Cyrus and we have Jonah coming back, but they're all more like, power level-wise, more similar to normal units.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: The other thing people may be surprised about is that there’s no Chaos.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Theysen: </strong>That was actually one of the things of course we discussed, but there are basically… ‘story reasons,’ let's say… why maybe Chaos would be a better fit later in this whole thing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Executive Editor of Features. </em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-dawn-of-war-4-interview-how-a-new-developer-took-on-warhammer-40000s-flagship-rts-why-it-returns-to-kronus-and-why-chaos-isnt-here-yet]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>