<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 22:10:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Pokémon TCG Accessories for Collectors in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-pokemon-tcg-accessories</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-accessories-for-collectors-in-2025.1188459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-pokemon-tcg-accessories<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's all well and good to buy up the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-pokemon-tcg">latest sealed Pokémon card boosters</a> and move in on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokmon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-may-9">single cards when the market is crashing</a> (like what we're currently seeing with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-journey-together-preview">Journey Together</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-surging-sparks-is-the-best-scarlet-and-violet-set">Surging Sparks</a>). However, if you don't have the accessories to look after all those cards, well, it's bad news. </p><p id="tldr-best-accessories"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="TL;DR: Best Accessories">TL;DR: These Are the Best Pokémon Card Accessories</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's nothing wrong with cheap deck boxes and relying on penny sleeves for bulk and budget decks; we all have to start somewhere. But as soon as trainers start putting more money behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-glory-of-team-rocket-single-prices-crashed-japanese">chase cards</a>, pulling gem mint cards, or investing in new sets like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-destined-rivals-preorder-guide-2025">Destined Rivals</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-where-to-buy">Black Bolt, and White Flare</a>, they must protect what they have. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are some great products I've found to do just that. From pre-grading your cards to affordable play mats for trainers, I've got you covered with decent products that will protect your collection for years to come.</p><p id="deck-boxes"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Deck Boxes">Best Pokémon Card Deck Boxes</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">All of these deck boxes are felt lined and made of solid materials to protect your decks. If you're like me and double sleeve your cards, all of these deck boxes have the room to fit a full 60 card deck and change.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/pxl-20250506-071623765-1746515818077.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">My premium deck box cases - Credit: Christian Wait</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Some even hold multiple decks and dice, which is very cool for someone like me who looks way too much into these things. The one I use holds three double-sleeved decks, has a dice drawer with felt lining and even features a faux leather Pokéball design. Perfection.</p><p id="grading-accessories"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Grading Accessories">Best Pokémon Card Grading Accessories</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It can cost upwards of $20 to get a single card graded, which is worth it if the Pokémon card is in awesome condition and worth a lot. But grading companies look at your cards down to a microscopic level to check for dints, scratches and other imperfections. You'll also need to penny sleeve then pop cards in a semi rigid sleeve or they won't accept them. If you're looking to get your cards graded, these are some of the accessories we'd recommend. </p><p id="display-options"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Display Options">Best Pokémon Card Display Options</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Magnetic card holders are a cheap way to display Pokémon cards on a shelf or stand without forking out a fortune to have all of your cards graded.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/pxl-20250504-163911753-1746515519420.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">My magnetic card holders, acrylic shelving with LED lighting - Credit: Christian Wait</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I personally use acrylic shelving and LED strips to really make my collection pop. If you want your card holders to stand up straight there's also a couple of options for acrylic stands too. It really doesn't have to break the bank to make those illustration rares shine.</p><p id="storage"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Storage">Best Pokémon Card Storage</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Going to a card show with some trades? They'll be something here for you. Want to display your grails in a nice looking cabinet? I've got you covered there too.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/pxl-20250504-164349344-mp-1746515590684.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">My cardboard card organizer - Image Credit: Christian Wait</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Ripping packs is awesome, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-trading-card-storage-ideas">storing all that bulk</a> for a deck-building session isn't. Our recommendations include everything from basic cardboard boxes with rows and dividers to foam-padded storage boxes with enough room for graded and top-loaded cards. </p><p id="card-sleeves"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Card Sleeves">Best Pokémon Card Sleeves</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's no good buying these cases, binders and deckboxes without card sleeves. If you like a card or pull anything holo, sleeve it. I personally like the "Perfect Fit" sleeves as they still fit in magnetic card holders, standard and penny sleeves. Double the protection, infinite peace of mind. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I can't build a deck without double sleeving cards. It's just a good habit to get into, especially if you're rocking all shiny energies and higher-end ex cards.</p><p id="binders"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Binders">Best Pokémon Card Binders</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Binders are one of the cheapest ways to store your Pokémon cards, and it beats any art or coffee table book for casual browsing. All of these binders are double-sided with nine pockets on each side. One even has four front windows to showcase those banger chase cards. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just don't forget to sleeve your cards before putting them in. I'm a big fan of good binder behaviour and will 100% judge you otherwise.</p><p id="playmats"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Playmats">Best Pokémon Playmats</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I recently found my original Pokémon TCG playmat from when the base set released. It's literally a bit of fabric so I put a playmat underneath anyway, but how retro is this!? God bless that broken Professor Oak trainer card.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/06/pixel-9-2025-05-06t080928-872-1746515374018.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">My very first Pokémon TCG playmat from 1999 - Credit: Christian Wait</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're playing Pokémon TCG, you need a playmat, end of story. You can double-sleeve your all-shiny deck and have a felt-lined deck box all day long, but slamming cards onto hard surfaces is going to deck your deck. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You might notice that some of these playmats are actually mouse pads; that's because they're pretty much the same thing. Just do what I do: Pick a cool design and roll with it. </p><p id="latest-stock-updates"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Latest Stock Updates">Pokémon TCG: Latest Stock Updates</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you've dedicated your life to pulling chase cards yourself, here's what we can find <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-12-2025">in stock right now</a>. Just watch out for pricing over MSRP, as we Pokémon trainers are in a weird spot right now, so don't pay more than what you have to, or consider buying single cards instead of gambling on overpriced ETBs. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whatever you decide, make sure you're having fun! For more, consider checking out our guide on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-release-full-release-schedule-2025">full Pokémon<strong> </strong>release schedule in 2025</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Card Marketplace TCGplayer Offering Store Credit Promotion on May 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/card-marketplace-tcgplayer-offering-store-credit-promotion-on-may-16</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/card-marketplace-tcgplayer-offering-store-credit-promotion-on-may-16.1188453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/card-marketplace-tcgplayer-offering-store-credit-promotion-on-may-16<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">All products purchased across the site will earn at least 10% in store credit.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Trading card marketplace TCGplayer is holding a special Mayhem promotion soon, where all purchases on the site will earn you at least 10% back as store credit. The offer will be available only from 9 a.m. ET to 11 p.m. ET on May 16, so you’ll need to plan ahead to take advantage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve never used TCGplayer before, it’s an online marketplace where sellers can post listings for all kinds of trading cards. You can buy specific cards or sealed products like bundles and booster packs, so there are options for established collectors or newcomers looking to build their first deck. Plus, you can preorder upcoming releases, including the anticipated collaboration between Magic: The Gathering and Final Fantasy (more on that in a bit).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are thousands of sellers on the platform with listings across an expansive list of games. That includes <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961055/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a>, Pokémon (in both <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961056/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>English</u></a> and <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961058/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Japanese</u></a>), <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961059/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Yu-Gi-Oh!</u></a>, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961060/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Digimon</u></a>, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961062/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Flesh and Blood</u></a>, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961065/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Disney Lorcana</u></a>, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961066/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>One Piece</u></a>, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961068/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Dragon Ball Super</a>, and lots more. There are dozens in all, with a detailed filtering system that lets you specifically search for what you’re looking for.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, let’s say you’re looking for Magic: The Gathering cards. You can select that as your product line, then further filters open up based on that line. So if you’re only interested in a particular color, you can specify that. Or if you want to see what’s available from a particular set, you can do that too. You can also filter by card type (like creature, sorcery, instant, etc.).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Every product line has its own unique filters. So for Pokémon cards, you can see holofoil listings. For Yu-Gi-Oh!, you can see 1st Editions and Unlimited cards. For Disney Lorcana, you can see cold foils. You get the idea. Or if you’re on the hunt for a specific card, you can bypass all those filters and just type the card’s name in the search bar.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For every card or pack in the shop, you’ll see how much the cheapest listing costs, how many total listings there are of that item, and the current market price of it. The market price is based on the history of completed transactions for that item. When you click on the item, you can see more information about the history of its market price and look at the prices and card quality of every available listing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All products on TCGplayer (other than gift cards) will be eligible for the store credit promotion from 9 a.m. ET to 11 p.m. ET on May 16. There are no limitations based on price, card type, or anything else. The timing might seem a little restrictive, but you can prepare beforehand by putting items in your cart and waiting to check out during the promotional period. That still counts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Everybody who checks out during that 14-hour period will get a base return of 10% of the purchase price. Existing TCGplayer subscribers — or anyone who subscribes before they make a qualified purchase during the Mayhem promotion — will get a base return of 12% plus an additional return based on how long they’ve been subscribed. This means if you <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961277/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>subscribe during the promo</u></a>, you can get 13% back.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As we mentioned earlier, there are preorder listings for upcoming releases, and they’re also eligible for the store credit promotion. That includes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2960906/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Magic: The Gathering’s collaboration with Final Fantasy</u></a></li><li><a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2960907/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Pokémon Destined Rivals</u></a></li><li><a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2960908/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Yu-Gi-Oh! Battles of Legend Monster Mayhem</u></a></li><li><a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2960926/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Flesh and Blood Armory Deck: Gravy Bones</u></a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re wary of buying from a marketplace, <a href="https://partner.tcgplayer.com/c/1442478/2961278/21018" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>TCGplayer Safeguard</u></a> offers protections to help make sure you get the item you’re looking for. If a product doesn’t arrive by its estimated delivery date or isn’t in the expected condition, TCGplayer will work with you and the seller to deliver a replacement. If that’s not possible, then you can get a partial or full refund. If you suspect an item you received is counterfeit, you can submit a claim with the customer service team and receive a full refund if your item is deemed to be counterfeit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to check out everything on offer, you can head over to TCGplayer right now to get started. Remember, you can add things to your cart now, but wait to check out until the promotional period on May 16 is happening.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Nvidia GeForce RTX 5070 Ti Graphics Card Is in Stock, Includes Doom: The Dark Ages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-ti-graphics-card-in-stock-on-amazon-includes-doom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-ti-graphics-card-is-in-stock-includes-doom-the-dark-ages.1188450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-ti-graphics-card-in-stock-on-amazon-includes-doom<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The best bang-for-your-buck Nvidia Blackwell GPU for 4K gaming.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you are planning a PC build and have been waiting patiently to get ahold of one of the new Nvidia Blackwell graphics cards, here's an opportunity that's as good as you're going to get. Right now Amazon has Nvidia GeForce RTX 5070 Ti Gaming graphics cards in stock starting at $899.99 shipped. Inventory is reserved for Amazon Prime members only.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also for a limited time, you'll get a free voucher for the upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a> game with purchase. <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/campaigns/doom-the-dark-ages-rtx-bundle/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to Nvidia</a>, the version you'll receive is the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-doom-the-dark-ages">Premium edition</a> that retails for $99.99.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nvidia GeForce RTX 5070 Ti GPU in Stock on Amazon</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Amazon Prime members only for some models</strong></em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although the MSRP for these cards range from $899.99 to $999.99, a reference GeForce RTX 5070 Ti card is actually <em>supposed</em> to sell for $750. More advanced cooling designs, a more uncommon colorway, or overclocking out of the box add to the cost, but even then, admittedly, these cards are still priced higher than what Nvidia originally advertised.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The reality is that even third party manufacturers like Gigabyte, MSI, Asus (and pretty much everyone else) are also taking advantage of the high demand by marking prices up from the get-go. Unfortunately, you'd be hard pressed to find another RTX 5070 Ti GPU for this price or less. <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7Evpn?object_uuid=11b2045e-4487-40cd-a8c9-3ebe3097ad25&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">RTX 5070 Ti GPUs are generally selling for over $1,000 on eBay</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The RTX 5070 Ti GPU Has Excellent 4K Gaming Performance</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Of all the Blackwell cards released thus far, the RTX 5070 Ti offers the best bang for your buck, especially when pitted against the previous generation GPUs. It performs neck-and-neck with the RTX 4080 Super and already marginalizes the RTX 5080, which is only about 10%-15% faster but costs 33% more. This GPU is capable of high framerates in nearly all games, even at 4K resolution with ray tracing enabled. Heck, even if you plan on using this card for AI, the RTX 5070 Ti might be the better value than the RTX 50870 since both are equipped with the same 16GB of GDDR7 VRAM.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 13, 2025 4:50 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>