<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 04:08:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Gamer Spends $2,000 on 24 Years of PS Plus to Avoid Increasingly Common Price Hikes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-gamer-spends-2000-on-24-years-of-ps-plus-to-avoid-increasingly-common-price-hikes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-gamer-spends-2-000-on-24-years-of-ps-plus-to-avoid-increasingly-common-price-hikes.1021422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-gamer-spends-2000-on-24-years-of-ps-plus-to-avoid-increasingly-common-price-hikes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">One forward thinking PlayStation fan has spent upwards of $2,000 on 24 years worth of PS Plus to avoid increasingly common price hikes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reddit user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayStationPlus/comments/1gbag2i/lads_i_did_it_subscribed_to_ps_plus_until_2048/?embed_host_url=https%3A%2F%2Fgamerant.com%2Fplaystation-plus-user-subscription-24-years-2048%2F" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On_Reddit_In_Class</a> said they "decided to stack PS Plus subscriptions until 2048 because of the absurd price increases the past few years." They plan to be gaming the rest of their lives so decided it would "save a good bit of money."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A PS Plus Essential subscription cost $79.99 per year, so 24 years worth costs $1,919.76. Then, Sony was kind enough to offer the player an 89% discount to upgrade to a Premium subscription in a bizarre loophole, charging just $199.99 instead of $1,889.75, meaning it came to $2,119.75 altogether,</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Best PS Plus Games (Extra &amp; Premium Tiers)</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While the reaction to On_Reddit_In_Class's post was a mixture of shock and awe, there is at least some logic behind the move, assuming PlayStation Plus remains a thing into the mid 21st century. Subscription service prices are on the rise, with everything from PS Plus to Xbox Game Pass and Netflix going up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-raises-price-of-playstation-plus-12-month-subscriptions-across-all-tiers">Sony last raised the price of PS Plus in September 2023</a>, from $59.99 to $79.99 for the most basic tier. "This price adjustment will enable us to continue bringing high-quality games and value-added benefits to your PlayStation Plus subscription service," it said at the time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-defends-ps-plus-price-rises">Analysts said this was inevitable</a>, so another increase in the future isn't out of the question. Xbox Game Pass has seen a similar price rise, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-appears-to-be-getting-another-price-hike">doubling from $9.99 at its launch in 2017 to $19.99 now</a>. Buying a subscription ahead of time guarantees the price remains the same, however, so On_Reddit_In_Class may be on to something.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dandy's World Codes (October 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dandys-world-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dandys-world-codes-october-2024.1021419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dandys-world-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for a big boost of Ichor to bolster your squad of Toons in Dandy’s World? We’ve got some redeemable codes that will load your wallet up with a ton of free cash. Below, you’ll find a list of all the currently active Dancy's World codes so you can get your hands on more Ichor and start buying some brand-new toons.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/25/roblox-dandys-world-1729872652438.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">Active Dandy's World Codes (October 2024)</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below, you'll find a list of the active and working Dandy's World codes in October 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>ICHOR</strong> - 50 Ichor</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Dandy's World Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following Dandy's World codes are expired and no longer work in October 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>SKINTICKET</li><li>2HUNDREDMILLION</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Dandy's World Codes</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/25/roblox-dandys-world-how-to-redeem-codes-1729872652437.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem Dandy's World codes, boot up the game and, once you’re in, follow the steps below:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Look at the tabs on the left-hand side of the screen. You’ll see icons for <strong>five tabs</strong>. </li><li>Click on the tab that reads <strong>"Use Code"</strong> to access the codes bar.</li><li>Input your code in this bar, being careful to make sure it’s in the right case and spelt correctly.</li><li>Click the <strong>use </strong>button<strong> </strong>and you should see the resources you unlock appear at the bottom of the screen.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn’t My Dandy's World Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If your Dandy's World code isn’t working, it’s likely due to one of two scenarios. The first is that the code was inputted incorrectly. Make sure you have the code inputted exactly as it is in the Active Codes section above. You can even copy and paste codes directly from this article over to Roblox if you want to make sure you’re inputting them correctly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other possibility is the code has expired or you’ve already used it. If you’ve used it, you’ll get a message below the bar reminding you the inputted code has already been redeemed. If you’ve inputted it and it doesn’t recognise the code at all, it likely means it's no longer available to use and is expired.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Get More Dandy's World Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re looking to scout out some Dandy's World codes yourself, the easiest way is through the game’s <a href="https://discord.com/invite/8TWD9V9" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official Discord</a>. After joining, you’ll be able to hop into the <strong>Announcements</strong> channel to find all the latest codes as they drop.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Dandy's World in Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Dandy's World is a mascot horror survival game in the same vein of spooky hits like Five Nights at Freddy's or Poppy Playtime. The major difference is Dandy's World is multiplayer, meaning you and up to seven other friends can jump in, pick a toon with unique abilities and perks to play as, and attempt to survive as long as possible while evading the game's endless supply of terrifying monsters. The longer you survive, the more Ichor you gather, allowing you to buy new toons to help you push further into the nightmare and get the drop on your foes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Callum Williams is an IGN freelancer covering features and guides. When he's away from his desk, you can usually find him obsessing over the lore of the latest obscure indie horror game or bashing his head against a boss in the newest soulslike. You can catch him over on Twitter at @CaIIumWilliams.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>