<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 16:39:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tron: Catalyst Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tron-catalyst-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tron-catalyst-review.1220796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tron-catalyst-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's easy to get drawn in by the unmistakable chrome and neon look of the Tron movies. It definitely made Tron: Catalyst, a top-down action game set in a different virtual world than those we've seen in the films, catch my eye. But in this case, those aesthetics only carried me so far. It doesn't make any critical system errors, but almost every part of it seems like it could have used a little more compute time.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Catalyst focuses on a determined and likeable courier program, Exo, who gets mixed up in a sweeping conspiracy relating to a potential hard reset of the server she and her fellow digital consciousnesses reside on. This Arq Grid was created by Kevin Flynn, AKA Jeff Bridges from the films, and is currently the stage for an interesting political struggle between the authoritarian organization Core and their free-thinking opponents, Automata. Getting to explore this world held my attention, but a lot about it felt two-dimensional.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Tron: Catalyst Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Most of the life it has is injected by occasional dialogue scenes with fairly respectable but somewhat inconsistent voice acting, and I’m not sure the cartoon character art hit quite the right tone. It almost reminds me of the animated kids’ shows Disney often does these days to follow up many of their popular, live-action blockbusters. And that doesn't quite fit the gloomy, noir vibes of apocalyptic intrigue. I did like the character designs conceptually, though. Every major player is certainly distinct and imaginative.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Catalyst really is the picture of a game that is merely pretty good and rarely ever great.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The plot is also just alright. At the risk of repeating myself, Catalyst really is the picture of a game that is merely pretty good and rarely ever great, in just about every arena. I was interested in the various factions and sub-factions, but they never got fleshed out enough to matter. I was intrigued by the central mystery and the looming threat of the server ending, but I rarely felt a strong urgency to unravel those threads. The writing at least does what it needs to do to move things, but frequently relies on what feel like deliberate leaps of logic to avoid breaking up the flow of a level.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The best example of this is the Glitch, a condition affecting Exo that allows her to reset the server to an earlier state. This is essentially a way to start the current chapter over from the beginning, but retaining any knowledge you've gained, abilities you've earned, and shortcuts you've unlocked remaining open. It’s a very clever idea, but I feel like this mechanic had a lot more potential than what it ends up being used for.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Glitch mechanic had a lot more potential than what it ends up being used for.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Most of the time, I simply pressed the reset button when the quest objective told me to, or when I'd goofed up big time by getting too much heat from the Core enforcers. There weren't enough instances in which I felt like I could use it in a clever or dynamic way to open up optional paths or gain an advantage I wouldn't have had simply by following the main quest rigidly. It’s a time loop story without a lot of opportunities to exploit the fact that you know what’s going to happen. Time travel is always tricky to work with, and Tron: Catalyst mostly plays it safe in that regard.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Combat is also, and I'm sorry again for sounding like a broken record, but… it's fine. The controls are very responsive and the animations are kinetic and snappy. It looks cool as hell to dance back and forth through a pack of cyber cops, bouncing the light disc off walls and slashing away with stylish violence. But it started to feel fairly repetitive and never really got my blood pumping or my neurons firing in the way a better action game might because its attempts to keep me on my toes never succeeded at breaking me out of the same basic hack and slash routine.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Len's Top 10 Games Based on 80s Movie Franchises</h3><p>The films of the 80s have inspired many a great game over the years. Here are some of the best.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There's a respectable difficulty curve, introducing new mechanics along the way like the ability to steal an enemy's code to copy their fighting style, or bosses that can only be damaged by parrying one of their attacks first. But too many fights can still be concluded swiftly and with token effort by spamming dodge and melee attacks. Eventually Catalyst introduces a stealth system, but I didn't use it except when I was forced to because it's pretty dull, and fighting through a level the loud way seemed so risk-free that it didn't even offer a meaningful advantage.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There's a respectable difficulty curve, introducing new mechanics along the way.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The key problem with combat is that it usually doesn't feel necessary to think very tactically to progress on the default difficulty. This is the entire skill tree right here, and it's possible to fill it out completely long before the end of the journey if you're meticulous about looking for secrets like I am, so there aren’t a lot of either/or choices to make. Even stolen enemy abilities that can power up your attacks like this blade module didn't end up feeling all that impactful for me, to the point that I wasn't bothering with them in the majority of fights. To be clear, it's not bad. It's fun enough. But that's all it ever is.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, a Tron game without light cycles would be very odd indeed, so Catalyst gives you one pretty early on that makes it quick and enjoyable to navigate some of its larger areas. Many outdoor zones still ended up being a bit cramped for how fast this thing is, though. And the few instances of light cycle combat or chases highlighted how clunky it can feel in certain circumstances. There's even a light jet you get to pilot later, but this felt even more like a minigame and less like a well-thought-out mechanic.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Maybe the aspect I was most underwhelmed by, though, was the music. At this point, I associate the Tron universe with the likes of Daft Punk and Trent Reznor. And that's a high bar, I'll admit. I doubt any of those guys are available to create bespoke music for a project of this modest scale. But Tron: Catalyst's subdued, understated, overly safe blend of orchestral and electronic never gave me the chills I was looking for, even when I put my nice headphones on and turned the volume way up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The score often fades into the background because it's too repetitive, and it doesn't vary enough in intensity between stretches of low-key exploration and the biggest plot reveals or action sequences. Sure, it does the job. But if there's one aspect where I would expect a Tron tie-in to go above and beyond, it would be the music. So it was harder to accept “merely acceptable” on that front.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While it might sound like damning with faint praise, I honestly think one of the aspects of Tron: Catalyst that works best is its restrained scope and length. It didn't even take me 12 hours to finish, playing pretty meticulously, and that's just about exactly how much attention I had to give its digital world. It would have been really easy to overstay its welcome, especially with the meager trickle of new mechanics it doles out, so it was definitely a smart decision to not pad this out. Playtime isn't directly correlated with quality, and I respect how much this adventure respected my time.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm Reviewing Death Stranding 2, Here's What I Thought of the Original]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/im-reviewing-death-stranding-2-heres-what-i-thought-of-the-original</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/im-reviewing-death-stranding-2-heres-what-i-thought-of-the-original.1220790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/im-reviewing-death-stranding-2-heres-what-i-thought-of-the-original<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hello. I’m Simon, and I’ll be reviewing Death Stranding 2: On the Beach for IGN. As you probably know, the response to the original Death Stranding was varied to say the least, so I thought it would be helpful to provide a bit of context regarding my own feelings about the 2019 sci-fi epic before hearing my thoughts on the sequel. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I didn’t review Death Stranding for IGN – that was the job of the excellent Tristan Ogilvie, and you can read his <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/11/01/death-stranding-review"><u>thoughts here</u></a>. His score of 6.8 isn’t anywhere close to the most negative assessment Death Stranding received at launch, but it’s also far from the glowing praise some others bestowed upon it. As I said, verdicts were varied, and I’m about to add yet another to that mix. Opinions are inherently subjective, especially when it comes to art, so naturally my thoughts on Death Stranding differ from Tristan's, albeit not by too much. This is not a re-review, so you won’t get a different score here, but let me explain what I did and didn’t like about the original.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s start with the story, arguably the most complex and divisive aspect of Death Stranding. It’s the element I enjoyed the most, as I fully embraced its ever-increasing glossary of fresh sci-fi terminology and ended up quite connected to its core cast of characters. I think it's definitely the sort of experience that rewards you the more you put into its world, and while it can prove a little impenetrable during its slower, earlier hours, I really did end up fully invested by its final act. Sam’s connection to Lou, as well as the dynamic between Cliff Unger and Die-Hardman, especially resonated with me. Die-Hardman’s final scene, brilliantly brought to life by Tommie Earl Jenkins, is one of the most affecting performances in a video game that I can remember. That’s not to say that the rest of the cast aren’t also fantastic; I could lay on praise for all of them, ranging from Margaret Qualley’s dual roles to Lea Seydoux’s complicated Fragile. I’m looking forward to seeing new faces join them this time around, in particular Elle Fanning’s enigmatic Tomorrow, and I’m willing to go on the record as saying I don’t trust her at all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yes, there’s a huge scale here in its world-ending events and giant oil monsters, but this is the sort of sci-fi and post-apocalypse fiction I really connect with – grand, global stories rooted in deeply personal tales, a la Denis Villeneuve’s Arrival or Cormac McCarthy’s The Road. Death Stranding delicately balances moments of wonder, whether they be colossal looming threats or simply walking over the crest of a hill to a dose of Low Roar, with one-on-one conversations that anchor that grandeur in relatable humanity. It’s those very human themes of birth, death, hope, and grief that we can all relate to, and I enjoyed greatly how these shone through, no matter how much alien language was thrown my way over the 40 or so hours its tale takes to tell.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>This is the sort of sci-fi and post-apocalypse fiction I really connect with – grand, global stories rooted in deeply personal tales.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">In terms of gameplay, it looks like we’ll be getting more of that MGS-flavour tactical espionage action from Death Stranding 2, if recent hands-on previews are anything to go by. This excites me greatly, because no matter how much I enjoyed the original’s story, I’d be lying if I said I didn’t find the act of actually playing Death Stranding a slog at times. In fact, it’s what made me bounce off of it when it first released back in 2019. On my first go around, I got just a handful of hours in before deciding all that walking just wasn’t working for me. Its routine of setting out for a hike, crossing rivers and mountains, before eventually reaching nothing more exciting than a delivery location became tiresome for me very quickly, especially during its laborious (and seemingly never-ending) third chapter. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But I’m very glad I gave it another shot a couple of years ago, this time playing the Director’s Cut to completion, as I found myself having a much more enjoyable time with it. That new version’s addition of deeper combat and new delivery tools, such as the companion bot and catapult, introduced some much-needed variety into the mix. Plus, the fact that many half-built highways, helpful ladders, and convenient bridges already existed in the world thanks to the online Chiral network definitely made the journey a lot smoother than it was at launch. The further I got into the game and the more my collection of tools grew, the more fun I found myself having. I bombed along on a motorcycle and enjoyed setting up zipline systems to dart around with ease. I’m hopeful that many of these more convenient delivery options are available from the get-go in Death Stranding 2.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Travelling across Death Stranding’s world was ultimately rewarding, then, but I still can’t say I ever fully clicked with its combat. Yes, I did have a good laugh chucking blood and piss grenades at a big oily lion, but I largely found its BT encounters a bit of trudge. It meant that I avoided conflict as much as I could – a perfectly valid way to play Death Stranding, but one that did result in me letting out a groan every time it started to rain. I also found myself largely dodging human enemies, too, with their yellow hazmat suits often signifying tedious stealth situations. I’m encouraged, then, that Death Stranding 2 looks to be quite a bit more action-heavy in the way it's expanding your arsenal and enabling you to deal with threats in more dynamic ways. While I’m not asking for Sam to become a super soldier able to take waves of enemies head-on, I am looking forward to wielding a bit more firepower this time around instead of opting to skirt around the edges of combat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, the TLDR version is that I really enjoyed the world of Death Stranding and its characters, but didn’t find the moment-to-moment gameplay consistently rewarding. I liked it, just didn’t love it. I am very excited to jump back in with Death Stranding 2, though – from what we’ve seen so far, it does look like the story is packed full of intrigue again, and that we’ll be treated to the sort of spectacle that rarely gets created outside of Kojima’s studio walls. I’m just hoping it has the gameplay to match its cinematic ambitions this time around, and doesn’t make the gaps between its gloriously sculpted cutscenes as much of a chore. I guess we’ll all find out when my review of Death Stranding 2 drops on June 23rd.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>