<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 18:24:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Reveals 'Silly Sketch' of Mario Kart World Cow That Led to the Game's Best New Character Becoming Playable]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-silly-sketch-of-mario-kart-world-cow-that-led-to-the-games-best-new-character-becoming-playable</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-reveals-silly-sketch-of-mario-kart-world-cow-that-led-to-the-games-best-new-character-becoming-playable.1195428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-silly-sketch-of-mario-kart-world-cow-that-led-to-the-games-best-new-character-becoming-playable<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">And why the game's not called Mario Kart 9.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has discussed Mario Kart World's fan-favourite new character, Cow, and shown off the piece of concept art that secured her place in the game as a playable character. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking as part of a fascinating <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-18-mario-kart-world-part-1/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask the Developer</a> interview, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> development team revealed their "silly sketch" that convinced the game's development team to upgrade Cow from a background character to a fully-fledged part of the game's roster.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"In previous games in the series, Cow was part of the scenery or an obstacle on one of the courses," producer Kosuke Yabuki said. "But when we were working on an early version of a course in this game set on a ranch that players can drive through, this sketch came up."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The sketch, which shows a smiling Cow driving a truck and looking like she does not have a care in the world, was immediately seized upon as inspiration for Cow to become Mario Kart's next playable character — and led to other background NPCs becoming playable, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Each new Mario Kart game features new characters to race with, but since we added so many to the previous game, we wondered where we could go from there," art director Masaaki Ishikawa continued. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"And then one of the designers came up with that silly sketch of Cow cruising along, and I thought to myself, 'This is it!' (Laughs) So that's when we realized the course surroundings actually contained a lot of untapped resources."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/21/image-1747839986951.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Mario Kart World's Cow concept art. Image credit: Nintendo.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Cow's addition to the Mario Kart World roster was quickly followed by Cheep Cheep (the red fish Mario often has to dodge) and Pokey (the smiling, wiggling cactus character) also becoming playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"It was like, 'They're NPCs, but they're playable? Which is it?'" Yabuki continued. "It's pretty funny to see a four-legged Cow holding onto motorcycle handlebars with her front hooves."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"But when she jumps, she strikes a proper quadrupedal pose," Ishikawa added. "So I'm pretty sure Cow is still in touch with her animal nature. (Laughs)"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere in the same interview, Yabuki confirmed that Nintendo had the name Mario Kart World in mind "from the early stages of development" when the game's open-world nature was already being worked on. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"If the idea had just been to add more courses, then I think we would've called it Mario Kart 9," Yabuki said. "But, that wasn't our approach this time. We wanted to take the series to the next level. So, we decided to drop the numbering this time and go with a completely new title."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, the development team discussed Mario Kart World's addition of unlockable character costumes, found by snacking on food at Yoshi's drive-thru restaurants in different in-game regions. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each region will unlock its own costumes, and offer its own food varieties. One example given is a Yoshi's drive-thru in a volcano region selling hot soup inspired by Bowser.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally, Nintendo says it hadn't linked its ideas for unlockable costumes and food together, with the former simply being planned to be purchasable from in-game shop locations. But stopping at these interrupted the game's open-world driving experience, developers said, and anyway — didn't Mario magically transform costumes already when he gobbled food up?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The question came up: 'Does Mario, in fact, eat mushrooms?'," Yabuki laughed. The query prompted Mario Kart World's development team to hunt down Nintendo legend Takashi Tezuka, and get his verdict.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Tezuka-san [answered], 'Yeah, he is'," Yabuki confirmed. And thus, Mario Kart World's costume-producing food was born.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps the biggest surprise to come out of the interview was the revelation that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-began-development-on-switch-1-and-suffered-performance-struggles-until-switch-2-delay-offered-ray-of-hope">Mario Kart World began development on Nintendo Switch, before performance concerns led to the game being delayed</a> for launch on Switch 2 instead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario Kart World, and Cow, will arrive on Switch 2 on the console's launch day — June 5, 2025.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies of P: Overture Wears its Bloodborne Inspiration Proudly on its Sleeve]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lies-of-p-overture-wears-its-bloodborne-inspiration-proudly-on-its-sleeve</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lies-of-p-overture-wears-its-bloodborne-inspiration-proudly-on-its-sleeve.1195425/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/lies-of-p-overture-wears-its-bloodborne-inspiration-proudly-on-its-sleeve<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">In 2021, Round 8 and NEOWIZ announced Lies of P, a moody soulslike that answered the question that no one had thought to ask: What if Bloodborne was actually a Victorian reimagining of Carlo Collodi’s Pinocchio? When it launched in 2023, it surprised skeptics and over-delivered in both how great its dark fantasy setting was and how incredibly fun its aggressive combat was. Two years later, I got to spend some quality time with Overture, the ironically-named encore of an expansion to the hit action game. And even though I didn’t get to see much more than around an hour of the first stage and the new Boss Memories mode, it was apparent very quickly that the South Korean team is poised to overachieve yet again. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Overture is a prequel to the events of Lies of P, right before the puppet frenzy starts and robotic thralls massacre everyone in the city of Krat. But as it turns out, many of its ideas for settings, weapons, etc. were actually meant for the base game, but got cut to keep the original release from being too bloated. Round 8 studio Game Director Jiwon Choi told IGN in an interview that he and his team weren’t content with letting these ideas go undeveloped and unrealized. Through a translator, he described Lies of P as finally “complete” with the addition of Overture.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Lies of P: Overture Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Lies of P has always been associated with Bloodborne, mostly because of how it looks but also because combat in both games adheres to soulslike traditions but forgo key behaviors like blocking. Even releasing a big DLC well after launch to put a bow on the original project has become a FromSoftware signature at this point. But Choi’s team embraces the comparison. “It is our honor [to be compared to FromSoftware].” He added that it motivates them to make something that can clear that high bar of expectation and they can only hope that they did with Lies of P, and will continue to do so in Overture.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Lies of P team embraces the Bloodborne comparison.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The first steps you take back in the boots of the titular character, P, is into the snow-packed region around the Krat Zoo, a building your disembodied guide, Gemini, seems very confused to see standing and not a pile of embers. Story details are light, and the developers are staying tight lipped about anything we haven't seen so far. After some preamble from your lantern cricket, it was very difficult not to spend a couple of seconds swinging around one of the brand new weapons in Overture: a gunblade that looks exactly like the kind Squall Leonheart would get commissioned for himself. This was one of a few new weapon types I chopped my way through this frozen menagerie with, on top of new weapons from existing types, and a pair of new, very cool, legion arms that did very different, yet very effective kinds of asskicking.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pale Knight, as the gunblade’s called, was my main weapon against the ergo-poisoned monsters both on the outskirts of the zoo and within its walls. It has the weight and attack pattern similar to a greatsword, but its heavy attack pulls the trigger and the double barrel firearm attached sends lead screaming at foes. The recoil of these shots push P around, so it can be useful when mixed into attack strings to remain evasive. A trick I learned far too late in my demo is that you can actually fire the weapon again to rocket yourself back towards the bad guys for a big follow-up attack. So basically, it's the coolest weapon ever made.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another new weapon type I dabbled with is the bow, the first completely ranged weapon in the series. It felt perfect for poking smaller enemies from afar but pretty incapable of making a reasonable mark on larger foes. I think with time there’s probably a way to exploit its perfect draw mechanic to menace all sorts of baddies from down range, but I couldn’t manage it in the hour I had. Another new weapon type I wish I spent more time with were a pair of long claws that shredded enemies with the kind of fury that is usually reserved for Best There Is At What He Does. This didn’t scratch the surface of weapons I glossed over that were clearly new additions to existing weapon types, but it was abundantly clear to me that people who really love the weapon customization aspect of the base game will have a lot of new toys to mash together in Overture.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The new legion arms I tried out also made great additions to P’s kit. My favorite was yet another gun: double-barrelled and chargeable to moderate the kind of force, spread, and impact on the bad guys. It’s a more close-ranged option, but even at half charge it made short work of the fodder that roamed around the snowy grounds or dilapidated halls of the zoo itself. At full charge, it was a reliable tool to stun bigger foes or at least interrupt their bevy of attacks for a second. I came to the second arm late in the demo, but it was certainly a strong offensive option in its own right. It launched blades that would swirl around enemies for a short time, similar to the throwable saw blade item, with two differences. One, it can fire multiple blades at once to do some significant damage over time on one target, and two, with a quick press of a button before releasing the flying blade, you can change the attack completely to a set of blades that dance around P instead, great for doing solid AOE damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of targets, the cast of enemies in this section was pretty unremarkable outside in the beginning of the level, but got very interesting as we got deeper into the zone. Some bitey wolves and grabby zombies were run of the mill, but standouts like some very angry kangaroos and an ergo-plagued elephant with a Resident Evil-style surprise really wowed me. I spent so much time against the latter that I only just made it to the end of the level to see the boss: an enormous crocodile twisted by ergo.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On that note, bosses will get a new focus in the patch for the base game that will accompany Overture with two new game modes: Battle Memories and Death March. Death March is a straight up boss rush, allowing you to make a playlist of at least 3 bosses and attempt to take them down all in one go. Battle Memories, meanwhile, allows you to return to old boss fights and attempt to beat them again, now in up to five different tiers of difficulty, with each tier increasing some unique stats that these bosses gain in this mode. Rewards for conquering these tiers have been hinted at, but not elaborated on. I went back to one of the old bosses, the Black Rabbit Brotherhood, to see how different it was on tier 3 than my memory of them in the base game. The way they beat me and my rusty fingers to death didn’t point out any real differences, but as with the rest of Lies of P, I'm sure teasing out the mystery comes with lots of experimentation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lies of P was one of the standout games of 2023, and among the best games in its action RPG subgenre not made by FromSoftware. Overture doesn’t play with the formula too much, but I found that the new ingredients it added, like the great new weapon types and fabulously freaky monsters, proved that there's never really too much of a good thing, even if it is largely the same thing.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Nintendo Redesigned Donkey Kong, According to Shigeru Miyamoto]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/why-nintendo-redesigned-donkey-kong-according-to-shigeru-miyamoto</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-nintendo-redesigned-donkey-kong-according-to-shigeru-miyamoto.1195419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/why-nintendo-redesigned-donkey-kong-according-to-shigeru-miyamoto<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This Kong now also has a funny face.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this year, we received <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-super-mario-bros-movie-appears-to-have-influenced-a-major-mario-kart-9-characters-redesign">confirmation that Donkey Kong's fresh new look</a> wasn't just for the Super Mario Bros. Movie. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-goes-all-in-on-donkey-kong-redesign-seen-in-nintendo-switch-2-and-mario-kart-9-first-look">Donkey Kong redesign was here to stay</a>, per the character's appearances in Mario Kart World, Donkey Kong Bananza, and more. Love it or hate it, that's your business, but now Shigeru Miyamoto has finally told us why the great ape got a makeover in the first place.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Miyamoto spoke to IGN at the unveiling of Universal’s new Epic Universe theme park in Orlando, Florida, which brings the new Donkey Kong Country expansion to the U.S. for the first time. In our interview, which you can read in full here, we asked Miyamoto about the new design, and what it was like seeing Donkey Kong "grow up" alongside Miyamoto's career at Nintendo. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's his response in full:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So when it comes to character creation and working with characters, I still take an active role in that. And looking back to the first generation Donkey Kong Country, we worked with Rare to create Donkey Kong Country.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>What can we do with the design to make it more expressive?</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">"When we were talking about trying to create new versions, evolving Donkey Kong, we created the game called Jungle Beat. We worked together with the team that made 3D Mario. With the technology that was available at the time, we were able to make Donkey Kong more expressive. And going back to the design that Rare came up with, we reevaluated; what can we do with the design to make it more expressive? And then when it comes to the movie, we decided to move forward with this new generation Donkey Kong design."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 - Donkey Kong Bananza</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">More expressive, huh? It certainly seems like Nintendo has nailed that. Fans have pointed out across social media that the new Donkey Kong is relatively similar to the old one, but has a sillier, more over-the-top look and expressiveness to him that the old design didn't quite capture. And it looks like we may see more Kong redesigns in the future to accompany him, as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/after-redesigning-donkey-kong-nintendo-has-tweaked-another-classic-character-and-heres-our-best-look-yet">Diddy Kong already got a very light redesign</a> (he has teeth now???) as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can catch up on our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-shigeru-miyamoto-interview-i-see-nintendo-as-like-a-talent-agency-and-we-have-within-our-roster-a-lot-of-talented-characters">full interview with Miyamoto at Universal right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Began Development on Switch 1 and Suffered Performance Struggles, Until Switch 2 Delay Offered 'Ray of Hope']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-began-development-on-switch-1-and-suffered-performance-struggles-until-switch-2-delay-offered-ray-of-hope</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-began-development-on-switch-1-and-suffered-performance-struggles-until-switch-2-delay-offered-ray-of-hope.1195416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-began-development-on-switch-1-and-suffered-performance-struggles-until-switch-2-delay-offered-ray-of-hope<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 2 launch title <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> was originally in development more than five years ago, solely for the original Nintendo Switch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Nintendo has said its development team struggled to get Mario Kart World's 24-player concept working on its aging Switch 1 hardware — to the point where it was faced with making major technological compromises. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the end, these compromises were abandoned in favour of a new approach. As early as 2020, Mario Kart World's developers say they had a rough idea of Nintendo's Switch 2 tech specs — and so began discussing a delay for the project onto Nintendo's next-gen machine.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking as part of a revealing <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-18-mario-kart-world-part-1/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask the Developer</a> interview, Nintendo's Mario Kart World team said they had approached the concept of incorporating open-world gameplay and 24-player multiplayer "from a calm and collected programming perspective" to see whether it would be possible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, the team soon decided it would not. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"It was difficult for us to incorporate everything we wanted, so we were always conscious of what we were giving up in return," said Mario Kart World programming director Kenta Sato. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We discussed things like toning down the visuals, lowering the resolution, and we even considered dropping the framerate to 30 fps in some cases. It was a tough situation."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While confident in the concept, Mario Kart World's team continued attempting to make it work, but felt they were "kicking the can down the road," according to producer Kosuke Yabuki.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We knew it was going to get messy," Yabuki continued. "But as we'd decided to release Mario Kart 8 Deluxe's Booster Course Pass, we thought that would give us a bit more time to continue development. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"That's when the conversation of moving it to the Nintendo Switch 2 system came up, and this suddenly opened up a bunch of possibilities on what we could do. It was truly a ray of hope."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This was "around 2020," the interview reveals, when Nintendo developers had "an idea of the next system [Switch 2]'s expected specs" but before working development units were available. So, the Mario Kart World team continued on, using estimates of the Switch 2 power they'd be able to play with. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"If we had included everything we wanted to in this game's vast world, then it wouldn't have run at 60 fps and would have suffered from constant framerate drops," Sato said. "I think there were a lot of people on the team who were worried about whether we could really manage it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"But once we decided to release this game on Switch 2, we expected our worries to evaporate all at once," he continued. "I remember being overjoyed when I discovered we could express even more than we'd originally set out to."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky @tomphillipseg.bsky.social‬</em><br>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>