<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 11:42:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woot Has Better Video Game Deals Than Amazon's Spring Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/woot-best-video-game-deals-amazons-spring-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/woot-has-better-video-game-deals-than-amazons-spring-sale.1147509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/woot-best-video-game-deals-amazons-spring-sale-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Save on Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth, Metaphor: ReFantazio, and so many more.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Springtime savings have been popping up left and right on a variety of items lately, and if you've been looking to score some sweet deals on video games, now's your chance. Not only are there some great deals on games in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a>, but other retailers like Woot (an Amazon-owned online retailer) and Walmart are offering discounts you definitely don't want to miss. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Woot, in particular, has some of the best deals we've seen so far this year on games, including 53% off <a href="https://zdcs.link/QGGe7K?object_uuid=4a37ee16-a5dc-45a5-82a1-c78c0226c9ba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</a> for PS5 and 64% off <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wXp5y?object_uuid=4a37ee16-a5dc-45a5-82a1-c78c0226c9ba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> for Xbox Series X. You can see those deals and so many more of our favorites at the moment below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Spring Sale Video Game Deals</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">A lot of the Woot deals are only available for a limited time, though. So if one of the games above has caught your eye, you'll want to act fast to pick it up now at its discounted price or before it sells out for good. There are several more games on sale right now at Woot that are worth looking at as well. Have a look at the retailer's '<a href="https://zdcs.link/z3RB2m?object_uuid=4a37ee16-a5dc-45a5-82a1-c78c0226c9ba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Spring Video Game Sale!</a>' page to see what else has been marked down.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Deals in Amazon's Spring Sale</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of video game deals, there are plenty of discounts worth exploring in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a>. This includes some stellar <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/a-selection-of-4ks-and-blu-rays-are-discounted-right-now-in-amazons-big-spring-sale">price drops on 4Ks and Blu-rays</a> and a "3 for 2" offer that can be used on a selection of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-3-for-2-book-deal-2025">books</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/comics-amazon-3-for-2-spring-sale-deal">comics</a>, movies, and more. Some of the items included with that offer are also on sale, so it's a win-win to stock up and save on certain items that catch your eye. It's also worth checking out our breakdown of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-under-25-amazon-big-spring-sale">best deals under $25</a> to see even more of our favorite items from the sale that fall on the cheaper side.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 28, 2025 12:40 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>