<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:43:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA: San Andreas's Original PC Version Can Now Be Beaten in Just an Hour Thanks to the Weirdest Skip You've Ever Seen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-san-andreass-original-pc-version-can-now-be-beaten-in-just-an-hour-thanks-to-the-weirdest-skip-youve-ever-seen</link>
            <guid>1420354</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Straight to the End of the Line.</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas is 22 years old, which as you can imagine means that people have cracked that game wide open with weird glitches, skips, and tricks. Over the years, speedrunners have found ways to break San Andreas that got an any% speedrun of it down to a little under three hours, but recently an absolutely buckwild bug was found that cut that time down even further, to under an hour. Buckle up, folks, because this is one heck of a wacky speedrun.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">First, some context. San Andreas has been broken and rebroken many times over the years across its multiple versions, and there's one specific "trick" that's upended the speedrunning landscape multiple times. It actually originated in GTA: Vice City, where a <a href="https://www.speedrun.com/gtavc/guides/0h9mr" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trick known as Script Stack Underflow</a> (SSU) was found that chopped an any% run down to around eight minutes. <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-speedrunning-trick-sh-1838953554" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Way back in 2019</a>, San Andreas runners found something similar that they called "Arbitrary Jump in Script", or AJS, specifically in the Window Store remaster of the game. This overly-complex trick essentially let speedrunners jump straight to the end of the game by doing a long series of very specific things such as killing a drug dealer, parking a bike in a very specific place, answering the phone at very specific times, and diligently avoiding vending machines at all costs.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While involved, it demonstrably worked, with the end result being the game executing a "JUMP" command to the start of End of the Line Part 3, the final mission. Ever since then the speedrunning community has had to split the category into any% and any% no AJS, because watching a run with AJS is fun exactly once and then you really just want to watch a proper, action-packed, multi-hour San Andreas speedrun. For a long time, this skip was limited to the Windows Store version of the game, though it was later found in the Definitive Edition remaster with some significant setup differences.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Well now, speedrunners have figured out how to do AJS in the original PC version of San Andreas. It is <em>also</em> completely different in how it's set up, and is somehow even wackier than any of the versions that have come before. u/Vitosi4ek on Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/speedrun/comments/1qpv1ji/a_skip_the_whole_game_strat_has_been_found_in_the/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has a really nice breakdown of all the steps involved</a> (though some runners have already found ways to smooth out certain bits of it). These include: winning $10,000 on horse betting, making a clone of yourself, doing stunt jumps on a superbike, betting in the casino with negative money, changing your clothes, doing a dance minigame, running two Mission at the exact same time, and a lot more. All of this will hopefully, if the game doesn't crash, send you to the start of End of the Line Part 3, and let you finish the game right there.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every GTA Game Ranked</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This glitch was literally just discovered, and in that time the world record run for an any% of GTA: San Andreas has dropped down to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zll2qkggyCU" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">53 minutes and 46 seconds by creezyful</a>. It's very likely that this time will get even more shaved off in the coming days and weeks as speedrunners continue to optimize. This has also resulted in the community splitting any% off from any% no AJS, so audiences can still enjoy a roughly three-hour run of San Andreas and all the hyjinks involved in that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's wildly impressive to me that people are still managing to crack games this old open even more than they've already been, and make their guts do ridiculous things. Just this past AGDQ, I watched someone run arbitrary code execution in The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker, something I'm pretty sure they didn't know how to do the last time the game was at the show. Video games, man!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, that does mean it'll probably be a long time before we get a run of GTA 6 that goes that fast. And that's if we can even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-is-delayed-again-until-november-2026">make it to launch day this November</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-san-andreass-original-pc-version-can-now-be-beaten-in-just-an-hour-thanks-to-the-weirdest-skip-youve-ever-seen]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The SteelSeries CS2 Dragon Lore Edition Wireless Gaming Mouse Drops by 62%, Now Under $60]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/steelseries-cs2-dragon-lore-edition-wireless-gaming-mouse-deal</link>
            <guid>1420348</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out this big price drop on a lightweight gaming mouse with no lack of flair. Starting today, Amazon has dropped the price of the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wBAAb?object_uuid=a0d375b8-6481-4348-a869-c9ce41beeb48&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">SteelSeries Counter-Strike 2 Dragon Lore Limited Edition wireless gaming mouse</a> to just $56.76 after a massive 62% off discount. Historically speaking, the price of this mouse was fixed at $150 since it first released last July... until today. The Dragon Lore Edition gets points for its gorgeous design, but it also happens to be an excellent performer for any gamer looking for a lightweight mouse with top-of-the-line accuracy and precision.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">SteelSeries CS2 Dragon Lore Edition Mouse for $56.76</h2><div id="234911"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234911" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>SteelSeries CS2 Dragon Lore Edition Wireless Gaming Mouse</h3></p></div></span></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong></strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/aX4Z6Z?object_uuid=a0d375b8-6481-4348-a869-c9ce41beeb48&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a> is offering 50% off the matching mousepad. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The SteelSeries CS2 Dragon Lore Edition is based off the venerable Aerox 3 wireless mouse but with a snazzy facelift. Instead of the "holey" honeycomb pattern, the CS2 Edition is kitted with a solid shell adorned with an intricate red and gold dragon illustration that replicates the legendary rare AWP skin in Counter-Strike. Art aside, I actually prefer the solid mouse cover; mice with a bunch of holes in its shells don't feel as sturdy, naturally, and accumulate dust faster.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite losing the honeycomb shell, the CS2 Edition mouse is still very lightweight at 71 grams while still providing all the features you'd want in a premium gaming mouse. It can connect wirelessly two ways: over 2.4GHz WiFi with the dongle (the preferred choice for PC gaming) and Bluetooth. The PixArt co-developed 18K dpi "TrueMove Air" optical sensor offers true 1:1 tracking. The battery lasts up to 200 hours per charge. The mouse buttons are mechanical with a nice clicky sound and are rated for 80 million clicks. At under $60, this is a steal.</p><div data-cy="paragraph"><p><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/steelseries-cs2-dragon-lore-edition-wireless-gaming-mouse-deal]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering's Lorwyn Eclipsed Booster Box Is Already Discounted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-lorwyn-eclipsed-booster-box-is-already-discounted</link>
            <guid>1420345</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> has a frankly ridiculous <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-full-release-schedule-2026"><u>schedule for 2026</u></a>, but while the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-where-to-buy-2026"><u>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</u></a>, The Hobbit, Marvel heroes, and Star Trek are on their way, we’re starting the year with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-most-expensive-cards"><u>Lorwyn Eclipsed</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An in-universe set that’s seeing positive buzz already, thanks to being a return to a fan-favorite plane and the fact that there’s no City Pigeon or Hot Dog Cart in sight, it launched on January 23 but is getting a discount already.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/zj8nBq?object_uuid=bfe167a9-2227-4297-a6c7-52f0124759bd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Amazon is offering a Play Booster Box of 30 packs for $129.98</u></a>, a 21% drop from the list price of $164.70.</p><div id="234771"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234771" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lorwyn Eclipsed Play Booster Box (30 Packs)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">Save On Magic’s Latest Set Right Now</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Some quick math will show you that with this discount, you’re paying $4.63 per card. That’s a drop of almost a dollar per pack, going by the per-pack pricing of $5.49.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s a lot of cards, and it might even be worthwhile splitting a Play Booster Box with a friend at this price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon’s been on a bit of a tear recently with Magic deals. In the last few days we’ve seen discounts on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-preorders-drop-to-new-record-low-price-amazon-just-weeks-after-last-discount"><u>upcoming Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Play Booster Box</u></a>, as well as the same product for Edge of Eternities - <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/save-on-a-play-booster-box-of-magic-the-gatherings-most-underrated-2025-set"><u>one of Magic’s most underrated 2025 sets</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Picking up a Lorwyn Eclipsed Play Booster Box is a great way to fill out your collection, or upgrade your Commander Decks. Speaking of which, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-precon-decks-in-stock-best-price-preview"><u>we’ve taken a look at the new decks in our guide</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Lorwyn Eclipsed, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-most-expensive-cards"><u>our list of the best chase cards</u></a> in the set right now, as well as a look at <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-weird-wonderful-creatures-of-magic-the-gatherings-new-lorwyn-eclipsed-set"><u>all eight creature types</u></a> in the new set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.<br>
</p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-lorwyn-eclipsed-booster-box-is-already-discounted]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>