<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:53:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Voice Behind Mortal Kombat's 'Toasty!' Is Leaving NetherRealm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-voice-behind-mortal-kombats-toasty-is-leaving-netherrealm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-voice-behind-mortal-kombats-toasty-is-leaving-netherrealm.1315573/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Few games have given us as many iconic one-liners as NetherRealm's fighting franchise, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mortal-kombat"><u>Mortal Kombat</u></a>, but this week we've learned that the voice behind one of the most famous — "Toasty!" — is leaving the studio.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Audio director Dan Forden worked at Midway and its successor NetherRealm Studios since 1989, most famously on the Mortal Kombat franchise. It's his voice we hear cry "Toasty!" in falsetto when we pull off an impressive uppercut. First appearing in 1993's Mortal Kombat II, Toasty went on to become one of the most recognizable lines of dialogue in all video games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, however, Forden is leaving NetherRealm, writing in a heartfelt message on social media that he was "really proud of what [the studio] accomplished."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Wednesday was my last day at NetherRealm. We made a lot of fun stuff over the years. I’m really proud of what we accomplished as well as how much fun we had making that stuff," Forden wrote on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DPTnVKxE6Ch/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Instagram</u></a>. "There are so many smart, talented people there — look for more great things to emerge over the next several years. I love the little touches that people left around the studio like this little Toasty homage on the bathroom mirror.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I wouldn’t have lasted 37 years in the industry if fans weren’t out there playing the games we made. Thanks to all of you for supporting what we’ve done. Live long and… Toasty!"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Asked in the comments why he was leaving now, Forden explained: "I figured I’d been around long enough. Want to reclaim that time for my own interests."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Forden's exit comes at an uncertain time for NetherRealm, which is owned by Warner Bros. In May, the studio confirmed what Mortal Kombat 1 fans feared after the launch of the Definitive Edition: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/confirmed-mortal-kombat-1-wont-get-any-more-dlc-characters-or-story-chapters-as-netherrealm-needs-to-shift-focus-to-the-next-project">no new DLC characters or story chapters would be released for the game</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In August, development chief Ed Boon said Mortal Kombat 1 had sold over 6.2 million copies. Its predecessor, Mortal Kombat 11, became the best-selling game in the franchise by passing Mortal Kombat X's nearly 11 million units sold worldwide soon after launch. By 2022, Mortal Kombat 11 had sold more than 15 million copies worldwide. Clearly, Mortal Kombat 1 has underperformed compared to previous games in the series.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">NetherRealm has said it shifted to "focus to the next project in order to make it as great as we possibly can," but it has yet to say what it is. Current speculation points to Injustice 3, a continuation of NetherRealm’s DC fighting game series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for what else is happening in the Mortal Kombat world? Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection, developed by Digital Eclipse and published by Atari, launches at the end of October. Movie sequel <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/mortal-kombat-ii"><u>Mortal Kombat II</u></a>  <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mortal-kombat-ii-movie-delayed-will-release-next-summer"><u>has been delayed from October 24, 2025, to May 15, 2026</u></a>. It's thought Warner Bros. and New Line Cinema believe the movie — which stars Karl Urban alongside Adeline Rudolph, Jessica McNamee, Josh Lawson, Ludi Lin, Mehcad Brooks, Tati Gabrielle, Lewis Tan, and more — will perform better at the summer box office given the wild fan response to the trailer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://youtu.be/1GWh4H4Xc18?si=SMYBdBX3RhXa_Mlr" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Atari / YouTube</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-voice-behind-mortal-kombats-toasty-is-leaving-netherrealm]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cheaters Have Come for the Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Beta, as Activision Said They Would]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cheaters-have-come-for-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-as-activision-said-they-would</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cheaters-have-come-for-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-as-activision-said-they-would.1315570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hack the planet.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 beta</a> is live now, and as Activision expected, cheaters have descended upon it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-knows-call-of-duty-cheaters-will-try-to-test-the-limits-during-the-black-ops-7-beta-says-thats-exactly-what-we-want">Activision said it was well aware that cheaters would strike the beta</a>, as they have previous Call of Duty betas, but welcomed the onslaught that was to come.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Cheaters will try to test the limits during the beta,” Activision said. “That’s exactly what we want because #TeamRICOCHET is here, watching, learning, and removing them as they appear. Any account permanently banned for cheating during the Beta will be banned across all Call of Duty titles, from Call of Duty: Modern Warfare to future releases.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision had highlighted its new aimbot detection, which it said is “one of the strongest detection systems we have ever built,” and its new wall hacking detections, “making it harder for cheaters who manipulate the game to see enemies through surfaces harder to escape detection.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But a cursory glance at social media shows a number of clips revealing cheaters enjoying themselves in the Black Ops 7 beta.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">There are already cheaters in the first hours of the Black Ops 7 beta 🤦‍♂️ <a href="https://t.co/oK6hp6C4ki" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/oK6hp6C4ki</a></p>— ModernWarzone (@ModernWarzone) <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone/status/1973854357541290347?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 2, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">CHEATER ON DAY 1 OF BLACK OPS 7 BETA LMFAO!!! <a href="https://t.co/KkkW55vZaO" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/KkkW55vZaO</a></p>— Nicari 🤍 (@Nicari) <a href="https://twitter.com/Nicari/status/1973848298223194383?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 2, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The hope is, of course, that data gathered during this beta period will help reduce cheating when Black Ops 7 comes out in November. But publishers like Activision face an uphill battle when it comes to hacks. Indeed EA faces the same problem with rival shooter Battlefield 6, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cheaters-already-spotted-in-battlefield-6-open-beta-despite-secure-boot-requirement">whose open beta also saw cheaters</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As part of the war on cheaters, publishers are starting to force PC gamers to enable TPM 2.0 and Secure Boot in order to play. EA’s done it with Battlefield 6, and Activision has done it for Call of Duty. More will surely follow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These features block modified hardware and unauthorized software, with the goal of creating a fair, secure environment for all players even as cheaters ramp up their efforts. But it remains to be seen just how effective they will be, with both Battlefield 6 and Black Ops 7 waiting in the wings.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For now, though, some Call of Duty console players are doing what they always do when a new game in the series comes out: turn crossplay off in a bid to avoid PC players. Cheating is more prevalent on PC (Activision recently confirmed as much, to the point where it said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-console-players-unlikely-to-be-cheating-theyre-just-killing-you-with-an-intel-advantage-activision-says"><u>if you believe you’ve died unfairly to a console player, it’s much more likely that they’ve used ‘intel advantage’ than cheats</u></a>). So, some console players head straight into Call of Duty’s settings to turn off crossplay across the board, just to take the potential for PC cheaters ruining their day out of the equation. Earlier this year, Activision added new console-only crossplay options for regular multiplayer, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-pc-players-who-do-not-cheat-are-being-penalized-by-new-console-only-crossplay-option-for-regular-multiplayer"><u>although PC players who do not cheat said they were being unfairly punished</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to get in on the action, check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-early-access-beta-and-open-beta-global-release-times-confirmed">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 beta global release times</a> to find out when it's playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/cheaters-have-come-for-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-as-activision-said-they-would]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rock Band 4 Is Being Delisted from Digital Stores This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rock-band-4-is-being-delisted-from-digital-stores-this-weekend</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rock-band-4-is-being-delisted-from-digital-stores-this-weekend.1315522/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Rock Band 4 DLC will also begin to vanish, fate of legacy DLC will be figured out over the coming months.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rock Band 4 is being delisted from both the Xbox and PlayStation digital stores this weekend due to expiring lusic licenses, developer Harmonix has confirmed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The news was posted across the game's official Discord channel and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Rockband/comments/1nv83uo/rock_band_4_game_and_dlc_delisting_information/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">its subreddit</a>. The warning has come with just days to act, and arrives on the eve of the game's 10th anniversary.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"On Sunday, October 5, 2025, Rock Band 4 turns 10," reads the team's statement. "What a ride it's been."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"With this milestone comes one big change: the original licenses for the core soundtrack are expiring. Because of that, Rock Band 4 will be removed from the PlayStation and Xbox digital stores. If you already own the game, nothing changes — you'll keep full access and still be able to download the game and songs to any new, compatible devices. The same applies to Downloadable Content (DLC): songs will come down as they hit the 10-year mark, but anything you've purchased will remain in your library.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We're so grateful for the passion this community has shown. From the team, it's been a special experience to serve you with Rivals challenges, a super deep DLC library and a best in class band sim. If you've been meaning to grab a few last songs, now's the time."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As of Sunday, Rock Band 4 and the Rock Band 4 DLC songs that were specifically released on its launch day will no longer be available to purchase. It has been clarified on Discord that DLC tracks from <em>prior </em>Rock Band games (released before Rock Band 4) are not being delisted "yet", but the team "will be figuring those out over the coming months."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Rock Band's unique approach to DLC has resulted in the ability for owners to carry their libraries of songs (plus exports of the tracklists of past Rock Band games) across three generations of console hardware. The approach has seen thousands of pieces of bespoke DLC released for the series since 2007, almost all of which can be played within Rock Band 4. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last DLC of the Rock Band 4 era was released in January 2024, after eight years of weekly content. The news that the axe is now looming for all Rock Band content, however, marks a sad moment in the history of the 18-year-old series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Luke is a Senior Editor on the IGN reviews team. You can track him down on Bluesky @mrlukereilly to ask him things about stuff.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/rock-band-4-is-being-delisted-from-digital-stores-this-weekend]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>