<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 13:49:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Game Sizes Revealed, and It Looks Like the 256 GB Internal Storage Will Keep Most Players Going for a While]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-sizes-revealed-and-it-looks-like-the-256-gb-internal-storage-will-keep-most-players-going-for-a-while</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-game-sizes-revealed-and-it-looks-like-the-256-gb-internal-storage-will-keep-most-players-going-for-a-while.1155198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-sizes-revealed-and-it-looks-like-the-256-gb-internal-storage-will-keep-most-players-going-for-a-while<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has confirmed some of its Switch 2 game sizes, and, thankfully, they’re relatively small.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Japanese My Nintendo Store lists a number of Switch 2 games alongside their file sizes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-tech-specs-battery-life-4k-and-up-to-120fps-storage-and-more">The Nintendo Switch 2 features 256 GB of internal storage</a>, which is a significant upgrade on the 32 GB available on the OG Switch and Switch Lite and the 64 GB on the Switch - OLED Model.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another big difference is that the Switch 2 requires microSD Express cards for up to 2 TB of extra storage, meaning the microSDXC cards the current Switch models support cannot transfer over to the new console.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But, based on the file sizes revealed on the Japanese store, that 256 GB of internal storage should keep most players going for a while.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nintendo Switch 2 game storage sizes:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>: 23.4 GB</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>: 10 GB</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamecube-titles-are-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-with-nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Classics: GameCube app</a>: 3.5 GB</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv">Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition ＋ Jamboree TV</a>: 7.7 GB</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-2-edition-star-crossed-world">Kirby and the Forgotten Land – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition ＋ Star Crossed World</a>: 5.7 GB</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The biggest file size here is, as you’d expect, Mario Kart World, but at 23.4 GB it only takes up around 10% of the Switch 2’s total internal storage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario Kart World is relatively slim compared to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-will-take-up-25-of-switch-2-internal-storage-its-a-64gb-install">the beefy Cyberpunk 2077</a>, which weighs in at 64 GB on Nintendo Switch 2. That's a chunky 25% of the Switch 2’s internal storage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo also recently confirmed that several new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-some-switch-2-game-cards-will-only-include-a-download-key"><u>Switch 2 game cards won’t always carry an actual game</u></a>, but instead contain a key for a game download. This isn't the case for Cyberpunk 2077, though.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For context, one of the biggest games on the original Switch, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, was just 16 GB.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that the GameCube app’s size is expected to grow as new games are added to the library. At launch, the GameCube app contains The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker, F-Zero GX, and SoulCalibur 2.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Switch 2 Game Boxes</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, how is the Nintendo Switch 2 able to get away with relatively small game sizes while offering up to 4K resolution?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In January, the internet spotted a Nintendo patent, filed July 2023 but published for the first time earlier this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-leaks-ramp-up-as-new-patent-suggests-ai-image-upscaling-tech"><u>that described AI image upscaling technology</u></a> that would help keep video game download sizes small enough to fit on a physical game cartridge while offering up to 4K textures. It was thought at the time that this applied to the Nintendo Switch 2, and could relate to Nvidia DLSS graphics technology.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nvidia DLSS (Deep Learning Super Sampling) is an AI-powered technology that uses machine learning to upscale lower-resolution images in real-time, enhancing both performance and image quality in games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, in the wake of the Nintendo Direct, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nvidia-says-its-custom-gpu-means-nintendo-switch-2-has-10x-the-graphics-performance-of-the-nintendo-switch">Nintendo and Nvidia confirmed the Switch 2’s custom GPU enables AI upscaling via DLSS and ray tracing</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nvidia described it as a “custom Nvidia processor featuring an Nvidia GPU with dedicated RT Cores and Tensor Cores for stunning visuals and AI-driven enhancements.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those upgrades include up to 4K gaming in TV mode and up to 120 FPS at 1080p in handheld mode. Nintendo Switch 2 also supports HDR, and AI upscaling “to sharpen visuals and smooth gameplay.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new RT Cores bring real-time ray tracing, delivering “lifelike lighting, reflections and shadows for more immersive worlds,” Nvidia continued.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tensor Cores, meanwhile, power AI-driven features like DLSS, “boosting resolution for sharper details without sacrificing image quality.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Details are thin on the ground, however. In a hardware-focused roundtable Q&amp;A in New York this week, attended by IGN, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-uses-dlss-and-ray-tracing-but-is-being-super-vague-about-the-details"><u>Nintendo representatives confirmed the Switch 2 uses DLSS</u></a>, but did not specify which version of the tech, or whether it had been customized for Switch 2. It was a similarly vague response when Nintendo confirmed the Switch 2’s GPU is capable of ray tracing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And what about the GPU itself? Tetsuya Sasaki, General Manager at Nintendo’s Technology Development Division, and Senior Director at its Technology Development Department, chimed in to say Nintendo prefers not to get in the weeds on things like the GPU.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Nintendo doesn't share too much on the hardware spec,” he said. “What we really like to focus on is the value that we can provide to our consumers. But I do believe that our partner Nvidia will be sharing some information.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced"><u>everything announced at the Switch 2 Nintendo Direct</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-why-the-nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-world-and-everything-around-them-is-so-expensive"><u>what the experts have to say about the Switch 2 price and Mario Kart World’s $80 price tag</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie's Marathon Finally Emerges From the Shadows to Tease… Something]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bungies-marathon-finally-emerges-from-the-shadows-to-tease-something</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungies-marathon-finally-emerges-from-the-shadows-to-tease%E2%80%A6-something.1155195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bungies-marathon-finally-emerges-from-the-shadows-to-tease-something<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Remember <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a>? It’s Destiny developer Bungie’s next game, and it looks like we’re about to finally see more of it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marathon is a PvP-focused extraction shooter set on the mysterious planet of Tau Ceti IV. Players inhabit the bodies of Runners, cybernetic mercenaries who have been designed to survive the planet’s harsh environments, exploring the lost colony that once inhabited Tau Ceti’s surface.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It has been some time since we saw or heard of Marathon. In October, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungie-shooter-marathon-is-on-track-but-too-early-in-development-to-show">Bungie released a lengthy development update <u>video</u> that shed light on Marathon's mechanics</a>, but stressed how early in development the game was. Player character models were, at that point, still "coming together," while enemy models were still in an "early state."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, though, half a year later, it looks like Bungie is finally ready to reveal what it’s been working on. A tweet from the official Marathon account, below, revealed a typically cryptic image and accompanying garbled signal noise. As fans have noticed, there’s ASCII art of footage from the debut Marathon trailer. Given this is Bungie we’re talking about, a developer known for its mysterious teasers, hidden clues, and Easter eggs, there’s probably much more here to discover, and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Marathon/comments/1jr6otv/unencrypted_code/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fans are already working to find out what it all means</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Either way, it very much looks like it’s finally happening for Marathon after what has been a troubled development.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/6NBgIdRVK2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/6NBgIdRVK2</a></p>— Marathon (@MarathonTheGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarathonTheGame/status/1907956872046690602?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungie-reveals-new-marathon-game-at-playstation-showcase"><u>Marathon was revealed in May 2023</u></a> as a reboot of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/4-ways-marathon-influenced-modern-games"><u>the classic Bungie franchise</u></a>, but with all its themes of "mysteries, eeriness, and psychological creepiness." But Bungie itself has suffered several controversies in recent years, headlined by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/destiny-developer-bungie-cuts-220-staff-some-of-the-most-difficult-changes-weve-ever-had-to-make-as-a-studio"><u>the laying off of 220 staff members</u></a>, meaning 17% of its workforce, in July 2024: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-industry-criticizes-bungie-management-ceo-pete-parsons-in-wake-of-layoffs-inexcusable"><u>a move even industry peers criticized</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This came <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pete-parsons-tells-employees-bungie-kept-the-right-people-to-work-on-destiny-2"><u>less than a year after 100 other layoffs at Bungie</u></a>, at which point <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungie-devs-say-atmosphere-is-soul-crushing-amid-layoffs-cuts-and-fear-of-total-sony-takeover"><u>staff told IGN the atmosphere was "soul crushing" at the studio</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Further controversy came when a report released weeks after the 220 job losses alleging <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marathon-director-was-fired-following-misconduct-investigation-at-bungie-report"><u>former Marathon director Chris Barrett was fired after an internal misconduct investigation</u></a> at Bungie. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/former-bungie-director-chris-barrett-suing-sony-interactive-entertainment-and-bungie-for-more-than-200-million">Barrett subsequently sued Sony Interactive Entertainment and Bungie for more than $200 million</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This all comes as Sony rethinks its focus on live-service games. Sony president Hiroki Totoki said in November 2023 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-commits-to-launch-just-six-of-playstations-12-live-service-games-by-march-2026"><u>the company was committed to launching just six of the 12 live service games it was working on</u></a> by March 2026, in a shift in strategy that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-game-cancelled-will-focus-on-single-player-games-going-forward"><u>saw The Last of Us multiplayer game cancelled</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Arrowhead’s Helldivers 2 was a breakout hit, becoming the fastest-selling PlayStation Studios game of all time with 12 million copies sold in just 12 weeks, Sony’s other live service games were either canceled or suffered disastrous launches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, Sony’s Concord is one of the biggest video game disasters in PlayStation history, lasting just a couple of weeks before it was brought offline amid eye-wateringly low player numbers. Sony later decided to kill the game entirely and shut its developer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And earlier this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games"><u>Sony reportedly canceled two unannounced live service games</u></a>, one a God of War title in development at Bluepoint, the other in the works at Days Gone developer Bend.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tekken Boss Katsuhiro Harada Says Dev Team 'Working Around the Clock' to Improve Tekken 8 Amid Backlash, 'Emergency' Patch Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tekken-boss-katsuhiro-harada-says-dev-team-working-around-the-clock-to-improve-tekken-8-amid-backlash-emergency-patch-planned</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tekken-boss-katsuhiro-harada-says-dev-team-working-around-the-clock-to-improve-tekken-8-amid-backlash-emergency-patch-planned.1155189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tekken-boss-katsuhiro-harada-says-dev-team-working-around-the-clock-to-improve-tekken-8-amid-backlash-emergency-patch-planned<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s all kicking off in the Tekken community. This week IGN reported on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tekken-8-community-in-uproar-over-season-2-balance-changes-pros-threaten-to-ditch-the-game-steam-reviews-on-fire">how Tekken 8 players had reacted in anger to the Season 2 update</a> because of big changes it made to the way the fighting game played.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.tekken-official.jp/tekken_news/?p=942" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Patch notes</u></a> revealed an across-the-board buff to character damage potential and offensive pressure, which caused some within the community to complain that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tekken-8">Tekken 8</a> has strayed too far from the classic Tekken experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The backlash got so bad that some pro Tekken players threatened to ditch the game, while others took to Steam to leave angry negative reviews.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In response, the Tekken development team at Bandai Namco issued a statement acknowledging the furore, and confirming an “emergency patch” would be released this month to address Paul and Jack specifically, with more balance changes to come.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Fighters,</p><p>we are aware of the current community feedback regarding <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TEKKEN8?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#TEKKEN8</a> Season 2.<br>We are carefully reviewing the balance of the game; expect more information about these changes soon.</p><p>In addition, an emergency patch will be released in April to adress the following issues👇 <a href="https://t.co/Gvet0IOISu" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/Gvet0IOISu</a></p></div>— TEKKEN (@TEKKEN) <a href="https://twitter.com/TEKKEN/status/1907742315751301562?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Tekken development chief has waded in, <a href="https://x.com/Harada_TEKKEN/status/1907797510762242238" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeting</a> one person’s complaint that the Tekken community had gone too far in directing its anger at specific staff on social media.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“In any case, it is clear to me that the result is a disconnect between what the community wants and the tuning results,” Harada said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I understand that whatever words I may be accused by the community about it, that is not the essential issue and it is not the time to worry about it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We have our Battle &amp; Tuning team working around the clock to read through all the feedback logs from the community and work on future policies and changes for the better.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Thanks.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Tekken characters in Season 2 <a href="https://t.co/n6UTHsSswn" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/n6UTHsSswn</a></p>— K-Wiss 🉐 (@KungFuKobi) <a href="https://twitter.com/KungFuKobi/status/1907779115291234747?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It seems unlikely that Harada’s comment will calm the angry responses from the Tekken community, or stem the tide of negative user reviews on Steam. Recent reviews there are now ‘overwhelmingly negative’ after thousands of negative reviews were left in the last week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I am baffled,” reads the current “most helpful” user review. “I never seen devs so out of touch with the community.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“New season dropped and they made every character into a braindead easy mix up machine without a single buff to defense. From the start of Tekken 8 players were vocal about the prominence of easy mix-ups and the glaring nerfs to defense compared to past Tekken games and yet they do a huge patch with lots of new moves that emphasise on every aspect the players disliked about the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No-one, literally no-one asked for these changes, even new players never asked for more offense in a game that clearly lacks defensive options and is easy to mash button and win like in most Tekken games.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>