<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 13:35:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looks Like The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Will Support Cloud Saves After All]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/looks-like-the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-will-support-cloud-saves-after-all</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/looks-like-the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-will-support-cloud-saves-after-all.1172400/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/looks-like-the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-will-support-cloud-saves-after-all<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom"><u>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</u></a> Switch 2 version <em>will</em> support cloud saves after all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We already knew that the Nintendo Switch 2 was set to get special enhanced versions of several Switch 1 games, including The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, but as IGN reported last week, a disclaimer had fans worrying that some games, or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-worried-tears-of-the-kingdoms-switch-2-version-wont-support-cloud-saves"><u>at least this one, wouldn't support Nintendo's cloud save functionality as they'd hope</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's because, initially, Nintendo's pages for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787249.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Tears of the Kingdom</u></a>'s Switch 2 edition carried the following disclaimer: "Please note: this software does not support the Nintendo Switch Online paid membership’s Save Data Cloud backup feature."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, however, Nintendo has updated its website to provide more information. While <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza"><u>Donkey Kong Bananza</u></a>'s page has since scrubbed all mention of cloud saves completely, Nintendo has revised the disclaimer on the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/The-Legend-of-Zelda-Tears-of-the-Kingdom-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-2787249.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Tears of the Kingdom page</u></a> so it now states: "Save data created in the second save data slot in The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition cannot be transferred to The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom on Nintendo Switch."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/24/screenshot-2025-04-24-at-11-47-01-1745492041341.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The disclaimer should reassure concerned Switch 2 owners.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This suggests players <em>will</em> be able to transfer their old Switch 1 Tears of the Kingdom saves to their new Switch 2 devices, but it won't be possible to transfer Switch 2 saves back to the OG system (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-edition-zelda-games-wont-support-cloud-saves-to-backup-your-data" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Eurogamer</u></a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> page also now includes the same message, suggesting an identical approach to save transfers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders went live overnight, with the price still fixed at $449.99 — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-went-live-and-were-predictably-a-mess"><u>and they went about as well as you'd expect</u></a>. Check out IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-order guide</u></a> for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes (April 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bubble-gum-simulator-infinity-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bubble-gum-simulator-infinity-codes-april-2025.1172397/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bubble-gum-simulator-infinity-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Mystery Boxes, Lucky V Potions, Coins, and more can all be yours with these codes.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for codes for Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY? Well, there's no bursting your bubble here. IGN has you covered with all the latest working codes, rewarding you with everything from Mystery Boxes to Lucky V Potions, Coins, and more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Working Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes (April 2025)</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are all the current and active codes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>throwback</strong> - 1x Infinity Elixir<strong> (NEW!)</strong></li><li><strong>Easter</strong> - 4x Mystery Boxes</li><li><strong>Lucky</strong> - 1x Lucky V Potion</li><li><strong>RELEASE</strong> - 500 Coins</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are currently <strong>no expired Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY codes</strong>. As soon as the codes above stop working, we'll move them to this section.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Redeeming codes in Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY is a straightforward experience. Just follow these steps:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/24/bubble-gum-simulator-infinity-codes-1-1745490177114.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Load up the <strong>Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Roblox</strong> experience</li><li>On the <strong>left-hand side</strong> of the screen, look for the <strong>bird icon that says Codes</strong></li><li>Click this and you'll be automatically taken to a bar that says <strong>Redeem Codes</strong></li><li>Enter the code, then <strong>press Redeem</strong> (despite what it says, <strong>you do not need to follow Rumble Studios</strong> to be able to redeem them)</li><li>Enjoy your goodies!</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Whenever a code isn't working, it's typically because it's been entered wrong. There are lots of Roblox experiences that have case-sensitive codes, so it's important that you enter the code exactly as you see it. To make it easier for you, we recommend copying them directly from this article. Each code is tested before we add it, so if it's here, it's valid! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other reason codes can not work is simply because they're expired. You'll usually receive a pop-up that says it's invalid or expired when putting the code in if this is the case.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where Can I Find More Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY Codes?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Rumble Studios has its very own <a href="https://discord.com/invite/rumble" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord Server</a> where Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY codes are posted. To save you scrolling through the chat or locating them yourself, however, we check for new codes each day, so you can be sure that if there's a new code, it'll be here!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY on Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you've ever wanted to blow enormous bubbles with your gum, and you'd love a gang of adorable pets, Bubble Gum Simulator INFINITY is likely to be your thing. You'll click to chew gum, sell the bubbles you make for coins, use those coins to hatch eggs for pets, and then have your pets help you collect coins. As you earn more, you can hatch better eggs and built a team of cute pets, as well as upgrade your gum for more profit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 1886 Is a Remake of the First Game Due Out 2027, Dev Insists It Will Continue to Update Frostpunk 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/frostpunk-1886-is-a-remake-of-the-first-game-due-out-2027-dev-insists-it-will-continue-to-update-frostpunk-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-1886-is-a-remake-of-the-first-game-due-out-2027-dev-insists-it-will-continue-to-update-frostpunk-2.1172358/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/frostpunk-1886-is-a-remake-of-the-first-game-due-out-2027-dev-insists-it-will-continue-to-update-frostpunk-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">11 bit studios has announced Frostpunk 1886, a remake of the first game due out in 2027.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Polish developer is using Unreal Engine 5 for this project, which it has revealed just over half a year after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/frostpunk-2">Frostpunk 2</a> came out. The first <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/frostpunk">Frostpunk</a> launched in 2018, so assuming the remake does come out in 2027, it’ll be nearly a decade on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Frostpunk is a city-building survival video game set in an alternate history late 19th century. You build and maintain a city during a worldwide volcanic winter, managing resources, making choices on how to survive, and exploring the area outside their city for survivors, resources, or other useful items.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/04/25/frostpunk-review">Frostpunk review</a> returned a 9/10. We said: “Frostpunk deftly mixes a variety of thematic ideas and gameplay elements into an engaging and unique, if occasionally unintuitive, strategy game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/frostpunk-2-review">Frostpunk 2 fared a little less well in IGN's review</a>, getting an 8/10. We said: "Thanks to a ground-up rethinking of its ice-age city builder mechanics, Frostpunk 2's larger scale is less intimate but more socially and politically complex than the original."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">11 bit insisted it still plans to update Frostpunk 2 with DLC and plans for the console launch remain, while working on Frostpunk 1886.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"With the studio’s proprietary Liquid Engine, which powered not only the original Frostpunk but also This War of Mine, no longer in development, the team has long sought a new foundation to carry forward the legacy of the first game,” 11 bit said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“While Frostpunk 2 continues to forge ahead with free major content updates, a console launch, and DLCs, this newly announced project marks a return to the franchise’s roots, offering both newcomers and longtime citizens of New London an evolved take on the harsh, morally challenging survival experience that started it all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“But Frostpunk 1886 — so titled to honour a pivotal moment in the timeline of the universe, when the Great Storm descended upon New London — is no mere visual overhaul. It builds upon the core of the original, expanding it with new content, mechanics, laws, and — perhaps most excitingly — an entirely new Purpose path, offering a fresh experience even for the most seasoned players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Reimagining Frostpunk in Unreal Engine also allows the game to become a living, expandable platform, bringing with it long-awaited mod support — a community request that was previously impossible to realize due to technical limitations of the original engine — as well as the possibility to add future DLC content.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">11 bit studios said its fans can “look forward to a future where Frostpunk 2 and Frostpunk 1886 evolve side by side — two paths forged in parallel, each carrying the vision of survival into unrelenting cold.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The studio is also working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-alters">The Alters</a>, which is due out in June.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>