<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:25:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obsidian RPG Avowed Can Hit 60FPS on Xbox Series X]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/obsidian-rpg-avowed-can-hit-60fps-on-xbox-series-x</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/obsidian-rpg-avowed-can-hit-60fps-on-xbox-series-x.1101801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/obsidian-rpg-avowed-can-hit-60fps-on-xbox-series-x<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Obsidian Entertainment's upcoming role-playing game Avowed can hit 60 frames per second on Xbox Series X.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though she offered no further insight, game director Carrie Patel told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dAtStowg2Rk" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MinnMax</a> that "you can get up to [60fps]" on Microsoft's more powerful console, though <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/avowed-runs-at-30fps-on-xbox-series-x-and-s-obsidian-confirms">the Xbox Series S version will be limited to the 30fps as previously confirmed</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's still unclear if Avowed will include a performance mode and graphics mode as has become standard, the former of which generally means 60fps with lower visuals while the latter generally means 30fps with improved visuals, or if the default setting hits 60fps on Xbox Series X naturally.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Avowed arrives February 13 for those willing to spend at least $89.99, though fans only willing to spend  $69.99 are forced by Microsoft to wait until February 18. This is a recent trend deployed by publishers but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-collectors-edition-price-drops-50-amid-cancelled-season-pass-and-early-access">has already been scrapped by the likes of Ubisoft</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in the same universe as Pillars of Eternity, Avowed is a first person fantasy RPG with a grand emphasis on player choice. The story weaves through tales of war, mystery, and intrigue, as players navigate the land and forge friendships or rivalries with those around them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It earned praise in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/avowed-the-final-preview">IGN's Final Preview</a> of the game, in which we praised its nuanced conversations, player freedom, and said "Avowed is just a lot of fun."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>