<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 16:18:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite OG Season 3 Launches Today Alongside The Walking Dead Assets Including Negan's Infamous Baseball Bat, Lucille]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-og-season-3-launches-today-alongside-the-walking-dead-assets-including-negans-infamous-baseball-bat-lucille</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-og-season-3-launches-today-alongside-the-walking-dead-assets-including-negans-infamous-baseball-bat-lucille.1144179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-og-season-3-launches-today-alongside-the-walking-dead-assets-including-negans-infamous-baseball-bat-lucille<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fortnite OG Season 3 launches today alongside the arrival of assets from The Walking Dead, including Negan's infamous baseball bat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chapter 1 Season 3 sees the return of the Lucky Landing POI and a meteor that’s on a “seriously worrying collision course!” Epic Games said. Also from the OG days, the 50v50 LTM returns as OG 50v50.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">OG 50v50 pits two 50-player teams against each other, and runs until 9am ET on April 14. Fortnite veterans will remember that 50v50 was the first-ever LTM to be added to Fortnite Battle Royale, all the way back in 2017.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The meteor will emerge in the sky later in OG Chapter 1 Season 3, and get closer and closer as the Season goes on. This, too, will be fondly remembered by Fortnite players who were there to see battle royale kick off back in the day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, starting today, March 25, anyone can create their own The Walking Dead Universe islands for Fortnite using Unreal Editor for Fortnite (UEFN) and Fortnite Creative.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Creators can start a new project using one of the new The Walking Dead Universe templates to access unique Walking Dead-themed weapons, Prefabs, Galleries, and Walker NPCs. Then, on May 16, developers will be able to publish their The Walking Dead Universe islands via the Creator Portal and make them available for people to play.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/25/fortnite-x-the-walking-dead-universe-shiva-shotgun-and-lucille-1742910536643.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Negan's infamous baseball bat, Lucille, hits Fortnite. Image credit: Epic Games.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Kirkman, creator of The Walking Dead, said: “This collaboration with Fortnite is an incredible opportunity to expand The Walking Dead in ways we’ve never imagined. Whether it’s Lucille smashing through hordes or the eerie presence of Walkers, I can’t wait to see where the Fortnite community’s creativity takes us.”</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Here’s a breakdown of some of the Walking Dead tools available for Fortnite creators today:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Walker NPC</strong> - Slow, unintelligent, horde enemies, Walkers are motivated by their primal drive to consume humans.</li><li><strong>Weapons and Items</strong> - Mow ‘em down with the Shiva Shotgun Ranged Weapon, an exotic, modded pump shotgun (which also triggers a Shiva tiger roar); use the Lucille Melee Weapon, the iconic heavy-hitting baseball bat wrapped in wire wielded by the infamous Negan (and perfect for bashing in Walkers and Survivors alike).</li><li><strong>Effects</strong> - Create with the new heavy linework post-processing effect, a shader that influences the overall look and feel of an island to bring the tone and visual style of The Walking Dead comics.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>