<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:08:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Cancels Two Unannounced Live-Service Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games.1084827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Edit: The story has been updated to report that Bluepoint's canceled live-service game was a God of War title.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has reportedly canceled two unannounced live-service games that were in development at Bend Studio and Bluepoint Games, respectively.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-16/sony-cancels-two-more-playstation-projects?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczNzA2ODk1MywiZXhwIjoxNzM3NjczNzUzLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTUTdFWjJUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.OtpjLAX_fLRPjeIhmdZSXLhsiFNDef1RlL6IxoCIQes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a> reports that Sony has ended production on two live-service games that were in the works at Bend Studio, best known for the zombie game Days Gone, and another separate game in the works at Bluepoint Games, best known for their remasters of games like Shadow of the Colossus and the Demon's Souls remake. The Bluepoint game was reportedly a live-service God of War game according to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lfvfm2febc2e" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jason Schreier</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A Sony spokesperson confirmed the cancellations to Bloomberg. Sony also added that neither studios will be closed and that they will work with them "to determine what are the next projects," from the two studios will be. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is another blow to Sony's ambitious live-service game plans. In 2022, Sony acquired Destiny 2 developer Bungie and announced plans to have 12 live-service games running by the end of the 2025 fiscal year. Those plans have failed to materialize after Sony revised that number <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-commits-to-launch-just-six-of-playstations-12-live-service-games-by-march-2026">down to just six</a>, of which Bend and Bluepoint's games were likely two of them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony also closed down Concord developer Firewalk Studio, oversaw layoffs at Bungie, and canceled numerous online projects like Naughty Dogs' The Last of Us PvP game, a rumored Spider-Man online game, a live-service Twisted Metal game, and a third-person Destiny spinoff titled Payback.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This leaves just Bungie's Marathon and Haven Studios' PvP project still in the works, alongside continued support for Helldivers 2 which Sony is publishing. There are also rumors of two online Horizon games, one co-op experience and another being an MMO.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's clear now that Sony seems to be rethinking its live-service strategy, but whether that means backing online projects it believes will succeed or abandoning the space altogether remains to be seen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk and Asmongold's Social Media Scrap Over Path of Exile 2, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elon-musk-and-asmongolds-social-media-scrap-over-path-of-exile-2-explained</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elon-musk-and-asmongolds-social-media-scrap-over-path-of-exile-2-explained.1084791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elon-musk-and-asmongolds-social-media-scrap-over-path-of-exile-2-explained<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">X/Twitter owner Elon Musk lit up social media feeds today when he launched a wave of posts publicly criticizing Twitch streamer and content creator Zack Hoyt (a.k.a. Asmongold) following controversy regarding the tech billionaire’s high-level gameplay of Grinding Gear Games’ <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Musk first shared his thoughts in <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1879798348993237046" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a reply to a post from YouTuber Screamheart</a>, who published a two-minute clip from a new video that dives into the allegations surrounding the X owner’s Path of Exile 2 gameplay. The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_CDYptQ-g04" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full video</a> totals eight minutes and includes approximately 20 seconds of footage from Asmongold's livestreams where he alleges that Musk is not totally responsible for the progress made on his level 97 Path of Exile 2 character.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There is no way he played that account. Like, I’m sorry,” Asmongold says in the clip. “I think he bought the account, or somebody played it for him. A hundred-f***ing-percent.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Asmon behaves like a maverick “independent”, but in reality has to ask his boss for permission before he can do anything. He is not his own man.</p>— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1879798348993237046?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 16, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Musk’s response includes a series of replies where he calls the streamer “not his own man.” The billionaire also took the opportunity to post what <a href="https://x.com/Asmongold/status/1879929652380385485" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Asmongold is calling</u></a> a <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1879798957301510341" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>picture of “leaked” direct messages</u></a> shared through X where the two previously spoke about how the streamer manages his YouTube account. It was a moment that has led to a messy back-and-forth between the two social media giants, and it’s preceded by in-depth investigation into Musk’s involvement in the gaming space.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Musk has long been championed as a gaming enthusiast. For years, he’s mentioned his appreciation for Blizzard Entertainment’s work on titles like Overwatch, and just yesterday, <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1879520605634220362" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>he said</u></a> he still plays games “as my one recreational activity to quiet my mind.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Musk's self-proclaimed gaming prowess has been brought into question in recent months as players began to take a closer look at his performance and knowledge of the games he plays.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One title that has seemingly taken up hundreds of hours of Musk’s time is 2023’s Diablo 4, though as he’s climbed leaderboards and chatted with developers on X, many have commented on how much time he might be dedicating to Blizzard’s dungeon-crawling experience. In November of last year, the billionaire <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7qZl_5xHoBw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>boasted about his place</u></a> as one of the top 20 Diablo 4 players in the world, and he <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2024/11/22/elon-musk-apparently-just-became-the-no-1-diablo-4-player-in-the-world/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>reached the number one spot a few weeks later</u></a>. While others spend hundreds if not thousands of hours merely chipping away at the never-ending faucet of content available, Musk has <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1708776354597003329" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>maintained his gaming status</u></a> while juggling his responsibilities as a figurehead of companies like X, SpaceX, Tesla, Neuralink, and more.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Leaking my DM's is one thing but this is absolutely uncalled for <a href="https://t.co/I4eRo2QPKF" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/I4eRo2QPKF</a></p>— Zack (@Asmongold) <a href="https://twitter.com/Asmongold/status/1879929652380385485?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 16, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Discussion about Musk’s abilities as a gamer reached a new level after a recent, early January livestream that saw Musk tackling endgame tasks in Path of Exile 2 drew criticism from fans. Videos like those from content creators such as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmEe3eUPWq4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Quin69TV</u></a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Ui4h0J1mIQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>penguinz0</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wlCCtrOCvu0" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Asmongold</u></a> have garnered millions of views as action RPG veterans analyze footage and commentary posted by the tech giant. One specific point of contention revolves around his (<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/percy-verence-elon-musks-infamous-path-of-exile-2-hardcore-character-dead-at-level-97/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>now deceased</u></a>) level 97 Hardcore character, Percy_Verence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Two weeks into the league, when people are playing the game, literally, they are staying up 40 to 50 hours without sleeping, only playing Path of Exile – and they are the most try-hard guys in the world – the highest-ranked player in the Hardcore trade league was level 93,” Quin69TV explains in his video 'Elon Musk is Lying About Being Good at Video Games.'</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You’re thinking to yourself, ‘That’s kind of close to 97.’ Every time you level up, it becomes exponentially harder to gain experience. A lot harder. So, these players, to get to level 97, had to be playing the game every day for the majority of their day.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Musk’s stream features a number of moments that players are pointing to as signs he may not be quite as familiar with Path of Exile 2’s endgame mechanics as one might expect him to be after spending so much time in its world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seemingly struggling to access Maps, strange tab names, illogical inventory management, leaving behind rare loot, and a disregard for notoriously powerful weapons is just some of the evidence from Musk’s stream that players are using to accuse the billionaire of not playing nearly as much as he says he is.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/16/gettyimages-2188387321-1737065042292.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Some are questioning Elon Musk's Path of Exile 2 gameplay. Photo by Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Many are working with the theory that Musk might be paying others to boost his Path of Exile account for him, though there is no confirmation of this. The “why?” in the formula remains a mystery, too, but the idea is that maintaining his status as a gaming expert is something Musk is interested in, regardless of whether he’s actually the one playing the games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Asmongold, whose YouTube channel features numerous other videos discussing content and updates for Path of Exile 2, took the time to address the topic with his own video called 'Elon Musk is not getting away with this...' In the footage, he largely agrees with Quin69TV’s analysis of the situation, believing that Musk may not be as truthful about his experience as he’s letting on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I thought it was really cool that Elon Musk was, like, a serious player of Diablo, and everything. I did,” Asmongold says. “I thought it was awesome, and I bet he probably did play PoE 2 on day one. I do. I bet he probably played it, and then he stopped.”</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I’m on hundreds of streams on YouTube/Twitch playing live with the world’s best players. </p><p>No other way to say this, but, while Asmon IS good at caustic commentary and making fun of people, he is NOT good at video games 🤷‍♂️</p></div>— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1879802284546408610?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 16, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">In the fallout of Musk’s posts to Asmongold, X’s own Community Notes feature has chimed in to clarify a few points. Regarding the tech billionaire’s comments suggesting that Asmongold must ask his bosses for permission, Community Notes clarifies that the employees mentioned in the leaked screenshots are the streamer’s editor, not his bosses. The user-driven feature also addressed Musk’s comment that Asmongold is “NOT good at video games” by listing his achievements in World of Warcraft.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Was he probably not happy about the PoE video? He’ll get over it,” Asmongold added <a href="https://x.com/Awk20000/status/1879704846846345302" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>in a recent livestream</u></a>. “Listen – it was so obvious. You cannot get mad at me for bringing this up. Everybody was talking about this. Come on, man.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elon has not directly addressed the widespread criticisms regarding his Path of Exile 2 gameplay at the time of this story’s publication.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker Early Access Review in Progress]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hyper-light-breaker-review-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-early-access-review-in-progress.1084659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hyper-light-breaker-review-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">So far this roguelike feels hyper light on content and the wrong kind of broken.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Normally, when a sequel is announced that’s a wild departure from the original, I welcome it with open arms – look no further than my inexplicable but everlasting love of Banjo-Kazooie Nuts N Bolts as evidence. But after just a day with Hyper Light Breaker – a follow-up (though not a proper sequel) to one of my all-time favorite indie games, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/04/14/hyper-light-drifter-review"><u>Hyper Light Drifter</u></a> – I feel like Vito Corleone telling y’all to look at how they massacred my boy. I’ve only sunk six hours into this incredibly challenging co-op roguelike so far, and although there’s clearly the skeleton of a good action-RPG in here somewhere, it’s currently buried deeper than the sun can see under sloppy combat mechanics, shallow and frustrating exploration, and scant content that began to feel repetitive only two hours in. Of course, this is its early access launch, so there’s always hope an initially rough package will transform into something much better with enough time – but in terms of what’s here right now, my disappointment is immeasurable and my day is ruined.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The goal of a run is to hunt around a randomized map for better gear and key items before taking on three highly deadly and supremely irritating bosses hiding out on each map, then extract yourself back to base to regroup, buy some upgrades, and do it again. I’ve already bested a couple bosses, which summon minions endlessly and flop around erratically to do massive damage, but have yet to complete a map in its entirety, which I’m assuming won’t happen until I near the end of what’s currently available in early access. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Combat makes an absolutely terrible first impresion.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Maybe the combat will grow on me once I get deeper in, but it makes an absolutely terrible first impression. There isn’t anything interesting about the melee hack-and-slash attacks you are given, the alternative third-person shooting option has very limited ammo, moving and dodging feel unresponsive and inconsistent, and the lock-on system constantly toggles itself off unexpectedly and gets me killed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">All of these things are especially frustrating when Hyper Light Breaker is immediately difficult – and I mean <em>extremely </em>difficult, and that’s coming from someone with all the achievements in Sekiro – but doesn’t bother to explain its rules and often punishes you with an onslaught of enemy attacks that feel cheap. It’s also extremely funny that you start with no healing items (and are only given them at great expense and extremely sparingly) when you’d think you would need them most at the beginning when you’re learning. Instead, you basically have to throw yourself at impossible odds until you can unlock the bare minimum you need to survive.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So I’ve spent most of my time running around procedurally generated worlds that at least look quite pretty, using a unique art style that channels Hyper Light Drifter in 3D quite well. But these repetitive areas are extremely irritating to navigate, filled with awkward cliffs and crooked landscapes that feel like I’m not actually supposed to be climbing them but offer me no other choice. On the bright side, they at least give you a neat hoverboard to ride around on and do tricks, and although the controls are as sloppy as everything else, hoverboards are indeed still dope as hell and there are definitely some good times to be had there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve got a whole lot left to do and see before I’m ready to finalize my review sometime next week, and it's a little encouraging that combat is becoming a bit more bearable as I start to understand its unpolished ways and gain more than zero healing items. But so far I’m not having a good time, and that’s not what I was expecting from this long-awaited follow-up, even taking into account this is its early access launch.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How the Monster Hunter Wilds Team Select Their Beastly Lineup – IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/how-the-monster-hunter-wilds-team-select-their-beastly-lineup-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-the-monster-hunter-wilds-team-select-their-beastly-lineup-%E2%80%93-ign-first.1084653/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/how-the-monster-hunter-wilds-team-select-their-beastly-lineup-ign-first<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you ask people who the main characters are in Monster Hunter, they might say “the hunters” – but others will tell you: “It’s all about the monsters.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So many striking creatures have appeared over the course of Monster Hunter’s 20-plus-year history. With each new hunter and each new hunt, we form new memories around these monsters. That's why players have pored over information about the new monsters appearing in the latest title, Monster Hunter Wilds, and why they let out shouts of joy when they heard that certain monsters would be making a long-awaited return.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">IGN First Monster Hunter Wilds Oilwell Basin Artwork</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In this interview with Kaname Fujioka, who was the director of the first Monster Hunter and now Executive Director and Art Director for Wilds, and Yuya Tokuda, director of both Monster Hunter: World and Wilds, we get to hear in detail about the process that new and returning monsters went through before appearing in Wilds, with a special focus on the processes of creation and selection. Throughout the interview, I felt the deep love that these developers have for their monsters, as well as the ceaseless work they've put into giving those monsters the greatest stage possible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tokuda first explains the process that goes into the creation of a Monster Hunter monster.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We first consider what we want players to experience when facing major monsters like Arkveld, as well as the setting, ecosystem and so on of the world, unique to each title,” he tells IGN. “We then think about the kind of monsters needed to do that. In a way, we start by putting puzzle pieces together, like, ‘If this monster exists in this place, how does the ecological pyramid work here?’”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It's easy to simply think that players will be happy so long as popular monsters make a reappearance, but the development team actually focuses most on the player's experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We don't focus too much on the proportion or number of new versus old monsters,” continues Tokuda. “What's important at the end of the day is the overall level design and order of monsters across the entire game, as well as the balance of ecological pyramids in each area. We take this multifaceted approach to decide which monsters to include." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">How will players play the game, and when will they encounter each monster? What will we see monsters doing in this latest title enabled by new technology? Fujioka says that this approach is extremely important, even when choosing to have older monsters make a reappearance.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"So even when we're selecting old monsters to put in the game, part of that involves making sure to stay true to that monster's concept while thinking about how much room each monster has to grow when they're reborn using current-day technology and game design," he says.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Setting the stage</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Among the monsters that live in the Forbidden Lands (or as the developers call it, "The East") like Doshaguma, which embodies the game's herd system, there are some monsters that quickly present new ways of hunting spread across the world of Wilds. During the open beta test in November, many players encountered Chatacabra, or Rey Dau, the apex monster of the Windward Plains. As the game's entryway into its world, the Windward Plains contains monsters whose designs were carefully made to match the overall game experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Herds are one of the major concepts in Wilds, and so we created Doshaguma as a monster that lets players experience this element of the game,” says Tokuda. “We were designing Doshaguma from a pretty early stage, in part to help verify the way that packs move."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In fact, Fujioka says, the design of Rey Dau, the boss of the Windward Plains, was finished before that of Arkveld, the marquee monster in Wilds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I think part of a monster's character can be an appearance that simply makes you think that it looks cool, even among all the other unique monsters,” he says. “We call these our ‘handsome monsters’. We believe that if we're able to have one of these cool monsters appear at just the right time, they'll stand out that much more as a unique character. We thought that Rey Dau was in a good position for that even during the design stage, and so we wanted it to be a cool monster. As Rey Dau's design was finalized before Arkveld's, even some of our own staff thought that it was the game's main monster until partway through development. That's just how handsome it is." However, once Arkveld’s design was finalized the whole team was satisfied they had found their flagship monster. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rey Dau is a monster that uses lightning, and it reigns over the Windward Plains as its apex monster. Tokuda explains that this background was used as a base for its attack patterns and movements.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Rey Dau's biggest attack is one where it stores lightning in its body and slides its face along the ground to unleash all of it at once,” he says. “As it grinds its wings into the sand, the lightning combines with it to create Fulgurite Ore. The amount of electricity it stores rises higher and higher when it wears these crystals, and it can store electricity faster as well. Thinking about this process is what caused it to become a monster notable for its wing-based physical attacks."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fujioka says that monster attacks are even a part of the game's stage design.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"When we were designing this stage, we talked about incorporating the process of lightning generating Fulgurite Ore,” he says. “The terrain is formed by Fulgurite Ore created when lightning strikes the ground, and villagers use the ore to ward off monsters. We hope that players pay attention to how monster biology and attack methods are connected to how the game's humans live."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While it may sound simple for ore to be generated when lightning shot from a monster hits the sand, a number of technical hurdles awaited the team before they could make this a reality. Conditions like the timing of the lightning hitting the sand or the desert and its sloping hills had to be calculated in real-time to generate this ore, and creating that system was no simple task.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, Monster Hunter is a real-time, synchronous multiplayer game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The feeling of playing together and being able to communicate on the same wavelength with shared information is extremely important to us. Our top priority during development is how we express the experience of people playing in the same space," says Fujioka. I'm overwhelmed for a moment when I hear this. Yes, this may of course be what multiplayer game development theory states, but the hurdles presented to this team by what they're attempting to depict are far greater than players imagine.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, compromise was not an option when it came to depicting Rey Dau's actions when considering the earlier discussion about a world where monster ecology is directly tied to the lives of human characters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Monster Hunter does depict a fantasy world, but we want players to feel a kind of reality from each individual thing they see in-game,” says Tokuda. “Graphics become higher-definition as hardware advances, and so we want the world's setting to be as authentic as possible, because this kind of reality is connected to the game's immersion." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These words make me feel how important the detailed creation of monsters is to Mr. Tokuda. The games depict their world through their monsters, and depict their monsters through their world. As this reciprocal relationship digs deeper and takes form, it completes the Monster Hunter experience.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Returning monsters</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Forbidden Lands act as this game's stage, so as a place unknown to hunters, the developers say that they included a higher proportion of new monsters at the start.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Among all of its monsters, the first familiar one that hunters encounter in the Forbidden Lands is Congalala. Its reappearance was a moment that shocked and delighted players. I had a chance to play the Scarlet Forest where it appears, and along with the story that involves the adorable Wudwuds who live in the Forest, it all made for a humorous sequence. Though a hunt is understood to be a serious task for players who've faced the harsh environments of the Forbidden Lands in the Windward Plains, this is still a moment on the lighthearted side.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Congalala was selected after an overall evaluation of the Scarlet Forest's ecosystem, comical twists and more. Still, Tokuda says that the dev team found ways in which it's a surprisingly good match even after their decision.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Congalala is a monster with straightforward action compared to the unique monsters of the Scarlet Forest that hunters will have faced so far, like Lala Barina,” he says. “It's easy to hit, and I think it ended up being perfectly placed for players to enjoy hunting as they make full use of what they've learned and the weapons they've created so far."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"When we have monsters appear, we're always conscious of not just trying to make them easy to understand for players new to Monster Hunter, but to also shock and delight fans of the series," Fujioka says, recalling the reaction fans had when they announced Congalala's return. "I think tossing Congalala out right there was just right for it. We announced it at Tokyo Game Show because we thought fans who know about Congalala would enjoy that. Once we did, the reaction ended up being even bigger than we imagined. We talked later about how that must have been the greatest moment of Congalala's life."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seeing these two as they say this makes me think that in a way, the Monster Hunter development team is also like a talent agency trying to sell its stars. Monster Hunter's monsters must feel as attractive and real as they do because of these creators who care about their monsters more than anything, searching for the place where they'll shine the brightest.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">The sensei returns</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For longtime fans, the reappearance of Yian Kut-Ku was likely even more of a shock than Congalala's. As a sort of rite of passage that teaches players the movements and methods they need while being a bit strict at times and kind at others, Yian Kut-Ku is known to series fans as Sensei, or “teacher.” Despite being a beloved monster, though, it didn't reappear in the series for the longest time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Yian Kut-Ku is a monster that many Monster Hunter lovers know, and we're aware that they call it Sensei, says Fujioka, clarifying the monster's positioning. “We designed it as a monster that teaches you the basics when facing large monsters."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's difficult to have Yian Kut-Ku act as a teacher, as that role is played in each game by different monsters that are suited for the environment of its new stages. The way that the fans love Yian Kut-Ku is important to these developers as well.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While Yian Kut-Ku's name would always come up whenever discussing which monsters would appear in each game, it was difficult for it to make an appearance without something new that still felt right for it. Tokuda says that the herds in Wilds are part of what helped to support Sensei's reappearance. That's because Yian Kut-Ku was always related to packs of monsters, even if they couldn't be depicted in the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Yian Kut-Ku herds did exist in the game's setting, but we never had a chance to make that a part of the actual gameplay until now,” he says. “It seemed like a good fit for the systems of Wilds that let us include packs of monsters, and we were able to find a moment for it to appear in the perfect way during the game's progression."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What could he mean by "a perfect way"? I try asking more about Yian Kut-Ku's position in Wilds.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"While Yian Kut-Ku is loved by many players right now, I think it was incredibly strong when it first appeared,” Tokuda elaborates. “It's placed at the moment in the game where the difficulty curve suddenly spikes upward, and we weren't sure that it'd be right to have it appear like that again to play the role of a teacher. That's why we thought we needed to do a deeper analysis of its strengths and what makes it feel strong. We looked at recent player trends and thought about the position they'd want Yian Kut-Ku to occupy instead of simply being a teacher, which is why we've prepared a different kind of position for it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also a bit of a behind-the-scenes story about Yian Kut-Ku. Tokuda is a lover of large reptiles, and his pet lizard that's over a meter long has a major relationship to Yian Kut-Ku's design this time around.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I made a garden that's like a miniature Ancient Forest for my lizards and even breed them there,” he says. “It's like there's vegetation inside of my home. I've made an ecosystem there, complete with water, light and wind. An artist who knew that I raise lizards told me to bring my largest lizard's shed skin, which we then scanned and processed in order to make it a part of Yian Kut-Ku's scales in the game."</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Monsters growing alongside fans</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Yian Kut-Ku was able to make a comeback thanks to the passion players had for their Sensei and the herds system implemented in Wilds. So then, which monster's comeback is most awaited out of those that haven't made an appearance (yet) in Wilds?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"That would have to be Lagiacrus," Tokuda instantly responds. "Ever since World, people ask us to bring Lagiacrus back no matter where in the world we go. It feels like we've been constantly asked since then."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fujioka nods vigorously as he sits beside Tokuda. "There really are a lot of fans both inside and outside of Japan who love Monster Hunter Tri,” he says. “It's a very memorable title for me as well. Listening to the fans, I get the sense that monsters like Lagiacrus and Brachydios enjoy a particularly deep-rooted popularity. Gore Magala as well, as it seems like many people have a lasting love of monsters that are featured on the cover art of a title."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As Tokuda says, Lagiacrus is a very memorable monster for both developers. The two were involved in its creation, with Fujioka as director during the development of Monster Hunter Tri and Tokuda as its lead planner of the monsters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I'm one of the creators of Lagiacrus myself, so I naturally have a deep attachment to it,” says Tokuda. “I might even say that I want to put it in the game more than anyone. There are a lot of difficulties, such as the fact that we haven't had aquatic battles or action ever since Monster Hunter 3 Ultimate, of course… But we've heard everyone's voices loud and clear, and I want fans to know that I want it to make an appearance just as much as anyone."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hearing Tokuda talk, I get a sense of the deep affection and attachment to specific monsters that goes beyond the categories of developer or player, held instead by people who love Monster Hunter. The monsters lovingly created by the developers are loved by players, with those feelings then reaching the developers. Perhaps this is how monsters in Monster Hunter change and grow.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"When looking at Monster Hunter as a series, I've always felt a kind of strong passion that's created through communication,” says Fujioka. “The biggest characters that appear in Monster Hunter are its monsters, at the end of the day. It's about how fans see those monsters, and that understanding is what creates the next step for Monster Hunter. That's why I think that carefully fostering the feeling of monsters as characters is key to Monster Hunter." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I ask about one more thing that's been on my mind: Rathalos, a monster that could be called a series mainstay. Rathalos' appearance in Wilds has already been revealed in a trailer, but how will it appear to us this time around? I ask, but Fujioka steadfastly keeps everything from the way it makes an appearance to its environment a secret. But what he does give me is a small glimpse at his feelings towards it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Rath is the poster monster for the series, so we're still keeping that a secret for now,” he says. “I feel like Rath is the kind of monster that makes both the creators and the players think, 'Yep, this is Monster Hunter' when it appears. That's why we always give a lot of thought about how it'll show up impactfully whenever we develop a new title.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"During World, there were a lot of people around the globe who still didn't know about Monster Hunter, and so we depicted Rath as the apex monster of the Ancient Forest's ecosphere, the game's first stage. But now that there are so many people who know about it through World, we've thought about how to place it in a position that they'd find interesting." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Depicting monsters means depicting the world of Monster Hunter. Contemplating the role of a monster means creating the experience hunters will have. Monsters are present at every point of the gameplay loop, and their creators truly care about them. It won't be long until we get to meet new ones and be reunited with old favorites in Wilds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of old favorites, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-the-monster-hunter-wilds-team-select-their-beastly-lineup-ign-first">Gravios has been revealed as a returning monster in Monster Hunter Wilds.</a> Check out our exclusive Gravios reveal, which includes details straight from the devs and brand-new gameplay. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds comes to PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S on February 28. For more on Monster Hunter Wilds, check out our exclusive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-exclusive-oilwell-basin-ajarakan-and-rompopolo-gameplay-ign-first">4K gameplay videos</a> battling Ajarakan and Rompopolo in the new Oilwell Basin area, our interview with the development team on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/evolving-monster-hunter-how-capcoms-belief-in-the-series-made-it-a-worldwide-hit-ign-first">how Monster Hunter has evolved</a> over the years, and details on the game’s delicious food system. And keep an eye out for more exclusives throughout January as part of IGN First!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Shuka Yamada is a freelance writer for IGN Japan. This article was translated by Ko Ransom.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>