<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:07:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Assassin's Creed Game Tier List]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/every-assassins-creed-game-tier-list</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-assassins-creed-game-tier-list.1141212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/every-assassins-creed-game-tier-list<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Which AC game do you think is the greatest? Rank them here.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest in Ubisoft’s long line of stealth-action open worlds, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-review">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a>, is finally here. But where does it rank in the series? We’re asking you to make that decision. There have been over 30 games released under the Assassin’s Creed banner, but we’re just including the “mainline games” here, so no mobile, side-scrolling, VR entries, or spin-offs like Bloodlines or Liberation here, I’m afraid.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">AC started all the way back in 2007 when Desmond Miles stepped into the Animus to fill the shoes of his ancestor Altaïr, and now finds itself in 16th-century Japan 18 years later as players take control of Naoe and Yasuke. This latest adventure is the 14th in the core series, and I’ve had a go at ranking them via one of our IGN Tier Lists, based purely on my personal enjoyment of each game. Take a look at my tier list here:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/19/screenshot-2025-03-19-at-12-11-28-1742386309547.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Simon Cardy's Assassin's Creed Tier List</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Assassin’s Creed 4: Black Flag is still the entry I hold closest to my heart. The mix of island exploration, ship combat, and colourful cast provides the best all-around AC experience in my mind. It’s joined by Assassin’s Creed 2 in the S-tier, the game that really catapulted the series into the limelight. I also have Valhalla in the A-tier, which may surprise some, but I really loved the Viking-influenced combat, and am a sucker for the Orlog minigame. Alongside it is Unity, a game whose recreation of French Revolution-era Paris still looks stunning a decade later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Don’t agree with me? Think that Valhalla is far too bloated for its own good? Think that Assassin’s Creed 2 is actually overrated? Well, why not have a go at ranking all of the mainline AC games yourself in a tier list below where you can compare your own S, A, B, C, and D tiers with the whole of the IGN community. </p><div id="every-assassins-creed-game-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Every Assassin's Creed Game Tier List</h3><h3>Every Assassin's Creed Game Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Enjoying Assassin’s Creed Shadows? Where in the world would you like the series to go next?  Let us know in the comments, as well as why you’ve ranked the consoles in the order you’ve chosen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editorial Producer who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>