<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 19:22:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Director Confirms Balance Adjustments, More Challenging Monsters, UI/UX Improvements, and Plenty More Are on the Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-director-confirms-balance-adjustments-more-challenging-monsters-uiux-improvements-and-plenty-more-are-on-the-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-director-confirms-balance-adjustments-more-challenging-monsters-ui-ux-improvements-and-plenty-more-are-on-the-way.1150119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-director-confirms-balance-adjustments-more-challenging-monsters-uiux-improvements-and-plenty-more-are-on-the-way<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is laying out its future roadmap. Alongside its planned Title Updates, director Yuya Tokuda has confirmed a few additional goals the team has, as post-launch support for the latest entry in the Monter Hunter franchise carries on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/topics/director-letter/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">letter from the director</a>, Tokuda started by laying out the roadmap <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-march-2025-everything-announced-for-title-update-1">seen in the recent Monster Hunter Wilds Showcase for Title Update 1</a> and beyond. The first big Title Update drops on April 4, this Friday. Then, the seasonal event Festival of Accord: Blossomdance runs from April 23 through May 7. Additionally, April 30 through May 21 will see the Arch-tempered Rey Dau storm into Monster Hunter Wilds.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the end of May, Update Ver. 1.011 will bring an unannounced Capcom collaboration and some "other additional features." Title Update 2 is then planned for this summer, with a new additional monster and seosonal event. Tokuda confirms more free updates are arriving beyond that.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">A greater challenge awaits</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Part of the Mosnter Hunter Wilds' director's letter dug into the question of challenging monster content. Already, fights like Tempered Arkveld, the aforementioned Arch-tempered Rey Dau, and a refight with Zoh Shia are confirmed. Tokuda also confirmed Mizutsune, arriving with Title Update 1, will have an 8-star Tempered Mizutsune fight, available at HR 41 or higher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The end-of-May update will add even more 8-star Tempered monsters to the Wilds. Tempered versions of Gore Magala, Rey Dau, Uth Duna, Nu Udra, and Jin Dahaad will make their way to the game in this update.</p><div id="monster-hunter-wilds-weapons-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Monster Hunter Wilds Weapons Tier List</h3><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds Weapons Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">"Each of these monsters have had various behind-the-scenes adjustments to make them more resilient, such as increased health, resistance to wounding, and tweaks to multiplayer scaling," Tokuda said. "Challenging monsters will also appear in future updates, so keep an eye out for further information about them."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Balancing it all out</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Specifically addressing feedback from launch, Tokuda said that Capcom is planning to make "various adjustments," including weapon balance changes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"These will be implemented gradually with each upcoming title update in order to make the game more enjoyable for everyone for a longer period of time," Tokuda said. "Depending on the content, these changes may take some time to prepare."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The director noted the Hammer as one weapon being considered for "upward adjustments," which sounds like good news for Hammer mains. Some "unintentionally overpowered" things will be adjusted down — the Corrupted Mantle is one example — but Capcom said it plans on adjusting other parts upward, making for a "generally balanced" update. The team is currently aiming to implement the overall weapon balance adjustments in either the end-of-May update or in Title Update 2 this summer.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Performance adjustments</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Additionally, Capcom is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-director-commits-to-addressing-stability-issues-with-pc-improvements-coming-in-title-update-1">targeting stability and performance for Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, specifically noting the PC version. Title Update 1 is planned to bring a reduction in VRAM usage and an upgrade to the DirectStorage version of the Steam version, which should result in an "overall improvement" of stability for PC players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">More improvements are planned, to bolster the overall technical experience for players on all platforms. Additionally, the in-game economy, balance, and other areas are planned for improvement too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Quality-of-life is also a major target for the Monster Hunter Wilds team moving forward. The Grand Hub, arriving in Title Update 1, is part of this, condensing various functions into one end-game area. The team has also reduced waiting times for facility functions at each location.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The team is continuing to work on UI/UX improvements and other quality-of-life updates too. A few items on the docket include restocking items, checking skill information, engaging in multiplayer quests, using the Seikret, and camera behavior during hunts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The rollout stars with Title Update 1 this Friday, April 4, and on into the summer as we approach Title Update 2. Though it's still fresh, Monster Hunter Wilds is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-breezes-past-10-million-sold-capcom-explains-why-its-done-so-incredibly-well">already one of the year's most popular games</a>, and it doesn't look like Capcom is planning to slow down its roadmap for it anytime soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RuneScape: Dragonwilds Announced as Jagex's New Take on the Open World Survival Genre]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/runescape-dragonwilds-announced-as-jagexs-new-take-on-the-open-world-survival-genre</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/runescape-dragonwilds-announced-as-jagexs-new-take-on-the-open-world-survival-genre.1150116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/runescape-dragonwilds-announced-as-jagexs-new-take-on-the-open-world-survival-genre<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, Jagex has announced that it's bringing the world of RuneScape into a new genre: survival. The developer revealed RuneScape: Dragonwilds, a cooperative open world survival game coming to early access this spring.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragonwilds takes place in Ashenfall, a new continent within the RuneScape universe, where one to four players can work together to learn new skills, build camps, grow stronger, and survive against powerful enemies, including lots and lots of dragons. Ashenfall has two regions, with five unique biomes, and the potential for more to be added later post-launch. Though Ashenfall is not the same continent most of RuneScape proper takes place on, RuneScape fans will find a lot of familiarity in the world, including some locations that may resemble familiar places from RuneScape itself, like a wizard's tower, or a certain castle...</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">RuneScape: Dragonwilds First Look Screenshots and Art</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Monsters may also look familiar, but come with a twist. While you'll still see rats, dragons, trolls, cows, and other creatures you'll recall from RuneScape, Ashenfall's wild magic has warped these creatures into strange, nature-fied versions of themselves with new appearances and fusions with plants, thorns, and other wild bits.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Core to survival in Dragonwilds is development of skills, and yes, they include classic RuneScape activities like cooking and woodcutting. These skills allow you to interact with the world in various ways - when I saw a few clips of the game at the Game Developers' Conference earlier this month, I was shown clips of a player using wind runes to gain the ability to glide through the air across distances. Even more nostalgic was a woodcutting skill that allows players to line up a row of trees and throw a spectral axe to chop them all down at once. It's a move I was told was referred to as "ax-tral projection." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">RuneScape: Dragonwilds is entering early access on PC sometime this spring, with hopes for a wider launch (including console) sometime in 2026. Jagex will host a deep-dive reveal of the game on Twitch on April 15 at 9:00 AM PT.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Mario RPG is Just $20 at GameStop Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-spring-sale-deal-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-mario-rpg-is-just-20-at-gamestop-today.1150113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-spring-sale-deal-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The springtime deals just keep on coming.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Spring has sprung, and with it, plenty of video game deals to check out at a variety of different retailers. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a> has been offering some great game deals, as has Woot with its own Spring Video Game Sale, and now GameStop is joining in on the seasonal sale action with a fantastic discount on Super Mario RPG.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The retailer has dropped the price of Super Mario RPG to just $20 (<a href="https://zdcs.link/z6oMk7?object_uuid=386abd37-8f6e-49fe-aa23-34eb2d2f2316&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see here at GameStop</a>). That's over 60% off its original price of $59.99, which is an excellent deal to take advantage of while it's still live. If you've had this one on your radar, there's no better time to scoop it up for your physical game library.</p><div catalogid="cb0fdcc7-dba7-4294-bd34-ec6cbcf6d7cd" id="217929"><div id="217929" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario RPG - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">We had a lot of love for Super Mario RPG in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-rpg-review">review</a>, in case you're in need of some convincing before adding it into your shopping cart. IGN's Tom Marks said, "Super Mario RPG already held up pretty well if you didn’t mind a bit of dust on its different systems, but now there’s no excuse not to see why Mario’s most unexpected adventure is still so beloved."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned earlier, there are plenty of video game deals floating around right now that are worth a look before some of the Spring Sales come to an end. Some of our favorites from both Amazon and Woot can be seen in our breakdown of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/woot-best-video-game-deals-amazons-spring-sale-2025">spring sale video game deals</a>, including discounts on Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Metaphor: ReFantazio, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today is actually the last day to take advantage of the deals in Amazon's Big Spring Sale. If you're curious what else is still available in the sale event, it's worth having a look at our overall breakdown of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a> to see some of our favorite offers from the event, with deals on everything from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-deals-amazon-spring-sale-2025">LEGO sets</a> to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/a-selection-of-4ks-and-blu-rays-are-discounted-right-now-in-amazons-big-spring-sale">tons of physical media</a>. If anything catches your eye, you'll want to act fast to scoop it up at its discounted price before the sale event is all over.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More From Today's Game Deals</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 31, 2025 3:42 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>