<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 12:35:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Fans Think The Game's Age Rating Suggests Premium Content Will Carry Forward From Black Ops 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-fans-think-the-games-age-rating-suggests-premium-content-will-carry-forward-from-black-ops-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-fans-think-the-games-age-rating-suggests-premium-content-will-carry-forward-from-black-ops-6.1250736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty fans believe they've discovered proof that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7"><u>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</u></a> will let players carry over their Black Ops 6 skins.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With the <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40736/call-of-dutyr-black-ops-7/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>ESRB rating</u></a> now confirming Black Ops 7 will be rated M 17+ and available on PC, PS5, Xbox Series, and last-gen consoles PS4 and Xbox One, a throwaway line in the rating summary reveals there'll be weapons that feature "marijuana/joints/paraphernalia: players' characters inhaling marijuana from a bong-like structure attached to a rifle; players' characters smoking joints or inhaling through bongs as part of execution sequences." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many players are interpreting this as reference to the Dank Days Tracer Pack from Black Ops 6, a bundle that includes a number of skins, finishing moves, and perks like weapon charms and sprays associated with weed. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If fans are on the money, this would indirectly confirm that the premium content available in Black Ops 6 — yes, even the silly stuff — will carry over to Black Ops 7. And while <a href="https://x.com/CptButcher/status/1947321508290077019" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>some players</u></a> are <a href="https://x.com/CarlosBitMe/status/1947381136763850993" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>delighted</u></a> that they get to keep their skins for the new Call of Duty instalment, not everyone's happy about it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So all the stupid s**t is being carried over," <a href="https://x.com/CharlesJhallory/status/1947310726357319753" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said</u></a> one player, while another simply <a href="https://x.com/xPhaNToM_LioNx/status/1947414950764548318" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>wrote</u></a>: "Carry forward confirmed, huge L."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Developed by Treyarch and Raven Software, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 — which was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-2025-everything-announced-so-far"><u>announced at the Xbox Games Showcase 2025</u></a> last month — is the first ever consecutive release within the Black Ops sub-series. Matt Cox, General Manager of Call of Duty, insisted that “as a team, our vision from the start was to create a back-to-back series experience for our players that embraced the uniqueness of the Black Ops sub-franchise.” It's set to star Milo Ventimiglia, Kiernan Shipka, and Michael Rooker, with Ventimiglia portraying David Mason, Shipka as new character Emma Kagen, and Rooker reprising his Black Ops 2 role of Mike Harper.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We know it'll feature the Skirmish and Overload multiplayer modes as well a 20v20 wingsuit option as details of a developer-only <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7"><u>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</u></a> playtest were <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-developer-accidentally-posts-private-playtest-details-to-public-cod-app"><u>accidentally released to all fans on the Call of Duty app</u></a>. Whoops.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-insists-heavily-criticized-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-ads-in-loadout-menus-were-a-test-published-in-error-strips-them-out-following-backlash"><u>Activision pulled controversial adverts placed inside Black Ops 6 and Warzone loadouts</u></a>, insisting they were a “feature test” published “in error.” It’s worth remembering that Black Ops 6 is a premium, $70 game, and this year’s Black Ops 7 is expected to jump to $80 after Microsoft said that gamers will see Xbox charging $79.99 for new, first-party games around the holiday season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-fans-think-the-games-age-rating-suggests-premium-content-will-carry-forward-from-black-ops-6]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>