<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 11:46:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's the 10 Most Valuable Prismatic Evolution Pokémon Cards That I'm Still Chasing in Sealed Boosters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolution-most-expensive-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-the-10-most-valuable-prismatic-evolution-pok%C3%A9mon-cards-that-im-still-chasing-in-sealed-boosters.1266069/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Prismatic Evolutions is still one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-most-expensive-cards-2025">most valuable Pokémon TCG</a> sets out of the <strong>whole Scarlet and Violet era</strong>. Its main chase card (<a href="https://zdcs.link/985GD8?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Umbreon ex-161/131</a>) is commanding over $800, with lower-end SIR cards still pulling well over $100.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The difference between now and a couple of months ago is getting these insanely valuable cards for the right price instead of paying over the odds. Here's a quick look at the <strong>top 10 most valuable cards</strong> to add to your collection, or deck if you've got Pokécoins coming out of your ears.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've gone into a bit more detail on every card, a touch more into the article, but the gist is that it's a <strong>good time</strong> to start collecting Prismatic Evolutions chase cards. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Believe it or not, prices have <em>actually</em> been correcting over the past two months, with some cards holding double their current value just a couple of months ago. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is very positive, meaning players and collectors can get their chase cards for the right price and watch them climb in value as time goes on. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Prismatic Evolution: Honorable Mentions</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Wait! Before we start:</strong> My favorite thing about Prismatic Evolutions is the sheer number of SIRs featuring non-Eeveelution Pokémon. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">They deserve some recognition too, so I’ve put together this <em>extra </em>list to balance out the usual Eevee dominance. Here are my top ten honorable mentions for Prismatic Evolution, with artwork that’s arguably among the best we have ever seen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">From the fantastical pastel color busts from <a href="https://zdcs.link/aebGZ6?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Terapagos ex SIR</a> and the abract highlight work on <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJgA6m?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Iron Hands ex SIR</a> to The stained glass style of <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gbwYy?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dragapult ex SIR</a> and the charging yet chaotic pose of <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBg7nv?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ceruledge ex SIR</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">They're considerably more affordable too, peaking at just under $94. That's where the value in Pokémon TCG is for me, the overlooked cards that are fantastic showpieces. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking to collect Prismatic Evolutions for cards that will increase in value over time without breaking your credit rating? This is where savvy collectors need to be looking in my opinion.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Eevee ex - 167/131 - $112.98</h2><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226491"><div id="226491" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Eevee ex - 167/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a03Ell?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Eevee ex SIR</a> from Prismatic Evolutions is a flexible card with a unique ability that allows it to evolve into any Pokémon ex that evolves from Eevee. Rainbow DNA opens up a wide range of build options and can slot into multiple strategies that rely on type variety or quick evolution plays. It can't evolve on your first turn or the turn it's played which helps keep the ability balanced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its attack, Coruscating Quartz, deals 200 damage for three Energy in Fire, Water, and Lightning. That Energy mix makes it a tough addition to a trainer’s deck, especially in formats where consistency and type synergy are key. Most players will lean on it for evolution plays rather than raw damage output.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eevee ex SIR remains a popular pull for collectors looking to complete their Eeveelution lineup. Its price has softened since release, but at $113, it is still one of the more valuable base Eevee cards we have seen in years and a vital piece for collectors aiming to build the full Prismatic Evolutions set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Roaring Moon ex - 162/131 - $143.67</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226490"><div id="226490" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Roaring Moon ex - 162/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a5w3gV?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Roaring Moon ex SIR</a> from Prismatic Evolutions is a high-risk attacker built for aggressive plays. Its first attack, Frenzied Gouging, knocks out your opponent’s Active Pokémon instantly but deals 200 damage to itself in return. It can swing the game fast but leaves you wide open if you don’t have a backup plan. Calamity Storm is a more flexible option, hitting for 100 or 220 if you discard a Stadium in play, which makes it a strong follow-up or setup attack in the right deck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The triple Darkness Energy cost means it’s better suited to decks that can ramp quickly or recycle Energy efficiently. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck, but one that rewards calculated aggression and tempo-heavy play. Roaring Moon isn’t for slow setups or cautious turns. It thrives when the goal is to close games quickly and apply pressure early.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a5w3gV?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Roaring Moon ex SIR</a> Is also one of the few Paradox Pokémon in this set that commands significant value, and at over $140, it remains one of the most powerful and visually striking cards outside the Eeveelution lineup. The SIR artwork leans into the Paradox Pokémon’s primal energy with a dark, dramatic design that gives it real shelf presence.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Flareon ex - 146/131 - $153.99</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226489"><div id="226489" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Flareon ex - 146/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/92x8Je?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Flareon ex SIR</a> from Prismatic Evolutions brings powerful fire-type pressure with two solid attacks. Burning Charge hits for 130 and accelerates energy by letting you search your deck for two Basic Energy and attach them to one of your Pokémon. It’s a strong early or mid-game setup option, especially in decks that need to build up attackers quickly. Carnelian deals a huge 280 damage, more than enough to take down most threats, though it comes with the drawback of preventing Flareon from attacking the next turn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That limitation makes careful sequencing important. You’ll want to pair it with switching effects or find ways to reset the attack clause. The energy cost across both attacks is manageable for Fire decks that already use acceleration tools, and Flareon’s 270 HP helps it stay on the board long enough to make an impact. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck and shines brightest when built around a fast, punchy game plan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/92x8Je?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Flareon ex SIR</a> is now at a reasonable $153.99, and I think it's worth every penny for its design alone. The SIR artwork is warm and energetic, showing Flareon in mid-leap with embers flying around it. It’s one of the more visually dynamic Eeveelution cards in the set, and while the price has dipped, but it's a hot pick for collectors and aggressive Fire-type builds.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Glaceon ex - 150/131 - $179.99</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226488"><div id="226488" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Glaceon ex - 150/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAy2m?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Glaceon ex SIR</a> from Prismatic Evolutions is a flexible attacker that can set up pressure early and close out games with precision. Frost Bullet deals 110 damage and chips 30 to a Benched Pokémon, which is useful for spreading damage or finishing off low-HP targets. Euclase is where the real power lies—it lets you instantly Knock Out a Pokémon that has exactly 6 damage counters on it. Timing this move well can swing the game by removing key threats without needing to hit massive numbers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 270 HP and one retreat cost make Glaceon reasonably durable and mobile on the field. It slots well into decks that aim to spread damage and play a patient control game. The Euclase setup does require planning, but it rewards clever players who can sequence damage properly. It's a tough addition to a trainer’s deck and particularly rewarding for those who enjoy outplaying their opponents with calculated board control.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAy2m?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Glaceon ex SIR</a> is up for grabs at $179.99 at the moment, making it one of the most valuable cards in this set whilst being much more reasonable than a couple of months back. The artwork captures Glaceon jumping infront of an snowflake-themed stained glass window, glowing with cool tones that perfectly reflect its icy theme. It’s a visually striking SIR and while the price has taken a hit, the card remains a strong pickup for control-focused decks and collectors alike.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Jolteon ex - 153/131 - $179.99</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226487"><div id="226487" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Jolteon ex - 153/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a5w3ed?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Jolteon ex SIR</a> from Prismatic Evolutions offers a lot of burst damage potential in an aggressive Lightning deck. Flashing Spear starts at 60 damage but can scale up fast by discarding up to two Basic Energy from your Benched Pokémon, adding 90 more damage for each. With a proper setup, that’s an easy 240 damage for just two Energy on a Stage 1, which can take out most threats in one shot. Dravite is a powerful finisher at 280 damage, though the downside is Jolteon can't attack next turn after using it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 260 HP and free retreat, Jolteon is easy to pivot in and out of the Active Spot, making it great in fast-paced, tempo-focused lists. Managing your Energy between the Bench and Jolteon becomes key to maximizing damage output. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck and best suited for players who like high-risk, high-reward plays that can swing a match quickly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/a5w3ed?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Jolteon ex SIR</a> has dropped in value by nearly half since may, but $179.99 value for an SIR card is still a very valuable card. With this price stablizing, the only way for Jolteon ex SIR value is up a year from now. The artwork is packed with energy, showing Jolteon mid-sprint with lightning crackling around it. The bright yellow tones and motion lines give it a real sense of speed and power, making it one of the most kinetic-looking cards in the set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Vaporeon ex - 149/131 - $200.98</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226486"><div id="226486" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Vaporeon ex - 149/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAy2m?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Vaporeon ex SIR</a> is one of the more disruptive cards in Prismatic Evolutions thanks to its board-wide pressure. Severe Squall hits every Pokémon ex your opponent controls for 60 damage, ignoring Weakness and Resistance. It’s a great way to chip at multiple threats at once, especially in formats where players rely on multiple evolved ex attackers. Its second move, Aquamarine, deals 280 damage, enough to take out nearly anything in front of it, though it comes with the usual drawback of preventing Vaporeon from attacking next turn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 280 HP and a Water typing, Vaporeon holds its own against a wide pool of current meta threats, especially when paired with support that can move it in and out of the Active Spot. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck and rewards players who enjoy spread damage and multi-turn strategies that slowly wear down the board.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAy2m?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Vaporeon ex SIR</a> Is rocking up at $200.98, and that's now a stable value on a very expensive card, which no doubt will climb as time goes on. The art here is peaceful but detailed, showing Vaporeon calmly hopping atop of a body of water lit with soft blue tones. It’s less action-packed than some of the other Eeveelutions, but the underwater atmosphere makes it visually striking and a beautiful card for collectors.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Leafeon ex - 144/131 - $209.99</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226484"><div id="226484" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Leafeon ex - 144/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QbbyOG?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Leafeon ex SIR</a> delivers high reward for players willing to build around its unique pressure and healing kit. Verdant Storm scales off Energy attached to all of your opponent’s Pokémon, dealing 60 damage per attachment, which makes it a strong counter to energy-heavy decks. Moss Agate hits for 230 and heals 100 damage from each of your Benched Pokémon, creating a swing turn that can punish aggressive decks while helping stabilize your board.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 270 HP and access to reliable healing, Leafeon ex is hard to remove once established. It fits best in decks that expect long games where sustaining your own board matters just as much as chipping away at your opponent. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck and shines brightest when piloted with patience and timing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a great time to catch Leafeon ex SIR at $209.99, its a highly valued card whilst being at the best price we've seen for it. The artwork features Leafeon resting in a lush, sun-drenched forest, blending soft  natural lighting with delicate linework. It’s tranquil and earthy, offering collectors a scenic moment that stands out in a set full of dramatic poses.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Espeon ex - 155/131 - $204.99</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226485"><div id="226485" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Espeon ex - 155/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QGgZ5M?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Espeon ex SIR</a> brings hand disruption and evolution control into one clean package. Psych Out hits for 160 and forces your opponent to discard a random card, which can slow down setup decks or break up combos. Amazez is where the real strategy lies. It devolves every evolved Pokémon your opponent has, shuffling their highest Stage back into their deck. Against evolution-heavy boards, this can completely reset your opponent’s progress and swing the game in your favor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 270 HP and a single retreat cost, Espeon ex is easy to slot into Psychic decks that want control elements. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck that rewards careful timing and matchup knowledge, especially against Stage 2-heavy builds or archetypes that rely on multi-turn setups.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QGgZ5M?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Espeon ex SIR</a> is holding its value at just above $200 and is still one of the most premium non-Umbreon options in the set. The art captures a serene moment as Espeon perches in a moonlit field, its gaze piercing through lavender-toned shadows. The subtle lighting and dreamlike backdrop make this one of the more visually contemplative designs in the Prismatic Evolutions set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Sylveon ex - 156/131 - $315</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226483"><div id="226483" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sylveon ex - 156/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/91jYo8?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Sylveon ex SIR</a> plays a strong support-control role with disruptive attacks that can shut down your opponent’s strategy fast. Magical Charm hits for 160 and reduces incoming damage from the Defending Pokémon by 100 on your opponent’s next turn. It’s a simple but effective stall tactic that can keep your key Pokémon alive longer. Angelite is the big closer, letting you choose two of your opponent’s Benched Pokémon and shuffle them and all attached cards into their deck. It’s a powerful reset that can dismantle a board in one move, though you can’t use it on back-to-back turns.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 270 HP and Psychic typing, Sylveon ex is a strong defensive piece in control-heavy decks or formats where board building is essential. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck that works best when played with patience and a plan to disrupt your opponent’s bench-focused strategy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/91jYo8?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Sylveon ex SIR</a> is going for $315 right now, which is a reasonable price whilst being the second most valuable Prismatic Evolutions card. The card's art shows Sylveon in a soft, storybook-style meadow filled with blossoms, with warm pink tones and flowing ribbons that capture its fairy-like charm. It’s one of the most elegant designs in the set and continues to attract collectors even at a lower price point.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Umbreon ex - 161/131 - $869</h2></div><div catalogid="57ec10e6-fcfb-4bea-b31a-5a84f0ff2426" id="226482"><div id="226482" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Umbreon ex - 161/131</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/985GD8?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Umbreon ex SIR</a> brings high-impact utility and pressure to Darkness decks with two strong attacks. Moon Mirage deals 160 damage and Confuses the opponent's Active Pokémon, forcing a coin flip before their next attack. That disruption can buy valuable time or force a retreat. Onyx is the showstopper. It discards all Energy from Umbreon ex and lets you take a Prize card outright, no matter the opponent’s board state. It’s a massive swing when used correctly and fits well into decks that want to finish games with surprise plays.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At 280 HP and with straightforward costs for its attacks, <a href="https://zdcs.link/985GD8?object_uuid=b3c790d9-82b4-4c0e-8c20-46feacaf3931&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Umbreon ex SIR</a> is a flexible threat that earns a spot in slower control strategies or as a closer in prize race decks. It’s a tough addition to a trainer’s deck because of the high discard cost, but when timed right, it can steal games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the crown jewel of the Prismatic Evolutions set. Even after falling from its $1300 high, Umbreon ex SIR still holds an incredible value at $869. Let's not forget that the market for this card is now stable, which means it's only going to climb in value as the months go on and Scarlet and Violet becomes the previous generation to Mega Evolution. The SIR artwork is dark, moody and abstract, showing Umbreon sitting on some kind of plynth with darkness energy bursting out and surrounding a moon. It's dramatic and the crazy kind of artwork that makes collectors look closer. Umbreon ex SIR continues to be the most premium chase cards in the set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Prismatic Evolutions Price Watch - Sealed Boosters</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Want to pull these cards yourself? Sealed Prismatic Evolutions product pricing is dropping significantly on TCGplayer. You won't find anything for MSRP, but nine times out of 10 it's a cheaper option than big box retailers such as Amazon. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With that being said, I'd still recommend saving up for single cards whilst they're at their lowest, as Prismatic Evolutions is a very hard set to pull hits from.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 8, 2025 10:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolution-most-expensive-cards]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rod Fergusson Departs Blizzard, Diablo Franchise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rod-fergusson-departs-blizzard-diablo-franchise</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rod-fergusson-departs-blizzard-diablo-franchise.1266012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">No word on why he left, or who will replace him.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Diablo general manager and Gears of War veteran Rod Fergusson has left Blizzard.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fergusson confirmed the news on his personal Twitter/X account:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">After five years of driving the Diablo franchise forward with four big launches, it's time for me to step away from Blizzard/Microsoft, sword in hand, and see what's next. The teams are set up for success, with an exciting slate of releases ahead. I'm incredibly proud of what… <a href="https://t.co/Fsh4gjmgVl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/Fsh4gjmgVl</a></p>— Rod Fergusson (@RodFergusson) <a href="https://twitter.com/RodFergusson/status/1953881496013689332?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">"After five years of driving the Diablo franchise forward with four big launches, it's time for me to step away from Blizzard/Microsoft, sword in hand, and see what's next," Fergusson wrote. "The teams are set up for success, with an exciting slate of releases ahead. I'm incredibly proud of what we've built together and looking forward to what comes next for Diablo, and for me."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Blizzard confirmed this news to IGN today as well, but declined to offer further comment as to why Fergusson has left the company, or who will run the Diablo franchise going forward.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Blizzard president Johanna Faries responded on Twitter/X, with the following:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Guiding a franchise like Diablo takes rare talent, vision, and collaboration. Thank you, Rod, for bringing all of those in spades. Sanctuary’s future is brighter because of the impact you’ve had! 🙏🏽✨ <a href="https://t.co/r479RGDkm3" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/r479RGDkm3</a></p>— Johanna Faries (@Joh_Burg) <a href="https://twitter.com/Joh_Burg/status/1953884570316943653?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Xbox head Phil Spencer also <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/xboxp3.bsky.social/post/3lvvuhk4ags26" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">responded on BlueSky</a>: "You brought strength, hellfire, and vision to one of gaming’s most iconic franchises. Playing Diablo IV with you was a blast—thanks for everything you gave to the game and the community."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rod Fergusson <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-of-war-boss-will-join-blizzard-to-oversee-diablo-franchise">joined Blizzard in 2020</a> after leaving Microsoft's The Coalition. Fergusson previously worked on every Gears of War game across his time at both Microsoft and Epic Games. At Blizzard, Fergusson headed up the Diablo franchise, joining shortly after Diablo 4 was first announced. Fergusson has done <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/whens-the-right-time-for-diablo-5-blizzards-rod-fergusson-wants-diablo-4-to-be-around-for-years-i-dont-know-if-its-eternal">numerous candid interviews</a> about his vision for the direction and future of the Diablo franchise. In April, Blizzard <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-blizzard-tells-ign-whats-coming-to-diablo-4-in-2025-and-2026-including-new-expansion-new-ranking-system-and-finally-leaderboards">unveiled a roadmap for Diablo 4 for 2025</a> that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4s-2025-roadmap-hasnt-gone-down-well-with-hardcore-fans-and-even-the-former-president-of-blizzard-isnt-sure-where-the-game-is-going">did not go down well with fans</a>. Most recently, Diablo 4 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/diablo-4-official-sins-of-the-horadrim-update-overview-video">received the Sins of the Horadrim update</a> with new Nightmare Dungeon updates and customizable spells.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/rod-fergusson-departs-blizzard-diablo-franchise]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>