<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:39:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout, Elder Scrolls, and Doom Workers Go on Strike in Protest at Parent Company Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft.1034778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hundreds of unionized ZeniMax workers go on strike today over an alleged lack of bargaining by parent company Microsoft.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Staff who are members of ZeniMax Workers United-CWA are on a one-day strike to call out Microsoft for an alleged lack of progress at the bargaining table over remote work and for allegedly unilaterally outsourcing quality assurance work without bargaining with the union.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In January 2023, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsofts-zenimax-media-sees-300-qa-workers-unionize">ZeniMax Workers United-CWA formed the first video game studio union at Microsoft</a>, representing over 300 quality assurance workers in Maryland and Texas. Today's strike takes place at four ZeniMax locations across Maryland and Texas, with workers set to return to their desks tomorrow, November 14. Microsoft did not immediately respond to a request for comment from IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">ZeniMax is the umbrella organization that includes The Elder Scrolls and Fallout maker Bethesda and Doom developer id Software, among other studios. It also owns <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> developer MachineGames and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blade-arkane">Marvel's Blade</a> developer Arkane Lyon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, Communications Workers of America Union (CWA) filed an unfair labor practice charge against ZeniMax for contracting out work without notification. ZeniMax Workers United-CWA members have raised concerns that ZeniMax’s recent unilateral decision to outsource quality assurance work threatens job security amid record layoffs across the video game industry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The strike comes hot on the heels of Microsoft gaming boss Phil Spencer's insistence that “the Xbox business has never been more healthy.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Video Game Franchise Xbox Owns After Acquiring Activision Blizzard</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After splashing out $69 billion on Call of Duty maker Activision Blizzard last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-lays-off-another-650-staff-from-its-video-game-workforce-xbox-boss-phil-spencer-sends-memo-to-staff">Microsoft has cut more than 2,500 jobs from its gaming business</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-closes-redfall-developer-arkane-austin-hifi-rush-developer-tango-gameworks-and-more-in-devastating-cuts-at-bethesda">closed three ZeniMax studios</a>. Sales of Xbox Series X and S continue to plummet, and Game Pass subscriber numbers are flat, although <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-biggest-call-of-duty-launch-ever-sets-new-single-day-game-pass-sub-record">Microsoft said it enjoyed a record bump from the recent day one launch of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a>, Spencer said 2025 is looking brighter for Microsoft’s gaming effort. “The Xbox business has never been more healthy,” he said, citing growth in cloud and PC gaming as well as console usage. “The business is performing right now, and I think that means a more healthy future for hardware and the games we build.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer is even optimistic about the growth of mobile games, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-layoffs-hit-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-which-didnt-hit-as-big-as-hoped">despite cutting staff from the teams behind the underperforming Call of Duty Warzone Mobile and Warcraft Rumble</a>. “I feel pretty good about where this industry is going,’’ he said. “To reach new players, we need to be creative and adaptive of new business models, new devices, new ways of access. We’re not going to grow the market with $1,000 consoles.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer is of course under pressure to deliver following the Activision Blizzard acquisition, and is in the middle of a big multiplatform push <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-gaming-boss-phil-spencer-wont-rule-out-any-xbox-exclusive-making-the-jump-to-playstation-including-halo">that may end up seeing Halo launch on PlayStation</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We run a business,” <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-boss-phil-spencer-explains-decision-to-launch-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-on-ps5">Spencer said in August</a>. “It’s definitely true inside of Microsoft the bar is high for us in terms of the delivery we have to give back to the company. Because we get a level of support from the company that’s just amazing and what we’re able to go do.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So I look at this, how can we make our games as strong as possible? Our platform continues to grow, on console, on PC, and on cloud. It’s just going to be a strategy that works for us.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Despite Buying Activision Blizzard for $69 Billion Just Last Year, Microsoft Is Still Looking at Even More Video Game Acquisitions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/despite-buying-activision-blizzard-for-69-billion-just-last-year-microsoft-is-still-looking-at-even-more-video-game-acquisitions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/despite-buying-activision-blizzard-for-69-billion-just-last-year-microsoft-is-still-looking-at-even-more-video-game-acquisitions.1034775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/despite-buying-activision-blizzard-for-69-billion-just-last-year-microsoft-is-still-looking-at-even-more-video-game-acquisitions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hey big Spencer.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft is still in the market for acquisitions despite having splashed out $69 billion for Call of Duty maker Activision Blizzard just last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a>, Microsoft Gaming boss Phil Spencer said he’s up for buying more companies, although cautioned that nothing’s “imminent” and big deals are off the table for now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, if Microsoft does open its wallet once again, what might it spend its billions on? Deals that add “geographic diversity,” including in Asia, might be worthwhile, Spencer said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Apparently Microsoft’s eyeing up buying another mobile company (Microsoft picked up Candy Crush maker King as part of the Activision Blizzard acquisition).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We definitely want to be in the market, and when we can find teams and technology and capability that add to what we’re trying to do in gaming at Microsoft, absolutely we will keep our heads up,” Spencer said.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Video Game Franchise Xbox Owns After Acquiring Activision Blizzard</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft is still busy absorbing Activision Blizzard employees, Spencer added, which is why very large deals are probably impossible right now. But that leaves the door open for major acquisitions in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer and co. will probably find future acquisitions easier to get over the line after Donald Trump becomes U.S. president in January. Microsoft faced a tough battle with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) over the Activision Blizzard deal — a battle it ultimately won. <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/11/07/donald-trump-ma-mergers-acquisition-doj-ftc-lina-khan/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wall Street is said to be foaming at the mouth</a> with all the possible mergers and acquisitions that may now go through with Trump as president.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The focus, it seems, is fleshing out its mobile offering ahead of launching an app store of its own. But Microsoft's App Store and Google Play rival has suffered a number of delays, with staff still trying to figure out a plan. According to Bloomberg, Microsoft still doesn’t have an effective way to get its own store on mobile phones, delaying the launch further.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft's gaming aquisition ambitions continue despite cutting an eye-watering 2,550 staff just this year alone, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-layoffs-hit-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-which-didnt-hit-as-big-as-hoped">Xbox mobile game development teams recently hit hard</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>