<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:25:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Says Donkey Kong Bananza 'Will Come to Symbolise 3D Donkey Kong' — in a Separate 'Branch' to 2D Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-says-donkey-kong-bananza-will-come-to-symbolise-3d-donkey-kong-in-a-separate-branch-to-2d-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-donkey-kong-bananza-will-come-to-symbolise-3d-donkey-kong-%E2%80%94-in-a-separate-branch-to-2d-games.1244196/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Plus more on DK's redesign.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 2 blockbuster <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> will be something of a template for the character's future 3D games, Nintendo has said, splitting DK's appearances in 2D and 3D titles. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Similar to how Mario still appears in both 2D and 3D installments — the most recent of each being Super Mario Bros. Wonder and Super Mario Odyssey, respectively — Nintendo now sees a similar delineation in its plans for its most prominent ape.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Expanding on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-exists-because-yoshiaki-koizumi-asked-the-mario-odyssey-team-for-a-3d-donkey-kong-game">comments previously made to IGN about Bananza's origins</a>, producer Kenta Motokura has said that the game's development began when Nintendo legend Yoshiaki Koizumi asked his 3D Mario team to work its magic making a 3D DK game instead.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"With an eye to expanding the Donkey Kong franchise further, I'd like the team that's been working on 3D Mario games to create a 3D Donkey Kong game," Motokura quoted Koizumi as saying, as part of a new <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/News/2025/July/Ask-the-Developer-Vol-19-Donkey-Kong-Bananza-Chapter-1-2871377.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ask the Developer</a> Q&amp;A. It was this instruction, combined with ongoing experimentation into voxel-based destruction, that led to Donkey Kong Bananza's genesis.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Asked how Bananza sits alongside other Donkey Kong games, Motokura continued by saying that the 3D Mario team considered this project to epitomise a new 3D Donkey Kong "branch", separate to the DK's 2D platformers — leaving the door open to both kinds of games still existing in future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"In a long-running series, novelty and continuity are both important, but we wanted this title to fully convey the appeal of Donkey Kong as a character," Motokura said. "Meanwhile, we thought that by creating something new, leveraging our experience developing 3D Mario games, we'd have the opportunity to create two separate branches – 2D Donkey Kong and 3D Donkey Kong – just as we did with Mario games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So, keeping in mind that this game will come to symbolise 3D Donkey Kong, and with the theme of bringing Donkey Kong's strengths and new actions to the forefront, we thought the concept of 'destruction' would be a good fit."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Donkey Kong Bananza Direct Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Motokura discussed Nintendo's recent Donkey Kong redesign in more detail, and said that it was the development of Bananza which spearheaded the company's search for a new DK look.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Donkey Kong Bananza sparked the creation of a design which I think better conveys the new Donkey Kong," Motokura said, noting that Nintendo's new 'standard' DK was actually another attempt to recapture the character's original design, drawn by Shigeru Miyamoto for the Donkey Kong arcade game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Outside of this game, Donkey Kong has recently appeared in The Super Mario Bros. Movie released in 2023 and in Mario Kart World, but there's a basic character design which provided the foundation for those versions of Donkey Kong," Motokura concluded. "That basic Donkey Kong design has been completely revamped. While overhauling the design, we returned to where it had all started. We took Miyamoto-san's original Donkey Kong as the basis, adding design elements from Donkey Kong Bananza here and there."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What's next for Donkey Kong? Well, it certainly sounds like the door is being left open for the character to reappear in further 2D games in future. And then there's the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-has-filed-a-copyright-notice-for-an-untitled-donkey-kong-motion-picture">intriguing copyright listing for an unannounced Donkey Kong movie</a>, spotted by Nintendo fans earlier this week. It seems like there's plenty in store for DK to come.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-says-donkey-kong-bananza-will-come-to-symbolise-3d-donkey-kong-in-a-separate-branch-to-2d-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>