<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 19:08:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TinyBuild Announces Second Annual Showcase for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tinybuild-announces-second-annual-showcase-for-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tinybuild-announces-second-annual-showcase-for-next-week.1194435/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tinybuild-announces-second-annual-showcase-for-next-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">New game reveals and demos with no fluff in less than 30 minutes.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">TinyBuild Connect is back this year to showcase a bunch of games that are on the way from tinyBuild, the publisher behind titles like Potion Craft, Graveyard Keeper, and Streets of Rogue. And once again, it’ll be a show focused on world premieres and exclusive new trailers with no talking heads or any other fluff. Just games.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>TinyBuild Connect Date, Time, and How to Watch</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The full event will be livestreamed on Tuesday, May 27 starting at 1:00 p.m. Eastern / 12:00 p.m. Central / 10:00 a.m. Pacific. For our friends across the pond, that’s 7:00 p.m. CET. It’ll start promptly at those times and will jump right into the games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/"><u>IGN.com</u></a> (our homepage)</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ign/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>IGN’s Facebook</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ign/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>IGN’s Twitter</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/ign" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>IGN’s Twitch</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ign?lang=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>IGN’s TikTok</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCKy1dAqELo0zrOtPkf0eTMw?themeRefresh=1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>IGN’s YouTube</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re not able to catch the show live, you’ll be able to watch the whole thing on our YouTube page after it finishes. Just like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XMre7n_HPao" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>last year’s show</u></a>.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>What to Expect from tinyBuild Connect 2025</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">This will be a dense show, with lots of reveals and announcements packed into less than 30 minutes. There will be a mix of premieres of previously unannounced games, new info about announced games, and updates for released titles, highlighted by upcoming titles Hello Neighbor 3, Ferocious, and Kingmakers. You can expect a new look at gameplay for both HN3 and Ferocious, while Kingmakers is getting a Steam Early Access release date announcement. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hello Neighbor 3 was announced last year and is the latest entry in the adventure sandbox thriller series. You’ll return to the town of Raven Brooks, this time as a stranger with no ties to the town. Raven Brooks functions as a real-time sandbox simulation, where every player’s decision is the right one. It’s populated by residents who act based on their personalities, relationships, desires, and goals. The game is currently in the playtesting phase, so now seems like the right time for an update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ferocious made a strong impression during last year’s Games Baked in Germany showcase with its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/ferocious-official-mecha-trailer-games-baked-in-germany-showcase"><u>cinematic trailer</u></a>. Developed by Omyog, a small German team with veterans from the film and AAA game industries, the game is a survival-focused, narrative-driven FPS set on a remote island filled with dinosaurs and hostile mercenaries. Among the team is the former Level Design Director of Far Cry 3, Narrative Director of Far Cry 4, and Campaign Creative Director of Star Wars Battlefront II, so it’s safe to say it’s an experienced team.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/tb-connect-2025-final-artwork-1747758278474.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kingmakers was revealed last year too, and it took the IGN audience by storm. We <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingmakers-combines-back-to-the-future-with-army-of-darkness-and-its-blowing-up-right-now-ign-next"><u>featured it on IGN Next</u></a> because its trailer was a surprise hit, getting more than 11 million views across our social channels. Like Ferocious, it resonated thanks to its unique premise. Kingmakers is a mix of third-person shooter and RTS set in medieval Europe. You might be thinking, “How could a shooter be set in medieval times?” Well, you’re a time traveler who’s been sent to the past with modern weapons to alter the course of history. TinyBuild has confirmed that they’ll be announcing the game’s release date in Steam’s Early Access, so you can look forward to that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those are some of the games you can expect to get updates, but there will be plenty more announcements and updates we can’t see coming. Tune in on May 27 to see all of it.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Players Have Had SEAF Buddies For Less Than 24 Hours, And They Already Love Them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-players-have-had-seaf-buddies-for-less-than-24-hours-and-they-already-love-them</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-players-have-had-seaf-buddies-for-less-than-24-hours-and-they-already-love-them.1194327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-players-have-had-seaf-buddies-for-less-than-24-hours-and-they-already-love-them<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">And if anything happens to them...</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A massive new battle has broken out in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a>. Today, developer Arrowhead Studios brought the fight to Super Earth, as the Illuminate are touching down on the Helldivers' home turf. Everyone is joining in the fight, from the player-led Helldivers to some fresh reinforcements in the SEAF.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Short for Super Earth Armed Force, the SEAF soldiers are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth">populating battles taking place on Super Earth</a>, helping the Helldivers hold out against the oncoming Illuminate forces. These troops can be ordered around using several commands, and will assist the Helldivers in defending the home of Managed Democracy. In turn, Helldivers 2 players already love their new NPC helpers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As seen in the new trailer for the Heart of Democracy update, SEAF soldiers are subject to roughly the same dire circumstances and thin survival odds as the Helldivers. Today's trailer has more than a few shots of SEAF soldiers getting absolutely routed by the invasion forces.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But the new SEAF pals are garnering both the sympathy and adoration of Helldivers, provoking the need to defend their newfound backup. Refrains of "PROTECT THE LIL UNS," a Warhammer 40K: Darktide reference, are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1kr4o3b/comment/mtapr7k/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">already picking up steam</a> in the comments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Aah look at them, they are so cute," wrote <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1kr0ftf/seaf_reacts_to_se_salute_this_is_beautiful/mt9mhhk/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one r/Helldivers user</a>, responding to the SEAF soldiers' reactions to the Super Earth salute. "Protect them at all cost helldiver."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Others draw comparisons to the Clone Troopers from Star Wars, especially the NPC allies you'd see in the classic campaigns of games like Star War: Battlefront. "Fired an EAT into a harvesters leg that was attacking a squad and one yelled out 'Glad the helldiver's on our side!'" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1kr4o3b/comment/mtakaer/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one user noted</a>, as it reminded them of the lines you'd hear in Star Wars: Battlefront calling out similar actions. "Now we just need overseers with wrist rockets."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Others have <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1kr2dmk/guyshear_me_out/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">come up with new ways the SEAF could help</a> the Helldivers in the future, as hopes seem high for the SEAF soldiers to leave Super Earth and venture with the Helldivers into other dangerous hotspots via stratagems. Honestly, having an NPC pal around to push those bunker buttons <em>would </em>be useful.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Either way, the Helldivers will absolutely need the help on Super Earth, as the new update seems quite chaotic. It's the culmination of a long series of events, stretching back to a really bad bug hive and a black hole, and it's been really fascinating to see it all come together.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not too long ago, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-ceo-says-youll-sht-your-pants-over-whats-coming-down-the-pipe">Arrowhead CEO Shams Jorjani declared</a> Helldivers 2 players would "shit [their] pants" when they found out what was coming down the pipe. You don't need to give me any unnecessary information, but I do feel like the scope of this update is living up to expectations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Helldivers 2's Heart of Democracy update, and the Illuminate invasion of Super Earth, is currently underway.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blades of Fire Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/blades-of-fire-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blades-of-fire-review.1194321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/blades-of-fire-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I always look forward to it when a studio steps out of its comfort zone to create something unexpected. Blades of Fire, a 3D action-RPG from developer MercurySteam, best known for the stellar <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-dread-review-nintendo-switch">Metroid Dread</a> and its action-packed take on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/09/29/castlevania-lords-of-shadow-review">Castlevania</a> during the PlayStation 3/Xbox 360 era, does just that. Combining its past successes to give you control of a blacksmith who crafts his own weapons of destruction seemed like a promising concept. Unfortunately, the superb crafting portions of this lengthy fantasy adventure are overshadowed by an uneven story and combat that lacks real depth. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You play as Aran, a commoner who gains access to a legendary forging hammer that sets him on a quest to stop the queen who is leading the kingdom into ruin. The three pillars of Blades of Fire are its satisfying but simple combat, enjoyable weapon crafting system, and emotionally unimpactful story. While very uneven, those were at least enough to keep me relatively entertained for the 55 hours it took me to reach the first round of credits. However, there’s only an unsatisfactory conclusion to find there, and it was the postgame scavenger hunt necessary to find the “true” ending that really drained what little enthusiasm I had left by the end.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Blades of Fire Review Slideshow</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Starting with the good, the crafting system stands as the tallest of the three pillars holding up Blades of Fire. Through the hammer Aran receives at the beginning of his journey, he can build the powerful weapons necessary to vanquish all that stand in his path. Initially you can only craft a singular weapon, a heavy polearm called the Hyssop that deals devastating strikes but uses a lot of stamina with each swing. However, after Aran vanquishes enough of a given enemy type, you will unlock a blueprint for the weapon they brandished against him. Dismantling 60 skeletons unlocks the claymore they would clumsily swing, while taking down just five spearmen from the queen’s transformed army grants access to a long spear that deals either piercing damage from afar or slashing damage in circular strikes. Finding and taking down each new enemy to expand your arsenal made for an enjoyable loop, and  encouraged me to take down the stronger optional enemies whenever they appeared.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Interacting with a forger anvil, which function as both rest points and a fast travel system, can then transport you to a mystical forge that lets you create those weapons. When you do, you can adjust several aspects of them: For example, the Twin Mallets are limited to customizing the size and shape of the head and handle, where larger weapons like the Glaive also have options for adding a pommel. These choices modify that weapon in small but noticeable ways, tweaking weight, balance, and damage to your liking, as well as altering Aran’s maximum stamina and how much stamina it costs to dodge while using it. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>While confusing at first, forging became my favorite part.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The final part of forging a weapon is the actual forging itself. Crafting weapons in most games ends after selecting your materials, but Blades of Fire has you actually striking the heated metal to match the weapon's shape. This system, while underexplained and confusing at first thanks to the lack of detailed tutorial, quickly became my favorite part of the journey. A weapon’s steel appears as bars similar to those on an audio visualizer, and some will shrink while others grow as you strike. The better you do, the longer a weapon will last before you need to sunset it to be recycled for parts or traded in to an ally for specific and often rarer materials. It took me half a dozen weapons before I figured out the proper technique for managing the strength, tilt, and width of each of my strikes, but once I did, I found myself confidently crafting weapons with the maximum rating every time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who end up not enjoying the crafting, there is an option to skip the process after the first time, but the maximum number of times you can repair it will be limited to the best results you’ve created manually. This smartly expedited my return trips to the forge, as I’d often hold off replacing weapons until they were all beyond repair, turning what would be a lengthy process into a short trip that got me back in the action sooner. Blades of Fire even gives you the option to name your weapon before setting out, which I initially reserved primarily for punny names like Captain Falchion or Let me Axe You something – but eventually as I saw them reach their final forms with the best materials and enhancements, giving them names suitable of their legacy like Gae Bolg or Masamune. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though there are 35 different weapons to wield and each vary between their speed, range, and other properties, combat unfortunately boils down to just eight attacks. These are performed by pressing the button on your controller that matches the part of an enemy you want to strike: So triangle/Y will strike at an enemy’s head, Circle/B will strike on the right, and so on. There are also charged attacks that deal higher damage and mutilate enemies if fatal, resulting in more gruesome deaths. It is disappointing, though, that mutilating an enemy's head with either a blunt weapon or piercing weapon has the same animation, and seeing them fall off the same way got old after the first dozen times. There are also no combinations of attacks that offer any real benefit, so alternating left and right strikes is virtually the same as mindlessly spamming a single direction. If it wasn’t for the use of parries and perfect dodges that offer a small window of opportunity to retaliate safely, combat would have felt even more bland than it already does. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Choosing the directions of your attacks carefully becomes more necessary later on as enemies start to have different levels of resistance on each body part, and some like elementals can even move these weak points mid-combat. To its credit, Blades of Fire does have a large variety of enemies to fight – unfortunately, nearly every one of them is humanoid. That means that even though they all have their own unique quirks and attack patterns, I was rarely impressed by anything new that was thrown at me. Outside of bosses, which can be hulking behemoths that shake things up more substantially, one of the few interesting regular enemy types were the trolls: they have constant health regeneration and two health bars, requiring you to drain one bar and then mutilate a limb with a charged attack before you can attempt to finish them off. But a mechanic like that is the exception rather than the rule, and the predictability of every enemy’s clearly telegraphed attacks meant fights often just came down to my parry timing. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It has one of the most disappointing endings I've seen in a while.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you do fall in combat, the powers of the legendary hammer mean Aran doesn’t stay dead for long. However, his temporary deaths come with the penalty of dropping your equipped weapon at that location, similar to how you drop souls, blood echoes, and other currencies in games like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/09/30/dark-souls-review">Dark Souls</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/03/24/bloodborne-review">Bloodborne</a>. Thankfully, Blades of Fire is much more forgiving, as any weapon dropped in a location turns to stone and remains in the world permanently until Aran retrieves it. This was a welcome change to the formula as the potential of permanently losing a weapon you’ve invested heavily into after consecutive deaths would have been extremely frustrating.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last and certainly least, the most disappointing pillar of Blades of Fire is its story, characters, and world exploration. Aran’s quest to stop the queen does keep a decent pace, but it never surprised or wowed me and many moments that seemed like they <em>should </em>be impactful are hindered by an uneven delivery. At one point after killing a major boss, he simply fell to his knee and sat there until I struck him once more – it felt like it was set up for more, but there was no dialogue and no flair. Just this previously important character falling to the ground in anticlimatic fashion. Blades of Fire also has one of the most disappointing endings I've seen in a while, rolling credits with little resolution and then immediately sending you off on a scavenger hunt that is too long for its own good if you want to find out what’s actually going on. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Jada's Favorite Action/Adventure RPGs</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Characters are generally one-note stereotypes, and often have dialogue that further enforces their simplistic nature. Aran regularly remarks that he’s not smart enough to solve the puzzles without the aid of Adso, a young scribe who accompanies him on the journey, though Adso doesn’t offer much advice outside of stating the obvious. Adso is the brains to Aran’s brawn, deciphering codices you find, reading ancient languages to reveal paths or secrets, and magically sealing coffins during fights occasionally. Adso also makes regular remarks about Aran’s size when climbing ladders, which ends up feeling like an out of place attempt at humor as Aran rarely responds or finds opportunities to tease back. They are written as if they’ve known each other for a long time despite meeting for the first time in the opening hours, which makes moments like these unearned and shoehorned in. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rounding out the cast are Glinda the Master Forger, a cranky witch of the woods type that lives in a house on top of a flying beetle, and Arwen, an impatient and hardheaded young girl that is only involved in the final dozen hours and yet conveniently turns out to be super important. As time went on, the uncanny parallels between these characters and those in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/04/12/god-of-war-review">God of War</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-ragnarok-review">God of War Ragnarok</a> became more and more distracting. Aran is just a less wise and somehow less charismatic Kratos, Adso deciphers ancient languages and takes note of enemies and other elements of the world similar to Atreus, Glinda fills in the role of Freya, and Arwen is essentially a less prominent Angrboða. You even fight a giant snake at one point, and explore places that strongly resemble areas like the temple resting above the Lake of Nine. Different games using similar character archetypes or tropes isn’t anything new or wrong on its own, but it does start to feel derivative to a fault here - especially when Blades of Fire doesn’t come off so hot in such a direct comparison.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s not the only way it’s put in a bad light, as a lackluster map system often makes exploring for secrets very cumbersome and confusing. There are a ton of little hidden paths to find that lead to cool optional collectibles like shrines for upgrading your weapon customization options, chests with items that increase your healing flasks, gems to up your maximum health or stamina, and different dyes to customize Aran’s outfits. But many locations have multiple levels of elevation, and apart from staring at the one-dimensional map while hoping that you are reading it correctly, you don’t really have a way of knowing which level you are on until you either reach the correct destination or the wrong one. You can leave markers on the map that create a streak of color in the world as guidepoints, which at least help by adding distance and elevation cues to the compass at the top of the screen, but that’s only a half measure. </p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Blades of Fire’s blacksmithing burns bright, but it doesn’t forge a sharp enough edge to put its customizable weapons to good use. The combat is serviceable but overly simplistic, and the mediocre story often failed to evoke any kind of emotion in me at all, positive or negative, as it just goes through the motions from start to finish. The unintuitive map also frequently left me&nbsp;running in circles, making what could have been a fun hunt for secrets feel more like a chore. And when those pain points are compounded by unflattering comparisons to the games it so clearly took inspiration from, Blades of Fire just can’t cut it.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade Developer Confirms Sequel Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-developer-confirms-sequel-plans</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blade-developer-confirms-sequel-plans.1194315/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-developer-confirms-sequel-plans<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stellar-blade">Stellar Blade</a> is getting a fully-fledged sequel, developer Shift Up has confirmed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PlayStation-published action game launched to a positive response back in April 2024, with players saying its gameplay mixed elements of NieR: Automata and Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Korean company Shift Up has confirmed a Stellar Blade sequel is on the way, via a chart showing the company's future plans published as part of its latest financial results released today. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As confirmed within a presentation slide detailing how Shift Up expects to expand its franchises going forward, a Stellar Blade sequel is listed as coming next among others that look set to be released before 2027.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Before the sequel arrives, there's mention of a "platform expansion" for Stellar Blade — this likely just refers to the game's upcoming PC version, which is set to arrive on June 11, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This development period — before 2027 — will also include the launch of Shift Up's mysterious Project Witches, a new multiplatform action RPG that's still yet to be fully revealed. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/screenshot-2025-05-20-152430-1747751824186.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Shift Up's development chart showing Stellar Blade sequel plans.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-devs-closely-discussing-mysterious-pc-region-lock-issue-with-sony">Shift Up said it was "closely discussing" a mysterious PC region lock issue with Sony</a> that had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blades-steam-rollout-mysteriously-blocked-in-over-100-countries">blocked the game's store page on Steam in more than 100 countries</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Stellar Blade stands out as a gorgeous and well-crafted action game with very impressive strengths and very clear weaknesses," IGN wrote in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-review">Stellar Blade review</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Both its story and characters lack substance, and some of its RPG elements are poorly implemented, like dull sidequests that very often require you to retrace your steps through previous levels with very little done to make the return trip feel unique or rewarding. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"But its action picks up most of that slack thanks to the rock solid fundamentals of its Sekiro-inspired combat system, a deep well of hideous monstrosities to sharpen your sword against, and plenty of hidden goodies that do a great job of incentivizing exploration throughout."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky @tomphillipseg.bsky.social‬</em><br>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>