<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 17:44:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War 4 – First Impressions From a Series Veteran]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-4-first-impressions-from-a-series-veteran</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-dawn-of-war-4-%E2%80%93-first-impressions-from-a-series-veteran.1275987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The thunder of bolters repelling an Ork incursion and the distinctive red and white ceramite armor of the Blood Ravens bring me right back to the moment the trailer for the original Dawn of War made me an instant Warhammer 40K fan more than 20 years ago. And it's that first game in the series that serves as the jumping off point for the upcoming Dawn of War 4. A lot has changed, but a lot remains the same, bringing bigger battles and snazzier graphics to a classic take-and-hold RTS that is equal parts spectacle and tactics. I played through the 1-2 hour demo a few times and it felt like Dark Crusade never left.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last we heard of this franchise was in 2018 when Relic ended support for the divisive Dawn of War 3, and this next chapter is deploying under different masters. King Art Games, the developer of the alt-history dieselpunk RTS Iron Harvest, has taken up the banner, and I can definitely see a throughline between the big, stompy robots in that game and the classic dreadnoughts and titans in this one. King Art has also elevated the cinematic carnage by adding a synced animation melee system that can simulate a scrape between any two of its many dozens of units.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War 4 - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Like the recent editions of the tabletop game on which it's based, Dawn of War 4 has jumped 200 years deeper into the 41st Millennium, after the Eye of Terror opened and split the Imperium of Man apart. The Blood Ravens are a scattered and beleaguered chapter trying to put themselves back together, serving as one of the four… and a half playable factions. Their roster reflects the newest Space Marines codex, with Primaris Intercessors and Bladeguard Veterans leading the charge. Older, tracked mainstays like the Rhino and Predator have been swapped for the higher-tech repulsor vehicles. But some classic favorites like the Dreadnought and Terminators have stuck around.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Dawn of War 4 has jumped 200 years deeper into the 41st Millennium, after the Eye of Terror opened and split the Imperium of Man apart.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marines focus on small, elite squads that are expensive to build and reinforce, but outshine most of their opponents pound-for-pound. Their buildings are large and expensive, with defensive structures being fully automated rather than manned. In fact, they barely pay attention to cover at all, which was an adjustment from having replayed Dawn of War 2 fairly recently. They do have a lot of tactical flexibility though, with most infantry squads being trained into a pool of strategic reserves that can be deployed by drop pod to anywhere you have vision. The drop pods are even armed, and will stay on the map as a light defensive turret until destroyed.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">ENEMIES OF THE IMPERIUM</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The other ubiquitous Dawn of War race from that very first trailer, the Orks, are the second faction, and the primary enemies in the demo I played. They have much more of a horde style of combat, though with a few units like the Meganobz in their petroleum-fueled power armor that can go toe-to-toe with a space marine. Their buildings are cheap, and all of them have some kind of little guy with a machine gun on them, so vomiting production structures across the map is also how you create defensive positions. The animations are especially thematic and entertaining, as it really looks like a giant heap of scrap that was chucked unceremoniously through the atmosphere.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Orks also, of course, get a WAAAGH! mechanic that lets them earn powerful deployable stratagems for causing all sorts of havoc.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as I was coming to grips with the Orks, though, one of my control points was taken by surprise by the other hostile race, the terminator-like Necrons. Hinted at in the epilogue of Dawn of War 3 but never fully materializing, they make a dramatic return with the monolith super unit that can warp in new squads to its location. For balance reasons, Necrons can't simply get right back up when killed like they can in the tabletop game. But they do get a special building called the Resurrection Chamber that can respawn a certain number of destroyed squads for free.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">They play the most differently from the other factions in that they aren't especially concerned with the requisition and power capture points dotted around the map. Rather, their economy relies on spreading their matrix – like an eerie, cybernetic form of zerg creep from Starcraft – that grants bonuses to their units when fighting on it and provides them with resources the more of the map is covered in it.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">STALWART ALLIES</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Having barely fought off the Necron incursion and getting pushed back hard by the Orks due to my divided attention, who would arrive at the crucial moment to join the Blood Ravens in turning the tide of battle? Would you believe it's a faction completely new to the Dawn of War series? The final of the four fully-playable multiplayer factions is the Adeptus Mechanicus, with their swarms of cyborg servitors and impressive, well-kept war machines.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The AdMech have a unique ability to see enemy contacts as blobs of color relative to their size and power on the minimap, even in the fog of war, so it's almost impossible to surprise them. Their buildings are also networked, providing them with powerful boosts to production for being in range of a network node, which can make them vulnerable to surgical strikes severing the connection. Their super unit is the titanic Imperial Knight, which really shows off Dawn of War 4's scale next to the puny units it's stomping over.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Imperial Guard were present on the mission I played as AI-controlled allies, although with a limited roster of units. They will also be playable in the tutorial mission of the campaign, but not in multiplayer. Not yet, at least.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I did say four and a half factions, though. The Imperial Guard were present on the mission I played as AI-controlled allies, although with a limited roster of units. They will also be playable in the tutorial mission of the campaign, but not in multiplayer. Not yet, at least.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other four factions will each have their own campaigns with branching story paths, taking us back to the planet Kronus from the Dawn of War: Dark Crusade expansion. The story features more than 40 minutes of CGI cutscenes across all factions, and was written by prolific Black Library author John French, author of the recent Ahriman novels among others.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Dawn of War 4 will also bring back the popular Last Stand mode from Dawn of War 2, though in a way that was described to me as less hero-centric and "less MOBA-like," focusing more on the classic RTS mechanics like Dawn of War 1. Co-op is also on the slate, and there was a conspicuously greyed-out "Painter" option on the main menu. The devs weren't ready to talk about this one yet, but told me their goal was to include everything the previous Dawn of War games had in terms of customization and then add a bit more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I certainly wasn't expecting a new Dawn of War any time soon, much less from a studio other than Relic. But from the bit of it I've played, it seems like King Art Games understands the assignment. As a Dawn of War 2 fan, I miss the emphasis on cover and move-and-fire tactics. But Dawn of War 4 has nevertheless made a big first impression. I can hardly wait to get dug in next year.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-4-first-impressions-from-a-series-veteran]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 14's Yoshi-P Says There May Be 'Good News' in the Future About FF14 on Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14s-yoshi-p-says-there-may-be-good-news-in-the-future-about-ff14-on-nintendo-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-14s-yoshi-p-says-there-may-be-good-news-in-the-future-about-ff14-on-nintendo-switch-2.1275981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Have you played the critically acclaimed MMORPG Final Fantasy 14? With an expanded free trial which you can play through the entirety of A Realm Reborn and the award-winning Heavensward AND Stormblood expansions now up to level 70 for free with no restrictions on playtime? What's that, you haven't? You only have Nintendo platforms and nothing else?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Well, never fear, because Final Fantasy 14 producer Naoki 'Yoshi-P' Yoshida is thinking of you. In an <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/yoshi-p-reveals-positive-discussions-over-nintendo-switch-2-final-fantasy-14-port/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with VGC</a> at Gamescom this week, Yoshi-P answered some questions about the potential to bring FF14 to Nintendo Switch 2, and the news seems promising. “For me, it’s just my aim to provide Final Fantasy 14 and 16 to as many players as possible, and I hope that as many players as possible will be able to enjoy those two games,” he said. “We are putting in our best efforts to ensure that this happens, so it’s fine to convey to your readership that I consider the possibilities very positively, and we are putting in our best efforts."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Yoshi-P continued by saying that this would be a boon for existing players too, as some players might want to raid or do main story content on PC, but could relax on the sofa with a Switch 2 and do gathering and crafting more easily.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“When it comes to players who haven’t played Final Fantasy 14 before, the younger generation of players, if they started playing Final Fantasy 14 on Switch 2, of course being an MMO, it might be a new genre for them, and I would be super excited to get these new players into this genre and enjoying the game as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So to this end, we have been discussing with Nintendo, and the discussions have been positive, so I do hope that players will look forward to hopefully good news in the future.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy 14 has long been available on PlayStation and PC, but it recently got <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-requires-game-pass-subscription-to-play-on-xbox">Xbox</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-mobile-announced-tencent">mobile</a> releases as well, making it one of the rare MMORPGs that's playable on most major platforms. Nintendo has been the main holdout, almost certainly due to past Nintendo systems not quite having the technical capability to run an MMORPG of that size. Could the Nintendo Switch 2 finally handle Eorzea and all its denizens? Hopefully yes, and hopefully soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yesterday, we did get some Final Fantasy 14 news at Gamescom Opening Night Live. We learned that a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-and-final-fantasy-14-collaborations-reveal-new-content-coming-this-fall">Monster Hunter x Final Fantasy 14 collaboration is on the way this fall</a>, adding FF14 content to Monster Hunter Wilds and vice versa. Unfortunately, if you're not already active in FF14, you won't be able to just jump in and enjoy the Monster Hunter content. You'll need to have finished the latest expansion, Dawntrail, which is a hundreds-of-hours-long endeavor if you don't pay to skip most of the story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14s-yoshi-p-says-there-may-be-good-news-in-the-future-about-ff14-on-nintendo-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Legacy of the Forge DLC Trailer Reveals September Release Date and Henry's New Home]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-legacy-of-the-forge-dlc-trailer-reveals-september-release-date-and-henrys-new-home</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-legacy-of-the-forge-dlc-trailer-reveals-september-release-date-and-henrys-new-home.1275978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Start building in just a few weeks.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Deep Silver and Warhorse Studios showed up for gamescom Opening Night Live 2025 to show off a first-look trailer for the next <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii"><u>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</u></a> story DLC, Legacy of the Forge, as well as a release date of September 9, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new footage arrived as one of many trailers that premiered throughout the two-hour show, updating players on the next chapter in Henry’s journey. It’s a 30-second video that mostly serves to whet the appetite for players ahead of its September release date for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Returning to Kuttenberg, Henry puts his blacksmithing skills to the test to acquire and repair a legendary burnt-down forge, where his father, Martin, spent his youth as an apprentice,” an official description for the Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Legacy of the Forge DLC says. “Venturing down memory lane, Henry learns of his father’s legacy as a blacksmith, revealing a part of his life that has remained hidden until now. Gaining new blacksmith prestige, Henry becomes a forge master, helping the people of Kuttenberg with sword crafting, armor-smithing, and other quirky requests.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warhorse tells Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 fans that Legacy of the Forge also comes with a new home customization system with more than 136 million combinations for Henry. Players can expect their new digs to be fully upgradable, with features like a forge and private quarters.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Legacy of the Forge DLC Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Legacy of the Forge will cost $13.99 on its own. It’s also included as part of the $30 Expansion Pass, which comes with the already released Shields of Seasons Passing and Brushes With Death DLC packs as well as the upcoming Mysteria Ecclesiae content. Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Gold Edition owners will also receive the new content at no extra charge.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Warhorse has plans to release more major content for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 through the end of the year. In the meantime, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/a-cinematic-cut-of-kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-will-get-the-film-festival-treatment"><u>why the medieval RPG sequel recently got the film festival treatment</u></a>. You can also see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-everything-announced"><u>everything else announced at gamescom Opening Night Live 2025</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-legacy-of-the-forge-dlc-trailer-reveals-september-release-date-and-henrys-new-home]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>