<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 23:38:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brandon Sanderson's Mistborn Deckbuilding Game Just Dropped to a New Low Price on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/brandon-sandersons-mistborn-deckbuilding-game-just-dropped-to-a-new-low-price-on-amazon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brandon-sandersons-mistborn-deckbuilding-game-just-dropped-to-a-new-low-price-on-amazon.1277730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A tabletop Cosmere experience.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're a fan of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/brandson-sanderson-cosmere-books-in-order">Brandon Sanderson's Cosmere books</a>, there's certainly no shortage of written content available. And in recent years, that same universe has started to trickle over into the world of tabletop games. One such experience is a collaboration with Brotherwise Games called Mistborn: The Deckbuilding Game, which is currently discounted on Amazon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Mistborn board game pulls from Era 1 of the Mistborn book series. These were some of the first Brandon Sanderson books I ever read and are, in my opinion, the best entrypoint into The Cosmere as a whole. If you're a fan of both the books <em>and </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deck-building-board-games">deckbuilding games</a>, I definitely recommend checking out this crossover board game.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Mistborn: The Deckbuilding Game Is on Sale at Amazon</h2><div catalogid="03f4581e-8b45-41ac-ae43-398a90ca5d3b" id="226306"><div id="226306" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mistborn: The Deckbuilding Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Mistborn board game was designed by John D. Clair and published by Brotherwise Games. The game itself pulls directly from its source material, and players will have to burn and flare metals as they battle each other or the Lord Ruler throughout play. Like any standard deckbuilding game, everyone will begin with a weaker deck of cards and slowly add new ones to their hand throughout the game. It's designed for up to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-4-players">four players</a> total, but can also be played <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-solo-board-games">solo</a> if you prefer that route.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The current discount on Amazon drops the price down to $39.17, which is the <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0DK3ZZFVM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lowest price we've ever seen</a> for this game. And while that's still not exactly cheap, it's just enough of a discount to make it worth considering.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 21, 2025 8:38 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/brandon-sandersons-mistborn-deckbuilding-game-just-dropped-to-a-new-low-price-on-amazon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DC Head James Gunn Teases New Future for WB Games With 'Some Bigger Things' Now 'in Early Stages']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dc-head-james-gunn-teases-new-future-for-wb-games-with-some-bigger-things-now-in-early-stages</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dc-head-james-gunn-teases-new-future-for-wb-games-with-some-bigger-things-now-in-early-stages.1277724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"One thing in particular I'm excited about, but it does take time."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">DC Studios co-CEO and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/superman-2025">Superman</a> Director James Gunn says big things are in store for Warner Bros. Games, but it’s going to take a while to see them come to fruition.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The comic book bigwig spoke about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-know-about-james-gunn-dcu-video-games-rocksteady-batman-superman">his plans to expand the DC</a> universe during an interview with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/dc-tv-shows/after-years-of-silence-dc-boss-james-gunn-teases-dcus-gaming-plans-theres-one-thing-in-particular-im-excited-about-but-it-does-take-time/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GamesRadar+</u></a>. As Gunn, co-CEO Peter Safran, and the rest of the DC Studios crew plot a new course for DCU shows and movies, the Superman moviemaker says he has no plans to leave gaming out of the equation.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“There's been some slight movement on different things," Gunn teased. "We have a couple of little DC games coming out. But we also have talked about – and in early stages of planning – some bigger things. One thing in particular I'm excited about, but it does take time. There's been some changes in <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/tag/warner-bros-games/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Warner Bros. Games</u></a>, and so we're dealing with new people.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those changes he’s referring to have unraveled throughout the last year or so and have seen WB Games <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-games-restructuring-to-focus-on-harry-potter-mortal-kombat-game-of-thrones-and-dc-franchises"><u>shifting its focus to four key franchises</u></a>: Mortal Kombat, Harry Potter, DC, and Game of Thrones. It’s a fundamental change to how Warner Bros. is looking to the future following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-flop-leads-to-200-million-impairment-charge-warner-bros-confirms"><u>massive losses tied to Rocksteady Studios’ Suicide Squad Kill the Justice League</u></a>, as well as the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-admits-multiversus-underperformed-contributing-to-another-100-million-hit-to-revenue-in-its-games-business"><u>underperformance</u></a> and<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-to-shut-down-when-season-5-concludes-in-may"> <u>eventual shutdown of MultiVersus</u></a>. WB Games head <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-games-boss-david-haddad-is-leaving-the-company-a-year-after-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-leagues-disastrous-launch"><u>David Haddad left the company</u></a> in January.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The studio also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-cancels-wonder-woman-game-closes-three-studios"><u>canceled its Wonder Woman game</u></a> and shut down Monolith Productions, Player First Games, and WB San Diego in February. Although WB Games has managed to deliver successful comic book-based video games like the Injustice series and Batman Arkham series, DC gaming still has some work to do if it wants to make up lost ground.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There's been some slight movement on different things.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunn teases things are finally in motion at WB Games but declined to share what kind of DC projects fans can expect to see in the future. However, GamesRadar+ adds that the director teased that there is a good chance Superman star David Corenswet could reprise his role for a video game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunn and Safran <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/itll-be-a-couple-years-before-we-see-the-first-dcu-video-game-james-gunn-says-but-first-fortnite"><u>shared earlier this year</u></a> that it will be “a couple of years” before fans get their hands on the first DCU games. Safran says they’ve been hands-on when it comes to new projects at studios like Injustice studio NetherRealm and Batman Arkham developer Rocksteady as they steer DC in a fresh direction.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We see designs for the projects in their very earliest stages,” Gunn added at the time. “We talk about those. We talk about when they're talking about what the story might be, we say, ‘Well, maybe you want to go this way because we're planning on maybe doing something with this character and so forth and so on,’ and help to deal with that.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It will be some time before a new vision for WB Games comes to fruition. In the meantime, the studio has been busy with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight"><u>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</u></a>, which it <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-announced-featuring-open-world-gotham"><u>announced</u></a> as part of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-2025-all-the-biggest-reveals-so-far"><u>gamescom</u></a> 2025 earlier this week. Although fans are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-really-does-have-just-7-playable-characters-and-its-dividing-fan-opinion"><u>divided due to its limited roster</u></a>, many have already found themselves drawn to its recreation of classic movie moments and Batman Arkham-like combat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/dc-head-james-gunn-teases-new-future-for-wb-games-with-some-bigger-things-now-in-early-stages]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Looks to be Significantly Bigger Than the Original Hollow Knight]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight.1277637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">More bosses, more enemies, more...?</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, we got our first real, new, meaty trailer for Hollow Knight: Silksong in several years, complete with a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-finally-has-a-release-date">September 4 release date</a>. Fans are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1mwfriy/silksong_might_be_2530_bigger_than_hollow_knight/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">already unpacking details</a> from the trailer, including pointing out that it looks like the base game of Silksong might be bigger than the base game of Hollow Knight - quite a feat for something that started out as DLC.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Evidence for this comes from the trailer above, which has text stating the game contains over 200 enemies and over 40 bosses. Compare that to Hollow Knight's launch trailer, which said over 140 enemies and over 30 bosses:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So it <em>sounds like</em> Silksong is launching with more enemies and bosses than Hollow Knight did. And though we don't know the size of the explorable area in Silksong, it stands to reason that it probably needs to be big enough to fit all those little guys, and thus its map is likely to be at least as big as the original Hollow Knight if not more. And while that may sound like a given for a sequel, it's helpful to remember that Silksong didn't start out as a sequel - it began as DLC, and then somehow morphed into something seemingly even bigger than its predecessor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, that comparison doesn't include Hollow Knight's DLC, which added tons of new enemies, areas, bosses, story, and other content. With all that included, the existing game of Hollow Knight is almost certainly larger than Silksong was at launch. That said, we learned today that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/team-cherry-says-it-has-plans-for-more-silksong-content-for-months-and-years-to-come">developer Team Cherry is still working on more Silksong for the months and years after the game's launch</a>, making it possible it will eventually surpass Hollow Knight's DLC as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you absolutely can't wait until launch to find out what some of these enemies and bosses entail, we did get to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-we-played-it-gamescom-2025">preview Hollow Knight: Silksong earlier this week</a> at Gamescom in Cologne, Germany. Funnily enough, it looks like the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-demo-at-gamescom-2025-is-a-shinier-silkier-version-of-the-same-demo-from-e3-2019">exact same demo we played back in E3 2019</a>, only with six more years of polish, illustrating how far the game has come in its lengthy development.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>