<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 09:15:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[inZoi Publisher Dismisses Plummeting Steam Concurrents, Insists Sales Are a Better Indicator of Performance Because It's a Single-Player Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/inzoi-publisher-dismisses-plummeting-steam-concurrents-insists-sales-are-a-better-indicator-of-performance-because-its-a-single-player-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inzoi-publisher-dismisses-plummeting-steam-concurrents-insists-sales-are-a-better-indicator-of-performance-because-its-a-single-player-game.1215255/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/inzoi-publisher-dismisses-plummeting-steam-concurrents-insists-sales-are-a-better-indicator-of-performance-because-its-a-single-player-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/inzoi">inZoi</a> publisher Krafton has addressed an ongoing debate about its plummeting Steam concurrent player count, insisting that as a single-player game sales are a better indicator of performance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The eye-catching The Sims competitor launched big on Steam with an all-time peak concurrent player count of 87,377. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-competitor-inzoi-sells-1-million-in-a-week-krafton-declares-it-a-long-term-franchise-ip">Krafton announced inZOI sold impressive 1 million copies in a week</a>, the fastest sales milestone ever for a game published by the South Korean megacorp. It rose to number one on Steam’s Global Top Sellers List (by sales revenue) just 40 minutes after release, with CEO CH Kim said at the time that Krafton planned to “foster" the game as a "long-term franchise IP."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, inZoi's Steam concurrent player count has dwindled since launch, with a 24-hour peak of 1,477. As <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/more-players-playing-16-year-old-sims-3-than-inzoi/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TheGamer</a> reported this week, inZoi’s peak concurrent player count even dropped below the 16-year-old The Sims 3 on Valve’s platform.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN asked Krafton for comment on the situation, and it responded to dismiss Steam peak concurrent player figures as a barometer of the game’s success because it is a single-player game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"inZOI continues to steadily generate sales, and as a single-player game, it would be most appropriate to refer to the additional sales count at each major update point as opposed to concurrent player count on Steam in measuring the game's performance,” Krafton said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The focus on Steam concurrent player numbers has become a hot topic within the industry in recent years, with a number of developers and publishers insisting they don’t tell the whole story of a game’s performance, particularly for single-player games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 2024, John “Bucky” Buckley, community chief at Palworld developer Pocketpair, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-dev-addresses-dead-game-debate-who-cares-if-theres-only-five-people-playing">said</a> our obsession with the concept of the “dead game” and player counts was unhealthy for the video game industry and gamers. And in April this year, Alex Bolle, production director on Helldivers 2, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arrowhead-wants-helldivers-2-to-be-around-for-years-and-years-and-years-to-come-and-what-about-a-warhammer-40000-collab">told IGN</a> that Steam concurrents are “a metric among many others.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">inZOI's Best and Most Cursed Creations</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for inZoi, Steam user reviews, which do have a significant impact on a game’s visibility on Valve’s platform, remain ‘mostly positive’ for all reviews, but are on ‘mixed’ for recent reviews. As an Early Access game, it has yet to fully release, a point Krafton made in its statement to IGN:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That said, Early Access is only the beginning of inZOI's journey, and in many ways our work is just starting. During this phase, the team's top priority is gathering player feedback and continuing the development of the game with more enhanced features, improved performance, and an overall immersive and engaging experience. We're thankful for our dedicated inZOI community and look forward to sharing new content updates over the coming months."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Krafton announced inZOI is coming to the Mac App Store and Steam in August. The Mac version of inZOI is optimized for the latest macOS on Apple Silicon, Krafton said, and takes “full advantage” of Apple’s MetalFX and Core ML “to deliver the same great gameplay experience as on Windows.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Untethered Meta Quest 3S Is on Sale Today: The Best Headset for New VR Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-deal-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-untethered-meta-quest-3s-is-on-sale-today-the-best-headset-for-new-vr-gamers.1215162/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-deal-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Both 128GB and 256GB models are on sale.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Starting this week, Meta has dropped the prices on both Quest 3 VR headset options. The <a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z15RK?object_uuid=abc75198-2cb1-4e93-be63-56b515f0fb81&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">128GB model is $269.99</a> after a $30 off discount. and the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qr2Xd1?object_uuid=abc75198-2cb1-4e93-be63-56b515f0fb81&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">256GB is $349.99</a> after a $50 off instant discount. These discounts are honored at major retailers including Amazon, Target, and Walmart. The Meta Quest 3S is widely considered the best value in VR gaming. Not only is it priced hundreds less compared to most other competitors (including Meta's own Quest3), it's also a standalone untethered gaming system that doesn't require a PC or PlayStation 5 to run,,</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To sweeten the pot even more, every Quest 3S purchase includes a copy of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/batman-arkham-shadow-review-meta-quest-3">Batman: Arkham Shadow VR</a> game and a three-month trial of Meta Quest+. In IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/batman-arkham-shadow-review-meta-quest-3">8/10 review</a>, Dan Stapleton wrote that "Batman: Arkham Shadow makes most of the Arkham series' defining gameplay work respectably well in VR, and its mystery story pays off."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Meta Quest 3S VR Headset with Batman: Arkham Shadow</h2><div id="222595" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="46006467-4f90-4d47-ad0b-ab15ae567c6a"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Meta Quest 3S 256GB VR Headset</h3></p></div><div catalogid="46006467-4f90-4d47-ad0b-ab15ae567c6a" id="207786"><div id="207786" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Meta Quest 3S 128GB VR Headset</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Quest 3S is an improvement over the original Quest 2 in every way and, amazingly, without a price increase. It also adopts many of the same features of the more expensive Quest 3, like the new and improved Touch controllers, the upgraded SnapDragon APU, and support for full color AR passthrough. In IGN's 9/10 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-review">Quest 3S review</a>, Gabriel Moss wrote that "raw processing power, full-color passthrough, and snappy Touch Plus controllers make the Quest 3S a fantastic standalone VR headset that also brings entry-level mixed-reality gaming to the masses for – arguably – the very first time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What really sets this deal above all other VR deals is that the Meta Quest 3S can be played <strong>completely untethered</strong>. That means you can play games like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/05/28/beat-saber-review">Beat Saber</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/11/08/pistol-whip-review">Pistol Whip</a> without having to own a powerful gaming PC or a PlayStation 5 console. Try to find another standalone VR headset at this price and you'll come up empty.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How Is the Quest 3S Different from the Quest 3?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Even at retail price, the Quest 3S comes in at $200, or 40% cheaper than the $500 <a href="https://howl.link/33aavd3s563fo" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Quest 3</a>. Obviously, some compromises were made to get the 3S to its competitive price point. The spec comparisons are listed below:</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Quest 3S vs. Quest 3 <u>Similarities</u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Snapdragon XR2 Gen 2 processor</li><li>Touch Plus controllers</li><li>120Hz refresh rate</li><li>Mixed reality passthrough (same cameras, different layout)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Quest 3S vs. Quest 3 <u>Differences</u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lower per-eye resolution (1832x1920 vs 2064×2208)</li><li>Fresnel lens vs. pancake lens</li><li>Lower FOV (96°/90° vs 104°/96°)</li><li>Smaller storage capacity (128GB vs 512GB)</li><li><strong>Longer</strong> battery life (2.5hrs vs 2.2hrs)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">For the price, the Quest 3S is a better value than the Quest 3, and the best choice for gamers who are just starting out in the world of VR and want to test the waters. It is hands down a major improvement over the Quest 2 that it replaces.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 11, 2025 12:10 am</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deltarune Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deltarune-review.1215105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Note: this review contains some small spoilers for Deltarune's first two chapters.</strong></em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was nearly seven years ago on Halloween when I woke up at the crack of dawn to download an ominous “Survey Program” from Undertale developer Toby Fox. It turned out that this program contained not just a simple survey, but the start of a grand adventure that I haven’t been able to stop thinking about since. Now, with the release of the third and fourth chapters, that adventure has truly started to take a more solid shape. Deltarune carries on the spirit of its predecessor by subverting expectations of the RPG genre in the wildest ways. It also shares the same sort of clever, heartfelt, and often absurdly hilarious writing, not to mention a truly unforgettable soundtrack. Don’t be fooled by its deceptively humble pixel art and initially simple plot: there’s a surprising amount of intrigue, beauty, and unpredictability just under the surface. The unsettling questions Deltarune raises about our relationship to the characters we control in games provides an engrossing layer of meta-commentary, while still celebrating the indomitable willpower and heart of extraordinary RPG heroes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That aforementioned creepy survey demo ended up only being the first chapter of Deltarune, with the second released in 2021, and finally the most recent two arriving just last week as part of its more traditional “full” release – although, that’s not to say it’s “finished” now, as more chapters are planned to arrive as free content updates in the future. But no matter if you are picking up where you left off years ago or starting fresh from the first chapter, you’ll be unceremoniously thrust into the body of a weird teen named Kris. There are a lot of similarities to Undertale here, but also more than enough differences in its setting and how battles work to set it apart. Where Undertale had you navigating an underground society of imprisoned monsters you either had to fight or befriend, Deltarune begins in a pleasant but unremarkable “Hometown” – though for some reason you’re still the only human around in a world of monsters. The only epic struggles to be found here are trying to stay awake through class, or dodging the extreme embarrassment of seeing your divorced adoptive monster parents run into each other at the store.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you played Undertale, you might get a kick out of seeing several of that game’s more notable figures living regular lives in this parallel story, but I wouldn’t quite say it’s required. In fact, I’d argue that Deltarune is at its best when it’s not trying to focus on what came before it – funny as those interactions may be. I’ll admit, at first I was a little disappointed to see familiar faces appearing in what was supposed to be a new adventure, but then I realized these aren’t simple fanservice cameos. In another universe, these were imposing boss monsters – kings and queens with terrifying strength and magical powers. Here, they’re just… ordinary townsfolk: teachers, bored police, and struggling shop owners. While they may have a role to play, this story isn’t truly about them.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It’s a great touch how even the menus and UI change to reflect this new realm.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Instead, things kick off when Kris and a rude, crude monster classmate named Susie find themselves transported into a world of fantasy straight out of an ‘80s adventure movie. Here, pencils and bandaids transform into swords and armor, while forgotten classroom toys or computer lab accessories spring to life as “Darkeners”, many of which will stand in your way. It’s a great touch how even the menus and UI change to reflect this new realm. The environments you’ll find yourself exploring in these “Dark Worlds” are anything but: they’re filled with vibrant and beautiful pixel art backdrops that work in harmony with a stunning soundtrack to capture the themes of these fascinating places.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Happy Feet, Dumbass</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s not long after arrival in the Dark World that you meet your third “party member:” a lonely Darkener prince named Ralsei who seems to know all about you, and gives you the grand spiel about cleansing dark fountains and saving the world from destruction. You know, hero stuff. To get to your goal, you’ll have to fight your way through enemies, frenemies, misunderstood goofballs – pretty much everything you can think of. As with Undertale, you’ll learn that the path to victory can be forged with turn-based violence or pacifism, but the long-term consequences aren’t as clear cut here. Striking enemies into submission allows you to get stronger quicker, though finding ways to spare opponents will lead to your own Dark World’s Castle Town becoming populated with now-friendly occupants, and may even change how certain scenes play out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Truly, the best part of battles is the ability to “Act” on your turn – winning over an opponent with enough mercy to spare them, in between dodging an ever-expanding variety of deadly bullet patterns on the enemy’s turn within the confines of a box that pops onto the screen. On paper, this system could easily lose its charm, but here it’s kept entertaining by exceptionally witty and context-sensitive execution. Each foe has different needs that get more complex (and often wacky) the further you delve into these adventures. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Things may start with you ordering a party member to flirt their way toward mercy, but it wasn’t too much later I found myself up against tougher ambulance-themed adversaries. Asking Susie to “Act” instead gave me a challenge: dodge the ambulance-themed bullets on the enemy’s turn to earn more mercy for a risky play (because she doesn’t trust doctors, naturally). Whereas Ralsei’s “Act” would suggest getting hit on purpose instead (because they’re here to… help?), which wasn’t a bad call if I was having trouble dodging already. It’s moments like these where Deltarune’s creative juices are at their tastiest, combining fun contextual commands that blend limitless humor while leaning into the personalities of both your team and the Darkeners you’ll face. Each new encounter left me eager to see what my Fun Squad could come up with, and with a mix of plentiful enemy variety and Dark World areas that never stretched on too long, I never really found myself getting tired of the opponents I came up against.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even beyond fighting and ACTing, I really came to appreciate how Deltarune’s three party members allowed me to develop synergies and tactics as time went on. Later battles became delicate dances of assigning heals or items, then having one person ACT so that another could spare on the same turn (provided my ACTs were successful). Even the process of dodging incoming attacks provides a new layer of strategy with the ability to “graze” the bullet patterns by moving my little heart icon alongside the attacks or dodging at the last second without getting hit to build a meter necessary to perform certain magical powers. Just like ACTing, certain magic could change depending on the battle to accommodate new strategies and challenges unique to that fight, and often made the risky play to get close to attacks worthwhile.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>The Power of Page Breaks Shines Within You</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Even when I wasn’t fighting, there was a lot to explore both in and out of the Dark Worlds I visited. Being able to wander around, talk to people, and interact with objects isn’t exactly a new RPG idea. (I have vivid memories of obsessively checking every trash can in a Pokemon game, often leaving disappointed.) But what I believe sets Deltarune apart is the confidence it has in making its world worth stopping in to smell the roses. You might find a container of Ice-E’s Cool Boys Body Spray “Spray For the Boys” Flamin’ Hot Pizza Flavor under the bathroom sink, for instance. Deltarune’s hilariously illogical humor oozes into every corner of the world like some sort of weird goop that’s actually kind of delicious and also addictive for some reason. It’s so intrinsically linked with everything else – combat, dialogue, story, puzzles, you name it – that I couldn’t imagine this adventure being any other way. Seriously, in what other setting would you encounter a weird little dolphin attacking you with internet pop-up screens in reference to some obscure 14-year-old meme about a desktop image trying to lure you into downloading viruses?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s not just the jokes, either (rampant as they may be); I found myself constantly intrigued by the world being set up around this adventure. Not all of it is laid out in big, showy cutscenes and plot developments. There’s a level of reward that is given to those willing to inspect things they may otherwise walk right past, or talk to someone you may not expect to have a nugget of wisdom to give. It’s a type of detail that doesn’t seem all that impressive at first glance, and yet I’ve come to appreciate immensely during my time in each of the four currently available chapters. Even something as random as inspecting an innocuous patch of moss can steadily grow into its own running gag between chapters, which  feels like I’ve uncovered a special secret. In this way, Deltarune is also rife with small, personal moments and anecdotes that allow its characters to shine in a way I rarely see anywhere else.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Each place you visit is accompanied by an embarrassment of phenomenal music.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Every location has these touches, and the areas I explored on my quest to seal the dark fountains led me through some pretty fantastical interpretations of otherwise ordinary places. The plush carpet of a forgotten classroom became a vast red forest with fields of rippling purple grass, while a computer lab transformed into a larger-than-life shining city of lights and superhighways built from advertisements, and all of it works wonderfully in the distinct pixel-art style. Deltarune is careful about keeping its scope in check, and instead saves moments of visual flair for just the right occasion when you least expect it. Even the amount of expression seen in its character portraits continued to delight me at just how well they were able to convey the right emotions, which only got better and more expressive each chapter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each place you visit is accompanied by an embarrassment of phenomenal music, and as with Undertale, the payoff of Fox personally composing the music in addition to developing so many aspects of Deltarune is clear to see. From its incredibly funky and catchy battle theme to the ethereal exploration of the first Dark World and the upbeat tunes beyond, every new area you’ll visit is a treat for the ears. There’s a wonderful mix of chiptunes in all sorts of genres, and each boss encounter theme somehow surpasses the last with no signs of slowing down. (Did my ears deceive me, or did I hear the TMNT: Turtles in Time soundfont being used?). It’s not just that the music is great, but its decisive inclusions elevate the material with careful use of leitmotifs to tie events and characters together. In one of the later chapters, there are certain rare sequences that bring out the raw emotion of a live piano playing, and left me floored at how well it empowered the scene to reach greater emotional heights.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>It’s Pronounced, “The $!$? Squad”</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s hard to pick which characters to talk about in a cast that’s so colorful. Whether it’s in the relatively normal Light World, or the dream-like Dark World, the assorted monsters I met made a lasting impression on me. So many of Deltarune’s cast members are actually very, very dumb (in an extremely endearing way, I promise!), and incredibly distinct in ways too numerous to count. Many times, it almost felt like a Royal Rumble of competing scene-stealers, with new challengers arriving all the time. I’d always get a sinking feeling that there would be no way a new chapter could top the previous one’s antics… and yet, each time I was proven wrong in ways I literally could not have expected from both new and returning faces. I still don’t even know if I like Rouxls Kaard (that’s pronounced “Rules Card”) as a person, but I’ll be damned if he didn’t leave me in tears every time he popped up – usually against everyone else’s wishes.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Brendan's Favorite Games Featuring Goofy Little Dogs</h3><p>Seemed like a good idea at the time.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">But I can’t not talk about the true “Lightener” stars of the show: Kris and Susie, one of my favorite teams I’ve had the pleasure of commanding in turn-based battles. They both go through some very different personal journeys over the course of each chapter, and though we still don't fully know where they lead, they continue to fascinate me. Kris, Susie, and yes - even Ralsei are each loners and outcasts in their own ways, and seeing them form a bond powerful enough to shake the pillars of Heaven has been immensely satisfying.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There was a point early on where I worried that Susie’s own character growth would sputter out too soon after calming down on the more extreme ends of her bullying tough girl act (which is expertly woven into Deltarune’s mechanics to manifest in clever ways both in and out of combat). Instead, I found a wild card. She’s as much the main protagonist of this story as Kris is… sometimes perhaps even more. Susie continually forges her own path when it suits her, leading to surprising revelations and tweaks on how Deltarune plays. She won’t even let you remove gear from her without giving her something else to equip – she’s that feisty! And yet, for all her bark, she makes a wonderfully vocal stand-in for us, going from annoyed disinterest to full-throated enthusiasm as she embraces her role in the story, and her newfound friends.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>They are truly a dumbass duo with joint custody of a single braincell.&nbsp;</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Her relationship with her classmate Kris is also something I never get tired of. It encapsulates some of the funniest, most heartwarming, and most sincere parts of Deltarune’s story so far. I can’t count the number of times I inspected an object and was presented with the option to do something profoundly stupid, only to have Susie right there beside me, excitedly goading me on. They are truly a dumbass duo with joint custody of a single braincell, and the enthusiasm they share for the absurd is inescapably contagious. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kris on their own is also a fascinating enigma, and explaining why will require a light amount of spoilers from the first two chapters. I hope you’ll forgive me on this, but it’s also one of the central parts of Deltarune’s themes, and how you play it. <strong>You can click on the spoiler tag below to read more.</strong></p><div><p>In Deltarune, you do not play as Kris: you control Kris. You, the player, are a diegetic force in this world, meaning your presence is a tangible entity. You’re a red, heart-shaped object referred to as a SOUL, often seen when selecting choices or dodging attacks. However, it’s soon revealed that you are something of an unwanted guest in Kris’ body, and they may have their own motives and goals that don’t always align with your own. At times, this can even culminate in you being forcibly removed from piloting your fleshy teenage mech, and left helpless as Kris goes off on their own. </p><p>As both a game mechanic and a story idea, it’s an incredibly wild and unique take on the RPG genre in how this possession manifests itself, and further solidifies how Deltarune isn’t just inspired by games that came before it, but also eager to break new ground. As the story unfolds, how can you know if what you are doing is what Kris wants to do? Or… do you even care? It also puts an entirely new layer of meaning onto how the character we control reacts to things, and what information we can glean from that – and the themes of freedom and control will continually vie for your attention as you uncover Deltarune’s secrets. There’s a subtle yet masterful way that Deltarune drops the tiniest of hints that while we may control much of Kris, they can still find ways to inject their personality into the world despite us. Kris may be a silent protagonist from our perspective, but it’s how others react to the tone of their words or expressions that provides a fascinating look into the life of the human we’ve hijacked.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I don’t want to say more about how your role continues to escalate in later chapters, nor do I wish to spoil much of the contents of Chapter 3 and 4. What I will say is that Chapter 3 felt like a demented roller coaster ride that somehow seamlessly inserted an entirely new way to play that was an absolute blast. Chapter 4 continued to step on the gas pedal, but not in the ways I was expecting – it was more like riding the aforementioned roller coaster into the gaping maw of a dread-inducing abyss. It does have a few slower parts, especially navigating some of the more maze-like areas that seemed to lack the usual unlockable shortcuts until the very end. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, nothing prepared me for the harrowing end to Chapter 4. The story remains unfinished, yes, but in no way did I feel let down by it ending where it does for now, having surmounted some incredible odds and witnessed some jaw-dropping moments to get as far as I have.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maxroll's Wizard of Legend 2 Database and Guides]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-wizard-of-legend-2-database-and-guides</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maxrolls-wizard-of-legend-2-database-and-guides.1215102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-wizard-of-legend-2-database-and-guides<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Wizard of Legend 2 is coming out of early access — check out Maxroll's guides to help you beat this roguelike!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizard of Legend 2 is an indie Roguelike from Dead Mage, the studio behind Children of Morta, published by Humble Games. You play as a Wizard attempting the trials to become Wizard of Legend. Gather your Arcana, grab a relic, and wear your medallion of choice as you brave the challenges ahead.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Getting Started in Wizard of Legend 2</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-1-getting-started-wol2-1749577796088.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To help you get started, take a look at <a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/wizard-of-legend-2-beginners-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll’s Wizard of Legend 2 beginner’s guide</u></a>. The guide explains the different starting loadouts (don’t worry, you eventually unlock all the spells anyway) and you'll learn all about the game’s combat system; how to navigate the trials, use your Arcana to defeat foes and unleash powerful ultimate spells! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you make your way through the game, you'll meet a variety of NPCs along the way. Some of them are vendors within the Trials, whereas others provide access to metaprogression systems in the main hub. In addition to these friendly NPCs, there are several formidable bosses to challenge, including powerful creatures and wizards who have mastered their element of choice.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Wizard of Legend 2 Metaprogression Systems</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-2-metaprogression-systems-1749578114395.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The metaprogression systems in Wizard of Legend 2 include Medallions, Runes, Arcana, and Relics, each of which contributes to your character's power. You gain more Arcanas and Relics during the run, but can only select Medallions and runes before starting out. Check out <a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/metaprogression-systems-in-wizard-of-legend-2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll's Metaprogression systems guide</u></a> or learn more about individual topics with their deep dives below: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/wizard-of-legend-2-medallions-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Medallions Guide</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/runes-difficulty-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Runes and Difficulty Guide</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/wizard-of-legend-2-relic-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Relic Guide</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/wizard-of-legend-2-arcana-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Arcana Guide</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/chaos-arcana-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Chaos Arcana Guide</u></a></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Wizard of Legend 2 Events, NPCs, and More</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-3-events-1749578160520.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">You'll encounter a variety of events within the trial. This can include defeating challenging foes or helping a fellow Wizard. Complete <strong>events</strong> to earn a variety of rewards, including Relics, Arcana, Arcana Enhancements, or a boost to maximum health. In particular, keep an eye out for <strong>purple portals,</strong> as they often have lucrative rewards. Learn more with <a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/events-in-wizard-of-legend-2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll's Events Guide</u></a>.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-4-vendors-1749578181039.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">There's a wide variety of NPCs and Vendors to interact with in Wizard of Legend 2. Several are found in the game's main hub; interact with them to unlock Runes, Medallions, starting Relics, and Arcanas. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are also vendors within the trials who sell you Arcanas, Relics, and Arcana Enhancements. Save up your gold to purchase something and give yourself an edge in combat — learn more with <a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/npcs-and-vendors-in-wizard-of-legend-2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll's NPCs and Vendors guide</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You'll also need to know about Afflictions, status effects that deal additional damage to enemies or provide beneficial crowd control effects: check out <a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/guides/afflictions-in-wizard-of-legend-2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll's Afflictions Guide</u></a> for more information.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Wizard of Legend 2 Boss Guides</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-5-elemental-boss-1749578462911.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">During the Trials, you'll face off against a series of wizards who have all mastered a different element. If you can defeat them, you'll earn a powerful Forgotten Variant for your Arcana. Check out these boss guides from Maxroll:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/frost-queen-anahita-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Frost Queen Anahita</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/earth-lord-terrus-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Earth Lord Terrus</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/thunder-ace-voltran-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Thunder Ace Voltran</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/flame-empress-mitra-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Flame Empress Mitra</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/wind-sovereign-flo-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Wind Sovereign Flo</u></a></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Wizard of Legend 2 Zone Bosses</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-6-zone-boss-1749578632702.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Each zone in Wizard of Legend 2 culminates in a battle against a powerful boss, and the final stage ends in a fight against Hieronymus himself. Learn the boss's patterns, or check out tips and tricks to defeat them with Maxroll’s boss guides.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/akram-bahadur-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Jungle - Akram &amp; Bahadur</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/jabara-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Desert - Jabara</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/king-queen-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Castle - King &amp; Queen</u></a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/bosses/hieronymus-boss-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Final Zone - Wizard of Legend Hieronymus</u></a></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Wizard of Legend 2 Database</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/10/wol2-7-database-1749578960951.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/wizard-of-legend-2/database/arcana" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Maxroll's Wizard of Legend 2 Database</u></a> has information on all of the Arcanas, Relics, Runes, and Medallions. You can browse Arcana by type and learn about the Forgotten Variants available for each spell. Relics are broken down by category; we recommend you keep an eye out for Legendary Relics, which are made by obtaining all of the Relics from a set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Written by IGN staff with help from Maxroll.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>