<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.ign.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.ign.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:12:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Fire Red and Leaf Green Get Nintendo Switch Launch Next Week, Priced at $20 Each]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-fire-red-and-leaf-green-get-nintendo-switch-launch-next-week-priced-at-20-each</link>
            <guid>1441444</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-firered-version">Pokémon Fire Red</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-leafgreen-version">Leaf Green</a>, which originally launched for the Game Boy Advance back in 2004, will arrive on Nintendo Switch next week to celebrate the Pokémon series' 30th anniversary. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The games will become available on Switch shortly after this year's Pokémon Presents broadcast — The Pokémon Company's annual announcement showcase held on February 27 each year — that is expected to be a very important one indeed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, The Pokémon Company also now firmed up the timing of the Pokémon Presents stream, which will be held at 6am Pacific / 9am Eastern / 2pm UK. </p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">════════════<br>Pokémon FireRed and Pokémon LeafGreen confirmed for Nintendo Switch!<br> ═══════════<br>These download-exclusive titles will be available after the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonDay?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#PokemonDay</a> Presents presentation which begins Friday, February 27, 2026, at 6AM PST. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonFRLG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#PokemonFRLG</a> <a href="https://t.co/m8xEFOOjle" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/m8xEFOOjle</a></p>— Pokémon (@Pokemon) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pokemon/status/2024757682851233891?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 20, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Unlike other retro games available as part of the Nintendo Switch Online subscription, Fire Red and Leaf Green will be standalone releases — sold via the eShop for $19.99 each. Local wireless play for battling and trading will be possible, though online features are not supported.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, the game is expected to enable players to connect and transfer Pokémon into Pokémon Home, the franchise's cloud-based monster storage service.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for next week's Pokémon Presents broadcast, fans are anticipating that the franchise's 30th anniversary will be marked by some big announcements. We'll hear more about promising upcoming life sim spin-off <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-pokopia">Pokémon Pokopia</a> of course, but fans will be waiting to see if the series' long-awaited 10th generation of games and creatures also gets a showing.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Expectations for this year's celebrations are sky high, following last year's so-called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-teraleak-reveals-unannounced-games-seemingly-laying-out-franchises-major-releases-through-2030">Teraleak of Pokémon game development data</a> that spilled <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/a-year-on-from-the-teraleak-hackers-release-pokmon-legends-z-a-files-including-gameplay-videos-showing-cut-content-and-early-builds">various details of the franchise's highly-anticipated 10th generation of games</a>. Alongside a fresh roster of new Pokémon, fans expect these titles to feature new gameplay mechanics and procedurally-generated areas for the first time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Pokémon has already begun its 30th anniversary celebrations by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-fans-dissect-new-pokmon-sets-praise-eevee-but-say-mega-bloks-did-pikachu-better">revealing the franchise's first LEGO sets</a> (which also drop on February 27) and airing a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemons-super-bowl-ad-asks-lady-gaga-trevor-noah-and-more-whats-your-favorite-pokemon">Super Bowl spot featuring Lady Gaga singing the Jigglypuff song</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Join us next Friday for Pokémon Presents, which IGN will be reporting on live.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-fire-red-and-leaf-green-get-nintendo-switch-launch-next-week-priced-at-20-each]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riftbound TCG: 10 Brilliant Spiritforged Cards That Fans Should Consider Picking Up as Singles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/riftbound-tcg-10-brilliant-spiritforged-cards-that-fans-should-consider-picking-up-as-singles</link>
            <guid>1441321</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-league-of-legends-tcg-riftbound-has-posted-explosive-early-growth-since-launch-with-searches-surging-over-300">League of Legends trading card game</a> Riftbound's second set, titled Spiritforged, was released in the US on February 13. The newest expansion has been out in China for a couple of months now, and in the west for just over a week, sowe've seen a general picture of how the new cards are impacting the metagame thanks to two recent Regional Qualifiers in Fuzhou and Chengdu. With that being said, these are some of the best Spiritforged cards I think you should look into picking up now that the set is finally available.</p><p id="blood-money"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Blood Money">10. Blood Money</h2></p><div id="234747"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234747" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Blood Money</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">At uncommon, this card is relatively easy to pick up at an affordable price as a single. This is a super cheap and efficient early removal spell to help you stay on tempo, and you'd be hard pressed to see Yellow decks like Viktor, Herald of the Arcane not running three copies. </p></div><p id="card-sharp"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Card Sharp">9. Card Sharp</h2></p><div id="234748"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234748" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Card Sharp</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Card Sharp is pretty versatile. There are a few Power hungry decks with Spiritforged, so being able to offset some of that cost with the Gold generated from Card Sharp and pressure with a 3 MIght body is worth considering. </p></div><p id="not-so-fast"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Not So Fast">8. Not So Fast</h2></p><div id="234749"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234749" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Not So Fast</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Thanks to the <a href="https://riftbound.leagueoflegends.com/en-us/news/rules-and-releases/riftbound-spiritforged-faq/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recent errata to refexive triggers</a>, nerfing cards like <a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/product/653046/riftbound-league-of-legends-trading-card-game-origins-icathian-rain" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Icathian Rain</a>, Not So Fast got significantly better. Before, you'd only be able to counter just one instance of damage, but now you can just counter the entire spell with Not So Fast. Definitely keep this card on your radar if you like Green decks. </p></div><p id="bellows-breath"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Bellows Breath">7. Bellows Breath</h2></p><div id="234750"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234750" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bellows Breath</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The new Repeat mechanic offers a more dynamic way to interact with opponents. Bellows Breath is one of these, being able to clear a Battlefield of smaller units in the early game. </p></div><p id="trinity-force"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Trinity Force">6. Trinity Force</h2></p><div id="234751"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234751" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Trinity Force</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One of my favorite new equipments from the set, Trinity Force is one of the few cards that allow you to store extra points. I can see this making waves in Master Yi, Wuju Bladesman, as his Legend ability buffs defending units. In the Origins meta, the deck was great at holding to score points, and looks to be the same situation with Spiritforged. </p></div><p id="piercing-light"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Piercing Light">5. Piercing Light</h2></p><div id="234752"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234752" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Piercing Light</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Like Bellows Breath, this can be an early game removal spell for tempo, or an easy two-for-one later on. Kai'Sa, Daughter of the Void typically ran two to three copies of <a href="https://zdcs.link/z64yqj?object_uuid=9f03421a-f93c-43ce-a309-393e5d0daab0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Falling Star</a>, so I can see this finding a home in that deck too. </p></div><p id="ferrous-forerunner"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Ferrous Forerunner">4. Ferrous Forerunner</h2></p><div id="234753"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234753" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ferrous Forerunner</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Ferrous Forerunner is a big body that continues to pressure your opponent even after it dies. Doing its best <a href="https://zdcs.link/aA85lL?object_uuid=9f03421a-f93c-43ce-a309-393e5d0daab0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wurmcoil Engine</a> impression, this guy will spit out two 3 Might Mech tokens upon death, allowing you to maintain your board presence. </p></div><p id="called-shot"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Called Shot">3. Called Shot</h2></p><div id="234754"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234754" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Called Shot</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if Called Shot had 1 Energy cost, I would consider extremely powerful. At 0 Energy <em>and </em>sporting the Repeat mechanic has convinced me it's the best draw and filter spell in the game. With a ton of ways to generate Gold tokens to help pay Power costs, this card is positioned to be seen in every Purple deck. </p></div><p id="guardian-angel"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Guardian Angel">2. Guardian Angel</h2></p><div id="234755"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234755" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Guardian Angel</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Guardian Angel is essentially copies four through 6 of <a href="https://zdcs.link/QLpyVX?object_uuid=9f03421a-f93c-43ce-a309-393e5d0daab0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Zhonya's Hourlgass</a>, which has the same effect. This, however, is an equipment, so it comes with a +1 Might buff and costs a Power to equip to a unit. Master Yi,  Wuju Bladesman is still poised to be a contender with Spiritforged, and this card is one reason for that. </p></div><p id="ezrea-prodigy"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Ezrea, Prodigy">1. Ezreal, Prodigy</h2></p><div id="234756"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234756" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ezreal, Prodigy</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While Draven, Glorious Executioner is easily the strongest deck in the Spiritforged meta, many lists are playing Ezreal, Prodigy, which is the best card in the set for my money. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Purple is undoubtedly very strong, and Ezreal's effect allows you to filter through your deck and a lot cards early, and fits into a few other archetypes nicely. </p></div><p id="where-to-buy-spiritforged"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Where to Buy Spiritforged">Where to Buy Riftbound: Spiritforged</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you prefer the rush of cracking packs hoping to pull your favorite chase cards, below are the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/league-of-legends-riftbound-tcg-spiritforged-where-to-buy-2026">Spiritforged sealed products available for purchase</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like Origins before it, the second set is already sold out on Riot's online storefront, but you can order through TCGplayer at pretty high markups if you're desperate to secure the goods.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Myles Obenza is a freelance writer for IGN. Follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mylesobenza.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mylesobenza.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/riftbound-tcg-10-brilliant-spiritforged-cards-that-fans-should-consider-picking-up-as-singles]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>