<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 19:17:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Clears 500,000 Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500000-copies-sold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500-000-copies-sold.1174044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-clears-500000-copies-sold<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">An auspicious start for the Expedition.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, the debut RPG from Sandfall Interactive, is already off to a strong start. The studio announced today that Expedition 33 has hit a sales milestone of 500,000 copies sold.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A milestone for us, reached sooner than we'd ever imagined," the team said in a post on <a href="https://x.com/expedition33/status/1915777375834452273" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a>. "Thank you all."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 went live yesterday, April 24, across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. It's also a day-one Game Pass game, and despite launching a few days after the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-finally-revealed-in-first-look-gameplay-and-its-out-today">shadow-drop of The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, the RPG still seems to be making waves. When Oblivion dropped, Clair Obscur's publisher Kepler Interactive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-publisher-acknowledges-the-barbenheimer-energy-of-releasing-the-same-week-as-oblivion-remastered">even jokingly compared it to "Barbenheimer."</a> The comparison, as it turns out, has been fairly accurate.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Developed by the newly formed studio Sandfall Interactive, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is a turn-based RPG that takes heavy inspiration from the genre classics, from Final Fantasy to Persona. It follows a crew of Expeditioners in a fractured, post-apocalytpic world where every year, a giant being called The Paintress etches a new number and erases anyone older than it. The members of the Expedition, the next up on the block, have one goal in mind: travel to the ends of the continent and destroy the Paintress, ensuring she can never paint death again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The reception of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has been widely positive, sitting at <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/clair-obscur-expedition-33/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">92 on MetaCritic</a> and <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/18026/clair-obscur-expedition-33" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">91 on OpenCritic</a>, putting it alongside Split Fiction and Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 as some of the year's most lauded games thus far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review">IGN's 9/10 review of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, our reviewer described it as a "modern RPG classic," wearing its inspirations on its sleeve and painting itself into the pantheon of great RPGs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're starting the adventure this weekend, or maybe already have, be sure to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Tips_-_Things_Clair_Obscur_Doesn't_Tell_You">check out our tips for the important things to know before going into Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TSA Warns That You Shouldn't Try to Fly With a Call of Duty Zombies Monkey Bomb Figurine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine.1174038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tsa-warns-that-you-shouldnt-try-to-fly-with-a-call-of-duty-zombies-monkey-bomb-figurine<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking to pick up some video game-inspired replicas or figurines while traveling, you might want to think twice about bringing anything that looks like a Call of Duty weapon in your baggage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's the takeaway, at least, from a recent post by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) discussing prohibited items. As spotted by <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/call-of-duty/call-of-duty-fan-runs-into-tsa-by-trying-to-take-monkey-bomb-on-plane-3185682/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dexerto</a>, the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo?fbid=1202998258156542&amp;set=a.407732524349790&amp;locale=en_GB" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TSA account on Facebook</a> highlighted a replica figurine of the Monkey Bomb from Call of Duty's Zombies mode that officers at Boston Logan International Airport found in a checked bag.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/493273042-1202998264823208-4830061258408916107-n-1745593633126.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Transportation Security Administration - TSA / Facebook.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Monkey Bomb, or Cymbal Monkey, has appeared in numerous Call of Duty games, from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-world-at-war">World at War</a> through to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a>. This particular figurine is meant to be a controller, with its hands outstretched to cradle your favorite game controller. But it's also a replica of a weapon that, well, looks like it has dynamite and cables strapped to it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This monkey may rack up points in a game, but in real life, leave the gear for your loadout screen, not your baggage," the post read. "Replica weapons and explosives, no matter how cool or collectible, aren't allowed in either carry-on or checked baggage."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The TSA website does also go into detail about <a href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/security-screening/whatcanibring/items/toy-guns-and-weapons" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prohibited toy weapons</a>, including "squirt guns, Nerf guns, toy swords, or other items that resemble realistic firearms or weapons." Maybe that's some decent advertising, at least, for the quality of the Monkey Bomb replica statue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's good to be aware of if you're heading to a convention or place where you might pick up some merch. Whether a monkey figurine or a set of <a href="https://x.com/TSA/status/1744728996741537919" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Naruto-themed throwing knives</a>, the TSA warns that it prohbiits any item in checked or carry-on baggage if they believe it poses a security threat, even if it's a replica.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Transportation Security Administration - TSA / Facebook.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>