<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:59:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: Coke Zero, Doritos, Borderlands 4, and Pokémon Legends Z-A Preorders]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-june-25-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-coke-zero-doritos-borderlands-4-and-pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-preorders.1228497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a tasty one today. Coke Zero is down to just $6.64 for a 12-pack over on Amazon, and you don’t even need to commit to Subscribe &amp; Save to cash in. If your snack drawer’s looking thin, there’s also a Doritos variety pack ready to restock the goods—with all the classics and some spicy curveballs too.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Today's Deals</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then there’s gaming. New Borderlands 4 preorders are live, Pokémon Legends: Z-A is up for both Switch generations, and Fanatical’s still running that stellar $25.49 price for Lies of P and Overture with the FANATICAL15 code. Don’t forget the new Donkey Kong and Pauline Amiibo either — it unlocks gold tiles and looks awesome on a shelf.</p><p id="coke-zero-sugar-12-pack"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Coke Zero Sugar 12 Pack">Coke Zero Sugar 12 Pack</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223557"><div id="223557" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Coke Zero Sugar 12 Pack</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Use on-site coupon with the subscribe and save discount</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if you change your mind and don't want to subscribe and save, you can still get this great deal on Coke Zero when you purchase. It's Coke with zero sugar, and there's 12 cans that you can drink out of and recycle (thumbs up).</p></div><p id="doritos-variety-pack"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Doritos Variety Pack">Doritos Variety Pack</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223558"><div id="223558" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Doritos Variety Pack</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Get that snack drawer stuffed up with this Doritos variety pack. There's heatwave and original as standard with some of their more novel bags of chips, and it's also on a subscribe and save deal too.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nintendo Switch 2 in Stock at AliExpress</h2></div><div catalogid="36a3b9f5-2ced-42c2-8fd0-f4fa3b4e7cdd" id="223120"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're still on the hunt for a Switch 2 console, here's an opportunity you might want to consider. The <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yDG7P?object_uuid=7785d645-aaac-4c4a-982a-432b23396048&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch 2 Mario Kart World Tour Console Bundle</a> is currently available for $547.90 with free delivery from a local US-based warehouse.  This is a genuine gaming console that has been imported from Hong Kong. Region locking is determined by your account, not by console, so all of these systems will play in the US without any problems. You'll also be able to select English as your default language just like any console you buy here. AliExpress offers a return window but the length varies depending on the item. These consoles all ship locally from the United States and usually arrive within one week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Note that although the console is region unlocked and works fine anywhere, the Mario Kart World Tour digital game voucher is region locked to Hong Kong. One of the reviews, however, mentions a workaround:</p></div><p id="donkey-kong-and-pauline-amiibo-preor"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Donkey Kong and Pauline Amiibo Preor">Donkey Kong and Pauline Amiibo Preorder</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223571"><div id="223571" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Donkey Kong and Pauline Amiibo Preorder</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This Amiibo will unlock a new dress for Pauline and give players access to explosive gold tiles in Donkey Kong Bananza. Plus it looks awesome and you need to collect all Amiibos ever, unless you don't. That's fine too.</p></div><p id="pokmon-legends-z-a-switch-2"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 2)">Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 2)</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223572"><div id="223572" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 2)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This is going to be the definitive edition of POkémon Legends: Z-A thanks to it's 4K 60 FPS gameplay performancce. I'm sure they'll be more cheeky features revealed closer to launch, but if you have a Switch 2 grab this version.</p></div><p id="pokmon-legends-z-a-switch-1"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 1)">Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 1)</h2></p><div id="223573" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Legends: Z-A (Switch 1)</h3></p></div><p id="tunise-rechargeable-portable-neck-fa"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Tunise Rechargeable Portable Neck Fa">Tunise Rechargeable Portable Neck Fan</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223570"><div id="223570" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Tunise Rechargeable Portable Neck Fan</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Use code 8Z2BHHVD at checkout</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a fan that you don't have to hold because it sits comfortably around your neck. This is such a cool and handy product for under $15, especially if you're like me and get warm at the thought of some sunshine.
</p></div><p id="symphonic-journeys-pokmon-red-blu"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blu">Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blue - IGN Exclusive Vinyl</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223366"><div id="223366" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blue - IGN Exclusive Vinyl</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Symphonic Journeys: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-version/walkthrough">Pokémon Red &amp; Blue</a> is now up for preorder in a stunning IGN-exclusive Fire Red vinyl variant. This 1xLP release features orchestrated arrangements of classic tracks like Pallet Town, Gym Leader Battle, and the Pokémon Center theme, performed by the renowned Budapest Scoring orchestra.</p></div><p id="lies-of-p-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Lies of P (Steam)">Lies of P (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223559"><div id="223559" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lies of P (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">We gave Lies of P a solid 8/10, so there's no reason to not pick up this absolute banger for $25.49. Just make sure to use the discount code FANATICAL 15 to get the full deal.</p></div><p id="lies-of-p-overture"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Lies of P: Overture">Lies of P: Overture</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223560"><div id="223560" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lies of P: Overture</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Overture also got an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lies-of-p-overture-review">8/10 from us</a> because it does exactly what it says on the tin, gives us more Lies of P. It's an excellent expansion that adds a whole lot more to a game that was already great.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Borderlands 4 PC Preorders</h2></p><div><div id="223561" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Borderlands 4 Standard Edition (Steam)</h3></p></div><div id="223562" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Borderlands 4 Deluxe Edition (Steam)</h3></p></div><div id="223563" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Borderlands 4 Super Deluxe Edition (Steam)</h3></p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">September 12th is closer than you think, so get Borderlands 4 preordered from Green Man Gaming and secure your preload on Steam. Randy Pitchford reckons that it's co-op  mode will be <a href="https://in.ign.com/borderlands-4/234678/news/borderlands-4-gearbox-ceo-claims-that-the-co-op-mode-will-be-the-best-ever-and-reveals-that-players" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"The best ever", </a>too.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon TCG Classic</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Sam's Club Pokémon TCG Classic deal is back, and it's massively undercutting other big box retailers and the secondary market. Just for comparrison, the top four cards from this set, Charizard, Blastoise, Venusaur and Mewtwo, are worth the same price as this discounted offer. This deal is well worth it and should be snapped up as soon as possible.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon TCG Stock Updates</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As usual we're looking at over-inflated pricing at big box stores, but it's a dependable source of sealed product for trainers looking to add to their collections or rip open boosters. Although we'd recommend checking out secondary market prices first, as big retailers are now regularly selling over market value now too. I've already done the hard work for you:</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TCG Player and eBay Pokémon Sealed Product</h2></p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">The Most Expensive Japanese Black Bolt White Flare Cards</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The most expensive cards from Pokémon TCG's Black Bolt and White Flare sets are already commanding serious prices in Japan. Top of the list are the Special Illustration Rares of Zekrom ex and Reshiram ex, both featuring intricate, hand-drawn artwork and fetching well over ¥20,000 (around $130–$150 USD) on the secondary market. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also climbing fast are the new BWR (Black White Rare) cards and the full-art Victini promos from the themed file sets. With stunning clay and knitted art styles also making their debut, collectors are pushing prices up across the board, especially for low-population, high-style secret rares.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">This Weeks Pokémon TCG Crashers and Climbers</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Black Bolt and White Flare wrapping up the Scarlet &amp; Violet era, all eyes are now on what’s next—and Mega Evolution is officially back. The Japanese Championships 2025 confirmed <em>MEGA Symphonia</em> and <em>MEGA Brave</em> as the first entries in the new Mega Expansion Packs, launching August 1 in Japan. These sets reintroduce Mega Evolution ex cards in a powerful new form, now Stage 2 Pokémon worth 3 Prize Cards when knocked out. Cards like Mega Gardevoir ex, Mega Venusaur ex, and Mega Lucario ex are leading the charge, and collectors are already snapping up classic Mega cards in anticipation of their return to the spotlight.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">MTG Live Preorders </h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Preorders are now live for Magic: The Gathering’s next major set, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-edge-of-eternities-preorder-guide">Edge of Eternities</a>, ahead of its August 1 release. You can lock in Play Booster Boxes, Bundles, Commander Decks, and Collector Boosters, with prices already dipping below MSRP in some spots. With some chunky lore, borderless cards, and premium packaging teased, now’s a good time to grab your picks before stock tightens closer to launch. </p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">MTG Stock Update</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's the usual suspects of insanely priced boosters such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2020/01/07/magic-the-gathering-exclusive-reveal-check-out-taranika-akroan-veteran-theros-beyond-death">Theros Beyond Death</a>, but there's also some discounts such as 9% off a box of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-cards-available">Assassin's Creed</a> collector boosters and a massive 32% off a booster box of<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-lord-of-the-rings-tales-of-middle-earth-impressions"> Lord of the Rings set boosters</a>.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">MTG Final Fantasy Chase Cards</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I was going to say how insane <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-cards-spike-thanks-to-new-final-fantasy-synergies">MTG Final Fantasy's</a> popularity is, but it's completely understandable. Whilst sealed stock is going up in value and becoming harder to get, there's plenty of option for the most in-demand cards for your deck or collection.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">MTG Aetherdrift Chase Cards</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em></em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-most-valuable-aetherdrift-cards">Aetherdrift</a> is one of Magic: The Gathering’s more experimental sets, blending high-speed vehicle mechanics with a bold visual style. Released as part of the Universes Beyond series, it introduced new archetypes and card types designed to shake up both casual and competitive formats.
</p><p id="3-months-free-audible"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="3 Months Free Audible">3 Months for $0.99 Audible Deal</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223445"><div id="223445" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>3 Months Audible Premium Plus for $0.99</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Audible’s doing that 99c a month deal again for Premium Plus, and it’s a steal. Amazon Prime Members get three months free, so make sure to check for an active subscription before looking for this deal. You get three audiobooks to keep, full access to the big library, and it works even if you’ve had a sub before as long as it’s not active now. I just logged in, saw the banner, and grabbed it. <em>Sunrise on the Reaping</em> is already in my library, and I’m eyeing that massive new Sanderson one next. Less than three bucks for all that? Easy win.</p></div><p id="3-months-free-kindle-unlimited"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="3 Months Free Kindle Unlimited">3 Months Free Kindle Unlimited</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223446"><div id="223446" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>3 Months Free Kindle Unlimited</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve never really stuck with audiobooks before, but this Kindle Unlimited deal finally got me into them properly. Right now you can get three months free if you’ve got Prime, and it works on your phone or tablet, not just a Kindle. I gave it a go, downloaded a couple of books, and now I’ve actually started finishing them while I’m out walking or doing stuff around the house. It’s made getting through my backlog way easier and I didn’t have to pay a thing to try it. If you’ve been on the fence, this is a solid excuse to dive in.</p></div><p id="sound-explosion-software-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Sound Explosion Software Bundle">Sound Explosion Software Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223447"><div id="223447" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sound Explosion Software Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve ever needed music or sound effects for a game, video, podcast, or anything creative, this Humble Bundle is ridiculous value. For $20, you get over 100 royalty-free audio packs covering everything from cinematic hits and ambient drones to meme sounds and upbeat pop tracks. I grabbed it just to have a library ready for whatever project pops up, and it’s already saved me time and cash. You can pay as little as a buck if you just want to check it out, and part of what you pay goes to charity too. Easy win if you ever mess with editing or content creation.</p></div><p id="alienware-aw3423dwf-curved-qd-oled-g"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Alienware AW3423DWF Curved QD-OLED G">Alienware AW3423DWF Curved QD-OLED Gaming Monitor</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223444"><div id="223444" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Alienware AW3423DWF Curved QD-OLED Gaming Monitor</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Alienware 34-inch QD-OLED is down to $649.99, and it’s an absolute beast. You’re getting a 165Hz refresh rate, deep blacks, punchy colours, and a super sharp 21:9 curved display that makes everything from games to edits look incredible. It’s fast, smooth, and built like a tank with FreeSync support and a proper creator mode if you need colour accuracy. It even comes with a 3-year burn-in warranty. For this price, it’s hard to beat.</p></div><p id="the-legend-of-zelda-master-sword-by"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="The Legend of Zelda Master Sword by ">The Legend of Zelda Master Sword by Proplica</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223448"><div id="223448" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Legend of Zelda Master Sword by Proplica</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The $200 Master Sword from Tamashii Nations is a full-size 41-inch replica with sound, rumble, and music from eight Zelda games built in. Press the buttons on the hilt to cycle through tracks from <em>Ocarina of Time</em>, <em>Breath of the Wild</em>, <em>Tears of the Kingdom</em>, and more. It comes with a sheath, a stand, and needs two AA batteries. Stock is limited, so if you're in move fast.</p></div><p id="monster-hunter-wilds-ps5"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Monster Hunter Wilds (PS5)">Monster Hunter Wilds PS5 and Xbox Series X</h2></p><div><div id="223368" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds (PS5)</h3></p></div><div id="223369" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds Xbox Series X</h3></p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> has hit its lowest price yet for the standard physical edition on PS5 and Xbox Series X at just $55.99, down from $69.99. This latest entry takes the series into a fully voiced narrative, dynamic biomes, and crossplay multiplayer. If you’ve been waiting for a price drop to jump into the Forbidden Lands, this is a solid time to grab a copy.</p><p id="symphonic-journeys-pokmon-red-blu"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blu">Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blue - IGN Exclusive Vinyl</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223366"><div id="223366" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Symphonic Journeys Pokémon Red &amp; Blue - IGN Exclusive Vinyl</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Symphonic Journeys: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-version/walkthrough">Pokémon Red &amp; Blue</a> is now up for preorder in a stunning IGN-exclusive Fire Red vinyl variant. This 1xLP release features orchestrated arrangements of classic tracks like Pallet Town, Gym Leader Battle, and the Pokémon Center theme, performed by the renowned Budapest Scoring orchestra.</p></div><p id="elden-ring-nightreign-official-strat"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Elden Ring Nightreign Official Strat">Elden Ring Nightreign Official Strategy Guide</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223371"><div id="223371" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Elden Ring Nightreign Official Strategy Guide</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The official strategy guide for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-review">Elden Ring: Nightreign</a> is now up for preorder, with a hardcover release set for September 30, 2025. Created by Future Press, this companion book dives deep into the game’s new roguelike multiplayer systems, class mechanics, and shifting world of Limveld. You’ll get detailed Nightfarer builds, bestiary entries, system breakdowns, and beautifully illustrated maps plus bonus art prints and lore. Sounds like a bargain to me.</p></div><p id="donkey-kong-bananza"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Donkey Kong Bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223370"><div id="223370" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Donkey Kong Bananza</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> is available now for preorder on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-review">Nintendo Switch 2</a> at $69.99, with a release date set for July 17. This all-new 3D platformer brings DK back into the spotlight with a full physical edition and gameplay reminiscent of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a>. If you've been waiting for the return of classic <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-is-officially-the-best-selling-game-on-amazon-right-now">Donkey Kong</a> exploration with modern polish, this looks like the one to watch.</p></div><p id="amfilm-switch-2-tempered-glass-scree"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="amFilm Switch 2 Tempered Glass Scree">amFilm Switch 2 Tempered Glass Screen</h2></p><div catalogid="bac8eeb1-cb76-4ce5-8784-e2fb014e64c5" id="223372"><div id="223372" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>amFilm Switch 2 Tempered Glass Screen</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">amFilm’s 3-pack tempered glass screen protector for the <a href="https://in.ign.com/nintendo-switch-2/234505/news/nintendo-switch-2-third-party-games-are-reportedly-not-selling-much-when-compared-to-first-party-tit" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nintendo Switch 2</a> (7.9") is down to $7.99 and includes everything you need for a smooth installation. The 0.3mm ultra-clear glass offers 9H scratch resistance, touchscreen sensitivity, and an oleophobic coating to reduce smudges. It also comes with a alignment frame, making it easier to apply without bubbles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 25, 2025 6:20 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-june-25-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crisol: Theater of Idols Is a Horror FPS Influenced by Spanish Folklore]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/crisol-theater-of-idols-is-a-horror-fps-influenced-by-spanish-folklore</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crisol-theater-of-idols-is-a-horror-fps-influenced-by-spanish-folklore.1228410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">All your weapons here are plasma rifles, if you think about it.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Crisol: Theater of Idols aims to blend Bioshock with Resident Evil-style gameplay in a horror FPS influenced by classical Spanish folklore. I crawled through abandoned streets, popping zombie-like enemies with guns that used my blood for bullets, ducking in and out of derelict storefronts looking for the ever-reliable genre staple bolt cutters, and dodging powerful enemies along the way. While Crisol showed more to set itself apart from stalwarts in the genre during my hands-on demo, its weapon designs and distinct aesthetic in particular left me interested to see more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Exploring a horrific, reimagined version of Spain called Hispania, Crisol’s world and character designs blew me away – especially the guns. Here, your blood is your health <em><strong>and</strong></em> your ammo, so reloading each gun triggers a spine-tingling reaction like when your handgun’s handle bristles with little needles, drawing blood from your hand, or when needles stick out of the base of your double-barrelled shotgun’s barrel, waiting to trade health for survival.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This push-and-pull forces you to keep tabs on both to keep yourself from wasting either and landing yourself in a sticky situation. You can pick up healing syringes to help restore ammo, but Crisol also encourages you to drain the blood from dead bystanders, killed by your mysterious foes, to heal and reload.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Crisol also encourages you to drain the blood from dead bystanders, killed by your mysterious foes, to heal and reload.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The gun designs themselves are cool too; gilded with red accents, they add a gothic pop of color that stands out, but doesn’t clash with the environments I saw in my short demo. The environments, on the other hand, didn’t have nearly as much character to them. While the trailer promises some pretty cool-looking set pieces, the dark streets of Hispania I wandered didn’t offer much deviation from the norm. That’s surprising considering just how well-designed the enemies and guns are.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Crisol: Theater of Idols Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Crisol doesn’t waste any time throwing you into the action. Within seconds of picking up the controller, lurching, puppet-like enemies stumbled towards me. Low light revealed unsettling details in their mask-like faces as they approached, eventually collapsing under my gunfire. Each enemy I encountered (or at least each one I was able to kill) reacted based on which part of their body I shot; crawling headless after I kneecapped them, and popped their heads. Both of the blood-soaked firearms I tried have an older feel to them, more like the oomph of the original BioShock than the punchy crack of the guns found in most contemporary shooters, though Crisol’s trailer (and weapon wheel) promise a seemingly diverse arsenal of sanguine shooters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After making my way through a few city blocks, absorbing blood from dead bodies and popping zombie-like critters blocking my path, I came across a locked gate with a winch. Locked by a padlock with a chain – classic! Like clockwork, I set out looking for the bolt cutters I’d found in half a dozen survival horror games before. But before I could start looking, some kind of gigantic, arcane cyborg – a towering mass of blood-soaked bones and clanking machinery with a mask of a woman’s face crying blood – picked me up and tossed me around.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/24/03-1750729005759.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The beast chased me down the street to the window (conveniently) of the hardware store, but couldn’t touch me once I dove in. Safe for now, I grabbed the bolt cutters from the back storeroom and every coin in the cash register and set out to snip the chains that kept me from safety. But the beast was back at my heels practically the moment my feet hit the dirt road, hurling threats my way as it hunted me down.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I hope Crisol doubles down on these two different kinds of survival horror to produce layers of tension between the blood-for-bullets combat and high-stakes stealth in the full release.&nbsp;</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Crouching to minimize the noise I made, I found a shortcut through a fish store, making a bunch of noise at one end before cutting through the store, snipping the chains, and cranking away at the winch to open the gate in front of me. I heard the creature thudding towards me, and just pushed away in the quick-time event faster, hoping I could squeeze through instead of running back to cover. The gate opened with just enough time to spare; I rushed out of the courtyard to safety, the gate snapping shut before my assailant could catch me.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/24/07-1750729018828.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">This puzzle-like stealth section, though very simple, added a lot to my demo. I can see the ways this could evolve into a tense blend of stealth and shooting if I eventually need to dodge bigger enemies at the same time as popping the smaller, stoppable ones with my sanguine arsenal. I hope Crisol doubles down on these two different kinds of survival horror to produce layers of tension between the blood-for-bullets combat and high-stakes stealth in the full release. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While I enjoyed my demo well enough, I felt like I hadn’t seen anything new beyond the Bloodborne-like, health-for-ammo trade-off and some really cool weapon and enemy designs. I’m sure puzzles and progression will begin to differentiate themselves from Resident Evil as the game gets more complex. But I didn’t get to see much of that in this demo, which was clearly very early in the campaign. Still, I have a feeling Crisol: Theater of Idols will be worth checking out for its distinct take on survival horror with a Spanish flair.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/crisol-theater-of-idols-is-a-horror-fps-influenced-by-spanish-folklore]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>