<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:46:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Patch 5.0.0 Arrives With an Incoming Message From High Command That's Already Got Players Worried]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-500-arrives-with-an-incoming-message-from-high-command-thats-already-got-players-worried</link>
            <guid>1370209</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Arrowhead has released <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> update 5.0.0, which makes big balance changes that actually raise weapon damage — but there’s also an incoming message from High Command that has the community worried.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Update 5.5.0 arrives alongside the jungle-themed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-finally-getting-a-minigun-and-other-fan-requested-weapons-as-part-of-the-jungle-themed-python-commandos-warbond">Python Commandos Warbond</a>, which adds a number of fan-requested weapons including a minigun.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But it’s the incoming message from High Command — an in-universe tease from Arrowhead to the Helldivers 2 community on what’s in store — that has raised eyebrows.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Super Earth has detected strange signals from previously unmonitored worlds on the Galactic map,” the message reads. “The Ministry of Intelligence is investigating the source of the signals. Helldivers, be vigilant and hold the high ground.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What does this mean? Players aren’t sure, although speculation is pointing to something Illuminate related, given the mention of “unmonitored worlds.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the patch, it makes a number of fixes, including for audio issues, XP modifiers, and several crashes, as well as more optimizations and improvements. The balancing changes raise weapon damage, and there are much-needed fixes to weapon FOV. The patch notes, courtesy of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/491583942944621274" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, are below.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Helldivers 2: Python Commandos Premium Warbond Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In other Helldivers news, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fast-furious-justin-lin-to-direct-helldivers-movie">we finally have confirmation that Justin Lin is set to direct the upcoming Helldivers 2 movie</a>. Lin is best known for his work on a number of Fast &amp; Furious movies, and was the director of the series from The Fast and the Furious: Tokyo Drift in 2006 until Fast &amp; Furious 6 in 2013.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Helldivers 2 Update 5.5.0 patch notes:</h2><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Balancing</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>General changes</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Decreased ergonomics penalty on magnifying scopes weapon attachments</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The intent is to make magnifying scopes more a matter of preference by decreasing the penalty they impose on a weapon's ergonomics (low ergonomics makes the weapons muzzle follow the crosshair slower).</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Some of the Pistol ammo balance update</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The intent with this change is to make some of the pistol rounds weapons more effective after the last pistol ammo re-balance that did make them more of a close range weapon.</li><li>The pistol rounds re-balance general intent is to make them more effective at close range while not more effective at long range then for example assault or marksman rifles</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>2x Tube Red Dot </strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased ergonomic modifier from (-3) to (-1)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>4x Combat Scope</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased ergonomic modifier from (-6) to (-2)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>10x Sniper Scope </strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased ergonomic modifier from (-9) to (-4)</li><li><strong>APW-1 Anti-Materiel Rifle </strong>is also effected by this change so it will get an increased ergonomics from 26 to 31</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Primary weapons</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>SMG-37 Defender</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 100 to 110</li><li>Increased durable damage from 20 to 22</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>SMG-32 Reprimand</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 135 to 140</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>M7S SMG</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 80 to 90</li><li>Increased durable damage from 16 to 18</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>VG-70 Variable</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased durable damage 20 to 23</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>M90A Shotgun</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased durable damage 15 to 20</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Sidearms weapons</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>P-2 Peacemaker</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 95 to 100</li><li>Increased durable damage 30 to 32</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>P-113 Verdict</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 135 to 140</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>M6C/SOCOM Pistol</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage from 110 to 125</li><li>Increased durable damage from 25 to 28</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Enemies</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>War strider</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased force strength on grenade explosion from 50 to 30</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Bile Spewer</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased force strength on artillery explosion from 50 to 30</li><li>Decreased force impulse on artillery explosion from 60 to 40</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Stalker</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Decreased force strength from 40 to 35 when a tongue attack hits the player</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">(<strong>Force strength</strong> is the value that decides if a player or enemy should stagger or ragdoll.)</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gameplay</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Keybind options for quick weapon function:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>New, unbound keybind options have been added for quickly swapping weapon functions (like changing fire modes or ammo).</li><li>The intent is to give players better ease of use, especially for weapons with multiple ammo types like the Halt, Autocannon, and the new "One Two" AR.    </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Updated First Person View (FPV)</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>We updated how First Person View (FPV) works with the intention of improving the aiming experience across different FOV settings (Field of view). </li><li>The intent is that the size and distance of the scope will be more consistent with different FOV settings.</li><li>We also updated how ergonomics works in FPV with the intent to make it more responsive.</li><li>Fixed instances of flickering textures in various city locations</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Fixes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Crash Fixes &amp; Softlocks</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a rare crash that would occur when combat music would start</li><li>Fixed a rare crash that could occur during 'Nuke Nursery' mission</li><li>Fixed crash after hotjoining a game that just started where the existing players are using certain stratagems</li><li>Fixed a rare crash when enemies would fall through the ground</li><li>Fix rare crash on mission load</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Weapons &amp; Stratagem Fixes</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue with the BR-14 Adjudicator, when aiming with the 10x scope on 200 m setting which would cause the model to disappear  </li><li>Fixed a visual issue on VG-70 Variable during the reload animation when aiming down sights</li><li>Fixed a torso clipping issue with the CE-07 Demolition Specialist armor</li><li>Fixed pump-shotguns sometimes not showing a new shell being inserted on reload</li><li>PLAS-45 Epoch now correctly zooms in ADS mode, just like any other support weapon</li><li>Fixed display related to no ammo being shown for Infinite Ammo weapons </li><li>Fixed the VO (Voice Over) line for “no ammo” being played after pressing reload whilst using Infinite Ammo weapons</li><li>Fixed a small bug where supply packs were giving ammo without consuming a charge when dropped</li><li>Fixed a bug that locks stratagems after drowning while holding that stratagem ball</li><li>Fixed the red glow that would happen if the player would empty one or two magazines with MG-206 Heavy Machine Gun, M-105 Stalwart or MG-43 Machine Gun</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Enemies</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Factory Striders will no longer be launched to sky erratically when dying</li><li>Hellpods that hit Factory Striders will no longer remain in the air after the enemy dies</li><li>War Striders now detonate mines</li><li>Enemy presence around Cognitive Disruptor Towers is now cleared from the mini-map when the objective is completed</li><li>Chargers no longer speed up when exiting charge</li><li>Fixed Rupture Warriors getting stuck below Sentries</li><li>Added a medium-armored weak spot to the vents on the backside of the Bunker, AA, and Mortar emplacements. This was done so these structures behave similarly to other comparable defenses..</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Miscellaneous Fixes</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed the terrain not being affected by explosions and the Entrenchment Tool (PS5 only)</li><li>Fixed a bug where the lights were missing/flickering on the Orbital Gatling</li><li>Fixed a thumbnail glitch in the Acquisition Center menu</li><li>Cryo-pods no longer clip into the Engineering Bay  when playing the ship arrival cutscene</li><li>Fixed an armor gap affecting CE-27 Ground Beaker and CW-9 White Wolf whilst using the 'Draw!' emote</li><li>The UI will no longer show inaccurate objective info on the Mission Summary screen if the host has left the game</li><li>Fixed a bug whilst joining a non-host in a cross-play lobby.</li><li>Fixed the NPC technician’s neck sticking through their shirt</li><li>Mini-map fog of war effect while exploring caves no longer persists between missions</li><li>Soon-to-be Helldivers will no longer be stopped from progressing the tutorial if they die in the flag room</li><li>Fixed issue where the automaton grinder sludge would be affected by weathering even though it's sealed behind glass</li><li>Fixed an issue where a missile inside the Destroyer’s hangar was misaligned. This dangerous act of asymmetry has been corrected. The undemocratic ship operator responsible for this disgraceful display of inefficiency has been promptly re-educated in a high-orbit correctional facility. Glory to the Office of Corrective Deployment!</li><li>Helldivers will no longer be locked out of the GATER when trying to get into the driver's seat simultaneously</li><li>Fixed a bug with missing haptics when a controller disconnects or reconnects</li><li>Fixed an issue on a command bunker where there was a lack of collision</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Optimizations</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Optimized lights on Automaton VFX</li><li>Optimized physics of rock assets throughout the game to improve performance</li><li>Improved the way environmental effects such as sandstorms, blizzards, and acid storms apply their status effects for reduced impact on performance</li><li>Improved ADS weapon placement and behavior </li><li>Reduced the amount of camera clipping on weapons</li><li>Fixed texture details used for weapons while aiming down sights</li><li>Improved depth of field when ADS and whilst scopes are zoomed in</li><li>Fix for textures sometimes appearing low resolution even when memory is available (PC only)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-500-arrives-with-an-incoming-message-from-high-command-thats-already-got-players-worried]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid 4 Remake Would Be 'Quite a Challenge,' Says Konami's MGS Series Producer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-4-remake-would-be-quite-a-challenge-says-konamis-mgs-series-producer</link>
            <guid>1370206</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://realsound.jp/tech/2025/11/post-2232566.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>recent Japanese interview</u></a> with Real Sound, Metal Gear series producer Noriaki Okamura discussed what’s next for the franchise after the Metal Gear Solid 3 remake, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Right now, we’re still thinking about what to make next,” Okamura said. “Since we created an opportunity (with MGS Delta) for new players to experience the Metal Gear series, I do want to continue with it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued: “It could be a remake, or we might challenge ourselves by creating a brand new game. The Metal Gear series is part of videogame history, spanning pixel art to cinematic presentation, and so each title requires a different approach to expressing and remaking it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We won’t apply the methodology used to make the recent MGS Delta to all other games in the series — rather we intend to find the best approach for each specific game.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Okamura also touched on the amount of time it took for the team at Konami to be in a position to remake Metal Gear Solid 3. “Most of the original staff members had left and the team had been reorganized, however we gathered people together and finally arrived at the point where we could make MGS Delta. As a team, we are confident that we achieved a level of quality that not only preserves the appeal of the original but also that modern players could enjoy. We are currently working out concrete plans for what we are going to do next.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, when asked about the possibility of a Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots remake, Okamura remained cautious, saying: “the hardware back then required very specific designs to get the most out of the 3D technology that was available at the time, so MGS4 ended up with some pretty unique code. It seems like it would be quite a challenge to bring that into the present day.” </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Kojima Game Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the moment, 2008’s Metal Gear Solid 4, which ties up all the loose ends in Solid Snake’s story, is only playable on PlayStation 3. Based on the original game release order and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-4-finally-freed-from-ps3-as-part-of-leaked-metal-gear-solid-master-collection-vol-2"><u>rumors</u></a>, a remastered port of MGS4 is expected to be included in the upcoming Metal Gear Solid Master Collection Vol. 2, however Konami has yet to announce the official line-up for this second anthology of MGS games to be released on current gen platforms.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Okamoto’s comments address a remake rather than a remaster, his thoughts on MGS4’s unique code may explain why it is taking Konami so long to release Volume 2. Okamura <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-master-collection-had-a-pretty-rough-launch-so-konami-says-its-being-more-careful-with-vol-2"><u>previously said</u></a> that the team are taking their time on Volume 2 to avoid the performance issues that dogged Volume 1 at launch: “we’re going to do everything we can not to repeat that, but we just have to ask for everyone to give us time.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-4-remake-would-be-quite-a-challenge-says-konamis-mgs-series-producer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Co-Founder and Former GTA Writer Dan Houser Says AI Is 'Like When We Fed Cows With Cows and Got Mad Cow Disease']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-co-founder-and-former-gta-writer-dan-houser-says-ai-is-like-when-we-fed-cows-with-cows-and-got-mad-cow-disease</link>
            <guid>1370203</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"AI is going to eventually eat itself."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar co-founder and former Grand Theft Auto writer Dan Houser has likened AI to mad cow disease, and claimed that humanity is being pulled in a direction “by a certain group of people who maybe aren't fully rounded humans.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The impact of AI has been swift and forceful, with the emergence of tech such as ChatGPT fueling an economic bubble some worry will burst. The way the internet works is being reshaped, too, with the idea of fair use of content for the training of AI models at loggerheads with copyright protection. This has resulted in ongoing lawsuits. Disney and Universal, for example, have sued the AI image creator Midjourney, alleging that the company improperly used and distributed AI-generated characters from their movies. Disney also sent a cease and desist letter to Character.AI, warning the startup to stop using its copyrighted characters without authorization.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/02/gettyimages-2237848702-1764673388048.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Dan Houser believes AI will eventually eat itself. Photo by Chelsea Guglielmino/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Enter Dan Houser, who left Rockstar in 2020 to found Absurd Ventures having worked on pretty much all the studio’s games up to that point. His new novel, A Better Paradise, is a story that revolves around AI, and so it stands to reason that he would be asked about the tech in a recent interview with <a href="https://youtu.be/d4RTTcvFxJU?si=3rw5DLWLXvhGrG7D" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Virgin Radio UK</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s fair to say Houser is sceptical about the future of AI.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Some of these people trying to define the future of humanity, creativity or whatever it is, using AI, are not the most humane or creative people,” he said. “So they're sort of saying we're better at being human than you are. And it’s obviously not true.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That is one of the other things we're trying to capture, that humanity is being pulled in a direction by a certain group of people who maybe aren't fully rounded humans.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued: “I think that AI is going to eventually eat itself. As far as I understand it, which is really superficial understanding, the models scour the internet for information, but the internet's going to get more and more full of information made by the models. So it's sort of like when we fed cows with cows and got mad cow disease.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I can't see how the information is going to get better. They’re already running out of data. It will do some tasks brilliantly but it's not going to do every task brilliantly. It’s going to become this sort of mirror of itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I'm slightly obsessed by the fact that when you search for the same thing again, it doesn't give you the same answers. And it's wrong a lot of the time, but it says it so confidently.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">GTA 6 Vice City Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Houser is talking here about what happens when AI models start training on their own output, which experts say puts them at risk of collapsing. The Large Language Models, or LLMs, that power the likes of ChatGPT are said to be cannibalizing themselves via Garbage In/Garbage Out (GIGO). Or, as Houser puts it, “it's sort of like when we fed cows with cows and got mad cow disease.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The use of AI in entertainment is one of the hottest topics across video games, movies, and television. Last month, the CEO of Genvid — the company behind choose-your-own-adventure interactive series like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-ascension"><u>Silent Hill Ascension</u></a> — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gen-z-loves-ai-slop-former-square-enix-exec-claims-a-lot-of-ai-sentiment-is-driven-by-emotion-rather-than-logic">claimed "consumers generally do not care" about generative AI in games, stating: "Gen Z loves AI slop."</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">But there is some pushback. This week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-artist-responds-as-fans-claim-game-now-includes-examples-of-blatant-ai-artwork-including-a-nine-toed-character-in-a-hammock">Epic Games came under fire for what fans believe to be AI generated art in Fortnite</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Chelsea Guglielmino/Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-co-founder-and-former-gta-writer-dan-houser-says-ai-is-like-when-we-fed-cows-with-cows-and-got-mad-cow-disease]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>