<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 14:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering: Foundations, Aetherdrift, and Ravnica Remastered Boosters Discounted at Best Buy Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-dotd-mtg-foundations-aetherdrift-and-ravnica-remastered</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-foundations-aetherdrift-and-ravnica-remastered-boosters-discounted-at-best-buy-today.1161672/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-dotd-mtg-foundations-aetherdrift-and-ravnica-remastered<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I don’t usually get excited about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-magic-the-gathering-mtg-deals">Magic: The Gathering deals</a> unless they involve a substantial discount or a chance to pick up chase cards without pawning my fetch lands. But the current <a href="https://zdcs.link/aD3E7e?object_uuid=05961934-c1ee-4ca7-b827-976157765e36&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Best Buy Deal of the Day</a> has me genuinely interested, and not just because I’m weak in the face of shiny foils and stitched-edge playmats. As with all DotD discounts, this is limited just to today as well, so pick up the cheap boosters while you can. Let's dig into what's available, and what I'd recommend picking up.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">MTG Discounts On Foundations, Aetherdrift, and More </h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s talk <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-foundations-preorders-are-live-right-now-on-amazon">Foundations</a>. This set isn’t trying to wow anyone with lore about a haunted mansion or a squirrel-led uprising. Instead, it focuses on being playable, readable, and shockingly welcoming. I think that’s a big deal, especially since we’re about to get Marvel and Final Fantasy collaborations through Universes Beyond. New players are going to get dropped into the multiverse with zero context, so a solid on-ramp like Foundations is going to be essential.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Foundations Bundle</h2><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218544"><div id="218544" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Foundations Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve never touched a deck in your life, the Foundations Beginner Box is a better teacher than half the humans I’ve seen try to explain Magic at a kitchen table. Pre-constructed decks, visual aids, and a guided tutorial make it absurdly approachable. t. There’s also the Foundations Bundle, which is going for $42.49. That's under market price and loaded with boosters and accessories. It’s great value, especially since Foundations is going to stick around in Standard for five years, giving you time to figure out what the heck a stack is.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Foundations Jumpstart Booster 2-Pack </h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218545"><div id="218545" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Foundations Jumpstart Booster 2-Pack </h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">And then there's Aetherdrift, which is for people who read the card <em>Blasphemous Act</em> and said, “but what if we did more?” The Aetherdrift Bundle is currently $34.99, which is a solid $16 off its usual price. It includes some of the more unhinged red spells and flashy threats to come out of Standard lately, including Marauding Mako (which is basically Magic's version of a landshark with anger issues) and Momentum Breaker, a mono-black tool that's found a home in aggressive Pixie decks. Yes, apparently that’s a thing now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Ravnica Remastered Draft Booster Sleeve</h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218546"><div id="218546" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Ravnica Remastered Draft Booster Sleeve</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Foundations also includes some pretty desirable chase cards if you're cracking packs. I’m looking at you, Rise of the Dark Realms with the new Borderless treatment, and Sire of Seven Deaths, the Eldrazi with seven keywords that feels like it was printed specifically to cause someone a rules headache. And don’t sleep on Banner of Kinship, which casually turns your Goblin deck into a math test your opponent definitely didn’t study for.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Bundle</h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218547"><div id="218547" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Yes, I noticed Ravnica Remastered is part of this sale. You can grab a Ravnica Remastered Draft Booster Sleeve for $4.99 (down from $6.99), which is actually one of the cheapest ways to chase after format staples like Crypt Ghast, Spark Double, and Divine Visitation. I think that’s a great price for anyone looking to bulk open product or toss a few into a sealed night with friends.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Collector Booster</h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218548"><div id="218548" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Collector Booster</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Personally, I love Ravnica sets. I’ve always been a sucker for guild mechanics, and Ravnica Remastered is basically Wizards saying, “Let’s throw all the good stuff into one nostalgic blender.” You get a mix of old-school Commander hits like <strong>Cyclonic Rift</strong>, weird-but-powerful tech like <strong>Cloudstone Curio</strong>, and alternate art versions that will either delight you or make you question whether you’re playing Magic or flipping through concept art for a lost anime series</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Commander Deck - Living Energy</h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218549"><div id="218549" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Aetherdrift Commander Deck - Living Energy</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I picked up a few sleeves myself, partly for the shot at Anime Borderless Bruvac, and partly because I have no impulse control when it comes to reprint sets. You don’t need to justify $5 packs when they include Shock Lands and cards with infinite combo potential.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering Fallout Commander Deck - Science!</h2></div><div catalogid="acace1da-a03b-4dfd-8975-e2ad8a5865b5" id="218550"><div id="218550" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizards of The Coast - Magic: The Gathering Fallout Commander Deck - Science!</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're already building for Commander or just pretending your collection isn’t entirely impulse buys, the Fallout Commander Deck – Science! is on sale for $33.99. That’s $26 off retail, and includes one of the better face Commanders to come from Universes Beyond: Dogmeat, Ever Loyal, who floods the board with Junk tokens if you build around equipment and auras. In my opinion, this deck is an underrated engine, and you get to play cards like Radstorm and Feral Ghoul, which sound like B-side punk albums but are surprisingly effective in-game.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">MTG: Ultra Pro Mana 8 Stitched Edge Playmats</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">I don’t usually care about playmats, but these Mana 8 stitched-edge ones are kinda gorgeous. At $16.49, they’re dramatic in all the right ways without costing you the same as a new commander deck. I think the Lotus one is low-key perfection.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 11, 2025 10:23 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>