<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:46:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball 40th Anniversary Event: Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-ball-40th-anniversary-event-everything-announced</link>
            <guid>1415425</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">2025 marks 40 years since Akira Toriyama’s ground-breaking Dragon Ball manga first hit shelves in Japan. The Dragon Ball Genkidamatsuri was held in Japan over the weekend to celebrate the global manga, anime and video game phenomenon. Taking up the huge Makuhari Messe event space near Tokyo, the event featured everything from exclusive merch, live game contests, and specially-curated exhibits of original artwork. The main stage was packed with exciting announcements about where the series is headed after the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/akira-toriyama-creator-of-dragon-ball-and-manga-pioneer-dies-at-68"><u>death of series creator Akira Toriyama</u></a>, including two new anime TV series, a new game and a “massive” new DLC for Dragon Ball Sparking! Zero.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Dragon Ball Super: The Galactic Patrol Anime</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The event kicked off with a brief talk between Son Goku’s Japanese VA Masako Nozawa and Dragon Ball series executive producer Akio Iyoku, followed by the premiere of a <a href="https://youtu.be/VSPa8C2WYTw?si=gnTb9cHARYZJJY85" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>special video</u></a> marking the 40th anniversary of Dragon Ball. Featuring music specially composed by Hans Zimmer, the film celebrates the evolution of Dragon Ball over the years, from Toriyama’s original manga drawings through to its various anime adaptations. The end of the video revealed a brand new anime series, Dragon Ball Super: The Galactic Patrol, prompting excited clapping from the audience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Ball Super: The Galactic Patrol will adapt the Moro or Galactic Patrol Prisoner Arc (Chapters 42 to 67) of the Dragon Ball Super manga. It follows on from the Universe Survival Arc of the Dragon Ball Super anime, which aired between 2015 to 2018. Dragon Ball Super: The Galactic Patrol is currently in production, and fans will have to wait until 2027 to see Son Goku and Vegeta battle it out against Moro.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/25/dragon-ball-1769330257081.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A key visual for the new Dragon Ball Super anime was revealed.</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Age 1000 Game Project</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Next, Iyoku was joined on stage by Dragon Ball Games producer Masayuki Hirano, who revealed a <a href="https://youtu.be/pLscMRafsLI?si=W0B4WUhoWDBBte_m" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>flashy trailer</u></a> for a brand new game project, Age 1000. However, the game’s official title will be announced later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Age 1000 project is good news for fans who thought they would never see any new creations from Dragon Ball creator Akira Toriyama after his death in 2024. Apparently, Bandai Namco started developing Age 1000 around seven years ago, and Toriyama himself put a lot of work into the game’s worldbuilding and brand new characters. The trailer shows a mysterious grey-haired young man decked out in Capsule Corp gear, with Hirano revealing that “I asked Toriyama sensei to create this character especially for the game.” Although the new character seems like a new Super Saiyan, Hirano was tight-lipped about who he is. However, fans will have to wait for Dragon Ball Games Battle Hour 2026 (to be held on April 18-19 in LA) for further details.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The project’s name calls to mind Dragon Ball Online, which took place in the age 1000- so it seems the new game will also be exploring this time period. “We have spent a long time carefully crafting this project.” Iyoku explained. “I think this game will allow us to experience a brand new part of the Dragon Ball world.” Age 1000 is slated for a 2027 release.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Announcing a New Dragon Ball Game Project, "AGE 1000", set for 2027!<br>A new world and new characters brought to life by Akira Toriyama!</p><p> The latest updates will be unveiled at Dragon Ball Games Battle Hour 2026 in the U.S. on April 18-19.<br>Stay tuned for more information. <a href="https://t.co/ouBqvz5FwA" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ouBqvz5FwA</a></p></div>— Dragon Ball Games (@dragonballgames) <a href="https://twitter.com/dragonballgames/status/2015246051461210565?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 25, 2026</a></blockquote> <h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Dragon Ball Sparking! ZERO to get “massive” new DLC</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Ball Sparking! Zero producer Jun Furutani revealed that the fighting game will be getting a “massive” new DLC this summer. The trailer for the DLC teased even more playable characters (including Super Android 17 and Demon King Piccolo), new costumes, new super attacks for Vegeta and Goku, as well as new stages and modes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The upcoming DLC will also have its own theme song, Zero, sung by series veteran Hironobu Kageyama- who is known for his many Dragon Ball Z theme songs. Kageyama performed the new song, saying he was honored to contribute to Dragon Ball again after 18 years. With Zero, he aimed to create a cheerful and powerful song that will energize anyone who hears it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who can’t wait, producer Furutani also reminded PS5, Xbox Series X/S and Steam players that Dragon Ball Sparking! Zero is getting a free DLC on January 26, the Mission 100 single player mode (which longtime fans will remember from Dragon Ball Budokai Tenakichi 3). He announced that Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 versions of the game will be getting the DLC at a later date: “please bear with us a little longer.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Absolutely limit-breaking.</p><p> New characters. New costumes &amp; Super Attacks. New stages. New mode.<br>New DLC for DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO coming soon. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DBSZ?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#DBSZ</a> <a href="https://t.co/CS1aRhVQsx" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/CS1aRhVQsx</a></p></div>— Bandai Namco US (@BandaiNamcoUS) <a href="https://twitter.com/BandaiNamcoUS/status/2015253868913799242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 25, 2026</a></blockquote> <h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Dragon Ball Super: Beerus Anime</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">After lunch, Dragon Ball series executive producer Akio Iyoku and Son Goku VA Masako Nozawa returned to the stage alongside VA Koichi Yamadera for another new anime series announcement. Dragon Ball Super: Beerus, a remake of Dragon Ball Super’s first arc, is coming in Fall 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Iyoku describes Dragon Ball Super: Beerus as an “enhanced version of the story.” The upcoming anime series is designed to be “more faithful to the original manga” created by Akira Toriyama. Dragon Ball Super: Beerus will feature enhanced visuals, redrawn and newly added cuts, narrative reworks, and promises to deliver “even more immersive battle scenes” than the original Dragon Ball Super anime.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Ball Super: Beerus also aims to show Beerus in a more serious light than the mischievous villain people are used to. “Beerus is a powerful enemy and a powerful character, so I wanted to make sure to bring that out this time.” Iyoku explained. Beerus’s voice actor Yamadera added, “You think he (Beerus) is just a weird uncle talking about food (…) but he’s actually the God of Destruction!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Ball Super: Beerus will be airing on Japan’s Fuji TV in Fall 2026, with details about international distribution expected to be announced soon. For now, check out the trailer, below.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Hype (@DbsHype) <a href="https://twitter.com/DbsHype/status/2015278347702722990?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 25, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Despite Akira Toriyama’s passing, Dragon Ball fans have plenty to look forward to over the next two years. Which announcement are you most hyped about?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Toei Animation.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-ball-40th-anniversary-event-everything-announced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>