<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 21:29:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon Soul Simulator Update Adds New Character, Relics System, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/demon-soul-simulator-update-adds-new-character-relics-system-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon-soul-simulator-update-adds-new-character-relics-system-and-more.1048791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/demon-soul-simulator-update-adds-new-character-relics-system-and-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A slightly smaller update ahead of the upcoming Christmas Event.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Developer Diligent Farmer just dropped Demon Soul Simulator Update V4.9.2, adding a new character, a new level cap, and a handful of balance tweaks for Roblox players everywhere.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Patch notes for this month’s changes were unveiled on <a href="https://www.roblox.com/games/8069117419/UPD-Demon-Soul-Simulator" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the experience’s Roblox page</a>. The full list ranges from larger additions, such as the new Relics System and Relics Gacha, to smaller adjustments, like Robux cloth adjustments.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/29/demon-soul-simulator-update-v4-9-2-roblox-1732903468466.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Demon Soul Simulator Update V4.9.2 Adds Enmu, Relics System, and More.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Demon Soul Simulator takes inspiration from the popular (and stylish) anime, Demon Slayer. That means fan-favorite characters like Tanjiro, Zenitsu, and Inosuke all make appearances in some form, and with Update V4.9.2, players can now enjoy another new character in Enmu. There are plenty of new additions to enjoy ahead of another update that is set to arrive next month, but Diligent Farmer also made sure to adjust some existing features, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the bigger changes sees the player level cap set at 1500. Boss level adjustments are here, too, as well as an increase for the Infinite Train Enemy shield and an adjustment to the Blood Moon enemy levels. There’s also a new update code (wgnsa2c2) for players to use once they enter the game.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Demon Soul Simulator Update V4.9.2 is only the latest content drop for Roblox players and anime fans to chew on. In mid-December, Diligent Farmer plans to release Update V4.10, which will add a Christmas event, new features, balance adjustments, and other additional content. Whether you’re looking to check out Demon Soul Simulator for the first time or if you’re a returning player, you can see our list of all active codes <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/demon-soul-simulator-codes"><u>here</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, you can see the full patch notes for the update below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Demon Soul Simulator Update V4.9.2 Patch Notes</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">New Content</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Relics System</li><li>Relics Gacha(Located at Train Station)</li><li>21 Relics</li><li>Character fragment conversion(In the bag)</li><li>Characters(Enmu)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Adjustment</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Player Level cap 1500</li><li>Blood Moon enemy levels adjusted</li><li>BOSS level adjustment</li><li>Infinite Train Enemy shield increased</li><li>Robux cloth adjustment</li><li>Murata can only get it from dispatch</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Update Code:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>wgnsa2c2</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get 2,000 Free Robux With This Early Cyber Monday Deal On Roblox Gift Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-early-cyber-monday-deal-roblox-gift-cards-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-2-000-free-robux-with-this-early-cyber-monday-deal-on-roblox-gift-cards.1048656/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-early-cyber-monday-deal-roblox-gift-cards-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Time to stock up on Robux. </h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Are you obsessed with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dress-to-impress-roblox">Dress to Impress</a>? Or the more action-packed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tower-defense-simulator-roblox">Tower Defense Simulator</a>? Maybe even catching fish in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fisch-roblox">Fisch</a>?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whichever “Roblox experience” has you or someone you know hooked, I’m sure it has microtransactions (things to spend real money on) in one form or another. Roblox gift cards can be converted into the Robux needed to make those purchases, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-black-friday-2024-deals">Cyber Monday</a> is one of the best times to find those gift cards on sale. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While there are slight discounts on digital gift cards, the best savings you can possibly get is by going physical: Right now, you can get <a href="https://zdcs.link/92bnVY?object_uuid=39532ff3-ef49-4e73-ba5e-8b9fe2472693&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">a full $20 off $100 Roblox gift cards</a>. Christmas is saved!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Best Roblox Cyber Monday Deal: $100 Gift Card for $80</h2><div catalogid="b9d778fc-984a-4acf-ab01-0de3d67a709b" id="212474"><div id="212474" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Lightning Deal - No Longer Available</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Roblox Physical Gift Card [Includes Free Virtual Item]</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Equivalent to 10,000 Robux, redeemable worldwide</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re doing some holiday shopping over Black Friday and Cyber Monday, a physical Roblox gift card is an unbeatable stocking stuffer. Though, I have to admit, getting $100 worth of Robux at a $20 discount is something you could even gift to yourself. A $100 gift card is equivalent to about 10,000 Robux. By saving $20, you're basically getting a whopping 2,000 Robux for free. Act fast, however, because I'm sure this Lightning Deal will sell out quick. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Depending on what month you redeem your Roblox gift card, you’ll also get a different free virtual item. In November, that gift is the Midnight Crimson Sombrero, but if you wait until December (heads up: That's tomorrow), you’ll get the Festive Deadpan Alpaca Head.  </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Does Roblox Have Its Own Cyber Monday Sale? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox as a platform doesn’t have an "official" Cyber Monday sale, but you might find deals, discounts, and special events within specific experiences. Feel free to scroll through <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp63DZ?object_uuid=39532ff3-ef49-4e73-ba5e-8b9fe2472693&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">the Roblox store on Amazon</a> for more discounts, or check out our roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/video-game-black-friday-best-deals-2024">best gaming deals</a> from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-best-black-friday-deals-2024-live">Nintendo</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals-black-friday-2024">Xbox</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps5-playstation-black-friday-deals-2024">PlayStation</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem Roblox Gift Cards</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Once you've received a Roblox Gift Card, you’ll want to head over to <a href="https://roblox.com/redeem" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Roblox.com/redeem</u></a>. From there, you will need to do the following:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Log into an existing Roblox account (or register for the first time) </li><li>Find the PIN/Code on the Gift Card and enter it into the white box on the website</li><li>Click the Redeem button</li><li>If successful, a success message will appear on screen and Credit will be added to the associated account</li></ol><p data-cy="paragraph">Congratulations! You’ve now got a new amount of Robux credit added to that account that can be spent in-game on whatever you want! You can check out our guide on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-roblox-gift-cards-robux">how to redeem Roblox gift cards</a> for more details. </p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 30, 2024 3:31 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>