<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 20:30:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2: 72 New Game Details - Mario Kart 9, The Duskbloods, and More!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-72-new-game-details-mario-kart-9-the-duskbloods-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-72-new-game-details-mario-kart-9-the-duskbloods-and-more.1153158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-72-new-game-details-mario-kart-9-the-duskbloods-and-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has finally given us <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">all the info on its new console</a>, the Switch 2. During the hour-long Direct, there was a LOT of info on both new and old games coming to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-23-new-details-release-date-price-gamechat-and-more">Nintendo’s new console</a>. From expected arrivals such as Mario Kart World to the complete surprise of what looks like a spiritual sequel to Bloodborne, here are 72 new details about the Nintendo Switch 2 games library as we know it right now.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Nintendo Switch 2 Direct April 2025 Games</h3><p>Every game shown in Nintendo's April 2 Nintendo Switch 2 reveal direct event.</p></div><h2 data-cy="title2"><u>Mario Kart World</u></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">1. The Switch 2’s flagship launch title looks set to be Mario Kart World, the first open-world Mario Kart game that will allow you to “drive almost anywhere”.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2. Many new tracks were seen in the trailer, including one based on the original Donkey Kong game and a metropolis that could be Super Mario Odyssey’s New Donk City.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 Mario Kart World Slideshow</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">3. The overworld’s roads and track conditions will change due to the environment’s changing weather and a day/night cycle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">4. Up to 24 drivers in a race were confirmed, almost certainly leading to even more Mario Kart havoc.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">5. A new mode for Mario Kart World called Knockout Tour will be introduced. These will be longer races where you follow the checkpoints and have to remain near the leaders to avoid elimination and ultimately take the crown.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">6. You can also drive freely around the open world and meet up with friends. A photo mode will help document these adventures.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">7. New racing mechanics look set to be introduced. We see wall-riding and grinding in the trailer, as well as what looks like Birdo transforming into a semi-truck and Mario eating a burger to transform into a different version of himself? I’m sure we’ll find out what the hell is going on here soon enough.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">8. And that time could be 6am Pacific Time on the 17th of April, when Mario Kart World will be having its very own Nintendo Direct stream.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><u>Other Switch 2 Nintendo Games</u></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">9. Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will be getting its very own Switch 2 version, which allows you to take advantage of the new joy-con mouse controls.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">10. Metroid Prime 4 will also be available to play in two different graphics modes. Quality Mode allows for  4K 60FPS with HDR enabled when docked and 1080p 60fps handheld. Performance Mode offers 1080p with HDR at 120fps docked, but 720p 120fps HDR when handheld.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">11. A new 3D Donkey Kong platformer called Donkey Kong Bananza is heading to the Switch 2 on July 17th. It appears we’ll be able to smash everything in it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">12. Kirby Air Riders, a follow-up to GameCube racing spin-off Kirby Air Ride, is also coming to the Switch 2. It will be directed by legendary Super Smash Bros. developer, and Kirby creator, Masahiro Sakurai.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">13. Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour will offer a “virtual exhibition” of the new hardware, as well as being filled with minigames. This will not be packed into each Switch 2 at launch, though, but a paid-for game in its own right.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">14. Drag X Drive is a launch game that uses the Nintendo Switch 2 Joy-Con mouse controls to enable three-on-three basketball-style matches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">15. Then there are a bunch of existing Nintendo-published games that will be getting Switch 2 upgrades. These won’t be free for existing owners, however, with paid upgrade packs being the barrier to entry. The list of Switch 1 games getting these upgrades so far includes: </p><p data-cy="paragraph">16. Mario Party Jamboree + Jamboree TV, the latter being an expansion centered around the Switch 2 camera and GameChat additions.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">17. The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom, with both receiving enhanced resolution and frame rates, as well as HDR implementation. A new Zelda Notes section on the Nintendo Today app will also be added to let you look at Hyrule’s map and easily share TOTK creations with other players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">18. Kirby and the Forgotten Land will be receiving an upgrade, as well as a new Star Cross World story expansion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">19. And Pokemon Legends Z-A will get its very own Switch 2 version with enhanced resolution when it arrives later in 2025.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><u>3rd Party Switch 2 Games</u></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">20. But that’s not it. During the Switch 2 direct a whole host of third-party games, both new and old, were revealed to be making their way to Nintendo’s upcoming console. We’ve got them all for you here:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">21. Perhaps the biggest surprise of the whole direct, FromSoftware is making what looks like a spiritual successor to Bloodborne exclusively for the Nintendo Switch 2. Releasing in 2026, The Duskbloods is officially described as “a brand-new multiplayer game" from the Dark Souls developers and we look forward to hearing much more about it when a Creator’s Voice article from Hidetaka Miyazaki himself drops on the Nintendo Today App on April 4th.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">22. FromSoft’s last game, Elden Ring, will also be making its way to Switch 2 with its Tarnished Edition.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">23. Hades 2 will arrive (presumably once out of early access)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">24. We finally got another little peek at Hollow Knight Silksong, which is listed for 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">25. Street Fighter 6 Years 1-2 Fighters Edition will be available on day one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">26. Daemon X Machina: Titanic Scion will launch on September 5th.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">27. Split-Fiction will also arrive at launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">28. Both the EA FC and Madden sports sims will be on Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">29. Hogwarts Legacy, complete with mouse controls, will be available at launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">30. The Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3+4 Remakes will arrive in summer, as well as what looked like a tease for a Spongebob level (?)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">31. The Hitman World of Assassination Signature Edition will let us carry out contracts on the go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">32. James Bond will make his way to Switch 2 when Project 007 is released by IO Interactive.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">33. A Bravely Default Flying Fairy HD Remaster will launch alongside the Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">34. Yakuza 0 Director’s Cut is also a launch title and comes packed with new cutscenes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">35. Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment – a prequel to Tears of the Kingdom – promises to tell the untold story of the Imprisoning War when it arrives from Koei Tecmo this winter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">36. Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4 are also set for launch day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">37. And Borderlands 4 will fire its way onto Switch 2 alongside its thousands of different ridiculous pieces of weaponry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">38. Civilization 7 will be taking advantage of the Switch 2’s mouse controls at launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">39. And both WWE 2K and NBA 2K will both be making their way to the console as well. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">40. Survival Kids, a colourful co-op survival game, will be arriving at launch, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">41. Cyberpunk 2077 Ultimate Edition is on the way from CD Projekt Red, complete with its Phantom Liberty expansion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">42. And Square Enix will also be bringing Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade to Switch 2 in all its glory.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">43. There were also MANY more games shown to be on their way to the Switch 2. Let’s rattle them off here, starting with Enter the Gungeon 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">44. Starseeker: Astroneer Expeditions</p><p data-cy="paragraph">45. Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</p><p data-cy="paragraph">46. Story of Seasons: Grand Bazaar</p><p data-cy="paragraph">47. Goodnight Universe</p><p data-cy="paragraph">48. Two Point Museum</p><p data-cy="paragraph">49. Wild Hearts S</p><p data-cy="paragraph">50. Witchbrook</p><p data-cy="paragraph">51. Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</p><p data-cy="paragraph">52. Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</p><p data-cy="paragraph">53. Marvel Cosmic Invasion</p><p data-cy="paragraph">54. Star Wars Outlaws</p><p data-cy="paragraph">55. Nobunaga’s Ambition: Awakening Complete Edition</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">56. Fast Fusion</p><p data-cy="paragraph">57. Shadow Labyrinth</p><p data-cy="paragraph">58. Raidou Remastered: The Mystery of the Soulless Army</p><p data-cy="paragraph">59. No Sleep For Kaname Date - From AI: The Somnium Files</p><p data-cy="paragraph">60. Reanimal</p><p data-cy="paragraph">61. Fortnite</p><p data-cy="paragraph">62. Arcade Archives 2 Ridge Racer</p><p data-cy="paragraph">63. Professor Layton and the New World of Steam</p><p data-cy="paragraph">64. Tamagotchi Plaza</p><p data-cy="paragraph">65. Human Fall Flat 2</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><u>Nintendo Switch Online + GameCube</u></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">66. But wait! There are more games. Even older ones! Nintendo Online will continue over to Switch 2 and if you subscribe to the +Expansion service, Switch 2 owners get exclusive access to a new classic game library: GameCube.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">67. There will be three titles at launch, including The Legend of Zelda: Wind Waker. Yeah, it’s not the HD remaster that many have been crying out for but at least it’s a way of replaying the fantastic GameCube adventure on the go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">68. SoulCalibur 2 is also a launch game, along with F-Zero GX. What’s more, multiplayer games like F-Zero GX will support four-player local and online play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">69. Games coming further down the line include Pokemon XD: Gale of Darkness, Super Mario Strikers, Fire Emblem: Path of Radiance, Chi bi-Robo!, Luigi’s Mansion, and Pokemon Coliseum.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">70. A 3D Mario platformer was also shown during the Direct, but not the brand-new one many were hoping for. Instead, Mario Sunshine will be available to Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion subscribers in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">71. All GameCube games benefit from superior image quality and improved resolution compared to the original versions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">72. Additionally, a dedicated Switch 2 GameCube controller is coming, available exclusively to Nintendo Switch Online members. It’ll connect wireless to Switch 2 and also has a C button for GameChat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And that’s all the important information we picked out about the games heading to Switch 2 from Nintendo’s extensive Direct. What games are you most excited to play on the upcoming console? Let us know in the comments. And for everything else Switch 2, stick with IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>