<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:13:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic’s Marvel Super Hero Crossover Includes Four New Commander Decks - Here’s All We Know So Far]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-set-includes-four-new-commander-decks-everything-you-need-to-know</link>
            <guid>1423522</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> has a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-full-release-schedule-updated-2026"><u>busy year in 2026</u></a>, particularly when it pertains to Universes Beyond.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">June 2026 will see a <a href="https://zdcs.link/a56LlN?object_uuid=a494e093-a88d-409b-9d45-44d48e9efcca&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Marvel Super Heroes</u></a> set arrive, and unlike Spider-Man, it’s bringing Commander precons. We’re still waiting for more information about what’s in each, but we’ll update this page as we hear more. <strong>Any you’ve got your eye on? Let us know in the comments!</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are four Commander Decks for the Marvel Super Heroes set, following in the footsteps of other Universes Beyond sets like The Lord of the Rings, Warhammer 40,000, and last year’s Final Fantasy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the lineup, including the brief description on the box of each precon, as well as their color identity.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Avengers Assemble (Captain America and Nick Fury - Red/White/Blue)<ul data-cy="list"><li>‘Grow your ranks, equipment and counters’</li></ul></li><li>Wakanda Forever (Black Panther - Green/White)<ul data-cy="list"><li>‘Power up with artifacts, reign as the Monarch’</li></ul></li><li>The Fantastic Four (The titular team - Red/Green/White/Blue)<ul data-cy="list"><li>‘Noncreature spells, protection fields’</li></ul></li><li>Doom Prevails (Doctor Doom and Loki - Blue/Black/Red)<ul data-cy="list"><li>‘Connive for power, drain life’</li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that Marvel’s Spider-Man, which launched in 2025, didn’t get the Commander Deck treatment. Given it’s Magic’s most popular format, we’re unsure if this is Wizards of the Coast correcting that oversight, or if it was always planned this way.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What's in the Collector's Edition Commander Decks?</h2><div id="234835"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234835" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Marvel Super Heroes - Collector's Edition Commander Deck Bundle</h3></p></div></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm glad you asked! The Marvel Super Heroes Commander Decks come in another, yellow box version. You're getting functionally the same cards, except these are all foil.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the name suggests, you're probably better off storing these in your collection rather than playing with them, but they command a high price because they're likely to be a limited printing <em>a la</em> Collector Boosters.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Lay of the Land In Commander Decks 2026 So Far</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Commander precons trailed off last year, with the last two being found in August’s Edge of Eternities set, with none in Spider-Man and Avatar: The Last Airbender.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, Wizards is back onto Commander decks in a big way. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-precon-decks-in-stock-best-price-preview"><u>Lorwyn Eclipsed</u></a> has two decks, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles has one, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-secrets-of-strixhaven-tcg-where-to-buy"><u>Secrets of Strixhaven has a whopping five</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Adding in the four from the Marvel Super Heroes set, and you’ve got 12 already - with multiple sets still planned for the second half of the year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">By our count, there were 13 in the whole of 2025, so if you’re looking for a way to jump in and play with minimal fuss, this is probably a good year to try your hand.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on the game’s current set, Lorwyn Eclipsed, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-most-expensive-cards"><u>our list of the best chase cards</u></a> in the set right now, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-precon-decks-in-stock-best-price-preview">our rundown of its Commander offerings</a>. You can also check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-commander-precons-best-decks">our list of the best Commander precons</a> from recent years that are still worth picking up - including The Lord of the Rings, Fallout, and some great beginner options.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where to Buy MTG x Marvel Super Heroes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The highly-anticipated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/magic-the-gathering/Every_Universes_Beyond_Set">Universes Beyond</a> set <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-super-heroes-tcg-where-to-buy">Marvel Super Heroes</a> is coming in June, and will be featuring our favorite heroes, villains, locations, and more from the iconic comic books.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's out right after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-secrets-of-strixhaven-tcg-where-to-buy">Secrets of Strixhaven</a>, and preorders are now live on Amazon, with some boxes already going out of stock. So, I'd act fast if you want to secure the rest of the set on release day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.</p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-set-includes-four-new-commander-decks-everything-you-need-to-know]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering's Newest Product Says the Quiet Part Out Loud]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-newest-product-says-the-quiet-part-out-loud</link>
            <guid>1423435</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The latest Secret Lair sold the same drop at different prices, drawing anger from the community.</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">This morning Wizards of the Coast put a new Magic: The Gathering product up for sale with an unexpected twist. The <a href="https://secretlair.wizards.com/us/chaosvault" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>“Prints Charming” Secret Lair drop</u></a> contains four reprinted cards with pretty excellent new art – but rather than simply telling us how much it costs, it was given five different non-foil store listings and five more for the foil version, each with a different price ranging from $10 all the way up to $50. The product description on all of them is careful to point out the following: “The only difference between listings is the price. Higher-priced listings do not include anything extra.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This, by my estimation as someone who has been playing Magic since the 90s and literally wrote <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/11/25/magic-the-gathering-reveals-new-secret-lair-drop-series-with-wild-art"><u>the announcement for the very first Secret Lair</u></a>, is pretty lame. Taken graciously, it’s a goofy marketing stunt meant to do something silly and get folk talking about it, but it nevertheless leaves those who arrived too late with a very sour taste in their mouth. A more pessimistic reading would be that WOTC is price testing what people are willing to pay for a Secret Lair drop in broad daylight, shedding even the thinnest veneer that may be hiding the capitalist hunger <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lawsuit-claims-hasbro-misled-investors-regarding-sales-of-controversial-magic-the-gathering-anniversary-set"><u>a lawsuit recently alleged</u></a> is designed specifically to hide shortfalls in other parts of Hasbro’s business. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Magic: The Gathering - "Prints Charming" Secret Lair Drop</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/1qu0vyc/sld_chaos_vault_prints_charming/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>The reaction</u></a> amongst the Magic community has been muddled. Some were confused. Some very generously assumed the higher price points were to bait automated scalper bots into spending more while real people could snag a more affordable version – an argument that doesn’t exactly hold water when you consider that <em>they could just make them all cheaper </em>if that was the desire. And some were just angry, either because the cheapest versions sold out so fast, or because they similarly see this as bold-faced market research in cardboard form.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I actually really love the idea of Wizards of the Coast’s Secret Lair line overall. Directly selling small drops of thematically linked cards with cool and unique art treatments is quite fun, and often comes at little-to-no cost for those who just want to ignore it. Being able to give <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-secret-lair-superdrop-brings-the-last-of-us-god-of-war-and-more-to-magic-the-gathering-in-october"><u>Kratos or Aloy their own cards</u></a> without the production lift a larger product would require is a neat tool in WOTC’s toolbelt. The “Chaos Vault” moniker this latest one was released under intentionally pushes the envelope even further with weird, off-schedule ideas and one-offs that are explicitly meant to experiment. I dig that! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But that does not mean Secret Lair is free from criticism. Most pressing here, folk (myself included) were already displeased by WOTC’s 2024 decision to move these drops from a “print to demand” model to one with limited and undisclosed quantities. The former system meant anyone who wanted a certain drop could get it within a specific timeframe, while the latter has historically meant you need to get in line <em>right </em>when a popular drop arrives in order to have a <em>chance </em>at purchasing it – something you can’t do if you, say, have work or school at the same time.</p><p>Regardless of intent, the result is a majority of players feeling like they were the ones left holding the bag.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, given there is already anxiety around the availability of Secret Lairs, one that got almost no pre-promotion offering an early bird discount (alongside the option to pay WOTC <em>more</em> money) is understandably frustrating. It’s the sort of thing that independent creators admittedly do with their products from time to time without drawing any ire, rewarding their most dedicated fans while also providing a way to support them even further for those who want to. But for a multibillion-dollar corporation to do it is not endearing in the same way – it comes across more like profit analysis wearing a sign around its neck that reads “it’s just a prank, bro.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Much to my dismay, both the lowest <em>and</em> highest priced versions of Prints Charming sold out the quickest, either lending some credence to the “ha ha stupid bots” theory or offering evidence that “speaking with your wallet” is and will always be a doomed suggestion. The standard Secret Lair pricing of $30 for non-foil and $40 for foil lasted much longer than the others, so it seems likely the “stock” for those versions was intentionally the largest of all the options. But even if that does make this one big stunt, or even a cute way to subsidize a few discounted drops through folk who are willing to spend a little more, the ultimate result is still that a majority of players feel like they are the ones left holding the proverbial bag.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I don’t know, maybe I am yelling at the clouds. The card-selling company is experimenting with how much money it can sell its cards for. This should not be a shock, nor am I surprised to see Prints Charming sell out within hours (the art is really excellent, even if its total reprint value of around $5 is not). But the quiet part is being said louder than usual here. The teacher has handed us a test, and I fear what the results will be. The theme of this drop is cards that speed up your green resource production, and if that’s not as on the nose as naming your giant evil space station the Death Star, I don’t know what is.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph"><em></em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomrmarks.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Tom Marks</em></a><em> is IGN's Associate Reviews Director and local MTG Cube obssessive. He loves puzzles, platformers, puzzle-platformers, and lots more.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-newest-product-says-the-quiet-part-out-loud]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>