<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:39:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 4 for PS5 Drops to Its Lowest Price Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-4-remake-ps5-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-4-for-ps5-drops-to-its-lowest-price-ever.1024257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-4-remake-ps5-deal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon's giving us quite a treat to cap off spooky season: the <a href="https://zdcs.link/92bwrD?object_uuid=24a4ea8d-82eb-45c6-8d7a-2709958094c4&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Resident Evil 4 remake for PS5</a> has dropped to just $20 at the retailer. According to price tracker <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0BJTKYLCB" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">camelcamelcamel</a> this is its <strong>lowest price ever</strong>, making it an excellent time to jump on this deal. And considering we hailed this game a 'Masterpiece' in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-4-remake-review">10/10 review</a>, why not add it to your collection right now?</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Resident Evil 4 Drops to $20</h2><div catalogid="d12ece05-313e-4735-a9f7-07d3b6e19435" id="209855"><div id="209855" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Resident Evil 4 - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Writer Tristan Ogilvie said in his <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-4-remake-review">Resident Evil 4 remake review</a> that the game's "combat is friction-free but no less stress-inducing thanks to its ferocious cast of creatures, its story rapidly shuttles through a series of action scenes that are diverse in structure but uniformly unwavering in intensity, and its world is rich in detail and full of fun and often snarling surprises." He called it "the most relentlessly exciting Resident Evil adventure of all time that’s been rebuilt, refined, and realised to the full limits of its enormous potential."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are plenty more game deals to check out right now, too. We have individual roundups for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PlayStation deals</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo Switch deals</a> that highlight the latest and greatest offers available for each console. We also have an overall roundup of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-game-deals">best video game deals</a> that features our favorite offers from each.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday and Cyber Monday on the horizon</a>, there are sure to be even more gaming discounts popping up over the next few weeks. Some retailers have already shared information on when their sales officially kick off in November, like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/walmart-black-friday-2024-when-does-the-sale-start">Walmart</a>, and they're earlier than you'd expect. Other retailers are sure to drop more information soon, so you won't have to wait too long to get into some good deals in November.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelance writer who works with the Guides and Commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 31, 2024 2:58 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Office Stars Reveal the Names of Michael and Holly's Kids]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-office-stars-reveal-the-names-of-michael-and-hollys-kids</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-office-stars-reveal-the-names-of-michael-and-hollys-kids.1024179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-office-stars-reveal-the-names-of-michael-and-hollys-kids<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pam Beasley actress Jenna Fischer and Angela Martin actress Angela Kinsey have revealed the names of Michael and Holly's kids who never made it into The Office themselves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The pair revealed on their <a href="https://officeladies.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Office Ladies</a> podcast, which is essentially an insiders' commentary on each episode, that the kids originally had a scene in the show's finale before being cut. The two sons, named by Michael, are called Chebonshur and Lowshebin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amy Ryan's Holly said in a talking head section that Michael's Steve Carell named the kids "based on the feeling he had when he first saw them." Holly was therefore intended to run for the final episode alongside Michael but Ryan's scheduling didn't allow it, and the scene was cut.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 25 Best Episodes of The Office of All Time</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Office ended its nine season run in 2013 and as one of the most beloved sitcoms of all time, though the universe is expanding again soon through a spin-off based on a midwestern local newspaper. It seemingly won't feature any of the original cast, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/steve-carell-wont-appear-in-the-office-spin-off">and definitely not Carrell</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I will be watching but I will not be showing up," he said in May. "It’s just a new thing and there’s really no reason for my character to show up in something like that. But I’m excited about it. It sounds like a great concept."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Carell also said Star Wars: Episode 9 - The Rise of Skywalker actor Domhnall Gleeson, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-offices-potential-follow-up-series-has-reportedly-already-cast-two-stars">who will reportedly appear in the spin-off</a>, was a great addition to the cast.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Darryl Philbin actor <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-office-star-craig-robinson-wants-to-play-darryl-in-a-reboot-but-doesnt-know-if-its-likely">Craig Robinson has expressed interest in returning</a> for a reboot or continuation though, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/breaking-bads-bryan-cranston-wants-to-see-an-office-movie-over-a-reboot-and-some-cast-are-on-board">Fischer said she'd</a> be on board if The Office co-creator Greg Daniels was involved.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Daniels is, working as co-creator of the spin-off alongside Michael Koman. The Office UK star Ricky Gervais did show up as David Brent in the U.S. series through a brief cameo, however, so perhaps anything is possible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>