<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:07:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 and 2 Return to PC at Last Today via The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle.1097142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-1-and-2-return-to-pc-at-last-today-via-the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA and Maxis are celebrating the 25th anniversary of The Sims franchise with a truly excellent surprise. Today, both The Sims 1 and The Sims 2 are available on PC once again via two Legacy Collections and The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has announced that it's releasing The Sims: Legacy Collection and The Sims 2: Legacy Collection today on PC. The two are available separately as well as combined for $40 in The Sims 25th Birthday Bundle.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Both games include all expansions and <em>almost</em> all stuff packs, as it looks like The Sims 2: Legacy Collection is missing the IKEA Home Stuff pack from 2008. But otherwise, everything's there. In fact, both collections include some bonus content, with The Sims 1 getting something called Throwback Fit Kit and The Sims 2 receiving a Grunge Revival Kit on top of all the other add-ons.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA's re-release of the two older The Sims games marks the first time in over a decade that both gave have been readily available to play. The Sims 1 was only ever released on disc, so for years now unless you were able to track down an old physical copy and somehow make it run on a modern Windows machine, there was just no way to get ahold of it (and that doesn't even include the expansion packs!). The Sims 2 was available more recently in 2014 via an Ultimate Collection on EA's Origin store, but the Ultimate Collection was taken down a while ago. So unless you took advantage of it at the time, The Sims 2 remained unavailable to you unless you could similarly find a physical disc. With these two new collections, all four The Sims games are now easily purchaseable and playable again through digital storefronts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We gave <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2000/02/05/the-sims-6">The Sims 1 a 9.5/10</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2005/10/28/the-sims-2-2">The Sims 2 an 8.5/10</a> waaaaay back in the day when we first reviewed them both. While the series has added numerous new features and ironed out a lot of kinks since then, the originals are still worth checking out for their goofiness, relative simplicity, challenge, and legacy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Sims: Legacy Collection and The Sims 2: Legacy Collection are both available now on Steam, the Epic Games Store, and through the EA app.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creator of Bloodborne 60fps Patch Says Sony Has Sent Him a DMCA Takedown — but Why Now?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-but-why-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-%E2%80%94-but-why-now.1097136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-bloodborne-60fps-patch-says-sony-has-sent-him-a-dmca-takedown-but-why-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The creator of the high-profile Bloodborne 60fps patch has said he’s received a DMCA takedown from Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lance-mcdonald-hacker-story-pt-god-of-war-bloodborne">Well-known video game tinkerer Lance McDonald</a> announced the news in a <a href="https://x.com/manfightdragon/status/1885347693125566806" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, saying he received a takedown notification on behalf of Sony Interactive Entertainment “asking that I remove links to the patch I posted on the internet, so I've now done so.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">McDonald then pointed to one of his <a href="https://youtu.be/i0tqppZDYxw?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube videos</a> on the Bloodborne 60fps patch, which he released in 2021, and recounted a meeting with former PlayStation executive Shuhei Yoshida in which he mentioned he made the 60fps mod for Bloodborne.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I met @yosp and said to him ‘I make mods for PlayStation games’ and he said ‘oh!.’ And I said ‘I made the 60fps mod for Bloodborne’ and he laughed so hard.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bloodborne is of course one of the biggest conundrums in the video game industry. The FromSoftware masterpiece launched on PS4 to critical and commercial acclaim, but since then Sony hasn’t touched it. Fans are desperate for an official next-gen patch that would make the game run at 60fps, up from 30fps, but there are also calls for a remaster and a sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That leaves it to the likes of McDonald to plug the gap. But more recently, fans managed to get PS4 emulators to deliver something akin to a remaster on PC. The tech experts at <a href="https://youtu.be/-zjzBbdl7hk?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry released a video</a> covering “a breakthrough in PS4 emulation” via ShadPS4, which means Bloodborne is now fully playable start to finish in 60fps. Could this breakthrough have triggered an aggressive response from Sony? IGN has asked Sony for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-hasnt-sony-done-anything-more-with-bloodborne-playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-has-a-personal-theory">Yoshida delivered his Bloodborne no-show theory</a> in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/jMsGB2PItes?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an interview with Kinda Funny Games</u></a>:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Bloodborne has always been the most asked thing,” Yoshida began. “And people wonder why we haven’t really done anything, even an update or a remaster. Should be easy, right? The company is known for doing so many remasters, right, some people get frustrated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I have only my personal theory to that situation. I left first-party so I don’t know what’s going on, but my theory is, you know because I remember, you know, Miyazaki-san really, really loved Bloodborne, you know, what he created. So I think he is interested, but he’s so successful and he’s so busy, so he doesn’t want, he cannot do himself, but he does not want anyone else to touch it. So that’s my theory. And the PlayStation team respect his wish. So that’s my guess, right? Theory. I am not revealing any secret information, to be clear.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The upshot is Bloodborne remains dormant nearly 10 years after the first game came out. But is there hope? In interviews, Miyazaki often deflects questions about Bloodborne, pointing to the fact FromSoftware does not own the IP. But in February last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fromsoftwares-miyazaki-responds-to-calls-for-bloodborne-remake-on-ps5"><u>Miyazaki at least admitted the game would benefit from a release on more modern hardware</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5 Drops to Its Lowest Price Ever at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-playstation-5-amazon-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-for-playstation-5-drops-to-its-lowest-price-ever-at-amazon.1097130/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-playstation-5-amazon-deal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Save $45 off its usual price.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-for-25-gamestop-dragon-age-super-mario-call-of-duty">GameStop's $25 sale on select video games</a>, Amazon's joining in on the fun by matching the price of <a href="https://zdcs.link/a0XoEN?object_uuid=7cb6546a-dc83-425b-9556-b210ef114e04&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DCMN43SC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5</a>, dropping its price to $24.99. This is 64% off its list price of $69.99, allowing you to pocket a whopping $45. That's an excellent deal to take advantage of, and according to price tracker <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0DCMN43SC" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">camelcamelcamel</a> it also marks the 2024 game's lowest price yet. No better time than now to scoop it up if you've had your eye on it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Get 64% off Dragon Age: The Veilguard for PlayStation 5 at Amazon</h2><div catalogid="5c4662f1-651b-4646-b42c-9add9fb85d7a" id="211158"><div id="211158" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dragon Age: The Veilguard - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're still on the fence about Dragon Age: The Veilguard, it's worth noting that we had very high praise for it in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review">review</a>. Writer Leana Hafer said, "Enjoyable action combat, a fantastic cast of allies with sweeping story arcs all their own, top-notch cinematics, and moving, nuanced character writing are the wings on which this triumphant dragon soars, pulling out all the stops in a whirlwind tour of Northern Thedas and capping it with a terrific finale that’s built on memorably tough choices and consequences."</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">More Gaming Deals Available Now</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned earlier, if you're looking for even more game deals, it's worth checking out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/games-for-25-gamestop-dragon-age-super-mario-call-of-duty">GameStop's sale that features select games down to just $25</a>. Alongside Dragon Age, this includes Super Mario RPG, EA SPORTS College Football 25, Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III and quite a few more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's also worth having a look at our individual roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PlayStation deals</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo Switch deals,</a> if you have a preferred platform you'd rather look at to see the best discounts available at the moment. For an overall look at the highlights for each console, check out our roundup of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-game-deals">best video game deals</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 31, 2025 3:30 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 Dev Recommends Even Experts Stick With the Tutorial for Their First Full Campaign — Here’s Why]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-7-dev-recommends-even-experts-stick-with-the-tutorial-for-their-first-full-campaign-heres-why</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-dev-recommends-even-experts-stick-with-the-tutorial-for-their-first-full-campaign-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-why.1097019/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-7-dev-recommends-even-experts-stick-with-the-tutorial-for-their-first-full-campaign-heres-why<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It’s a good strategy.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The developer of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Civilization 7</a> has explained why it strongly recommends even veteran Civ players stick with the tutorial for their first full campaign.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1295660/view/508445172204306615" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, Ed Beach, creative director at Firaxis Games, offered his tips for your first game of Civilization 7.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Civilization 7 is a big game, with many new systems and mechanics that differentiate it from earlier games in our series,” he began. “There's a lot to learn, so we felt that it was important that we provide some suggestions to ensure everyone has a successful first experience.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a reference to Civilization 7’s Ages system, which is a drastic change for the long-running strategy series. A full campaign in Civilization 7 is one that goes through all three Ages: Antiquity, Exploration, and Modern. Once the Age is completed, all players (and any AI opponents) experience an Age Transition simultaneously. During an Age Transition, three things happen: you select a new civilization from the new Age to represent your empire, you choose which Legacies you want to retain in the new Age, and the game world evolves. The Civilization games have never had such a system.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beach then explained why Firaxis chose Small as the default map size for Civilization 7.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We know that many veteran Civ players love to play on the largest map size and see the maximum number of empires battle it out,” he said. “However, there's a very deliberate reason that we chose Small as the default map size. With three other empires on your home continent, and a few more to discover later in the game, Small Maps make for a very comfortable experience while you are learning the ins and outs of Civ 7.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We especially recommend this map size as you get your feet wet with our new Diplomacy system. Tracking your relationship and ongoing diplomatic activities with a manageable number of opponents makes it way easier to get the hang of how you want to spend and manage your Diplomatic Influence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We also recommend sticking with Continents Plus for your Map Type selection. The extra islands just off-shore help ease you into the ocean exploration – a key element of the Exploration Age, the second chapter of our game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the Tutorial and Advisors, Beach confirmed that when you launch into your first game of Civilization 7, it turns the Tutorial on for you. He also strongly recommended Civ pros play with the Tutorial on, at least for their first full game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The Tutorial is designed to provide tips and explanations exactly when you first encounter something new,” Beach explained.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Fans experienced with earlier Civ titles may scoff at the idea of playing with the Tutorial on, but with so many of our game systems having received upgrades and revisions, we really do recommend sticking with the Tutorial for your first full campaign through our three Ages.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Keep in mind that the game has four different Advisors, and you can control which ones are actively leading you through a series of quests to teach you their portion of the game. If it's too much to take in all at once, we suggest listening to only a single Advisor at a time.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even after you’ve mastered enough systems to turn the tutorial off, you should switch to the setting Only Warnings, Beach recommended.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This setting allows these same Advisors to jump in and warn you if your empire's progress is about to undergo a major setback,” he said. “Even our internal team at Firaxis that knows this game so well plays with these warnings enabled!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Overnight, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-7-post-launch-roadmap-reveals-free-and-paid-content-updates-for-2025">Firaxis unveiled <u>Civilization 7</u>’s post-launch roadmap</a> as part of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GKbxcOGKINE" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a special livestream event</u></a> (Great Britain has been relegated to DLC). Civilization 7 itself launches on PC via Steam, on Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X and S on February 11, although the more expensive Deluxe Edition grants access from February 6.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>