<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:59:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-Action Horizon Zero Dawn Movie Has a 'Working Script,' Sony's Release Plans Revealed in New Court Document]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/live-action-horizon-zero-dawn-movie-has-a-working-script-sonys-release-plans-revealed-in-new-court-document</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/live-action-horizon-zero-dawn-movie-has-a-working-script-sonys-release-plans-revealed-in-new-court-document.1327765/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony is hoping to start filming of its live-action Horizon Zero Dawn movie in 2026 with a release at some point in 2027, according to a new court document.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-horizon-zero-dawn-movie-filming-release/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Game Post</a> said it had spotted the revelation in a court document filed as part of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-blasts-tencents-knock-off-horizon-lawsuit-response-as-nonsense-insists-damage-is-done-and-calls-for-injunction">Sony’s ongoing legal tussle with Tencent over Light of Motiram</a>, which it accuses of being a “knock-off” of Guerrilla’s video game, Horizon: Zero Dawn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the legal document, PlayStation Productions boss, Asad Qizilbash, said the Horizon Zero Dawn movie now has a working script and Sony is on the hunt for a director. The plan is to start filming next year and release the movie in 2027.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are in development for a film based on Horizon in partnership with Columbia Pictures,” Qizilbash said in his declaration. “We already have a working script and are actively searching for a director, with the goal of shooting the picture in 2026 and releasing it in 2027. The live-action film follows the recent collaborations between Columbia Pictures and PlayStation Productions on the 2022 film Uncharted and the 2023 film Gran Turismo.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Qizilbash also described Horizon protagonist Aloy as a “key icon in the anticipated film” and emphasizes her importance “to the flywheel of franchise building.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-film-confirmed">Sony announced the Horizon movie back in January during Sony's CES 2025 press conference</a>. Columbia Pictures produced the successful 2022 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/uncharted"><u>Uncharted movie</u></a> starring Tom Holland as Nathan Drake and Mark Wahlberg as Victor Sullivan, so it’s no surprise to see the collaboration continue here.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/17/gettyimages-2192213046-1760707612860.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">PlayStation Productions chief Asad Qizilbash. Photo by Ian Maule / AFP.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking on-stage at CES, Qizilbash said: "Columbia Pictures and PlayStation Productions are at the early stages of developing a film adaptation of the award-winning Horizon Zero Dawn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Just imagine, Aloy's beloved origin story set in a vibrant, far future world filled with the giant machines, brought to you for the first time on the big screen."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">During the same press conference, Sony announced <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-helldivers-2-film-in-production"><u>a film adaptation of Helldivers 2</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-anime-coming-exclusively-to-crunchyroll-in-2027"><u>an anime series adaptation of Ghost of Tsushima</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The question now is, who should play Aloy?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/live-action-horizon-zero-dawn-movie-has-a-working-script-sonys-release-plans-revealed-in-new-court-document]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Blasts Tencent's 'Knock-off Horizon' Lawsuit Response As 'Nonsense,' Insists 'Damage Is Done' And Calls For Injunction]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-blasts-tencents-knock-off-horizon-lawsuit-response-as-nonsense-insists-damage-is-done-and-calls-for-injunction</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-blasts-tencents-knock-off-horizon-lawsuit-response-as-nonsense-insists-damage-is-done-and-calls-for-injunction.1327762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has asked the courts for a preliminary injunction against <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/light-of-motiram"><u>Light of Motiram</u></a> maker Tencent to stop the Chinese megacorp from commencing pre-release promotion of the upcoming adventure game, filing its opposition to Tencent's motion to dismiss the high-profile copyright lawsuit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It comes after Sony <a href="https://thegamepost.com/damage-sony-tencent-nonsense-protect-light-of-motiram-horizon-knock-off-lawsuit/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>accused</u></a> Tencent of developing a "knock-off game [of Horizon Zero Dawn] so blatant that the public loudly decried the obvious and pervasive copying of Horizon’s protected elements," claiming the release of Light of Motiram "jeopardizes Horizon's continued success, including current expansion plans for the franchise."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony claimed Tencent's upcoming game Light of Motiram was nothing more than a "slavish clone" of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn"><u>Horizon Zero Dawn</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/sony-sues-tencent-over-slavish-horizon-knock-off-ign-daily-fix"><u>filed a copyright lawsuit in a California court at the end of July</u></a>, outlining numerous similarities and comparing various marketing screenshots from both games, as well as their descriptions. As we explained at the time, just like Horizon, Light of Motiram takes place in a post-apocalyptic world overrun by giant robot dinosaurs who roam large, natural environments such as tropical forests, deserts, and snowy mountains. Both games even feature red-haired women protagonists that wear very similar outfits and styles, and devices similar to Aloy's "Focus" earpiece.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Just days after Sony filed its lawsuit <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-is-suing-tencent-over-shameless-horizon-knock-off-game-light-of-motiram"><u>alleging the upcoming game was a "slavish clone" of Horizon</u></a>, Tencent quietly updated its Light of Motiram Steam page and swapped out a number of screenshots, including its cover image, before responding to Sony's lawsuit by claiming it was only making use of "well-trodden" tropes and suggesting the PlayStation maker's own game was too similar to Enslaved: Odyssey to the West.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tencent then hit back by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-copycat-drama-continues-as-tencent-claims-sony-was-already-concerned-its-game-too-closely-resembled-enslaved"><u>describing Sony's lawsuit an overreach</u></a>, highlighting other game franchises with similar elements to Horizon Zero Dawn such as The Legend of Zelda and Far Cry. It was "startling," Tencent said, that Sony was now attempting to claim Horizon's concept was original, rather than an idea based on "ubiquitous genre ingredients."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, as reported by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/damage-sony-tencent-nonsense-protect-light-of-motiram-horizon-knock-off-lawsuit/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>The Game Post</u></a>, Sony has dismissed Tencent's response as "nonsense," insisting "the damage is done – and it continues" and accusing the Chinese company of trying to minimize its involvement by using "shell" entities even though the Chinese firm remains "at the helm."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The copying was so egregious that numerous journalists and Horizon fans called Light of Motiram 'a major Horizon rip off,' 'an obvious knock off,' a 'copycat' with a main character that 'resembles Aloy to a tee,' and ‘extremely similar to Horizon Zero Dawn'," Sony wrote.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best PS5 Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That's not all, though. As spotted by <a href="https://gamesfray.com/breaking-sony-asks-judge-corley-for-preliminary-injunction-against-tencents-upcoming-light-of-motiram-in-november-or-december/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Games Fray</u></a>, Sony has also filed for a preliminary injunction in a bid to prevent Tencent from using a red-haired character in Light of Motiram, as well as other visuals or storyline elements close to that of the Horizon franchise. It hopes for the injunction to be enacted by the end of the year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tencent, however, maintains that with a scheduled release date on Q4 2027, Sony "cannot possibly hope to demonstrate the ‘immediate threatened injury’ that is the prerequisite of a preliminary injunction" given the game is so far from release. It attached declarations from a number of key stakeholders, including Guerrilla's head of music, Lucas van Tol, and artist Jan-Bart Van Beet who both claim they were "shocked" when they saw Light of Motiram, with Van Beet writing: "Tencent’s promotional material presents a visual setting almost identical to SIE’s Horizon promotional material."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"After spending over a decade creating and developing the Horizon franchise, it was disappointing to see our work copied to such a significant extent," he wrote. "Instead of spending the years and money that we invested into creating the Horizon world, Light of Motiram simply copied it, sidestepping the investment we made — and significant risk we took — in developing Horizon."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued: "There is an even greater risk of harm to the Horizon franchise if Light of Motiram, once released, does not have the same high quality as the Horizon games. The confusion caused by Light of Motiram promotions has already interfered with our existing Horizon development strategy, as there is a risk that future expansion could be incorrectly interpreted as copying Light of Motiram."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Van Tol wrote: "I have reviewed the music and sounds in Light of Motiram's promotional materials. I found striking similarities between their promotional trailer and the Horizon music. Light of Motiram's promotional materials contain the same core features of the Horizon sound, including the pillars, instrumentation, intimacy of the lead female voice, melodic composition, and rhythm, creating a similar overall feel."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The case continues. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-blasts-tencents-knock-off-horizon-lawsuit-response-as-nonsense-insists-damage-is-done-and-calls-for-injunction]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>