<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 06:38:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mojang Rules Out Minecraft 2: 'Do You Think We’re Going to Have an Earth 2?']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-rules-out-minecraft-2-do-you-think-were-going-to-have-an-earth-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mojang-rules-out-minecraft-2-do-you-think-we%E2%80%99re-going-to-have-an-earth-2.1142241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-rules-out-minecraft-2-do-you-think-were-going-to-have-an-earth-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft">Minecraft</a> celebrated its 15th anniversary last year, but despite growing into those troublesome teenage years, it appears that developer Mojang has no plans to replace it with a sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On a recent trip to the Stockholm studio, IGN asked about the possibility of the best-selling game of all time getting a sequel. Ingela Garneij, executive producer of Minecraft Vanilla, had an amusing, yet to-the-point answer for us: “Do you think we're going to have an Earth 2? No, no, there's no Minecraft 2.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Minecraft 2.0 is evidently not on the horizon, that doesn’t mean the survival-crafting phenomenon won’t continue to evolve. In fact, plans stretch way into the future, with a goal of at least doubling its current lifespan.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“We've existed for 15 years”, stated Garneij. “We want to exist at least 15 years more so we actually, Agnes [Larsson, Minecraft Vanilla’s game director] and I, we work as a team. We set the vision and strategy for our game for what can we do beyond that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s an ambition propelled by Mojang’s desire to innovate, continuing the mine and craft, so to speak, new ideas upon their rock-solid foundations. Those foundations are beginning to show their age, though, Garneij admitted, and while there are no plans for an engine overhaul, it does mean that new content, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-upgrade-the-start-of-a-new-graphical-journey">the newly revealed Vibrant Visuals graphics update</a>, does take time to put into practice. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I think the age of the game is a challenge," Garneij said. "It's a 15-year-old platform, 15-year-old technology that slows us down in one sense. So other new games have new engines, and they can run really fast. So I would say the technology and our age [are our biggest challenges].”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite this, Minecraft continues to be one of the most popular games in the world, and, as far as we can tell, shows no signs of slowing down. There's also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-its-the-best-deal-in-the-world">no plan for Minecraft to go free-to-play</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-wont-use-ai-minecraft-is-about-creativity-and-creating">take advantage of generative AI technology</a>. Just don’t expect to be playing Minecraft 2 in the near future. Not on this Earth, anyway.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-live-2025-vibrant-visuals-flying-happy-ghast-and-everything-announced">everything announced at Minecraft Live 2025</a> for more on what's coming to the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editorial Producer who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mojang Won't Use Generative AI, Minecraft Is 'About Creativity and Creating']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-wont-use-generative-ai-minecraft-is-about-creativity-and-creating</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mojang-wont-use-generative-ai-minecraft-is-about-creativity-and-creating.1142235/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-wont-use-generative-ai-minecraft-is-about-creativity-and-creating<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft">Minecraft</a> developer Mojang has no intention of incorporating generative artificial intelligence into its game development process.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The ever-increasing creep of generative AI into game development makes itself evident by the day, whether it’s Activision admitting to using generative <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-finally-admits-it-uses-generative-ai-for-some-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-assets-after-backlash-following-ai-slop-zombie-santa-loading-screen">AI art in Call of Duty: Black Op 6</a>, or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-and-hellblade-developer-ninja-theory-built-an-ai-called-muse-designed-to-generate-ideas-for-a-games-design-and-its-already-making-complex-gameplay-sequences">Microsoft building Muse</a>, an AI designed to "generate game ideas."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But, by the sound of it, Mojang has no plans of taking advantage of its parent company’s new technology, much preferring the human touch that resulted in Minecraft becoming the biggest-selling game of all time with an incredible 300 million sales.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Here for us, just like Minecraft is about creativity and creating,” stated Minecraft Vanilla game director Agnes Larsson during a recent event attended by IGN, “I think it's important that it makes us feel happy to create as humans. That's a purpose, [it] makes life look beautiful. So for us, we really want it to be our teams that make our games.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ingela Garneij, executive producer of Minecraft Vanilla, expanded on this sentiment: “For me, it's the thinking outside of the box part. This specific touch of: what is Minecraft? How does it look? That extra quality is really tricky to create through AI. We even try to have remote teams sometimes and guide them in building things for us, which has never worked, because you have to be here working together face-to-face.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I mean creativity is... you need to meet like this as a person, as a human to really truly understand the values and principles and the ecosystem, the lore, everything. It's so massive Minecraft, it's a planet, it's massive."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The humans making Minecraft continue to build on its record-breaking foundations. The newly revealed graphics update, titled <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-upgrade-the-start-of-a-new-graphical-journey">Vibrant Visuals, is due out in the near future</a>, and Mojang <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-its-the-best-deal-in-the-world">continues to refuse to make Minecraft free-to-play</a>. This philosophy of improving and expanding the original game also goes hand-in-hand with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-rules-out-minecraft-2-do-you-think-were-going-to-have-an-earth-2">Mojang's desire to not make a “Minecraft 2</a>." It may be 16 years old now, but there’s truly no sign of Minecraft slowing down, and no sign of generative AI finding its way into the Nether.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-live-2025-vibrant-visuals-flying-happy-ghast-and-everything-announced">everything announced at Minecraft Live 2025</a> for more on what's coming to the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editorial Producer who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Won't Go Free-to-Play: 'It's the Best Deal in the World']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-its-the-best-deal-in-the-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-its-the-best-deal-in-the-world.1142232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-its-the-best-deal-in-the-world<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Battle passes aren’t on their way.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">In an age when many live service games of its kind have pivoted to a free-to-play business model, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft">Minecraft</a> stubbornly remains a premium experience. During a recent interview with IGN, developer Mojang said it's determined to stick with the established "buy and own the game" approach, even now, 16 years after it came out. In short: don't expect Minecraft to go free-to-play any time soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Yeah, it doesn't really work with the way we built it," explained Ingela Garneij, executive producer of Minecraft Vanilla.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I mean we built the game for a different purpose. So monetization doesn't work in that way for us. It's a purchase of the game and then that's it. For us it's important that our game is available for as many people as possible. And so I think that's a very core value that it should be accessible for everyone. It's the best deal in the world.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As the industry has evolved over the years, many games have made the jump to free-to-download but infested with battle pass and cosmetic pack waters, with mixed results. Examples include Overwatch 2’s decision to go free-to-play, Destiny 2, or Minecraft’s Microsoft stablemate Halo Infinite (at least when it comes to its multiplayer).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The pressure is of course on video game publishers and developers to find new ways to monetize to survive, but this is seemingly a pressure not felt by Garneij and her Mojang teammates: “No, no. What's important for us is that many people can enjoy it still and that's going on strong still.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a sentiment expanded upon by Minecraft Vanilla’s game director, Agnes Larsson: ”I mean for me, it’s part of the important values of Minecraft. I think it's become such an important thing of what Minecraft is and the perfect culture and values, and I think we all here can agree on that. It's a thing for the game and it's one part of what makes the game strong. It has strong values.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Minecraft Vibrant Visuals Comparison Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Minecraft will continue to evolve without asking its players to spend money for new features, then. This is exemplified by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-upgrade-the-start-of-a-new-graphical-journey">the upcoming Vibrant Visuals graphics overhaul</a>, which arrives free of charge in the coming months. And with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mojang-rules-out-minecraft-2-do-you-think-were-going-to-have-an-earth-2">no plans for a Minecraft 2 on the horizon</a>, there’ll be no need to purchase the best-selling game of all time again any time soon. Unless you want to play it on another one of the seemingly endless amount of devices it finds itself on these days, of course.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-live-2025-vibrant-visuals-flying-happy-ghast-and-everything-announced">everything announced at Minecraft Live 2025</a> for more on what's coming to the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editorial Producer who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>