<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:46:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: A Great Deal On Samsung Galaxy S25 And MTG FF Preorder Is Still Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-14-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-a-great-deal-on-samsung-galaxy-s25-and-mtg-ff-preorder-is-still-live.1188942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-14-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I love getting a new phone, but what if you could get the latest <a href="https://zdcs.link/z62wwd?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Samsung flagship with double the storage and a $50 Amazon gift card</a> at no extra charge? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Welcome to today's deals, everyone. I am all over bargains this morning, including some cool preorders that are still live thanks to Magic: The Gathering <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjpwr2?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Final Fantasy Starter Kit</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QdbYZ2?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Bundle</a>. </p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">How about <a href="https://zdcs.link/av4Wwq?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">8 Xbox Game Studios Steam Keys for $10</a>? Humble has you covered. How about 15% off a <a href="https://zdcs.link/QKgjjV?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nvidia RTX 4070Ti prebuilt gaming PC</a> to play them all on too? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've even got a solid way to stay hydrated on filtered water with a <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7VV0?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">cheeky $30 discount thanks to Dreo</a>. You'll need a good fan to keep you cool this summer too, so I've found <a href="https://zdcs.link/QdbYlv?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$10 off one of the best Pedestal Fans</a> I've used for a while.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Everyone loves Squishmallows, every plushy or teddy bear should feel this soft. <a href="https://zdcs.link/91j3gn?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">There's up to 76% off them right now on Woot</a>, so there's no excuses this time. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Played Split Fiction yet? It's just got it's <a href="https://zdcs.link/aebN12?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">first discount for a PS5 physical copy over on Amazon</a>. Don't want to play games? No worries, watch one of the best Anime movies of all time with<a href="https://zdcs.link/aXWlby?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> an awesome steelbook in 4K</a> instead. Of course, we're talking about the cult classic, Akira.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Don't bother cleaning up before putting your feet up either, there's <a href="https://zdcs.link/z3Gxx3?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">20% off one of the best robot vac and mop</a> right now too. Let's get into it:</p><p id="prismatic-evolutions-surprise-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Prismatic Evolutions Surprise Box">Prismatic Evolutions Surprise Box</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220665"><div id="220665" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Prismatic Evolutions Surprise Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This was nearly $90 earlier this week, and it's still at a ridiculous price. The thing is, people are buying <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-review">Prismatic Evolutions</a> <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbblow?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Suprise Boxes</a> at multiple times their MSRP. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is one of the cheapest prices that's been live at Amazon. So if you wanted to buy one, now is likely a good time, especially since $59.99 now seems to be the market price at the very least.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Pokémon TCG Restocks</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">All the products in this caurosel are sold and shipped by Amazon, and there's some cool products in here including changes at Sword and Shield era chase cards in the Mimikyu ex Box and some lower priced Elite Trainer Boxes, such as Shrouded Fable, that are incredibly slept on at the moment. The choice is yours, but here's some great deals on Journey Together single cards.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Journey Together Single Cards</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We're seeing up to a 12% drop in Journey Together SIRs over the past couple of weeks, especially Lillie's Clefairy 184/159. Will it drop anymore? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Only time will tell, but it's on a steady downward trend, likely due to restocks and Journey Together pull rates being miles better than the likes of Prismatic Evolutions and the over saturation of Pokéball reverse holo cards. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for a steal? Articuno 161/159 has dropped by nearly over 50% since launch, finding its feet at a comfy $26.97 right now. It's a gorgeous illustration rare and deserves to be in everyone's binder.</p></div><p id="magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy">MTG Final Fantasy Starter Kit</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220727"><div id="220727" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Starter Kit</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Preorder, releases June 13</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Arguably one of the most popular boxes, the FFVII-focus starter kit features Cloud and Sephiroth decks and it's just under $20. If you was thinking about getting into Magic and have childhood trauma from swapping discs on PlayStation, this is your chance. </p></div><p id="mtg-final-fantasy-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="MTG Final Fantasy Bundle">MTG Final Fantasy Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="68e93635-0241-4f31-a015-1855f7eb6ae6" id="220749"><div id="220749" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy - Bundle</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Release Date: June 13, 2025.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/akKPW6?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Bundle</a> just went up for preorder at Walmart. This collectible set includes two traditional foil extended-art cards, 16 traditional foil basic lands, 16 nonfoil basic lands, two reference cards, a sturdy card storage box, and an oversized spindown life counter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The first wave of preorders for MTG Final Fantasy products was insane. Most products were cleared out within hours of them going live, but Wizards of the Coast seem to be ramping up production. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">More MTG Preorders and Restocks</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The current available products on Amazon are a mixed bag, with older products going for an absolute fortune with the $748.87 Theros Beyond Death Booster to preorders on the upcoming Edge of Eternities products, including the Collector Booster Box and Play Booster Box. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm really close to snapping up those Lord of the Rings sample bundles too.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">MTG Final Fantasy Single Cards</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Like Pokémon TCG, the savvy collectors and players will want to focus on single card prices. We're seeing a predictable climb on Kefka, Court Mage #332, with a listing starting at $68.33 at the end of May  and peaking at $77.53. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It looks like it's going to settle at around the $76.02 judging off current listings, but this could rise further following the release window of MTG Final Fantasy.</p></div><p id="xbox-game-studios-game-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle">Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220800"><div id="220800" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/av4Wwq?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Game Studios Humble Bundle</a> delivers eight must-play titles for as little as $5, including Wasteland 3, Ori and the Will of the Wisps, Quantum Break, and more. You don’t need an Xbox or a subscription, these are full Steam codes ready for PC players. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With classics like Sunset Overdrive and Age of Empires: Definitive Edition in the lineup, this collection offers hundreds of hours of gaming across a mix of action, strategy, and storytelling hits. Plus, every purchase supports Gameheads, a nonprofit helping underrepresented youth break into the tech and gaming industries.</p></div><p id="samsung-galaxy-s25-edge"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge ">Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge </h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220794"><div id="220794" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge </h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>+ $50 Amazon Gift Card + x 2 Storage</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/985rKd?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge</a> bundle gives you a serious upgrade: double the storage and a $50 Amazon Gift Card when you pre-order. This 512GB model pairs a sleek, ultra-slim titanium design with serious performance, thanks to Samsung’s most powerful processor yet. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its 200MP main camera captures pro-grade photos and crisp night video, while the titanium build and Gorilla Glass Ceramic 2 face offer excellent durability. Pre-orders close May 29, so if you want Samsung’s latest flagship with bonus perks, now’s the time to lock it in.</p></div><p id="sekiro-statue"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Sekiro Statue">Sekiro Statue</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220799"><div id="220799" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sekiro Statue</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Bring a piece of feudal Japan home with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QP82dP?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Sekiro Shadows Die Twice - Sekiro Statue</a>, now available for pre-order from the IGN Store. Crafted by First 4 Figures, this highly detailed resin collectible captures the Wolf mid-stride, gripping Kusabimaru with the Mortal Blade on his back. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">From the intricate design of Sekiro’s Prosthetic Arm to the weathered look of his shinobi robes, no detail is missed. Standing over 12 inches tall and set atop a themed base, this limited edition release also comes with an authentication card for collectors. Estimated to ship in Q2 2026.</p></div><p id="split-fiction-ps5"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Split Fiction (PS5)">Split Fiction (PS5)</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220804"><div id="220804" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Split Fiction (PS5)</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>First time discounted and top three best reviewed games of this year</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Team up for an unforgettable adventure with <a href="https://zdcs.link/aXWlZy?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Split Fiction for PlayStation 5</a>, a clever co-op platformer that flips between sci-fi and fantasy worlds. Designed for split-screen gameplay, you and a partner must master new mechanics and abilities in every level, coordinating closely to survive the surprises ahead. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The story follows Mio and Zoe, reluctant allies whose bond becomes their lifeline. We loved it so much that we awarded it an Editors' Choice badge and a strong 9/10 in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-review">our review</a>. If you're looking for your next great two-player experience, Split Fiction is a must-play.</p></div><p id="akira-4k-blu-ray-steelbook"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Akira 4K Blu Ray (Steelbook)">Akira 4K Blu Ray (Steelbook)</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220805"><div id="220805" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Akira 4K Blu Ray (Steelbook)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The landmark anime classic returns with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aXWlby?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Akira - Steelbook 4K UHD Blu-ray</a>, delivering a stunning remaster of one of the most influential sci-fi films ever made. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Follow Kaneda’s motorcycle gang as they tear through the streets of Neo Tokyo, only to be pulled into a secret government project when Tetsuo gains devastating psychic powers. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This sleek steelbook edition captures the full visual and sonic impact of Akira’s revolutionary animation in glorious 4K, making it essential for any serious anime collection.</p></div><p id="squishmallow-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Squishmallow Sale">Squishmallow Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220803"><div id="220803" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Squishmallow Sale</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Grab a bargain on fan-favorite plushies with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QbbZYj?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Squishmallows Woot Garage Sale</a>, where prices start at just $5.97. Score cuddly characters like the 10-inch Onel the Orange Eel, Torize the Pumpkin Pie, and Mac the Acorn, plus the 8-inch Bimbi the Clown all at massive discounts up to 81% off the original price.</p></div><p id="skytech-gaming-pc-desktop"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Skytech Gaming PC Desktop">Skytech Gaming PC Desktop</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220796"><div id="220796" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Skytech Gaming PC Desktop</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Intel Core i7 12700F 2.1 GHz, NVIDIA RTX 4070 Ti, 1TB NVME SSD, 16GB DDR4 RAM 3200, 750W Gold PSU, 360mm AIO</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Get high-end gaming performance with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7VK0?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Skytech Gaming PC Desktop</a>, now available for $1,699.99 (15% off). Packed with an Intel Core i7-12700F processor, an NVIDIA RTX 4070 Ti graphics card, 16GB DDR4 RAM, and a 1TB NVMe SSD, this rig is ready to crush 4K Ultra HD gaming at smooth frame rates. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also features a 360mm AIO cooler, a sleek tempered glass case with RGB fans, and comes bundled with a gaming keyboard and mouse. Perfect for everything from Warzone and Elden Ring to Valorant and Fortnite, this build is ready to tackle today’s most demanding games right out of the box.</p></div><p id="yeedi-s14-plus-robot-vacuum-and-mop"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Yeedi S14 Plus Robot Vacuum and Mop">Yeedi S14 Plus Robot Vacuum and Mop</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220797"><div id="220797" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Yeedi S14 Plus Robot Vacuum and Mop</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Make deep cleaning effortless with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxA0mO?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Yeedi S14 Plus Robot Vacuum and Mop</a>, now marked down to $949.99 (21% off). This powerhouse combines 18,000Pa suction with the advanced OZMO Roller mopping system to tackle stubborn stains and embedded dirt. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The ZeroTangle 2.0 tech keeps hair clogs at bay, while the smart OMNI Station automates everything from dust emptying to hot water mop washing and drying. Edge-to-edge cleaning is no problem thanks to TruEdge 2.0 precision, and you can fine-tune settings via the Yeedi app for an optimized carpet and floor-cleaning experience. A serious all-in-one upgrade for busy households.</p></div><p id="dreo-reverse-osmosis-water-filter-co"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Dreo Reverse Osmosis Water Filter Co">Dreo Reverse Osmosis Water Filter Countertop</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220795"><div id="220795" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dreo Reverse Osmosis Water Filter Countertop</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Enjoy pure, great-tasting water wherever you need it with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7OW3y?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dreo Reverse Osmosis Water Filter Countertop</a>, now $269.99 (10% off). This compact, no-installation-required system features a 7-stage filtration process that removes up to 99.99% of contaminants. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its 3:1 pure-to-drain ratio makes it eco-friendly, while the dual portable BPA-free pitchers let you hydrate at home, the office, or on the go. A real-time TDS monitor and smart display help track water purity and filter life effortlessly. Perfect for anyone looking for a plug-and-play upgrade to their daily water intake.</p></div><p id="dreo-pedestal-fan-with-remote"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Dreo Pedestal Fan with Remote">Dreo Pedestal Fan with Remote</h2></p><div id="220798" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dreo Pedestal Fan with Remote</h3></p></div><p id="silent-hill-2-ost-6lp-vinyl"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Silent Hill 2 OST 6LP Vinyl">Silent Hill 2 OST 6LP Vinyl</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220730"><div id="220730" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Silent Hill 2 OST 6LP Vinyl</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Preorder: Releases November 2025</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Dive deep into the atmosphere of Silent Hill with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aebeOW?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Silent Hill 2 Original Soundtrack 6LP Vinyl Box Set</a>, now available for pre-order at the IGN Store. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Featuring 93 haunting tracks from the 2024 remake, composed and reimagined by series legend Akira Yamaoka, this heavyweight vinyl collection comes housed in a deluxe rigid slipcase with printed sleeves and a 32-page art book filled with exclusive liner notes. Experience the eerie magic of Silent Hill like never before when it ships in November 2025.</p></div><p id="silent-hill-f-ps5-steelbook"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Silent Hill f - PS5 + Steelbook">Silent Hill f - PS5 + Steelbook</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220729"><div id="220729" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Silent Hill f - PS5 + Steelbook</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Amazon UK exclusive preorder, ships to US</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Preorder the <a href="https://zdcs.link/985pkR?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Silent Hill f - PS5 + Steelbook (Amazon UK Exclusive)</a> for £69.99 and experience a new chapter of psychological horror. Follow Hinako Shimizu through the fog-choked streets of Ebisugaoka, solving twisted puzzles and facing grotesque monsters in a town lost to silence. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This edition comes with an exclusive Steelbook case, and US buyers can also import it easily through Amazon UK with international shipping available.</p></div><p id="pathfinder-second-ed-asian-fantasy"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pathfinder Second Ed. Asian Fantasy ">Pathfinder Second Ed. Asian Fantasy Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220731"><div id="220731" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pathfinder Second Ed. Asian Fantasy Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Embark on your next epic adventure with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJgwPl?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pathfinder Second Edition Asian Fantasy Bundle</a> from Humble. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pay $5 or more to unlock a massive collection of 42 Pathfinder books, including Fists of the Ruby Phoenix and the Tian Xia Character Guide, packed with new campaigns, settings, and character options. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With a $691 value, this bundle is perfect for veterans and new adventurers alike — and every purchase helps support Stop AAPI Hate. Available for a limited time.</p></div><p id="dreamegg-portable-white-noise-machin"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Dreamegg Portable White Noise Machin">Dreamegg Portable White Noise Machine</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220728"><div id="220728" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dreamegg Portable White Noise Machine</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Block out distractions anywhere with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QqwAND?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dreamegg Portable White Noise Machine</a>, now just $13.19 on Amazon. This ultra-compact, egg-sized device weighs only 1.6 ounces yet delivers impressive sound quality with 16 different nature-inspired tracks, from ocean waves to gentle rain. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Upgraded with a 1000mAh battery, it can run for days on a single charge — perfect for travel, hotel stays, office privacy, or restless nights at home. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Dreamegg also includes precise volume control, an easy-to-use button layout, and convenient timer options to help you drift off faster.</p></div><p id="gravastar-wireless-mercury-m1-pro"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="GravaStar Wireless Mercury M1 Pro">GravaStar Wireless Mercury M1 Pro</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220671"><div id="220671" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>GravaStar Wireless Mercury M1 Pro</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Use 20% on-site coupon for full discount</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAp3p?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">GravaStar Mercury M1 Pro Wireless Gaming Mouse</a> combines a lightweight magnesium alloy body with a 26,000 DPI PAW3395 sensor for ultra-precise tracking. It supports tri-mode connectivity across 2.4GHz, Bluetooth, and wired options, with up to 200 hours of battery life. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fully programmable buttons, 4K polling support, and customizable RGB lighting round out a premium package for under $80 right now with stacked discounts. I've been using this for a couple of weeks now and it's become my favorite for work and getting a bit of Fortnite in.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Gaming Mouse Deals</h3></div><p id="xbox-game-studios-game-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle">Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220705"><div id="220705" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qr2OdE?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Game Studios Game Bundle</a> offers eight PC games for just $10, including highly rated hits like Ori and the Will of the Wisps, Quantum Break, Wasteland 3, and Sunset Overdrive. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">All titles redeem on Steam with no Xbox console required. With a total value of $214, it’s one of the best bundles running, and your purchase helps support the nonprofit Gameheads.</p></div><p id="corsair-k70-rgb-pro-cherry-mx-red"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Corsair K70 RGB Pro Cherry MX Red">Corsair K70 RGB Pro Cherry MX Red</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220694"><div id="220694" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Corsair K70 RGB Pro Cherry MX Red</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/akKXp5?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Corsair K70 RGB PRO Mechanical Gaming Keyboard</a> features fast, linear Cherry MX Red switches, an 8,000Hz hyper-polling rate for ultra-low latency, and durable double-shot PBT keycaps. It also includes a soft-touch palm rest and a tournament mode switch for competitive play. Down to $99.37 from $169.99, it's a strong pickup for serious gamers.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Gaming Keyboard Deals</h3></div><p id="clair-obscur-expedition-33-art-prin"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Art Prin">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Art Prints</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220704"><div id="220704" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Art Prints</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Measure at 12x16. Available on paper or canvas.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://null/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 12x16 Print</a> brings striking artwork from one of 2025's most anticipated games to your wall. Printed on premium hot press fine art paper or stretched canvas, each piece features vivid, fade-resistant colors on bright white, ultra-smooth stock or a durable solid wood frame. Officially licensed and exclusive to the IGN Store, it's a perfect addition for fans prepping for the surreal world of Expedition 33.</p></div><p id="buy-2-books-save-50-on-1"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Buy 2 Books, Save 50% on 1">Buy 2 Books, Save 50% on 1</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220697"><div id="220697" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Buy 2 Books, Save 50% on 1</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon is running a major <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qdb5Mx?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Buy 2, Save 50% on 1 Book Sale</a> across thousands of titles. Add any two eligible books to your cart and you’ll automatically save half off the lower-priced item at checkout. Popular picks include Sunrise on the Reaping by Suzanne Collins, The Let Them Theory by Mel Robbins, and The Psychology of Money by Morgan Housel. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a great chance to stock up on bestsellers, new releases, or even collectible editions at a serious discount. Just make sure to check for the "Qualifying Item" label before adding to cart. Oh, and don't miss the below Legend of Zelda books.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">My Favorite Books In This Sale</h3><div><div id="220698" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Included in Buy 2 Books, Save 50% on 1</p></div></div><div id="220699" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Legend of Zelda: Art &amp; Artifacts</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Included in Buy 2 Books, Save 50% on 1</p></div></div></div></div><p id="apple-airpods-pro-2"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Apple AirPods Pro 2">Apple AirPods Pro 2</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220700"><div id="220700" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirPods Pro 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aebeB1?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Apple AirPods Pro 2</a> are down to $169 at Amazon, their lowest price in months. These premium earbuds feature powerful Active Noise Cancellation that removes twice as much background noise as before, Adaptive Audio for seamless switching between noise canceling and transparency modes, and personalized Spatial Audio for a more immersive soundstage. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Powered by Apple’s H2 chip, they deliver clearer calls, richer bass, and better battery life, with a dust-, sweat-, and water-resistant design. The addition of hearing health features and a customizable fit makes these a smart upgrade for iPhone users.</p></div><p id="lego-technic-planet-earth-and-moon-i"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="LEGO Technic Planet Earth and Moon i">LEGO Technic Planet Earth and Moon in Orbit</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220701"><div id="220701" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Technic Planet Earth and Moon in Orbit</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9yDKLn?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">LEGO Technic Planet Earth and Moon in Orbit Building Set</a> is currently on sale for $59.95, down from $74.99 at Amazon. Designed for kids aged 10 and up, this 526-piece model lets young builders create a moving representation of the Earth and Moon orbiting the Sun. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It features printed months, moon phases, and an interactive crank mechanism to show how the orbits affect seasons. Whether used for learning or as cool space-themed room décor, it’s an imaginative way to bring the solar system to life.</p></div><p id="jason-x-4k-uhd-blu-ray"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Jason X 4K UHD Blu Ray">Jason X 4K UHD Blu Ray</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220702"><div id="220702" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Jason X 4K UHD Blu Ray</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7Rgg?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Jason X 4K UHD Limited Edition</a> is now $28.99 at Amazon, down from its $49.95 list price. This cult sci-fi slasher flings Jason Voorhees into deep space, where he unleashes carnage on an unsuspecting spaceship crew. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Arrow Video release comes packed with extras, including new and archival commentaries, documentaries, and a double-sided poster. Featuring Kane Hodder back in the mask and an upgraded 4K Dolby Vision transfer, this is a must for horror collectors.</p></div><p id="nintendo-switch-2-travel-carrying-ca"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Travel Carrying Ca">Nintendo Switch 2 Travel Carrying Case</h2></p><div catalogid="cfdff7da-51da-4bf2-8b73-9ca328f77d30" id="220703"><div id="220703" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Nintendo Switch 2 Travel Carrying Case</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Keep your gear safe with the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QKgbJD?object_uuid=460a8d70-11cc-469b-9083-e28afa15d211&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TZGZT Travel Carrying Case for Nintendo Switch 2</a>, now just $12.84 at Amazon (down from $27.73). Designed for the new Switch 2, this lightweight EVA hard case holds your console, accessories, and up to 24 game cards securely. It also comes bundled with two 9H tempered glass screen protectors for added protection. Tough, waterproof, and shock-resistant, it's perfect for travel or everyday carry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 14, 2025 11:47 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest 12 Creator Yuji Horii 'Can't Say Anything' Specific, But Wants You To Know He's 'Putting Lots of Work Into' The Secretive Sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-creator-yuji-horii-cant-say-anything-specific-but-wants-you-to-know-hes-putting-lots-of-work-into-the-secretive-sequel</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-12-creator-yuji-horii-cant-say-anything-specific-but-wants-you-to-know-hes-putting-lots-of-work-into-the-secretive-sequel.1188936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-creator-yuji-horii-cant-say-anything-specific-but-wants-you-to-know-hes-putting-lots-of-work-into-the-secretive-sequel<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Please look forward to it is the only thing I can say."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Quest creator Yuji Horii has confirmed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-quest-xii-the-flames-of-fate"><u>Dragon Quest 12: The Flames of Fate</u></a> has not been canceled. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-xii-the-flames-of-fate-officially-announced"><u>Dragon Quest 12 was announced</u></a> as part of the series' 35th anniversary celebration back in 2021, signalling the first mainline entry since 2017's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-quest-xi-echoes-of-an-elusive-age">Dragon Quest 11: Echoes of an Elusive Age</a>. It's been pretty quiet ever since, however; the last we heard about Dragon Quest 12 was in February, when <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-information-to-be-revealed-little-by-little-series-creator-yuji-horii-says"><u>Horii broke his silence to say the development team at Square Enix is “working hard”</u></a> and information about the game will be released “little by little." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And he wasn't wrong. Since then it's been complete radio silence, but in a new interview with <a href="https://www.gamereactor.eu/yujii-horii-still-working-really-hard-on-dragon-quest-xii-series-could-be-compatible-with-switch-2-1541753/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Gamereactor</u></a>, Horii has once again popped up to reassure fans everything is still on track.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/14/dq-1739184663911-1747220843178.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">All we have of Dragon Quest 12 is this logo, released in 2021.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Yes, indeed, I can't say anything, I apologize," he said. "I am making it, putting lots of work into it... I can only say that the next work will be great too, [I'm] working really hard. Please look forward to it is the only thing I can say."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While perhaps not quite as reassuring as a trailer or even some screenshots, this should at least come as a relief to fans who'd worried Dragon Quest 12 might have been canceled amid <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-maker-square-enix-takes-140-million-hit-in-content-abandonment-losses-as-it-revises-game-pipeline"><u>restructuring at Square Enix and a lack up updates</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In May 2024 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-still-in-development-despite-square-enix-cancellations"><u>Horii noted the deaths of Dragon Quest character designer Akira Toriyama and composer Koichi Sugiyama</u></a>. The series’ lead producer Yu Miyake had by that point already stepped down from his position to lead Square Enix’s mobile game division.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wait, Is That a Kid in GTA 6?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/wait-is-that-a-kid-in-gta-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wait-is-that-a-kid-in-gta-6.1188933/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/wait-is-that-a-kid-in-gta-6<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Grand Theft Auto series does not feature kids in gameplay. It’s a golden rule for pretty much all video games that let you indiscriminately kill NPCs. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/inzoi-players-surprised-to-discover-you-can-run-over-children-despite-teen-rating">Look at what happened with The Sims competitor inZoi earlier this year</a>, when players found they were able to run over children (the developer quickly patched it out and called it a bug).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, you can understand why a seemingly innocuous screenshot released for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">GTA 6</a> that looks like it shows a kid in-game has sparked so much speculation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The screenshot in question is of the Grassrivers section of GTA 6 (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/gta-6/Grassrivers">we’ve got a whole page devoted to the area if you want to know more</a>). If you look closely at the bottom right-hand corner of the image, below, you can make out a few people sitting at an outside table. One of these people looks a lot smaller than the other two, so much so that observers are saying it’s a child.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/14/grassrivers-02-1747219300699.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Time to play Where's Waldo? with this GTA 6 screenshot.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This detail was picked up by X / Twitter account TheGTAVerse and their post has since gone viral, picking up over 1.5 million views.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">A kid spotted in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTAVI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GTAVI</a> screenshot 👀 <a href="https://t.co/pGjSuNn9yt" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/pGjSuNn9yt</a></p>— TheGTAVerse (@TheGTAVerse) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGTAVerse/status/1922008313551606253?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 12, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that there is a <em>zero</em> chance that kids will be out and about in the GTA 6 game world, because that would mean you would be able to kill them, and that is a big no-no. GTA games are famous for letting you kill pretty much anyone in all manner of over-the-top ways. From simply beating a poor NPC to death with your bare hands to landing a plane on their head, GTA 6 will no-doubt ramp up the reckless NPC destruction.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So no, this screenshot does not confirm you can kill children in GTA 6. It is a screenshot of GTA 6 over a year away from the game’s release date. It is a snapshot of the game at this moment, and nothing more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But it is… odd to see what could be a child in a GTA 6 screenshot. If it is indeed a child. While most people do think it is a child, it could be a small adult, or there could be some sort of graphics effect at play here that makes what is an adult look smaller in this situation.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The release of GTA 6 Trailer 2 and Rockstar's accompanying info-dump has sparked all sorts of speculation about what to expect from what is sure to be the biggest video game of all time. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-some-grand-theft-auto-fans-think-liberty-city-is-a-secret-location-in-gta-6">Some GTA fans even think Liberty  City may end up in GTA 6 either at launch or as post-launch DLC</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we wait to find out, we’ve got plenty more on GTA 6, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/89-details-from-the-gta-6-trailer-2">all the details we’ve discovered so far</a>, a roundup of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-70-brand-new-screenshots-reveal-the-characters-and-places-of-leonida">70 brand new screenshots</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-gta-6-look-even-better-on-ps5-pro-experts-give-their-verdict">the expert opinion on how GTA 6 will look on PS5 Pro</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>