<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 17:08:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alex Garland’s Elden Ring Movie Should Feel Like Fantasy Warfare]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/alex-garlands-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alex-garland%E2%80%99s-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare.1218549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/alex-garlands-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you could hire any director to make an Elden Ring movie, who would you pick? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You might settle for fantasy heavyweights like Peter Jackson or Guillermo del Toro, or maybe you’d tap Miguel Sapochnik, the man who brought you many of Game of Thrones’ biggest battles, including Hardhome and Battle of the Bastards. If you’re looking for something a little more avant-garde, you could even pick Robert Eggers (Nosferatu), Yorgos Lanthimos (Poor Things), or Bong Joon Ho (Mickey 17) – filmmakers who, like Elden Ring developer FromSoftware, relish in the surreal, cryptic, and uncanny. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chances are, you wouldn’t pick Alex Garland. The British writer and director is known for the grounded, slow-burning science fiction dramas Ex Machina and Annihilation, as well as the inventively named war films Civil War and Warfare – none of which resemble FromSoftware’s work in any notable way. However, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/live-action-elden-ring-movie-on-the-way-from-a24-and-director-alex-garland">Garland is precisely who film studio A24 has selected to adapt Hidetaka Miyazaki’s magnum opus</a> for the big screen. Considering Garland – who, in addition to directing, is also set to write the screenplay – isn’t one to take his multi-digit checks and phone it in, you have to wonder how he’ll try to make this work. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/11/elden-ring-dragon-1749649681736.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A24's Elden Ring could focus on the moment-to-moment journey of a single Tarnished, rather than the sprawling saga of the land's lore. | Image credit: FromSoftware</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At a glance, Garland and Elden Ring do indeed seem like an odd match. Despite his considerable experience with sci-fi, Garland has yet to try his hand at hardcore fantasy – a tricky genre in its own right, and even trickier when dealing with video game adaptations. On top of this, his style doesn’t have a lot in common with FromSoftware’s. The narratives of Ex Machina and Annihilation are rooted in plot, dialogue, and characterization, while games like Dark Souls, Bloodborne, and Elden Ring tell their stories largely indirectly, through item descriptions and environmental design. (Civil War, set in tomorrow’s United States, was widely criticized for its lack of deep backstory). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But just because Garland has never made a fantasy film, doesn’t mean he can’t. He’s reinvented himself and ventured out into new frontiers before – Civil War and Warfare are radically different from Ex Machina and Annihilation, which are themselves unlike the films he wrote before making his directorial debut – so who’s to say he won’t do so again?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Actually, making an Elden Ring movie wouldn’t entirely constitute uncharted territory for Garland. Many people – including his own fans – don’t know this, but he’s actually an avid gamer. His experience playing the Resident Evil games apparently inspired his script for the 2002 horror 28 Days Later, and the 2000 film The Beach – based on one of his novels – features a game-inspired scene which <a href="https://www.polygon.com/opinion/601104/elden-ring-alex-garland-dredd-video-game-movies" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polygon’s Matt Patches described as “the closest thing we will ever get” to a Banjo-Kazooie movie</a> starring Leonardo DiCaprio.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Warfare evokes surprisingly similar feelings to those experienced while playing Elden Ring: outnumbered, outmatched, overwhelmed, afraid for your life (or runes). </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While many filmmakers seemingly feign interest in the material they’re hired to adapt in order to placate said material’s existing fanbase (to this day I refuse to believe M. Night Shyamalan watched even a single episode of Avatar: The Last Airbender), Garland’s love for The Last of Us, BioShock, and – most importantly – Dark Souls seems to be sincere. He appears to have a decent grasp of what makes the series unique and special compared to other games. <a href="https://youtu.be/TMdasaWiYD8?t=855" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Talking to Gamespot</a> back in 2020, Garland said, “The Dark Souls games seem to have this kind of embedded poetry in them. You’ll have some weird bit of dialogue with some sort of broken soul sat outside some doorway and it feels like you’ve drifted into this existential dream.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sticking to this image of an “existential dream,” Garland could take his Elden Ring adaptation in the direction of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/03/13/annihilation-review">Annihilation</a>, which upon release was praised for its psychedelic visuals. This would work, but it is not the only path forward. Another less obvious but arguably more effective plan of action would be to adapt Elden Ring in the mold of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warfare-review-alex-garland-will-poulter-noah-centineo">Warfare</a>, Garland’s nail-biting thriller about Navy SEALs fighting in Iraq. I say this not because there is something fantastical about this film – on the contrary, it’s been marketed as the one of the most realistic war films ever made – but because watching it evokes surprisingly similar feelings to those you experience while playing Elden Ring: outnumbered, outmatched, overwhelmed, afraid for your life (or runes). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Swap the war-torn Iraqi town of Ramadi for the ruins of Limgrave, alleyways of Leyndell, or badlands of Caelid, and what you’re left with is a film that adapts not the game’s encyclopedic, overarching backstory – the backstabbing saga of Marika, Godrick, Radagon, and the Demigods – but the minute, moment-to-moment experiences of the player’s Tarnished character wading through the Lands Between, so caught up in reaching the nearest Site of Grace in one piece that they have completely lost sight of their larger quest to become Elden Lord, whatever the hell that means. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Given that Garland is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-movie-director-eyeing-warfares-kit-connor-for-upcoming-adaptation">reportedly looking to cast one of the actors from Warfare</a> – Kit Connor – in the lead, it’s possible that his Elden Ring adaptation will end up adopting a similarly suspenseful tone, not to mention retread those themes of fear, despair, and senseless violence that Connor has already proven himself capable of conveying. Using Warfare as a blueprint for Elden Ring would not only take advantage of Garland’s strengths as a filmmaker who explores psychology through graphic, carefully choreographed action, but also follow the example set by the – fight me – only solid video game adaptation out there, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-1-review">season one of HBO’s The Last of Us</a>, whose quality is in large part derived from the fact that its creators understood what made the original great as a game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elden Ring, like FromSoftware’s other games, is not a power fantasy where heroes with supernatural abilities beat up giant monsters through flashy cutscenes and epic quick time events. It’s an anti-power fantasy that reduces players to nameless warriors who become well-acquainted with death and bang their head against the fog wall until they finally succeed. For Garland’s adaptation to reach the heights of his previous films, he’d do well to capture that bittersweet sentiment. And through his work on Warfare, we can catch a glimpse of what could be when Elden Ring finally arrives in cinemas. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tim Brinkhof is a freelance writer specializing in art and history. After studying journalism at NYU, he has gone on to write for Vox, Vulture, Slate, Polygon, GQ, Esquire and more.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pragmata Shows Capcom Trying New and Fun Ideas, and It Seems to Be Paying Off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pragmata-hands-on-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pragmata-shows-capcom-trying-new-and-fun-ideas-and-it-seems-to-be-paying-off.1218366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pragmata-hands-on-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">An all-new third-person shooter might be the most exciting thing in Capcom’s lineup.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom has been firing on all cylinders with its marquee franchises – <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-was-the-best-selling-game-in-the-us-for-march">Monster Hunter is seeing increasing success</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-9-requiem-hands-on-preview">Resident Evil train is continuing to roll,</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-launch-helps-street-fighter-6-hit-5-million-sales-2-years-after-launch">Street Fighter continues to be a staple in the fighting game community</a>. It has a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-gets-new-summer-game-fest-trailer-showing-more-slashy-combat">new Onimusha on the way</a>, and the last time we saw <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/06/devil-may-cry-5-review">Devil May Cry was on a high note</a>. But every now and then, Capcom experiments with something new, to varying degrees of success. And that latest experiment is in Pragmata, a sci-fi third-person shooter that stole the show for me at Summer Game Fest 2025 – even after just a brief 15-minute hands-on demo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another sci-fi third-person shooter may not sound too enticing on the surface, but Pragmata is an example of how a single idea can go a long way in distinguishing a game from the rest of the pack. Here’s the thing – in Pragmata you don’t just damage your enemies by shooting them, you have to hack them to open up their weaknesses. The way this works is by aiming down sights and engaging in a hacking minigame where you navigate a five-by-five grid using the face buttons to draw a path that connects specific nodes together. And you have to do this in real-time. Along that path, you can hit additional nodes to inflict status effects or open up weak spots, which can be risky when you’re locked in a room of multiple menacing robots chasing you down.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pragmata - Preview Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re nimble enough with your rocket-boosted dodge and smart with your positioning, you can pull this off unscathed, and it is so damn satisfying when it all comes together. When you’re mostly fighting in tight spaces, creating space to hack and shoot can be challenging. Pragmata isn’t exactly a fast-paced game in the same way as Vanquish or Returnal, and it moves more like a Dead Space or Gears of War, and I enjoy that chunky, heavy feel. You’re also not outfitted with a ton of weapons – while you have a six-shot pistol with unlimited magazines, you pick up disposable weapons like a slow, powerful heavy rifle and a Bola gun to temporarily immobilize enemies. These effective, limited-use weapons push you to be more resourceful and make combat more interesting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since you’re not blasting through waves of robots and drones, the combat encounters feel more deliberate – and I think that’s important for not overdoing it with the hacking minigame. My worry for now is that the novelty of the hacking minigame will wear off the deeper you get into Pragmata, but that’ll be determined by how the gameplay mechanics evolve and the way further combat encounters present new challenges. I’m actually bummed that the demo ends right when you approached a huge mech for what appeared to be a boss fight because it could’ve been an opportunity to showcase more of Pragmata’s potential.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>[Capcom's] latest experiment is in Pragmata, a sci-fi third-person shooter that stole the show for me...</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Hacking is also integrated in environmental puzzles and exploration, presenting you with different styles of sequential button prompts to deactivate security locks or access terminals. Little things like this to break up the pace are important in a fairly linear game where you’re chomping at the bit for the next big fight. You need that variety to balance out even the best parts of a campaign, and I at least enjoy the fact that engaging with levels still revolves around the hacking premise in some form.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether it be in combat or in exploration, I find a lot of fun in games that give you a more active element to engage with in its core gameplay. Although completely different genres, the timing-based mechanics of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 made its turn-based RPG combat feel fresh, and even the gesture-based inputs for abilities in Scarlet Nexus were a fun way to distinguish itself from other action-RPGs, which I still praise to this day. If Pragmata can build on its best ideas in smart ways, it might be able to wedge itself into this conversation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The demo didn’t have much in terms of story (and I’m glad it focused on its enticing gameplay hook instead), but it does leave me curious as to what the hell is going on in Pragmata. The basic premise is that you’re stuck on a high-tech space station on the moon, and you control a man named Hugh who dons a mech suit and uses a small arsenal of high-powered firearms, all while a mysterious little girl named Diana, who’s the hacking genius, sits on your shoulders to hack enemies. But even if the story is simply a vehicle to take you through its uniquely thrilling combat scenarios, I’m inclined to believe that’s all it has to be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I had no idea what Pragmata was when it was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-pragmata-capcom-release-date-2022">first revealed in 2020</a>, and after years of silence and delays, we know that it's real and on its way in 2026. I’m not expecting it to be the next greatest game or become a pillar of Capcom’s catalog, necessarily, but I’m all for new and well-executed ideas – especially at a time when AAA releases sometimes blend with each other.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mouse: PI for Hire Might Fill the Animated Void Cuphead Left Behind]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mouse-pi-for-hire-might-fill-the-animated-void-cuphead-left-behind</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mouse-pi-for-hire-might-fill-the-animated-void-cuphead-left-behind.1218339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mouse-pi-for-hire-might-fill-the-animated-void-cuphead-left-behind<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Cuphead did something in 2017 that we'd arguably never seen before in a video game, or at least nowhere near the degree Cuphead went to: it built an entire game around completely hand-drawn art and animation a la a 1930's cartoon. We haven't seen it since probably since doing all of that painstaking visual work by hand is incredibly difficult, time-intensive, and laborious. But now, a new hand-drawn and hand-animated project is getting ready to grace our PCs and consoles. It's called Mouse: P.I. for Hire, and fully handcrafted art is about the only thing it's got in common with Cuphead. Mouse is its own, equally gorgeous game, and after getting a look at a hands-off demo, I'm just as interested in it as I was when I first saw Cuphead. Which is to say, I’m very interested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you can obviously see, Mouse is in black and white. It's reminiscent of the Steamboat Willy era of early animation, complete with guns that are always wobbling even when they aren't in use, as if they're made of rubber. (More on the guns in a bit.) As you can also plainly see, Mouse is a first-person shooter. In it, you play as Jack Pepper, who in-demand video game voice actor Troy Baker plays with a stereotypical-on-purpose New York accent. He's an early-20th-century gumshoe, after all, see? He's got to sound like one. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mouse screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">What I really liked about the demo I saw of Mouse was that it wasn't just a mindless run-and-gun first-person shooter (not that there's anything wrong with that). Instead, the mission I saw part of was set at an opera house, where Pepper had to find and question the stage designer. We started at the back door, where we spoke to a waiter and asked about Roland, the aforementioned stage designer. He hasn’t seen him, so in we go to investigate for ourselves.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>What I really liked about the demo I saw of Mouse was that it wasn't just a mindless run-and-gun first-person shooter.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Inside, the kitchen gives you a better look at the visual aesthetic at play here. Notice how the characters are 2D within the 3D space, not unlike the monsters in the original Doom. A peek through the porthole window of the kitchen door shows off one of Mouse’s detective-y features: reconnaissance, as Jack takes a photo and sees some members of the Big Mouse Party – aka not guys we want anything to do with.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Moving to the back of the kitchen, we meet up with a slick waiter who’s happy to help sneak us upstairs to where we need to go quietly – for $30. We decline the bribe and instead find a vent we can sneak through. A bonus stash of cash hiding in the vent is appreciated, but the bottom falling out of the vent, crash-landing us back outside where we started, is very much not appreciated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Attempt number two takes us back through the kitchen and into the same vent, carefully crawling around the newly made hole in the floor and taking us to the dressing room, where a Thompson machine gun and some ammo await. You’re not supposed to be in here, of course, and the Big Mouse Party members don’t take kindly to your presence. It’s here that we get our first look at the first-person shooter combat, including one of the gorgeous reload animations.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We hear a muffled voice that might be Roland, but first a safe gives us a chance to see the lockpicking minigame in action, along with what the safe was hiding: a cup of coffee? Then things get really loud, as the wall in front of us blows up and we have to snuff out the bad guy that emerges from the smoke before using TNT ourselves to make a hole in the floor so we can make our way down into the bowels of the opera house.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, we’ve found Roland. He’s been beaten up by the extras, who Jack deduces aren’t extras at all, and learns the Big Mouse Party’s real plan: to assassinate mayoral candidate Stilton, who’s sitting in the balcony for that evening’s show, during intermission, using the cannon on stage that is both full of live ammo and pointed directly at him. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Fast-forward to more combat, including the shotgun, which looks like it packs a nice wallop – and also has a pretty awesome reload animation of its own. Plus a look at explosive barrels that leave the bad guys burning in the most cartoonish way possible. There’s even an ice barrel – liquid nitrogen, perhaps? – that freezes nearby foes when detonated, allowing you to kick them so they shatter into a thousand pieces, Terminator 2-style. Moments later we also got a look at the third weapon featured in the demo: the turpentine gun, which melts these cartoon characters who are literally made of paint, not unlike the Dip from Who Framed Roger Rabbit? </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The turpentine gun melts these cartoon characters who are literally made of paint, not unlike the Dip from Who Framed Roger Rabbit?</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">After a bit of platforming and fighting a new helicopter-tailed enemy type, we found our way back upstairs…only to have a trap door below our feet open up, dumping us back into the basement. It’s here we meet the Old Rat Stuntman, who teaches Jack the double-jump maneuver. After testing it out and discovering a secret – a baseball trading card of “Brie” Ruth (get it, because they’re mice and love cheese?) – we find our way back on stage to sabotage the cannon and save Stilton, which triggers a boss battle with a raging opera performer. The turpentine gun finishes him off, and we get a look at its reload animation, which if you ask me is even cooler than the others we’ve already seen.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The fire from the stage has spread to the rest of the opera house, and we’ve gotta get out of here. But we’re going to have to shoot our way out using every weapon at our disposal. No problem for Jack Pepper. Let’s watch some combat now, uninterrupted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally escaping the building, we meet up with the stage designer, who coughs up what he knows about the performer who’s vanished. Something about a secret lab underneath his mansion? No, that doesn’t sound suspicious at all… And with that, we exit the level and the demo ends.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And so, though I haven’t yet played it myself, from what I’ve seen of Mouse – and you just saw most of what I saw – I’m really eager to give it a try. It seems like it’s got the right lighthearted, somewhat comedic tone while also being self-aware but offering a solid first-person shooter at the core of it. After all, as gorgeous and admirable as its hand-drawn art and animation are, if the gameplay can’t back it up and also maintain my interest in it over the course of its campaign, then it won’t really matter how pretty it is. But at this point, I’m extremely optimistic.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mixtape Hands-on Preview: That Old, Familiar Song]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mixtape-hands-on-preview-that-old-familiar-song</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mixtape-hands-on-preview-that-old-familiar-song.1218318/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mixtape-hands-on-preview-that-old-familiar-song<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I remember the first time a boy made me a mixtape (okay, mix CD, same diff). It wasn't even a romantic gesture - he made them for all our friends. Mine had a now-embarassing mix of Morrowind music, Naruto OPs, Queen and Kansas (inexplicably), and uh, <a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/58184" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this song</a>. It was a wild mix of nerd stuff and absolute bangers that made no sense together at all. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So I can appreciate a really, really <em>good</em> mixtape, one that makes you feel big feelings and think big thoughts. Sure, I make my own Spotify playlists now for myself, but there's something tangibly retro about someone handing you a physical item of songs, perfectly selected and ordered, that they curated for a person, a moment, a space and time. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So what if that, in video game form? That's the entire premise of the aptly named game Mixtape that I previewed at Play Days last week. Mixtape follows three teens: Rockford, Slater, and Cassandra, though it's told from the perspective of Rockford and their final mixtape of the summer: a collection of musical hits to encapsulate their last night together with their best friends. See, Rockford has big dreams, and is headed to New York in the morning to take a huge, ridiculous swing on a future career that's incredibly, appropriately teenager of them and unlikely to pay off (though Rockford's plenty confident). So Rockford has assembled a pretentious lineup of perfect songs, each backing a different vignette from the crew's final night of mischief (and, occasionally interrupted by a flashback or a song they didn't necessarily intend to include).</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Mixtape manages to effectively capture a very specific flavor of reminisence for one's youth.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Look, even if Rockford's whole schtick is being a music elitist, they're right about one thing: they <em>do</em> compile an excellent mixtape. The whole game opens on "That's Good" by Devo, and the segment I played proceeds through Jesus and Mary Chain, Alice Coltrain...I don't want to spoil it too much, because the songs themselves <em>are</em> such a fundamental part of each moment and do a lot of heavy lifting to play into Mixtape's overall aura of nostalgia.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In fact, I think one thing I appreciate most about Mixtape is that <em>aside</em> from the music, this isn't a game jam-packed with specific pop culture references like so many other nostalgia plays love to do. The songs have got it covered. I'm not stopping every few seconds, pointing at an artifact or a joke and going, "I recognize that!" And yet, Mixtape manages to effectively capture a very specific flavor of reminisence for one's youth, and that feeling is injected into everything from Rockford's room decor to how the characters speak to the gentle, golden, almost-autumnal light permeating everything in the opening. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mixtape Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's another thing that struck me: the three main characters are, frankly, pretty annoying! And I love it! They're such <em>teens.</em> Older teens, sure, on the cusp of adulthood, but teens! I'm 34! I can't take them remotely seriously, and I'm not supposed to. The trio, while distinct in their personalities, all carry a slightly exaggerated self-obsession, that feeling I remember well from being 17, 18, 19, and thinking my concerns were at the center of the universe. Obnoxious quirks and all, I'll be happy to spend a full evening with all three in the full game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The actual meanest thing I can say about Mixtape is that at least in the snippet I played, you're not <em>doing</em> very much. There's some skateboarding, and a sequence where you careen through the town on a shopping cart, and in both situations you steer, but I'm not sure there's really any consequences for doing either activity well or poorly, or any reason to try very hard. You can headbang to music played loud in a car. Mostly, from what I saw, you walk around a room and look at things while talking to your friends. The most interesting gameplay was an extended section where you simulate two awkward teenage tongues making out in a simultaneously hilarious and disgusting interchange. I get the sense that the wider game will likely play out more as a series of minigame vignettes that one specific flavor of video game, but as it stands I'm hard-pressed to explain to you what it is you're going to be doing, mostly, throughout the rest of Mixtape.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The thing is, whether the rest of the game turns out to be action-packed or not, I'm not really sure it matters for what Mixtape is going for. This is a <em>vibes</em> game through-and-through, and Mixtape's vibes are impeccable. I'm happy to let Rockford take me along on whatever journey they and their friends are about to head out on, one song at a time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>