<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:21:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders Revealed During Nintendo Switch 2 Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-revealed-during-nintendo-switch-2-direct</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-air-riders-revealed-during-nintendo-switch-2-direct.1152696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-revealed-during-nintendo-switch-2-direct<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby’s racing spinoff Kirby Air Ride is making a tremendous comeback after more than 20 years, thanks to a new entry for Nintendo Switch 2: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The project made its grand debut during today’s special Switch 2 presentation, revealing a cast of colorful Kirbys and new spacey vehicles to travel with. No gameplay was revealed, with Nintendo instead choosing to reveal the project with a cinematic trailer and the promise of a 2025 release window. We likely won't have to wait too long to see how the sequel builds on the original GameCube game, but we can at least rest easy knowing Kirby creator and Super Smash Bros. mastermind Masahiro Sakurai is serving as the project's director.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see the Kirby Air Riders reveal trailer below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo released its original <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kirby-air-ride">Kirby Air Ride</a> spinoff for GameCube players in 2003. It's an off-the-wall entry for the all-powerful pink hero that sees him trading out platforming challenges for fast-paced racing gameplay. It's unclear how exactly Kirby Air Riders will shake up the formula, but after more than two decades of waiting, Sakurai and his team will surely have plenty to reveal at a later date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last original new Kirby game was Kirby and the Forgotten Land for Nintendo Switch. This was Kirby's first adventure in a full 3D perspective, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-review">we gave it an 8/10</a>. We said that it "successfully warps the series’ already fun mix of ability-based combat, platforming, and secret hunting into the third dimension. The post-apocalyptic setting may not be as thematically interesting as Planet Popstar, but it is still lovely and vibrant, with cleverly designed levels that make consistently smart use of Kirby’s abilities."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 - Kirby AirRiders</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 is currently scheduled to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-confirmed-during-nintendo-direct">launch June 5, 2025</a>. You can catch up on everything announced at today's Nintendo Switch 2 Direct right <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4 Are Launching Alongside the Nintendo Switch 2 in June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapters-3-and-4-are-launching-alongside-the-nintendo-switch-2-in-june</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deltarune-chapters-3-and-4-are-launching-alongside-the-nintendo-switch-2-in-june.1152690/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapters-3-and-4-are-launching-alongside-the-nintendo-switch-2-in-june<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Toby Fox has been a busy guy. During today's Nintendo Switch 2 Direct, the small white dog dev showed the first full trailer for Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4, revealing that chapters 3 and 4 will launch alongside the Nintendo Switch 2 on June 5. It will also be available on all other platforms: PS5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Deltarune's first two chapters are mysterious little RPGs following a character named Kris through their adventures in a "Dark World" with their classmate Suzie and a prince named Ralsei. They borrow a number of characters and themes from Fox's previous work, Undertale, but thus far it's been unclear if there's any relationship between the two stories. Trailers lately have been referring to it as a "parallel" story to Undertale.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In today's trailer, we got our first-ever look at Chapters 3 and 4, though the look was cryptic as is Fox's wont. There was a brief look at the Castle Town with all the characters we've met so far hanging out together (including Queen!), a new battle that looked like some sort of rock show with Guitar Hero-like controls, Suzie throwing Kris into what looks like a chapel with both characters slightly off-color, and a look at two new villains. One, for Chapter 3, appears to be a creepy smile in a static-y TV (recalling the tease at the end of Chapter 2), and the other, a bit less comprehensibly, seems to be a pile of...weird jellyfish? That Suzie and Kris are running from? No idea.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Deltarune has thus far been released chapter by chapter, with chapter 1 coming out on Halloween 2018, and Chapter 2 debuting in September of 2021. Both of the first chapters were free. The total number of chapters is still unknown, but the menu screen has previously seemed to hold room for seven total, meainng that two more may be on the way. The anticipation for these latest chapters has only grown in the last year, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapters-3-and-4-will-100-come-out-in-2025-says-creator-toby-fox">Fox confirming last Halloween that 3 and 4</a> would "100% come out in 2025". The Nintendo Switch 2 version will include all four chapters, including the two previously released.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though we haven't yet reviewed the beginnings of Deltarune, we gave Fox's previous game, Undertale, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/09/18/undertale-review">rare 10/10</a>, calling it a "masterfully crafted experience."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can catch up on everything announced at the Nintendo Direct today <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Finally Implements a Real, Normal Voice Chat Feature With Its New C Button]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-finally-implements-a-real-normal-voice-chat-feature-with-its-new-c-button</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-finally-implements-a-real-normal-voice-chat-feature-with-its-new-c-button.1152684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-finally-implements-a-real-normal-voice-chat-feature-with-its-new-c-button<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A first look was shown during today's Nintendo Direct.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">They did it. The absolute madmen did it. During today's Direct covering all things Nintendo Switch 2, it was demonstrated that for the first time ever, the console will have a built-in voice chat feature thanks to its infamous C button.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The showcase revealed how players will be able to seamlessly bond when playing their favorite Nintendo Switch 2 titles, all with the press of that C button. Discord users will note that the footage shown reveals a variety of familiar features, including a similar layout where players can watch each other enjoying the same or different titles and, with the help of a camera that can be purchased separately, even see each other. It's made all the easier by a built-in microphone that is shown to be relatively reliable regardless of each player's gaming environment.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo is looking to bring that gaming party setting to players to the comfort of their homes when Switch 2 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-confirmed-during-nintendo-direct">launches this summer</a>. That means helping a friend out by watching their game stream will be just as easy as organizing a group photo in a game like Mario Kart World. The C button's chat menu aims to be an all-in-one multiplayer feature that could result in Nintendo's most successful online push in decades.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has tried out a version of a voice chat before, but none of them have ever been just a normal voice chat feature like everyone else has. In 2017, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/07/19/nintendo-switch-online-app-is-available-to-download">it launched the Nintendo Switch Online app</a>, which allowed players to voice chat with friends while playing specific, compatible games. However, the app's functionality was limited, and critically, tied to the phone instead of the system itself. This is the first time Nintendo's ever had the voice chat actually built in, and at last puts a cap on a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/03/18/nintendo-voice-chat-podcast-episode-1">running joke IGN's been making about Nintendo Voice Chat for years now</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We're still dissecting everything we saw this morning on the Nintendo Switch 2, so check out our breakdown of everything announced today. And if you want to tune into the real Nintendo Voice Chat that's been there for you all along, you can <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/nintendo-voice-chat">check out our podcast page</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 C Button &amp; Camera Slideshow</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Everything Nintendo Switch 2 voice chat is able to do remains unclear, but it already looks leaps and bounds better than the previous Switch voice chat option that required the use of a mobile app. For a better look at everything else Nintendo had to show during today’s Nintendo Switch 2 Direct, you can click <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Developing...</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>