<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:55:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every God of War Game on PS5 in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/all-god-of-war-games-on-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-god-of-war-game-on-ps5-in-2025.1316089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">You can play most of the mainline series on a current-gen console. </h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's hard to deny the massive effect the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/god-of-war">God of War</a> franchise has had on the gaming landscape. Kratos' initial Greek-inspired revenge story was one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps2-games">best PS2 games of all time</a>, while his powerful redemption arc in the more recent Norse soft reboot earned first place on our list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps4-games">best PS4 games</a>. I'd go so far as to say Kratos is one of PlayStation's most recognizable mascots. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking to catch up on all of the adventures Kratos has taken, or simply want to revisit the God of War games you loved in the past, you'll be able to play most of them on your current-gen PlayStation 5. Here's what you need to know. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">How Many God of War Games Are There on PlayStation 5?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">God of War: Ragnarok is the only game in the series that has launched during the PS5 generation. However, there are a total of <strong>six God of War games available to play on the current-gen console</strong>. This includes all six mainline entries in the series, which span from God of War (2005) to God of War Ragnarok (2022). Two of those games relies on backward compatibility, while three of the earlier titles require a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/playlist/igneditorial/lists/playstation-plus-premium-tier-games">PlayStation Plus Premium subscription</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The two God of War spin-offs on PSP, Chains of Olympus and Ghost of Sparta, are not currently available on PS5. Here's to hoping that Sony will eventually add these two well-received portable games to PlayStation Plus.</p><div catalogid="622d6e82-9d6e-4fe2-9fc0-5c878daf6f75" id="228765"><div id="228765" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>God of War: Ragnarok</h3></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">Every God of War Game on PlayStation 5 in Release Order</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">God of War III Remastered (2010)</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/zn5e4b?object_uuid=14ce168e-1a3e-4a3f-998f-c8436592da6f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See on Amazon</a> (PS4) </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/07/14/god-of-war-3-remastered-review">God of War III Remastered</a> serves up visual and performance improvements to the third mainline game, which also serves as the final entry in Kratos' Greek saga. In it, Kratos climbs Mount Olympus as he seeks to reach its zenith and bring his full might down upon the gods who wronged him. This provides a satisfying end to his original character arc that began with God of War (2005), making it essential for truly understanding the emotional stakes of 2018's soft reboot. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">God of War (2018)</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QKqYpY?object_uuid=14ce168e-1a3e-4a3f-998f-c8436592da6f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See on Amazon</a> (PS4) </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/04/12/god-of-war-review">God of War (2018)</a> gives one of its most aggressive and venegeful characters in gaming a true redemption arc as well as an all-new combat system. In this wildly successful and emotionally potent soft reboot, Kratos has left the Greek pantheon and traveled to the Norse realm where he's now tasked with raising his young son, Atreus, while attempting to hide his past. But as the duo fight through a harsh and unforgiving land, Kratos is forced to face the truth that there remain parts of his nature he can't surpress if he wishes to protect those he loves most.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">God of War Ragnarok (2022)</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/zj7b2P?object_uuid=14ce168e-1a3e-4a3f-998f-c8436592da6f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See on Amazon</a> (PS5) </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Picking up about three years after God of War (2018), <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-ragnarok-review">God of War Ragnarok</a> sees Kratos and Atreus forced to take on the Norse pantheon in an attempt to stop the complete destruction of the nine realms. Ragnarok's story continues to deal with larger themes of familial trauma and identity as Kratos comes to terms with his son becoming a young man while also trying to figure out what's next in his own journey for true redemption. This entry features a larger world to explore and more combat options, as well as many more characters used to fill out a more expansive narrative.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Available God of War Games on PlayStation Plus Premium</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The remainder of the God of War games require you to have a PlayStation Plus Premium subscription. Here are the games you can only play if you've signed up for PlayStation Plus Premium:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>God of War HD (2005)</li><li>God of War II HD (2007)</li><li>God of War: Ascension (2013)</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Upcoming God of War Games</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">No new games in the God of War franchise have been announced since <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/god-of-war-ragnarok/Valhalla_DLC_-_Overview_and_Guide">God of War Ragnarok's unexpected Valhalla DLC</a> in 2023. However, rumors have circulated about both a 2D metroidvania spin-off set in the Greek era, while the next mainline entry <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/reinvention-is-key-to-god-of-wars-continued-success">could potentially take place in ancient Egypt</a>. Until developer Santa Monica Studio makes a formal announcement, though, it's best to take it all with a grain of salt. Otherwise, the God of War franchise is celebrating its 20th anniversary this year with a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-ps5-controller-where-to-buy">new limited edition PS5 controller</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Billy Givens is a freelancer at IGN with over a decade of experience writing gaming, film, and tech content. His work can also be found on GameSpot, USA Today, Digital Trends, Tom's Guide, and more. You'll find him blabbering on about video games and more on Twitter at @mektige.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 3, 2025 6:03 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/all-god-of-war-games-on-ps5]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: The 10 Best New Mega Evolution Cards That I Think Are Worth Chasing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-most-popular-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-the-10-best-new-mega-evolution-cards-that-i-think-are-worth-chasing.1316086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-release-full-release-schedule-2025">Pokémon TCG’s latest expansion, Mega Evolution</a>, has only just landed, yet it’s already reshaping <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-most-expensive-cards-2025">collector wishlists</a> and competitive deck-building alike. From glittering Special Illustration Rares to powerful Mega ex cards, the set has proven to be a goldmine for players and investors.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even when the set first launched, there were already those that had been declared the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-cards-most-expensive-cards"><u>most valuable cards in Mega Evolution</u></a>. Days later, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gjRDe?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGPlayer’s</u></a> best-seller charts have now revealed which cards are flying off digital shelves, and why fans are rushing to pick them up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are the most in-demand singles from Mega Evolution that are almost certainly worth chasing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">TL;DR: 10 Best-Selling Pokémon Cards from Mega Evolution</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who want to jump right in, here are the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qxxm8P?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">top-selling Pokémon cards from the Mega Evolution set on TCGPlayer</a> so far. The Mega Evolution expansion is already a collector’s dream, with Mega Lucario ex (Holo Rare) topping sales at a $1,299.99 market value &amp; Mega Gardevoir ex close behind at $799.99. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Venusaur ex ($499.99) and Marshadow ($199.99) round out the heavy hitters, while Lillie’s Determination and even Gumshoos are proving surprisingly popular. Below, however, check out the full rundown of the ten hottest cards fans are chasing right now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Mega Latias ex – 181/132 (Special Illustration Rare)</h2><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228664"><div id="228664" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Latias ex - 181/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">At approximately $299.99, <a href="https://zdcs.link/aADOL4?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Latias ex</a> offers versatility in combat to go with its striking visuals, immediately showing why it’s one of the Pokémon TCG’s most in-demand cards from Mega Evolution. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its Strafe attack enables clever switching plays, while Illusory Impulse deals a blistering 300 damage at the cost of discarding Energy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Akira Egawa’s colourful, swirling art makes the Dragon-type legend look like it’s bursting straight out of the card. It’s as playable as it is collectable, and it earns its spot as the set’s tenth hottest seller.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Lillie’s Determination – 119/132 (Uncommon)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228665"><div id="228665" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lillie's Determination - 119/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Currently trading around $8.99, this budget-friendly Supporter has nonetheless become a staple. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The effect, of <a href="https://zdcs.link/ao6voe?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Lillie’s Determination</a>, refreshing your hand and potentially drawing up to eight cards if you’re at full Prizes, makes it both flexible and efficient. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Collectors also appreciate Atsushi Furusawa’s sunny artwork, which frames Lillie in a lovely pastoral scene, making even the lowest-rarity printing feel special.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Lillie’s Determination – 169/132 (Ultra Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228666"><div id="228666" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lillie's Determination - 169/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Jumping up in price, this version of <a href="https://zdcs.link/QWERLd?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Lillie’s Determination</a> sits at about $38. While this variant of the card shares the same gameplay text, its foil treatment and alternate pose of Lillie in a breezy summer outfit elevate it for collectors. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Competitively useful and aesthetically pleasing, it hits that sweet spot of playability and visual charm for lovers of both the Mega Evolution set and the Pokémon Trading Card Game in general..</p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Mega Venusaur ex – 177/132 (Special Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228667"><div id="228667" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Venusaur ex - 177/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">At roughly $220, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QmOlAn?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Venusaur ex</a> shows why Grass decks are back in the conversation. Its Solar Transfer ability allows players to reposition Energy across the board, while Jungle Dump brings a hefty 240 damage and healing on top. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The bold, almost neon background complements Venusaur’s bulk, making it one of the most visually explosive cards of the set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Gumshoos – 153/132 (Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228668"><div id="228668" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Gumshoos - 153/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Surprisingly, <a href="https://zdcs.link/aN8KL3?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Gumshoos</a> is among the hottest sellers, shifting for around $59.99, above its current market price of $28. The card’s Evidence Gathering ability lets you effectively cycle a card from hand into your deck, smoothing consistency in unexpected ways. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mina Nakai’s gritty alleyway artwork adds narrative noir flair, giving this otherwise humble Stage 1 the kind of character that turns heads.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Mega Lucario ex – 179/132 (Special Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228669"><div id="228669" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Lucario ex - 179/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This Special Illustration Rare of <a href="https://zdcs.link/9l2eRx?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Lucario ex</a> currently fetches about $280, and it’s easy to see why. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Aura Jab accelerating Fighting Energy and Mega Brave hitting for a massive 270, Lucario slots perfectly into aggressive decks. The art, by 5ban Graphics, depicts Lucario mid-leap with fierce energy bursts against a Mega Venusaur, a dynamic visual that mirrors its high-impact playstyle.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Lillie’s Determination – 184/132 (Special Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228670"><div id="228670" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lillie's Determination - 184/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Another entry for <a href="https://zdcs.link/aDrJLN?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Lillie’s Determination</a>, and this one’s both the most valuable and in-demand, going for around $225. The floral backdrop and soft colour palette make this perhaps the most elegant version. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond its art, the card remains a valuable draw engine in decks seeking early-game acceleration, ensuring it appeals to both sides of the player base.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Mega Lucario ex – 188/132 (Hyper Mega Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228671"><div id="228671" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Lucario ex - 188/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The undisputed third best-seller, the golden <a href="https://zdcs.link/QdpZGv?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Lucario ex</a> card is topping Pokemon TCG listings charts at a staggering $900 price against a $570 market price. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Aura Jab enabling Energy recovery and Mega Brave delivering 270 damage like its other versions, this card exemplifies the high-risk, high-reward nature of Mega ex. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The gold finish, courtesy of 5ban Graphics, turns Lucario into a gleaming centrepiece. Competitive players want it, collectors covet it, and together they’ve pushed it to the very peak. If you have one of the cheaper versions of Mega Lucario ex, it’s better to keep this one safe in your binder rather than put in your deck.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Marshadow – 146/132 (Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228672"><div id="228672" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Marshadow - 146/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Marshadow has spiked dramatically since launch, with listings around $110 vs an $73 market price. The attack Shadowy Side Kick not only hits decently, but also protects <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gjR2G?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Marshadow</a> from retaliation if it takes a knockout. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Combined with Tomomi Ozaki’s moody, lantern-lit forest artwork, the card’s blend of tactical resilience and atmospheric presentation explains its meteoric rise.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Mega Gardevoir ex – 178/132 (Special Illustration Rare)</h2></div><div catalogid="2dce66b8-2022-48cf-9c52-e0e3ddf24bc6" id="228673"><div id="228673" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Gardevoir ex - 178/132</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Both sitting as the one of the highest-priced cards in Mega Evolution, and being the most popular, it’s not difficult to understand why this <a href="https://zdcs.link/akwW4g?object_uuid=00e6cc59-5995-4504-98ae-f4364156b82c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Gardevoir ex</a> is the biggest chase card in the set. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gardevoir’s Overflowing Wishes accelerates Psychic Energy across your bench, while Mega Symphonia scales into massive damage with enough Energy in play. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Takuya’s art envelops the card in a symphony of pinks and whites, making it as enchanting as it is powerful in Psychic archetypes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 3, 2025 5:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-most-popular-cards]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>