<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:26:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Boss Todd Howard Won't Rule Out an Elder Scrolls TV Show, but Says Fallout Was 'More Uniquely Suited' for an Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-boss-todd-howard-wont-rule-out-an-elder-scrolls-tv-show-but-says-fallout-was-more-uniquely-suited-for-an-adaptation</link>
            <guid>1375144</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After the huge success of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/fallout-the-series">Amazon Fallout TV show</a>, some have wondered whether The Elder Scrolls, Bethesda’s fantasy video game franchise, might be next in line for an adaptation. But what does Bethesda boss Todd Howard think?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/an-elder-scrolls-tv-series-cant-be-ruled-out-todd-howard-teases-but-remains-tight-lipped-on-the-status-of-the-wolfenstein-adaptation" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> ahead of the launch of Fallout Season 2, Howard refused to rule out the possibility of an Elder Scrolls TV show, but did suggest the post-apocalyptic sci-fi franchise Fallout was better suited to an adaptation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I will say this, the Fallout journey was like a 10 year one," Howard replied to the suggestion of an Elder Scrolls adaptation. "After Fallout 3, people were asking to do a movie or show for Fallout, and we really took our time."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Howard "can't rule in or rule out an Elder Scrolls thing in the future," Eurogamer said, but he also believes the Fallout franchise was "more uniquely suited" and had "more to say in its genre.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Howard continued: "But, you never know. I think the impact of the show on Fallout as a franchise has been bigger than I expected, so it does make you think like, 'Hey, is there a path?' But, nothing today... [and] I'm willing to say 'no' for a decade."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Fallout series is wide-ranging in tone and content. Indeed, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-knew-what-i-was-walking-into-fallout-season-2-star-macaulay-culkin-already-knew-all-about-the-lore-from-watching-youtube-videos">Season 2 star Macaulay Culkin touched on this in a recent interview with IGN</a>, explaining why he’s so big into the Fallout lore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You could have zombies in it, you have deathclaws, you have monsters and things like that,” he said. “I mean, gosh, you have aliens. You name it, you can throw it at the wall. Even Fallout 76, I mean, the Mothman is now fair game. It is that kind of stuff. There's no really shape to it. You can kind of stick any kind of shape piece into that hole.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Fallout Season 2: Who's Confirmed to Return and Who's New?</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And in any case, there’s no sign of Fallout slowing down when it comes to the TV series. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-season-2-premieres-december-2025-renewed-for-season-3">Season 3 is already confirmed</a>, and its stars have indicated they’d be willing to continue playing their characters for many more series beyond that. In May, Aaron Moten, who plays Brotherhood of Steel hopeful Maximus, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-tv-show-has-a-season-5-or-season-6-type-of-endpoint-maximus-actor-says">said the Fallout series’ “endpoint” runs until Season 5 or Season 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“When I signed on to do the series, we would have a starting point and they gave me the endpoint,” Moten said. “And that endpoint hasn’t changed. But it is Season 5, 6 type of endpoint.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We’ve always known that we were gonna take our time with the development of the characters.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps when that is done and dusted, Bethesda might turn its attention to an Elder Scrolls adaptation. Will <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi">The Elder Scrolls 6</a> be out by then? One can only hope.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-boss-todd-howard-wont-rule-out-an-elder-scrolls-tv-show-but-says-fallout-was-more-uniquely-suited-for-an-adaptation]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Lord of the Rings Chess Set Is the Gift You Didn't Know You Needed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-chess-set-gift-for-2025</link>
            <guid>1375036</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I've always loved The Lord of the Rings. I wouldn't necessarily say I'm fanatical about it, though. I already own copies of the books <em>and</em> the movies, so I'm not usually swayed by the endless barrage of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-lord-of-the-rings-gift-ideas">Lord of the Rings gifts</a> the internet seems to throw my way. I <em>do</em> really like the look of this Battle for Middle-Earth Chess set, however. I've seen a lot of really <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-chess-sets">cool chess sets</a> in my day, but this one appears to be surprisingly well done for how affordable it is. I don't even play that much chess and I've found myself adding it to my Christmas wishlist this year.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Lord of The Rings Chess Set: Battle for Middle-Earth</h2><div catalogid="6975b578-071f-48b6-80c8-76451dd7ba35" id="233400"><div id="233400" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Lord of The Rings Chess Set: Battle for Middle-Earth</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Made by The Noble Collection.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This chess set is made by The Noble Collection, which I do actually have some experience with already. They create all kinds of gifts for various popular fandoms like The Lord of the Rings and Harry Potter. You might be most familiar with its collection of Harry Potter wands, which the company first began releasing back in 2004. The Noble Collection is generally known for making high quality products at affordable prices, including <a href="https://www.noblecollection.com/ItemSearch--search-Chess-Sets--srcin-1?" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a variety of chess sets</a> like this one. There's even a high-end <a href="https://www.noblecollection.com/Item--i-CSS-LR-2990" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$500 version of this same thing</a> that is absolutely glorious, though that is way out of my price range.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">More Lord of the Rings Gifts</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're on the hunt for more Lord of the Rings gifts like this one, we have found quite a few. There's the deluxe illustrated version of the books, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-lord-of-the-rings-puzzles">Lord of the Rings puzzles</a>, board games, and even a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-lord-of-the-rings-book-nook-10367">LEGO book nook</a> available. </p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 6, 2025 1:30 am</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-chess-set-gift-for-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>