<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 15:54:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’re Only a Few Weeks Into 2025 and Already There’s a New GTA 6 Trailer 2 Release Date Theory]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/were-only-a-few-weeks-into-2025-and-already-theres-a-new-gta-6-trailer-2-release-date-theory</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we%E2%80%99re-only-a-few-weeks-into-2025-and-already-there%E2%80%99s-a-new-gta-6-trailer-2-release-date-theory.1087740/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/were-only-a-few-weeks-into-2025-and-already-theres-a-new-gta-6-trailer-2-release-date-theory<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">2025 is only a few weeks old, and yet we’ve already seen so much. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-finally-reveals-its-next-gen-console-confirms-switch-2-name">announcement of a new Nintendo console</a>. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tiktok-is-back-online-in-the-us-after-being-officially-banned-on-january-18">death and resurrection of TikTok</a>. And now, a new Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2 release date theory.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This one (believe it or not there are more than a few GTA 6 theories doing the rounds) was sparked into life by <a href="https://x.com/RockstarGames/status/1879925333790539845" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">another seemingly innocuous GTA Online promo tweet by Rockstar Games</a>. “Claim a free Vapid Dominator GT muscle car and more with GTA+,” the tweet reads. “Members also earn bonuses on Priority FIB Files and Terrorbyte Client Missions, save with Arcade Property discounts, and much more.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What information-starved GTA fans were most interested in, however, was the accompanying image, which includes a shot of a metal shipping container with a series of numbers printed on its side. One number is singled out with a slightly enlarged font and a rectangle around it: 2.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/21/gta-main-1737468480158.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The numbers Mason, what do they mean?! Image credit: Rockstar Games.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s all it took for eagle-eyed obsessives to set off on yet another GTA 6 theory brainstorm. The 2 must be a reference to GTA 6 Trailer 2, right? But what if you add up all the other numbers? Does that mean anything?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">X/Twitter account <a href="https://x.com/GTA6Plus" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@GTA6Plus</a> did the math and came up with the number 30. "They made sure to include the numbers in the post," GTA6Plus insisted. "They have to mean something." January 30, 2025 for the GTA 6 Trailer 2 reveal?</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">They made sure to include the numbers in the post. They have to mean something. <a href="https://t.co/icQSlVp11g" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/icQSlVp11g</a></p>— GTA 6+ (@GTA6Plus) <a href="https://twitter.com/GTA6Plus/status/1880056599752188121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 17, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">There’s more to this theory. It turns out the release dates for both Red Dead Redemption 2 and Grand Theft Auto V were announced on a Thursday. January 30, 2025 is a Thursday. Coincidence?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans have also pointed out that Rockstar parent company Take-Two is set to release its next set of financial results on February 6, so a release date announcement as part of a new trailer beforehand might make sense.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve been here before, of course. Multiple times. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-rockstar-officially-unveils-first-trailer-early-after-leak"><u>Rockstar released GTA 6 Trailer 1 to record-breaking viewership</u></a> in December 2023, but it hasn’t released a single asset in the 13 months since. The year-long wait for more information has fueled increasingly bizarre conspiracy theories about when Rockstar will release GTA 6 Trailer 2. These have included <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/on-the-gta-6-trailers-1-year-anniversary-fans-are-debating-youtube-playlist-updates-and-batting-away-misleading-ai-generated-images"><u>counting the holes in Lucia’s cell door net</u></a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/were-now-at-the-bullet-holes-and-braille-stage-of-gta-6-fan-theory"><u>bullet holes in the car from Trailer 1</u></a>, and even analyzing registration plates. But chief among the conspiracy theories is GTA 6’s ongoing moon watch, which was, remarkably, proven to have accurately predicted the date Rockstar announced when it would release GTA 6 Trailer 1 last December, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-community-devastated-by-gta-6-trailer-announcement-no-show-after-moon-theory-proved-incorrect"><u>debunked as a hint at the release date for Trailer 2</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Crazy? <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-could-easily-announce-the-gta-6-trailer-2-release-date-but-its-staying-quiet-on-purpose-because-its-a-really-good-marketing-tactic-ex-dev-says">One former developer at Rockstar recently expressed his delight at the many wild conspiracy theories surrounding GTA 6</a>, insisting staff at the studio will be enjoying watching the community go off the deep end.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It <em>is</em> remarkable that Rockstar has gone a year without following up GTA 6 Trailer 1 with any new information at all. With GTA 6's fall 2025 release window on PS5 and Xbox Series X and S still on the cards, according to Take-Two, you’d expect Rockstar to pipe up sooner rather than later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While you wait to find out, IGN has much more on GTA 6 to check out, including an ex-Rockstar dev who says <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-gta-6-be-delayed-to-2026-one-ex-rockstar-dev-says-the-studio-probably-wont-be-able-to-make-that-call-until-may-2025"><u>the studio probably won’t be able to decide whether GTA 6 is delayed until May 2025</u></a>, the boss of Take-Two's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/is-gta-6-coming-to-pc-take-two-boss-has-a-coy-response"><u>coy response on whether GTA 6 is coming to PC</u></a>, and the expert opinion on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-ps5-pro-run-gta-6-at-4k60-probably-not-say-the-experts"><u>whether the PS5 Pro will run GTA 6 at 60 frames per second</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Pulled GTA 6 Parody Game Grand Taking Ages From the PlayStation Store — but It’s Now Cleared for Release on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-pulled-gta-6-parody-game-grand-taking-ages-from-the-playstation-store-but-its-now-cleared-for-release-on-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-pulled-gta-6-parody-game-grand-taking-ages-from-the-playstation-store-%E2%80%94-but-it%E2%80%99s-now-cleared-for-release-on-steam.1087650/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-pulled-gta-6-parody-game-grand-taking-ages-from-the-playstation-store-but-its-now-cleared-for-release-on-steam<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The people behind the controversial Grand Theft Auto 6 parody game Grand Taking Ages are back with a Steam page after Sony pulled it from the PlayStation Store.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grand Taking Ages is, according to its creators, a parody management simulator where players run a game development studio.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, despite using what looked like AI-generated art to satirize the ongoing wait for Rockstar’s GTA 6, the inclusion of a list of unlikely gameplay features, as well as fake awards from video game websites, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-parody-grand-taking-ages-vi-pops-up-on-the-playstation-store-once-again-reminding-us-that-curation-basically-doesnt-exist">Grand Taking Ages VI appeared on the PlayStation Store</a> with a May 2025 release date. Users were even able to wishlist the game on PlayStation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Inevitably, Sony pulled Grand Taking Ages VI from the PlayStation Store, but now it’s back on Steam after what its creators said were key adjustments made to convince Valve of the project's validity.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/21/slop-1737462004799.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Grand Taking Ages is back, this time on Steam.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Developer Violarte told IGN that Grand Taking Ages had been through a “thorough” review process, and was now approved for publishing on Steam. On the Steam page are a brand new trailer and updated screenshots, all leaning on the parody angle its developer is using as justification for the project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So what’s changed? As well as ditching the “VI” in the game title, Violarte changed the game’s logo, descriptions, and overall presentation “to clearly differentiate Grand Taking Ages from the original inspiration, GTA 6, and to emphasize its unique direction.” Gone is the art that looked a lot like Rockstar’s iconic GTA imagery, in its place art that looks a <em>bit</em> like Rockstar’s iconic GTA imagery.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Grand Taking Ages is still riddled with generative AI. As per Steam’s AI rules, Violarte disclosed on the Grand Taking Ages Steam page that it used "AI services" for voice overs — and a cursory glance at the trailer will demonstrate how well this worked out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And here’s the new description on the Grand Taking Ages Steam page:</p><blockquote>Coming Soon Since Forever! Start your game dev journey in mom's garage! Battle angry fans, dodge ruthless journalists, and perfect the art of "creative" deadlines. Survive on pizza and energy drinks while building your dream studio into... a slightly better garage!</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Violarte said it took a different approach with Valve to get the game on Steam than it did with Sony to get the game on the PlayStation Store. “We approached Steam differently by engaging with their team about the concept of our game before officially submitting it,” a representative told IGN. “This allowed us to get their perspective early on, ensuring alignment with their guidelines.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The company pointed to other projects such as Grand Theft Hamlet, a documentary about two out of work actors who attempt to put on a production of Hamlet inside GTA Online, as evidence that parodies of GTA should be protected from takedowns. “These examples showcase how parody can celebrate and entertain within existing genres while remaining creative and engaging,” Violarte said.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/21/slop-again-1737462058393.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Grand Taking Ages uses generative AI for its trailer voice over.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Violarte now wants Grand Taking Ages back on the PlayStation Store. “We genuinely believe that, with the recent updates, Grand Taking Ages is now ready to be relisted on the PlayStation Store,” it said. To that end, Violarte said it had sent a request to Sony that points out that the changes it’s made to the game have convinced Valve to approve it for release on Steam. “We strongly believe that there will be no issues with Sony this time, given the adjustments we've implemented,” Violarte said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grand Taking Ages's appearance on the PlayStation Store called Sony’s curation process into question, but Valve’s open-door policy on Steam is well-documented. The likes of Steam, the various app stores, and even the Nintendo eShop are packed with slop, and, increasingly, generative-AI is being used to make it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA 6, meanwhile, launches on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S in the fall of 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Snap Back Online After TikTok Ban, Devs Searching for New Publisher to Stop It Happening Again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-snap-back-online-after-tiktok-ban-devs-searching-for-new-publisher-to-stop-it-happening-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-snap-back-online-after-tiktok-ban-devs-searching-for-new-publisher-to-stop-it-happening-again.1087644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-snap-back-online-after-tiktok-ban-devs-searching-for-new-publisher-to-stop-it-happening-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-snap">Marvel Snap</a> is now back online in the U.S. after it was banned alongside TikTok, and its developer Second Dinner is looking for a new publisher to ensure another takedown doesn't happen in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, January 21, marks "the start of a new era for Marvel Snap," according to Second Dinner, which posted on <a href="https://x.com/seconddinner/status/1881535498709266691?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a> to announce the digital trading card game's return alongside the search for a new publisher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tiktok-is-back-online-in-the-us-after-being-officially-banned-on-january-18">TikTok was banned in the U.S. on January 19 over "national security concerns"</a> but was brought back online after around 14 hours. TikTok owner ByteDance owns Marvel Snap publisher Nuverse too, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-snap-has-also-been-banned-in-the-us-following-the-tiktok-shutdown">so the game was also taken down but took a little longer to come back online</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Marvel Snap Card Art</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Marvel Snap is back online in the U.S," Second Dinner said. "But to make sure this never happens again, we’re working to bring more services in-house and partner with a new publisher. This is the start of a new era for Marvel Snap.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We know this probably leaves you with even more questions than answers. We appreciate your patience, but in the meantime enjoy playing Marvel Snap. We’ll continue to update with more information as soon as possible."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marvel Snap arrived in 2022 as a fast-paced TCG featuring the likes of Spider-Man, Iron Man, Thor, and many other Marvel superheroes and villains.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-snap-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, IGN said: "Marvel Snap packs bold ideas, deep gameplay, a punchy presentation and lots of love for Marvel. Its approach to building a collection and randomness in gameplay won't be for everyone, but it's still well worth playing."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>