<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 09:09:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Season 2 Episode 4: TV Show vs Game Comparison]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-4-tv-show-vs-game-comparison</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-4-tv-show-vs-game-comparison.1181013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-4-tv-show-vs-game-comparison<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Red flares, strung-up corpses, and a little bit of A-ha. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>The following article contains </em><em><strong>spoilers </strong></em><em>for The Last of Us season 2, episode 4.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Last of Us season 2 hits its midway point with its strongest episode so far. It adapts one of the most memorable sections of the game – Seattle Day One – and so that means we get Ellie and Dina checking out Downtown before moving onto the Channel 13 TV studio and escaping the WLF through the subway tunnels. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are five key sequences from the original game that are adapted for this episode. Here we’ve compared them against the original source material, analysing what’s changed and what’s stayed the same. You can see both versions in the video above, or read on below for our written explanations.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Downtown</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/05/music-shop-1746427277512.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Ellie and Dina arrive in Downtown Seattle shortly after this episode begins. This section of the game was open by design, and so allowed you to look around several different buildings. We get just two of them in the show; Weston’s Pharmacy and Valiant Music Shop. The pharmacy gets only a couple of minutes of screentime but it does feature an adaptation of The Last of Us’ key gameplay mechanic: opening drawers and looking for junk. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Valiant Music Shop, meanwhile, gets more love. The show’s set has windows adorned with music-themed vinyl decorations, just as it does in the game. On the ground floor is the same red drumkit, and Dina plays around with them just as she does in the game. It’s upstairs where the main event happens, though, when Ellie discovers a guitar in an overgrown room. Bella Ramsey’s performance of A-ha’s Take On Me is very similar to that seen in the game, with a talk-y vocal style and slow melody.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Forward Base</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/05/torture-1746427300083.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Episode 4 introduces us to the leader of the WLF, Isaac Dixon. This sequence is adapted from much later in the game’s sequence of events, when you play as Abby rather than Ellie, although due to the game’s overlapping dual timeline structure it seems likely that this sequence takes place at the “correct” time in the show. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">During Abby’s half of the game, we see her visit the WLF’s forward operating base. There she meets Isaac, who is briefly seen conducting a torturous interrogation on a member of the Seraphites. In the show, we see a version of this scene play out in its entirety. Similar to the game, the WLF’s captured Seraphite has been stripped completely naked, but the show sees them tortured in a kitchen rather than a bathroom. Isaac’s brutal methods of torture were only implied in the game, but in the show we see him actively injuring his prisoner in an attempt to learn more about the Seraphites’ plans. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Channel 13 </h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/05/tv-studio-1746427317253.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Ellie and Dina’s trip to the Channel 13 TV studio was naturally going to be the central event of this episode. In the game this is the sequence when the duo are first confronted with the murder cult-like methods of the Seraphites, as well as marking their first move towards finding where Abby is. The show recreates the key elements of the TV studio in grisy detail; WLF soldiers are strung up above the studio floor, and the Seraphites’ symbol is drawn on the wall in blood just as it is in the game. Ellie’s investigation of the area is interrupted by members of the WLF who, as in the game, are horrified to see what has become of their comrades. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The escape from the TV studio is shown to be a little more frantic than it is in the game, and the stormy weather adds even further drama to the scene, but in general the set design and pathway Ellie and Dina take feels authentic to the game, even if it’s not a one-to-one recreation. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Tunnels</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/05/subway-tunnels-1746427334489.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">One of The Last of Us Part 2’s most exhilarating sequences is Ellie and Dina’s journey through the Seattle subway tunnels. Bathed in red light and infested by clickers, it’s a genuinely terrifying level. Unsurprisingly, HBO went to lengths to capture the striking visuals here, with the abandoned subway cars eerily lit by the WLF’s red flares and searching flashlights. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are key differences between the game and the show's version of events, though. This is very much a survival horror sequence in the game, with just a small but incredibly deadly collection of infected to avoid. The show, meanwhile, makes this more action packed – rather than have the infected lurk around the subway cars, they arrive as a charging, clawing horde. This makes the sequence much more action-oriented, with Ellie and Dina scrambling to get away rather than sneaking through the tunnels. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are changes made to the sequence’s climax, too. In the game, Ellie gets trapped in the turnstile and Dina saves her by shooting an attacking clicker in the head. In the show, both Ellie and Dina get trapped in the turnstile, and Ellie allows herself to be bitten by the attacking clicker to protect Dina. It’s this bite that results in Ellie revealing her immunity to Dina. In the game, that reveal comes a few minutes prior, when Ellie’s gas mask is shattered by an attacking runner. Because spores are not a concern in the show (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-three-reasons-spores-need-to-return">at least for now</a>), the characters do not wear masks and thus this turn of events couldn’t be used. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">I’m Pregnant </h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/05/pregnant-1746427356476.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The last scene of this week’s episode recreates the culminating part of the game’s Seattle Day 1: Dina reveals to Ellie that she’s pregnant. In both versions, Dina shares the news at the Pinnacle Theater, which the duo has made their home base. In the game, it’s a subdued and anguished moment, with Dina looking notably stressed by the idea. The show’s take is quite different, as the reveal pretty much instantly turns into an impassioned kiss between Ellie and Dina. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more from The Last of Us, check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-review-spoiler-free">spoiler-free season two review</a> and our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-4-review-secrets">spoiler-filled review of the fourth episode</a>. You can also catch up with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-3-tv-show-vs-game-comparison">our comparison of the previous episode</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: LEGO Star Wars, Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake, Corsair K70, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-4-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-lego-star-wars-dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-corsair-k70-and-more.1180878/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-4-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for May 4 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save 30% Off This LEGO Star Wars R2-D2 Set</h2><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220094"><div id="220094" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Star Wars R2-D2 Building Set</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">To celebrate May the 4th, you can score this 2314-piece LEGO Star Wars R2-D2 set for just $167.99. This is an excellent collector's item for any collection, as R2-D2 is the perfect size to fit on any shelf! Every detail from the iconic droid is captured in this set, including its rotatable head!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga for $10</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220086"><div id="220086" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga - Standard Edition - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga is by far the biggest LEGO game available, with hundreds of characters to collect across numerous planets. You can pick up the game for just $10 at Amazon right now for PS4, making this a deal you won't want to pass on. All nine films are included in this game, with characters from newer Disney+ Star Wars series as well.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Star Wars Millennium Falcon A New Hope 25th Anniversary Collectable Model for $67.95</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220093"><div id="220093" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Star Wars Millennium Falcon A New Hope 25th Anniversary Collectable Model</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up, you can also save on this LEGO Star Wars Millennium Falcon Set. This set celebrates the 25th anniversary of LEGO Star Wars, making it a must-own for any collector. Many of the Falcon's iconic details are all here, including the round table inside and the satellite dish on top.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Monster Hunter Wilds for $54.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220084"><div id="220084" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds - Standard Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds is still one of the biggest games of 2025, and you can save $15 off the PS5 version for a limited time at Woot. This is by far the most beginner-friendly Monster Hunter to date, with new features like Focus Mode that allow you to approach fights in new ways. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Monster Hunter Wilds continues to smooth off the rougher corners of the series in smart ways, making for some extremely fun fights but also lacking any real challenge."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake for $45.67</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220096"><div id="220096" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>DRAGON QUEST III HD-2D Remake (NSW)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake was one of my favorite games last year, offering gorgeous HD-2D visuals, an orchestrated soundtrack, and plenty of charm. This weekend, you can save ~$15 off a Nintendo Switch copy, which is a sweet deal considering this game has not made it on sale much. Now is the time to start building your catalog for Nintendo Switch 2, and what better place to start than Dragon Quest?</p><h2 data-cy="title2">11th Gen iPad for $299</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219548"><div id="219548" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>New Apple iPad 11-inch: A16 chip, 11-inch Model - 128GB</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, you can save $50 off the newest iPad. Powered by the A16, the newest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/apple-ipad-11th-generation">11th-generation iPad</a> is an exceptional addition to any workspace. You can use this device with both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ipad-accessories">Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard Folio</a> to make the most out of it without having to go for the iPad Air or iPad Pro. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order Ghost of Yotei Now</h2></div><div catalogid="e3234859-17ec-4093-81f2-be710ac1b038" id="220005"><div id="220005" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ghost of Yotei (PS5)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Yotei is finally up for pre-order at Amazon. Set in the Hokkaido region in 1603, you'll play as Atsu to gain revenge on those who killed your family. While not much has been revealed for this game yet, we can expect Yotei to play very similarly to its predecessor, Ghost of Tsushima. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Visions of Mana for $34.99</h2></div><div id="219546" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (PS5)</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219547"><div id="219547" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (XSX)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Visions of Mana released at the end of August, and it's available on sale for the first time this weekend. This is the first new Mana game in almost two decades, starring a cast of characters on a quest to save the world. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-review">our 8/10 review</a>, we stated, "Visions of Mana finally brings the long-dormant classic RPG series into the modern age, looking great and playing even better thanks to multi-layered class and skill systems that interact in clever ways."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Corsair K70 RGB PRO Mechanical Keyboard for $99.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220097"><div id="220097" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Corsair K70 RGB PRO Wired Mechanical Gaming Keyboard (Cherry MX RGB Red Switches)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can save $70 off the Corsair K70 RGB PRO Mechanical Keyboard this weekend at Amazon. This keyboard comes with Cherry MX RGB Red Switches, which provide a linear and fast response. There's a magnetic soft-touch palm rest included that you can use if you wish, in addition to durable double-shot PBT Pro keycaps. At $99.99, this is a really solid deal.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Mario Party Jamboree for $44.99</h2></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218600"><div id="218600" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">With the recent reveal of Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games, it's no question that you are going to want to save anywhere you can. The Nintendo Switch 2 Edition of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-party-jamboree-review">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a> is set to cost $79.99, but you can upgrade from a Nintendo Switch copy for presumably $20. This weekend, save your cash and pick up a copy of Super Mario Party Jamboree from Woot for only $44.99.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 4, 2025 7:04 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Monster Hunter Wilds, 11th Gen iPad, Xbox Series X, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-3-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-monster-hunter-wilds-11th-gen-ipad-xbox-series-x-and-more.1180554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-may-3-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hunting for great deals.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for May 3 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Monster Hunter Wilds for $54.99</h2><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220084"><div id="220084" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Monster Hunter Wilds - Standard Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds is still one of the biggest games of 2025, and you can save $15 off the PS5 version for a limited time at Woot. This is by far the most beginner-friendly Monster Hunter to date, with new features like Focus Mode that allow you to approach fights in new ways. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Monster Hunter Wilds continues to smooth off the rougher corners of the series in smart ways, making for some extremely fun fights but also lacking any real challenge."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">11th Gen iPad for $299</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219548"><div id="219548" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>New Apple iPad 11-inch: A16 chip, 11-inch Model - 128GB</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, you can save $50 off the newest iPad. Powered by the A16, the newest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/apple-ipad-11th-generation">11th-generation iPad</a> is an exceptional addition to any workspace. You can use this device with both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ipad-accessories">Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard Folio</a> to make the most out of it without having to go for the iPad Air or iPad Pro. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order Ghost of Yotei Now</h2></div><div catalogid="e3234859-17ec-4093-81f2-be710ac1b038" id="220005"><div id="220005" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ghost of Yotei (PS5)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Yotei is finally up for pre-order at Amazon. Set in the Hokkaido region in 1603, you'll play as Atsu to gain revenge on those who killed your family. While not much has been revealed for this game yet, we can expect Yotei to play very similarly to its predecessor, Ghost of Tsushima. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Visions of Mana for $34.99</h2></div><div id="219546" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (PS5)</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219547"><div id="219547" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (XSX)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Visions of Mana released at the end of August, and it's available on sale for the first time this weekend. This is the first new Mana game in almost two decades, starring a cast of characters on a quest to save the world. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-review">our 8/10 review</a>, we stated, "Visions of Mana finally brings the long-dormant classic RPG series into the modern age, looking great and playing even better thanks to multi-layered class and skill systems that interact in clever ways."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Series X for $479.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220085"><div id="220085" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox Series X 1TB SSD Console</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Xbox announced this week <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-raises-the-price-of-all-xbox-series-consoles-xbox-games-confirmed-to-hit-80-this-holiday">that the Xbox Series X will increase in price by $100 in the United States</a>. This puts the almost five-year-old console at $599.99, but you can still score an Xbox Series X for under its previous MSRP at Amazon right now. At $479.99, you're saving $120 off the new price of Xbox Series X, and there's no telling when or if we will see it this low again soon.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga for $10</h2></div><div catalogid="2f2b25f8-7da9-4714-9fd0-863f29720c8b" id="220086"><div id="220086" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga - Standard Edition - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga is by far the biggest LEGO game available, with hundreds of characters to collect across numerous planets. You can pick up the game for just $10 at Amazon right now for PS4, making this a deal you won't want to pass on. All nine films are included in this game, with characters from newer Disney+ Star Wars series as well.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Mario Party Jamboree for $44.99</h2></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218600"><div id="218600" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">With the recent reveal of Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games, it's no question that you are going to want to save anywhere you can. The Nintendo Switch 2 Edition of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-party-jamboree-review">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a> is set to cost $79.99, but you can upgrade from a Nintendo Switch copy for presumably $20. This weekend, save your cash and pick up a copy of Super Mario Party Jamboree from Woot for only $44.99.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 3, 2025 6:04 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>