<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:39:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Update 1.1.1.5 to Finally Fix Infamous Sledgehammer Drone Exploit and Deliver Weapon Dispersion Tweaks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-update-1115-to-finally-fix-infamous-sledgehammer-drone-exploit-and-deliver-weapon-dispersion-tweaks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-update-1-1-1-5-to-finally-fix-infamous-sledgehammer-drone-exploit-and-deliver-weapon-dispersion-tweaks.1349254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA and Battlefield Studios have published update 1.1.1.5 patch notes for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6"><u>Battlefield 6</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-redsec"><u>REDSEC</u></a>, delivering a variety of quality-of-life changes for weapons and vehicles and, at long last, a fix for the sledgehammer Recon drone glitch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The team behind last month’s new Battlefield game detailed everything arriving in the new update in the patch notes <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1987957508426608743?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted to social media</a> today. It comes with a full breakdown for tweaks related to weapon accuracy, vehicle countermeasures, and other bug fixes before update 1.1.1.5 rolls out for Battlefield 6 and REDSEC tomorrow, November 11, at 1 a.m. PT / 4 a.m. ET.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Topping the list of changes is a fix for one of the most notorious bugs to arrive since the launch of Battlefield 6: the drone glitch. For the uninitiated, players have figured out that standing on top of a friendly XFGM-6D Recon drone and smacking it with a sledgehammer causes the device to fly upward. It began as a goofy activity for those looking to add a dash of comedy to their matches and quickly evolved into an annoying exploit, as players eventually learned it could be used to reach otherwise inaccessible vantage points.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Battlefield 6 sledgehammer drone glitch will finally be laid to rest tomorrow, but it’s far from the only change on the way. Update 1.1.1.5 will also introduce a few tweaks to how vehicles operate. Both ground and air vehicle users will be happy to know the glitch affecting the use of countermeasures like flares has been fixed, which should result in more reliable protection against lock-guided missiles. A bug tied to incorrect vehicle spawns in Breakthrough and Conquest will also be fixed with tomorrow’s update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to general fixes for battle royal match flow as well as progression, audio, and UI, infantry will notice less dispersion when aiming down sights after sprinting. It, as well as other fixes related to player movement and shooting, should have players feeling more accurate when they’re on the move.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield 6 launched October 10 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S. It’s since received a waterfall of updates as EA and BF Studios continue their attempts to keep up with fan feedback amid regular seasonal drops. Recent highlights include an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-gets-major-overhaul-of-challenges-and-assignments-with-significant-reductions-to-challenge-requirements-available-now"><u>overhaul for progression that reduced requirements for many of the tougher challenges</u></a>, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-won-battlefield-6-fans-rejoice-as-ea-tones-down-bright-colors-on-monster-energy-skin"><u>toned down colors for one of Battlefield’s most controversial skins ever</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best Battlefield Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While we wait to see how the Battlefield 6 and REDSEC community will respond to update 1.1.1.5, you can read about how some dedicated fans <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-map-debate-reaches-new-level-as-players-meticulously-measure-70-maps-from-bf3-bf2042-and-more"><u>measured nearly 15 years of multiplayer maps</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/this-is-brilliant-battlefield-6-players-flock-to-giant-fan-made-conquest-maps-as-map-size-debate-rages-on"><u>why another group of players started creating their own Portal Conquest maps</u></a>. You can also check out our<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-review"> <u>7/10 REDSEC review</u></a> and our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-review-multiplayer"><u>8/10 Battlefield 6 multiplayer review</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see the full patch notes below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Battlefield 6 Update 1.1.1.5 Patch Notes:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We’re rolling out a Quality of Life update on <strong>11 November at 09:00 UTC</strong>, bringing refinements to vehicle countermeasure reliability, weapon accuracy, Battle Royale match flow, and overall gameplay stability.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Major Updates for 1.1.1.5:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an exploit allowing players to ascend and access unintended areas when standing on a XFGM-6D Recon Drone by hitting it with the Sledgehammer.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Lock-Guided Missiles did not get countered as expected when met with enemy countermeasures such as flares.</li><li>Fixed an issue where vehicles did not spawn correctly in Breakthrough and Conquest.</li><li>Fixed multiple Battle Royale issues affecting match flow, squad revives, and End of Round transitions.</li><li>Addressed progression, audio, and UI issues, improving overall clarity, reliability, and immersion.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>CHANGELOG</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PLAYER:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where dispersion would be higher than intended when going from sprint to firing in ADS.</li><li>Fixed an issue where dispersion would incorrectly scale with movement speed and always assume the player is moving at maximum movement speed for the stance.</li><li>Tuned landing animation to reduce excessive camera and weapon movement when aiming down sights, improving visual stability during and after landing. This update also resolves instances where the ADS aim could be displaced when sliding.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>VEHICLES:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where Lock-Guided Missiles did not get countered as expected when met with enemy countermeasures such as flares.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>GADGETS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an exploit allowing players to ascend and access unintended areas when standing on the XFGM-6D Recon Drone by hitting it with the Sledgehammer.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>MAPS &amp; MODES:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where vehicles did not spawn correctly in Breakthrough and Conquest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where matches sometimes would start with all sectors and objectives active at the same time.</li><li>Fixed an issue in Strikepoint on Siege of Cairo where destruction did not reset at halftime.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UI &amp; HUD:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue in Vehicle Customisation locked Anti-Air Vehicle presets did not display their unlock criteria as intended.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PROGRESSION:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the shotgun weapon challenge “Kill 5 Enemies With a Shotgun Without Reloading” did not complete properly.</li><li>Fixed an issue where progress for the “Engineer Specialist 3” Assignment did not save correctly.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PORTAL:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where “SpawnLoot” would not spawn Ammo or Armor.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players with community creations privileges set to Block could still access user-generated Community Experiences when the party leader hosted a match.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>AUDIO:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where activating the BF PRO Radio Channel through the Commorose did not play any sound.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>REDSEC</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PLAYER:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where Battle Royale (Quads) matches did not end after the last team was eliminated.</li><li>Fixed an issue where being killed immediately after a mobile respawn completed could result in the squad being eliminated instead of reviving remaining teammates.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players could become stuck in a top-down view of the map after redeploying.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players retained their Second Chance after redeploying and did not transition to the End of Round screen after their next elimination.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UI &amp; HUD:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where all squad members displayed the same highlighted stat on the Squad Placement screen.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PROGRESSION:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the “Battle Royal Master Challenge 4” did not track progress correctly.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-update-1115-to-finally-fix-infamous-sledgehammer-drone-exploit-and-deliver-weapon-dispersion-tweaks]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seven Deadly Sins: Origin Preview: It's a Whole Vibe, and the Combat’s Not Bad, Either]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/seven-deadly-sins-origin-preview-its-a-whole-vibe-and-the-combats-not-bad-either</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/seven-deadly-sins-origin-preview-its-a-whole-vibe-and-the-combat%E2%80%99s-not-bad-either.1349149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sometimes, you go into a game not really knowing much about it. I knew exactly three things going into Seven Deadly Sins: Origin: one, it is based on the popular Seven Deadly Sins manga/anime; two, it is an action-RPG; and three, that I could play it on PC or PS5. I looked at it long enough to decide that it could be up my alley, and then dived into its closed beta test blind. And I’m happy I did. Seven Deadly Sins: Origin is an impressive game, even with its gacha mechanics, and I enjoyed hanging out in its world and spending time with its characters. Oh, and the combat? That’s not bad, either.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seven Deadly Sins: Origin follows Prince Tristan of Liones and Tioreh. After stumbling upon a strange cave inside a tree (that’s not a typo), our heroes discover a mysterious pendant called the Book of Stars that seems to have mystical powers neither of them fully understand. When they emerge from the cave after a knock-down, drag-out brawl against a surprisingly large and hostile golem, our heroes discover that the world is a little different than when they left it. The topography’s changed, creatures that are supposed to be extinct are running around in living color, and Hawk – everyone’s favorite flying ham – was being chased by a dragon. He’s not really sure how he ended up here – he could have sworn he was in Purgatory – but he’s down to clown with Tristan and Tioreh while they figure out what’s going on. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Oh, and this weird black corruption is springing up all over, long-dead heroes are showing up to cause problems, and there’s this mysterious scholar named Clotho who seems to know both everything about the Book of Stars, which can magically restore broken things, and where Tristan and Tioreh are going to be before they get there. Time travel shenanigans? Multiple timelines? Something funky’s going on, y’all, and our intrepid crew are going to get to the bottom of it.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>What sells The Vibe™ of Seven Deadly Sins: Origin is how it looks. It’s absolutely stunning.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The story here is fun (and very well-acted, though there was no English dub in the beta, so everything I heard was in Japanese), but what sells The Vibe™ of Seven Deadly Sins: Origin is how it looks. It’s absolutely stunning, but what impressed me most was how well-animated everything was. There’s a particularly great scene where Tristan is trying to hand over the Book of Stars, only to find it’s stuck to his hand, that had me rolling, but there’s a lot of really great moments here. Seven Deadly Sins: Origin has a story to tell, and you can tell its developers have taken that responsibility seriously.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But there’s a solid action game here, too. Origin is an action-RPG at heart, and there’s meat on this combat’s bone. In addition to a standard defensive dash (the only way you’ll be blocking in Origin is with your face), each character comes with a standard combo, a couple of special attacks, and an ultimate that can range from calling in some fireballs to transforming into a demon. These distinctions are what gives each character flavor, and I really enjoyed playing around with them, whether I was buffing my standard fire attacks with Tioreh or using Howzer’s wind-based strikes, and everything in-between. And yes, characters like Diane are here, too. Just… smaller than you might figure.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since each character’s abilities are associated with an element, it’s good to have a balanced team. You can have up to four characters traveling with you at once, and switch to them on the fly. Play your cards right, and they’ll even come in with an attack. The twist is that your whole team shares a health bar; there’s no switching characters when you’re running low on health to save the day.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Combat is about managing your cooldowns, landing hits when you can, and most importantly, not getting hit. Origin is kind enough to show you where large attacks are going to be ahead of time, and smaller hits generally have enough windup so that you can get out of the way if you’re paying attention and not just mashing buttons. This isn’t Devil May Cry or Ninja Gaiden, but there’s some juice here, and combat feels good.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>This isn’t Devil May Cry or Ninja Gaiden, but there’s some juice here, and combat feels good.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">But it’s not all about hitting things with all manner of sharp and blunt objects. You can also collect materials in the world and use them to craft potions to keep you alive in a pinch, cook a delicious meal, or upgrade your characters with permanent stat buffs. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also a lot to explore. Soon after meeting Hawk, I could ride him around, and like seemingly every video game released since The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, you can climb on objects in the environment if you’ve got the stamina for it, and glide down from high places. All of this is good because the world of Britannia is absolutely massive. You can teleport around if you activate the fancy fast-travel stones scattered around the environment, but that means you gotta find ‘em first. So, you know, be prepared to do a little walking. Or pig-riding.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But spending time in the world means you’ll get to do Origin’s sidequests. They’re simple stuff, and, as you’d expect, not nearly as well-produced as the story beats, but I enjoyed trying to help out a crying kid and got a kick out of a castle worker who was so lazy that I had to deliver food for her. Stuff like that makes the world feel more lived in.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If there’s one thing about Seven Deadly Sins: Origin that gives me pause, it’s the gacha-ness of it all. I’m inherently wary of gacha and other reward systems built on gambling, and Origin is one of those games. It seems fairly easy to get enough currency to roll the dice, but the beta throws currency at you, and it’s hard to get a sense of the economics of something when that happens. Whether or not that will be true in the full game remains to be seen. The UI also feels designed for a mouse and keyboard in a way that makes it awkward to navigate on a controller, especially when you’re managing a lot of gear. It’s not gamebreaking, but it’s something I wonder about when it comes to a full release.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I spent about five hours with Seven Deadly Sins: Origin, unlocking several characters, opening up the ability to party up with other players, and taking the main quest far enough that Tristan and Tioreh got to the point that they’d demonstrated enough skill to be trusted to head to the Fairy King Forest. That seemed like a natural place to stop, but before I did, I wanted to take on one of the beta’s optional bosses. In my case, it was a red demon who belched fire and had a thing for belly flops, and another weird looking thing with arms that were doubling as legs. I couldn’t beat either, mostly because I just wasn’t doing enough damage. My choices were clear: level up, get more gear, and play more gacha to Get My Numbers Up, but I opted out. I’d seen the fights, which were fun enough that I wanted to play them again if I jumped in at release, and I was tired of fiddling with the inventory screen. End on a high note.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sometimes, going into a game blind can be the best thing you can do for yourself. I enjoyed spending time in Seven Deadly Sins: Origin’s world, hanging out with its characters, and riding around a flying hog. And yeah, the fighting stuff part was pretty solid, too. I’m always wary of gacha elements in games, but the core of Seven Deadly Sins: Origin got my attention. The only question is whether it can hold it when it comes out next year. I wouldn’t mind a rematch with a couple of those bosses, but I’m not in a rush. They’ll be there when I return to Britannia.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/seven-deadly-sins-origin-preview-its-a-whole-vibe-and-the-combats-not-bad-either]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>