<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:09:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online Library Adds Game Boy Classic Donkey Kong Land 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-library-adds-game-boy-classic-donkey-kong-land-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-library-adds-game-boy-classic-donkey-kong-land-3.1051602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-library-adds-game-boy-classic-donkey-kong-land-3<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has added Game Boy classic Donkey Kong Land 3 to the Nintendo Switch Online library.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A trailer revealed the platformer from developer Rare is available today, December 4, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-rares-game-boy-platformer-donkey-kong-land">wraps up the trilogy of Donkey Kong Land games which Nintendo has re-released</a> onto its subscription service over the last month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Fame and fortune seekers have journeyed far and wide in search of the fabled Lost World," reads the official synopsis. "Eager to find it first, Donkey Kong and Diddy Kong set off to discover its entrance, unaware that Baron K. Roolenstein and his Kremling Krew are hot on their tail.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1864135813874770005?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">"Meanwhile, Dixie Kong is left behind to babysit her younger cousin, Kiddy Kong. But that won't stop her from answering the call of adventure! Help Dixie Kong and Kiddy Kong through 36 Kremling-infested levels, each containing their own secret areas and bonus levels."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong Land 3 is available at no extra cost to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-expansion-pack-release-date-pricing-n64-sega-games">users who have a Nintendo Switch Online membership and have purchased the Expansion Pass</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo periodically adds a handful of classic titles to its myriad Switch Online libraries, which also includes games from the Nintendo Entertainment System, Super Nintendo Entertainment System, Game Boy Advance, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Boss Hermen Hulst Says AI Will Never Replace the 'Human Touch' of Video Game Development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-boss-hermen-hulst-says-ai-will-never-replace-the-human-touch-of-video-game-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-boss-hermen-hulst-says-ai-will-never-replace-the-human-touch-of-video-game-development.1051509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-boss-hermen-hulst-says-ai-will-never-replace-the-human-touch-of-video-game-development<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">But could "revolutionize" gaming.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation co-CEO Hermen Hulst has said artificial intelligence will never replace the "human touch" of video game development but still expects AI to feature prominently in the industry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hulst told the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c4gpz291z59o" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BBC</a> he believes AI has the potential to "revolutionize" video game development but studios will have to strike the right balance between using it and creating games through the traditional route.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I suspect there will be a dual demand in gaming: one for AI-driven innovative experiences and another for handcrafted, thoughtful content," Hulst said. "Striking the right balance between leveraging AI and preserving the human touch will be crucial."</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Striking the right balance between leveraging AI and preserving the human touch will be crucial.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This comes as many fans and creators of video games are growing increasingly concerned with the use of AI-generated content, though executives at various publishers have shared different perspectives on it so far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-says-ai-is-the-very-core-of-its-business-what-does-that-mean">EA CEO Andrew Wilson has said AI is at "the very core" of its business</a>, for example, while others, such as Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa, have expressed more caution. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-says-generative-ai-can-be-used-in-creative-ways-but-highlights-ip-issues">AI can be used "in creative ways," he said in July</a>, but its use "also raises issues with intellectual property rights."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">AI isn't quite ready to replace human developers, however, as support studio <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/video-game-made-purely-with-ai-failed-because-tech-was-unable-to-replace-talent">Keywords Studios tried creating a video game solely using AI</a> only to deem the technology was "unable to replace talent." But one area it is impacting already is voice over, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/voice-actor-strike-makes-progress-as-last-sentinel-dev-signs-ai-protection-agreement">a video game voice actor strike currently ongoing under The Screen Actors Guild — American Federation of Television and Radio Artists</a> (SAG-AFTRA).</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Video Game Voice Actors' Thoughts on AI</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Myriad voice actors have commented on the threat of AI already, including Metal Gear Solid and Mass Effect actress Jennifer Hale. "The truth is, AI is just a tool like a hammer," she said. "If I take my hammer, I could build you a house. I can also take that same hammer and I can smash your skin and destroy who you are.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-voice-actor-doug-cockle-calls-ai-inevitable-but-dangerous">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt lead Doug Cockle similarly expressed caution and frustration</a> at the growing presence of AI within the video game industry, calling it "inevitable" but "dangerous."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cissy Jones, a voice actor known for her roles in Disney's Owl House, Destiny 2: The Witch Queen, Shin Megami Tensei 5, and more, has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-company-fighting-to-make-ai-ethical-for-voice-actors">started a company called Morpheme.ai to let voice actors embrace AI and gain control of their own voices going forward</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image Credit: EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP via Getty Images</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Global Release Times and Early Access Pre-Download Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-global-release-times-and-early-access-pre-download-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-global-release-times-and-early-access-pre-download-confirmed.1051443/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-global-release-times-and-early-access-pre-download-confirmed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a> developer Grinding Gear Games has confirmed plans to make the Early Access launch available to pre-download, and announced the game’s global release times.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Path of Exile 2 is GGG’s hotly anticipated free-to-play action role-playing sequel set years after the original game. Players return to the world of Wraeclast and seek to end a spreading corruption, with six character classes, each with two Ascendancy Classes, available to play at the launch of Early Access later this week. There’s co-op for up to six players, but you can play solo. Check out IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-mercenary-class-hands-on-endgame-first-look">Path of Exile 2 preview</a>, where we gave the Mercenary class a whirl and got a first look at the endgame, for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://www.pathofexile.com/forum/view-thread/3591631" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">forum post</a>, GGG said it’s making the standalone PC client available to download at 5pm PT on December 5, or 1am GMT on December 6 in your local time. The developer noted that when patching begins for the Early Access, players may also have a few remaining files they’ll need to update as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Once you’ve downloaded the client, you won’t be able to log in until the Early Access launch itself, which is set for 11am PT on December 6, or 7pm GMT on December 6 in your local time. You can get the client download through the Path of Exile 2 website, but GGG said it’ll make a torrent available with the client download at the same time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The pre-download is already available on Xbox, although GGG said there will likely be updates on launch. As for PlayStation, Founder’s packs should go live 24 hours before Early Access starts (so, 11am PT on December 5). If you buy one of these packs, you’ll be able to pre-download on PS5.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Path of Exile 2 Early Access Global Release times</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>PT: 11am, December 6</li><li>ET: 2pm, December 6</li><li>GMT: 7pm, December 6</li><li>CET: 8pm, December 6</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>