<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.ign.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.ign.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:24:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Build LEGO Pokémon Eevee: A Perfectly Adorable Evolution of Bricks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-lego-pokemon-eevee-set-72151</link>
            <guid>1446088</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon has been a part of my life for as far back as I can remember. I was just starting first grade when Pokémon Red and Blue came out on the Game Boy, but I still remember it like it was yesterday. My brother and I only had one Game Boy between us, and since he was older, he got to play it far more often than I did. Before we got a copy of Pokémon Blue for Christmas that year, the only Game Boy game we'd actually had the chance to play was Tetris. So needless to say, I was instantly enamored with the concept of catching and battling with all 151 of the original Pokémon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And of those original Pokémon in that game, I was always particularly interested in Eevee. Not because it's arguably the most adorable, but because of all of the evolutionary paths you could take once you had one. And you could <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-version/eevee">only have one per playthrough</a>, after all, since you couldn't actually catch Eevee in that game. As one of the most versatile Pokémon out there and I always find myself choosing a different Eevee-lution each time I play a new game.</p><div id="234361"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234361" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Eevee - LEGO Pokemon</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Now in 2026, with a new collaboration with LEGO, I had the chance to experience Eevee evolving into something much more exciting: an adorable little LEGO set. LEGO provided IGN with a copy of the set for a test build and I was lucky enough to be the one to put it together. At just 587 pieces, it only took me a few hours to assemble, but I was in love with every part of this build. Each new section of the set has you slowly piecing together a surprisingly lifelike LEGO Eevee, and the end result is nothing short of phenomenal. Once I placed the final touch of the build, I was honestly amazed at just how good it looks despite being made up of tiny plastic bricks.</p><p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">LEGO Pokémon Eevee Build</h3></div></span></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">At $59.99, the LEGO Eevee build is the most affordable of the three Pokémon sets now available to buy. And of those three, I think Eevee is the most realistic looking. Due to its price compared to the other sets, it's also the one I think most people are probably going to buy. Despite that lower price point, however, the whole build still felt like a premium experience. The set came with a total of six bags, all of which were made of nice recyclable paper. The instruction booklet also included the official Pokédex entry for Eevee, which I thought was a nice touch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You start off the build with Eevee's core body. This is the foundation of the whole set, which you can see start to come together with various places for the legs, tail, and head to connect. This is the least exciting part of the whole experience, but I always enjoy these parts of the build due to the insight you get into how LEGO actually designed these sets to work. The connecting slots for legs give you a glimpse of how you'll be able to articulate those limbs once they're added, and the giant connector on top gives you an idea of just how massive Eevee's head is going to be compared to the rest of its body.</p><p>I was honestly amazed at just how good it looks despite being made up of tiny plastic bricks.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Once you move on to building the actual legs, the set really starts to come to life. Starting with the front legs, the instructions have you build one limb at a time before attaching it to the main body. Each of these is fairly straightforward to put together and looks fairly blocky until you get to the voluptuous fluff on each shoulder. You use a series of rounded pieces that really smooth out the overall look of each leg. Then the final touch of rounded pieces at the end ensure almost all of the LEGO studs are covered up. The end result is a surprisingly soft looking leg that will contribute to Eevee's overall fluffy visage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After you finish building and attaching all of the legs, you can already start playing around with all of the different positions the final product will be able to move into. Each of the legs can articulate forward and backward, allowing you to move the body into various sitting and standing poses. I was even able to move it into a full standing position, which is admittedly much harder to balance once Eevee's head and tail are added to the equation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The tail is where I really felt the build starting to add enough complexity to earn its 18+ age rating. Because you're essentially turning bricks into what will appear as a fluffy tail, you need to ensure that each of the pieces is facing the right outward direction. I ended up making a few mistakes here without realizing and had to backtrack later so I could actually connect all of the rounded pieces on both sides later on. You shouldn't have any issue here unless you try to rush through things and ignore instructions like I do. Once the whole thing is put together, it attaches neatly to the back of the set and can move from side to side.</p><p>"Each of the legs can articulate forward and backward, allowing you to move the body into various sitting and standing positions."<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">With the entire body and tail put together, you get to move on to Eevee's surprisingly massive noggin. I was particularly nervous about this part of the build because I had feared that it would involve some sort of sticker element. I had put together <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-wednesday-things-apartment-76785">a LEGO Wednesday set last year</a> that had a ton of different stickers and made some horrendous mistakes that made the end result look just weird enough to bother me forever. Thankfully, my fears of having an Eevee with horribly misplaced eyes were quickly banished when I found that the pieces themselves already had the designs printed on them. So once you build the actual head, all you need to do is attach a few pieces to get a perfectly designed face.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The final step of the build is Eevee's long pointy ears. These are relatively easy to put together, and like all of the other parts of the set, can be articulated into various positions. Each ear can be moved up and down, allowing for a symmetrical look or that cute lopsided look that you see on the box. And although you've already got a mostly complete Eevee set right up until this point, it isn't until you add the ears that the whole thing comes alive.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All-in-all, I found the Eevee set to be one of the most enjoyable LEGO builds I've ever done. I'm obviously a bit biased due to my deep nostalgic love of Pokémon, but it's honestly just a really cool build at a surprisingly affordable price point. And now that it's been fully put together I have a full-on Eevee action figure that I find myself adjusting and displaying in random spots throughout the house. It's my new favorite display set and it has me excited for what the LEGO Pokémon collab will bring in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jacob Kienlen is a Senior Audience Development Strategist and Writer for IGN. Born and raised in Portland, Oregon, he has considered the Northwest his home for his entire life. With a bachelor's degree in communication and over 8 years of professional writing experience, his expertise is spread across a variety of different pop culture topics -- from TV series to indie games and books.</em></p></div></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-lego-pokemon-eevee-set-72151]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Global Release Timings Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-global-release-timings-revealed</link>
            <guid>1446085</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom's hugely-anticipated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> is now just over a day from launch, with preloading already live on some platforms. But when will you be able to actually start playing? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Thankfully, via a post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3764200/view/525369184506347557" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, Capcom has now issued a detailed rundown of when Requiem will unlock across the world in major territories — with differences in some regions depending on platform. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're on Steam, you can also now begin preloading the game if you are a pre-order customer — ensuring you slip back into the shoes (and snazzy jacket) of Leon S. Kennedy as quickly as possible.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Across the world, PlayStation and Xbox copies of the game will typically unlock at midnight on February 27 in your local timezone, except in the U.S., when these will unlock at your equivalent to midnight EST (9pm Pacific). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On PC, where the game is available via Steam and Epic Games Store, the timing is different again, and there is an added wrinkle for the game's launch on Nintendo Switch 2 in Mexico. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With just hours left until Requiem's release, there's time for one last word of caution around the game's spoilers now spreading like wildfire online. Capcom has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-pledges-firm-action-following-widespread-resident-evil-requiem-leaks-begs-fans-not-to-ruin-excitement-for-others"><u>promised "firm action" against those responsible</u></a>, though this seems to have done little to curb the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-faces-uphill-battle-to-stop-resident-evil-requiem-leaks-as-ending-spoilers-and-videos-appear-online"><u>clips of the game's finale now being widely shared</u></a>, which IGN verified as legitimate. Earlier this week, Resident Evil 2 director and famed developer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-leakers-deserve-a-thousand-deaths-hideki-kamiya-says">Hideki Kamiya said those who revel in ruining surprises for others "deserve a thousand deaths"</a> and should "be cursed to never be able to play games again."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Resident Evil Requiem Review Screens</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Read on for a full rundown of when Resident Evil Requiem will release in your own timezone — and stay tuned here on IGN for our full launch coverage, including our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-review">Resident Evil Requiem review</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Resident Evil Requiem Global Release Times</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Los Angeles (PST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 26 21:00</li><li>PC: Feb 26 21:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>New York/Toronto (EST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 0:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Mexico City (CST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console (PS5/Xbox): Feb 27 0:00</li><li>Console (Switch 2): Feb 26 23:00</li><li>PC: Feb 26 23:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>London (GMT)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 5:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Paris/Berlin/Rome (CET)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 6:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Tokyo (JST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 14:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Auckland (NZDT)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 18:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Singapore (SGT)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 18:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Seoul (KST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 14:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Riyadh (AST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 08:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Johannesburg (SAST)</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Console: Feb 27 0:00</li><li>PC: Feb 27 7:00</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-global-release-timings-revealed]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-review</link>
            <guid>1446079</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Within the hallways of the sinister sanatorium where Resident Evil Requiem’s opening hours take place lies some of the most frightening encounters I’ve experienced in the series to date. With my headphones on and the lights off, the ninth mainline adventure in Capcom’s longrunning survival horror saga forced me to endure moments so palpably tense and prolonged I discovered muscles to clench that I didn’t previously know I had. Yet hours later I was no longer holding my breath, but holding my fist in the air instead, as I gleefully mowed down masses of undead meatsacks like it was D-Day in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/world-war-z">World War Z</a>. In an effort to please both survival horror stalwarts and action-horror advocates, Resident Evil Requiem runs the gore-soaked gamut from anxiety-inducing chills to trigger-happy thrills. The result is yet another supremely hair-raising horror story, despite the fact its most potent scares have all been delivered by the time it arrives at its more gloriously gung-ho second half.  </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Resident Evil Requiem Review Screens</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Not unlike 2023’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/alan-wake-ii">Alan Wake II</a>, Resident Evil Requiem initially focuses on a young FBI agent, in this case series newcomer Grace Ashcroft (Angela Sant'Albano), a fresh-faced analyst who’s sent to investigate a series of mysterious deaths among the survivors of Raccoon City, several decades after the 1998 outbreak. Grace’s flashlight-lit forensic search through the grimy insides of a shuttered hotel is ultimately short-lived, however, since she’s soon ensnared by Victor Gideon (Antony Byrne), Requiem’s main antagonist whose menacing air, disgustingly disfigured face, and greasy goggles make him seem like some sort of steampunk Emperor Palpatine. Victor traps Grace in the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center, a Spencer Mansion-style labyrinth of locked doors crawling with all manner of flesh-eating freaks, but thankfully help is on the way in the form of uber stylish series veteran, Leon S. Kennedy (Nick Apostolides). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Survival horror’s preeminent himbo has clearly seen better days – the strange bruising on his skin suggests he’s battling some sort of affliction potentially related to T-Virus exposure, while the shiny new Porsche he’s driving implies he’s also not immune to a midlife crisis. But it’s Grace who is the standout here. Resident Evil characters have historically exhibited an exaggeratedly campy quality that’s injected a large dose of goofiness amidst the gore, but for my money this inexperienced FBI agent is by far the most relatably human heroine the series has ever had. Her evolution from being perpetually on the brink of a panic attack to becoming self-assured enough to fight back made for a journey that I found as captivating as it was consistently creepy. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Saving Grace</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Requiem allows us to alternate control between Grace and Leon at specific story junctions over the course of its roughly 10-hour campaign, but it’s the former whose predominately stealth-based sections are undoubtedly the most fear-inducing. Underpowered and under constant threat from twisted stalker ghouls that are liable to descend from the rafters at any moment, Grace’s efforts to escape from the terrors of Victor’s hospital is a wonderfully stressful slab of unrelenting survival horror. There’s precious little ammo to find, a miserly number of inventory slots to manage, and Grace moves at such a slow speed that it makes timing your careful crouch-walk to avoid a prowling pack of zombies an exercise in pinpoint pathmaking, especially if you don’t have a rare breakable bottle to toss in order to create a distraction. All the while you have to puzzle through a stimulating series of body part-based riddles and elaborately locked doors, never really knowing when you’re going to turn a corner and come face to flabby face with a grotesquely girthy golem that’s urgently squeezing its way down the hallway towards you.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph">I spent so much time trying to steer clear of the numerous considerable threats, that on the occasions Grace was forced into a confrontation the results really rattled me. When played in the default, claustrophobic first-person perspective, her guns feel genuinely startling to fire and the impact of every precious pistol shot is immense. Bullets tear the festering flesh off zombie faces leaving eyeballs to dangle from their stems, and blood spatter paints the walls and persists even when you backtrack through the area later on. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The gallons of gore that covers the floor isn’t just there for spectacle, mind you, since Grace is equipped with a handy blood collector that allows her to syringe up the infected plasma pooling around zombie corpses, and combine it with other pieces of scrap to craft invaluable items like medkits and single-use hemolytic injectors. The latter can be jammed into the spine of an undead monster caught unaware, causing their entire body to swell up and explode in the most gloriously blood-soaked manner of stealth-kill possible, but you can also use it to effectively dispose of a body you’ve downed previously. I found that to be a smart move in areas that I knew I’d be revisiting, since Requiem’s zombies also have a terrifying tendency to reanimate and mutate when you least expect them to. (Seriously, these guys reform and come back more often than The Eagles.)   </p><p>On the occasions Grace was forced into a confrontation the results really rattled me.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grace’s quest only grows more intense as it takes her through the suffocating shadows of the hospital’s basement and beyond, but moving through Requiem’s danger-filled surroundings at a snail’s pace didn’t just keep my nerves on edge, it allowed me to observe and appreciate the efforts that Capcom has put into enhancing the eerie behaviour of its undead army. These are no longer the groaning, foot-dragging mouth-breathers encountered during the original Raccoon City outbreak, instead they retain traces of humanity that somehow makes them seem far more unsettling than the more animalistic werewolves in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-village">Resident Evil Village</a>. Like the ones that idly flick light switches on and off like bored toddlers, or the others that wander around muttering and laughing to themselves before suddenly collapsing to their knees to hungrily feast on the corpse of one of their former friends. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Leon: The Professional</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">While Grace’s plight is a desperate and deliberate crawl that had me second-guessing every shadow, the ominous sounds of silence are shattered by the roar of ferocious ultraviolence when you switch control to Leon for what are initially brief, tension-breaking bursts, as everyone’s favourite ex-RCPD recruit attempts a not-so-subtle rescue mission. These levels default to a third-person view to really show off the slaughter, and within minutes of his arrival I’d slipped comfortably back into Resident Evil 4 mode, nailing headshots and ending the undead with effortless execution moves. To my surprise, however, Requiem quickly pushed the insanity meter beyond <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-4">Resident Evil 4</a> into <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dead-rising">Dead Rising</a> levels of delirium by allowing Leon to actually wield a chainsaw to carve through the zombie crowds. Leon’s sections are up-tempo and gruesome to a degree that left me giddy, and almost every major zombie Leon dispatches is met with a delightfully deadpanned dad joke.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Where Grace must use the scarce amounts of scrap in her surroundings to make her own rapidly destructible knives, Leon is toting a powerful hatchet that can be easily maintained with an everlasting flint. While Grace has to carefully count each round in her small handful of handguns, Leon enjoys an extensive bevy of teeth-rattling boomsticks from beefy shotguns to head-splitting sniper rifles. Plus, if Leon gets bored of his own weapons he can use someone else’s – after killing a zombie who drops a fire axe or lead pipe, he has the option to smoothly scoop it up and launch it at another enemy nearby, which is every bit as slick and satisfying as the similar sword-flinging feature of last year’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>. That’s not to mention that instead of having to painstakingly harvest blood samples to craft with, Leon is rewarded with a special currency for every kill that can be conveniently cashed in at a de facto ATM for artillery to buy useful weapon upgrades, extra ammo, and even body armour. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Simply put, there's no off position on Leon’s arse-kicking switch – his gunplay is John Wick-slick and bloodier than ever before – and in addition to his surging slaughter of zombie hordes it’s also within Leon’s levels that the bulk of Requiem’s appropriately epic boss encounters take place. There are plenty of colossal clashes to be found here, from brand new behemoths to brilliantly reimagined threats from previous Resident Evil stories, and there isn’t a single Del Lago-sized dud among them. I particularly loved how the hulking nasty faced inside a cramped chapel midway through the story subverted my expectations of how a Resident Evil boss fight should play out. Sure, being tasked with blasting the glowing weak points that cover a marauding monster’s torso is nothing new. That is, until you realise that while piercing each swollen blister does inflict damage to the beast, it also spews streams of infection onto the zombie underlings around him, instantly mutating them into brawnier forms of backup for you to contend with. Leon may be armed to the teeth, but that doesn’t mean Requiem doesn’t still find creative ways to ramp up the challenge.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Shorn of the Dread</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As much as I love Leon, though, I do wonder if perhaps his sections become a bit too dominant once Requiem settles into a more action-oriented groove in its second half, as the story moves beyond the grounds of Rhodes Hill and deep into what remains of Raccoon City. Let me be clear, Resident Evil 4 is my personal favourite instalment in the series, so it certainly gave me a great deal of pleasure to once again wield a military grade arsenal and pull-off skull-shattering finishing moves as the series’ hunkiest mutant murderer. There’s also plenty of variety in the violence, from a full-throttle highway chase sequence to heavy artillery strikes that seem straight out of a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty">Call of Duty</a> campaign. But after playing almost exclusively as Leon through a roughly five-hour stretch towards Requiem’s conclusion, I did find myself yearning for a few more tastes of Grace’s superbly nerve-shredding stealth sections as a more regular change-up from Leon’s comparatively scare-free carnage.</p><p>There's no off position on Leon’s arse-kicking switch.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">That desire was eventually gratified to some extent by a terrifyingly taut late-game tip-toe through a facility crawling with some truly menacing monsters returning from the series’ past, but given that the story ended soon afterwards my overriding impression of Requiem was that it was very much a game of two halves. The former predominately a slow and steady scare-a-thon, and the latter largely a run-and-gun splatterfest. I very much enjoyed both flavours in their own right; I just wish for the sake of its pacing that they’d been blended together a touch more over the full course of the journey. Instead, Requiem is a bit like ordering a whiskey and Coke and having it served in two separate glasses instead of being mixed into one. </p><span data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><section data-cy="user-list-embed"><span><div><h3 data-cy="title3">Tristan's Favourite Horror Games</h3><p>Intensity in ten entries.</p></div><span><a href="https://www.ign.com/playlist/tristan_ign_au/lists/tristans-favourite-survival-horror-games" sx="[object Object]" data-cy="see-all-btn" title="View All Games">See All</a></span></span></section></span><p data-cy="paragraph">To be fair, Grace’s absence from a significant stretch of Requiem is justified within the context of its story, and overall it’s a tale that gripped me harder than a zombie nurse gnawing on my neck. There are a number of blindsiding twists that cast new light on the origins of the Umbrella Corporation and the ambitions of its founder, along with an excellent mix of zombie-riddled locations both fresh and familiar to puzzle and pummel your way through, and plenty of vital notes to collect along the way. Some of these memos are crucial to understanding the intriguing mystery behind Grace’s abduction and the truth about her past, while others are just genuinely funny gags to help ease the tension. After encountering a specific zombie type in one medical wing that was obnoxiously singing at the top of her lungs, I got a good laugh out of uncovering a doctor’s report that had diagnosed her with ‘Main Character Syndrome’, for example. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also one particularly iconic location that Leon explores that I’m reluctant to spoil here (although it has been teased in pre-release trailers), which is jam-packed with fun Easter Eggs that made it a real treat to revisit as someone who’s been enjoying Resident Evil adventures ever since the T-Virus made its first outbreak on a black-bottomed CD for the original PlayStation. </p></section><p><span><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Like the result of an experiment conducted in an underground Umbrella Corporation lab, Resident Evil Requiem successfully splices two separate strains of survival horror together into the one highly infectious new mutation. It signals the return of a series legend and the arrival of a likeable new lead, amps up the gore to a new stomach-turning standard, and unleashes a scarier breed of zombie alongside some truly beastly boss fights. The lack of any meaningful side content like The Mercenaries mode is a touch disappointing, and I do wonder if a slightly more consistent balance could have been struck with the ebb and flow from jaw-clenching moments of tension to all-out assault, rather than frontloading the story with frights before giving way to a more bullet-riddled back half. Even so, from my first trembling steps into its shadows all the way to the tremendous, titan-sized takedown at its climax, Resident Evil Requiem kept me completely absorbed and consistently entertained whether it was all hair-raising or all guns blazing.</p></div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-review]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Takes Swipe at Jet Pack Cat Dominance, Addressing Its Reign of Terror in Fresh Hotfix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/blizzard-takes-swipe-at-jet-pack-cat-dominance-addressing-its-reign-of-terror-in-fresh-hotfix</link>
            <guid>1446076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve been playing Overwatch during the last couple of weeks, you’ve likely been haunted by the sound of a pair of small thruster engines followed by a squeaky “meow” serving as a precursor to your chosen hero’s face being scratched to death. Well, in order to soften this horror, Blizzard has released a hotfix attempting to address the terror that is Jet Pack Cat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The patch, released on February 24, applies the following nerfs for the supposed support character — not to her healing capabilities, nor her core offensive skills, but to the perks that lead to her becoming a killing machine.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Overwatch "The Reign of Talon" New Hero Images</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">These include her minor perk, Claws Out, having its cooldown increased from 6 to 8 seconds, meaning you’ll at least feel the pointy end of her paws a little less frequently. Also listed is a significant reduction to the major perk, Territorial, which sees the damage dealt reduced to 33% from 50%. Interestingly, there is no mention of any planned tweaks to her Ultimate ability, which effectively guarantees an enemy elimination due to its pick-up-and-drop nature. Cats don’t like wells, unless they’re lobbing you into one, it seems.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It will come as no small irony to long-term Overwatch players that the owner of this feline friend, Brigitte, also pretty much broke the game upon her introduction back in 2018, which led to a fair few weeks of her being practically unkillable before her loadout was addressed. While Jet Pack Cat is nowhere near as powerful as the Swedish support hero was, there’s no denying that they were a nuisance that needed to be tweaked. We’ll see if these fixes have the desired effect over the coming days, but as is the case with any online multiplayer game, adjustments always need to be made, especially when introducing five brand new characters in one go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of those other additions, they’ve also received a mixture of buffs and nerfs to their kit and cooldowns. Fellow healer, Mizuki, has seen the duration of his ultimate, Kenkai Sanctuary, increased from 6 to 7 seconds. DPS hero Emre’s burst rifle has had its damage increased from 20 to 22, and flaming fan-wielder Anran has seen the cooldown of her Inferno Rush ability reduced from 8.5 to 8 seconds, as well as an increase to the distance you can move while Dancing Blaze is active to 2.25 meters from 1.5.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While not as new as Emre or Anran, fellow walking weapon Vendetta has seen the damage of her overhead sword swing reduced from 130 to 120, as well as a bug fix allowing for that move to now be affected by horizontal knockbacks. Then there’s Domina, my dear beloved — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/domina-from-overwatch-will-you-be-my-valentine"><u>you can read all about how much I enjoy her here</u></a>. The destructive tank has, thankfully, only received a minor nerf, with the cost of her ultimate increasing by 12%. I’ll still be able to have my fun.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What do you make of each of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-is-ditching-the-2-amid-launch-of-new-story-driven-era-with-10-new-heroes">five new heroes that have made their way into Overwatch ever since it ditched the “2”?</a> Let us know in the comments. Be sure to keep it locked to IGN for all future updates on Overwatch, including if and when we see an updated look for Anran now that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-agree-that-she-can-be-even-better-overwatch-director-responds-after-voice-actor-and-fans-say-changes-are-needed-to-new-character-anran">the backlash to her appearance has been recognised by Blizzard</a>. </p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/blizzard-takes-swipe-at-jet-pack-cat-dominance-addressing-its-reign-of-terror-in-fresh-hotfix]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>