<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:22:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We're Taking Your Concerns Very Seriously but There Are No Easy Solutions' — Arrowhead Explains Why the Helldivers 2 Installation Size Is So Big on P]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/were-taking-your-concerns-very-seriously-but-there-are-no-easy-solutions-arrowhead-explains-why-the-helldivers-2-installation-size-is-so-big-on-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/were-taking-your-concerns-very-seriously-but-there-are-no-easy-solutions-%E2%80%94-arrowhead-explains-why-the-helldivers-2-installation-size-is-so-big-on-p.1315720/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii"><u>Helldivers 2</u></a> developer Arrowhead Studios still doesn't have a solution for the shooter's groaning installation size on PC — but it is working on it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/543369627969783286" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>update</u></a> posted to Steam earlier today, Arrowhead's deputy technical director, Brendan Armstrong, penned the first in a series of posts in which the engineering team talks about the "technical health" of the game, as well as the "technical challenges we're working through."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Admitting that the installation size "seems to be a hot topic right now" — at 150GB, Helldivers 2 takes up three times the space on PC than it does on console — the developer revealed that one of the reasons the PC size is so much bigger is because of data duplication and mechanical hard drives.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"The main issue with a mechanical HDD is seek time," Armstrong explained. "An HDD stores data on a spinning platter, and a physical arm with a read head has to move across the platter to find and retrieve data. The time it takes for this arm to 'seek' or move to the correct location is a significant performance bottleneck. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Imagine a large game level with various objects — trees, rocks, buildings, props. If the data for these objects is scattered all over the hard drive, the read head has to physically jump around the disk, which adds a lot of time to the loading process."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This, the director added, is why Arrowhead deliberately duplicates certain data files like a common tree texture or a sound effect and "place copies of them in physically close proximity to where they would be needed in the game."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Much of the data in the PC version of Helldivers 2 is duplicated. The practice of duplicating data to reduce loading times is a game development technique that is primarily used to optimize games for older storage media, particularly mechanical HDDs and optical discs like DVDs," the director explained. "This practice is largely unnecessary for games deployed on Solid State Drives (SSDs) which is why the console versions of Helldivers 2 do not do this."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, the post admits that with the advent of SSDs — which store data on flash memory chips that have no moving parts — seek time is virtually nonexistent, but as long as mechanical HDDs are part of the minimum spec PC requirements, it has to be included. Steam user surveys are "unable to give us data on mechanical HDD use in the overall gamer population," but Arrowhead's "best estimates" put it at around 12% of all PC gamers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Until we can more accurately determine the number of mechanical HDDs that Helldivers 2 is installed on, it is difficult to know how many players will be impacted by reducing the amount of data duplication," the post said. "Even if that number is small, keep in mind that the load time for each player dropping into a mission is determined by the slowest member of the squad."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Helldivers 2 Review Update Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While Arrowhead grapples with this issue and tries to get better data on how many of their players use mechanical HDDs, the team said it's made "some small gains in the next update" by sweeping for unused assets and "obvious problems," but admits we "will not likely notice them because the new stuff we’ve added will eat those gains."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the longer term, the team will make improvements to the engine to ensure the game doesn't waste RAM loading common data that isn't needed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Beyond that, the remaining work is a bigger, riskier, more speculative project where we apply some kind of compression to the game data and potentially replicate some of the de-duplication we do on consoles," the post concludes. "We don’t yet know if the impacts to load-times could make these approaches infeasible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We’re taking your concerns very seriously but there are no easy solutions. Until we live in a world where we know that most of our PC players are using SSD drives, sacrificing some extra hard drive space is necessary to ensure we’re all able to load into missions in a reasonable amount of time. We’ve clearly reached the limits of how much duplicated data is acceptable so smarter solutions and compromises are now required. We are very carefully weighing up the costs and tradeoffs of the options we have, and we’ll be sure to find a better balance between loading times and installation size soon."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/were-taking-your-concerns-very-seriously-but-there-are-no-easy-solutions-arrowhead-explains-why-the-helldivers-2-installation-size-is-so-big-on-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The God of War 20th Anniversary DualSense PS5 Controller Is Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-ps5-controller-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-ps5-controller-is-up-for-preorder.1315717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A controller worthy of Kratos.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has been on a roll lately with custom designed PS5 DualSense controllers. We’ve seen limited-edition controllers with themes based on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-ps5-and-dualsense-preorders-are-now-live-where-to-buy">Ghost of Yotei</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-joyful-limited-edition-dualsense-ps5-controller-is-up-for-preorder-where-to-buy">Astro Bot</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-death-stranding-2-ps5-dualsense-controller">Death Stranding 2</a>, and more. The next one to release is now available to preorder at a handful of retailers (<a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4L44?object_uuid=3d957a38-d31f-4848-b66b-7f382f9bc199&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0FST1H26R" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it at Amazon</a>). It’s a God of War-themed PS5 controller that’s made to celebrate the series’ 20th anniversary. The God of War 20th Anniversary Limited Edition controller costs $84.99 and will release on October 23, 2025. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">God of War 20th Anniversary DualSense PS5 Controller</h2><div catalogid="8108a751-5523-4b95-ae4c-aa0d7222a3ee" id="228715"><div id="228715" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>God of War 20th Anniversary DualSense PS5 Controller</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4L44?object_uuid=3d957a38-d31f-4848-b66b-7f382f9bc199&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0FST1H26R" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/akwVMg?object_uuid=3d957a38-d31f-4848-b66b-7f382f9bc199&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Best Buy</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QGrYjK?object_uuid=3d957a38-d31f-4848-b66b-7f382f9bc199&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at PS Direct</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aBDJyB?object_uuid=3d957a38-d31f-4848-b66b-7f382f9bc199&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Walmart</a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The design itself is elegantly understated. It’s a white controller, with a jagged red stripe starting on the right trigger and going down the front of the device, past the face buttons and onto the grip. It’s an instantly recognizable design, as the stripe matches the Omega tattoo on Kratos’ face. The white body of the controller also echoes Kratos’ skin, which is white because the Oracle cursed him to wear the ashes of his dead family forever (fun times!).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The face buttons are white, with all-red symbols (circle, triangle, square, and cross), and the D-pad is white with tiny red arrows on each direction. The touchpad is also white. Unlike most other <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-ps5-dualsense-colors-in-order">PS5 controller colors</a>, the inside of the grips and the area around the thumbsticks is also white. On the back of it there’s a God of War 20th Anniversary logo.</p><p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">God of War 20th Anniversary DualSense PS5 Controller</h3></div></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The original God of War launched in 2005 for PlayStation 2. Since then, our boy Kratos has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-games-in-order">appeared in a whole lot of games</a> across nearly <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-playstation-console-release-dates-in-order">every piece of PlayStation hardware released</a> in the meantime. He’s killed gods on PS3, PS4, and PS5, as well as the handheld platforms PSP and PS Vita. He’s killed gods in Greek mythology and Norse mythology. No mythology is safe. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a commerce editor and deals expert for IGN. He also runs IGN's board game and LEGO coverage. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 3, 2025 12:14 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-ps5-controller-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Mega Evolution: Where to Find ETBs, Boosters, and More In Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-where-to-buy-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-mega-evolution-where-to-find-etbs-boosters-and-more-in-stock.1315714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's here, and it's all shiny and new. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a> has moved on from its Scarlet &amp; Violet series of expansions and is now in its official Mega Evolution era. The first of which is aptly titled "Mega Evolution", and is now available to buy (supposedly). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the US, at least, stock is remarkably scarce; no surprise there. While in Europe and EMEA regions (including the Middle East and Africa), the <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/uk/pokemon-news/important-notice-about-the-upcoming-pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-expansion" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official release has been delayed until October 10, 2025</a>. The Pokémon Company has said this is down to "challenges impacting product delivery dates," which sure clears things up... right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Well no. But for now, we're going to focus on where you can <em>actually </em>buy Pokémon TCG: Mega Evolution in the US, and find those elusive ETBs, Booster Bundles, and more in stock. Be sure to bookmark this page and check back often to stay informed. We will keep this page updated when there are developments for the UK and Europe as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To make navigating the preorder chaos as easy as possible, here’s the complete breakdown of where to secure your Mega Evolution boxes, bundles, and packs before launch. Just to note, it'll likely cost you, as finding sealed products like these at a fair price is already a challenge. </p><p id="elite-trainer-boxes-etbs"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Elite Trainer Boxes (ETBs)">Mega Evolution: Elite Trainer Boxes (ETBs)</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Evolution is already shaping up to be one of the most competitive Pokémon TCG sets in years, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-brave-symphonia-most-expensive-cards">Mega Lucario ex and Mega Gardevoir ex</a> driving demand through the roof. Unsurprisingly, Elite Trainer Boxes availability is chaotic, and pricing depends heavily on where you shop.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The retail price is $49.99, but most outlets are out of stock or only show fleeting availability. Best Buy and Walmart do occasionally cycle listings back in at or near MSRP, though they rarely last long once they appear. Amazon and similar retailers are far less reliable, with most third-party sellers inflating prices well into triple digits.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to secure the product without the hassle of chasing restocks, TCGPlayer is the most straightforward option, though it comes at a premium. Resale prices there are averaging around $90, while Pokémon Center exclusives have reached roughly $200-$300. The best value remains catching a restock at <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q47mEG?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Best Buy</a> or <a href="https://zdcs.link/zEg2bG?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Walmart</a>, but if reliability matters more than price, TCGPlayer is where you’ll actually get what you want.</p><p id="sealed-boosters"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Sealed Boosters">Mega Evolution: Where to Buy Sealed Boosters</h2></p><div catalogid="4aaeaa5d-9765-4a22-8fef-b266790ea2f0" id="227469"><div id="227469" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Booster Box (36 Packs)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aAgKV7?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mega Evolution's Booster Box</a> is the best option if you want the largest number of packs in one go. TCGPlayer has them for around $298.21 market price, which breaks down to about $8.28 per pack. That is still a markup versus MSRP (~$5), but still <em>slightly</em> better value than buying singles or smaller bundles. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Most other major retailers are sold out, so if you want a box right now, a trustworthy site like TCGPlayer is the place to get one, and has the <strong>best prices going in the secondary market right now</strong>.</p></div><div catalogid="4aaeaa5d-9765-4a22-8fef-b266790ea2f0" id="227470"><div id="227470" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Booster Bundle (6 Packs)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If $300 feels too steep, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z12dY?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Booster Bundles</a> are the next best option. Each comes with six packs and usually sells for MSRP when available, though they rarely stay in stock anywhere. On TCGPlayer, they run closer to $56.42, which is expensive but reliably available. Yet, they are ultimately also the worse value on paper, at an average cost of $9.40 per pack.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right now, singles are the cheapest way in when retailers have them, typically $4-5 each, but they almost always sell out fast. On TCGPlayer, they sit at about <a href="https://zdcs.link/zEgOjX?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$8.62 per pack</a> or <a href="https://zdcs.link/985MLv?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$34.92 for a four-pack</a>, which is pricier but far easier to find. </p></div><div catalogid="4aaeaa5d-9765-4a22-8fef-b266790ea2f0" id="227474"><div id="227474" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sleeved Booster Pack Art Bundle (4 Packs)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Note, that while technically more expensive, buying the four pack of boosters is still more cost effective as you ultimately save on delivery, and that would probably be my recommendation for anyone looking to pick up a few packs without any stress.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, there's the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aDgwVw?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Blister Packs</a>, which bundle three boosters with a promo card, are another strong choice for casual buyers. They are listed around <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qdbk7K?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$40 on TCGPlayer</a>, more than double retail, but unlike most big-box stores, they are actually in stock.</p></div><p id="build-battle-boxes"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Build &amp; Battle Boxes">Build &amp; Battle Boxes</h2></p><div catalogid="4aaeaa5d-9765-4a22-8fef-b266790ea2f0" id="227475"><div id="227475" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME01: Mega Evolution (MEG)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Build &amp; Battle Box Display</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aebVww?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Build &amp; Battle boxes</a> include four booster packs and a 40-card deck, making them ideal for local pre-release events. They have not yet seen a wide release, so availability is limited and prices are volatile. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On TCGPlayer, individual boxes are holding steady at around $55, while <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjpL42?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">10 unit bundles are pushing closer to $550</a>. Walmart still lists these at $59.99 when they appear, which is a steep jump from the usual $19.99 to $24.99 range and strangely even more than the resale market.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The best approach is to wait for wider release and target a box closer to MSRP, but if you want guaranteed access before then, TCGPlayer offers the most reliable option despite its inflated pricing. They are currently set to ship for October 10, 2025.</p></div><p id="most-valuable-chase-cards"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Most Valuable Chase Cards">Most Valuable Chase Cards</h2></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/02/top-15-best-chase-cards-pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-ign-1759401864957.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">With towering HP values, stunning full-art designs, and the punishing 3-Prize rule when a Mega ex is knocked out, Mega Evolution cards are already making waves in both the collector market and competitive play. As with any major set, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-cards-most-expensive-cards">few chase cards have quickly risen to the top</a> thanks to playability, artwork, or sheer popularity. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help you in the chase for some rare pulls, we have sought out the most expensive chase cards in the Mega Evolution set so far. That includes the highly sought after golden "Hyper Mega Rare" Mega Lucario ex and Mega Gardevoir ex, both of which are already reaching <a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/content/article/Pok%C3%A9mon-TCG-Mega-Evolution-Pull-Rates/40cbeedc-21ce-473b-aef1-74e3969d9f91/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$500+ market price due to some painfully harsh pull rates</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, prices are shifting constantly in these early days of release, so the live <a href="https://zdcs.link/QVExJN?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGPlayer page</a> is also worth checking out daily for any daily changes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For now, other highlights include heavy hitters like Mega Venusaur ex and Mega Latias ex, alongside nostalgic Special Art Rares such as Lillie’s Determination. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Collectors are scrambling to secure these cards before prices climb further, making Mega Evolution one of the most volatile and exciting sets in years. If you're opening packs, be sure to look out for all these chase cards along your journey, and good luck!</p><p id="whats-next-for-mega-evolution"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="What's Next for Mega Evolution?">What's Next for Mega Evolution?</h2></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/22/phantasmal-flames-pokemon-tcg-preorder-cover-1758583155341.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">That's an easy one, it's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy">Mega Evolution: Phantasmal Flames</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The next <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-release-full-release-schedule-2025">Pokémon TCG expansion on the 2025 release schedule</a> lands fairly soon on 14 November, 2025, and collectors are already scrambling to secure their favourite sealed products before the inevitable shortages. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With headliners like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-september-5"><u>Mega Charizard X ex</u></a> taking centre stage, demand is set to run hot across every major retailer... again!</p><div catalogid="6aed4ddb-a526-4eb5-b395-65faeb0ca009" id="228294"><div id="228294" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>ME02: Phantasmal Flames (PFL)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/z7MWBL?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGplayer</u></a> is still the only place with standard Phantasmal Flames ETB stock readily available. However, these Elite Trainer Boxes are listed for around $164.49 (yikes), while the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qxx04m?object_uuid=5949c6fe-9e19-4301-910c-85c54d598ef1&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Pokémon Center-exclusive version</u></a> is an eye-watering $587.93 right now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's significantly more than the initial Mega Evolution ETBs are running for, so fingers crossed prices come down closer to launch.</p></div><p id="navigating-mega-evolutions-scarcity"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Navigating Mega Evolution's Scarcity">Navigating Mega Evolution's Scarcity Post Launch</h2></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/23/mega-sets-new-pokemon-ign-2-1750688466013.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Evolution is now fully released, and finding sealed products at retail is already close to impossible. Best Buy and Walmart may list items at MSRP, but restocks vanish in seconds and are more of a lottery than a strategy. Unless you enjoy sitting on endless refresh cycles, it is not a realistic way to secure the set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The secondary market is where most collectors will need to turn. TCGPlayer is the most reliable option, with steady availability across all product types. Prices are inflated, with Booster Boxes already around $280 and rising, but you are paying for certainty rather than chasing ghost stock at traditional retailers.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon is best avoided. Almost every listing comes from third-party sellers, and markups are among the steepest you will see, with little to justify the premium beyond fast shipping.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At this stage, the best approach is to accept that MSRP is gone. If you want Mega Evolution products, TCGPlayer is the most straightforward path, while retail sites are little more than a distraction. Acting sooner rather than later is wise, as scarcity is only pushing prices higher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Anderson is Senior Commerce Editor and IGN's resident deals expert on games, collectibles, trading card games, and more. You can follow him <a href="https://x.com/robertliam21" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter/X or <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/robertliam21.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bluesky</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This article contains contributions by Ben Williams.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-where-to-buy-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>