<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:57:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save on the Magic: The Gathering Fallout Bundle and Get Each Commander Deck for Under $40 at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-fallout-bundle-commander-decks-amazon-prime-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-on-the-magic-the-gathering-fallout-bundle-and-get-each-commander-deck-for-under-40-at-amazon.1317928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fallout with friends, just in time for Season Two.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> has offered Universes Beyond crossovers with other franchises for a few years now, and while some become full sets like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-spider-man-most-popular-cards"><u>Spider-Man</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-are-up-for-preorder"><u>Final Fantasy</u></a>, others are more squarely focused on Commander.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of these is Fallout, which was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-fallout-decks-touted-by-hasbro-ceo-as-one-of-the-best-selling-commander-sets-ever"><u>particularly popular</u></a> back in 2024 and offers a fantastic quartet of Commander decks to play, whether you’re an experienced player or just looking to get started. Better yet, <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6D8BR?object_uuid=6034817e-26e6-4737-83e4-709a58b40a4e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>a bundle of all four is discounted at Amazon right now</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Fallout Commander Decks: Under $40 Each With This Bundle Deal</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has all four decks for $144.99, a reduction of 11% on the $162.99 list price. That might not sound like a huge amount, but consider what that value represents when the Mutant Menace deck is selling for $70 and upwards on its own.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the decks, the good news is that they’re all pretty great. Mutant Menace is one of the best, powering up its spooky Mothman Commander with counters as you deal radiation to everyone else at the table, while Hail Caesar is all about being aggressive and sacrificing cards to power up Caesar himself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Science! offers something a little different since it leans into energy counters and powering up the board with artifacts, while Scrappy Survivors is definitely popular since it’s helmed by the adorable Dogmeat and has the series’ four-legged star rummaging through your graveyard for equipment and tokens.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As a reminder, each of these decks comes with a Collector Booster Sample Pack, too. They contain two cards each, but it’s better than getting irradiated, right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you already have any of these, Amazon has discounts on a couple of them, too. At the time of writing, you can pick up <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6D8Bk?object_uuid=6034817e-26e6-4737-83e4-709a58b40a4e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Scrappy Survivors for $44.99</u></a>, a discount of 25%, while <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxRpb?object_uuid=6034817e-26e6-4737-83e4-709a58b40a4e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Hail Caesar undercuts it by literal cents</u></a>: It’s $44.95. Finally, Amazon isn’t showing it as discounted, but <a href="https://zdcs.link/QOgy2B?object_uuid=6034817e-26e6-4737-83e4-709a58b40a4e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>$40 is a decent price for Science</u></a>!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.<br>
</p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 6, 2025 5:30 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-fallout-bundle-commander-decks-amazon-prime-day]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Day One Patch Includes Changes to Movement, Weapon Recoil, Rush, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-day-one-patch-includes-changes-to-movement-weapon-recoil-rush-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-day-one-patch-includes-changes-to-movement-weapon-recoil-rush-and-more.1317922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA and Battlefield Studios have previewed some of the gameplay tweaks and balance changes coming with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6"><u>Battlefield 6</u></a> day one patch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Information about the first patch for this week’s long-awaited back-to-basics Battlefield game was outlined in a post on <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/news/community-update-play-your-way" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>its official website</u></a> today. It comes with a breakdown from the team explaining how their pre-release Battlefield Labs and beta tests helped them prepare for launch, with the first Battlefield 6 patch set to provide an even more stable foundation.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Those who played the Battlefield 6 open beta in August will notice several fundamental changes to how the DICE, Criterion, Ripple Effect, and Motive-developed game feels after its day one patch is downloaded. Today’s first look at the Battlefield 6 launch update is only a taste of what's to come, with full patch notes for the more than 200 changes set to arrive later this week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Topping the list are tweaks the BF Studios team says will make movement feel more responsive, including fixes for “several movement issues” and changes to pacing. Weapon attachments should also display correctly across the Battlefield 6 experience, with the day one patch also promising rebalanced automatic weapons that make long-range gunplay more rewarding for tap firing and burst control.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beta players will also be happy to hear Rush and Breakthrough have been reworked to improve balance between both the attacking and defending teams. Gadgets in Battlefield 6 will also be changed for the day one patch. The MBT-LAW, for example, is now set as the default Engineer launcher, while the MAS 148 now behaves more realistically, and Deploy Beacons have been updated to limit one spawn per player.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best Battlefield Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While the Battlefield 6 day one patch also promises updated UI and HUD elements, cleaner audio, improved network stability, and more, today’s post also comes with an update on one of the most hotly contested topics in the community: Open vs. Closed Weapons. Closed locks guns to specific classes, while Open allows each class to utilize a variety of different weapon types. Despite waves of fans hoping to see the BF Studios team lean on Closed classes for Battlefield 6, the team insisted in today’s post that Open classes were preferred by “the vast majority of players.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Lastly, another key insight from the Open Beta was that the vast majority of players, after trying both playlist types, chose to stick with Open Weapons,” BF Studios says. “This reinforces our belief that Open Weapons is the right path forward for Battlefield 6. At the same time, we recognize that some players prefer the Closed Weapons experience. To support them, official Closed Weapons playlists will be available at launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Additionally, Closed Weapons mutators will remain part of the Portal toolset, so players can create and share their own custom experiences.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield 6 has a release date of October 10 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. Check out the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-global-release-times-confirmed"><u>Battlefield 6 global release times</u></a> if you want to know when you'll be able to play in your timezone. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-roadmap-revealed-heres-what-to-expect">Season 1</a>, meanwhile, kicks off October 28 and will deliver additional maps, guns, vehicles, and more, with additional updates planned for November 18 and December 9.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Based on our time with the Battlefield 6 beta, we’ve got a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/Battlefield_6_Beta_Beginner%27s_Guide_and_Tips">BF6 Beginner’s Guide and Tips</a>, plus the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/Best_BF6_Loadouts">best Battlefield 6 Loadouts</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/BF6_Range_Finder_Explained">how to use the Range Finder</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/How_to_Deploy_Bipod">deploy the Bipod</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/How_to_Turn_Off_Haptic_Feedback">how to turn off Haptic Feedback in Battlefield 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, you can see everything we know about the Battlefield 6 day one patch below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Battlefield 6 Day One Patch Notes Preview:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following gameplay updates will be included in our launch day patch, with over 200 changes focused on bug fixes, balance improvements, and polish for release. Stay tuned for the full launch day update notes closer to launch!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Player</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>You’ll notice that movement feels more responsive, with changes made to pacing and with several movement issues addressed to keep gameplay smooth and balanced.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Weapons</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Recoil has been rebalanced on automatic weapons, making long-range gunplay more characteristic, rewarding tap firing and burst control.</li><li>Numerous weapon attachments have been fixed so they now display correctly in menus and in-game.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Gadgets</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The LTLM II (Laser Designator) has been refined with smoother deploy animations, updated visuals, and several fixes for better feel when used.</li><li>The MBT-LAW is now the default Engineer launcher, with a more accurate trajectory, improved guidance, and clearer sights.</li><li>The MAS 148 Glaive is enhanced with more realistic missile path, improved zoom and lock-on, sharper scope visuals, and more reliable vehicle damage.</li><li>Deploy Beacons are now limited to one spawn per player (four per squad total), helping maintain balance and prevent overuse.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Maps and Modes</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Rush and Breakthrough layouts have been revised for better balance between attackers and defenders.</li><li>Operation Firestorm has been updated with improved vaulting, lightning, and performance, while Siege of Cairo spawn killing and Out of Bounds issues have been addressed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UI &amp; HUD</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>UI and HUD elements are clearer, with updated overlays, animated pings, new minimap options, and smoother loadout and deploy navigation.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Settings</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Settings and controls have expanded with new options like VO volume sliders, sprint bob reduction, and a camera roll toggle for accessibility, plus refinements across platforms.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Audio</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Audio has been cleaned up so pings are easier to hear, weapons and vehicles sound sharper, and missing delayed effects won’t get in the way of your awareness.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Network</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Netcode improvements reduce desync, make time-to-death feel fairer, and address cases of invisible damage.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-day-one-patch-includes-changes-to-movement-weapon-recoil-rush-and-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: Pokémon TCG, Games and Funko Prime Day Deals Drop Early]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-october-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-games-and-funko-prime-day-deals-drop-early.1317919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2025-news-and-predictions">Prime Day</a> doesn't drop until tommorow, but we're already seeing big savings across Pokémon Switch 1 games, Funko Pop! and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-most-expensive-cards-2025">trading card game sealed products</a> at market value or less. It's a great day to be a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-september-12">Pokémon</a> Trainer, and I'm about to save you some Pokédollars on from legendary and mythical merch you've had your eye on for a while.</p><p id="tldr-deals-for-today"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="TL;DR: Deals For Today">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Highlights today include <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wjrRp?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Team Rocket’s Mewtwo ex Box for $30.95</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6D88Y?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Surging Sparks Elite Trainer Box dropping to under $75</a> on TCGPlayer. More into Funko Pops than trading cards? <a href="https://zdcs.link/9217mE?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Pokémon Advent calander for this Christmas is down to $44.99</a>, not to mention <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gjkPn?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mew is down to just $8</a>. It's also a great time to fill up that Pokémon backlog collection thanks to the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9YM1Wd?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">EU version of Detective Pikachu Returns is down to $34.17 </a>(don't worry, Switch 1 and 2 aren't region locked) and a <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBDYgb?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">massive 27% off Shining Pearl at $43.50. </a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Need more deals? Let's get into it:</p><p id="prime-day-pokmon-switch-games"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Prime Day: Pokémon Switch Games">Prime Day: Pokémon Switch Games and Consoles</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fancy trying out the first Pokémon Legends game before Z-A launches? <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6D8oj?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Legends: Arceus is down to $52.49 </a>right now, a lovely 13% discount off RRP. If you're looking for something that performs better on Nintendo Switch 2? Well Pokémon Violet is now a completely different (pocket) monster since it's Switch 2 patch. Playing this game on native hardware at a smooth 4K 60 FPS is brilliant. Yes, it's still buggy and pop-in is here to stay, but it's an enjoyable romp. <a href="https://zdcs.link/QWEowK?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">It's also dropped by 13%, down to $51.99</a> which is well worth it.</p><p id="prime-day-pokmon-funko-pop"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Prime Day: Pokémon Funko Pop!">Prime Day: Pokémon Funko Pop!</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you've been on the fence about collecting Pokémon Funko Pops! like I have, this might be the time that pushes me over the edge. Even my first ever starter <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4rgg?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Bulbasaur is on offer in its soft color variant</a> (Which is also an Amazon exclusive) Throw in <a href="https://zdcs.link/QmOb3N?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Squirtle for $10</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yGALn?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charmander for $13.49</a> and i've got all three Kantonian starters for way below RRP. <a href="https://zdcs.link/zn5Voj?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Grookey is nice and cheap at $10.50</a> too, so don't sleep on these deals.</p><p id="pokmon-tcg-price-watch"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG Price Watch">Pokémon TCG Price Watch</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">We might be on the verge of prime day and a couple of sealed products coming in slightly lower than market value in Mega Evolution Booster Bundle and this years Holiday Calendar, but TCGPlayer is still showing up big box retailers with their sellers market value pricing. From <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBDYYE?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">saving $27.94 on a Mega Evolution Elite Trainer Box</a> to catching a cheeky <a href="https://zdcs.link/aN866B?object_uuid=256fdf8d-c5dd-46dc-8520-989a54106dbd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$5 off a Prismatic Evolutions Surprise Box</a>, your money is better in your pocket.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-october-6]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crimson Desert Is This Month’s IGN First, Check Out 11 Minutes of New Quest Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-gameplay-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crimson-desert-is-this-month%E2%80%99s-ign-first-check-out-11-minutes-of-new-quest-gameplay.1317778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Retaking the Captured Fortress.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/06/crimson-desert-gameplay-banner-1759758606289.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The wild and expansive open-world adventure, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/crimson-desert">Crimson Desert</a>, is the focus of October’s IGN First. As is tradition, we’re kicking off a month of exclusive content with a brand new gameplay video. Above, you can watch a playthrough of The Captured Fortress, one of Crimson Desert’s faction quests, in which you help Duke Wells retake his castle from rebel forces. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This 11 minute-long video showcases a number of Crimson Desert’s key features. First and foremost, of course, is combat. Ever since we <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-is-like-god-of-war-and-dragons-dogma-had-a-baby-gamescom-2024">first played Crimson Desert at Gamescom 2024</a>, we’ve known that developer Pearl Abyss has been assembling something special when it comes to battle, and here you can see protagonist Kliff making use of a wide array of abilities. Among our favourites is using a spear to pole-vault into an enemy, and the incredibly powerful, magically-charged heavy attacks. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But this demonstration mission covers more than just combat. You’ll also see how Kliff can explore the environment using magic leaps, a Spider-Man-like swing, and his Crow Wings ability, which allows him to glide through the skies towards far-off objectives. You’ll also see him using his sword to reflect light, a skill that highlights points of interest in the world and guides you towards interesting discoveries. By following the shining lights, Kliff is able to infiltrate the Duke’s captured fortress in a more stealthy manner… and discover some extra loot along the way, too. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, a Crimson Desert showcase wouldn’t be complete without a boss battle, and so this video concludes with a full, violent clash against Fortain, the Cursed Knight. This armour-clad bad lad wields a sword with a mighty, supernatural ability that you don’t want to miss. You might even be able to claim it for yourself…</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And remember, this video is just the first drop. Throughout the month of October, IGN First will take you on a journey into the world of Crimson Desert. You’ll get to see many more bosses, regions, combat abilities, and two or three exciting new things you’d never guess would be part of a medieval fantasy game. For all that, stay tuned to IGN over the next few weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Executive Editor of Features. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-gameplay-ign-first]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Walmart Is Granting Paid Members Early Access to Pokémon TCG Restocks Today, Here's What's Up for Grabs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prime-day-elite-trainer-box-discount-walmart-plus-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/walmart-is-granting-paid-members-early-access-to-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-restocks-today-heres-whats-up-for-grabs.1317775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Grabbing Prismatic Evolutions cards at a good price has felt like a lost cause for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a> collectors, but Walmart has confirmed that its upcoming <a href="https://zdcs.link/9217my?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">October Deals event</a> will include a significant offer that seems too good to be true.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beginning on 6 October, from 7 PM ET, paid <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/walmart-plus"><u>Walmart+ members</u></a> will have early access to purchase the highly sought-after <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4PlZ?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Prismatic Evolutions Elite Trainer Box for $59.99</a>, a 50% reduction from its "regular" $119.99 price.</p><div catalogid="33f87b44-ee72-4240-98ad-021acd5d3806" id="192311"><div id="192311" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Walmart+ Membership</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>30-day free trial available. Then it's $12.95/month, or $98/year.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're not already a member, it’s admittedly a slight drag that you’ll essentially have to add $12.95 onto that $59.99 price tag; it’s still better than the $200 minimum you’ll currently find on other marketplaces like <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxLBp?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGPlayer</u></a> for the same set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Plus, this is going to sell out FAST, and I highly doubt there will be any remaining for the general non-Walmart+ shoppers looking for a bargain. Not only that, but you're going more for your money if you're looking to grab the brand new and upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-cards-most-expensive-cards"><u>Mega Evolution</u></a> expansion, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy"><u>Phantasmal Flames</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Walmart is doing a repeat of the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4PlZ?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Prismatic Evolutions deal preview drop</a>, but this time with preorders for the upcoming set featuring Mega Charizard X during Walmart Collector Con. The preorders will drop at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET on October 9, so you better bookmark those links and be ready to go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a big deal, and even worth dropping the $13 on Walmart+ alone, considering just the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QqReJ0?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Phantasmal Flames Elite Trainer Box is going for $160+ right now resale</a>, and Walmart will be selling for just $55! Holy smokes! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you're after Prismatic ETBs or elusive preorders at MSRP for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy"><u>Phantasmal Flames</u></a>, picking up a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/walmart-plus">Walmart+ membership</a> is undoubtedly the move this week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s also important to know that whilst Walmart+ does have a 30-day trial available, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9213Ay?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart+ hub page</u></a> states that only paid members will have access to its early deals on 6 October. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The annoying part of the Walmart+ subscription process, if you want to buy early access items right away, is that you're only given the initial option to claim the 30-day trial. <strong>However, you can get around this by starting your free trial, cancelling it, and resubscribing for paid access. </strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Walmart Deals event, scheduled for 7-12 October, is designed to compete directly with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/amazon-prime-day"><u>Amazon’s Prime Day</u></a>. However, Walmart+ members will benefit from exclusive early access starting the day prior, on 6 October. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The idea is that after that early access day, the deals will then be made available to the wider public who don’t have Walmart+. However, given how quickly almost any MSRP-priced stock for new sets in the Pokémon TCG is selling out at all retailers, we’re certain this particular ETB will be sold out within hours, if not minutes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A Walmart+ subscription is priced at $12.95 per month, or $98 annually, and offers a range of benefits beyond early shopping privileges. Members receive free delivery with no order minimum, savings on fuel, access to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/paramount-plus"><u>Paramount+</u></a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/peacock"><u>Peacock</u></a> at no extra cost, and additional perks such as pharmacy delivery and discounts at selected partners. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although we are expecting Amazon Prime Day and the upcoming Black Friday sales to offer some decent Pokémon TCG deals of their own, this is still quite frankly one of the best we’ve seen this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We don’t expect Walmart to repeat this kind of deal for the foreseeable, or Walmart to match it. Even so, there’s no guarantee you’ll be able to beat out all the other keen collectors, scalpers, and their bots who might be trying to nab one before you can. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">What we’d advise is to have your paid Walmart+ subscription set up and you be logged in on 6 October, and if you get the chance to add one of those half-priced Prismatic Evolutions ETBs to your basket, you take it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Note: Pokémon TCG pricing is incredibly volitile and any mention of sale pricing is indicative of the current market rate for the aforementioned products. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, Pokémon Elite Trainer Boxes are meant to sell for around $50-$60 MSRP, but instead retailer at around $100+ post launch.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 6, 2025 4:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prime-day-elite-trainer-box-discount-walmart-plus-early-access]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>