<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:44:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Dev Already Hitting Skills With Big Nerfs: 'It Is Better to Do This Early Before It Feels Obligatory to Use the Skill']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-dev-already-hitting-skills-with-big-nerfs-it-is-better-to-do-this-early-before-it-feels-obligatory-to-use-the-skill</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-dev-already-hitting-skills-with-big-nerfs-it-is-better-to-do-this-early-before-it-feels-obligatory-to-use-the-skill.1055865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-dev-already-hitting-skills-with-big-nerfs-it-is-better-to-do-this-early-before-it-feels-obligatory-to-use-the-skill<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We're currently playing alongside you all…"</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a> developer Grinding Gear Games has already identified a number of skills it plans to nerf following the action RPG’s explosive Early Access launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just a day after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-enjoys-massive-launch-becomes-15th-most-played-game-ever-on-steam">Path of Exile 2 launched to huge concurrent player numbers on Steam</a>, GGG <a href="https://x.com/pathofexile/status/1865502715297865891" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a> to say it had “finally hit that point where a skill with unacceptable balance has been discovered.” The skill in question is Supercharged Slam, which GGG said is dealing “far too much damage than was intended given the short channel window required to hit maximum stages.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The developer reduced its damage via a hotfix soon after issuing the tweet. “As much as we are trying to avoid nerfing skills and builds, it is better to do this early before it feels obligatory to use the skill,” GGG explained. “It is important that a wide variety of skills feel viable and fun to play and it simply diminishes all other abilities when one is clearly outshining the others like this.” Another nerf is set for Supercharged Slam to adjust how long it takes to build up charges, “as it is far too quick at the moment.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then, on December 8, GGG <a href="https://x.com/pathofexile/status/1865656519670497550" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said</a> it had found another skill in an “unacceptable” balance state: Magnetic Salvo. Path of Exile 2’s next hotfix reduces its damage. “Note that this isn't the only skill on our radar right now but we're really just trying to address egregious cases at the moment,” GGG said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We're currently playing alongside you all and are also collating a lot of your feedback that we'll be addressing as much as possible in the upcoming week once the team is back in the office before the holidays.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And then, on December 9, GGG <a href="https://x.com/pathofexile/status/1865939374304886931" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said</a> it's “a bit too easy” to detonate Gas Cloud explosions when combined with persistent Ignite skills like Flame Wall. Yet another upcoming hotfix will nerf explosion damage of both Gas Grenade and Gas Arrow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“In the future, we want to update it such that the potency of the Ignite or Detonator contributes to determining the damage of the Gas Cloud explosions, that way we would be able to avoid balancing around the simplest and most efficient way to apply Ignites,” GGG explained.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Path of Exile 2 is GGG’s action role-playing sequel set years after the original game. Players return to the world of Wraeclast and seek to end a spreading corruption, with six character classes, each with two Ascendancy Classes, available to play at the launch of Early Access. There’s co-op for up to six players, but you can play solo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It launched across PC via Steam, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S on December 6 and immediately ran into server issues that prevented players from logging in. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-never-expected-things-to-go-this-big-during-early-access-path-of-exile-2-dev-braces-itself-for-over-1-million-concurrent-players"><u>GGG had warned players that Path of Exile 2 might struggle with the influx of players at launch</u></a>, and so it proved. But over the course of Friday and into the weekend, the New Zealand developer began to get on top of the problems, and its concurrent player count on Steam shot up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/Classes_Guide:_Which_Class_to_Pick_in_PoE_2_Early_Access"><u>which class to pick in PoE 2 Early Access</u></a>, plus an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/Early_Mercenary_Build"><u>early Mercenary build</u></a> guide and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/Sorceress_Frozen_Explosion_League_Starter_Build_Guide"><u>Sorceress build guide</u></a> to help you get started. Beyond that, if you’re wondering <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/How_to_Get_More_Spirit"><u>how to get more Spirit</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/How_to_Trade"><u>how to trade</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/path-of-exile-2/How_to_Ascend"><u>how to ascend</u></a>, we’ve got you covered.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>