<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:27:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Battle Royale Official Name and Release Date Reportedly Leak Online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-official-name-and-release-date-reportedly-leak-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-battle-royale-official-name-and-release-date-reportedly-leak-online.1334263/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> appears to have suffered yet another leak, this time relating to its battle royale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone/status/1981741907387523203" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ModernWarzone</a>, which has a track record of accurate reporting around unannounced video game information, particularly in relation to Call of Duty, the Battlefield 6 battle royale is called Battlefield: RedSec.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">ModernWarzone also reported that it’s free-to-play and is due out on October 28, the same day Battlefield 6 Season 1 is set to launch. Given EA and Battlefield Studios are yet to make any announcements about this so close to that date, a shadowdrop is expected.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While EA is yet to comment on this particular leak, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-gameplay-highlights-multiplayer-combat-in-latest-bf-labs-leak">it’s seen various gameplay clips emerge from playtests of the battle royale</a>. And today <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-community-update-reveals-long-list-of-gameplay-changes-ahead-of-season-1-and-battle-royale-launch">it outlined gameplay changes coming to battle royale ahead of its release</a>, based on feedback to those playtests.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s what BF Studios said today:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s a quick look at what changes you may notice the next time you play:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Close-range TTK</strong>: We’ve adjusted time-to-kill at close range for all weapons to reward clean positioning and tracking while giving players more time to counter attacks. We’ll keep monitoring this once it’s live.</li><li><strong>Armor Changes</strong>: Everyone will now have the capacity for 2 armor plates at the start of the game. All players will spawn with 1 plate, so you will have the chance to upgrade as soon as you start looting, giving everyone an equal chance at upgrading their armor fully.</li><li><strong>World Improvements</strong>: We’ve been fixing pesky world bugs and optimizing areas to improve the environment. With these improvements, we made adjustments to the lighting as well as enhancing the visibility across the map.</li><li><strong>Vehicle Balance</strong>: We’ve adjusted the balance for helicopters and combat vehicles to keep them as powerful tools showing off Battlefield’s core DNA, without making them necessary to survive or win the late game. This includes significant adjustments to the heli countermeasures and ammo economy.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">We have also been working on providing smoother performance overall. We have identified and addressed a range of issues that affected performance that we simply couldn’t have done without our players’ involvement in the tests.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we wait, it’s worth checking out the Battlefield 6 update 1.1.1.0 patch notes, below, which go into detail on the changes coming to the game with Season 1. Finally, be sure to check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/All_Multiplayer_Maps"><u>full list of all currently available Battlefield 6 multiplayer maps</u></a>. Those looking to brush up on their online skills can also read <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/Multiplayer_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>our multiplayer tips and tricks guide</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Battlefield 6 Season 1 update 1.1.1.0 patch notes:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We are deploying Update 1.1.1.0 on Tuesday, October 28, followed by the Season 1 launch later that day at the following times:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>09:00 UTC:</strong> Update 1.1.1.0 goes live on all platforms. Players will be prompted to download and install the update, which includes all technical and gameplay changes.</li><li><strong>15:00 UTC:</strong> Season 1 content, including the Battle Pass and new seasonal features, becomes available for all players.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Between these times, players can continue to play Battlefield 6 as normal after updating, but <strong>Season 1 content and progression will unlock at 15:00 UTC</strong>.The Season 1 Update marks the next step in our ongoing journey to evolve and expand the Battlefield 6 experience. This includes fixes, balance changes, and quality-of-life improvements focused on polish, performance, and player feedback to deliver an even smoother experience moving forward.<strong>Major Updates for 1.1.1.0:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved core movement and animations, including smoother landings, faster stance transitions, better vaulting behavior, and reduced “bouncing” issues on landing or spawning.</li><li>Reworked weapon dispersion to better align accuracy and handling with each weapon’s intended design and performance over range. These changes address cases where accuracy behaved inconsistently, such as dispersion not properly settling after sprinting, and bring overall firing behavior closer to the intended balance between precision, control, and weapon power.</li><li>Significant visibility and lighting improvements, with better exposure transitions, interior lighting, and reduced fog and smoke persistence.</li><li>Audio overhaul, adding new projectile flybys, destruction and explosion sounds, refined vehicle and weapon mixes, and improved haptic feedback across multiple interactions.</li><li>UI and HUD updates for clarity and consistency, including overtime indicators, end-of-round fixes, and new unlock markers for weapons and gadgets.</li><li>Map fixes across multiple locations, resolving spawn animations, out-of-bounds issues, misaligned assets, and general stability across Conquest, Breakthrough, and Rush modes.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>CHANGELOGPLAYER:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where combat dive could break when diving uphill.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players would detach from ziplines when entering at high speed.</li><li>Improved steady aim and sight centering for more consistent precision.</li><li>Fixed an issue where movement could interrupt steady aim.</li><li>Adjusted misaligned character hitboxes for upper body and head to better match the visual models.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the jump animation could play twice when aiming down sights.</li><li>Landing animations now have their animation path properly centered, instead of shifting to the side when landing.</li><li>Fixed an issue where jump inaccuracy could linger too long after landing.</li><li>Fixed a visual issue causing weapons to appear rotated incorrectly after spawning.</li><li>Fixed an issue where throwing grenades from prone could make players appear standing in third-person view.</li><li>Fixed an animation delay when opening doors while sliding.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players could get stuck while vaulting over certain objects.</li><li>Fixed a visual issue where dead players appeared alive while swimming.</li><li>Fixed an issue where quick meleeing with a gadget would swap back to the primary weapon instead of the gadget.</li><li>Fixed an issue where getting killed by a mine would highlight it in the killcam.</li><li>Fixed a camera jitter that could occur when entering ladders and looking down.</li><li>Fixed an issue where camera and weapon sway behaved incorrectly after entering or exiting vehicles.</li><li>Fixed an issue where weapons of other soldiers could clip through walls when they entered your view.</li><li>Fixed an issue where pistols disappeared while swimming.</li><li>Improved lighting precision for visibility while hip-firing and aiming down sights.</li><li>Reduced occurrences of bouncing or landing issues when dropping onto certain objects.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the killer snapshot sometimes did not display in the killcam.</li><li>Small improvements to weapon and camera sway for smoother movement.</li><li>Fixed an issue where enemies could take melee damage in protected vehicle seats.</li><li>Fixed an issue where vaulting could fail if triggered right as the player hit an obstacle.</li><li>Fixed an animation issue where repeated vaulting could cause incorrect hand placement.</li><li>Fixed an issue where simultaneous melee hits could make an enemy briefly invisible</li><li>Fixed an issue where soldier heads briefly disappeared during redeploy transitions.</li><li>Improved training path progression display to better match actual unlocks.</li><li>Fixed an issue where friendly players could clip into each other when climbing ladders.</li><li>Fixed an issue preventing vaulting directly from a slide.</li><li>Fixed an issue causing the camera to rotate abruptly after a takedown.</li><li>Fixed an issue where hands briefly disappeared after using the AJ-03 COAG Med Pen.</li><li>Improved stab animations when reviving with drag and revive.</li><li>Fixed issues affecting peeking and prone transitions, ensuring both actions function correctly.</li><li>Fixed a camera clipping issue when going prone while strafing.</li><li>Fixed a missing third-person animation when transitioning from prone to sprint.</li><li>Fixed an issue where falling while sprinting caused incorrect hand movement.</li><li>Fixed visual clipping when soldiers stood too close to glass doors.</li><li>Fixed jittery aim animations in third-person when mounted.</li><li>Fixed a bug where mounting near walls prevented aiming left or right.</li><li>Fixed an issue where leaning, peeking, or mounting could cancel unexpectedly.</li><li>Fixed an issue where third-person hit reactions were missing when hit while mounted.</li><li>Fixed an animation issue where the character’s knee clipped with the camera when falling while crouched.</li><li>Fixed takedown inconsistencies, allowing players to properly perform melee takedowns even near walls.</li><li>Fixed an issue where taking melee damage interrupted weapon fire.</li><li>Fixed multiple visibility improvements including lighting, exposure, and fog behavior for better contrast and clarity across all maps.</li><li>Improved vaulting, parachute, and door-opening animations for smoother transitions.</li><li>Fixed rare animation freezes for friendly soldiers reloading off-screen.</li><li>Fixed minor inconsistencies in mounting, peeking, and prone transitions for more reliable gameplay.</li><li>Added parachute customization for soldiers.</li><li>Prevented unintended shoulder bump animation when equipping a weapon while sprinting.</li><li>Improved ragdoll impacts for more consistent and reliable reactions.</li><li>Improved stance transition and landing animations to settle faster and feel smoother.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>VEHICLES:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed missing haptic feedback when switching between tank weapons.</li><li>Fixed a visual issue where the player’s hand clipped with the M1A2 SEPv3 handle when sitting in external seats.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>GADGETS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a rare issue where the MAS 148 Glaive could block the first-person view during a combat dive.</li><li>Fixed a MAS 148 Glaive visual issue during combat dives in first-person.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Defibrillators appeared floating during vaulting animations.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Supply Pouch would sometimes not resupply correctly.</li><li>Deployable gadgets are not destroyed/removed from debris piles</li><li>AT grenades now create a small sized crater instead of a medium one.</li><li>Buildings now take more hits to be destroyed by a Sledgehammer.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>WEAPONS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Weapon dispersion has been rebalanced to better match each weapon’s damage profile across all ranges. Lower-damage weapons will now see a slightly higher increase in dispersion when firing, while higher-damage weapons will experience slightly less.</li><li>Using Sniper Rifles with any class other than Recon will no longer increase weapon spread. Instead, weapon sway will now begin during the zoom transition, maintaining balance and distinguishing Recon’s precision advantage.</li><li>Fixed a misalignment issue with top-mounted red dot sights.</li><li>Fixed an issue where mounting a bipod while zoomed only changed the FOV instead of using the correct optic.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Long Suppressor used the wrong attachment point cost for some weapons.</li><li>Improved reticle settling for automatic weapons to make burst firing more efficient.</li><li>Fixed an issue where using a bipod too close to complex geometry could throw the player off position while prone.</li><li>Balanced sledgehammer damage against world objects for better consistency.</li><li>Fixed an issue preventing players from leaving the Firing Range.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>MAPS &amp; MODES:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved fog and smoke effects after destruction to prevent them from lingering too long and impacting visibility.</li><li>Improved exposure transitions between indoor and outdoor areas for better visibility.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the zipline carabiner could appear offset and fly next to the wire instead of along it.</li><li>Squad names are now randomized at the start of Squad Deathmatch matches.</li><li>Added visible bomb meshes to armed M-COMs in Rush.</li><li>Updated overtime UI visualization across all modes.</li><li>Fixed animation and positioning issues during insertion sequences on all maps.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the game mode UI could display incorrect scores or fail to update during a round.</li><li>Fixed an End of Round progression issue in King of the Hill mode.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players could encounter a bouncing animation when spawning at HQs after capturing new territories in Escalation across multiple maps.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Mirak Valley</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a misaligned zipline mesh in Conquest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the deploy camera in Rush displayed attackers on the wrong side of the map.</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented players from arming M-COM A in Rush due to a misplaced asset.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Siege of Cairo</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed overlapping territory lines and boundaries during the briefing screen in Escalation.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Liberation Peak</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue in Escalation where a portion of the map on the NATO side was disconnected during the first period of the match.</li><li>Fixed an issue in Rush where part of the Attacker’s HQ area was incorrectly marked as out of bounds.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>New Sobek City</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue preventing players from capturing part of Flag C in Escalation.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players could ignite when spawning near a burning lorry in Team Deathmatch.</li><li>Adjusted an infantry vehicle spawn that was placed too close to a building in the PAX Armata HQ area.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Manhattan Bridge</em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue in Breakthrough where players could become stuck on the End of Round screen if the party leader left during the EOR sequence.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UI &amp; HUD:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added new markers for newly unlocked weapons, weapon packages, attachments, gadgets, and throwables.</li><li>Updated 3D previews for certain gadgets to show their deployed state.</li><li>Added preview videos demonstrating how gadgets work.</li><li>Added new cosmetic options for selected gadgets.</li><li>Changed “Save &amp; Close” to “Close” in the Deploy menu for clarity.</li><li>Fixed various UI issues in Loadouts.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Battlefield 6 Ownership XP Boost did not display properly at End of Round.</li><li>Fixed multiple text inconsistencies in Dog Tags and Challenges.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the HUD would not appear when using a 16:10 aspect ratio with certain resolutions.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>SETTINGS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Flick Look bindings to Helicopter, Jet, and Transport control schemes.</li><li>Fixed visual issues where some aspect ratio settings caused transparent borders or inconsistent display behavior.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>SINGLE PLAYER:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue in Mission 01 where players were unable to lean out during the Last Stand sequence if the cinematic began while the knife was equipped.</li><li>Fixed a black screen issue in the Night Raid mission.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PORTAL:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the Host Experience screen did not display the Portal experience image.</li><li>Fixed a crash that could occur if a party leader started a Portal server while Content Packs 01 and 04 were disabled.</li><li>Improved loading times for the Server Browser experience info tab to ensure joining functions properly.</li><li>Corrected a spelling error in the message shown when attempting to join an unavailable server.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>AUDIO:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where footstep sounds were missing when moving with the knife equipped.</li><li>Fixed a voiceline issue where directional callouts (e.g., “enemy north”) played the wrong direction.</li><li>Tuned haptic feedback across multiple actions, including window barging, defibrillator use, swimming, rocket pods, mounted MGs, and sea vehicle collisions.</li><li>Polished large projectile audio with new missile, rocket pod, and cannon shell flyby effects; improved distance handling and overall mix for more realistic impact sounds.</li><li>Updated audio configs for light rockets and LMGs; refined explosion sound crossfades and adjusted distant sound behavior.</li><li>Improved vehicle and weapon firing audio balance, reducing noise artifacts, unwanted phasing, and over-saturation.</li><li>Added radio chatter through controller speakers.</li><li>Fixed an issue where firing range dummies and vehicle-hit reactions sometimes played incorrect or processed hurt sounds.</li><li>Disabled radio processing for stationary vehicle pings and fixed compass orientation for ping indicators.</li><li>Fixed missing or incorrect ambient and destruction sounds across several maps, including Siege of Cairo, as well as missing explosion sounds for silos and tanker trailers.</li><li>Added missing ambient audio setups for environmental props like construction barriers and buses.</li><li>Added new sound effects for the bulletin and takeover sections of the main menu, including improved reveal animations.</li><li>Fixed an issue where delayed challenge tab displays triggered early audio playback.</li><li>Fixed an issue where defibrillator loop sounds could get stuck when vaulting.</li><li>Fixed missing or out-of-sync reload sounds.</li><li>Corrected the M39 EMR using suppressed audio when unsuppressed.</li><li>Restored missing external sound effects for RWS Gunner countermeasure mines.</li><li>Fixed issues where soundtrack tracks cut off abruptly or skipped mid-song.</li><li>Reload audio polish for several weapons.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>This announcement may change as we listen to community feedback and continue developing and evolving our Live Service &amp; Content. We will always strive to keep our community as informed as possible.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-official-name-and-release-date-reportedly-leak-online]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals for Today: Mario, Pokémon and Zelda Christmas Tree Ornaments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-october-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-mario-pok%C3%A9mon-and-zelda-christmas-tree-ornaments.1334188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">So I'm going to be that guy and start bringing up Christmas 2025 before Halloween has started, but for good reason. Ever thought "My Christmas tree needs more Nintendo?" Well Hallmark just dropped their Mario, Pokémon and the Legend of Zelda tree ornaments and I want to buy all of them.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals for Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not ready to get festive just yet? How about a beast of a power bank from Anker that can handle Macbooks, Xbox ROG Ally X and Switch 2? Yeah, it's a cracking prime-exclusive deal. In other deals today i've found a craceking deal on a cult classic 4K steelbook and some last minute Steam game deals that you can't ignore, so let's get into it:</p><p id="nintendo-christmas-tree-ornaments"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Nintendo Christmas Tree Ornaments">Hallmark Nintendo Christmas Tree Ornaments</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today's deals article marks the only time i've paid attention to anything Hallmark, and it's a worthy sacrifice considering I could have Link, Elephant Mario and Snorlax hanging on my Christmas tree this year. Pricing varies, but I couldn't ignore all of these epic Christmas tree decorations.</p><p id="anker-737-24000mah-140w-power-bank"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Anker 737 24,000mAh 140W Power Bank">Anker 737 24,000mAh 140W Power Bank</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229863"><div id="229863" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Amazon Prime Members Only</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker 737 24,000mAh 140W Power Bank</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There's hardly any power bank brands I trust more than Anker, as every product i've bought or tested has been brilliant. So coming across this prime member-exclusive 32% discount on a 24,000mAh 140W Power Bank for $74.99 is Black Friday territory. This will charge anything from a Macbook or handheld gaming PC to your smartphone, so don't sleep on this deal.</p></div><p id="the-fog-1980-limited-edition-ste"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="The Fog (1980) - Limited Edition Ste">The Fog (1980) - Limited Edition Steelbook 4K Ultra HD + Blu-ray</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229877"><div id="229877" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Fog (1980) - Limited Edition Steelbook 4K Ultra HD + Blu-ray</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A 4K Steelbook with stunning artwork at 55% off? That once sentence sells this deal, but The Frog (1980) is also a cult classic. 100% worth $17.99 if this kind of film is up your street. </p></div><p id="edens-zero-standard-edition-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="EDENS ZERO Standard Edition (Steam)">EDENS ZERO Standard Edition (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229878"><div id="229878" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>EDENS ZERO Standard Edition (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Using code "OMENVIP" will bag players Edens Zero on Steam for just $35.33, down from $49.99. Pretty great deal, right? It's a 3D action RPG based on the Manga and Anime "Eden Zero" by Hiro Mashima, and might just be your way in if you don't have the patience for reading or binge watching a new anime. </p></div><p id="zone-of-the-enders-the-2nd-runner"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner (">Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229879"><div id="229879" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Zone of the Enders: The 2nd Runner (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It's $4.68 for a steam code, what's not to like? It's a full-length remaster of the original featuring full Steam VR support, native 4K support and surround sound. So now if going to be a great time to take JEHUTY out for a spin.</p></div><p id="unknown-9-awakening-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Unknown 9: Awakening (Steam)">Unknown 9: Awakening (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229880"><div id="229880" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Unknown 9: Awakening (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Another banger for the price of a posh coffee, Unknown 9: Awakening for $4.99 is well worth it. Redeemable on Steam, play as Haroona who's able to pull powers from a parallel dimension known as "The Fold" to dodge bullets, vanish, fire energy Dragon Ball style and more.</p></div><p id="hulu-with-ads-live-tv-for-6499"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Hulu (with ads) + Live TV for $64.99">Hulu (with ads) + Live TV for $64.99/mo for 3 Months</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229847"><div id="229847" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Save 30% Off Your First 3 Months of Hulu + Live TV</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Hulu (with ads) + Live TV for $64.99/mo for 3 Months</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">30% off Hulu just in time for the world series? Yes please! It contains adds, but a saving is a saving especially when it's commitment free after the offer ends. Just in time for the holiday season, you can have cosey film nights for less this year.</p></div><p id="77"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="77" lg="" evo="" c5="" oled="" smart="">77" LG Evo C5 4K OLED Smart TV</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229844"><div id="229844" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Includes LG S40T 2.1ch Soundbar and Subwoofer Bundle</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>77" LG Evo C5 4K OLED Smart TV</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Over $2,000 off one of the best TVs of this year, plus you get free stand or wall mount setup and a LG S40T Soundbar and Subwoofer bundle (Worth $229.99), just add it to your basket. If you need a new TV in time for the holidays, this is an absolute banger to have in the lounge.</p></div><p id="anker-25000mah-165w-power-bank"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Anker 25,000mAh 165W Power Bank">Anker 25,000mAh 165W Power Bank</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229845"><div id="229845" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>with Two Built-In USB Type-C Cables</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker 25,000mAh 165W Power Bank</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">No more loosing USB-C cables with this bad boy. It pumps out enough power to charge anything from your phone and Nintendo Switch 2 to a Macbook. The 25,000mAh power capacity means it'll store more than enough more to charge two devices at once too. It's a win-win kind of deal.</p></div><p id="lenovo-legion-5-pro-gen-10"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Lenovo Legion 5 Pro Gen 10">Lenovo Legion 5 Pro Gen 10</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229846"><div id="229846" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>16" OLED Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX RTX 5070 Ti Gaming Laptop (16GB/1TB)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lenovo Legion 5 Pro Gen 10</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">30% off an Nvidia RTX 5070Ti gaming laptop brings the price of entry for DLSS 4 to way under $2,000. 16GB of DDR5 RAm alongside a Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX processor backing up the GPU means this 16-inch Lenovo Legion beast is well worth it!</p></div><p id="football-manager-26-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Football Manager 26 (Steam)">Football Manager 26 (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229848"><div id="229848" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Spend over $15 and get a free Scream Sale Game</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Football Manager 26 (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Preorders are now available for Football Manager 26 over on Fanatical, which gives players early access for pre-purchasing. New features such as Premier League and Womens Football is included this time around, to there's plenty to go at in this new instalment.</p></div><p id="once-upon-a-katamari-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Once Upon A KATAMARI (Steam)">Once Upon A KATAMARI (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229849"><div id="229849" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Spend over $15 and get a free Scream Sale Game</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Once Upon A KATAMARI (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Releasing today, Once Upon a Katamari introduces tiem travel to the frankly insane cult classic series from Bandai Namco. Roll through Jurrasic, Ice Age and other eras to rebuild the Earth and Moon that the king destroyed whilst playing as The Prince and one of his 68 cousins. Mental.</p></div><p id="silent-hill-f-steam"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="SILENT HILL f (Steam)">SILENT HILL f (Steam)</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229850"><div id="229850" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Spend over $15 and get a free Scream Sale Game</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>SILENT HILL f (Steam)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in 1960s Japan, Silent Hill f follows Shimiza Hinako as she deal with her town and home covered in a strange fog, turning her life into a living nightmare. This next instalment focuses more on Psycological horror and finding beauty hidden in terror. I'd find out for myself, but i'll be giving my goldfish a bath instead (I'm scared).</p></div><p id="alienware-desktop-discounts"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Alienware Desktop Discounts">Alienware Gaming Desktop Discounts</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9gjkmG?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Fancy a solid RTX 5080 build for under $2,000 including free delivery?</a> You'll be able to take advantage of DLSS 4 with more gas in the tank than a RTX 4080 Super, which is one of Nvidias best graphics card releases last year. Buyers can look forward to high frame rate 4K gameplay with all the bells and whistles added. We're talking ray tracing and definition sharper than any console can currently output. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5080-review">Check our review out</a> for more information on this epic GPU.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Alienware Gaming Laptop Discounts</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">When it comes to gaming laptops in general, picking one within your budget is the first major step. For something worth gaming on, the $1,000 mark is the price of entry. <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxxqD?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">That will include a RTX 5060</a>, going all the way up to <a href="https://zdcs.link/ao68Om?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$3,549 for a RTX 5090 build</a> if you really want that mobile gaming flex.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Nvidia RTX 5000 Series Refurb Deals</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still running a Nvidia RTX 1000 to 3000 series? This is your chance to upgrade your rig to DLSS 4 and Ray Tracing with Woots RTX 5000 series refurbished sale. The sweet spot with this generation has to be <a href="https://zdcs.link/QKqqBy?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">RTX 5080 that includes 16GB of GDDRR6 RAM</a> that can handle 4K gaming and all the frames. Need to upgrade on a budget? <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qxxxrp?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">RTX 5070 12GB is a great option for $529</a> too. </p><p id="mtg-cheapest-at-amazon"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="MTG: Cheapest at Amazon">MTG: Cheapest at Amazon</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's a handful of booster boxes available for slightly less at Amazon this week, but it's a bit of a poor turnout for Magic: The Gathering players. Most of the listing on Amazon are above MSRP and higher than secondary market values, but the carosel above are good deals when compared to TCGPlayer.</p><p id="mtg-cheapest-at-amazon"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="MTG: Cheapest at Amazon">MTG: Cheapest at TCGPlayer</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">TCGPlayer's sellers are keeping away from the sneaker-heads and crypo bro mentality that's hit Magic and Pokémon TCG is 2025 and is keeping prices down. Market value for MTG sealed product goes off what people are willing to pay, and it shows. There's so much here that's at a lower price than big box retailers it's embarassing. But, it's great for your pocket!</p><p id="blaziken-ex-volcanion-ex-premium-c"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Blaziken ex &amp; Volcanion ex Premium C">Blaziken ex &amp; Volcanion ex Premium Collection</h2></p><div catalogid="688f638e-8444-4126-a204-e1320f401009" id="229712"><div id="229712" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Blaziken ex &amp; Volcanion ex Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Trainers and collectors will get five Destined Rivals Boosters and five Journey Together Boosters in this bad boy, so that's about the right kind of ball park for ten booster packs, plus you're getting the promo Volcanion ex and Blaziken ex promo card and a jumbo version of Blaziken ex. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I think these promo's would work great together in a fire-themed deck. Use Blazikens Seething Spirit to grab fire energy from your discard pile to build up Volcanion. In the meantime Volcanion can burn opposing Pokémon then use Scorching Cyclone for 160 damage then transfer all it's energy to a benched Pokémon. So many possibilities here.</p></div><p id="pok-tcg-mega-evolution-in-stock"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Poké TCG: Mega Evolution In Stock">Poké Price Check: Mega Evolution In Stock</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Evolution seems to be a well-printed start to the next era of Pokémon TCG. I'm seeing boosters in convienience stores and some products on physical shelves, not to mention the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QLM8mm?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Booster Bundle ($52.89)</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxADp?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Gardevoir ETB ($88.81)</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxA8p?object_uuid=e21d07a5-938b-4d28-a16a-b0b73a4a8e76&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Three Booster Blister ($28.90)</a> available on Amazon. Like the rest of the products in this carousel though, the cheapest is TCGplayer right now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 24, 2025 3:30 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-october-24]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pixel Quest Codes (October 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pixel-quest-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pixel-quest-codes-october-2025.1334182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Shoot, loot, and level up with these codes.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pixel Quest is a brand new 2D bullet hell RPG, where you'll face an onslaught of foes across biomes that range from the beach to the desert. The Third Dimension has been destroyed by 1x1x1x1, and now the Robloxians will need to work together to protect the pixelated 2D land of Robloxia. There are over 70 quests to complete, and legendary loot to obtain that will make it far easier to eviscerate hordes of enemies. With so much to do, you'll want some codes to make use of.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Working Pixel Quest Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are all the currently active Pixel Quest codes. Be sure to redeem them before they expire!</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>LUCKYDAY</strong> - 1x Gold Clover, 2x EXP Booster, 1x Medium Dungeon Key, 3x Defense Infusion</li><li><strong>PQDISCORD2025</strong> - Wumpus Skin</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Use Pixel Quest Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Redeeming Pixel Quest codes is a straightforward process. Launch the experience and complete the tutorial if you haven't already done so. When you're in the main hub, here are the steps you need to follow:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Locate the chat box on the bottom left of the screen. It says "To chat click here or press / key".</li><li>Click or press the / key and then press / again. This will bring up a list of commands.</li><li>Type code, so it now says /code in your text box.</li><li>Copy and paste the code from the article and enter it into the box, <strong>e.g. /code PQDISCORD2025</strong></li><li>Hit enter.</li><li>You'll then see a message in the chat that tells you if the code has been redeemed successfully, and what the reward is.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Claim Gifts from You Gift Box</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Some codes will give you rewards that you need to claim from your Giftbox. On the righthand side of the screen, you'll see a yellow and red gift box. Click on this and you'll be automatically transported to the southeast corner of the main hub. The Gift Box menu will also automatically open, so you can drag them into your inventory.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Find Skins</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you receive a skin via a code, then you'll want to find the icon on the left side of the screen that shows a person and says Wardrobe. When you open the Wardrobe, you'll see three sub-menus: Skins, Badges, and Titles. You can then scroll through and see any Skins, you've unlocked.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Pixel Quest Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">You're in luck! There are currently no expired Pixel Quest codes, but don't let the above ones slip away before you use them.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Pixel Quest Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Codes for Roblox experiences are usually case-sensitive, so the best way to ensure you've got a working code is to directly copy it from this article. We check all codes before we upload them, so you can guarantee they're working. Just double-check that you haven't copied over an extra space!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">When Is the Next Pixel Quest Update?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Pixel Quest is currently in Alpha release, but that doesn't mean that the Pixel Quest! group isn't already working hard to bring new content to the RPG. The next update is planned for Sunday, 26th October. This mini update will introduce a new dungeon and new Legendary items. 
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pixel-quest-codes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>