<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 19:37:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Weeks In, Elden Ring Nightreign Players Are Inventing Some Creative Ways to Skip Around the Map]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/three-weeks-in-elden-ring-nightreign-players-are-inventing-some-creative-ways-to-skip-around-the-map</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/three-weeks-in-elden-ring-nightreign-players-are-inventing-some-creative-ways-to-skip-around-the-map.1224219/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's been roughly three weeks since <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> dropped on May 30, and players have started to get their heads around all the different tools and abilities available to them in Limveld. What some are starting to do with those abilities, though, is pretty fascinating.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the top posts on the r/Nightreign subreddit this morning <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1lg0on3/new_strategy_for_getting_to_noklateo_quicker/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">was from user u/Quantam-Law</a>, who was playing with a Raider under the username "BRO....". BRO had a pretty great idea: the trio of Nightfarers had the Noklateo Shifting Earth event, and rather than storm the front gate of the city, BRO popped Raider's ultimate to provide a new platform for entry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Noklateo, and other Shifting Earth events, are random, map-changing alterations that can appear, adding new encounters and areas to explore in the process. But while this usage of Totem Stela is good for that, it gets the gears turning on other places and ways you could use the massive brick to get up and around designed obstacles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Raider's not the only one with tricks, either. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1lfvzuf/crater_wylder_skip/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">u/Mockz_ also had a recent skip posted</a> up on the Elden Ring Nightreign subreddit, this time for the Crater Shifting Earth event. In this one, Mockz uses their abilities, and a little bit of good ol' fashioned gravity to get where they need to go, at the bottom of the Crater.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another user, u/ninjabladeJr, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1lfox8v/consistent_crater_skip/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted a feasible</a>—albeit challenging and dangerous—skip of their own to the bottom of the Crater, using a spectral hawk and specific line-ups. Are these Crater skips dangerous? Absolutely. Is it awesome to see someone breeze past the many, many encounters of the dungeon and straight to the big boss, the ultimate goal and prize of the Shifting Earth event? You betcha.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Heck, there are people <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1l691iv/mountaintop_event_skip_to_save_you_some_time/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">even finding ways to the top of the Mountaintop event</a> by just Skyrim-jumping their way up the side of the cliffs like an ibex. Shifting Earth events are a fun, fascinating part of Nightreign's construction and layout, and it's amazing how players are already finding ways to navigate them faster and smarter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The actual usability of these is absolutely up-in-the-air. I could see popping the Noklateo totem-skip in a random lobby, but I think attempting the spectral hawk Crater skip in a room with two random players who don't know what I'm doing is a fast path to two, if not three, Nightfarers down.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But the fact players are getting so creative with their abilities and finding such interesting uses for them bodes well for the long-term health of Elden Ring Nightreign. As of this writing, the speedrun leaderboards for Elden Ring Nightreign <a href="https://www.speedrun.com/Elden_Ring_Nightreign/news/mxl4856p" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">still aren't live</a>, but these community-discovered skips already have me intrigued to see what speedrunners can showcase with the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve got plenty of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>Nightreign tips and tricks</u></a> to help you take down <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Nightlord_Boss_Guides"><u>all the eight Nightlord Bosses</u></a>, and if you’re wondering how to unlock the two locked <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Nightfarers_-_List_of_Character_Classes"><u>Nightfarer Classes</u></a>, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Unlock_the_Revenant"><u>How to Unlock the Revenant</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Unlock_the_Duchess"><u>How to Unlock the Duchess</u></a>, plus <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Change_Characters"><u>How to Change Characters</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/three-weeks-in-elden-ring-nightreign-players-are-inventing-some-creative-ways-to-skip-around-the-map]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deltarune Chapter 5 Will Release in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapter-5-will-release-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deltarune-chapter-5-will-release-in-2026.1224216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After a three-year wait between previous chapter releases of Deltarune, developer Toby Fox is promising a faster turnaround on the next episode of the saga. Chapter 5 is currently set for a 2026 release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This information was revealed in the end credits of Deltarune Chapter 4, which released alongside Chapter 3 earlier this month. No further specificity about dates or windows was given.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/20/deltarune-ch-5-1750433683939.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Deltarune is a "sequel" of sorts to beloved indie RPG Undertale, and has released chapter by chapter starting in 2018, with Chapter 2 releasing in 2021 and the two most recent chapters <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapters-3-and-4-are-out-now-and-its-already-exploding-on-steam">dropping alongside the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2 earlier this month</a>. The game follows a human named Kris who lives in a peaceful town of monsters familiar to those who played Undertale. Together with the school bully Suzie, they fall into a mysterious "Dark World" and meet a prince named Ralsei, who charges them with saving both the dark and light world by sealing dark fountains. Each chapter tackles a different dark fountain in something like a "monster of the week" format, though Chapter 4 goes off the rails a bit in exploring the game's overarching meta-plot that fans speculate may eventually tie the game back to Undertale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chapters 1 and 2 are available on all major platforms for free, while the full game including Chapters 3, 4, and all future chapters (up to at least seven) costs $25. With the paid release, we reviewed all of Deltarune so far, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-review">giving it a 9/10</a> and saying that "its incredible and well-refined culmination of captivating characters, hilarious and earnest writing, and stellar music has already left one hell of a lasting impact I’m not likely to forget."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/deltarune-chapter-5-will-release-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>