<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:52:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: MTG Sale, Tech Bargains and Pokémon TCG Restock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-mtg-sale-tech-bargains-and-pokmon-tcg-restock</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-mtg-sale-tech-bargains-and-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-restock.1219413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-mtg-sale-tech-bargains-and-pokmon-tcg-restock<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Another Monday and another fresh start for daily deals, and it's starting off with a bang. Big box online retailers have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop">Pokémon TCG</a> product in stock that's near or under market value, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-review">Prismatic Evolutions</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-journey-together-preview">Journey Together</a> single card values cool off (Finally). The same can't be said for the wave that is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-most-expensive-destined-rivals-cards">Destined Rivals</a> however, with single-card prices bobbing up and down the secondary market seas.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of the worlds biggest Franchise ever, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mtg-aetherdrift-preview">Magic: The Gathering - Aetherdrift </a>sealed product has been discounted on Amazon, so there's never been a better time to rip open the expansion. Whilst <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-where-to-buy-in-stock">MTG: Final Fantasy</a> has finally dropped, there's still plenty of buying options for sealed product from big box retailers and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-pokemon-cards-to-buy-tcgplayer-mayhem-sale">TCG Player</a>. I've also found some cracking bargains on <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wRRkq?object_uuid=dd8f7c62-50dd-458a-9254-ce965ea069b7&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">SSDs</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObbV2?object_uuid=dd8f7c62-50dd-458a-9254-ce965ea069b7&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">portable storage</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7OO7y?object_uuid=dd8f7c62-50dd-458a-9254-ce965ea069b7&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">DDR5 RAM</a>, games and more. Let's get into it:</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon Restock Updates</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Checking these prices against TCG Player secondary market values, a lot of these products aren't far off the mark. Make no mistake, they're still way off MSRP, but finding Pokémon products on shelves that haven't been marked up past the point of anyone caring is a positive. Still refusing to pay over MSRP for new sets? Well played, I'm proud of you. Here's some single card highlights for you to shuffle through instead. Spoiler, there's plenty of deals to be had.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Destined Rivals Singles Are On The Rise (Again)</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's hard to stick a pin on Destined Rivals single card values right now, and the dips in value seem to match the little bits of stock distributors release to stores. Looking at the tracking charts for each of these cards, we can see mostly plummets from day one, then either upticks or cards for sale that exceed the original value at launch. It's crazy, but we now know how low these cards can go. Sure there's always attempts at market manipulation, but I wouldn't buy any cards on the rise right now.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Journey Together Singles Are Settling In Value</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Having keeping an eye on the market since launch, Journey Together singles are now more affordable than ever. Many of these cards have stabilized, with the main chase card - Lillie's Clefairy ex SIR, settling at around $150. If you were planning on getting into Journey Together at some point to collect the illustration rares and SIRs, now is a great time to jump in.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Epic Primastic Evolutions Cards That Aren't Umbreon</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's so many great cards in this set that aren't Umbreon ex SIR, all of which are a damn sight more affordable right now. Because I hate anything popular (Yes, I know I'm a massive fan of the most popular IP on earth), my two favorite cards are Dragapult ex SIR and Roaring Moon ex SIR. The former is now down to a respectable $125, with the latter holding it's value well since launch, floating towards the $200 mark. These prices and below are great deals for these cards, so don't miss out.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Discounted MTG: Aetherdrift Boxes </h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Magic: The Gathering discounts at a big box store like Amazon? Surely not! Aetherdrift turned the MTG meta on its head introducing vehicles and other unique mechanics. This is a great time to jump into it and rip open some packs, it's deffinately one of the most "out there"  twists on the ever popular trading card game.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Where To Buy MTG: Final Fantasy</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's finally here, Magic the Gathering: Final Fantasy is out in the wild. If you got a preorder for MSRP, well played, but many TCG and Final Fantasy fans missed out. Fear not, there's still some options on sealed products available right now, including options from the secondary market with TCG Player which is around the same or lower than the pricing of big box retailers right now.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Big Discounts On Crucial DDR5 and Storage</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Crucial are one of the most dependable brands when it comes to M.2 and portable drives, and is a great option for those wanting the benefits of DDR5 RAM without flashy RGB and it's price tag. Here's some of the best deals in the Crucial price slashing marathon on Amazon right now. I currently use the X10 Pro 4TB for backing up files and folders on my PC and for watching videos on my projector, just a solid piece of kit.</p><p id="kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-ps5"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Kingdom Come: Deliverance II (PS5)">Kingdom Come: Deliverance II (PS5)</h2></p><div catalogid="12468fbf-8990-4f79-9cda-997cbff2a2aa" id="223003"><div id="223003" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II (PS5)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Kingdom Come Deliverance II drops you into the brutal heart of 15th century Bohemia, and right now the PS5 version is just $47.99, down from $69.99. You play as Henry, a blacksmith’s son caught in a fight for survival, revenge, and rebellion. With over five hours of cinematic storytelling, a massive open world, and intense first-person melee combat, this sequel builds on everything that made the original a cult hit. Whether you're swordfighting, smithing, or trying to navigate life in a war-torn land, this is medieval roleplaying at its most immersive.</p></div><p id="doom-the-dark-ages-art-print"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="DOOM The Dark Ages Art Print">DOOM The Dark Ages Art Print</h2></p><div catalogid="12468fbf-8990-4f79-9cda-997cbff2a2aa" id="223004"><div id="223004" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>DOOM The Dark Ages Art Print</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This limited-edition DOOM The Dark Ages art print is a must for fans of the Slayer's latest crusade. Officially licensed and hand-numbered out of 995 copies, it's printed on high-quality art paper and comes with a certificate of authenticity. Produced by one of the UK’s oldest commercial printers, the A3-sized piece measures 11.69 x 16.53 inches and captures the brutal tone of the game perfectly. Pre-orders are open now, with shipping expected in July 2025.</p></div><p id="power-up-pride-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Power Up Pride Bundle">Power Up Pride Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="12468fbf-8990-4f79-9cda-997cbff2a2aa" id="223005"><div id="223005" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Power Up Pride Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Power Up Pride Game Bundle brings together seven standout indie titles for just $13, with all games yours to keep. You’ll find cozy village life in Echoes of the Plum Grove, charming shop sim gameplay in Sticky Business, and emotional storytelling in titles like Haven and A Normal Lost Phone. It’s a solid mix of narrative-driven adventures, life sims, and visual novels, all picked for their unique stories and engaging mechanics. Great value, great games, and a portion of your purchase supports charity through Xperience Studios.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 16, 2025 12:35 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Ambassador Charles Martinet Clarifies He's Still Allowed to Perform Mario's Voice, but Won't Improvise Dialogue — and It's His Choice to Protect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-ambassador-charles-martinet-clarifies-hes-still-allowed-to-perform-marios-voice-but-wont-improvise-dialogue-and-its-his-choice-to-protect-integrity-of-nintendos-iconic-mascot</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-ambassador-charles-martinet-clarifies-hes-still-allowed-to-perform-marios-voice-but-wont-improvise-dialogue-%E2%80%94-and-its-his-choice-to-protect.1219407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-ambassador-charles-martinet-clarifies-hes-still-allowed-to-perform-marios-voice-but-wont-improvise-dialogue-and-its-his-choice-to-protect-integrity-of-nintendos-iconic-mascot<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Mushroom for compromise.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Charles Martinet, the voice of Mario for almost 30 years, has clarified how he will perform in-character when meeting fans — and the reason why — after confusion sparked on social media following a recent convention appearance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now recognised by Nintendo as an official Mario Ambassador, Martinet is beloved for enthusiastically performing his Mario voices when greeting fans in-person. But a recent social media post by YouTuber Ricky Berwick prompted concern that Martinet had been restricted by Nintendo in what he could perform — until Martinet himself spoke up to offer clarification.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following an appearance by Martinet earlier this month at the Phoenix Fan Fusion 2025 convention, held in Phoenix, Arizona, a social media post by Berwick — who has 6.25 million subscribers on YouTube and 14.1m subscribers on TikTok — claimed the voice acting legend "wasn't even allowed to do the voice of Mario or any of his iconic character's voices" while at the meetup. "It's a f**king shame," Berwick added.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The post caught the internet's attention, as it came just hours after it was revealed that Martinet's former Mushroom Kingdom colleague <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/princess-peach-and-toads-veteran-voice-actor-says-nintendo-told-her-shed-been-replaced-on-switch-2-launch-day-as-mario-kart-world-released-without-her-in-it">Samantha Kelly had been replaced as the voice of Princess Peach and Toad</a>, with the actress told of the change by Nintendo on the day <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/platform/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> launch title <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> launched without her in it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-charles-martinet-is-not-involved-in-super-mario-bros-wonder">Nintendo officially retired Martinet back in 2022</a>, though provided the actor with a notable send-off in the form of a farewell video featuring Mario creator Shigeru Miyamoto and the promise that Martinet would continue to work with Nintendo as Mario Ambassador going forward. Martinet himself later stated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/charles-martinet-on-being-mario-ambassador-i-dont-know-what-that-is-yet">he wasn't really sure what that title bestowed</a>, but has maintained a busy schedule of convention appearances in the years since.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/16/gettyimages-598849994-1750074217094.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Charles Martinet. Photo by Isaiah Trickey/FilmMagic.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, in response to Berwick's post, Martinet has <a href="https://x.com/CharlesMartinet/status/1932458680542474319" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">responded</a> to state that the issue in question here was that of him performing improvised dialogue as one of his former Nintendo characters (alongside Mario, Martinet also voiced Luigi, Wario, Waluigi, Baby Mario, Baby Luigi and others).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Oh Ricky, I do the voice for every fan I meet," Martinet wrote in response. "I just don't improvise non-Mario phrases or dialogue."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Martinet went on to state that this was his own decision, born out of his own desire not to have Nintendo's character say things that weren't already a part of the company's games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"That's my choice to be sure," Martinet continued. "I always maintain the integrity of the character. But come and visit me at any Comic Con or fan expo and you'll hear super Mario for sure! #woohoo"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario's voice is now provided by Kevin Afghani in all Nintendo video games — or Hollywood's Chris Pratt in the Super Mario Bros. Movie, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/unannounced-super-mario-bros-movie-sequel-title-super-mario-world-published-then-pulled-from-nbcuniversal-press-release">which next year will get a sequel</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Isaiah Trickey/FilmMagic.</em>
<em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>