<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.ign.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.ign.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:20:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Developer Full Circle Hit With Layoffs as EA Looks to 'Better Support' the 'Long-Term Future' of the Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/skate-developer-full-circle-hit-with-layoffs-as-ea-looks-to-better-support-the-long-term-future-of-the-game</link>
            <guid>1446571</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/skate"><u>Skate</u></a> developer Full Circle has announced layoffs affecting an undisclosed number of staff as it aims to “better support” the “long-term future” of its free-to-play title.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Publisher EA revealed its “reshaping” plans with <a href="https://www.ea.com/ea-studios/full-circle/news/an-update-from-fullcircle?utm_campaign=skt_hd_ww_ic_ic_twt_fc-update-from-full-circle&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;cid=88627&amp;ts=1772050332079" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a blog post</u></a> on the studio’s website. No detailed information about the number of affected employees or their roles was given, with the message only stating that “making changes to our team structure” means that “some roles will be impacted.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“The teammates affected are talented colleagues and friends who helped build the foundation of skate.,” Full Circle said. “Their creativity and dedication are deeply ingrained in what players experience today. This decision is not a reflection of their impact and we’re committed to supporting them through this transition.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The post mentions that tens of millions of players have played the free-to-play Skate reboot since it launched as an Early Access title for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X | S September 2025. Today’s restructuring is said “to better support skate.’s long-term future and focus the team on the things that matter most to you.” EA and Full Circle sign off by assuring fans they will work with the community as they “move faster, listen more closely, and deliver consistently” as development on Skate continues.</p><p>This decision is not a reflection of their impact and we’re committed to supporting them through this transition.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">“To our departing teammates: thank you. skate. exists because of your hard work and dedication to the craft.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Full Circle’s restructuring is only the latest in a string of layoffs and game cancellations at EA. Following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-to-lay-off-around-670-to-advance-the-way-we-work"><u>layoffs impacting around 670 workers</u></a> in early 2024, the Battlefield and Madden publisher <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn"><u>cut 300 additional jobs across the company</u></a> in April 2025. That move alone saw <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted"><u>the cancellation of a new project set in the Titanfall universe</u></a> at Respawn Entertainment, as the studio accounted for around 100 of the affected roles at the time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA went on to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-pushes-full-return-to-office-effectively-ends-remote-hiring"><u>end remote hiring and push employees to return to the office</u></a> the following month. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games"><u>closure of Cliffhanger Games</u></a>, the studio behind the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-developers-wave-goodbye-to-ambitious-and-special-black-panther-game-it-breaks-my-heart-the-world-wont-see-it"><u>now-cancelled Black Panther video game</u></a>, then arrived just weeks later. September 2025 then saw the company announce it had accepted <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-with-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners-andrew-wilson-to-remain-as-ceo"><u>a $55 billion acquisition offer</u></a> from Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund (PIF), Jared Kushner’s Affinity Partners, and Silver Lake.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Full Circle will continue development on Skate as it works to secure its long-term future. As detailed in <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/skate/skate/news/seasonal-roadmap-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a separate post last week</u></a>, the free-to-play skating revival will soon launch into Season 3. The rest of its roadmap includes the promise of additional features, cosmetics, game modes, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN reached out to EA for comment regarding the restructuring at Full Circle, but was pointed back to the note shared by the studio in lieu of further comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/skate-developer-full-circle-hit-with-layoffs-as-ea-looks-to-better-support-the-long-term-future-of-the-game]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Only Has 7 Playable Characters Because They Are “More Differentiated With Much Deeper Gameplay” | IGN Fan Fest ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-only-has-7-playable-characters-because-they-are-more-differentiated-with-much-deeper-gameplay-ign-fan-fest-2026</link>
            <guid>1446565</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Quality, not quantity.</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ever since Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight’s reveal at gamescom 2025, one of the hottest topics surrounding it has been the surprisingly small number of playable characters on its roster. But developer TT Games promises that there’s a very good reason for this.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the past decade or so, Lego games ranging from DC and Marvel superheroes to Star Wars and Harry Potter droids and wizards have included unlockable playable character numbers stretching into the hundreds, but in the upcoming Legacy of the Dark Knight, that total at launch is just seven. Those that made the cut include the Bat family and a few friends: Batman, Robin, Nightwing, Batgirl, Jim Gordon, Talia Al Ghul, and Catwoman.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently spoke to the head of the TT Games development team, Jonathan Smith, to find out why this number has been reduced so drastically by comparison. “We're taking these individual characters on a journey,” Smith explains. “So you are constantly upgrading and developing new skills and opening up new abilities for each of those characters. Within the Bat family, as well, we really wanted to focus on making those characters really unique, making their personalities come across and their abilities very distinct.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, Batman can throw batarangs and use his grapple to assist in combat as well as solve puzzles, but Catwoman can utilise her rangy whip and call in the help of her kittens by triggering a laser pointer on a target. Those same cats can also be directly controlled by the player to grant access to small vents and distract unsuspecting guards with a delightful “meow”.</p><p>You still get that moment in the Bat Cave where you've got all the different suits from all the different characters arrayed in front of you.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the focus is seemingly on a deeper gameplay experience this time around, with a Rocksteady Arkham-influenced combo-based combat system leading that charge, fans of old-school Lego games shouldn’t fear too much, as Smith promises there will still be plenty to collect across its open world and movie-inspired levels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The story is more focused on a tighter roster of characters that are now more differentiated with much deeper gameplay,” confirms Smith. “So they work well in partnership with each other, and we then want to give you lots and lots of options to see the full range of what those characters can be by giving you more than a hundred different suits to collect. So you still get that moment in the Bat Cave where you've got all the different suits from all the different characters arrayed in front of you, colorful and glorious. You're still compelled to want to complete that collection.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Bat Suits, take a look at every one confirmed to be in Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight so far, and if you want to know a lot more about the game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-are-not-leaving-anything-behind-how-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-is-balancing-old-and-new-ign-fan-fest-2026">check out more from our interview</a> with the studio as part of IGN Fan Fest 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-only-has-7-playable-characters-because-they-are-more-differentiated-with-much-deeper-gameplay-ign-fan-fest-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Really Glad to Have Some Space': Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Developer Breathed Sigh of Relief After GTA 6 Delay | IGN Fan Fest 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/really-glad-to-have-some-space-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-developer-breathed-sigh-of-relief-after-gta-6-delay-ign-fan-fest-2026</link>
            <guid>1446559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar's most recent <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">GTA 6</a> delay might mean a longer wait for the year's biggest launch, but it also brought relief to other developers previously set to release games in the same timeframe. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That includes TT Games, the storied British studio behind numerous LEGO titles such as LEGO Star Wars, LEGO Harry Potter, and the promising-looking <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Due to launch for PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on May 29 (with a Nintendo Switch 2 edition to follow on later), the open-world Gotham action adventure is now set to launch within days of Rockstar's previous GTA 6 date — May 26. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">TT Games made its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-announced-the-game-awards-2025">Legacy of the Dark Knight release date announcement</a> last December at The Game Awards, a month after Rockstar's latest GTA 6 delay was made public. (GTA 6 now looks to have a seemingly-final launch date, with marketing set to ramp up this summer ahead of its long-awaited arrival on November 19.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We knew we wanted to come out in spring of this year," TT Games Head of Production and Strategic Director Jonathan Smith told IGN in a recent interview, discussing the "space" now opened up by GTA 6's delay to this holiday. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Look, I want to play that game [GTA 6], but we're also really glad to have some space for people to play Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight. We're giving you an open city and a fantastic experience for all players. Which I thoroughly recommend."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Cosmetics</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Going hands-on with the game last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-is-the-arkham-game-youve-been-waiting-for-gamescom-2025">IGN came away impressed</a>, saying that "LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight was the Arkham Game you've been waiting for."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For much more, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-are-not-leaving-anything-behind-how-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-is-balancing-old-and-new-ign-fan-fest-2026">IGN's full Fan Fest preview describing how Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight is balancing old and new</a> to celebrate the best of the caped crusader's many exploits — plus new footage of the game — and check out more detail on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-only-has-7-playable-characters-because-they-are-more-differentiated-with-much-deeper-gameplay-ign-fan-fest-2026">why the game has a smaller roster of just seven playable characters</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/really-glad-to-have-some-space-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-developer-breathed-sigh-of-relief-after-gta-6-delay-ign-fan-fest-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We Draw Upon Everything': It Sounds Like Good News for Fans Wanting the Batfleck Suit in LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight | IGN Fan Fest 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-draw-upon-everything-it-sounds-like-good-news-for-fans-wanting-the-batfleck-suit-in-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-ign-fan-fest-2026</link>
            <guid>1446556</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</a> developer TT Games has shared a positive-sounding update on whether suits from the Dark Knight's brooding Ben Affleck era will be included in the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the game's character roster may be limited (and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-only-has-7-playable-characters-because-they-are-more-differentiated-with-much-deeper-gameplay-ign-fan-fest-2026">we've also got more detail on why that is, too</a>), LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight will feature an enormous wardrobe of 100 Batsuits to celebrate the character's long history.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Already, there have been confirmations of Bat-clothes as worn by Robert Pattinson, Christian Bale, Val Kilmer, Michael Keaton and Adam West — but what about Ben Affleck, who portrayed the character in a handful of movies through the DCEU era, including Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and Justice League.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Batfleck's Batsuit has been a key question among fans of the Caped Crusader, and one that IGN was keen to ask TT Games Head of Production and Strategic Director Jonathan Smith when we recently got a chance to find out more about the promising-looking LEGO Batman game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We draw upon everything across the history of the franchise into this game," Smith said when questioned specifically about references to Ben Affleck's incarnation of the character and the DCEU era overseen by director Zack Snyder. "So yeah, you've got suits and moments and vehicles that everyone will recognize from across all movies," Smith continued. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the majority of LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight's Batsuits are being kept under wraps for players to find, TT Games has already shown off around a dozen through early trailers. We've listed everything that fans have spotted so far below, along with further details if we have them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other than Batfleck, are there are there any other suits you'd like to see? </p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight Batsuits</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Batman: The Brave and the Bold (from the Brave and the Bold animated series)</li><li>Golden Age Batsuit  (inspired by Detective Comics #27, unlocked via pre-launch WB Games account signup)</li><li>Rainbow Batman (as seen in Detective Comics #241)</li><li>The Dark Knight (Christian Bale's outfit from the second Christopher Nolan movie)</li><li>The Batman (Robert Pattinson's suit from his 2022 movie)</li><li>The Serials (inspired by 1940s black and white Batman films)</li><li>Batman '66 (Adam West's costume from his classic TV series)</li><li>Batman Forever Sonar Suit (as worn by Val Kilmer in Batman Forever)</li><li>Batman: The Animated Series (inspired by the 1990s cartoon)</li><li>Batman '89 (Michael Keaton's suit from the 1989 Batman movie)</li><li>2025 Batsuit (based on the minifigure used in recent LEGO toys)</li><li>And many more...</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">For much more, be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-are-not-leaving-anything-behind-how-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-is-balancing-old-and-new-ign-fan-fest-2026">IGN's full Fan Fest preview describing how Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight is balancing old and new</a> to celebrate the best of the caped crusader's many exploits — plus new footage of the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Kevin Mazur/Getty Images</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-draw-upon-everything-it-sounds-like-good-news-for-fans-wanting-the-batfleck-suit-in-lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-ign-fan-fest-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection Developers Comment on New Locales Trailer, More | IGN FanFest 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection-developers-comment-on-new-locales-trailer-more-ign-fanfest-2026</link>
            <guid>1446457</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection’s release date is right around the corner, and IGN had the chance to speak to the developers in depth about a brand new locales trailer released at IGN Fan Fest. We’ve got never-before-seen concept art of the three main bases in the game – Azuria Castle, Sheparden, and Galyad – and insightful commentary from director Kenji Oguro, art director Takahiro Kawano, and lead game designer Daisuke Wakahara. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection">Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection</a> is shaping up to be a beautiful game, which is wholly supported by the diverse scenery you’ll encounter on your journey as an environmentalist Ranger. The Monster Hunter Stories 3 team allocated a lot of time and research into making the locations enjoyable for players, and their attention to detail shows. You can watch the new locales video with commentary direct from the developers above, or, if you’d like to immerse yourself in the scenery with no commentary and a few bonus scenes, check out the trailer below. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Azuria </h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve played the free demo version of Monster Hunter Stories 3, you’ve seen Azuria. This land features fields, forests, and picturesque mountains on the horizon with a castle town on a lake, lending a classic storybook backdrop. 
</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Azuria Concept Art - Monster Hunter Stories 3</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“In the design process, we wanted to make the stereotypical fantasy castle type of design to depict how peaceful Azuria is, and to depict the beautiful nature of the world of Azuria and the castle itself,” Kawano said. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The team had some real-world inspiration that made its way into the concept art for the surrounding area of Azuria and its castle, specifically, a Spanish castle called Alcazar de Segovia. This wouldn’t be the first time the castle has inspired a creator – as part of its 100th anniversary, The Walt Disney Company revealed in 2023 that it was the inspiration for Snow White’s castle. A magical locale, indeed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kawano also described how the wing-like flags represent the wings of Rathalos to signify the special bond Azuria has with the endangered species. The town even has a runway of sorts for monsters to take flight, something uniquely logical for the Stories series, where Riders form bonds with monsters called Monsties and, as the name suggests, ride them. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The attention to detail in the scenery carries into the connection of Twisted Reflection's story as well. The main catalyst of the plot in Stories 3 is the “Crystal Encroachment,” a phenomenon with unknown origins affecting both the environment and monsters, but the crystals it leaves behind is used by the residents of Azuria and elsewhere as a source of light. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Sheparden</h2><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sheparden is the second locale the protagonist and the rangers will visit, and if you’ve played a certain entry in the regular Monster Hunter lineup, you may recognize the lush environment. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“One key feature of [Sheparden] is that monsters from Monster Hunter Rise inhabit the area around it,” revealed Kawano. “So based on Monster Hunter Rise, as you may have known, it has a very Eastern, Asia-like taste. So Sheparden and the surrounding area is also designed after that art style.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You might also notice a structure at the base of the stairs to the village elder’s place inspired by Japanese torii gates, clearly recognizable as orange, angular arches. Right beneath that torii gate are masks stuck into the ground, which represent the graves of the former elders of the village, explained Kawano. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another Sheparden detail the team had to consider is that this village is not built for Riders the way Azuria is. As such, there aren’t stables – so Ratha, the protagonists’ Rathalos, is stuck into a very small space that’s part of an unused residence. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Galyad</h2><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Galyad Concept Art - Monster Hunter Stories 3</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Galyad is a bustling, prosperous town surrounded by desert and relatively desolate lands compared to Azuria and Sheparden. It’s covered in decoration, stones, and jewelry, somewhat fueled by the residents’ successful trade of Egg Quartz. Kawano described that as you get deeper into the city of Galyad, you might discover a boundary between the prosperous residents and the not-so-fortunate residents, and find slum-like areas. 
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The city’s architecture and design is actually inspired by Mediterranean regions and even has a Lagiacrus fountain in the city center. It's especially interesting given the desert environment – Lagiacrus is, after all, a Leviathan monster known to inhabit the water. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Galyad used to be an ocean port city that was floating on top of the ocean,” Kawano explained. “So all the jewelry and the decorations were based off of the Mediterranean sea theme, but desertification has caused the city to lose all the water and it is currently barren, sandy. So that is the reason why there's a difference between the decorations and the actual cityscape itself.” 
</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Monster Hunter 3: Twisted Reflection Q&amp;A </h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, I had to take advantage of the time I had speaking with the Monster Hunter 3: Twisted Reflection developers, so I asked a few questions unrelated to the new trailer I thought might be interesting. We got into the game's more mature protagonist, the weapon availability, the habitat restoration mechanic, and dual-element monsters. 
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>The interview below has been lightly edited and condensed for clarity.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I'd say habitat restoration is one of the biggest new gameplay mechanics in Monster Hunter Stories 3. Can you describe the inspiration behind building the system and why you included it?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Kenji Oguro: </strong>The first reason we wanted to implement this feature into Stories 3 is because of the protagonist. He or she is the captain of the Ranger Corps and their objective is to protect and preserve the environment. So we wanted to express the preservation of the environment, not just only in the storyline, but in the actual gameplay cycle itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tthe second reason we implemented habitat restoration is to expand on the Monster Hunter Stories series formula, where deepening bonds with the monsters is very important. In the previous entries, you would collect monster eggs from dens, hatch them, and raise them, but the places where you could get those eggs were very limited and were the same across all players. But for Monster Hunter Stories 3, by implementing this habitat restoration feature, every player will have their very own environment. So your environment and my environment might differ a lot. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">By restoring the monster populations and sending them off back to the wilds, you might be able to find some rare eggs with dual-element monsters, as well as Deviant Monsters. [Deviant Monsters] are popular monsters from the previous Monster Hunter mainline series games. You might be able to find eggs of the Deviant monsters by raising the ecosystem rank within the habitat restoration feature. We wanted to reward players for helping to protect the environment and restoring the endangered species and growing their population in the world by providing rare monsters that might hatch from the eggs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: In the first Monster Hunter Stories, changing a Monstie’s element worked differently, and was achieved by swapping genes to change their stats. Can you tell us the reason behind changing this method to the new one? </strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Kenji Oguro: </strong>In the first Stories game, when you change the genes of the monster and get a dual-element monster, the element that monster possesses completely changes. So that might end up as a disadvantage for a player if you get the wrong combination. But for Stories 3, the team wanted to expand the user's options more and also make habitat restoration more unique. So they implemented habitat restoration and by raising the ecosystem rank and getting the rare eggs, you are rewarded with the dual-element monster. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For Stories 3, the dual-element monster will retain their original element. So if the original monster has a fire element, they will keep the fire element, and on top of that, they'll get their second new element. So in the combat, players might want to keep the original fire element and get a new element on top.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This gives players an advantage and more options when they are forming their parties. Usually for RPG games, players tend to go for the strongest character or strongest monster with the highest stats and abilities. But developing Monster Stories 3, with the dual-element feature, you get special monsters with different appearances. One of [my] favorites is the Velocidrome imbued with the dragon element. So you get a pitch black Velocidrome, very badass. And that was [my] favorite monster within the development cycle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After finding [my] favorite dual-element monster, [I] found that, "Hey, maybe I can just play with my favorite monster instead of focusing on the stats or the ability skills." So that's one of the ways that the players can enjoy the game. It's not just going for the strongest, most powerful monsters, but instead finding a true partner that you love and want to bond with.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I played the Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflections demo, and I did notice that the Long Sword was added to this game. It hasn't been in Monster Hunter Stories yet. But I didn't see the Sword and Shield in my bag. Can you tell me if the Sword and Shield is in Monster Hunter Stories 3, and why you decided to add the Long Sword?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Daisuke Wakahara: </strong>So first off, we implemented the Long Sword because the Long Sword itself throughout the Monster Hunter series is very popular amongst hunters and riders. However, we did have some trouble implementing the weapon itself into the RPG formula in the previous games. But in Monster Hunter Stories 3, we were able to come up with a formula to have the Long Sword join the weapon roster.</p><p>In terms of Sword and Shield, unfortunately, it is not going to be included in Monster Hunter Stories 3.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">And in terms of Sword and Shield, unfortunately, it is not going to be included in Monster Hunter Stories 3 this time around. The reason why we came to this decision is because we had to carefully think about the weapon balance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When looking at the overall weapon roster for Stories 3, we have Slash, Blunt, and Piercing weapon types. And having both Long Sword and Sword and Shield would change the roster to go towards the Slash weapon types a little too heavily, so we had to take out the Sword and Shield from the roster, unfortunately.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: The main character this time around is more of an adult than the previous protagonists in the Monster Hunter Stories series. Can you tell me why you made that decision to make the protagonist more mature this time around?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Takahiro Kawano: </strong>We wanted to differentiate this with the previous entry stories, Monster Hunter Stories and Monster Hunter Stories 2, where the focus was on a child growing into a young adolescent. We decided to start the story off with a full-grown adult as the elite rider. So in terms of the setting for Monster Hunter Stories 3,  the protagonist actually starts off already grown up as a prince or a princess of Azuria, and is an elite rider.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Is there anything else you want to say to the fans watching before we let you go?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Takahiro Kawano: </strong>As you've seen in the video, we put a lot of effort into the background character designs for Monster Hunter Stories 3. So we’d like to have the players have fun and enjoy the beautiful scenery and the characters in Monster Hunter Stories 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Daisuke Wakahara:</strong> Thank you to all the players for supporting the Monster Hunter Stories series from the first title. You'll be surprised at how much the Monster Hunter Stories series has evolved throughout Stories 2 and the newest entry, Monster Hunter Stories 3. We are very confident in this game and that any player can enjoy it as an RPG title. So even if you haven't tried out the Monster Hunter Stories series yet, we highly encourage new players to try out the Monster Hunter Stories series. </p><div data-cy="paragraph"><p><strong>Kenji Oguro:</strong> [I’ve] played through Monster Hunter Stories 3 10 to 20 times during the development process. And every time I go through the gameplay, there's something new that the player can find. I’m very surprised that there's many, many cards up the development team’s sleeves. So we highly encourage you, the players, to have fun with the game. </p><p>Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection is coming to PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch 2 on March 12, 2026. You can play a free trial right now featuring a huge portion of the first area, Azuria, and continue your progress in the full release.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Casey DeFreitas is Deputy Editor of Guides at IGN, and is a first fleet Monster Hunter. Catch her on Socials like Bluesky @ShinyCaseyD. </em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection-developers-comment-on-new-locales-trailer-more-ign-fanfest-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>