<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 20:52:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Cancels Black Panther Game, Closes Cliffhanger Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games.1201077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This is the third round of layoffs at EA this year.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Electronic Arts is canceling its planned Black Panther game and shutting down developer Cliffhanger Games, IGN has learned.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an email sent to staff from EA Entertainment president Laura Miele, Miele said that these changes, alongside other recent cancellations and layoffs, are being done to "sharpen our focus and put our creative energy behind the most significant growth opportunities."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to closing Cliffhanger and canceling Black Panther, EA is also laying off some individuals on both its mobile and central teams. When asked for an exact number of individuals impacted, EA declined to comment. IGN understands the total number of affected individuals in this wave is less than the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn">roughly 300 roles cut last month</a> across Respawn and EA's Fan Care teams - but cannot confirm by how much. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"These decisions are hard," Miele wrote. "They affect people we’ve worked with, learned from, and shared real moments with. We’re doing everything we can to support them — including finding opportunities within EA, where we’ve had success helping people land in new roles."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As with past rounds of layoffs, EA is endeavoring to place affected individuals in other roles across the company. The company has made use of this placement program with each round of layoffs in recent years, an effort that remains possible despite the constant team cuts likely due to EA seemingly drastically increasing headcount on other teams at the same time. <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/wait-a-minute-eas-headcount-rose" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Per Game File's reporting</a>, EA employed 800 more people as of March of this year than it did the same time in 2024.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">To that end, Miele's email continues, the company is focusing on a small handful of franchises going forward: Battlefield, The Sims, Skate, and Apex Legends. Miele also reassures EA will continue to invest in its Iron Man game at Motive and the third Star Wars: Jedi game, as well as it maintain its mobile business despite today's cuts, while Bioware works on the next Mass Effect. Additionally, last year, CEO Andrew Wilson <a href="https://www.ea.com/news/continuing-to-evolve-our-business-and-teams" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced the company would be</a> "moving away from development of future licensed IP that we do not believe will be successful in our changing industry."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The email doesn't mention EA Sports, but this is due to Miele running EA Entertainment, while EA Sports is a separate division. IGN understands that the sports division is unaffected by these changes for now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Notably, Marvel and EA's agreement for Black Panther was part of a three-game deal that included Iron Man and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-and-ea-sign-three-game-deal-starting-with-iron-man">a third, unannounced title</a>. Little has been shown of Black Panther so far since its announcement in 2023, though we know from a job listing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/eas-black-panther-appears-to-be-an-open-world-sandbox-based-on-job-posting">it was to be a single-player, action-adventure, open-world game</a>. Black Panther was being developed by the newly-formed, now-closed Cliffhanger Games, which was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-ea-studio-dedicated-to-open-world-action-adventure-will-be-led-by-former-monolith-studio-head">formed in 2023</a> with some former developers of Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-announces-black-panther-game-from-some-of-the-developers-behind-middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor">headed up by Kevin Stephens</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These cuts come on the heels of multiple other rounds of layoffs and cancelations at EA over the last few years and especially in 2025. Just last month, EA <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn">laid off roughly 300 individuals</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted">around 100 at Respawn, while canceling an in-development Titanfall game and another incubation project</a>. Earlier this year, EA restructured BioWare, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams">moving some developers to other projects</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect">laying off others</a>. In 2024, there was a massive restructuring at EA that resulted in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-to-lay-off-around-670-to-advance-the-way-we-work">670 workers</a> laid off company-wide, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-hit-by-layoffs-amid-eas-ongoing-reductions">around two dozen workers at Respawn.</a> And in 2023, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs">50 jobs were cut at BioWare</a> and an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/f1-developer-codemasters-suffers-round-of-layoffs">unknown number were cut at Codemasters</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, EA recently implemented <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-pushes-full-return-to-office-effectively-ends-remote-hiring">mandatory return-to-office for all workers,</a> a move that some employees told IGN has left many currently remote workers with concerns about what will happen to their roles long-term.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When asked for comment on the exact number impacted, the reasons for these repeated cuts, or if more cuts are expected in the near future, EA referred IGN back to Miele's email. Marvel has not yet responded to IGN's request for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does the New PlayStation VR2 Deal Finally Make It Worth Buying?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/does-the-new-playstation-vr2-deal-finally-make-it-worth-buying</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-the-new-playstation-vr2-deal-finally-make-it-worth-buying.1200981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/does-the-new-playstation-vr2-deal-finally-make-it-worth-buying<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">PSVR 2 is back down to its all-time low price.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The PlayStation VR2 headset has dropped to match its all-time low price thanks to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-days-of-play-sale-2025-live">PlayStation Days of Play sale</a>, so if you've been considering picking one up for yourself, right now would be the time to do so. But the question is: Should you actually buy one in 2025? The PSVR2 originally launched for a whopping $599, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-psvr2-headset-price-cut-deal-is-now-live">Sony dropped the price</a> down to just $399 back in March. The latest discount brings that price all the way down to only $349 for both the stand-alone headset and the Horizon Call of the Mountain Bundle.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The PlayStation VR2 Headset Is On Sale at Amazon Today</h2><div catalogid="f4357a55-1b57-400c-ac5d-2dc92766936f" id="221877"><div id="221877" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>PSVR 2: Horizon Call of The Mountain Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The new $50 discount on the PSVR2 bundle is certainly tempting if you've been wanting to get into VR, but there are a few things to consider before you buy. This is likely the lowest price we'll see on this headset for quite some time and it is the only VR option for PS5 owners. If you want to play Horizon Call of The Mountain, owning a PSVR2 is currently the only way you'll be able to do that. Just last year Sony also released the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-vr2-pc-adapter-review">PSVR2 PC adapter</a> that allows you to connect it to your PC and play VR games there as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That being said, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-cuts-investment-in-vr-development-only-two-first-party-vr-games-currently-in-development-report">Sony isn't really investing </a>much into first-party VR games anymore. And with the price drop back in March and the release of the PC adapter, it definitely seems like PS5 owners aren't going to be seeing a slew of new and exciting VR games any time soon.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Is It Worth Buying a PSVR 2 in 2025?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that the PSVR 2 is cheaper than the standard Meta Quest 3 <em>and</em> has PC compatibility, it's worth considering if you're looking to get into VR. Since it is really the only VR option for PlayStation, this price definitely makes it worth it if you have both a PS5 and a PC that can handle VR games. You do have to purchase the PC adapter if you want to access your SteamVR library, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-connect-ps-vr2-headset-to-a-pc">connecting to PC is a fairly simple process</a> overall.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you don't own a PS5 and are just looking for a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-vr-headsets-for-pc">decent VR headset for PC</a>, the PSVR 2 probably isn't worth your money. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-review">Meta Quest 3S</a> is still cheaper and doesn't require any sort of extra adapter to start playing games. Since the PSVR 2 isn't a standalone VR headset, you'd also be better off going with the Quest 3 if you don't have either a PS5 or a PC to connect to.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>May 28, 2025 5:55 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crystal of Atlan Launches May 28 and Shakes Up MMORPG Combat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-and-shakes-up-mmorpg-combat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-and-shakes-up-mmorpg-combat.1200900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-and-shakes-up-mmorpg-combat<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Crystal of Atlan is an action MMORPG from developer VI-Games that wants to put its own unique spin on the gameplay of the genre. It features a focus on class-based build diversity, fast-paced aerial combat, and chaining together abilities to build up your combo meter. It's available to <a href="https://coau.onelink.me/Kb3c/rqg5e02q" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">download for free</a> right now, but if you're looking for more info before you dive in, we've got you. Let’s start with the classes.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Diverse Class Paths for Personalized Builds</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are five base classes available at launch, all unlocked for free at the start of the game: the melee damage dealing Swordsman, ranged attacker Musketeer, magical Magister, martial artist Fighter, and summoner Puppeteer. Each class branches into specialized subclasses, with a total of 11 subclass options and more than 20 unique abilities to experiment with and tailor to your preferred style.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-image-1-1747937274930.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, the Swordsman branches into the Magiblade or Berserker. They’re both melee damage dealers, but the Magiblade adds magical abilities (which you could probably guess from the name), and the Berserker can sacrifice health to generate shields and increase power as you get closer to death. Regardless of the subclass you choose, each of the skills you unlock have individual cooldowns. You can mix and match those skills at any time, letting you come up with unique character builds and find skills that chain together well to build combos.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-puppeteer-subclass-1747937366873.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Seamless Ground-to-Air Combat Innovation</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Traditional MMO combat focuses on ground-based attacks with a fairly simple stand-and-attack style. Crystal of Atlan differentiates itself by including a heavy focus on the Z-axis, introducing a system that encourages you to seamlessly transition between ground and aerial combat.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-platforming-1747937405449.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">You can attack and dodge in mid-air, allowing you to pull off aerial combos and adding a new dimension to each battle and a level of responsiveness to moment-to-moment gameplay. You can jump to avoid attacks, then chain that into aerial combos to keep the pressure on enemies. So you’re rewarded for staying on your toes, reacting quickly, and using all your abilities to fluidly chain attacks together.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That focus on ground and air combos also informs the design of Crystal of Atlan’s varied environments. All of the game’s maps, from the fantastical Wonderland to the mechanical Chrome Military Factory, have an open 3D layout to allow freedom of movement. Couple that with smooth animations and you get a combat system that’s fluid and fast-paced.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-image-2-1747937438520.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Cooperative Challenges and Social Progression</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As you might expect from an MMO, there are a variety of dungeons you can tackle with other players. You fight through packs of normal enemies before getting to the end and facing off against a boss with unique mechanics. That’s all pretty standard, but Crystal of Atlan mixes things up by requiring synchronized team coordination.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-image-3-1747937464007.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">There are numerous dungeons with interaction-based mechanics that require teamwork to solve problems. Naturally, if your whole group is tackling such a dungeon for the first time, you’ll need to communicate and help each other figure out what to do. Once you’ve gotten the hang of it, you can take on a mentor role in future runs, but everyone will always need to work together.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also a fleet system, which is basically like guilds you’ve probably experienced in other games. It’s a key part of Crystal of Atlan's social ecosystem, allowing you to link up with friends to tackle co-op gameplay together or just hang out and chat.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Competitive PvP and Creative PvE Challenges</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re the competitive type, there are also options for PvP combat. There are 1v1 and 3v3 battles, with attributes, skill damage, and skill cooldowns balanced so there’s no competitive advantage. It’s all about skill.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Crystal of Atlan is an MMO at heart, it has plenty of content for solo players too. In classic MMO style, there are hub areas where you can see lots of other players. These areas are where you’ll find quests to complete and new zones to explore.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-magiblade-subclass-1747937517467.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Adventure Mode takes you through the game’s main story, which unlocks in stages. You can tackle these stages solo, and they have a variety of different goals. Some will be focused on combat, where you need to defeat groups of enemies or take on a boss. Others introduce new elements, like requiring you to use stealth to sneak past enemies or use platforming to progress through the area.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are plenty of other modes you can tackle solo or co-op. The main one is the Arena, where you can fight alone or with a partner and gradually work your way up through tiers of opponents, earning escalating rewards as you do. If you manage to get through all the tiers, you can reach the Finals for the ultimate reward.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/22/crystal-of-atlan-image-4-1747937545618.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To sum it all up, Crystal of Atlan is an MMORPG that mixes together classic staples of the genre with evolved gameplay to keep things fun, fast, and fluid. It launches May 28 on PC, PS5, iOS, and Android, with crossplay across all platforms. The PS5 version has an optimized HUD layout to avoid clutter and utilizes the haptic feedback of the DualSense controller. It also has a remapped UI for controller input, using a function wheel you’re probably familiar with from other games. There’s HDR support for enhanced lighting, and PSSR is enabled on the PS5 Pro for sharper visuals and more stable frame rates.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/21/crystal-of-atlan-ps5-command-wheel-1747849581064.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">For more info on the world, classes, and features of Crystal of Atlan, you can check out <a href="https://coa.nvsgames.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">the official website</a>. Or to join the community and get news updates, you can follow them on <a href="https://x.com/CoA_Global" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/CrystalofAtlan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@crystalofatlan.en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">TikTok</a>, and <a href="https://discord.com/invite/tWEcmGhWgv" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Discord</a>.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>