<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:58:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher Books Box Set Drops to a Great Low Price for Amazon's Cyber Monday Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-books-box-set-cyber-monday-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>1368679</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The original Geralt of Rivia.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-black-friday-sale-2025-new-deals#new-book-deals">dropping new book deals</a> since Black Friday, and one of the most popular discounts available has been on The Witcher books. Andrzej Spkowski's Witcher series is the basis for the entire phenomenon. The popularity of the series may have been elevated by The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt and the Netflix series, but its the original story that has inspired the dark fantasy world we've come to love.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest Cyber Monday deal on this box set drops the price down to just $33.79 for the whole paperback set. This is a lower price than what we saw last week when the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-black-friday-book-deals-at-amazon-2025">buy 2, get 1 free sale was still live</a>, so it's worth picking up as an individual set before the deals end tomorrow.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Witcher Boxed Set Deal at Amazon</h2><div catalogid="b38ea8ec-a4f1-40e8-aed9-aed0d99c4997" id="231575"><div id="231575" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Witcher Boxed Set</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This convenient collection comes with a box to store all five books on your shelf. The spines all sport the same red binding, making them pop on your shelf. The main novels follow Geralt of Rivia, the titular Witcher, and his decades-long quest to protect Ciri, the child prophesized to have the power to alter the world. Here's what you'll get in this collection: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Blood of Elves</li><li>The Time of Contempt</li><li>Baptism of Fire</li><li>The Tower of Swallows</li><li>The Lady of the Lake</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Not included here are the two short story precursors to Blood of Elves, The Last Wish and Sword of Destiny. These detail how many of our characters meet and give much deeper history and backstory for a better understanding of this world. The other two prequel novels, Season of Storms and Crossroads of Ravens, are required reading for anyone looking to experience the entirety of the saga. All four books are discounted on Amazon right now as well, so you can pick them up separately if you want to coplete the collection. All but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-prequel-book-crossroads-of-ravens-where-to-buy">Crossroads of Ravens</a> feature the same style of cover and spine art, so they'll look really nice with on your shelf with the rest of the series. You can check out the full <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-books-reading-order">reading order of The Witcher books</a> to see what you're missing or see our larger <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-buy-2-get-1-free-sale-on-book-box-sets-black-friday-2025">list of book box sets on sale</a> today.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h3 data-cy="title3" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Other Witcher books included in the sale</h3></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Myles Obenza is a freelance writer for IGN. Follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mylesobenza.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mylesobenza.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 30, 2025 6:10 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-books-box-set-cyber-monday-sale-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>