<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:21:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Really Does Seem To Have Changed Its Nipple Policy — And Now It's Not Just Homer Simpson's Chest That's in the Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-really-does-seem-to-have-changed-its-nipple-policy-and-now-its-not-just-homer-simpsons-chest-thats-in-the-game</link>
            <guid>1373299</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> fans believe developer Epic Games has indeed relaxed its rules around the depiction of male nudity, as the game's first fully detailed areola have now been spotted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A shirtless style for the game's new Chapter 7 battle pass skin Carter Wu shows a relatively detailed nipple present and correct on the character's chest — the first in almost a decade of Fortnite history.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The development comes <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-believe-homer-simpsons-nipples-point-to-fortnite-policy-change">just weeks after fans spotted two telltale dots on the chest of Fortnite's underpants-wearing Homer Simpson skin</a>, and wondered whether the game's long-term decision not to show nips had been reconsidered. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time, Homer's design featuring nipples was debated as potentially being an exception to Fortnite's no-nips rule — perhaps due to some licensing requirement, or because his cel-shaded model was low in detail. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But the arrival now of a standard Fortnite skin — prominently available in Chapter 7's first battle pass, no less — suggests otherwise, and points to more nipples likely now appearing within Fortnite in future. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the past, everyone from Travis Scott to God of War's Kratos, Avatar: The Last Airbender's Aang, WWE's John Cena, Dragonball Z's Goku, and Marvel superheroes such as Drax and The Hulk have all appeared in Fortnite topless, with smooth nipple-less chests. Even third-party creator-made modes have been nipple-free, with a high-profile promotional crossover with body hair shaver brand Philips featuring a smooth-chested model. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Could Epic Games now re-add nipples to previous skins, restoring characters like Kratos to their fully chested glory? We will have to wait and see. IGN has often contacted Epic Games about Fortnite's previous no-nipple policy for more detail, though is yet to receive an official statement on the subject.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-really-does-seem-to-have-changed-its-nipple-policy-and-now-its-not-just-homer-simpsons-chest-thats-in-the-game]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High on Life 2: Boss Fight Gameplay – IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/high-on-life-2-boss-fight-gameplay-ign-first</link>
            <guid>1373296</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Boss battles in the first High on Life were memorable. Take a look at one from the sequel.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Our IGN First "cover story" game for December is High on Life 2, the upcoming comedy first-person shooter sequel to the 2022 original breakout hit from Squanch Games. We got our coverage warmed up with the funny <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/high-on-life-2-official-humanzapro-pharma-teaser-trailer-ign-first">in-universe ad for Humanzapro</a>, and then we posted <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/high-on-life-2-exclusive-early-campaign-gameplay-ign-first">ten minutes of exclusive new gameplay</a> from early in the campaign set in Pinkline Harbor, one of three in-game hubs you'll explore. And today, we've got a boss fight reveal, showing off a battle against Kreg Button, a pirate-themed bounty hunter. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">High on Life 2 aims to double down on what worked in the original, with new and returning talking guns voiced by the likes of JB Smoove (Curb Your Enthusiasm), among others. It also adds plenty of new gameplay, such as skateboarding. Check out the new boss fight gameplay below. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/high-on-life-2-official-announcement-trailer-xbox-games-showcase-2025">original announcement trailer</a> if you missed it, and stay tuned all December long for more exclusive High on Life 2 content, including more gameplay, new weapon reveals, interviews with the developers, a fresh hands-on preview of the latest build, and more!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/high-on-life-2-boss-fight-gameplay-ign-first]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything Announced at Creative Assembly's Total War 25th Anniversary Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-announced-at-creative-assemblys-total-war-25th-anniversary-showcase</link>
            <guid>1373293</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Creative Assembly’s Total War 25th anniversary showcase featured a number of major announcements in the strategy series, including a brand new game, a significant update to an existing game, and the tease of a new game announcement at The Game Awards.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Total War: Medieval 3 announced</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/total-war-medieval-3-announced-as-the-rebirth-of-historical-total-war-new-total-war-game-to-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards">Creative Assembly announced Total War: Medieval 3</a>, the long-awaited return to the franchise’s historical roots, with a live-action reveal trailer. Here’s the official blurb:</p><blockquote>Now in early pre-production, this next chapter is both a tribute to its legendary predecessors and a bold revolution for the series. Built as the ultimate medieval strategy sandbox, it will empower players to shape realms, rewrite history, and immerse themselves in the Middle Ages like never before. Combining meticulous historical authenticity with unprecedented player agency, this is more than a sequel, it’s the rebirth of historical Total War.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Total War: Warhammer 3 - Lords of the End Times announced</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Next came Total War: Warhammer 3 - Lords of the End Times, which coincides with the subseries’ 10th year. The Lords of The End Times Pack adds four new Legendary Lords into the Immortal Empires campaign experience in summer 2026. The first to be revealed is the great necromancer, Nagash, who returns to reclaim his lost power and drown the world in undeath. These new lords also herald the arrival of the free End Times Update. Here’s the official blurb:</p><blockquote>Taking inspiration from the lore, players will face a campaign experience transformed, with apocalyptic scenarios and cataclysmic events that push the boundaries of strategy and survival. And to crown this update, a new Legendary Lord will rise, ready to leave their mark on the cataclysm to come.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Creative Assembly ended the announcement by saying there’s more to come from Total War: Warhammer, insisting “the series is far from over.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">The Warcore game engine to bring Total War to consoles</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up was the announcement of the Warcore game engine, the latest version of Creative Assembly's own tech which allows for future Total War games to launch on console. Here’s what Creative Assembly had to say:</p><blockquote>Building on 25 years of strategy innovation, Warcore is the next evolution of Total War’s proprietary engine. As the most advanced technological foundation in the franchise’s history, it empowers developers with a suite of tools that allows for gameplay to be more immersive, dynamic and responsive than ever before. Designed to evolve over time, it will continue to unlock new capabilities, ensuring the franchise stays at the cutting edge of strategy gaming for years to come. In a franchise first, it also enables future games to be released on PlayStation and Xbox, welcoming a new generation of commanders to the scale, immersion, and tactical mastery that defines Total War.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">'Surprise' Total War game set for The Game Awards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The showcase ended with a tease for The Game Awards on December 11, when a “surprise” third game will be revealed. “This title will be Total War’s next major release and represents one of the most ambitious projects in the franchise’s history, marking the beginning of an exciting new era,” Creative Assembly said. “We hope to see you there.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-announced-at-creative-assemblys-total-war-25th-anniversary-showcase]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fallout: New Vegas: 15th Anniversary Bundle for PC Is Now Up for Preorder at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-pc-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>1373251</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Get ready for a replay next June.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">Fallout: New Vegas</a> turned 15 this year, and to celebrate, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-here-are-the-contents">Bethesda announced a Fallout: New Vegas 15th Anniversary Bundle</a> back in October. For those who simply can't wait to get their hands on a bundle of their own, preorders are now finally live at <a href="https://zdcs.link/921MB1?object_uuid=07fabf42-9777-441a-9f20-2b6c812ed4de&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0G4NDX1DX" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon</a> (as well as at the <a href="https://zdcs.link/zEJn54?object_uuid=07fabf42-9777-441a-9f20-2b6c812ed4de&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Bethesda Gear Store)</a> for $154.99.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, there's still a little ways to wait before fans will be able to boot it up in their PCs, as it's currently set to be released on June 30, 2026. So it'll have to be a slightly delayed anniversary celebration, but a fun one nonetheless.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Preorder the Fallout: New Vegas: 15th Anniversary Bundle</h2><div catalogid="0ed8a31d-50dd-49c0-af05-801af8c1bd35" id="233338"><div id="233338" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Fallout New Vegas: 15th Anniversary Bundle - PC</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This looks like the ultimate bundle for New Vegas fans to enjoy, too. First and foremost, it comes with a PC digital code for Fallout: New Vegas Ultimate Edition, which includes the Dead Money DLC, Honest Hearts DLC, Old World Blues DLC, Lonesome Road DLC, Courier’s Stash Weapon Pack, and Gun Runner’s Arsenal Weapon Pack. What's even better, though, is that it comes packaged in a retro Collector’s Big Box (which can be seen in the photo above) which was exclusively made to celebrate the game's anniversary.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside the PC code and collector's box, it also comes with an 8-inch PVC statue of Victor the Securitron, a set of Doc Mitchell’s evaluation cards, a Vault Boy enamel pin, a Mojave Express patch, and an NCR Recon patch. What better collection to have to celebrate 15 years of this excellent game? Plus, with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-season-2-takes-the-fog-of-war-approach-to-avoid-making-any-new-vegas-ending-canon-creators-say">Fallout TV show heading to New Vegas for its second season,</a> there's no better time to play it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for even more Fallout-themed items to pick up, whether for fun or shopping for a fan for the holidays ahead? Check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-fallout-gear-and-collectible-gift-ideas">best Fallout gear and collectibles</a> to see some more of our favorite picks, alongside this bundle, that we think are well worth a look right now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 4, 2025 4:48 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-pc-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime Actor Confirms Identity of Mysterious Cut Intro Voice]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-actor-confirms-identity-of-mysterious-cut-intro-voice</link>
            <guid>1373248</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Metroid Prime, up until this week’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, at least, is mostly free of spoken dialogue — especially when it comes to its mute protagonist, Samus Aran. But an unused monologue was recorded for the original Metroid Prime, and eventually uncovered by fans, with its performer remaining unknown. Until now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently sat down with legendary Mass Effect and Metal Gear Solid (among many, many others) voice actress, Jennifer Hale, who provided the voice for Samus — entirely grunts and effort sounds — in the original Metroid Prime trilogy. While we were talking with her (and before it was confirmed she had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-has-replaced-samus-voice-actor-for-metroid-prime-4-so-its-no-longer-mass-effects-jennifer-hale-doing-the-grunts"><u>been replaced for 2025’s Metroid Prime 4</u></a>) we thought we’d get to the bottom of the mystery surrounding who voiced that once-lost voice-over that was left on the cutting room floor. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Metroid Prime 4 Beyond Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That monologue goes as follows, for those who are unfamiliar:</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“Ten years ago, below the surface of planet Zebes, the mercenaries known as Space Pirates were defeated by interstellar bounty hunter Samus Aran. Descending to the very core of the Pirate stronghold, Samus exterminated the energy-based parasites called Metroids, and defeated Mother Brain, the leader of the Pirate horde. But the' Space Pirates were far from finished. Several Pirate research vessels were orbiting Zebes while Samus fought on the surface below. After the fall of Mother Brain, the ships escaped, with the hopes of finding enough resources to rebuild their forces, and take their revenge. After discovering a possible Pirate colony on planet Tallon IV, Samus has again prepared for war, hoping to end the Pirate threat forever.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Hale being the most famous voice of Samus, you’d perhaps assume she also recorded these introductory lines to the world of Prime. Well, you’d be wrong.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That's Vanessa. Vanessa Marshall," Hale reveals. It's perhaps not a surprise, as Marshall is already credited with also lending her talents to the voice of Samus in Metroid Prime, notably contributing her death scream to the sound library. Marshall also starred alongside Hale in Marvel’s Midnight Suns, as well as Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty as Olga, and may be familiar to fans of animated TV as the voice of Hera Syndulla in Star Wars' Rebels and Bad Batch series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As to why Retro Studios and Nintendo went with Marshall over Hale for this prospective monologue, only to then ditch it anyway, Hale says she's unsure. “I adore Vanessa,” Hale adds. “I love that we actually shared this role. It's so crazy, and I'm not sure why. I never remember saying no to this. I would never have said no to doing this. They may have preferred her work. I have no idea.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While not getting to record these fully formed sentences, Hale did get the lion's share of the grunt work on Metroid Prime. It sounds an intriguing process, which she went on to explain in more detail:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I like to have identified a character's way of speaking before I do grunting for them, because how you grunt is different to how I grunt, to how anyone else grunts," Hale explained. "It's very specific. If you are a civilian and you're grunting, you're like... [makes surprised grunt noise] because it's all surprising and it's all new. If you've done it a million times, you're like [makes short grunt noise], because you've gone under fire 1,800 times and you're used to it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While that once-lost intro narration was never used in the original Metroid Prime, parts of the monologue would later see the light of day, thanks to Super Smash Bros. Brawl. Jay Ward, who voiced Star Fox’s Wolf O’Donnell in the Nintendo fighting game series, rerecorded certain lines of it that were laid under the Opening/Menu - Metroid Prime track on the soundtrack.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Who knows where this monologue will turn up next, or why it was never actually used in the final game. At least for now, thanks to Samus herself, part of this mystery has been solved. Would you have liked the intro narration to have been kept? Although I do love the lonely, wordless nature of Metroid Prime, I do like the “Ripley at the end of Alien” feel this gives to the game. Let us know what you think in the comments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Metroid Prime, make sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review"><u>our review of Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</u></a>, and for more from Jennifer Hale, read all about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-love-that-universe-im-ready-anytime-jennifer-hale-calls-on-fans-to-tell-bioware-theyd-love-to-see-commander-shepard-return-for-mass-effect-5"><u>why she’d love to return to the Mass Effect series as Commander Shepard or “anyone” BioWare want</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-actor-confirms-identity-of-mysterious-cut-intro-voice]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>