<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 15:31:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition Gets Surprise Update on Console and PC, Adds Visual Features That Were Exclusive to Mobile Versions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-definitive-edition-gets-surprise-update-on-console-and-pc-adds-visual-features-that-were-exclusive-to-mobile-versions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-trilogy-definitive-edition-gets-surprise-update-on-console-and-pc-adds-visual-features-that-were-exclusive-to-mobile-versions.1033551/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-definitive-edition-gets-surprise-update-on-console-and-pc-adds-visual-features-that-were-exclusive-to-mobile-versions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar issued a surprise update for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-the-definitive-edition">GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition</a> today, November 12 — nearly two years since the last one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition, a 2021 compilation of 2001’s Grand Theft Auto 3, 2002’s Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, and 2004’s Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas, was heavily criticized upon launch on PC and console. IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-the-definitive-edition-review">GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition review</a> returned a 5/10. We said: “GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition is defective, disappointing, and surprisingly disrespectful to three classic games and their many legions of fans.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In contrast, the mobile versions of Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition, released in December last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mobile-ports-of-gta-trilogy-receiving-praise-a-day-after-release">met with critical acclaim</a>. Players praised the ports for fixing several issues found on the console and PC versions, including lighting, shadows, reflections, and draw distance.  A Rockstar Games <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/8978k883335o83/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-the-definitive-edition-now-available-on-n" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>blog post</u></a> published at the time mentioned that these ports include a new classic lighting mode "that restores the look and feel of the sky in the original games."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, finally, this classic lighting option is in Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition on PC and console. Early reports indicate sweeping visual improvements across the board that are already going down well with fans.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GTA</a> Definitive Editions just got an update which added the classic lighting option.</p><p>Not gonna lie, it actually looks nice on a screen bigger than a phone.</p><p>I'll test now to see if the same problems still exist with it though like they did on mobile a year ago... <a href="https://t.co/Qv5J68hYos" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/Qv5J68hYos</a></p></div>— TJGM (@TJGM_) <a href="https://twitter.com/TJGM_/status/1856313225819693332?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">I just checked it!<br>Also they readded the ambient clouds high up in the sky <a href="https://t.co/YHBrX6NEUr" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/YHBrX6NEUr</a></p>— /V\@|₹¡0 ßμ†∅†∅ (@MarioButoto99) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioButoto99/status/1856316353478611246?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Reports also indicate Grove Street Games, original developer of Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition, is no longer mentioned in-game. The mobile versions were developed by Video Games Deluxe, the Australian studio behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/la-noire-the-vr-case-files">L.A. Noire VR Case Files</a>.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Looks like mentions of Grove Street Games and their logos have been removed from the splash screen and main menu of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GTA</a> Definitive Editions as well. <a href="https://t.co/ZmXpccyiyS" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ZmXpccyiyS</a></p>— TJGM (@TJGM_) <a href="https://twitter.com/TJGM_/status/1856316469954453783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">If you are diving in to GTA 3, GTA Vice City, or GTA San Andreas in the GTA Trilogy, here's a cheat code refresher for each: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas/Cheat_Codes_and_Secrets"><u>GTA San Andreas Cheats</u></a>,<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/grand-theft-auto-vice-city/Cheats_Codes_and_Secrets"><u> GTA Vice CIty Cheats</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/grand-theft-auto-3/Cheats_Codes_and_Secrets"><u>GTA3 Cheats</u></a> — and how to enter cheats on every platform, including mobile.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a busy time in the world of GTA, with Rockstar continuing work on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">GTA 6</a>. Parent company Take-Two recently <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-insists-it-wont-release-gta-6-and-borderlands-4-close-to-each-other">doubled down on GTA 6's promised fall 2025 release window</a> for what will no doubt be the biggest video game launch of all time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Walmart Has The Best Pokémon TCG Black Friday Deal So Far This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-walmart-early-black-friday-deals-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/walmart-has-the-best-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-black-friday-deal-so-far-this-year.1033545/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-walmart-early-black-friday-deals-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Get two for price of one!</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Walmart is pulling out all the stops this <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/black-friday">Black Friday</a>, slashing prices on the ultra-desirable <strong>Pokémon TCG </strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/9YdGLr?object_uuid=dcdd689a-fe9b-4cc0-868b-ab03cdb7cde5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Tsareena EX Premium Collection</strong></a> and<a href="https://zdcs.link/98b8w2?object_uuid=dcdd689a-fe9b-4cc0-868b-ab03cdb7cde5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong> Tyranitar EX Premium Collection</strong></a> to just <strong>$20 each</strong> — a whopping 50% off their usual $39.99 price tag. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These premium sets are bursting with goodies, from exclusive etched foil EX cards to booster packs, card protectors, and more. For serious collectors or anyone looking to treat themselves, this is the kind of early <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> magic <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-walmart-early-black-friday-deals-2024">Walmart</a> is serving up.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pokémon TCG Tyranitar Ex Premium Collection</h2><div catalogid="afe6637a-d53d-44ca-ac56-ba3000400c18" id="210500"><div id="210500" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Walmart Pokémon Trading Card Games Tyranitar Ex Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <strong>Pokémon TCG Tyranitar EX Premium Collection</strong> is a standout Black Friday deal, now available for $20 (down from $39.99). Featuring Tyranitar EX with its formidable HP and high damage output, this card is a must-have for players looking to dominate. The Double Rare artwork by 5ban Graphics enhances its appeal, while its ability to avoid Bench damage makes it a resilient and tactical choice.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tyranitar’s Mountain Hurl attack delivers 120 damage, though it requires discarding the top two cards from your deck — perfect for bold strategists. Its Lightning Rampage attack hits for 150+ damage and gains an extra 100 damage if any Benched Pokémon have damage counters, creating a path to decisive knockouts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This premium collection includes six booster packs, a magnetic card protector, and exclusive Tyranitar sleeves, making it a stellar choice for players and collectors alike. It’s one of Walmart’s best Black Friday deals for anyone wanting to enhance their deck with power and style.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pokemon TCG Tsareena Ex Premium Collection</h2></div><div catalogid="afe6637a-d53d-44ca-ac56-ba3000400c18" id="210499"><div id="210499" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokemon Trading Card Games Tsareena Ex Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <strong>Pokémon TCG Tsareena EX Premium Collection</strong> is a must-grab Black Friday deal at just $20 (down from $39.99), making it a standout in Walmart’s early sale lineup. Hailing from the <em>Paradox Rift</em> set, Tsareena EX is a Water-type Stage 2 Tera EX with a robust 310 HP and a Bench-damage-blocking ability that ensures durability.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its Icicle Sole attack can reduce an opponent’s HP to 30, setting them up for an easy knockout, while Trop Kick deals a hefty 180 damage, heals Tsareena EX by 30 HP, and removes any Special Conditions, keeping it ready for the fight.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This premium collection includes six booster packs, exclusive card sleeves, and a magnetic display base, offering excellent value for players and collectors alike. With Tsareena EX leading the charge, it’s a deal worth adding to your collection.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">When Is Black Friday 2024?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The actual date of <strong>Black Friday in 2024 falls on November 29</strong> this year, but the deals season will begin a lot sooner than that. Leading up to the big event, retailers will begin to open deals online. This usually <strong>starts in the last week of October</strong>, just before Halloween. Each week leading up to the event will slowly roll out more deals, which ultimately leads to Black Friday. Retailers will not reveal their biggest Black Friday deals until the big day, but most general deals will be available well in advance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Christian Wait is a UK-based freelancer for IGN, you can follow him @ChrisReggieWait on Twitter/X.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 12, 2024 12:46 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Pacifist Who’s Already Hit Prestige Without Killing Anyone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-pacifist-whos-already-hit-prestige-without-killing-anyone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meet-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-pacifist-who%E2%80%99s-already-hit-prestige-without-killing-anyone.1033470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-pacifist-whos-already-hit-prestige-without-killing-anyone<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> is a game all about shooting guns and killing other players. At least, that’s how it’s meant to be played. Not for one determined pacifist, however, who has managed to Prestige without killing a single player.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Redditor Pilgore revealed his in-game stats after reaching Prestige 1, confirming a remarkable 0.00 K/D after 111 games, or 19 hours and 26 minutes of Multiplayer. That means he managed to gain enough experience to level up past 55 and trigger Prestige despite having zero kills. Perhaps even more remarkable, Pilgore achieved the feat with a 1.92 win ratio.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">How did Pilgore manage it? Why do this in the first place? And where does he go from here? IGN interviewed Pilgore, real name John, to find out, and obtained permission to publish one of his matches on the Nuketown map to show off his impressive pacifist tactics. Check it out in the video below.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In short, Pilgore employs a combination of playing the objective (I know, rare for Call of Duty!), and using the Spy Cam Tactical equipment and Scrambler Field Upgrade to gain score during the match, then calls in the UAV, CUAV, and HARP scorestreaks as they become available. Pilgore also shoots down any enemy scorestreaks as soon as they come in. Pilgore does not shoot at enemy players at any point; rather, he plays Call of Duty like the most useful support class you could ever want.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you'd expect, Pilgore has many more victories in objective-based modes such as Hardpoint and Domination than K/D-focused modes such as Team Deathmatch and Kill Confirmed. And if you’re interested in Pilgore1’s Perks, he uses Flak Jacket, Gearhead, and Dispatcher to trigger Strategist, with the Tactical Expert wildcard granting an extra Tactical. "Four Spy Cams can genuinely get you UAV/CUAV on its own," he said.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, why bother playing Call of Duty as a pacifist? It turns out Pilgore has done this before with previous Call of Duty games, joking with a friend that he could Prestige before him even if he got zero kills on Black Ops Cold War. “I enjoyed playing that way so I just kept on going,” Pilgore said. He managed to hit Prestige 15 on Cold War, 10 on Vanguard and Modern Warfare 2, and 15 on last year’s Modern Warfare 3 playing this way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s one hell of an achievement and shows incredible focus and discipline, but one thing that bothers me about all this is how Pilgore was able to avoid killing an enemy player just once, even accidentally. I play a lot of Call of Duty and I’ve often killed enemy players by mistake, simply by either pressing the wrong button at the wrong time, or having a rocket intended for a scorestreak blow up an enemy player who just happened to get in my way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It was definitely risky at the start (previous games) and I got lucky a few times,” Pilgore explained. “I'd throw a Decoy grenade and it would sometimes hit somebody, luckily, it never got me a kill (yet). I've gotten much better at being careful after doing this for 51 Prestiges now. There's almost no worry of it happening this game as the Spy Cam has replaced Decoys for me.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pilgore added that he’s been lucky enough not to have an enemy player jump in his crosshairs while he’s shooting down scorestreaks. And it’s worth noting that the player who calls in a scorestreak gets the kills if it crashes down on other players, so there's no danger of an accidental kill there.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/12/ss-ac03caa8430a111c836669ad53651613069a0c67-1920x1080-1731411855835.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Pilgore spends a lot of time shooting scorestreaks out of the sky. Image credit: Activision Publishing.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I also assumed that it would take an excruciatingly long time to gain enough XP to Prestige while playing as a pacifist, but Pilgore insisted his method is “actually a pretty decent way to get score/XP.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I consistently get at least 7,000 score a match,” he went on. “My tactics haven't really changed over the years. Experimented with different loadouts but the main gameplay has been the same. Earning XP doing this is much better than you'd think.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Keep going until I get a kill or get bored. I have a buttload of patience.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The inevitable next question is what’s next for Pilgore? Perhaps unsurprisingly, given his history playing Call of Duty as a pacifist, there’s no turning back now. “Keep going until I get a kill or get bored,” he vowed. “I have a buttload of patience.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Taking on Zombies mode? We've got <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Essential_Zombies_Tips_and_Tricks">Essential Zombies Tips and Tricks</a> to help you get started, plus a guide on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Exfil_in_BO6_Zombies">How to Exfil</a>. Both Zombies maps are full of easter eggs and secrets; here's everything we've found in both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Terminus_Easter_Eggs_and_Secrets">Terminus</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Liberty_Falls_Secrets_and_Easter_Eggs">Liberty Falls</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Pack-a-Punch_in_Liberty_Falls">How to Pack-a-Punch in Liberty Falls </a>and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Get_the_Meteor_Easter_Egg">How to Get the Meteor Easter Egg</a> in Terminus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Sued After Shutting Down The Crew]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-sued-after-shutting-down-the-crew</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-sued-after-shutting-down-the-crew.1033467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-sued-after-shutting-down-the-crew<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The game was made unplayable in March.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft is being sued by two gamers in California over its shutdown of open-world racing game The Crew in March.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A class action lawsuit spotted by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/476979/ubisoft-the-crew-shut-down-lawsuit-class-action" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polygon</a> was filed November 4 by Matthew Cassell, who bought The Crew from a GameStop in early 2020, and Alan Liu, who also bought it from a GameStop but in November 2018.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Both plaintiffs were "under the impression" they were "paying to own and possess the video game The Crew instead of paying for a limited license to use The Crew." This license over product argument will likely be at the crux of Ubisoft's defence.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>You never knew that the manufacturer could come in one day, and, without your control, leave you with a skeleton of what you thought you paid for.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">"Imagine you buy a pinball machine, and years later, you enter your den to go play it, only to discover that the all the paddles are missing, the pinball and bumpers are gone, and the monitor that proudly displayed your unassailable high score is removed," the lawsuit reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Turns out the pinball machine manufacturer decided to come into your home, gut the insides of the pinball machine, and remove your ability to play the game that you bought and thought you owned. Even though you paid full price to receive this game, you never knew that the manufacturer could come in one day, and, without your control, leave you with a skeleton of what you thought you paid for."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-crew-delisted-from-all-digital-storefronts-servers-shut-down-early-2024">The Crew is, indeed, no longer playable.</a> No version of the game, whether it's physical or digital or even if it's owned already and has been since it launched in 2014, can be bought and played in any capacity. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-adding-offline-modes-to-the-crew-2-and-the-crew-motorfest-but-the-original-is-gone-for-good">Ubisoft has taken measures to create offline versions of The Crew 2 and sequel The Crew: Motorfest</a>, but no similar action was taken for the original, rendering it non-existent.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The lawsuit seeks monetary relief and damages for those impacted by The Crew's shutdown but only time will tell whether it is successful. Ubisoft declined to comment when contacted by Polygon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Storefronts including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/steam-now-warns-customers-theyre-buying-a-license-not-a-game-before-they-continue-to-payment">Steam are now adding an up-front warning to customers that they’re buying a license, not a game</a> ahead of a Californian law going into effect in 2025. The change to Steam came after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/californias-new-law-will-force-storefronts-to-disclose-that-buyers-dont-actually-own-their-digitally-purchased-media">California governor Gavin Newsom signed a law</a> forcing digital marketplaces to make it clear to customers that when they buy media, they only buy a license to that media.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that the new law still doesn't prevent companies from yanking your content away from you, but at least they'll have to warn you about the true nature of your purchase before you click that buy button.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>