<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:48:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza Is the Next Nintendo Switch 2 Game Worth Buying]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-is-the-next-nintendo-switch-2-game-worth-buying</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananza-is-the-next-nintendo-switch-2-game-worth-buying.1248906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Best Buy still has it in stock.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Instead of launching with a new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-3d-platformer-ranked">3D Mario game</a> like many expected, Nintendo opted to create the first 3D Donkey Kong game since Donkey Kong 64, marking the first brand-new DK game since 2014. Donkey Kong Bananza stars the fan-favorite Kong naturally, but it also features a young Pauline, who first reappeared in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/10/26/super-mario-odyssey-review">Super Mario Odyssey</a> back in 2017. Together, the two aim to smash their way to the center of the planet, where wishes are supposedly granted. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Donkey Kong Bananza Is Out Now!</h2><div catalogid="c98403e2-b486-4735-a4e3-b129ab1054cb" id="225410"><p data-cy="paragraph">As you hunt for the hundreds of Banandium Gems scattered throughout each layer of the world, you'll need to open up the terrain using Donkey Kong's abilities. Donkey Kong Bananza completely reinvents the Donkey Kong formula, allowing the titular Kong to smash, break, and crash his way through any terrain. You can choose to smash through an entire wall, take a piece of the wall and throw it, or even surf on a slab of rock.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, Bananza would not have been possible without the power of Nintendo Switch 2. The game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/like-mario-kart-world-donkey-kong-bananza-was-originally-a-switch-1-game-nintendo-confirms">initially began development on the Nintendo Switch</a>, but the team quickly realized that the limited hardware would prevent the game from reaching its potential. This is the best showcase of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/nintendo-switch-2/Nintendo_Switch_2_vs_Nintendo_Switch_Comparison_Chart">Switch 2's hardware</a> yet, especially with the Voxel technology used throughout.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong Bananza is available now for Nintendo Switch 2, with the full game available on the cartridge. If you've yet to pick up the game, now is the perfect time to do so at <a href="https://zdcs.link/z62pyl?object_uuid=432e0149-f0b2-4091-b02d-3bb18f8825c0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Best Buy.</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Noah Hunter is a freelance writer and reviewer with a passion for games and technology. He co-founded Final Weapon, an outlet focused on nonsense-free Japanese gaming (in 2019) and has contributed to various publishers writing about the medium.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 21, 2025 3:36 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-is-the-next-nintendo-switch-2-game-worth-buying]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country – Meet Your Mafia Family | IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mafia-the-old-country-meet-your-mafia-family-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-%E2%80%93-meet-your-mafia-family-ign-first.1248900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Our third "Mafia Monday" in July offers you an introduction to the Torrisi crime family members you'll meet in Mafia: The Old Country, the upcoming prequel to and fourth major entry in the long-running narrative-driven action-adventure series. You play young Enzo Favara as he works his way up in the Torrisi family. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the third entry in our IGN First series of exclusives on Mafia: The Old Country. Be sure to check out the exclusive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mafia-the-old-country-9-minutes-of-exclusive-gameplay-ign-first">gameplay</a> and our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mafia-the-old-country-exclusive-hands-on-preview-ign-first">hands-on preview</a> that we've already posted. And next week we'll have a deep-dive interview with the game director and development studio president about returning Mafia to its linear roots. For now, though, get to know your early-20th-century Sicilian family by clicking through the images and character bios provided by the Hangar 13 development team in the gallery below. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mafia: The Old Country – Meet Your New Family</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Mafia: The Old Country will be released for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S on August 8.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/mafia-the-old-country-meet-your-mafia-family-ign-first]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Has Restocked Pokémon TCG: Black Bolt Elite Trainer Boxes, If You're Willing to Pay the Price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/black-bolt-pokemon-tcg-amazon-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-has-restocked-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-black-bolt-elite-trainer-boxes-if-youre-willing-to-pay-the-price.1248894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">We don't expect this to last long.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Following the combined launch of both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop">Pokémon TCG</a> expansions last week, the new Black Bolt and White Flare Elite Trainer Boxes (ETBs) have been hotly sought after, with prices skyrocketing well above MSRP. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Amazon has recently dropped the price of the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QbbEJo?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Black Bolt ETB to $78.75</u></a>, down from the retailer's inflated list price of $109.99. That's a 28% reduction if you're looking for market price, but still over $28 more than the standard $50 MSRP.</p><div catalogid="cc0b3227-d28a-42b7-bd75-cd5e876cb02f" id="225543"><div id="225543" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokemon TCG Scarlet &amp; Violet Black Bolt Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Just like with recent restocks for Destined Rivals, the main retailers listing Black Bolt &amp; White Flare ETBs at above retail are Walmart and Amazon. <a href="https://zdcs.link/985d5q?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart</u></a> continues to list both at around $99, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJg4gD?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Amazon still lists the White Flare ETB</u></a> for roughly $105, but Black Bolt's price cut is an unexpected bargain in contrast.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, this is still way above what these would normally be priced at. The best-priced among big stores listing Black Bolt &amp; White Flare at their actual value is <a href="https://zdcs.link/QP8r8Z?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Best Buy</u></a>, at $49.99 for each ETB, but both are sold out at the time of writing. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s the same case for the<a href="https://zdcs.link/aXWMWm?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u> Pokemon Center</u></a>, which was listed both for a slightly more expensive $59.00.  Whichever retailer you buy from, though, each Black Bolt &amp; White Flare ETB contains:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Nine respective booster packs</li><li>Full-art promo card — Thundurus with Black Bolt, Tornadus with White Flare<ul data-cy="list"><li>The Pokémon Center version also comes with an extra full-art promo with the website’s logo</li></ul></li><li>65 sleeves for your cards</li><li>45 Energy Cards</li><li>A player’s expansion guide</li><li>Damage counter dice, coin flip-die, and condition markers</li><li>Collectable box with dividers</li><li>Pokémon Trading Card Game Live code card</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The assumed reason for these inflated prices is to both scare off scalpers and bots, since these automatically reduce reseller profit margins, whilst still making the money from those who are still willing to pay. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon UK had implemented its own fairer way of controlling the stock shortage of Pokémon cards by implementing the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-destined-rivals-etbs-are-back-in-stock-at-amazon-uk-for-prime-day-but-theres-a-catch"><u>invite-only system</u></a>, allowing any with an invitation to buy ETBs at their RRP value. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sadly, the US equivalent doesn’t seem to want to follow suit. Still, Amazon and Walmart have technically followed the market value of Pokémon card products like these, even if they are still going a fair amount higher. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On dedicated selling platform TCG Player, for instance, the market price for the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yDEDJ?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Black Bolt ETB</u></a> is around $91 whilst <a href="https://zdcs.link/znxExG?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>White Flare’s</u></a> is almost $92 at the time of writing. eBay also have listings that are a little bit cheaper, showing <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7E4w?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Black Bolt ETBs going for at least $86</u></a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjpE7M?object_uuid=6138f8ba-6961-4be0-a5fc-c0108b2b4a4d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>White Flare for $85</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even going by the most expensive cards from the Japanese version of the set, Black Bolt and White Flare have plenty of valuable potential pulls to make the higher investment worth it, but we know it’s still a major sting knowing you’re paying well above what you should be. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whichever way, though, paying around 50% mark-up at minimum for an ETB appears to just be the name of the game in the Pokemon TCG market these days. If you want to get any of these new cards at the best price available, grab this Amazon deal whilst you can before you have to pay at least $10 more from an eBay seller. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 21, 2025 1:59 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/black-bolt-pokemon-tcg-amazon-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>