<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:22:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Season 1 Trailer Highlights Blackwell Fields and Eastwood Maps Ahead of Next Week's Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-trailer-highlights-blackwell-fields-and-eastwood-maps-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-season-1-trailer-highlights-blackwell-fields-and-eastwood-maps-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch.1331776/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"The world is a tinder box..."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The first <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6"><u>Battlefield 6</u></a> Season 1 trailer is here, revealing a first look at the new Blackwell Fields and Eastwood maps, new weapons, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA and Battlefield Studios published the debut trailer for the Season 1 update ahead of its launch next week, October 28. The two-minute video shows off glimpse of the team’s plans to keep Battlefield 6 content flowing following its strong October 10 launch for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Blackwell Fields spans besieged facilities and homesteads under a burning horizon, supporting all combat sizes with land and air," an official description for the new Battlefield 6 Season 1 maps says. "Eastwood turns a quiet villa and golf retreat into a frontline, with land vehicles and helicopters in play."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today’s Battlefield 6 Season 1 trailer shows off first gameplay on the Blackwell Fields map and Eastwood map, but it also serves as an update for content fans have already been told to expect. BF Studios previously <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-roadmap-revealed-heres-what-to-expect"><u>shared a roadmap for its first seasonal content run</u></a> earlier this month, revealing three waves of updates that are set to roll out from next week through December 9.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/22/image-14-1761146939471.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption"><strong>Battlefield 6 Season 1 Content Roadmap. Image courtesy of EA.</strong></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Things kick off with the Rogue Ops update next week, starting with highlights like Blackwell Fields, the Strikepoint mode, Traverser Mark 2 vehicle, GGH-22 pistol, SOR-300SC carbine, Mini Scout sniper rifle, rail cover &amp; LPVO attachments, and more. California Resistance content then follows November 18, bringing the Eastwood map and Sabotage limited-time mode, as well as a trio of new weapons. Finally, Empire State gets the Ice Lock makeover with the Winter Offensive update December 9. We know it includes at least one new tool in the form of the Ice Climbing Axe melee weapon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players have spent the weeks since launch combing over every weapon attachment, challenge, and camo Battlefield 6 already has to offer. When the community isn't <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-launched-just-hours-ago-and-players-have-already-recreated-call-of-duty-map-shipment-in-portal">recreating Call of Duty maps in Portal</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-engineers-are-becoming-in-game-artists-instead-of-capturing-the-objective">using the Engineer class' repair tool to draw on walls mid-match</a>, they've mostly spent their time encouraging EA and BF Studios to make tweaks to the overall experience. One recent change saw the developers <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-dev-increases-xp-gain-addresses-progression-complaints-and-targets-xp-farms-taking-up-server-space">outline a plan to address feedback regarding challenges, XP, and progression</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Battlefield 6 Season 1 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Today’s Battlefield 6 Season 1 trailer homes in on the content dropping throughout the next month. While we wait to see more, you can read about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-sparks-zoomers-vs-battledads-war-over-movement-but-the-devs-are-looking-for-somewhere-in-between"><u>how EA and BF Studios are keeping tabs on the war between “zoomers” and “battledads.”</u></a> You can also catch up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-devs-say-new-conquest-tweaks-will-improve-the-pace-of-matches-but-fans-have-other-ideas"><u>the recent decision to reduce Conquest ticket sizes</u></a>, which was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-recently-patched-conquest-mode-to-make-the-matches-shorter-the-community-complained-and-now-the-developers-have-reversed-the-decision"><u>quickly reverted following fan outcry</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, be sure to check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/All_Multiplayer_Maps">full list of all currently available Battlefield 6 multiplayer maps</a>. Those looking to brush up on their online skills can also read <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/Multiplayer_Tips_and_Tricks">our multiplayer tips and tricks guide</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-trailer-highlights-blackwell-fields-and-eastwood-maps-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once Upon A Katamari Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/once-upon-a-katamari-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/once-upon-a-katamari-review.1331770/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Miraculously meditative and frantic in equal measure, Once Upon A Katamari scratches the same carnal itch that the rest of the series always has. It delivers relentless charm, a wheeze-laugh-inducing sense of humor, brain chemistry-altering music, and soulfully satisfying-but-simple gameplay in psychedelic technicolor. This time-trotting adventure rolls out the red carpet for The Prince, The King of All Cosmos, The Queen, and their cadre of silly little cousins with flamboyant aplomb. And with more levels and a greater focus on replayability, there’s more Katamari to go around than ever before. The first new mainline Katamari game in 14 years doesn’t try to reinvent the misshapen mass of things you roll around, and that’s fine by me, because Katamari doesn’t need fixing. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At first blush, you probably wouldn’t be able to tell the difference between the original Katamari Damacy from 2004 and Bandai Namco’s latest iteration aside from the obvious jump from 480p to 4K. That’s because developer Rengame understood the assignment: Once Upon A Katamari is just as funny, satisfying, joyful, and energetic as the series has always been.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After showing off his juggling skills with a powerful scroll, the godlike King of All Cosmos flings it into the night sky, yet again destroying the heavenly bodies that inhabit it. It’s up to his son, The Prince, and his cousins to go to Earth and roll up everything in sight to make stars and planets to repopulate the sky. It might not make sense if you haven’t played a Katamari game (or, frankly, even if you have), but this setup has proven as reliable as Bowser kidnapping Princess Peach, and serves as a vehicle for some spectacularly funny stuff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The King, a flamboyant, self-important, all-powerful – though overall benevolent – god who likes to wear really tight pants is beloved by all, even though he talks down to The Prince and his goofy-looking cousins. Making the most of every last syllable of dialogue, I chuckled at least once just about every time he mused on the nature of the universe or paid himself a compliment with his record-scratch-sound voice. Once Upon A Katamari is a masterclass of comedic writing and localization, efficiently using its humor to set up the goal for each level before the rolling starts without ever letting a joke get stale.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Once Upon A Katamari is a masterclass of comedic writing.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Completing a level will often reveal a quick and silly scene showing The King or The Queen getting up to some kind of shenanigans, like rolling a bunch of wild west outlaws into a katamari after a standoff that pays homage to The Good, The Bad, And The Ugly, or The King catching a giant crab and flinging it into the sky. Even failing a level has some cheek to it, as The King berates you for messing up, softening the sometimes frustrating blow of falling short of the goal. Despite this pervasive sense of humor, it never becomes cloying or overly self-aware, reliably delivering a smile at nearly every turn beyond The King’s pompous monologues. The overworld level-select maps are just as full of funny touches, like cats and dogs wandering around the Ancient Greek agora in Spartan armor or a cow sitting at a campfire like a human, warming its hooves next to its owner.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each level takes advantage of just how much stuff there is to find within the seemingly chaotic splatter of candy, flowers, statues, lanterns, and TVs that camouflage a subtle, effortless sense of humor and direction within the madness. Tumbleweeds chase cowboys around in circles, titanic Super Sentai-style heroes practice wrestling their moves on kaiju over the horizon, bears and cows prepare for an all-fronts war, and mummies make TV shows underneath the pyramids. Again: madness. But even in the immense, sometimes overwhelming, chaos of each level, every object you can roll up is placed with deliberate care for either comedic effect or a satisfying sequence, like an octopus wreaking havoc on a pirate ship or bottles of soy sauce set up like bowling pins that will quickly push you into the next weight class so you can finally pick up that bowl of ramen in the other room.</p><div id="rank-every-mainline-katamari-game" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rank Every Mainline Katamari Game</h3><h3>Rank Every Mainline Katamari Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Controlling your designated roller, you’ll whirl your massive ball of stuff around different time periods like the Jurassic period or Edo-era Japan, picking up anything smaller than your dung beetle-like ball. You might start a level the size of a pushpin or matchstick, but you could end it picking up cities or even planets by the end. The classic goal is simply to get your katamari (which literally means clump or mass in Japanese) as big as possible, but sometimes you’ll need to follow special rules. They could be as simple as collecting as many fish as possible, or as complex as only rolling up sweet items while avoiding savory or bitter things like hot sauce or charcoal because the child who asked you to do so wants to eat something sweet after a big meal.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">No matter what you’re picking up, snowballing your <em>katamari </em>into a bigger and bigger collection of books, cannonballs, eggs, and flatware is oddly cerebral. Tapping into the same inexplicably satisfying, brain-scratching sensation you get from games like Tetris or PowerWash Simulator, there’s a zen-ness to decluttering Japanese palaces, Ice Age caves, and the decks of pirate ships washed in a low-poly-day-glo look.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Once Upon A Katamari’s oddly gripping, maximalist soundscape counters this calm with gusto. Different items snap to your odd ball with a satisfying <em>zhoop</em>, with certain things making unique noises like a wailing cat or a street punk scatting, turning your katamari the strangest chorus you’ve ever heard. As you roll up a ball of various odds and ends, Once Upon A Katamari matches your collection with an equally eclectic soundtrack. Inspired by the poppy hodge-podge sound of J-Pop subgenre Shibuya-kei, Once Upon A Katamari’s soundtrack stands shoulder-to-shoulder with the musical giants it’s following as a spectacular album in its own right, with or without a game to accompany it.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The soundtrack stands shoulder-to-shoulder with the musical giants it’s following.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The only unifying themes among the notes are paying subtle homage to <em><strong>the </strong></em>Katamari riff (you know: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M7EXlS9-XpU" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>that catchy one</u></a> that goes na naaa nanana nana na na na na nana naaa) that permanently tattoos itself on your hippocampus after playing any game in this series. Otherwise, Once Upon A Katamari’s soundtrack is a diverse smorgasbord of different sounds and genres, from the energetic techno-rap opening theme, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ns6wGXBFkYc" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Katamari Time</u></a>, to the funk-jazz-fusion jam, Power of Katamari Damacy, to the unexpectedly lovely choral title track from one of the series’ original composers, Asuka Sakai, featuring the San Francisco Boys Choir. There’s not a bad track among the 36-song bunch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But Once Upon A Katamari is happy to oblige your sonic nostalgia for the other games, too, with nearly every track from the series’ 21-year history available in a music selector that has a handful of options to tweak. You can make a playlist of your favorite songs from across the series or loop a specific favorite over any of Once Upon A Katamari’s levels. It’s frustrating that you can’t just play an individual game’s soundtrack in order, and that multiple games are inexplicably clumped together in two separate eras instead of game by game, but the playlist feature at least more or less makes up for those shortcomings. The shuffle feature also has an odd hiccup where whichever song played last starts over when you start the next level. And since some of these levels are shorter than much of the near-100-song tracklist, you might wind up hearing some songs more times in a row than you’d want when choosing shuffle, but you can always select a new song before starting a level to fix that.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Charlie Wacholz’s Favorite Video Game Soundtracks</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Rengame’s surgical approach to recreating the immutable charm of this series deftly avoids the uninteresting pitfalls of hollow nostalgia. Instead of treating iconic levels from the original as gospel doomed to be worn out in every Katamari game like the requisite recreation of 1-1 in the Mario series, nearly every stage here is wholly original. Katamari’s newest custodians toy with the formula with careful precision, supplementing the flow of what I’ve come to expect from a roll-icking good time with new level types and even power-ups to augment your rolling while taking care not to disrupt the delicate balance of calm and chaos that defines Katamari. Combining that with subtle modernizations established in more recent Katamari games, like a clearer scoring system, Once Upon A Katamari threads the needle between old and new surprisingly well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, using both joysticks to control where and how you roll has always been deliberately awkward, with the mass becoming harder and harder to maneuver as you grow exponentially. Once Upon A Katamari makes zooming around at smaller sizes feel a little more precise than it used to, which I didn’t like at first, but this ultimately helped highlight the sense of scale this series has always been good at in bright yellow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The power-ups add a nice layer to the rolling as well, and let Rengame play with new design ideas that emphasize the puzzle element of efficiently finding your way around – even breaking the trance-like flow for a certain level or part of one to instead experiment with puzzle-like problems to solve. The Rocket power-up, for example, helped me brave a powerful wind storm to pick up a few extra items, but only lasted for a short burst of speed, adding an extra layer of challenge and strategy I wasn’t normally used to. The Radar power-up helped me find specific items to complete a pharaoh’s series of requests in one of the Ancient Egypt levels as he asked for 10 bananas or a dozen eggs. None of these drastically reshape or redefine the rolling at Katamari’s core, but do open up new level design ideas that offer fun diversions from the standard “make your <em>katamari </em>as big as possible” levels.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Katamari’s newest custodians toy with the formula with careful precision.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Once Upon A Katamari is by far the biggest game in the series to date, though still relatively small in scope overall - it took me around 10 hours to complete every main level at least once. Rengame acknowledges and helps buttress this with new collectibles to find in each level and unlockable challenges to keep me coming back with a new approach. In addition to finding cousins who serve as additional playable characters and gifts that unlock new customization options for them, three crowns are hidden in each level, adding extra challenges and legitimately compelling reasons to revisit levels. Having a certain number of cousins or crowns will open up extra levels, too, adding even more reason to roll around the same place a few times. Challenges don’t offer the same rewards, but they’re a nice nod to players like me who regularly revisit completed Katamari games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That all said, the stages that are available are unfortunately lopsided, with a majority of the levels taking place in Edo Japan – it holds more than double the amount of levels as the next biggest era. I understand that this series has always embraced Japanese culture, but in the context of Once Upon A Katamari’s time travel concept, it feels like a lot of ground was left uncovered across the nine other eras, some of which only host as few as three or four levels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rengame also builds on the multiplayer modes established in the other Katamari games with the series’ best take on multiplayer to date. While co-op control of a single katamari isn't available this time around, the PvP mode once again has you and other rollers try to pick up the most stuff. But unlike previous entries, you earn points by depositing your hard-earned stuff in a UFO, giving more utility to the new power-ups and adding a more dynamic flow to competition than just rolling as much as possible. Once your time’s up, The King intervenes to hand out bonus points in a Mario Party-style round-up that awards competitors for stuff like the number of times they’ve used a power-up or rolled up their opponents. It’s nothing revolutionary, but a step up that makes multiplayer feel like more than just an afterthought.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/once-upon-a-katamari-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Announces Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 October 2025 Lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-wave-2-october-2025-lineup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-wave-2-october-2025-lineup.1331767/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft has announced Wave 2 of its Xbox Game Pass October 2025 lineup, fleshing out the rest of this month’s titles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting today’s announcement on <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/10/22/xbox-game-pass-october-2025-wave-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox Wire</a> follows <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cancellations-anger-and-frantic-subscription-stacking-the-internet-reacts-to-microsofts-xbox-game-pass-price-hike">Microsoft’s Game Pass price hike and rebranding of some tiers</a>. So, we’re now talking about what’s on Game Pass Premium and Essential, rather than Standard and Core. Xbox Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass keep their names.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Xbox Game Pass Tier and Price Changes, October 2025:</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Xbox Game Pass Ultimate:</strong> $29.99 a month, up from $19.99 a month</li><li><strong>Xbox Game Pass Premium:</strong> $14.99 a month, the same as the old Standard subscription</li><li><strong>Xbox Game Pass Essential:</strong> $9.99 a month, the same as the old Core subscription</li><li><strong>PC Game Pass:</strong> $16.49 a month, up from $11.99</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">So, available today, October 22, on Game Pass Premium, is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/commandos-origins">Commandos: Origins</a> (Cloud, Console, and PC), now with Game Pass Premium. Here’s the official blurb: “Commandos: Origins revisits the six iconic commandos from the original series. Witness elite stealth-tactics gameplay, use your team’s unique abilities to execute complex strategies, and combine your forces in 2-player co-op multiplayer. The battlefield is calling. Do you have what it takes?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also now on Game Pass Premium is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S). “Pursue your aviation career with dynamically generated missions, compete against other pilots, and explore the most detailed digital twin of the world to date. Set out on your global adventure with our largest fleet of aircraft as Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 takes simulation to new heights of authenticity and realism. The sky is calling!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tomorrow, October 23, PowerWash Simulator 2 (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) hits Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass as a day one Game Pass launch. IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/powerwash-simulator-2-review">PowerWash Simulator 2 review</a> returned an 8/10. We said: "PowerWash Simulator 2 smartly sticks to what made the original formula such a blast while throwing in some upgrades to deal with few of its pesky problems."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Also on Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass as a day one title on October 23 is Bounty Star (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S). “Bounty Star is an over-the-shoulder 3D action game that marries mech combat and customization with farming and base building. The player takes on the role of a broken but powerful ex-soldier named Clem, a war veteran, talented fighter and expert mech pilot.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The day one launches continue on October 24 with Super Fantasy Kingdom (Game Preview) (PC) via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass. “Rebuild your kingdom and explore a vibrant fantasy world in this roguelite city builder. Defeat hordes of monsters with a unique team of defenders as you harvest, build, mine, cook, brew, and grow. But if your defenses should fail, be prepared to watch it all burn!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Halls of Torment (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) hits Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, and PC Game Pass on October 28. “Slay hordes of terrifying monsters in this horde survival roguelite. Descend into the Halls of Torment where the Lords of the Underworld await you. Treasures, magical trinkets, and a growing cast of heroes will grant you the power to vanquish these horrors from beyond. How long can you survive?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s a big one: Obsidian’s The Outer Worlds 2 (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) launches straight into Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass on October 29. “The Outer Worlds 2 is the eagerly-awaited sequel to the award-winning first-person sci-fi RPG from Obsidian Entertainment (just look at the exciting number of dashes in this sentence!). Time to clear your calendar – get ready for an action-packed adventure with a new crew, new weapons, and new enemies in a new colony! Pre-order the Premium Upgrade Edition now to get up to 5 days early access, the Commander Zane’s Anti-Monopolistic Battle Pack, DLC Pass for 2 future story expansions, and more!”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And moving into next month, 1000xResist (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) hits Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, and PC Game Pass on November 4. “1000xResist is a thrilling sci-fi adventure. The year is unknown, and a disease spread by an alien invasion keeps you underground. You are Watcher. You dutifully fulfil your purpose in serving the Allmother, until the day you discover a shocking secret that changes everything.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rounding out the lineup is another big hitter: Football Manager 26 (PC) via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass as a day one launch on November 4. “New foundations set the stage for you to define your football destiny. Built on the Unity engine, FM26 is the legacy, redefined and where storytelling evolves, placing you at the heart of the beautiful game. A reimagined interface and more immersive matchday experience brings you closer to the action and combine to elevate every decision and match-defining moment.” This also includes Football Manager 26 Console (Cloud, Console, and PC) on the same day via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 October 2025 lineup:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/powerwash-simulator-2">PowerWash Simulator 2</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) – October 23, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/bounty-star">Bounty Star</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) – October 23, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-fantasy-kingdom">Super Fantasy Kingdom</a> (Game Preview) (PC) – October 24, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/halls-of-torment">Halls of Torment</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) – October 28, Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2">The Outer Worlds 2</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) – October 29, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/1000xresist">1000xResist</a> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) – November 4, Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/football-manager-26">Football Manager 26</a> (PC) – November 4, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/football-manager-26-console">Football Manager 26 Console</a> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – November 4, Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">As always, a number of games leave Xbox Game Pass this month. You can save up to 20% off your purchase to keep playing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Leaving Xbox Game Pass on October 31:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/jusant">Jusant</a> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metal-slug-tactics">Metal Slug Tactics</a> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/return-to-monkey-island">Return to Monkey Island</a> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-wave-2-october-2025-lineup]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The Game We Are Making Now Is a Nintendo Game' — Metroid Prime Producer Kensuke Tanabe Reveals Creative Tensions With Retro in New Book]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-we-are-making-now-is-a-nintendo-game-metroid-prime-producer-kensuke-tanabe-reveals-creative-tensions-with-retro-in-new-book</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-game-we-are-making-now-is-a-nintendo-game-%E2%80%94-metroid-prime-producer-kensuke-tanabe-reveals-creative-tensions-with-retro-in-new-book.1331764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo and Retro Studios brought Metroid into stunning 3D with 2002's Metroid Prime, rebooting the series in a first-person shooter style through a sometimes challenging but ultimately fruitful relationship between Japanese and Western teams -- each with their own unique backgrounds and perspectives. But it wasn’t always smooth rolling for Samus along the way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s according to a new book: Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective, in which Metroid Prime series producer Kensuke Tanabe comments throughout, sharing memories and insights from his perspective working with the U.S.-based Retro Studios on a Metroid game. This was a significant cross-seas, collaborative effort for Nintendo. Retro was working on a completely separate first-person game before series producer (and Super Mario and The Legend of Zelda creator) Shigeru Miyamoto proclaimed it should be a Metroid game. Metroid Prime was thus born. Tanabe recalls: “Metroid Prime was not a project that was originally planned. It was a title that came about by chance, as a result of Mr. Miyamoto clarifying the direction Retro should take… In a way it could be called a miracle.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The game we are making now is a Nintendo game.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Tanabe frames the relationship between Retro Studios and Nintendo as ultimately hierarchical, with Nintendo having final say. “...Nintendo retained the final decision-making authority, there were many instances early on where our approaches to the specifications did not align, leading to disagreements. Retro often explained, ‘This is how Western studios approach and think about game development.' To help them understand our perspective, I told them, ‘Yes, but the game we are making now is a Nintendo game, and this is Retro’s first time working on one. I’ve been working on Nintendo games my whole career, so I believe I have the most experience in making Nintendo games. So please trust me first.'”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This led to creative tensions, with Retro holding its ground, clearly unwilling to totally cave to Nintendo. “One day, during a video conference about the Meta Ridley battle, our discussions kept clashing, and we couldn’t find common ground," Tanabe continued. "Time slipped away and by the time the meeting (which had started in the morning) finally ended, the sun was setting.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Tanabe describes a Retro Studios that needed to be introduced to a set of design philosophies unique to Nintendo, for example enemy design beyond bosses was something Miyamoto had strong feelings about. “Many Nintendo developers have learned from Mr. Miyamoto that the appearance of enemy characters should be designed based on functionality… this had not yet been articulated quite so concisely. As a result, it took time for us to convey the concept clearly to Retro.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see the collaboration working well in some cases, for instance, Retro won out in the implementation of morph ball rolling. In Metroid Prime, you generally view the game through Samus’s visor in first-person fashion, but for puzzles and tight spaces, Samus can transform into a rolling Morph Ball at which point the camera zooms out to third-person. Tanabe says of this: “The transition animation for shifting from first-person Morph Ball mode was proposed by Retro …however Retro also suggested a skip feature to reduce morphing time, but Mr. Miyamoto directed that it should be unskippable, as it was one of the opportunities to view Samus in third-person.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It seems that Retro really pushed hard for the rolling mechanic to be expanded and ultimately won out, in an example of Nintendo relenting in the face of a great idea. Tanabe says: “Retro also proposed the mechanic of rolling through half-pipes in Morph Ball mode. Initially, Nintendo was skeptical, questioning whether it would actually be fun. However, Retro responded, ‘Please try it first before deciding.’”</p><div id="nintendo-series-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Nintendo Series Tier List</h3><h3>Nintendo Series Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The exchange of ideas and a willingness for teams to learn from one another paid off ultimately in a game IGN called a "must-have masterpiece” and which, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-remastered-review"><u>for the 2023 remake, I scored a perfect 10/10</u></a>. Tanabe reflects: “[The Metroid Prime Trilogy] was made possible by Retro maximizing the hardware’s potential through expert engineering, incorporating countless ideas without compromise to refine game design, and setting new standards for graphics in Nintendo titles.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective is out October 28, 2025 and shares hundreds of pieces of concept art from the trilogy across Gamecube, Wii, and the Prime remake on Nintendo Switch. Comments from Retro Studios accompany Tanabe’s frequent notes, along with text taken from the game’s ample expository logs and scans. Metroid Prime 4, the latest team-up between Retro Studios and Nintendo, is set for Nintendo Switch 1 and Switch 2 on December 4, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Samuel Claiborn is IGN's managing editor and a fixes/breaks ancient arcade and pinball machines in his garage. TCELES B HSUP to follow him </em><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/Samuel_IGN" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@Samuel_IGN</em></a><em> on Twitter.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-we-are-making-now-is-a-nintendo-game-metroid-prime-producer-kensuke-tanabe-reveals-creative-tensions-with-retro-in-new-book]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>