<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:22:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Subnautica 2 Developer Breaks Silence After Shock Removal: 'To Find That I’m No Longer Able To Work At The Company I Started Stings']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ousted-subnautica-2-developer-breaks-silence-after-shock-removal-to-find-that-im-no-longer-able-to-work-at-the-company-i-started-stings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ousted-subnautica-2-developer-breaks-silence-after-shock-removal-to-find-that-i%E2%80%99m-no-longer-able-to-work-at-the-company-i-started-stings.1237581/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">&nbsp;"We know that the game is ready for early access release and we know you’re ready to play it."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the co-founders of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/subnautica-2"><u>Subnautica 2</u></a> studio, Unknown Worlds, has released a statement about last week's "shock" decision to replace the leadership team, saying the decision to oust them "stings."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a heartfelt post, Charlie Cleveland revealed on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lryw9o/what_is_a_wave_but_a_thousand_drops/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit</u></a> that while he and his colleagues believed Subnautica 2 was "ready for early release," "that decision is in Krafton's hands." A recent <a href="https://unknownworlds.com/en/news/subnautica-community-letter" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>statement</u></a> from the publisher, however, intimated a release was not imminent as an update about the release schedule, including an "Early Access timeline," would be "coming soon."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though not an explicit comment, the discrepency perhaps shows a disconnect between Krafton and the studio's original management.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Krafton's statement also addressed other community concerns, such as the potential introduction of microtransactions, writing: "Nothing has changed with how the game is structured. It will remain a single-player first experience, with optional co-operative multiplayer. No subscriptions. No loot boxes. No battle pass. No microtransactions."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pubg-parent-company-buys-subnautica-studio"><u>Krafton acquired Unknown Worlds in October 2021</u></a> and at the time, <a href="https://krafton.com/en/news/press/krafton-inc-to-acquire-unknown-worlds-the-developers-behind-subnautica-and-natural-selection/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said</u></a> the Sabnautica studio would continue to operate as an independent outfit. Last week, however, former Striking Distance CEO, Steve Papoutsis, joined Subnautica 2 developer Unknown Worlds as CEO. The shock announcement confirmed that the previous leadership team — Ted Gill, Charlie Cleveland, and Max McGuire — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/subnautica-2-developers-entire-leadership-team-replaced-in-shock-move-krafton-said-will-bring-renewed-energy-and-momentum"><u>were replaced "effective immediately</u></a>."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cleveland didn't explain what led to the team being removed, nor commented on Papoutsis' appointment as CEO.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"[Y]ou can see why for Max, Ted, myself, the Unknown Worlds team, and for our community, the events of this week have been quite a shock," Cleveland wrote on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lryw9o/what_is_a_wave_but_a_thousand_drops/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit</u></a>. "We know that the game is ready for early access release and we know you’re ready to play it. And while we thought this was going to be our decision to make, at least for now, that decision is in Krafton’s hands. And after all these years, to find that I’m no longer able to work at the company I started stings.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I want you to know that whatever happens to the founders, to the team and to the game, our priority is, and has always been, to make the best damned game we can for the best community in the world. With your Gorge plushies and your hand-drawn fish fan-art, and yes, your hard-earned dollars, you’ve supported us in every way, in every season, cold and warm, since Half-Life modding was even a thing."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ousted-subnautica-2-developer-breaks-silence-after-shock-removal-to-find-that-im-no-longer-able-to-work-at-the-company-i-started-stings]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3's Karlach Voice Actor Says Character Was 'a Piece of Work in Hell']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3s-karlach-voice-actor-says-character-was-a-piece-of-work-in-hell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3s-karlach-voice-actor-says-character-was-a-piece-of-work-in-hell.1237578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Karlach's greatest, rage-filled monologue is "the core of her" according to Samantha Béart.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fan-favorite <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur's Gate 3</a> character Karlach is almost universally beloved for a number of reasons — chief among them, her cheery, sweet, and playful personality. But according to her voice actor Samantha Béart, that upbeat exterior belies something far, far darker, shaped by time spent in the bowels of Hell itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/samantha-beart-interview-karlach-baldurs-gate-3/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with The Gamer</a>, Béart spoke about their time playing Karlach, including the recording process and some very specific plot points. Béart specifically goes in deep on one of Karlach's late-game monologues, delivered after a character who has essentially ruined Karlach's entire life and future is finally dealt with.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Warning! </strong></em><em>Spoilers for Baldur's Gate 3 lie ahead. Read on at your own risk.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those who have played Baldur's Gate 3 and seen Karlach's story through know where this is going. Karlach is a tiefling who, prior to the events of the game, has spent a decade in Hell thanks to a fellow named Gortash, who sold her to an archdevil and replaced her heart with what amounts to a bomb that will eventually, inevitably kill her sooner rather than later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That time in hell will really mess with a person, Béart says. So while most of the player's interactions with Karlach are jovial, that's Karlach making a choice to become someone better — it's not who she's always been.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“For me, [Karlach's story is] a redemption arc,” Béart said. “I think she was a piece of work in hell. She would have had to be [...] It was life in prison. That's where I was in my head with that, because otherwise, it's quite hard to relate it to something realistic. You just think about how people behave in those very small communities. Essentially, I think you can completely change to survive.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When the player finally slays Gortash, Béart as Karlach delivers an incredible monologue unleashing all the pent-up rage, sorrow, and fear that Karlach has felt from spending all that time in Hell and facing her own inevitable demise. It's a really fantastic scene, and according to Béart, that monologue is at the center of who Karlach is:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That's the core of her. That's the bit of her she's been hiding until she can't anymore,” Béart explained. “It's a piece I auditioned with, so I always knew it was coming. When it did happen, all the gates were off. All the ugliness can come out. It was a very satisfying and cathartic experience to film."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Béart added that this side of Karlach is absolutely something they discussed with Larian during recording, so even during Karlach's most upbeat moments, that undercurrent of pain still exists, which is perhaps why Béart's performance throughout is so effective.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In fact, it's in no small part thanks to performances like Béart's that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-review">we gave Baldur's Gate 3 a 10/10</a>. "With crunchy, tactical RPG combat, a memorable story with complex characters, highly polished cinematic presentation, and a world that always rewards exploration and creativity, Baldur's Gate 3 is the new high-water mark for CRPGs," we wrote. Sadly, Larian recently said goodbye to active development on the game with its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-notes-include-final-farewell-message-as-larian-looks-ahead">final major patch in April</a>, as the studio moves onto new projects.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3s-karlach-voice-actor-says-character-was-a-piece-of-work-in-hell]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>