<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:44:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['What the Duck Is This?' — Arc Raiders Duplication Glitch has Players Running Into Hoarders With Hundreds of Squeaky Bath Toys]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/what-the-duck-is-this-arc-raiders-duplication-glitch-has-players-running-into-hoarders-with-hundreds-of-squeaky-bath-toys</link>
            <guid>1421656</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">A new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders"><u>Arc Raiders</u></a> duplication glitch has fans worried about exploits, but others just want to know why it’s being used to spawn mountains of rubber duck trinkets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-big-arc-raiders-update-of-2026-adds-solo-vs-squads-matchmaking-bird-city-and-more-tomorrow">Headwinds update</a> brought new content, alongside fresh gameplay tweaks, when it launched for Arc Raiders players across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S earlier this week. While the 40+ level matchmaking option, Solo vs. Squads, was positioned by developer Embark Studios to be its big selling point, some players are more concerned with the return of an item duplication exploit and how it has affected the in-game (duck) economy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although players are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qqb1oq/evidence_of_a_bp_duplication_glitch_in_matches_we/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">no doubt</a> using the dupe glitch to amass piles of rare items like blueprints, it seems a few fans are manipulating the system to make some serious coin – and maybe even a quick joke. The duck has slowly become a bit of a running gag for fans on its own, as the squeaky bath toy is one of a few lightweight trinkets that can be found topside and then sold in Speranza for a decent chunk of Raider Coins. It also happens to be the sillier items in Arc Raiders, so when a recently patched dupe glitched returned in a new form, those looking to exploit the system knew just what to do.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those who are discovering topside players with hundreds of ducks, however, are just confused.</p><p>Did we come across the duck Santa Clause or something?<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Did we come across the duck Santa Clause or something?” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qmdxju/what_the_duck_is_this_we_found_two_dead_raiders/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user said</u></a> a few days before the launch of Headwinds. “Dupe hacking gone wild? At first we thought it was some joke because the stash was just full of ducks but then we realized they were stacks of 15 ducks each.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Okay so I actually came across a guy in blue gate in a random house just spamming ducks on the ground,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qmdxju/comment/o1lccl2/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a>. “I assumed he was duping. The floor was littered with them, probably like 100 of them. He wouldn't respond and kinda just stared at me til I walked away.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders’ mallard problem has only gotten bigger in the aftermath of Headwinds, as the January content update also introduced a handful of more valuable (and more vibrant) ducks to collect as part of the new Bird City map condition. It’s resulted in an abundance of ducks across Buried City…and some very awkward moments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“A raider caught on fire in Buried City Metro, went down without saying a word, and left behind a mountain of Familiar Ducks,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qqv3yd/a_raider_caught_on_fire_in_buried_city_metro_went/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>user shared</u></a>. “I extracted with $2.8M. Still confused.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Was doing the pharmacist quest for Lance, heard the tell tale duck noise...came upon this silent raider,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qpvg2q/random_encounter/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>person said</u></a>, sharing a picture of a solo Raider standing alone in a dark attic.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Referencing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-and-the-finals-hit-by-extensive-coordinated-ddos-attacks-dev-says"><u>a recent cyber-attack</u></a> against Embark and Arc Raiders, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qpvg2q/comment/o2cofp8/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>someone replied</u></a>, “This must be what brought down the servers. DDOS (Duck Duplication on Server).”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a game that constantly sees players backstabbing each other for a small chance to net worthwhile resources, it’s hard to deny the comedy in PvP players only finding stacks upon stacks of little rubber duckies. Still, it’s definitely the kind of thing Embark <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-promises-significant-changes-after-players-report-widespread-issues-with-cheaters">promised to clean up earlier this month</a>. Players have complained of cheaters and exploiters in Arc Raiders for weeks, so as goofy as these issues are, they are still causing some players to worry that others have an unfair advantage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's especially concerning for those who have kept up with Arc Raiders updates since launch. Embark <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/patch-notes-1-12-0" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">issued update 1.12.0</a> January 20 and fixed a handful of exploits, including an item duplication glitch. It took less than a week for players to begin reporting what appears to be a new version of the exploit, and it's unclear how long it will take for the developers to publish a new patch or how many other glitches will be discovered in the meantime.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Arc Raiders cheater crackdown has seen <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-update-targets-infamous-stella-montis-glitch-but-some-say-rats-are-still-in-the-walls">holes plugged in Stella Montis</a> to try and ward off wall explolits, while some players, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/streamer-tfue-hit-with-30-day-arc-raiders-ban-amid-cheater-purge-then-immediately-unbanned">like streamer Tfue</a>, have found themselves banned (and then unbanned) without notice. As Embark tries to bring cheats to a halt, players are still finding the fun both in and outside of the game. Some have even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/please-try-to-be-friendly-to-other-guests-arc-raiders-players-bombard-real-life-stella-montis-hotel-with-5-star-reviews">looked to the real-world Stella Montis hotel to leave positive reviews</a>. Others are just enjoying Headwinds while they wait for everything else promised in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-roadmap-promises-a-new-map-more-arcs-and-even-a-little-love-for-scrappy-by-april-2026">the 2026 roadmap</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, you can read about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-good-loot-is-actually-bad-loot-and-that-needs-to-change">why we think the best Arc Raiders loot needs a serious buff</a>. You can also check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-says-players-who-spawn-late-dont-realize-they-economically-profit-way-more-than-players-who-dont">why Embark believes players who spawn into a raid late actually benefit more than most</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qqv3yd/a_raider_caught_on_fire_in_buried_city_metro_went/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>endgame2937 / reddit</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/what-the-duck-is-this-arc-raiders-duplication-glitch-has-players-running-into-hoarders-with-hundreds-of-squeaky-bath-toys]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google's Project Genie Seemingly Causes Some Investors to Lose Faith in Roblox, Unity and...GTA 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/googles-project-genie-seemingly-causes-some-investors-to-lose-faith-in-roblox-unity-andgta-6</link>
            <guid>1421623</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Just one day after the announcement of Genie, Google's generative AI-powered virtual world creator, a number of major video game companies are seeing their stock prices tumble, seemingly because some investors think you can just generate an entire video game with AI now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, that's not what Genie is. Genie essentially lets you create a virtual "world" by offering prompts to describe the environment, a main character, and first or third-person view. Once it's created, you can control the described character and wander around the world you've made.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And that's...kind of it? While you can walk around these virtual spaces with your keyboard, critically, there's nothing else you can really do. There are no game mechanics, there's no one to talk to, no goals, no scores or meaningful interactions. Additionally, each generation is limited to just 60 seconds. And while you could maybe argue that this is just the first step on a road to eventually getting AI to generate playable 3D video games, there's no real evidence yet that such a thing is possible, or that the games would be good or even coherent. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/869726/google-ai-project-genie-3-world-model-hands-on" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Verge</a>, for instance, tried to basically copy Breath of the Wild using Genie, and while they got something that essentially looks identical, that's just it. It's not playable, the "Link" looks kind of frightening actually, and Genie had to copy something that already existed to make this. It didn't come up with this on its own. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But that hasn't really stopped a lot of investors from suddenly jumping off the video game train, a conclusion first posed by <a href="https://ca.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/unity-stock-falls-alongside-taketwo--roblox-after-googles-project-genie-launch-4429665" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Investing.com</a> and shared by others, including <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3mdnsmltgmk2f" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg journalist Jason Schreier</a>. Perhaps the most notable decline is Take-Two Interactive, which reached a six-month low this morning and, while it rallied somewhat by the closing bell, still ended down 8%. Engine maker Unity is in a similar spot, dropping 24% today also to a six-month low. Roblox stock also cratered today by 13% by close today, though notably Roblox has been on a downward trend since November. Still, it's a six-month low for Roblox, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not every gaming company is seeing a massive nosedive. Ubisoft is technically down 7% today, but with its stock down to just $1/share, any small movement in either direction will seem significant. The company has been in pretty dire straits for months, even years now, and its announcement of more layoffs, closures, and cancelations earlier this month already had stock even further in a downward spiral. EA stock hasn't changed much today at all, but that's understandable, given EA announced last fall that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-goes-private-in-55-billion-deal-with-pif-silver-lake-and-affinity-partners-andrew-wilson-to-remain-as-ceo">it was preparing to sell</a> to an investor group headed up by the Saudi Arabian government and will soon exit the public trading market. Meanwhile, Nintendo stock, down just under 5% today at the time this piece was written, has been all over the place all month, following a steady downward trend since November. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The pattern I'm seeing here between Take-Two, Roblox, and Unity is a sudden distrust not in games as an idea, but rather concerns about "platforms". Unity is a game engine. People use it to make games. If Genie can also make games, who needs Unity? In Roblox's case, Roblox is a pure user-generated content (UGC) factory - something that would likely become obsolete quickly if Genie took over. And for Take-Two, the publisher is about to release Grand Theft Auto VI later this year (we hope), which would very likely be accompanied at launch or not long after with some new version of GTA Online. While the current GTA Online doesn't rely on UGC, there have been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-launches-official-user-generated-content-marketplace-for-mods">recent suspicions this new version might</a>. Again, the thinking here is seemingly that if people can just make their own little games in Genie, why would they bother doing it in Roblox or GTA or Minecraft or Fortnite or Unreal or anywhere else (Microsoft, for its part is too big to see any stock impact from Genie today and Epic Games is not publicly traded).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Is selling shares of major game publishers going to pay off for these investors? I'm not a stock expert, but if nothing else, it doesn't seem to be like a good idea to bet against GTA 6 right now (though Take-Two's earnings are next week, so we'll see I guess). And while Genie doesn't seem up to the task of making a whole video game out of nothing, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/larian-ceo-responds-to-divinity-gen-ai-backlash-we-are-neither-releasing-a-game-with-any-ai-components-nor-are-we-looking-at-trimming-down-teams-to-replace-them-with-ai">plenty</a> of other <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/runescape-developer-jagex-insists-no-generative-ai-will-ever-be-present-in-any-asset-that-a-player-can-touch-hear-or-feel">studios</a> are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-create-hundreds-of-thousands-of-unique-ideas-needed-to-build-in-game-environments">coming out</a> on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-publisher-defends-generative-ai-use-insists-every-game-company-is-now-using-it">one side of the fence</a> or the other on using generative AI of any kind in their work. It seems that one way or another, the folks betting big money on generative AI will reap whatever harvest of that investment there is sooner rather than later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/googles-project-genie-seemingly-causes-some-investors-to-lose-faith-in-roblox-unity-andgta-6]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Magic: the Gathering Players Attending Lorwyn Eclipsed Pre-release Events Got an Unwanted Surprise: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/some-magic-the-gathering-players-attending-lorwyn-eclipsed-pre-release-events-got-an-unwanted-surprise-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles</link>
            <guid>1421617</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Two weeks ago, I happily attended my first-ever pre-release event for a new Magic: the Gathering set. This was for Lorwyn Eclipsed, which veteran players inform me is a long-awaited return to the fantasy stylings of Magic's Lorwyn plane after nearly 20 years. As you can imagine, there were a lot of long-time Magic fans who were <em>very</em> excited about this release, but in the minutes before my pre-release event began, I kept overhearing a tone of anxiety in the conversations around me.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The cause of the anxiety? Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you've never been to a pre-release event, what happens is this: you're given a nice little box that contains several booster packs, which you will use to build a deck for the event and play some matches with other attendees. The boxes also tend to contain other goodies, which in the case of Lorwyn Eclipsed involved a deck box, a die, and a single foil card from the set. The foil you get is random, but it's <em>supposed</em> to come from the set you're there to play. And when I opened my box, that's what I encountered. A nice little foil of Shadow Urchin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But the reason for the anxiety at the event was because word had gotten around that some people were <em>not</em> receiving Lorwyn cards as their foil promo card. Instead, a number of social media posts had been circulating showing players with six Lorwyn Eclipsed booster packs and one foil card from the upcoming Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, this is quite the mix-up! Not only is TMNT, uh, <em>very</em> different from Lorwyn, but the TMNT set isn't even supposed to be out yet. It's coming on March 6, just under two months from the date this was happening. So not only was this causing an issue for Lorwyn fans, but TMNT fans excited for the upcoming set were now getting previously unrevealed cards shown off via random social media posts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This situation also complicated the event itself: normally, a TMNT card would not be legal in a Lorwyn Eclipsed pre-release deck. Fortunately, Wizards of the Coast <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/magic.wizards.com/post/3mclkkr2dka2k" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">issued a statement</a> pretty quickly about the situation, saying that stores should replace the TMNT promo cards where possible with Lorwyn cards. Where not possible, players would be allowed to play with the TMNT cards. That... sort of helps, but the fact is that Lorwyn Eclipsed cards are part of a set that's meant to be played together, with cards and mechanics that coordinate with one another to create a balanced game. A single TMNT card is more likely than not going to struggle to fit into decks like that. What's more, shops would have to break into unsold pre-release boxes to take out the replacement foil cards, which essentially just eats through inventory for no reason.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, you could argue, it's just one card! Who cares! And that's fair. But another sentiment I heard both online and at the event I attended was that the turtle invasion felt like a slap in the face to veteran Magic players. Not only has the wait to return to Lorwyn been long, but some long-time players have grown frustrated at how many collaborations with outside IP (dubbed "Universes Beyond") Magic has been doing lately. Wizards has been doing these crossovers since 2020, though at the time Universes Beyond cards weren't planned to be made legal in the Standard format and many of the ones that followed were just reskins, making them fairly easy to put up with if you didn't want to see Transformers or Doctor Who in your Magic game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But starting last year with Final Fantasy, that changed. The wildly popular Final Fantasy set was dubbed Standard-legal, and this year, Magic is getting more Universes Beyond sets than ever before: TMNT in March, Marvel in June, The Hobbit in August, and Star Trek in November. That's four standard sets - more than Wizards is releasing of non-Universes Beyond sets, of which we are only getting three: Lorwyn Eclipsed, Secrets of Strixhaven, and Reality Fracture. This is a lot to keep up with both mentally and financially, and while you could argue there's no pressure to "keep up," there is if you play the game's Standard format, which always revolves around the most recently-released sets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's also worth noting that groups of fans aren't the only ones who are annoyed here. Recently, shareholders of Wizards' parent company, Hasbro, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lawsuit-claims-hasbro-misled-investors-regarding-sales-of-controversial-magic-the-gathering-anniversary-set">filed a lawsuit against it</a>, alleging that it was overprinting sets of cards, thereby devaluing ones that already existed. In the suit, shareholders also claimed Hasbro had previously done some fairly manipulative things with Magic card sales to cover up shortfalls elsewhere in the company. Regardless of whether or not anything comes of the lawsuit, there are some pretty hefty accusations in the complaint that would understandably sow further distrust among those who already felt Magic was overplaying its hand.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, back to the pre-release event, you can imagine perhaps being a long-time Magic fan, excited for the return of Lorwyn, ready to play some games involving elves and fairies and merfolk, maybe rubbed the wrong way a bit by the sheer volume of Universes Beyond but trying not to let it bother them, only to open their pre-release pack and find "Michelangelo, Weirdness to 11" in shiny foil. Doesn't feel great. Heck, I've only been playing a year, and I breathed a sigh of relief when my pre-release pack (and, in fact, my entire card shop) was decidedly turtle-free.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To their credit, <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/announcements/on-turtles-faeries-and-the-lorwyn-eclipsed-prerelease" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wizards has acknowledged fan frustrations and is trying to make good</a>. In a lengthy blog post written by communications director Blake Rasmussen, he apologized for the "shell shock" of seeing a turtle in a Lorwyn box. "We wouldn't blame you if you found it cool, but maybe a bit rude, that Lorwyn Eclipsed had to share the spotlight with an upcoming set," the post reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In response, Wizards went ahead and updated its image gallery to include official art of all rares and mythic rares from the main set. "They're already out there if you know where to look, and we'd rather you have them all in one official place," the post reads. "It's ready for you now if you want to take a look."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rasmussen also announced plans for some sort of make-good event for the stores that had to deal with turtles at the event, though they weren't clear as to what that would look like just yet. Here's what he said:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Then, to keep the Lorwyn Eclipsed party going, we're going to do—something. We're playing catch up a bit and we wanted to get this article out sooner rather than later, but we're assessing how widespread the issue was and working on some kind of cool, back-end, Lorwyn Eclipsed-related thing we can do for affected stores because we're really proud of this set and we want to make sure it gets its time in the sun. We're going to figure said thing out and get back to you all."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The response to this from the community has been mixed. A lot of people weren't mad about the turtles to begin with. Universes Beyond, some argue, is a great way to get new players into the hobby who might not have otherwise noticed Magic before. Some others who were annoyed with the turtles appear to have been pacified by Wizards' statement and response. Others still aren't happy, believing this is a symptom of a larger problem at Wizards (too much emphasis on Universes Beyond) and an overall lack of care.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We won't really know where the community writ large's heart lies on the broader issues until later this year, when the Magic card deluge has fully arrived and we have a better idea of whether or not people are actually buying all these dang sets. As for Lorwyn Eclipsed, hopefully whatever Wizards is plotting to help assuage the affected stores is appropriately celebratory of Lorwyn, which frankly is a pretty cool setting. I ended up having a grand time at my pre-release event, and will probably attend future ones as a result, provided there are no horror stories of Borg showing up in Strixhaven. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/some-magic-the-gathering-players-attending-lorwyn-eclipsed-pre-release-events-got-an-unwanted-surprise-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Catherine O'Hara, Beloved Actress Best-known for Schitt's Creek and Home Alone, Has Died at 71]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/catherine-ohara-beloved-actress-best-known-for-schitts-creek-and-home-alone-has-died-at-71</link>
            <guid>1421614</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Catherine O'Hara, the beloved actress best known for her roles as Moira Rose in Schitt's Creek and Kate McCallister in Home Alone, has reportedly died at the age of 71.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This comes from <a href="https://www.tmz.com/2026/01/30/catherine-ohara-dead/?adid=social-tw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TMZ,</a> which spoke to two sources with direct knowledge of the matter, as well as <a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/catherine-ohara-dead-schitts-creek-home-alone-1236646029/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Variety,</a> which confirmed with her manager. Variety reports that O'Hara died at her home in Los Angeles, following "a brief illness."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/30/gettyimages-2204017326-1769798331944.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Catherine O'Hara. Photo by Robby Klein/Getty Images</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">O'Hara had a storied career spanning over 50 years, beginning in 1974 as a The Second City cast member in Toronto and moving into sketch shows, cartoon voice work, and eventually various television and film roles. In film, she appeared as Delia Deetz in Beetlejuice, Kate McCallister in Home Alone and Home Alone 2, was the voice of Sally in The Nightmare Before Christmas (a role which she also voices in Disney Dreamlight Valley and Disney Speedstorm), and Cookie Fleck in Best in Show. We <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/frankenweenie-video-interview">interviewed her back in 2012</a> about her role as Susan Frankenstein in Frankenweenie.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In television, O'Hara was best-known for portraying the eccentric Moira Rose in Schitt's Creek from 2015-2020 across all six seasons, a role for which she won an Emmy for Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series, as well as a Golden Globe for Best Actress. She also appeared in numerous other roles, such as Carol Ward in Six Feet Under, Dr. Orwell in A Series of Unfortunate Events, and most recently Patty Leigh in The Studio, and Gail Lynden in The Last of Us. Her final film appearances included as Ruth in Argylle, a reprise of her portrayal of Delia in Beetlejuice Beetlejuice, the voice of Pinktail in The Wild Robot, and as herself in the documentary John Candy: I Like Me.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/catherine-ohara-beloved-actress-best-known-for-schitts-creek-and-home-alone-has-died-at-71]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Update to Alter 2 Controversial Cosmetics After Fans Accuse EA of AI-Generated Content and Call of Duty: Ghosts Inspiration]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-update-to-alter-2-controversial-cosmetics-after-fans-accuse-ea-of-ai-generated-content-and-call-of-duty-ghosts-inspiration</link>
            <guid>1421611</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Addressing more feedback as Season 2 looms.</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield Studios and EA have published <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> version 1.1.3.6 patch notes, revealing the next update will alter the controversial “Call of Duty: Ghosts” skin and a seemingly AI-generated sticker.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Details on the incoming patch, which launches across PC and consoles February 3, were published via the official Battlefield website today. It’s a relatively insubstantial update that targets quality-of-life issues across the experience, but one bullet point tucked under the “Player” changes section makes it clear the developers are still listening to fans as they move toward the delayed launch of Season 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The one-sentence change says the Objective Ace and Winter Warning cosmetics will be altered to “better align with Battlefield’s visual identity.” It’s easy to miss but one of the more important changes Battlefield 6 has received in the last month, as it relates to two of the biggest controversies for the entry so far.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">This definitely looks AI Generated right? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Battlefield6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#Battlefield6</a> <a href="https://t.co/VLYMhEMOqQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/VLYMhEMOqQ</a></p>— Battlefield 6 News (@BF6Updates) <a href="https://twitter.com/BF6Updates/status/2002568867575705950?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 21, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Winter Warning was perhaps the most infamous of the two cosmetics, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-fans-accuse-ea-of-selling-ai-generated-image-after-spotting-what-looks-like-an-m4a1-with-two-barrels"><u>drawing criticism from players who feared it had been generated using artificial intelligence</u></a>. Questionable features, such as unrealistic finger placement and, most notably, a double-barreled M4A1, were what first saw players cast accusations regarding the use of generative AI. In the time since conversation began in mid-December, players still reference Winter Warning as one example of their issues with Battlefield 6.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Objective Ace Assault skin brought upon completely <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1pzqhui/this_is_litteraly_a_cod_ghosts_mask/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>new issues when fans took notice of its mask’s resemblance to the logo for 2013’s Call of Duty: Ghosts</u></a> in late December. What began as poking fun turned into allegations of stolen art when users across social media began to call attention to specific details, such as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1pzqhui/comment/nwtg3o7/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>shared cracks across both designs</u></a> and streaks of paint <a href="https://x.com/DETONATEDcom/status/2006232679943987569?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>that seemed almost identical</u></a>.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Players have noticed similarities between a NEW Battlefield 6 Skin and the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CallofDuty?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#CallofDuty</a> Ghosts Logo 🤔 <a href="https://t.co/fsf5fbBSbK" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/fsf5fbBSbK</a></p>— DETONATED (@DETONATEDcom) <a href="https://twitter.com/DETONATEDcom/status/2006232679943987569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 31, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Interestingly, it doesn’t seem like BF Studios will be removing Objective Ace or Winter Warning, saying only that they’ve been “updated.” Although Battlefield 6 already has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-devs-leave-wicked-grin-skin-almost-unrecognizable-after-community-calls-out-bright-colors">a history of tweaking skins to appease fans</a> in its nearly four-month lifespan, it’s unclear how each cosmetic will be altered to lower the temperature in the community.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also included with Battlefield 6 update 1.1.3.6 are fixes for player movement related to sprint-jump momentum, REDSEC battle royale parachute behavior, and glitch-y destruction, as well as “a handful of UI, audio, and stability issues.” The patch is set to arrive this Tuesday, two weeks before EA attempts to regain its balance with the launch of Season 2. The publisher <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-2-delayed-to-february-as-ea-tackles-community-feedback-with-an-extended-season-1"><u>announced it had chosen to delay the season earlier this month</u></a> amid complaints from fans related to both cosmetics and gameplay as a whole.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the extended Season 1 continues, you can check out the full patch notes for the February 3 update below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Battlefield 6 Update 1.1.3.6 Patch Notes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Update 1.1.3.6 is a small quality-of-life update focused on polish, stability, and targeted fixes across Battlefield 6. It addresses a selection of gameplay flow issues, UI reliability improvements, audio consistency fixes, and map-specific adjustments, with a particular focus on smoothing out edge cases reported by players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The update will be available on Tuesday, February 3 at 09:00 UTC.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Major Updates for 1.1.3.6</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed player movement issues, including cases of excessive sprint-jump momentum and unintended movement behaviour. This won't impact player movement at a large scale and is meant to target those specific edge cases.</li><li>Addressed REDSEC Battle Royale issues affecting insertions, parachute behaviour, and redeploy UI elements.</li><li>Resolved a set of destruction-related visual and lighting issues on Eastwood that could result in lighting artifacts, blackouts, or incorrect colour rendering.</li><li>Fixed a handful of UI, audio, and stability issues, including crashes related to challenges, minimap accuracy, unintended gadget audio playback, and platform-specific problems.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">CHANGELOG</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">PLAYER:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where sprint-jump momentum could behave inconsistently and grant higher or lower momentum than intended.</li><li>Updated the Objective Ace and Winter Warning cosmetics to better align with Battlefield’s visual identity.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">MAPS &amp; MODES</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue on Eastwood where destroying a building near the A flag could cause unintended green or purple visual effects across nearby structures.</li><li>Fixed an issue on Eastwood where destroying a building near the B flag could cause a complete lighting blackout across the map.</li><li>Fixed an issue on Eastwood where destroying the villa near the B flag could cause excessively bright lighting artifacts to appear.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">UI &amp; HUD:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where downed squadmates were shown on the minimap for classes unable to revive them.</li><li>Updated legal text to reflect current policies and requirements.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">AUDIO:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where UAV Drone enemy detection audio could be heard by all teammates instead of only the operator.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">PERFORMANCE &amp; STABILITY:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue on PlayStation 5 where ownership validation could fail during system lifecycle events, causing connectivity issues.</li><li>Fixed an out-of-memory crash on Xbox Series S that could occur when loading Daily and Weekly Challenges.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">REDSEC</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">PLAYER:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where Battle Royale Initiation matches did not end after eliminating the final AI opponent.</li><li>Fixed an issue where parachute deployment could remain linked to the jump leader after breaking off.</li><li>Fixed an issue where players could become stuck mid-air during insertion after progressing through the pre-deploy sequence.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">UI &amp; HUD:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where the Second Chance redeploy icon could incorrectly transfer to a living teammate.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Second Chance redeploy timer refreshed each time the map was opened.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-update-to-alter-2-controversial-cosmetics-after-fans-accuse-ea-of-ai-generated-content-and-call-of-duty-ghosts-inspiration]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aniimo Preview: All the Fun of Creature-Catching With All the Transactions of Gacha]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/aniimo-preview-all-the-fun-of-creature-catching-with-all-the-transactions-of-gacha</link>
            <guid>1421608</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">When you say the words “creature collector,” you already have my attention. I’ve been both curious and wary in equal measures since Aniimo was first announced. I’m far from the only person hungering for a worthy competitor in the creature-collection, monster-taming space, and I’ve dabbled in quite a few. Aniimo looks particularly vibrant, vast, and cutesy to boot. It’s the addition of gacha elements that has had me a little on the fence. If you’ve ever sunk hours into a gacha, you understand the trepidation. Will this be the sort of gacha experience that has me gleefully forking over my credit card info, or resenting every microtransaction?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After about four hours with Aniimo, I’d say I’m still cautiously optimistic. It has all the ingredients of my favorite games: open-world exploration set in a fantastical alien world, lots of critters to collect, challenges to complete, and… farming? Okay, there might be a few too many ingredients added to this pot, but I’m willing to let Aniimo cook.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Big Butts, Tiny Waist</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We leap straight into creating our Aniimo character. I can easily sink hours into a good character creator, so I was pumped to give Aniimo’s a try. From the get-go, the character creator feels super in-depth. I was given six default presets for both a “male” and “female” avatar (not great for all my non-binary pals). You can combine up to three different face presets to get something a little different, or you could just dive head first into the face customization options.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Aniimo Screenshots</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Aniimo’s character creation allows you to adjust the position, prominence, and size of pretty much every facial feature, from your nasal wings to your eyelids. However, it didn’t take me long before I noticed one glaring oversight: skin tone. After searching for a bit, I finally found the options for skin tone buried under all the other menus for “makeup”. Don’t let the three default options take you aback - like it did me - Aniimo won a bunch of points in my book by including a color wheel for unlimited skin tone options.</p><p>Aniimo won a bunch of points in my book by including a color wheel for unlimited skin tone options.<span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, the character customization lost me again in two areas: one, hair options are <em>extremely </em>limited. I can only assume - based on the “fashion” vouchers I saw redeemable later on in my playthrough - that you unlock more hairstyles through in-game currency or progression. Having appearance and cosmetics locked behind gacha mechanics might be expected. The fact that there is only one natural curly hair option - if you can even call it that - available from the start, however, is frankly disheartening.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And second, I was similarly disappointed in the body customization. While I had so much control over fine-tuning the shape of my face, the sliders for body proportions were lacking to say the least. I never expect much in terms of body diversity when it comes to this genre of game, but having to choose between being eerily thin or skinny with a nice butt and boobs was disconcerting.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Which Aniimo Are You?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">With character customization out of the way, I got my first look at my in-game self - and the adorable Aniimo! - in a cutscene reminiscent of a Twitch “IRL” livestream. The livestream overlay, complete with “real-time” chat bubbles from fictional viewers, threw me off a little bit, but luckily, we didn’t linger in the social media influencer realm for long. I found myself in the alien world of “Idyll”, an aptly named "idyllic" planet teeming with lush greenery and charming wildlife with unique powers, called Aniimo.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Our first Aniimo crosses our path - an adorable little fire-type Emberpup - smoothly introducing catch mechanics I’m already plenty familiar with. With an Emberpup at my side, my friend Nico laid down the basics of commanding Aniimo to use their abilities to remove obstacles or solve puzzles in the world. After catching a few more Aniimo and commanding my new pals to charge into deadly combat, the story began in earnest.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">BINI, our little robo companion, is abruptly hijacked by a mysterious glowing D20 die, which pulls me and Nico into some sort of pocket dimension. In these strange ruins, I encountered murals on the wall depicting Aniimo I’ve yet to encounter. Each mural poses a cryptic question, ala a Buzzfeed personality quiz. The reason for this soul-searching became clear once I reached the glowing mural at the end of the path. The depictions of a yellow lion and blue fox in this mural materialized into two tiny Aniimo who can… talk? I was recommended to choose between Helion or Lunara, based on how I answered the murals’ questions earlier.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I really liked being offered a “sorting quiz” to guide me towards which “starter” Aniimo I should choose. After all, the “starter” you choose clearly says so much about you. Only having two options to choose from was a little unsatisfying, though it appears to tie into some sort of “sun and moon” mythology which could be central to Aniimo’s story. I went for Helion, personally, not only because he was recommended, but because of his sassy little personality. With Helion by my side, I was thrown into combat with my first big foe: a giant armored dragon Aniimo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The combat was fun enough for my tastes, if a little button-mashy. I can imagine that timing your dodges and managing your cooldowns might take some deeper consideration as you progress. What really impressed me was the Twining mechanic. Yup, in Aniimo, you actually get to <em>be</em> the creatures. Playing as Helion - rather than just sitting back as a trainer - made for some engaging, brawly combat.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Getting Schooled</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as quickly as I was transformed into Helion and defeated the dragon-type Aniimo, I was thrust into a whole new region. I found myself transported to the Polaris Institute, a futuristic academy devoted to studying Aniimo, located on my home planet of Astra. At this stage of the tutorial, things became a little bogged down in dialogue and instructional demos. To continue my adventure, I needed to become an official student at the Polaris Institute, instead of just a particularly precocious livestreamer, or whatever I was doing before.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">To qualify to be a student, I was strong-armed into a combat simulation, which broke down the bare bones of accumulating “EP” and how to choose Aniimo that are elemental counters. Next up, I received my first free outfit - a school uniform - and sat through a quick Character menu breakdown. When I was finally teleported back down to Idyll with this hot anime guy and his hot wolf Aniimo - don’t judge me, you <em>know</em> that’s exactly what they were going for here - I hunkered down for another round of tutorials. After using the Report Terminal and building my Aniimo loadout, I finally had my first taste of exploration.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">The Creatures</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">This is where I could start to see myself becoming hooked on Aniimo. There’s something so intrinsically appealing about running around a beautiful countryside and stopping to look at every shiny thing on the ground. There are fast travel spots to discover, new areas of the map to unveil, treasure chests to find, and most importantly, Aniimo to catch!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It quickly became clear that catching Aniimo has a bigger role to play than simply filling out your Aniilog or battling other Aniimo. Depending on their elemental type or other abilities, I relied on my Aniimo to help me solve environmental puzzles, like excavating buried treasure chests or floating on geysers of air. Getting to transform or “twine” with my Aniimo had me squealing with joy. Who doesn’t want to be a tiny little rock crab, walking through a field of flowers?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I quickly discovered how foundational the first Aniimo I caught were, as I swam across streams as Skippy, burned thorny obstacles with Emberpup, or glided around as Celestis. This gave me plenty of motivation to constantly be swapping around my “team” of Aniimo for a reason other than battle prowess. As I discovered later, even keeping starter evolutions - or “Lumin” stage - Aniimo is integral to completing some of the challenges and puzzles scattered around Idyll.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I spent a lot of time wandering around the map, catching new Aniimo, and collecting Lumin Amber to upgrade the Branch, a giant dandelion which improves the capture chance in that region, and completing miscellaneous milestone tasks, called “Elite Training”. These tasks felt a bit like chores: open “x” amount of chests, hatch “y” eggs, and so on, but completing them did fast track my level quickly while giving me a solid understanding of the core mechanics of Aniimo.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/30/cubbo4-1769793781632.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">All of the Aniimo I caught while exploring were super cute, if a little… bland. I love some whimsy in my creature-collectors, a healthy mixture of adorable critters with some cursed-looking monstrosities. What’s neat about Aniimo, however, is that there seems to be a bunch of variations in each type. Most Aniimo have branching options for their second or final “stage” of evolution, and on top of the rare “Prismana” Aniimo which can be caught, I found a few fun “alternative” versions with different appearances based around the region I found them in.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">#VanLife Influencer Era</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">A few hours into my playtime with Aniimo, I stumbled upon another of its key features: the RV. After discovering this NPC in the middle of a field, I abruptly found myself the proud owner of my own interdimensional RV. After a quick customization, I was prompted to teleport to the nearest “RV Park”. This vibrant campsite seems to be some sort of meeting place where you can get together with other Aniimo players and show off your own little outdoor deck.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/30/malangel-1769793842657.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">As an aside, it wasn’t until I found the RV Park that I discovered that while - no, you cannot pet your Aniimo (boo) - you <em>can</em> pick up the Aniimo. Huh. That revelation made, I stepped through the interdimensional door in the back of my new RV and entered the “Homeland Space.” I assumed that this would be some sort of home-building mechanic, perhaps allowing me to decorate my own little space or interact with my Aniimo. Instead, I found myself on a small patch of barren farmland.</p><p>While no, you cannot pet your Aniimo (boo), you can pick up the Aniimo. <span><span>“</span></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Homeland tutorial had me clearing up the farm’s clutter and sowing my first seeds. Once grown, I was able to harvest my crops to sell. As reward, I received “Home Coins,” a currency I can only assume is unique to the Homeland section of Aniimo. With only this brief experience to go off of, I’m guessing that the Homeland farming is meant to be a sort of supplemental gameplay element which will let me idly generate currency every day. In exchange for my Home Coins, it appears that I can trade for other important in-game items, such as Eggs, or purchase “RV Welcome Packages”, which I’m hoping offer plenty of RV furniture and customization.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/30/susuta2-1769793861500.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Honestly, the RV and Homeland feel a little discordant with the rest of my Aniimo experience. I love a good farming sim, but I cannot see myself motivated to spend time planting and selling crops every day if my only reward is just a slow grind to purchasing rare materials. Completing order requests just for extra Home Coins and coupons for RV furniture feels like it would quickly become a slog.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, I was pleasantly surprised during my time playing Aniimo. This is exactly the type of game I can see myself sinking hours into exploration and creature-collecting. The Aniimo were super adorable, and getting to play <em>as</em> the creatures you’re collecting is novel enough in itself to keep me interested. In some other areas, including the main story, Aniimo does feel admittedly empty or bland. I don’t imagine I’ll be filling out my entire Aniilog or progressing far enough to reach late-game mechanics. I’m still hyped to download Aniimo on my PC - maybe even on my mobile or Xbox Series X|S - when it releases, so I can run around as a little Nimbi once again.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/aniimo-preview-all-the-fun-of-creature-catching-with-all-the-transactions-of-gacha]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Go Back and Play Morrowind and Tell Me That's the Game You Want to Play Again' — Former Bethesda Veteran Delivers His Verdict on Potential The Elder ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/go-back-and-play-morrowind-and-tell-me-thats-the-game-you-want-to-play-again-former-bethesda-veteran-delivers-his-verdict-on-potential-the-elder-scrolls-remasters</link>
            <guid>1421605</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Why not go and make something new?"</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">A former veteran Bethesda developer has cast doubt on the possibility of a Morrowind remaster in the same vein as the recently released Oblivion remaster, saying going back to play The Elder Scrolls 3 now, over 20 years after it came out, would make fans “cringe.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda is heavily rumored to be preparing Fallout remasters, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-3-remaster-still-on-the-way-report-claims">with Fallout 3 and New Vegas suggested as in the works</a>. But Morrowind — considered by many to be the greatest The Elder Scrolls game ever released — does not seem to be part of the remaster conversation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Why? In an interview with <a href="https://www.pressboxpr.co.uk/news/bruce-nesmith-exclusive-skyrims-design-lead-on-where-he-would-set-the-elder-scrolls-6-and-what-to-expect-from-the-future-of-fallout" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Press Box PR</a>, Bruce Nesmith, who left Bethesda in 2021 midway through the development of Starfield having worked at the company for over 17 years, highlighted a number of reasons why Morrowind probably won’t be top of Todd Howard’s remaster list.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Elder Scrolls Review</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“The problem with doing Morrowind is that I bet they don’t have the original code,” Nesmith said. “The game is so old. I don’t know if the original source code exists anymore. If it does, can you even compile it? When you’re looking at Oblivion, they still had the code. They could still compile it. Putting the code into the new version of the engine was a possibility.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The other thing I would say is go back and play Morrowind and tell me that’s the game you want to play again. We all have these fond memories of things that were pivotal moments in our gaming fantasy histories that we absolutely move but you go back and play a 20 year old game and you will cringe. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“People even had cringe moments with the Oblivion remake but they forgave it because they’re reliving something, they’re enjoying the nostalgia. I worked on Oblivion. I’m even responsible for some of those cringe moments! The further back you go, the more that’s going to be an issue. The reality of playing Morrowind would not stand the test of time, in my opinion. </p><span data-cy="faceoff-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph">“Now if you were to completely remake Morrowind with the Skyrim engine, to try and rebuild it from the ground up, that’s a whole other story, but that’s an entire project. That’s a whole four-year development cycle. Why not go and make something new?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Let's revisit the lands of Morrowind and do a new story. You can include the giant crab palace and all of that stuff but make it new and avoid all the things that would not have survived the test of time.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On that point, Nesmith suggested Morrowind could be an area Bethesda returns to in another game, perhaps The Elder Scrolls 6, alongside Hammerfell, High Rock, and Summerset Isle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“If anything, there's places that would be too interesting,” Nesmith suggested. “I think Elsweyr would be a challenge with its cat people who change the nature of their catness as they mature. That one might be a little challenging to do. But I think pretty much anywhere you go, there's lots of cool, interesting stuff you could do.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesdas-former-elder-scrolls-loremaster-reveals-his-idea-for-the-elder-scrolls-6-story-and-how-it-would-have-set-up-elder-scrolls-7">Bethesda’s former Elder Scrolls loremaster revealed his idea for <u>The Elder Scrolls 6</u> story, and how it would have set up The Elder Scrolls 7</a>. In January last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-announcement-is-now-as-old-as-skyrim-was-when-the-elder-scrolls-6-was-announced"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 announcement became as old as predecessor Skyrim was when The Elder Scrolls 6 was announced</u></a>. Skyrim was released on November 11, 2011, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/11/e3-2018-the-elder-scrolls-vi-announced-at-bethesda-press-conference"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 was revealed on June 10, 2018</u></a> — 2,403 days afterwards. It is now seven-and-a-half years since the announcement, and we’re no closer, it seems, to the release of the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/go-back-and-play-morrowind-and-tell-me-thats-the-game-you-want-to-play-again-former-bethesda-veteran-delivers-his-verdict-on-potential-the-elder-scrolls-remasters]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>