<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:04:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Looks Like the Marathon Release Date Has Leaked via the Xbox Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/it-looks-like-the-marathon-release-date-has-leaked-via-the-xbox-store</link>
            <guid>1409950</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">We already knew that Bungie’s delayed extraction shooter revival, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon"><u>Marathon</u></a>, was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marathon-sets-march-2026-launch-window-and-40-price-point-as-bungie-unveils-new-gameplay">toying with a March 2026 release window and a $39.99 price point</a>, but it seems as though an advertisement on the Xbox Store has prematurely announced the big day: March 5, 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was Redditor TheJuiceBaba who spotted it first, providing a recording of a now-deleted Marathon teaser trailer on Xbox, which ended with: "Coming March 5, 2026. Pre-order now."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In news unlikely to surprise you, shortly thereafter the trailer was yanked from Xbox, and TheJuiceBaba's post is nowhere to be seen (if not quite before people were <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-release-date-leaked-via-xbox-community-page-march-5th-deluxe-edition-available.1409665/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>able to rip and mirror it</u></a>), giving us our strongest hint yet that the trailer could be authentic. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Marathon has certainly endured a troubled development and has suffered multiple delays. At the end of last year, parent company <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-says-bungie-hasnt-brought-in-as-much-money-as-it-thought-it-would-when-it-bought-the-developer-as-destiny-2-falls-off-a-cliff"><u>Sony said Bungie had failed to meet its sales and user engagement targets, resulting in a $200 million impairment charge</u></a>, and the studio <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marathon-developer-bungie-launches-thorough-review-after-once-again-being-found-to-have-used-work-from-an-uncredited-artist"><u>found itself battling yet more accusations of plagiarism back in May</u></a> after an artist accused Bungie of lifting aspects of her artwork for Marathon (the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/artist-who-said-bungies-marathon-had-assets-lifted-from-poster-designs-she-made-in-2017-confirms-the-issue-has-been-resolved">issue has since been resolved</a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last June <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marathon-delayed-as-bungie-promises-to-reveal-new-release-date-this-fall"><u>Marathon was delayed into 2026</u></a> as Bungie worked to respond to feedback from playtests. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungies-ready-to-invite-players-to-try-another-slice-of-sci-fi-shooter-marathon-via-a-new-closed-technical-test"><u>Things went dark until Marathon re-emerged in October</u></a>, when Bungie announced the extraction shooter was ready for a limited, invite-only playtest for players in North America and Europe across PS5, Xbox Series X and S, and Steam.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/it-looks-like-the-marathon-release-date-has-leaked-via-the-xbox-store]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: This Mega Charizard X Ultra-Premium Collection Just Scored a Major Price Drop at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-charizard-x-ex-ultra-premium-collection-phantasmal-flames-price-discount-amazon</link>
            <guid>1409947</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's dropped $100 since last year. But is it still the best deal going?</h2></p><div><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon is continuing its hot streak of tidy <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-phantasmal-flames-elite-trainer-box">TCG deals</a>, and this week has blessed us with a fairly outstanding $100 discount on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mega-charizard-x-ex-ultra-premium-collection-hits-pokemon-tcg-and-its-worth-the-splurge-for-fans">Pokémon TCG: Mega Charizard X ex Ultra Premium Collection</a> that launched alongside Phantasmal Flames at the end of last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can pick it up for just <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxepJd?object_uuid=ec040ff1-4680-4669-9043-d81847984562&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$149.99 ($100 off its $249.99 list price)</a> while stock lasts at Amazon, which is pretty much bang on its current market price (i.e., what most folk are prepared to pay for it/ what it can be reliably sold for).</p><div id="232834"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="232834" data-cy="solo-product-card"><div><p>ME02: Phantasmal Flames (PFL)</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Charizard X ex Ultra Premium Collection</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">That being said, you can also pick it up for around <a href="https://zdcs.link/98PqJq?object_uuid=ec040ff1-4680-4669-9043-d81847984562&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$145 at the trusted resale marketplace TCGplayer</a> right now as well, if you're so inclined to save that extra $8. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You'll need to pay for delivery on top, bear in mind, but it's still a good choice if you're not already packing some Amazon gift cards. Also, if we're making comparisons, Amazon will likely deliver this bad boy faster, especially if you have Prime. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, now that you're packing all the information you need, you can make an informed decision and come away happy. If you're keen on picking it up while the discounts last, here’s a complete list of what’s included in the collection: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>1 foil full-art promo card featuring Mega Charizard X ex</li><li>1 foil full-art promo card featuring Oricorio ex</li><li>65 card sleeves featuring Mega Charizard X</li><li>1 playmat featuring Mega Charizard X</li><li>1 deck box featuring Mega Charizard X</li><li>1 metal coin featuring Mega Charizard X</li><li>6 damage-counter dice</li><li>18 Pokémon TCG booster packs:<ul data-cy="list"><li>2 Surging Sparks TCG booster packs </li><li>4 Journey Together TCG booster packs </li><li>4 Destined Rivals TCG booster packs </li><li>4 Mega Evolution TCG booster packs </li><li>4 Phantasmal Flames TCG booster packs </li></ul></li><li>A code card for Pokémon TCG Live</li></ul><p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pokémon TCG: Mega Charizard X ex Ultra-Premium Collection (Phantasmal Flames)</h3></div></span></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Note, in my opinion, there’s nothing inherently wrong with what’s here, but the selection of booster packs feels just a tiny bit tired. More Phantasmal Flames, or even Mega Evolution packs, would have gone a long way. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Instead, the heavy reliance on Surging Sparks and Journey Together makes the whole thing feel a step behind where it should be. Still, if that isn't an issue for you, than this is the best value going for the latest Ultra Premium Collection online right now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking to just chase cards, however, I'd also recommend checking out how much some of the best single chase cards are going for right now, to pick up individually. Or, to consult after you've cracked open all your packs. Good luck!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's a whole lot more Phantasmal Flames goodies up for grabs right now, at more reasonable prices. But, I'd still recommend checking on TCGplayer to ensure you're getting a good deal, or even just ordering from there altogether, as it often has the best prices.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Best Phantasmal Flames Cards Chase Cards</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">According to marketplaces like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-phantasmal-flames-most-expensive-cards"><u>TCGPlayer</u>, certain Phantasmal Flames cards</a> have already skyrocketed further in price, and, following up from our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-cards-most-expensive-cards">Mega Evolution round-up</a>, we’ve ranked the ten most expensive cards so far just above. From aggressive Mega attackers to powerful evolution support, Phantasmal Flames brings a fiery mix of competitive threats and high-demand pulls. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Anderson is Senior Commerce Editor and IGN's resident deals expert on games, collectibles, trading card games, and more. You can follow him <a href="https://x.com/robertliam21" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter/X or <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/robertliam21.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bluesky</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 19, 2026 12:51 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-charizard-x-ex-ultra-premium-collection-phantasmal-flames-price-discount-amazon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Custodes Are Not Space Marines' — Games Workshop Addresses 'The Telemon in the Room' and Explains Warhammer Lore Behind New Female Miniatures]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/custodes-are-not-space-marines-games-workshop-addresses-the-telemon-in-the-room-and-explains-warhammer-lore-behind-new-female-miniatures</link>
            <guid>1409941</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop has published a Warhammer lore explanation for the existence of female Custodes following a new miniature range announcement on Friday.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">During a preview livestream, the British company behind tabletop wargames Horus Heresy and Warhammer 40,000 revealed new models for the Adeptus Custodes, a faction made up of genetically-engineered, functionally immortal transhumans who work as the Emperor’s bodyguards on Terra. The Custodes are not Space Marines. Indeed, they are bigger, faster, and more powerful than the average Space Marine. And, as we shall explore, they are created in a very different way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop showed off new, eye-catching Custodes models during the livestream, and alongside the male types are female types. While female Custodes had been mentioned in previous Warhammer 40,000 material, and even starred in an official Warhammer animation, their debut in miniature form was enough to set off complaints online from some who accused Games Workshop of retconning the established lore. These people believe the Custodes should remain male only because, they insist, this is what the lore had set out. Some also accuse Games Workshop of pandering to a "modern audience" with the female Custodes, echoing the so-called “anti-woke” rhetoric.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/19/custodes-image2-0ixb1sbgx4-1768821269708.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Female Custodes are now in-game. Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps mindful of this reaction, Games Workshop had a <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/kcuvmezh/new-custodes-your-questions-answered/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lore article</a> ready to go following the reveal. In it, the company explained how female Custodes are made possible and how they differ from Space Marines, which remain male only. The gist, according to this article, is there is no retcon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Lore wise, Space Marines are made from human males, willing aspirants or unwilling conscripts on the cusp of adolescence,” Games Workshop explained. “They are subjected to a series of horrific trials, and the strongest emerge as remorseless killers, their humanity stripped away so they can serve as living weapons in the Emperor’s armies. There are no female Adeptus Astartes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Custodes are not Space Marines. Other than the obvious point that they are both towering, gene-enhanced warriors, the similarities pretty much stop there. Custodes are taken as infants and recrafted by ancient science.The process is arcane and bespoke to each individual. The Emperor himself retained oversight of the process (at least until that whole Horus Heresy thing went down).”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/19/image6-6-u7wp04o8ym-1768821383328.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop also addressed the belief that all the Custodes are made from the sons of Terran noble houses, as set out by Custodes lore established for the 8th Edition of Warhammer 40,000. While some Custodes are made this way, that was not the only source of recruitment, Games Workshop explained.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Other methods might have been equally overt, others far more secretive,” the company said. “Noble daughters could also have been taken, and at some point, you run out of noble houses — even after you’ve conquered all of Terra, the inexorable war machine of the Imperium still requires a constant churn of recruits.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop concluded: “all Custodes, male or female, embody the pinnacle of the genetic and cellular engineering the Emperor employed when creating his armies. They are all flawless creations, pushed beyond the limit of human potential. There is no difference in combat efficacy between a male Custodian and female Custodian.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s safe to say the weekend has been packed with ‘discourse’ following the Custodes reveal. YouTube comments, social media, and subreddits do indeed have many comments from people complaining about the mere existence of these female Custodes models. Some are so upset they’re threatening to leave the hobby behind over it. But it’s important to note that there is a significant pushback on this sentiment from many Warhammer 40,000 fans who have no problem whatsoever with female Custodes and dismiss any retcon concerns.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth remembering that, for all the complaints about retcons, Warhammer 40,000 “lore,” such as it is, has always been an unreliable thing. Indeed, it is built upon the idea that all we know of what was, what is, and what will be comes from <em>a certain point of view</em>. Crucial events are often delivered from a character’s perspective, and that character may have an agenda of their own. The Imperium itself — a rotting, fascist regime built upon 10,000 years of propaganda — twists the facts, if we can even call them such. There is little in the Warhammer 40,000 universe that can be relied upon. That is kind of the point.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And we’ve been here before. The Necrons — now one of the most popular xenos factions in the setting — were once mindless automatons all. Now, we have novels about individual Necrons with more personality than your average agent of the Inquisition. We don’t call the Imperial Guard the Imperial Guard anymore (well, we’re not meant to!). We are to refer to the Guard as the Astra Militarum and not to say another word on it thank you very much.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/19/tithes-1768821769620.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Tithes Episode 2 stars an Adeptus Custodes called Tyrith. Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">From the same 8th Edition Custodes codex that stated all the Custodes are made from the sons of Terran noble houses:</p><blockquote>Not even the most knowledgeable of the Imperium’s scholars can say when the Emperor fashioned the Custodians. The truth is hidden in fragments of the past, accounts of figures appearing in crude hieroglyphs and cave etchings, stasis-locked scads of parchment and gene-sealed tomes that no man now can open.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">And:</p><blockquote>The method by which such remarkable individuals are created has always been known only to those of the Imperial household, and is carried out by the most accomplished chirurgeons and bio-alchemists of Terra within gilded laboratories locked away from the sight of Humanity’s masses. With the Adeptus Custodes fighting only for the Emperor himself, and beholden to the commands and scrutiny of no other, the secrets of their recruitment have never been revealed, for not even the High Lords of Terra have the right to demand them.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Games Workshop had laid the groundwork for the introduction of female Custodes by mentioning Custodes Calladayce Kesh in the latest Custodes codex back in April 2024 (some didn’t like the way this was done, or the tweet Games Workshop put out about it back then, and at the time there were no female Custodes models to go alongside the lore reveal).</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Since the first of the Ten Thousand were created, there have always been female Custodians.</p>— Warhammer Official (@warhammer) <a href="https://twitter.com/warhammer/status/1779544596172689822?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 14, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Then, in September 2024, fans were treated to a Warhammer animation starring a female Custodes called Tyrith Shiva Kyrus, who spent her time ripping tyranids to shreds and staring down Space Marines in the way only a Custodes can.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tyrith Shiva Kyrus was Games Workshop's first portrayal of a female Custodian since the lore revelation that Custodians could be any gender just a handful of months prior. "This fact came as a real surprise to many, since it wasn’t something previously explored," <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/TBbxxG5O/the-tithes-episode-2-custodes-dont-ask-twice/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Games Workshop said at the time</a>. "That, in and of itself, isn’t a particularly unusual thing for Warhammer 40,000 and its lore; there are simply loads of things the Warhammer Studios have never expressly stated, whether that’s ruling them in or out. Since the earliest conversations about bringing the Horus Heresy to the tabletop and Black Library fiction, the exact nature of the Custodians has been under discussion — after all, their origins and means of creation, unlike for example, the Legiones/Adeptus Astartes, are shrouded in mystery.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A significant advantage to this portrayal is that it helps us to address a common misconception — that the Custodes are just bigger, better Space Marines. They aren’t. Space Marines were made through industrialised ritual to be mass-produced, brute-force weapons of conquest. And even 10,000 years after their creation, draped in self-assigned glory, that’s still true of them at their core. Each Custodian, on the other hand, is unique. Painstakingly made through peerless craft and arcane artifice, their physique, their psyche, their very soul, is a bespoke instrument of the Emperor they unquestioningly serve."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These "gaps" in the Warhammer lore, where things are left unsaid or unexplained, are "quite intentional," Games Workshop said as part of that same September 2024 explanation. "They let you as collectors, players, and fans fill the spaces with your own characters, stories and narratives — making the Warhammer hobby truly yours," the company continued. "They also allow us to revisit factions through miniatures, stories, and animations and offer something new and interesting. (Imagine how sad it would be if we ever said 'And that’s it. That’s everything you’ll ever see in this army. No new models ever.' – that’d be rubbish.)"</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, we finally have female Custodes minis, which shouldn’t have come as much of a surprise at all. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/40k/comments/1qew51e/comment/o00wvvt/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As redditor SchmittVanDean put it over the weekend</a>:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And it's increasingly embarrassing and weird, like people who still complain bitterly about the Necrons. Tithes Episode 2 is a really fun short story of a female Custodes and her Sister of Silence buddy and the characterisation of their motivations and interactions — especially with Space Marines — are fantastic; their depiction and the way they fight is just cool. The new models are exceptional. The lore rationale — the Custodes are created via a perfected form of the earlier mass production gene editing that could only produce male Space Marines — improves both Marines and Custodes conceptually as factions.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Or, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Warhammer40k/comments/1qgz6n2/comment/o0g4yx7/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as redditor tghast said</a>: “I truly truly truly could not think of something I give less of a shit about.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Games Workshop.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/custodes-are-not-space-marines-games-workshop-addresses-the-telemon-in-the-room-and-explains-warhammer-lore-behind-new-female-miniatures]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Developer Rockstar North Suffers 'Structural Damage' Following Report of Explosion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fire-shuts-gta-6-developer-rockstar-north-following-report-of-explosion</link>
            <guid>1409935</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Rockstar Games has told IGN that its studio opened today following the incident attended by emergency services in the early hours of this morning.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Early Monday morning, there was a malfunction in one of the heating boilers at Rockstar North," a Rockstar Games spokesperson confirmed to IGN in a statement. "Many thanks to those that reached out with concern, and also to the police and fire crews who were on scene quickly to assess the situation - please know that everyone is well and our studio remains open and operational."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier reports from emergency service personnel made mention of securing "structural damage" to the building, though Rockstar's statement appears to suggest this was minimal. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>ORIGINAL STORY:</strong> Fire services attended the offices of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> developer Rockstar North this morning and secured "structural damage" following a reported boiler explosion.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seven vehicles were mobilized to attend the main Rockstar North building in Edinburgh, Scotland at 5.02am local time (just after midnight Eastern), following an incident that local news outlet <a href="https://www.edinburghlive.co.uk/news/edinburgh-news/edinburgh-fire-crews-rush-ongoing-33257244.amp" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edinburgh Live</a> described as an "explosion in a boiler room." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Crews remained on-site for over four hours but have now left the scene, Scottish newspaper <a href="https://www.heraldscotland.com/news/25776012.gta6-dev-rockstar-north-building-taped-off-boiler-explosion/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Herald</a> has reported.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We were alerted at 5.02am on Monday, 19 January to attend an incident on Holyrood Road, Edinburgh," a Scottish Fire and Rescue Service spokesperson said. "Operations Control mobilised three fire appliances and specialist resources to the scene, where firefighters worked to secure structural damage at a commercial building.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There were no reported casualties and crews left the scene at 9.21am."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar Games' Edinburgh office has long served as the heart of the company, with development of every major Grand Theft Auto and Red Dead Redemption game taking place within its walls. Most recently, the building has been the site of protests over Rockstar's sudden firing of workers amid an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-says-we-stand-by-our-course-of-action-as-judge-rejects-fired-gta-6-developers-application-for-interim-relief">increasingly bitter dispute that the layoffs were due to the employees' union membership</a> — a claim that Rockstar itself has vehemently denied.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Rockstar North and Take-Two Office Protest Photos Nov 2025</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It's believed that office remains shut today, though it's too early to say how this setback might impact the release of the twice-delayed GTA 6. Rockstar's hugely-anticipated game is currently set to launch on November 19.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has contacted Rockstar Games for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fire-shuts-gta-6-developer-rockstar-north-following-report-of-explosion]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>