<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:08:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chappell Roan is Joining Fortnite, and Here's How She Looks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/chappell-roan-is-joining-fortnite-and-heres-how-she-looks</link>
            <guid>1424590</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fresh from her appearance at the Grammys, Pink Pony Club singer Chappell Roan is hot to go in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> this week. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Roan is the latest music icon set to headline the game's Fortnite Festival mode, which will feature a redesigned main stage decorated like a medieval castle — inspired by her recent tour.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Music Pass owners, including Fortnite Crew subscribers, will get the basic Chappell Roan outfit included, alongside themed instruments. But, as ever, there will be a snazzier, second skin available from the Fortnite Shop: the Roan of Arc outfit, inspired by her 2024 VMAs costume. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/03/fnxchappellroan-musicpass-pink-1920x1080-1770124162936.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Fortnite's basic Chappell Roan outfit — you can also switch its color to red, and remove her hat.</figcaption></figure></output><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/03/fnxchappellroan-itemshop-1920x1080-1770124183774.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Roan of Arc outfit, available in the Fortnite Shop. And yes, there's a Pink Pony pet.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Several of Roan's best-known songs are already available as Jam Tracks in Fortnite, including Good Luck, Babe!, Hot To Go and The Giver. The infamous Pink Pony Club will also soon join this number — and there will even be a Pink Pony Sidekick pet for you to take along for the ride. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Roan herself is a Fortnite fan and previously noted her desire to appear in the game. Fans have expected her arrival ever since, which has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-think-fortnite-might-be-about-to-turn-into-the-pink-pony-club-with-a-chappell-roan-crossover">recently been teased in-game and online</a>, as Epic Games promised that February would be a "pink" month. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fortnite's Chappell Roan collaboration will officially kick off this week on Thursday, February 5, as the game's previous Festival star Lisa (from Blackpink) departs. Previous Festival faces have included Billie Eilish, Lady Gaga, Sabrina Carpenter, Metallica and Snoop Dogg. Who might be next?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/chappell-roan-is-joining-fortnite-and-heres-how-she-looks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>