<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 07:34:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Movie Adaptation Gearing Up as Hollywood Begins Circling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-movie-adaptation-gearing-up-as-hollywood-begins-circling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-movie-adaptation-gearing-up-as-hollywood-begins-circling.1140987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-movie-adaptation-gearing-up-as-hollywood-begins-circling<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next" tabindex="-1"><header></header><main data-cy="page-main-content" id="main-content"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Multiple Hollywood studios are reportedly keen to secure the rights.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Split Fiction is getting a film adaptation, according to <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/split-fiction-movie-video-game-adaptation-1236344367/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Variety</u></a>, which reports a package is being put together in response to offers for the movie rights coming in from “multiple top Hollywood studios.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Variety’s sources stated that Story Kitchen, a media company that specialises in film and TV adaptations of games and other non-traditional properties, is currently assembling the project’s writers, director, and cast into a package deal. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dwayne-johnson-executive-produce-it-takes-two-movie"><u>upcoming film adaptation of Hazelight Studios’ previous game, It Takes Two,</u></a> was handled by the same team. Other Story Kitchen projects (formerly known as dj2 Entertainment) include the Sonic the Hedgehog films and Netflix's Tomb Raider: The Legend of Lara Croft.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">No further details are known at this stage.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s more good news for Split Fiction; earlier this month it was confirmed that the spectacular co-op action adventure had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-hits-2-million-sales-after-just-1-week"><u>sold over two million copies in its first week on sale</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN’s review called Split Fiction an unmissable co-op adventure that stays <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-review"><u>fabulously fresh for its full, 14-hour duration.</u></a></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week Hazelight director Josef Fares confirmed the studio is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-dev-calls-ea-a-good-partner-as-hazelight-begins-work-on-next-game"><u>already working on its next game.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Luke is a Senior Editor on the IGN reviews team. You can track him down on Bluesky @mrlukereilly to ask him things about stuff.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></main></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak Is the Control Multiplayer FPS I Didn’t Know I Wanted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-is-the-control-multiplayer-fps-i-didnt-know-i-wanted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-is-the-control-multiplayer-fps-i-didn%E2%80%99t-know-i-wanted.1140876/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-is-the-control-multiplayer-fps-i-didnt-know-i-wanted<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Control was IGN’s Game of the Year in 2019 – and I was one of the many editors that voted for it – but even I was skeptical when Remedy, a studio known for telling great single-player stories in third-person games, announced it was doing a Control multiplayer game. That project turned out to be FBC: Firebreak, a three-player PvE first-person multiplayer shooter set six years after the events of Control. And in the hands-off demo I saw, it very quickly became clear that my skepticism was completely unwarranted. Firebreak is refreshingly original in an oversaturated space, delightfully weird amidst a sea of same-y military and/or sci-fi online shooters, and perhaps best of all, it doesn’t require a massive commitment like so many of its contemporaries. As game director Mike Kayatta put it, "We're not about daily check-ins. We're not interested in monthly grinds. We don't want to give anybody a second job." Say it again, Mike, for the people in the back.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">FBC: Firebreak is a three-player co-op FPS with, if what Remedy is promising comes to pass, no nonsense. You can play for 20 minutes or a few hours if you want to, with Perk unlocks and new combinations amongst characters keeping things fresh for repeat runs. But what the heck are you doing here, back in The Oldest House, with a bevy of bizarre weaponry in your hands? Essentially, you are volunteer first responders in The Oldest House when things go seriously sideways. Your characters are secretaries, rangers, and other “normal” occupations who heed the call of service. The Federal Bureau of Control wouldn’t say you’re expendable, but…you’re expendable. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">FBC: Firebreak - March 2025 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When you log in to play, you choose a Job (aka a mission) and a Crisis Kit (essentially, your loadout) before setting the Threat Level (difficulty) and Clearance Level, which determines how many zones you'll be playing through in a run. The zones are separated by containment doors, which will take you to the next stage of the Job. And the Job I saw is called Paper Chase, and it’s set in a fairly mundane office section of the FBC building. The Hiss are spreading, and it’s up to you and your two teammates to work together to beat them back. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, you can get the hell out of there as soon as you can if you like, but if you want to get your hands on currencies that let you upgrade and buy new gear, you have to escape safely with them. And the longer you spend exploring for currency, the harder it is to make it back to HQ in one piece. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of gear, that’s where FBC: Firebreak starts to set itself apart from other multiplayer shooters. Many of the guns are charmingly unusual, and most have a homebrew feel, like the hand-cranked snowball-launching gun that can put out fires (or your friends who are on fire) and soak the sticky-note monster (uh, more on him in a bit). Or the cobbled-together zapper that, when fitted with the right nozzle, can rain down lightning storms on a room full of bad guys. Or the large wrench that, when a squeaky piggy bank toy is attached, causes a swirl of coins to pelt your opponents. Don’t worry, though; there are still staples like a machinegun and shotgun – the latter of which is the go-to for after you’ve either soaked or zapped one of the sticky-note monsters.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Many of the guns are charmingly unusual, and most have a homebrew feel.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Oh yes, about them: the entire point of this particular Job is to eliminate all of the sticky notes before they overrun the entire brutalist building. Note the number of sticky notes left to destroy in the upper left corner. It will actually go way up as the mission progresses because, by the end of it, you face off against…a gigantic sticky-note monster. Think Sandman from the end of Spider-Man 3, but made out of sticky Post-It notes instead of sand.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But it’s not just about weird weapons. There are also fun in-universe gameplay mechanics, too, like the office supply shelf that refills your ammo, the makeshift turret you build after literally dumping it out of a box onto the floor, the stereo speaker that keeps the Hiss at bay, and the rinse station that washes any aggressive sticky notes off of your face. Unlockable Perks also inject more spice and variety into the gameplay. A couple of examples I saw: a Perk where each missed bullet has a chance to return to your clip, and another that lets you extinguish yourself by jumping up and down. Also, if you get two of the same Perk you get a stronger version of it. If you get three, you can share the Perk’s effect with nearby teammates. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">By the way, in case you’re wondering, you don’t have to have three people in order to play. You can play solo or in duos as well. Meanwhile, Remedy is aiming for a lower minimum PC spec than usual, but on the opposite end of the spectrum, FBC will also support DLSS4 with multi-frame generation as well as nVidia Reflex and full ray-tracing. It’ll also be Steam Deck verified, and it’s launching into Xbox and PC Game Pass on day one along with PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium. Finally, there is a post-launch content plan that Remedy isn’t ready to share quite yet, and there will be paid cosmetics, but that’s the extent of the microtransactions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In fairness, I haven’t actually played FBC: Firebreak yet, so I have to be cautious about my enthusiasm. But so far, it certainly passes the eye test. This is almost certainly not a run-of-the-mill multiplayer shooter, in a very good way. And the fact that it’s a get-in and get-out online game that doesn’t require a massive ongoing time commitment in order to enjoy it is a refreshing throwback to the days when that was the norm.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Post-Apocalyptic Platformer Resetna Makes 14 Updates in One Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/post-apocalyptic-platformer-resetna-makes-14-updates-in-one-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/post-apocalyptic-platformer-resetna-makes-14-updates-in-one-month.1140873/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/post-apocalyptic-platformer-resetna-makes-14-updates-in-one-month<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Working with players to shape the game for the future</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It's a post-apocalyptic, action adventure platformer, and now <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resetna"><u>ReSetna</u></a> has made 14 updates in just one month after responding to fan feedback. Indie developer Today’s Games calls it a "game reworked by players" and is dedicated to continuing working with its community. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest update, the Ruby Armor Upgrade, includes an overhaul of the combat system, better player controls, and a strong focus on the way battles will feel. Players facing the final boss will get a new cut scene, the game's environments have had a renovation, and the UI has been tweaked to provide clarity for players. Oh, and there's that gorgeous red armor set too.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Combat improvements</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>All weapons are improved, more responsive and enjoyable: animations and combos have been re-made and optimized for player's experience</li><li>Axe combo now has fast responsive chain of attacks, Sabre's attacks are now much more enjoyable and responsive with its parry-counterattack and in-air attacks,</li><li>Naginata has also been reworked to feel more impactful and heavier</li><li>Lesser projectiles from most basic enemies are now reflectable - the player is now able to avoid annoying ranged attacks, reflect them and still do a strong parry-counterattack while doing tha</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">ReSetna launched on January 30 on Steam and Nintendo Switch, and its titular robotic hero, ReSetna, has been woken from dormancy by Apex AI to track down the origin of a mysterious signal that is driving robots insane. Luckily there's back up from a drone companion called IXA who can help out by hacking enemies and providing medical aid. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rachel Weber is IGN's Managing Editor. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>