<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 17:44:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, Mario Kart World's Cow Can Eat Burgers and Steak]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-mario-kart-worlds-cow-can-eat-burgers-and-steak</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yes-mario-kart-worlds-cow-can-eat-burgers-and-steak.1155915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-mario-kart-worlds-cow-can-eat-burgers-and-steak<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">We're grilling Nintendo about this.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I feel like we've earned a reprieve today from the news chaos of tariffs and Nintendo Switch 2 pricing, so here's something fun (?) for your Friday: IGN played <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> at a Nintendo event in New York this week, and confirmed that yes, the new Cow character can in fact eat burgers and steak (and many others things as well).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're wondering what on earth we could possibly be talking about, allow me to point you to the recent announcement of Mario Kart World, which included the introduction of the Moo Moo Meadows Cow as a playable racer. The Internet, of course, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/you-can-play-as-the-moo-moo-meadows-cow-in-mario-kart-world-and-the-internet-is-thrilled">is thrilled about this</a>, already coming up with dozens of memes and fanart of the adorable Cow that, until recently, was nothing more prominent than a fun background character in a single Mario Kart track.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, as news of Cow spread throughout the land, fans began pointing out a potential, erm, problem, with another element of the Mario Kart World reveal. In the Nintendo Direct 2 trailer from Wednesday, Mario eats a burger. Burgers are (typically) made of beef. Would Cow, whose people are ostensibly a source of beef, consume beef herself? Fans really wanted to know.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Well at the Nintendo preview event, we found out. You see, the food items we saw in the trailer are obtainable in Mario Kart World at Yoshi's diner locations scattered across courses. They function like a drive-thru, allowing racers to drive up and grab a bag of take-out just like they would an item box. There are a lot of different food items that can be inside, including burgers, steak kebabs, pizza, and donuts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And yes, Cow can eat them all.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Yes, Cow CAN eat steak in Mario Kart World. <a href="https://t.co/qN5PZ9IIM4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/qN5PZ9IIM4</a></p>— IGN (@IGN) <a href="https://twitter.com/IGN/status/1908259261769003473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">During our session we also saw Cow eat a number of other items, including the burger. We're still a little hazy on what these items are actually doing for Cow — other racers change costumes when consuming them, but Cow doesn't seem to experience any effects. Could she be eating beef just because she enjoys it? Is there a secret power-up she gets from burger consumption that we just don't know about yet because Nintendo hasn't revealed it? Or perhaps are these veggie burgers and Beyond meat kebabs?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN reached out to Nintendo to try and clear all this up, but we haven't heard back yet. I'm sure it's because they're busy at their New York event, and not because this is an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o5RRyyHsjoU" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">unhinged question to ask</a> their PR about. Yeah, that's probably it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Anyway go check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">preview of Mario Kart World</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">video version of which</a> features an appearance by our friend Cow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Fans Fear Impact of Tariffs on Switch 2 Price: 'I Shouldn't as an Average Person Be Priced Out of This']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-fans-fear-impact-of-tariffs-on-switch-2-price-i-shouldnt-as-an-average-person-be-priced-out-of-this</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-fans-fear-impact-of-tariffs-on-switch-2-price-i-shouldnt-as-an-average-person-be-priced-out-of-this.1155912/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-fans-fear-impact-of-tariffs-on-switch-2-price-i-shouldnt-as-an-average-person-be-priced-out-of-this<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Gaming fans are feeling the heat after Nintendo announced its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-delays-switch-2-pre-order-date-in-the-us-to-assess-impact-of-trumps-tariffs"><u>Switch 2 U.S. pre-order date was delayed</u></a> as a direct result of the newly announced tariffs posed by the Trump Administration.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wednesday morning, Nintendo fully unveiled its hybrid console sequel alongside plans to open pre-orders come April 9 — news that <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/04/02/nx-s1-5345802/trump-tariffs-liberation-day" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Donald Trump would soon implement sweeping tariffs across the globe</u></a> arrived just hours later. It was a moment of whiplash that the industry is still struggling to come to grips with, and now, two days later, the average gaming fan is already feeling the impact.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Pre-orders for Nintendo Switch 2 in the U.S. will not start April 9, 2025 in order to assess the potential impact of tariffs and evolving market conditions,” Nintendo said in a statement shared with IGN. “Nintendo will update timing at a later date. The launch date of June 5, 2025 is unchanged.”</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">I really hate being right. I kept telling folks that things can literally change tomorrow. People kept yelling at me that the tariffs won't affect us...aight man 😒</p>— JG (@UTxJGTheDon) <a href="https://twitter.com/UTxJGTheDon/status/1908178855614939240?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>46% tariff on Vietnamese imports announced now.</p><p>Nintendo Switch 2 are produced there…</p><p>It’s so fucking over. <a href="https://t.co/5N1iAMI2Jm" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/5N1iAMI2Jm</a></p></div>— Pory (@pory_leeks) <a href="https://twitter.com/pory_leeks/status/1907553111587119567?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 2, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">they’re gonna make it even more expensive <a href="https://t.co/5Y8FL9FZF6" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/5Y8FL9FZF6</a></p>— Just Some Bread (@garliclessbread) <a href="https://twitter.com/garliclessbread/status/1908176095750349221?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">“Wait a minute… are you saying <em>we</em> have to pay the tariffs??” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1jqgd82/comment/ml7lqwa/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user commented</u></a>. “Who could have possibly foreseen this?!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While pre-order timing for other territories, including the UK, remains unchanged, Nintendo didn’t mince words when it came to how tariffs will affect those in the United States. However, changes to a release schedule, even when it comes to something as simple as pre-order timing, signal that Nintendo has more on its mind than it has revealed thus far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There were fears that Nintendo’s proposed $450 Switch 2 price and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-costs-80-will-gta-6"><u>$80 games</u></a> might be too big of an ask pre-tariffs — a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendos-switch-2-treehouse-livestream-is-just-a-flood-of-angry-comments-shouting-drop-the-price"><u>movement aiming to get Nintendo to lower its price plans</u></a> already began shortly after that initial reveal — but the struggle for affordable games is just getting started. While some <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-why-the-nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-world-and-everything-around-them-is-so-expensive"><u>analysts had suggested</u></a> Switch 2 prices were calculated with potential tariffs in mind, Nintendo’s announcement today suggests those numbers have room to increase.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>So then</p><p>Those WERE the pre tariff prices</p><p>Yeah the Switch and Mario Kart bout to be 650 after taxes</p></div>— Colin (@IntroSpecktive) <a href="https://twitter.com/IntroSpecktive/status/1908178481998856672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Americans checking the updated Switch 2 prices after complaining about the old ones <a href="https://t.co/fsC60LU5YE" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/fsC60LU5YE</a> <a href="https://t.co/t4RwqXia8J" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/t4RwqXia8J</a></p>— imonlyhereforpikmin (@onlyhereforpkmn) <a href="https://twitter.com/onlyhereforpkmn/status/1908193024774991920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo hasn’t announced when or if its Switch 2 prices will change, but there is plenty of reason to worry they will shift in a more expensive direction. What began as a wave of frustration aimed at the current Switch 2 price has now evolved into an ocean of people who, of course, are still angry, but now they are just hoping they’ll be able to afford the new console.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I shouldn’t as an average person be priced out of this, yet I probably will be.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“This unironically frustrates me so much,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jre39o/comment/mldx0xw/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user added</u></a>. “The switch 2 was already going to be quite expensive (compared to the OG) but I was still okay with paying the extra money for it. The games were another blow. Was too expensive already but whatever. But this? Huge tariffs <em>Plus Sales tax</em> Plus tariffs on the games???</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I don’t want to pay 130$ for a damn copy of a game or 600$ for the new Switch. I genuinely (think) this will impact the amount of people able to buy into all of this. I shouldn’t as an average person be priced out of this, yet I probably will be. Augh…”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">I feel bad for all my US followers. If you thought the Switch 2 price was expensive before. It looks like its going to get even worse due to new tariffs.</p>— Genki✨ (@Genki_JPN) <a href="https://twitter.com/Genki_JPN/status/1908178594280747027?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">We've <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/industry-analysts-react-to-nintendo-switch-pre-order-chaos-due-to-tariffs-we-are-living-in-unhinged-times">spoken to other industry analysts</a> who acknowledge that these unprecedented tariffs have gamers and game-makers walking into uncharted territory and that there's no telling what exactly will happen with the Switch 2. While some believe we could soon see a price increase, others aren't so sure, but all agree that the industry will no doubt feel the impact of the Trump Administration's wide-reaching tariff plans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 is Nintendo’s latest groundbreaking console, but a suddenly increased price could be just the start of what’s to come. We <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/esa-responds-to-trump-tariffs-if-we-think-its-just-the-switch-2-then-we-arent-taking-it-seriously"><u>spoke with Entertainment Software Association (ESA) spokesperson Aubrey Quinn to learn more about how Trump’s unprecedented tariffs will impact video game fans moving forward</u></a>. As many have already feared, the ESA says there’s no reason to believe the damage will stop at Nintendo.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>It does not stop at Nintendo Switch 2 btw. </p><p>-PC parts like CPU's and GPU's are gonna go up</p><p>-Laptops going up</p><p>-Anything Tech related is going up.</p><p>Next PlayStation and Xbox gonna require a blood sacrifice.</p></div>— Mightykeef (@MightyKeef) <a href="https://twitter.com/MightyKeef/status/1908206300543995993?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The prices of your consoles, tech, and pretty much every daily necessity are about to go up.</p><p>There's a good chance Nintendo is about to announce a price hike for the Switch 2. Do not be surprised if Sony and Microsoft follow suit.</p><p>PC market is already screwed. <a href="https://t.co/M40UFMyRH5" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/M40UFMyRH5</a></p></div>— KAMI (@Okami13_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Okami13_/status/1908185619408257499?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 is priced at $449.99 at the time of this piece’s publication. For more, you can read up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/does-the-price-of-the-switch-2-overshadow-its-reveal"><u>how we think it’s original price announcement impacted how players felt about the Switch 2 Direct</u></a>. You can also click <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-launch-games-confirmed-so-far"><u>here</u></a> to see the full launch lineup so far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>