<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 23:19:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards Are Up for Preorder at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-are-up-for-preorder-at-amazon.1112766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s one for fans of either Final Fantasy or Wizards of the Coast. The latest Magic: The Gathering crossover finds characters from Final Fantasy making their way to the most famous collectible card game on the market. We’re talking characters like Cloud, Terra, Tidus, and many more, pulled from Final Fantasy 6, 7, 10, and 14. Basically, the gang’s all here. These cards are set to release on June 13, but <strong>you can preorder them all right now (see them at </strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/QbxJwx?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Amazon</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/aD3pwR?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Best Buy</strong></a>). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Read on for details about what comes in the many bundles on the market. And for more info about the crossover, check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-deck-reveal-spoilers">Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Commander Deck reveal</a> feature.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Where to Buy Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Scroll to the left to see quick buy links for each MTG: FF configuration.</p><p id="starter-kit"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Starter Kit">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Starter Kit</h2></p><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215428"><div id="215428" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Starter Kit</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Starter Kit contains 2 ready-to-play 60-card decks, 2 deck boxes to store them in, 1 Magic play guide booklet, 4 double-sided tokens (2 with each deck), 2 double-sided reference cards to aid you as you play (Turn Order/Attacking &amp; Blocking), and two Magic: The Gathering Arena code cards to unlock both decks for two people to play online. Account registration required. Code expires September 1, 2030. This product does not contain a serialized card (available in English-language Collector Boosters only). </p></div><p id="gift-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Gift Bundle">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Bundle: Gift Edition</h2></p><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215430"><div id="215430" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Bundle: Gift Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>*Sold out at Amazon</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">This bundle contains 1 Collector Booster, 9 Play Boosters, 2 Traditional Foil Extended-Art cards, 16 Traditional Foil and 16 nonfoil Full-Art Basic Land cards, 1 oversized Spindown life counter, 1 special foil Final Fantasy card storage box, and 2 reference cards. A serialized card may be found in &lt;0.1% of English-language Collector Boosters only. </p></div><p id="bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Bundle">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215429"><div id="215429" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>*Sold out at Amazon</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">This Bundle includes 9 Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Play Boosters (each containing 14 cards), 2 Traditional Foil Extended-Art cards, 16 Traditional Foil and 16 nonfoil Full-Art Basic Land cards, 1 oversized Spindown life counter, 1 Final Fantasy card storage box, and 2 reference cards. This product does not contain a serialized card (available in English-language Collector Boosters only). </p></div><p id="collector-booster-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Collector Booster Box">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Collector Booster Box (12 Packs)</h2></p><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215432"><div id="215432" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Collector Booster Box (12 Packs)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Each of the 12 Collector Boosters in this box contain 15 Magic: The Gathering cards and 1 Traditional Foil double-sided token, including 5–6 cards of rarity Rare or higher and 3–6 Uncommon, 3–5 Common, and 1 Full-Art Land cards, with a total of 8–12 Traditional Foil cards and 0–3 cards with a special foil treatment. Serialized card in &lt;0.1% of English-language Collector Boosters only. </p></div><p id="play-booster-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Play Booster Box">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Play Booster Box (30 Packs)</h2></p><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215431"><div id="215431" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Play Booster Box (30 Packs)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Each of the 30 Play Boosters in this box contain 14 Magic: The Gathering cards and 1 Token/Ad card or Art card. (A regular Art card can be found in 30% of packs and a foil-stamped Signature Art card can be found in 5% of packs.) Every pack Includes 1–4 cards of rarity Rare or higher and 3–6 Uncommon, 6–9 Common, and 1 Land cards. One card of any rarity is Traditional Foil. The Land card is also Traditional Foil in 20% of boosters. This product does not contain a serialized card (available in English-language Collector Boosters only). </p></div><p id="commander-decks"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Commander Decks">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Commander Deck Bundle</h2></p><div id="215433" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Commander Deck Bundle</h3></p></div><div catalogid="ef23d812-2f63-404f-ae6a-ad790e721c40" id="215434"><div id="215434" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Collector’s Edition Commander Deck Bundle</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/98L76O?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DTN1MH2J" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Commander Deck 1: Revival Trance</a> - $69.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QPp4Jj?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DTN5LM6H" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Commander Deck 2: Limit Break</a> - $69.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aewJ0l?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DTMTWVGT" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Commander Deck 3: Counter Blitz</a> - $69.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aX2J3B?object_uuid=afd5d53d-6df8-4b40-bed1-a1e6167e7180&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DTN47WHG" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Commander Deck 4: Scions &amp; Spellcraft</a> - $69.99</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">You can buy the four Commander Decks in a regular bundle, collector's edition bundle, or individually. Each Commander Deck includes 1 deck of 100 Magic cards (98 nonfoil cards and 2 Traditional Foil Legendary cards), a 2-card Collector Booster Sample Pack (contains 2 alt-border cards, with at least 1 Traditional Foil), 10 double-sided token cards, 1 deck box (can hold 100 sleeved cards), 1 strategy insert, and 1 reference card. This product does not contain a serialized card (available in English-language Collector Boosters only).</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a deals expert and commerce editor for IGN. You can follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@chrislreed.com</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Feb 18, 2025 7:45 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jenna Ortega, George R.R. Martin, Stephen King, and More to Headline IGN Fan Fest 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/jenna-ortega-george-rr-martin-stephen-king-and-more-to-headline-ign-fan-fest-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jenna-ortega-george-r-r-martin-stephen-king-and-more-to-headline-ign-fan-fest-2025.1112601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/jenna-ortega-george-rr-martin-stephen-king-and-more-to-headline-ign-fan-fest-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Plus Paul Rudd, Ashley Burch, Osgood Perkins, Jack Quaid, Rob McElhenney, Keanu Reeves, Alexandra Daddario, and many more. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-fan-fest-is-back-with-monster-hunter-wilds-daredevil-born-again-idxbox-and-more"><u>IGN Fan Fest 2025</u></a> is less than a week away and stars from your favorite movies, series, games, and comics have teamed up for what will be our biggest Fan Fest ever. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Starting Monday, February 24, be sure to tune into IGN for tons of exclusive reveals, trailers, clips, gameplay, and spoiler-filled interviews from all the biggest upcoming titles in the world of games and entertainment. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jenna Ortega</strong> and <strong>Paul Rudd</strong> will be on hand to delve into their upcoming A24 movie, <strong>Death of a Unicorn. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Osgood Perkins, Stephen King,</strong> and <strong>James Wan</strong> stop by for an in-depth interview on how they brought their creepy new movie, <strong>The Monkey</strong> to life. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li>Director <strong>Bong Joon-ho</strong> will introduce a brand-new exclusive look at his upcoming film, <strong>Mickey 17.</strong> </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Charlie Cox</strong> and <strong>Vincent D’Onofrio</strong> along with the creators of <strong>Daredevil: Born Again </strong>will break down their new Disney+ series.</li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li>The team behind <strong>Monster Hunter Wilds</strong> including producer <strong>Ryozo Tsujimoto</strong> and director <strong>Yuya Tokuda</strong> give us an exclusive look at their massive new game.  </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li>The cast of <strong>The White Lotus</strong> including <strong>Walton Goggins, Parker Posey, Carrie Coon, Leslie Bibb, Michelle Monaghan, Aimee Lou Wood, Sarah Catherine Hook, Sam Nivola, Jason Isaacs,</strong> and<strong> Patrick Schwarzenegger</strong> answer all our questions about what we’ve season in Season 3 so far. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jack Quaid, Amber Midthunder, </strong>and <strong>Jacob Batalan </strong>preview their upcoming film, <strong>Novocaine</strong>. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>George R.R. Martin</strong> sits down with us to talk about the new movie <strong>In The Lost Lands, </strong>based on his short story. Plus <strong>Mila Jovovich</strong> and <strong>Paul. W. S. Anderson</strong> will be on hand to premiere an exclusive clip from the film. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jeffrey Dean Morgan</strong> and <strong>Lauren Cohan</strong> will preview the upcoming season of <strong>The Walking Dead: Dead City</strong> along with Executive Producer <strong>Scott Gimple. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jeff Probst </strong>stops by with an exclusive look at <strong>Survivor</strong> Season 48 and chats about the future of the long-running franchise. </li></ul><output data-cy="article-video"></output><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Alexandra Daddario</strong> gives us a preview of the season finale of <strong>Anne Rice’s Mayfair Witches. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Keanu Reeves</strong> and <strong>Gard Hollinger</strong> tell us all about their upcoming documentary <strong>The Arch Project. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Mythic Quest </strong>shows up big with <strong>Rob McElhenney, Megan Ganz, David Hornsby, Charlotte Nicdao, Danny Pudi, Imani Hakim, </strong>and<strong> Jessie Ennis</strong> on hand to talk about Season 4 and give us a sneak peek at an upcoming episode. Plus <strong>Katie McElhenney, Genevieve Jones, Megan Ganz, </strong>and <strong>Ashly Burch</strong> debut a trailer for their upcoming spin-off <strong>Side Quest. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Johnny Yong Bosch</strong> and <strong>Adi Shankar</strong> give us a sneak peek at their upcoming Netflix series <strong>Devil May Cry,</strong> based on the popular video game. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Julian McMahon </strong>gives us a look at his new movie, <strong>The Surfer</strong>, also starring Nicholas Cage. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Brandon Lee </strong>shows us a never-before-seen preview of the upcoming Crunchyroll anime <strong>The Beginning After the End. </strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li>J-pop megastar <strong>Ado</strong> pops by with a special surprise for fans. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li>The team from <strong>CRKD</strong> comes by to show off a new controller. </li></ul><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/16/ff25-announce-1up-copy-1738270221966-1739743865177.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">IGN Fan Fest Returns February 24-28.</figcaption></figure></output><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Doctor Who: Fifteenth Doctor </strong>writers <strong>Dan Watters </strong>and<strong> Kelsey Ramsay</strong> answer all of our burning questions about the comic series. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</strong> director <strong>Charles Benoit</strong> will give us a preview of the game set to release this March. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Blade Runner: Tokyo Nexus</strong> creators <strong>Kianna Shore </strong>and <strong>Mellow Brown </strong>go deep on their comic series and show off exclusive behind-the-scenes visuals from artist Mariano Taibo.</li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Todd McFarlane</strong> and Brand Creative Director <strong>Brian Walters </strong>unveil some incredible new collaborations from <strong>McFarlane Toys.</strong></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jason Aaron </strong>and <strong>Caleb Goellner </strong>will give us updates on what’s next for the <strong>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</strong> in the world of comics and debut some never-before-seen looks at multiple TMNT series. </li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Xin CHANG, </strong>creative Director and producer at Bad Guitar Studio, stops by to give us a look at the upcoming tactical FPS <strong>Frag Punk. </strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">And that’s just a taste of what’s on deck for IGN Fan Fest 2025. Tune in all next week for livestrams focusing on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/idxbox-showcase-to-kick-off-ign-fan-fest-2025">what's next from ID@Xbox</a> along with horror, anime, games, and entertainment showcases. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check back later this week for the full Fan Fest schedule along with information on how you can tune in and not miss a moment. </p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>