<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 10:08:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Backlash Against $10 Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour Heats Up, Reggie Fils-Aimé Tweets the Story of Wii Sports Pack-in From IGN Interview — and Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/as-backlash-against-10-nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-heats-up-reggie-fils-aim-tweets-the-story-of-wii-sports-pack-in-from-ign-interview-and-everyone-knows-the-point-hes-trying-to-make</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/as-backlash-against-10-nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-heats-up-reggie-fils-aim%C3%A9-tweets-the-story-of-wii-sports-pack-in-from-ign-interview-%E2%80%94-and-ever.1160112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/as-backlash-against-10-nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-heats-up-reggie-fils-aim-tweets-the-story-of-wii-sports-pack-in-from-ign-interview-and-everyone-knows-the-point-hes-trying-to-make<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Former Nintendo of America boss Reggie Fils-Aimé has pointed to the story of Wii pack-in game Wii Sports in thinly-veiled tweets addressing the controversy surrounding Nintendo’s decision to charge for Switch 2 tutorial game Welcome Tour.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amid the furore around <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-price-confirmed"><u>the $449.99 price of the Switch 2</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-costs-80-30-cheaper-if-you-buy-it-bundled-with-the-nintendo-switch-2"><u>Mario Kart World's $79.99 price tag</u></a>, there was also shock at Nintendo’s decision to charge for interactive instruction manual, Welcome Tour.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo revealed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-will-be-a-paid-tour-of-your-new-nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</u></a> during its Nintendo Direct last week. It’s a game set to launch alongside the Switch 2 in June that offers a guided tour of the console itself in video game form.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour is described as a "virtual exhibition" of the new hardware. Per Nintendo: "through tech demos, minigames and other interactions, players will get to know the new system inside and out in ways they may never have known about otherwise."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Direct showed footage of a small player avatar exploring a super-sized Switch 2, reading about the different features and facts about the console. It also includes mini-games such as Speed Golf, Dodge the Spiked Balls, and a Maracas Physics Demo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-will-be-a-paid-tour-of-your-new-nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</u></a> costs $9.99 and is a digital-only product. That’s significantly cheaper than other Switch 2 games, but IGN has already reported to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-would-you-make-people-pay-for-that-nintendos-decision-to-charge-for-switch-2-tutorial-game-welcome-tour-sparks-backlash"><u>the complaints from some Nintendo fans that Welcome Tour costs money at all</u></a>, with many saying it should be a Switch 2 pack-in, as DualSense tech demo game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astros-playroom-ps5-review"><u>Astro's Playroom</u></a> was for PlayStation 5.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Fils-Aimé has tweeted three clips from IGN’s two-year-old interview with the former Nintendo executive in which he discussed the internal battle he had with legendary developer Shigeru Miyamoto to get Wii Sports as a free pack-in for the hugely successful Wii console.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the first clip, Fils-Aimé says "it is an understatement to say that Mr. Miyamoto pushed back” on the call to make Wii Sports a Wii console pack-in. As we know, this is a battle Fils-Aimé won to a degree, with Wii Sports bundled with the Wii everywhere except Japan.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">The story of Wii Sports pack in ...<a href="https://t.co/LhflSFWaL3" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/LhflSFWaL3</a></p>— Reggie Fils-Aimé (@Reggie) <a href="https://twitter.com/Reggie/status/1910052940242620563?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 9, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The second interview clip Fils-Aimé tweeted pointed to a similar battle to bundle Wii Play with the Wii Remote. In the clip from our interview, Fils-Aimé revealed he “pissed off” Miyamoto once again with the suggestion. “He was not happy about that either.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And finally, tweeting “and the results,” Fils-Aimé clipped out the section from our interview in which he reveals that all this was, ultimately, the right call.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“In the Americas and in Europe Wii Sports was packed in with the Wii proposition. It was not in Japan, which created a bit of a test market. It was obvious that in the markets where Wii Sports was packed in that we became much more of a phenomenon. Wii Sports itself became much more of a phenomenon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We did pack the Remote with Wii Play. And it became the fifth best-selling piece of software in the history of the Wii.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">And the results.<a href="https://t.co/xrFTDeJMQf" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/xrFTDeJMQf</a></p>— Reggie Fils-Aimé (@Reggie) <a href="https://twitter.com/Reggie/status/1910052943690150239?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 9, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It’s clear to see what Fils-Aimé is doing here. Although he’s not directly commenting on Nintendo’s Switch 2 strategy, he is making the point that free pack-ins have worked in the past for Nintendo consoles,so it stands to reason that it would do so again for Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans know what’s up, too. “Hahaha, guys I think Reggie is watching our comments about the Switch 2,” said one X / Twitter user. “We know you would have packed in Welcome Tour,” said another.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, IGN published its interview with Nintendo of America's Vice President of Product and Player Experience, Bill Trinen, conducted at a recent Switch 2 preview event in New York, but before Nintendo announced the delay to pre-orders due to Trump’s tariffs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Trinen said there’s more to Welcome Tour than it appears based on the showing during the Nintendo Direct and even during recent hands-on opportunities the media had access to. Based on what’s actually in the game, Nintendo decided $9.99 “is not an exorbitant price,” he continued.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/10/reggie-1744265519979.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Reggie fought for Wii Sports as a Wii pack in. Photo by Susan Goldman/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's an interesting product,” Trinen began. “We're actually getting ready today, we're going to be doing some Nintendo Treehouse Live segments and covering a lot of games in detail. That's one of them. And I think people will be able to see through Treehouse Live probably a little bit more maybe than you were able to see on the show floor. It's a pretty robust piece of software. There's a lot of great detail in there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“For some people, I think there are people who are particularly interested in the tech and the specs of the system and things like that, for them I think it's going to be a great product. It's really for people that want more information about the system rather than necessarily a quick intro to everything it does.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"And for that reason and just the amount of care and work that the team put into it, I think it was decided that, 'Yeah, this feels like $9.99 is not an exorbitant price. It feels like a good value for what you're getting out of the product.' "</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Welcome Tour is of course just one part of Nintendo’s next-gen push to become embroiled in controversy, and we’ve also got <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-exclusive-mario-kart-world-justifies-its-80-price-tag-nintendo-insists-in-first-comments-addressing-cost-controversy"><u>Trinen’s response to questions surrounding the company’s decision to go for $80 Switch 2 games</u></a>, as well as going for $450 for the Switch 2 itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Susan Goldman/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>