<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:40:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I'm Preaching Patience' — The Elder Scrolls 6 Is 'Still a Long Way Off,' Todd Howard Warns Fans, Teases Potential Shadowdrop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/im-preaching-patience-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-warns-fans-teases-potential-shadowdrop</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/im-preaching-patience-%E2%80%94-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-warns-fans-teases-potential-shadowdrop.1348933/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi">The Elder Scrolls 6</a> — one of the most hotly anticipated video games in the world — won’t be out for some time yet despite being announced over seven years ago, Bethesda development chief Todd Howard has said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/article/fallout-4-anniversary-todd-howard-interview" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GQ magazine</a> to celebrate the release of Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition, Howard said The Elder Scrolls 6 is “still a long way off.” He added: “I’m preaching patience. I don’t want fans to feel anxious.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In January this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-announcement-is-now-as-old-as-skyrim-was-when-the-elder-scrolls-6-was-announced">The Elder Scrolls 6 announcement became as old as predecessor Skyrim was when The Elder Scrolls 6 was announced</a>. Skyrim was released on November 11, 2011, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/11/e3-2018-the-elder-scrolls-vi-announced-at-bethesda-press-conference"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 reveal on June 10, 2018</u></a> came 2,403 days after that. It is now seven years and five months after the announcement, and we’re no closer, it seems, to the release of the game.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When the six year anniversary of The Elder Scrolls 6 announcement arrived in June last year, even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-teaser-is-now-6-years-old-and-even-todd-howard-paused-to-say-oh-wow-that-has-been-a-while"><u>Todd Howard paused to say, "oh wow, that has been a while."</u></a> The Elder Scrolls 6 is at least in production, with Bethesda confirming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-officially-in-early-development-but-dont-expect-to-hear-about-it-soon"><u>it had entered "early development" in August 2023</u></a> and "early builds" were available in March 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, in the GQ article, Howard has once again admitted that it’s taken too long to get The Elder Scrolls 6 out the door, but did tease an The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered-style shadowdrop — without confirming anything.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I do like to have a break between them, where it isn’t like a ‘plus one’ sequel,” Howard said of making The Elder Scrolls games again. “I think it’s also good for an audience to have a break — The Elder Scrolls has been too long, let’s be clear. But we wanted to do something new with Starfield. We needed a creative reset.” Bethesda is currently playtesting The Elder Scrolls 6, Howard revealed.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Elder Scrolls Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So when will it actually come out? It seems likely at this point that it will be released for Microsoft’s next-gen Xbox console and PC. Will it also be a PS6 game? A cross-gen title perhaps?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I like to just announce stuff and release it,” Howard continued. “My perfect version — and I’m not saying this is going to happen — is that it's going to be a while and then, one day, the game will just appear.” The Oblivion Remastered shadowdrop was “a test run,” Howard teased. “It worked out well.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for what Bethesda has going on right now, hundreds of people are working on Fallout, Howard said, across Fallout 76 “and some other things we're doing, but The Elder Scrolls 6 is the everyday thing.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, it was confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-will-feature-a-memorial-character-for-a-much-missed-fan-following-85000-donation-to-make-a-wish"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6</u> will include a character designed in memory of a much-missed fan</a>, after a remarkable charity campaign that raised more than $85,000 for Make-A-Wish. Howard revealed that Bethesda has spent some time talking with the group of fans who organized the fundraiser about what they want to see from The Elder Scrolls 6, and commented: “I think we’re aligned.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/im-preaching-patience-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-warns-fans-teases-potential-shadowdrop]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-of-all-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-100-best-nintendo-games-of-all-time.1348930/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Video games are synonymous with the name Nintendo. But which of the hundreds of incredible games that have graced the legendary Japanese company’s numerous home and handheld consoles are the best? Well, here at IGN, we’ve teamed up with our friends at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nintendo Life</a> to try and answer that question. What follows is the 100 best Nintendo games of all time, based on a combination of each site’s expert opinions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">From iconic Nintendo in-house series such as Super Mario, Metroid, and The Legend of Zelda, to third-party heroes who have made their home on everything from the NES to Switch 2, narrowing down the field was no easy task. These aren’t necessarily the best games to play right now, but a ranking based on a combination of historic innovation, modern ingenuity, and the legacy each has left behind. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Have an opinion on what should be placed where? You can contribute to our <strong>public ranking</strong> by voting in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/faceoffs/the-100-best-nintendo-games-ever-faceoff">this faceoff</a> or let us know in the comments below. Over the course of this week, we’ll be steadily revealing our picks, with 20 being revealed each day until the full ranking is complete on Friday, November 14. So, without further ado, here are the top 100 Nintendo games of all time:</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 100 Best Nintendo Games of All Time</h3></div></output><p id="picks-100-81"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Picks 100-81">100. Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem</h2></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/eternal-1762440216844.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">More than 20 years on, there’s still nothing quite like Eternal Darkness: Sanity’s Requiem (which, yes, is probably due in part to Nintendo's now-expired sanity system patent). Not only did it have the temerity to jump between wildly distinct time periods, but it also went to great lengths to mess with your mind should you get spotted by enemies too much. Whether it’s an unsettling noise, a slightly skewed camera angle, or the game straight up simulating a ‘blue screen of death’, it made for one of the most memorable experiences in the horror genre. The Lovecraftian aesthetic still sings to this very day, and a certain bathtub scene is just as sure to give you the willies now as it did back in 2002. A remarkable game that deserves a second chance in the spotlight.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">99. GTA: Chinatown Wars</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/gta-1762440272145.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">A GTA game releasing exclusively (until its later PSP arrival) for a Nintendo handheld seems like an incongruous proposal. But, in 2009, Rockstar gave the DS Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars, a standalone story of Triads and tribulations in GTA 4’s modern Liberty City setting. This top-down ode to the series’ roots miraculously converted the open-world cinema we’d come to expect, adapting to its handheld confines through smart touchpad mechanics and a stylised, cell-shaded comic-book-like aesthetic to stunning effect. What could so easily have been a misguided experiment between Rockstar and Nintendo instead became one of the DS’s most essential games.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">98. Star Fox</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/starfox-1762440315739.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">From the days when the word “polygon” was exclusively found in math textbooks comes Nintendo’s 3D evolution of a mainstay arcade genre: the SHMUP. Taxing the SNES hardware so much, even the Super FX chip included inside the cartridge couldn’t get the action to run even at a targeted 12 frames per second, Star Fox followed the linear stage setups of R-Type and co., but played from a behind-the-ship and first-person perspective. The “talking” animals are here to remind you that you’re playing a Nintendo game, but in the end, Star Fox is a highly technical and experimental harbinger of the future. Far from being just a tech demo, it’s also a really fun game, however, thanks to challenging players to play again and again to perfect their runs and experiment to discover alternate paths.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">97. Super Castlevania IV</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/castlevania-4-1762440382804.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">While it's effectively a re-thread of the original Castlevania, this fourth mainline instalment in the series really does elevate things to an entirely different level of quality. Sure, Castlevania 3: Dracula's Curse might be the better game overall, but Super Castlevania IV reimagines Transylvania through a 16-bit lens; the visuals are stunning, with Mode 7 effects adding a new dimension to proceedings, while the music is so good you'd swear it was being streamed from a CD. Subsequent entries would arguably take the franchise to the next level of brilliance, but one thing is clear: Super Castlevania IV remains a masterpiece.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">96. 999: Nine Hours, Nine Persons, Nine Doors</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/999-1762440449087.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo DS became a haven for visual novel fans; an interactive storybook device that could ease you into a deep night’s sleep. 999: Nine Hours, Nine Persons, Nine Doors was far more likely to keep you up all night, however, with its twisted game of life and death. Chunsoft’s first entry into the Zero Escape series, 999 placed you alongside eight other potential victims inside a sinking cruise liner that tested your puzzle and deduction skills as you unraveled the web woven by a mysterious mastermind. It’s twisted, clever, and a great example of handheld experimentation that he console would become known for.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">95. Fire Emblem Three Houses</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/three-houses-1762440512155.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Three Houses is a Fire Emblem game that got it all so right; it's been hard to readjust to the series in its aftermath. You see, Three Houses gives us the turn-based strategy we're all fiending for, yes, and it does so with style to spare. However, the real draw here, and the thing that makes this one so worthy of note overall, is the focus and effort that’s been placed on the socialising, customisation, relationships, and all that good stuff that happens between scraps. It's a game you could quite happily live in for a bit.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">94. Professor Layton and the Unwound Future</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/layton-1762440564926.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">What does Professor Layton hide under that huge hat? Perhaps, a towering cylindrical head of a shape unlike any other in human history. He’d certainly need one to house a brain big enough to solve all of the puzzles thrown his way over the course of his many DS and 3DS adventures. A consistent quality of cosiness mixed with Sherlock Holmes-esque yarns can be found across the Layton series, but we’ve gone with The Unwound Future as our pick of the bunch. Its time-traveling tale, full of memorable twists and turns, thrills just as much as solving one of its dozens of conundrums does, satisfying brains of all shapes and sizes to great effect.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">93. WWF No Mercy</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/wwf-1762440600703.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">25 years later, WWF No Mercy, the THQ-published wrestling game released on the Nintendo 64, is not only still considered to be the pinnacle of the N64 wrestling game boom, but it's also widely thought of as the greatest wrestling game of all time. Since its release, it's been the benchmark for what any wrestling game, with or without the WWE license, has aspired to be. It's developed a cult-like following, with fans still playing (and modding) No Mercy to this day, updating its 25-year-old roster with modern superstars when the latest 2K game doesn't live up to its standards. It's not often a game still stands strong after a quarter of a century, and it's even rarer when it's a sports game. All of this makes WWF No Mercy not only the greatest-ever wrestling game, but perhaps Nintendo's greatest-ever sports game that doesn't include Mario.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">92. Kirby: Planet Robobot</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/kirby-robot-1762440684724.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirby: Planet Robobot, a truly astonishing little game for the Nintendo 3DS that encapsulates all that is best and beloved about the pink puffball. Robobot has everything: a deep roster of unique and useful copy abilities, colorful and creative levels, an interesting one-off gimmick in the robot armor, silly minigames, and a plot that starts with Kirby taking a nap and ends in a giant galactic battle against a superintelligent, planet-sized being.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to all this, Kirby: Planet Robobot is one of the very few games to really make effective use of the Nintendo 3DS's 3D capabilities. While the game itself takes place on a 2D plane, it features a number of levels that have depth as well as length, and look absolutely fantastic with the 3D turned on, as cars drive directly at the player and giant ice cream cones tip over and spill on the camera. While Kirby has since gained other new copy abilities, minigames, and even his first 3D adventure in the years since, most of them struggle to hold a candle in our hearts to Planet Robobot's breadth, depth, and pure charm.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">91. Diddy Kong Racing</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/diddy-kong-racing-1762440752385.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Apart from Nintendo itself, Rare was the N64’s most important developer, and one place the UK-based studio actually outpaced Nintendo was in the kart racer category. Mario Kart 64 is an undeniable classic, but Diddy Kong Racing just inches ahead as our pick for the best kart racer on the 64. In addition to chaotic split-screen kart racing, Diddy Kong Racing drove the genre forward with three vehicle types (your friend could be in a plane flying alternate routes during the same race you were in a car!), an adventure mode complete with boss battles, and an amazing soundtrack from Donkey Kong Country composer David Wise. Plus, it was the first appearance of Banjo and Conker ahead of their solo platformer outings – and it’s the forgotten, cute, family-friendly version of Conker well before he started drinking, smoking, and swearing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">90. The World Ends With You</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/world-ends-1762440864188.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Though it's been ported and remade several times, none of the more recent versions of The World Ends With You has managed to capture how excellent this game was back when it first released on Nintendo DS. We could go on all day about what makes it great: the art style, the deep fashion mechanics, its accurate portrayal of Shibuya and Japanese youth culture, its unusual story with multiple wild twists, its incredible cast of characters, the MUSIC. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But maybe the best element of TWEWY that we've lost in subsequent editions is its battle system, which made unique and brilliant use of both the system's dual screen and its touch controls simultaneously with its D-pad to effectively simulate two different characters synchronizing their attacks with one another in two different realms. Combined with a wide variety of "pins" that could be activated with different types of touch attacks, there was endless room for creativity and growth through multiple playthroughs. Which you definitely wanted to do, if only to hear Calling and Three Seconds Clapping one more time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">89. Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/captain-toad-1762440906371.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">After years of being relegated to supporting roles, our little mushroom-headed friend Toad finally got his own game in Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker. Nintendo, over the years, has done a brilliant job of designing games fit and tuned perfectly to the personalities of each of its mascots, and Captain Toad is no exception. The cute, diorama-like levels proved to be magnificent puzzles for our intrepid explorer to navigate one by one, presenting a slower and cozier pace from other Nintendo challenges, yet still being perfectly, whimsically Nintendo. It's a shame we never got another one of these.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">88. Golden Sun: The Lost Age</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/golden-sun-lost-age-1762440966390.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">We could’ve gone with either Golden Sun and Golden Sun: The Lost Age as our entry on this list, but we’ve settled for the second part of Camelot's two-act RPG adventure, as it is ultimately the better half. Golden Sun was already an absolute feat, with its creative Psynergy and Djinn systems, gorgeous environments and music, and surprisingly robust open world. In the sequel they quadrupled the size of that world, added even more Psynergy and Djinn and classes, came up with more banger songs and environments, and opened the second act with a wild party switching twist that would go on to be subverted further in a triumphant march to the final battle. Golden Sun and The Lost Age are nuts in the best way, The Lost Age even more so, and are among the best GBA games of all time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">87. Mario Golf: Toadstool Tour</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/mario-golf-1762443474955.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario has tried his hand at a lot of different sports over the years, but few have had the staying power of golf. Originally driving off on the NES, before approaching the 3D world of the N64, it’s Toadstool Tour on the GameCube where the plumber really nailed the action on the green. Its sizeable roster of characters and compelling courses offered a great round of multiplayer fun for those looking for a more laid-back time away from the hectic rush of Smash Bros. and Mario Kart, and the furious consequences of Mario Party.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">86. Super Monkey Ball 2</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/super-monkey-1762443539892.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Super Monkey Ball’s brilliance lies in the fact that you’re tilting the stage to roll your monkey around rather than directly moving the character itself, and its table maze concept has never been more finely tuned than in Super Monkey Ball 2. The 2002 GameCube sequel is stuffed with 140 stages to clear – ranging from fun and simple courses perfect for laughing at the silly monkeys on family game night to downright brutal challenges that’ll make you go bananas as you lose hundreds of lives trying to clear them. Mastering everything it has to offer is extraordinarily satisfying, and its physics, momentum, and controls are so pinpoint that a study found that surgeons who warm up by playing Super Monkey Ball 2 are more efficient and precise in simulated surgeries compared to the surgeons who didn’t play. Video games really can save lives!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">85. Viewtiful Joe</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/viewitful-joe-1762443584954.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Viewtiful Joe practically attacks your eyeballs with its standout art direction and frantically fun combat. It’s unfiltered Hideki Kamiya at an exciting career crossroads, melding his Devil May Cry action with a colourful paintbrush palette that would later evolve into the likes of Okami and The Wonderful 101. A wholly original side-scroller that threatens to burst out of its purple cube confines if your fingers don’t keep up with its cell-shaded antics, it's an exciting combo of 2D and 3D platform action that felt fresh in 2003, with an intoxicating style that few have come close to matching since. It spawned sequels, but none truly reached the heights of the original, which has stood the test of time as one of the GameCube’s very best.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">84. F-Zero GX</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/f-zero-gx-1762443720093.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">F-Zero is about cheating death to go faster, and F-Zero GX’s uncompromising difficulty and incredibly high skill ceiling represent a peak of the futuristic racing genre. Like F-Zero X before it, GX forces you to sacrifice your machine’s health bar to get a boost, resulting in tense risk-reward scenarios that get your blood pumping every time. And if you fall off the track while trying to shave off an extra split second, Lakitu won’t swoop in to save you – you’re dead. You must master GX’s tight mechanics and memorize its radical track designs to even stand half a chance against its toughest CPUs, and you hit a high most video games can’t reach when you finally cross the finish line in first place. The cold-blooded challenge only works because GX runs perfectly at 60 fps and looks fantastic with strong art direction that rivals the GameCube’s best, like Metroid Prime and Rogue Leader. F-Zero GX is a masterpiece, and probably the most hardcore Nintendo game since the NES.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">83. Ring Fit Adventure</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/ring-fit-1762443812379.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Ring Fit Adventure is one of the best-selling Nintendo Switch games, thanks largely to a global pandemic making indoor exercise briefly appealing. Unfortunately, like many other exercise programs, most people who started Ring Fit fell off the game before they could discover how much more than just an exercise game it really is. Ring Fit Adventure is genuinely one of the most unique RPGs of the generation. It has a colorful cast of characters, bolstered by surprisingly good writing, a battle system revolving around your own physical movement, complete with skill trees, elemental weaknesses, and even healing items you can craft through more exercise. Plus, its soundtrack is straight work-out bangers, too.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">82. Phoenix Wright: Ace Attorney</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/phoenix-wright-1762443881507.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Nearly every moment of Phoenix Wright’s original courtroom adventure is iconic. From Phoenix’s debut trial against Mr. Sahwit (Or should I say... Mr. Did It!) to cross-examining a literal parrot, the first Ace Attorney fully commits to its completely unhinged world and never looks back. Exposing witnesses’ lies and uncovering the truth of each case is exhilarating, largely because of its excellent soundtrack and lively character animations, and the way Ace Attorney balances its unabashed silliness with genuinely serious, heartfelt moments is nothing short of masterful. It’s also an essential game in its genre, as Ace Attorney’s surprisingly successful sales paved the way for more visual novel and puzzle games to find a footing in the West.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">81. Castlevania 3: Dracula’s Curse</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/11/06/castlevania-3-1762444015514.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Considered by many to be the apex of the 'classic' Castlevania entries, Dracula's Curse remains a wonderful example of a talented group of developers pushing aging hardware to its maximum potential. By the time it arrived in 1989, the 16-bit era was already in full swing and the NES was looking very old-fashioned. However, despite the humble nature of the host hardware, Konami created a stunning action platformer, boasting multiple playable characters and optional routes through Dracula's castle. Indeed, many consider this to be superior to the first 16-bit entry in the series, Super Castlevania IV, which arrived just a short time later in 1991.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Come back tomorrow when we'll be revealing numbers 80 to 61...</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-100-best-nintendo-games-of-all-time]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>