<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:38:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jurassic World Evolution 3 No Longer Includes Generative AI Portraits Following Fan Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/jurassic-world-evolution-3-no-longer-includes-generative-ai-portraits-following-fan-backlash</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jurassic-world-evolution-3-no-longer-includes-generative-ai-portraits-following-fan-backlash.1227462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Frontier Developments is walking back the use of generative AI in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/jurassic-world-evolution-3">Jurassic World Evolution 3</a> following backlash from fans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Jurassic World Evolution 3 finally sprouted legs when <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/jurassic-world-evolution-3-official-reveal-trailer-summer-game-fest-2025"><u>its official reveal trailer</u></a> was published as part of Summer Game Fest 2025 earlier this month. Its existence marked the end of a four-year wait for a third game in the dinosaur strategy simulation franchise, but much of the excitement was quickly soured when fans discovered that Frontier had used controversial generative AI technology to create certain scientist portraits in-game.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Shortly after this realization, fans gathered to campaign against the use of AI in Jurassic World Evolution 3 in hopes that Frontier would reverse its decision in favor of content created by actual human beings. It’s a movement that seems to have achieved the desired results, as the team behind the Jurassic Park video game now <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2958130/discussions/0/599654768975026771/?ctp=16#c599656262950498876" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied to a popular Steam post</u></a> to confirm that generative AI portraits will be removed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Thanks for your feedback on this topic,” the post says. “We have opted to remove the use of generative AI for scientist portraits within Jurassic World Evolution 3.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those who visit the Jurassic World Evolution 3 Steam page will now find that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valve-announces-changes-to-how-its-handling-ai-content-on-steam">Steam’s AI Generated Content Disclosure</a> can no longer be found above the list of its system requirements. It’s a move that’s already being celebrated by the Jurassic World Evolution 3 community as they look forward to seeing art that wasn’t created by artificial intelligence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Thank you. As a dev myself, this was wholly unnecessary from the start and such an own goal that I'm happy to see the pivot, and to be able to wish the team the best for a successful launch,” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2958130/discussions/0/599654768975026771/?ctp=16#c599656331050239759" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam user said</u></a>. “Been such a fan of JWE1+2 (and PC/PZ), so this change takes me from a never-buy to a buy-at-launch!”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Frontier W</p><p>Jurassic World Evolution 3 will not use any generative AI!</p><p>I repeat: Jurassic World Evolution 3 will NOT USE ANY GENERATIVE AI!</p><p>💯 <a href="https://t.co/x3O0y9VJpP" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/x3O0y9VJpP</a></p></div>— Evolution Square (@EvoSquareYT) <a href="https://twitter.com/EvoSquareYT/status/1937489605411906046?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Well, it looks like it's the perfect frontier game now. They removed the Generative AI from <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/jurassicworld?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#jurassicworld</a> evolution 3. <a href="https://t.co/K0YCkQpias" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/K0YCkQpias</a></p>— Herald Of Geese (Stealer of geese) (@GeeseHerald) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeseHerald/status/1937523298600099983?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Frontier confirmed in a statement to <a href="https://www.gamewatcher.com/news/jurassic-world-evolution-3-no-longer-using-generative-ai-for-scientist-portraits-following-initial-feedback" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GameWatcher</u></a> that Jurassic World Evolution 3 still has a release date of October 21, 2025, for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. In the meantime, you can read up on how other companies, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ai-darth-vader-was-the-beginning-epic-reveals-plans-to-let-people-create-their-own-ai-npcs-in-fortnite"><u>Epic Games</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-and-hellblade-developer-ninja-theory-built-an-ai-called-muse-designed-to-generate-ideas-for-a-games-design-and-its-already-making-complex-gameplay-sequences"><u>Microsoft</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-create-hundreds-of-thousands-of-unique-ideas-needed-to-build-in-game-environments"><u>Capcom</u></a>, are using AI in their video games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/jurassic-world-evolution-3-no-longer-includes-generative-ai-portraits-following-fan-backlash]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft Movie Director Duncan Jones Returns With First Look at Rogue Trooper Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-movie-director-duncan-jones-returns-with-first-look-at-rogue-trooper-adaptation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-movie-director-duncan-jones-returns-with-first-look-at-rogue-trooper-adaptation.1227456/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Get down to brass tacks.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/rogue-trooper">film adaptation</a> of the classic British comic <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/rogue-trooper">Rogue Trooper</a> is on the way — and the first look images for the film have officially arrived, featuring What We Do in the Shadows stars Jemaine Clement and Matt Berry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rogue Trooper is written, directed, and produced by Duncan Jones, whose last movie, Mute, came out in 2018. Jones also directed the 2016 Warcraft movie, 2011's Source Code, and 2009's Moon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The batch of images gives fans a nice glimpse into the world of the animated film, which used facial capture tech to bring some characters to life. Dunkirk star Aneurin Barnard <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/duncan-jones-rogue-trooper-explained-who-is-2000-ads-blue-super-soldier">debuts as the Rogue Trooper</a>, while Clement and Berry can be seen as Mr. Brass and Mr. Bland, two battleground looters who will undoubtedly be a big dose of comic relief.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Rogue Trooper First-Look Images</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans also get to see a large war vehicle traveling across Nu Earth, the planet where the brutal war between the Norts and Southers, two different societies, takes place. The final first look image shows two Souther soldiers lost on the battlefield.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are so excited to share a first look of the film and show the amazing fidelity with which the team have used our actors on set performances to drive the animated characters,” producer Stuart Fenegan said in a statement. “That level of detail and nuance was a priority from day one.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Director Duncan Jones’ comments were simple: “AHHHHHHHHHHHH! WE’RE ALMOST FINISHED! SEE YOU AT SDCC!!” The director will appear at the festival on July 25.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rogue Trooper “tells the story of 19, a ‘Genetic Infantryman,’ who finds himself the sole-survivor of an invasion force. Desperate to track down the traitor who sold him and his comrades out, the super soldier is accompanied by three killed-in-action squad mates, whose personalities have been stored in his gun, helmet and backpack.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside Barnard, Clement, and Berry, the movie boasts an awesome ensemble cast that includes Hayley Atwell, Jack Lowden, Daryl McCormack, Reece Shearsmith, Diane Morgan, Alice Lowe, Asa Butterfield, and Sean Bean.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite getting closer to release with these first look images, the film has yet to set a release date. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lex Briscuso is a film and television critic and a freelance entertainment writer for IGN. You can follow her on Twitter at @nikonamerica.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-movie-director-duncan-jones-returns-with-first-look-at-rogue-trooper-adaptation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's The 12 Best-Selling Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Cards Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-best-sellers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-the-12-best-selling-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-right-now.1227321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards">Final Fantasy Universes Beyond crossover</a> is already proving to be a massive hit. After breaking preorder records, the set is now <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards">flying off shelves and selling out everywhere</a>, with collectors and Commander fans alike scrambling to pick up iconic characters in card form. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you're opening boosters, sorting through prerelease pulls, or keeping tabs on the market for trade value, it's clear this set is drawing serious attention.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're curious which cards are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-magic-the-gathering-best-cards-to-chase-and-buy-today">in highest demand right now</a>, either to cash in or just to see what the hype is all about, we've broken down the top 12 best-selling Final Fantasy cards based on data from trusted marketplace TCGPlayer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve simplified the list for clarity, grouping some variants, like Borderless and Surge Foils, with their base versions, while also noting the specific card number that’s proving most popular (i.e, Aerith Gainsborough - 519). Not every slot is a Mythic Rare either. This list includes a bit of variety to reflect what’s actually trending, while still focusing on the standout cards from the set. Let’s dive in.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">12. Aerith Gainsborough - 519</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/zEggxX?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Aerith Gainsborough</a> is a deceptively powerful engine for life gain and +1/+1 counter strategies. With lifelink built in, she can start growing immediately,every time you gain life, Aerith picks up a +1/+1 counter. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And when she dies, she passes that strength on, putting <em>X</em> +1/+1 counters on each legendary creature you control, where <em>X</em> is the number of counters she had. In the right deck, that can be a game-ending swing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The card’s popularity is reflected in its pricing. The standard print is just $1.83, while the foil version goes for $16.81. For collectors or premium deckbuilders, the borderless version is around $39, but the rare <a href="https://zdcs.link/zEggxX?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>borderless surge foil</strong> sits at a much steeper $140+</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">11. Starting Town - 289</h2><div id="223183" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Starting Town - 289</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Starting Town is an early-game powerhouse, especially in multicolor decks. If you can play it on turn one, two, or three, it enters untapped, giving you immediate access to mana without slowing your tempo. Beyond that, it taps for colorless, or you can pay 1 life to generate one mana of any color, making it a flexible piece in almost any deck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That versatility comes at a price. The <a href="https://zdcs.link/aXW4VZ?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">regular version is currently going for around $14</a>, while the foil will set you back just under $17. Still, for decks that care about fast, reliable mana across multiple colors, it's proving to be well worth the cost.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Summon: Knights of Round - 359</h2><div id="223175" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Summon: Knights of Round - 359 (Borderless)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aBg8gV?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Summon: Knights of the Round</a> is one of the hottest cards from the Final Fantasy crossover right now, and it’s not hard to see why. For just five mana, you create three 2/2 white Knight creature tokens, instantly building a board. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But it gets even better with its [V] ability, Ultimate End, which gives all your other creatures +2/+2 until end of turn and puts an indestructible counter on each of them. Combined with the card’s own indestructible keyword, it turns even a modest board into a nearly unstoppable force.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBg8gV?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">borderless version is currently going for $35.99</a>, which marks a 25% drop in market price this month. The standard print is more budget-friendly at <a href="https://zdcs.link/aeb8K1?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$21.88</a>. Either way, it’s a powerful pickup for Knight, token, or white-based Commander decks, and one that’s likely to remain popular.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Traveling Chocobo - 210</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The chase card of all chase cards, there are just 77 gold foil Traveling Chocobos out there, available. There are other versions, including <a href="https://zdcs.link/z622ER?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Neon Ink versions going for well over $1000</a>, but if you manage to find the gold foil, it is <em><strong>the one</strong></em> you’ll want to find when you’re cracking open <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q477Xd?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Collector Boosters</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Considering how much the ink versions are <em>already</em> going for, I can't imagine how much the Gold Foil variant would actually be valued at, maybe you just win at money and never have to pay for Magic cards again, now that would be nice. But, that being said, one did recently sell for <a href="https://www.wargamer.com/magic-the-gathering/golden-chocobo-40k-sale" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">around $30K on eBay</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Summon: Bahamut - 1</h2><div id="223174" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Summon: Bahamut - 356 (Borderless)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I love a big ol’ dragon in my Magic collection, and Bahamut certainly fits that bill. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not only does this Summon create a 9/9, but it can remove permanents, trigger card draw, and use Mega Flare to essentially finish a game of Commander. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">All yours for around $93 in the borderless variant, or <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJg8rq?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">around $30 for the standard print</a> right now at TCGPlayer.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Lightning, Army of One - 545</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">How many card variants do you NEED? Apparently, Final Fantasy 13’s protagonist, <a href="https://zdcs.link/av48Ab?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Lightning</a>, needs at least five. To be fair, that makes sense considering how many spin off games she got. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Army of One is all about the Stagger mechanic, teeing your foes up for double damage while also offering lifelink, first strike, and trample in a three-cost card. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Market price is already up to around $256.50 for the most popular <a href="https://zdcs.link/92xx6W?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Borderless Surge Foil</a> version, while my personal favorite is seemingly the cheapest (but still just as popular), <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7B4g?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">normal print for $20.58</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Yuna, Hope of Spira - 549</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Yuna's an interesting one, as it's just her <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7OOo8?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">549 Borderless Surge Foil</a> that have drawn the <em>most </em>interest from eager buyers in the secondary market. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yet, her <a href="https://zdcs.link/QVX5wN?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">standard variant</a> is also going through much more of geniune surge in value over the past couple of weeks, rising +143.65% in value, jumping from a low of $5.68 to around $20.15 most recently. It's a big jump in such a short space of time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Tifa Lockhart - 536</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aBg8ob?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Tifa Lockhart</a> continues to be a main stay of the best selling Final Fantasy cards, and even featured as one of the most popular during the presale period just before the Universes Beyond set launched. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tifa has a Landfall trigger that doubles her power alongside her existing Trample keyword. As TCGPlayer points out, you can grow her attack power with something like Titanic Growth and then use Fabled Passage to double it again. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">She’ll set you back between <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q4755k?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$9.10 for the standard version</a>, and all the way up to <a href="https://zdcs.link/91j30q?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$187.60 for the Borderless Surge Foil</a> variant. Otherwise, and quite surprisingly, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObjjO?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">non-foil Borderless version</a> is pretty good value for money at around $25.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Buster Sword - 255</h2><div id="223171" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Buster Sword - 351 (Borderless)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">What’s Cloud without the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z1A1P?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Buster Sword</a>? Thankfully, this iconic weapon gets the treatment it deserves in Magic’s Final Fantasy set, with a stunning borderless version illustrated by Karuta Shiki. It’s more than just a collector’s piece too, it’s a powerful piece of equipment in its own right.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Buster Sword gives the equipped creature +3/+2, making it a serious threat in combat. But the real payoff comes when that creature connects with a player. Not only do you draw a card, but you can immediately cast a spell from your hand with mana value equal to or less than the damage dealt, without paying its cost. </p><div id="223177" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Buster Sword - 255</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, a card this flashy doesn’t come cheap. While current listings on <a href="https://zdcs.link/QqwJw6?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGPlayer hover around $66</a> for the standard issue, it has already sold for as much as <a href="https://zdcs.link/9Z1A1P?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$208.30 this month for its fantastic borderless version</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're a fan of Cloud or just love flashy, high-impact equipment, this is one to watch, and anything under triple digits is looking like a bargain right now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Vivi Ornitier - 248</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy 9 spellcaster <a href="https://zdcs.link/aXW44O?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Vivi Ornitier</a>, by Toshiyuki Itahana (character designer on the game), might just be one of the best cards in the game right now. So, it's hardly surprising that it's standard card is up there as the third most popular in the set currently. Market price isn't too bad either (at least compared to the rest of this list), if you're looking to buy one standalone.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Borderless version is also the absolute definition of a collector’s item if I've ever seen one, and proving to have plenty of interest as well. Both of these can also be considered a top 10 card for collectors, also demanding a rather mighty price at around <a href="https://zdcs.link/av484E?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$72.13 for the former</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJ3J2?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$232.71 for the later</a> in the market right now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Cloud, Midgar Mercenary - 520</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJ342?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Cloud, Midgar Mercenary</a> is, unsurprisingly, by far one of the most popular cards from the Final Fantasy x MTG Universes Beyond set. Low mana cost and double equipment triggers make Cloud very close to Stoneforge Mystic, but with some striking new anime art from Kazto Furuya.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not only is the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJ342?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Borderless Surge Foil</a> variant one of the priciest cards from the new set (sitting at around $466 market), the Borderless, Extended Art, and Normal print all also fetch a pretty penny right now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In terms of popularity, the Borderless Surge Foil is shoulders above the rest, but the Normal print is also exceedingly popular right now according to TCGPlayer, and still one of the top 20 cards players have been chasing since the new set released. Finding any of these, or deciding to buy them out right standalone, are good reasons to get excited. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Sephiroth, Fabled Soldier - 527</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aAg8bw?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Sephiroth, Fabled Soldier - 0527 (Borderless) (Surge Foil)</a> is the most popular card in the game right now, and has surged to a market price of $701.55 this week, up +74.09% just this month. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But it's not the only version that's proving popular either, with the 382 and 317 Borderless, alongside the 115 Normal print also proving to increasingly sought after right now, which is unsurprisingly reflected in the market prices right now as well. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where to Buy Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/19/where-to-buy-mtg-final-fantasy-ign-new-update-1750332391774.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm going to give it to you straight right from the off. It's painfully hard to get hold of any of these sets from major retailers right now. While we saw some big restocks over the past month, pretty much everywhere is sold out of Final Fantasy MTG at the time of writing. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I can provide some handy links to bookmark so you can check back in, but for now, your best chance of securing <em>anything </em>will be via the <a href="https://zdcs.link/a033mN?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">most trusted third-party resellers like TCGPlayer</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Or perhaps, collectors will instead be most interested in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-secret-lair"><u>new Final Fantasy x Secret Lair drops</u></a>, instead. It’s been a busy year for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secret-lair-release-full-release-schedule-2025">Wizards of the Coast’s limited-time mini-sets</a>, and while the company sold out of all three Final Fantasy drops in record time (leaving many disappointed), you can <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRn3lV?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">still get them via third-party sellers</a>... if you're willing to pay the inflated costs, that is.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are a trio of Final Fantasy Secret Lair sets, Weapons, Grimoire, and Game Over, each offering unique art and names for Magic: The Gathering cards. Everything is available in standard and foil, alongside the Japanese variants as well. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But, since they've sold out, you won’t find Secret Lair drops at the same price as you’d find them directly from Wizards of the Coast (<strong>standard $30 nonfoil, $40 rainbow foil</strong>), with most being listed anywhere between <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRn3lV?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>$80-$150 or above</strong></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a huge markup, so if you're looking to buy, be sure you're 100% informed of what you're paying for. You can buy them from eBay, but we’ve always found <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRn3lV?object_uuid=0621f3de-3084-4c97-85b0-358229155561&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGPlayer</a>, while still eBay-owned, to be the most secure and trustworthy way to nab Secret Lair drops post-release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is Gaming Editor @ Daily Star. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay. He's also a tech, gaming, and fitness freelancer seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar, Tom’s Guide, IGN, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This article also includes contributions from Lloyd Coombes. Thanks to <a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/content/article/The-16-Cards-Everybody-Wants-from-MTG%E2%80%94FINAL-FANTASY/3572aa48-a271-40d6-9264-c05125216ec7" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TCGPlayer</a> for the data and information that informed this article.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-best-sellers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>