<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 21:52:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Update Adds Unexpected Visual Issues as Bethesda Works on a Fix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix.1174239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Stop right there!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered"><u>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</u></a> PC players ran into trouble after a surprise update launched today, but Bethesda says a fix is on the way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players woke up to find that Virtuos’ massive re-release received an unexpected update earlier today. With no patch notes or clear answer as to what the update addressed, most proceeded with their play sessions as normal. Others, however, quickly found that the first Oblivion Remastered update was causing more problems than it fixed</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Twon. (@Web3Twon) <a href="https://twitter.com/Web3Twon/status/1915794767478247930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 25, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">“Can't change the upscaling methods anymore,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/oblivion/comments/1k7lsaz/comment/moz0mwp/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user pointed out</u></a>. “It's set to ‘off’ and while the arrows are clickable nothing happens. So I closed the game, disabled fluid motion in the NVidia app (was testing something before the patch came) and started the game again. Loading times for my save are long again and still can't change upscaling settings lol.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Now I am stuck with 40-60 fps in high settings with a 5800X3D and a 5080. Nice patch :D”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While some players haven’t noticed much of a change in performance, others are reporting new struggles related to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/oblivion/comments/1k7lsaz/comment/moz2o4t/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">low framerates</a>. Many have also noted that upscaling settings have been completely closed off, leaving fans with major visual issues ahead of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-launches-big-on-steam-and-its-only-going-to-get-bigger"><u>Oblivion Remastered’s first weekend in players’ hands</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda finally attempted to address concerns with <a href="https://help.bethesda.net/?linkId=100000361536740#en/answer/69841" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post</a> published on its official support page. As for what today’s Oblivion Remastered update was meant to fix, the post explains the patch simply included “a few backend tweaks and nothing directly impacting game play.” Unfortunately, it seems those who own Oblivion Remastered through the Microsoft Store are the ones running into problems with their upscaling and anti-aliasing options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Any graphic settings adjusted prior to the Microsoft Store hotfix are still enabled and function normally," Bethesda clarified. "However, you will temporarily be unable to adjust those settings due to the issue with the settings UI. The team is taking a look and working out a resolution, we will share more info as soon as we can."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For now, there’s no telling when exactly a resolution for what was originally supposed to be an under-the-radar hotfix will arrive. In the meantime, it appears players on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X | S consoles can continue playing with no issue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion launched for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X | S earlier this week. For more on Bethesda’s shadow-drop re-release, you can check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>why Bethesda and Virtuos aimed to maintain the jank of the original game</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago"><u>why some players still love it all these years later</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Is Teasing Something NieR-Related Again in a Cryptic Website Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-is-teasing-something-nier-related-again-in-a-cryptic-website-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-is-teasing-something-nier-related-again-in-a-cryptic-website-update.1174167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-is-teasing-something-nier-related-again-in-a-cryptic-website-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Re-reincarnation.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if you enjoyed NieR: Automata and its predecessor, NieR: Replicant, you could be forgiven for not knowing that game actually got a sequel, and a pretty good one too. Unfortunately, that sequel, mobile game NieR: Re[in]carnation, hasn't been available for almost a year after being taken offline in April of 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But fortunately, a Square Enix website is dropping some pretty wild in-universe hints that this might be about to change.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As pointed out to us on BlueSky by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/thewillarowe.bsky.social/post/3lnnoessmzk2k" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">journalist Willa Rowe</a>, an official NieR website that's currently publishing a NieR special movel to commemorate the series 15th anniversary is teasing something NieR: Re[in]carnation-related via cryptic in-text hints and webpage source code. As a part of today's update to the novel, the <a href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/nier-anniversary/15th-novel/e58f8b/space/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">just-published chapter 4</a> ends with some strange text that reads as follows:</p><blockquote>[WARNING] : Recovery protocol initialized...[ERROR] : Redirecting to backup node: &lt; https://www.jp.square-enix.com/nierreincarnation/ &gt;[INFO] : Analysis comments added to the source code.<br>[FATAL] : Process forcibly halted.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">What does THAT mean? Who knows? But wait, there's more. If you hit "View Source" on that page, there are even more weird teases in the code comments, as hinted at above. They read, in order:</p><blockquote>SECURITY NOTICE: Unauthorized transmission detected. Signal disruption logged. Countermeasure protocol active. Redirecting to backup node: <a href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/nierreincarnation/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.jp.square-enix.com/nierreincarnation/</a></blockquote><blockquote>TODO: Optimize rendering efficiency. Contradictions in "Her" emotions may interfere with signal clarity. Ensure transission remains undistorted.</blockquote><blockquote>FIXME: Visibility settings enabled for crashed observer system. He is watching...Adjust access permissions before deployment. His name is............</blockquote><blockquote>HACK: Log discrepancy detected. Records indicate previous modification attempts due to excessive interference from The Cage. Cross-check against original transmission before proceeding.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Okay, there's a lot here, some of which is inscrutable and some of which makes sense. "The Cage", for instance, is the main location where most of NieR: Re[in]carnation takes place. And "Her" is a key character (yes, that's Her name) in Re[in]carnation as well. Between that and the hyperlink, it's pretty obvious what all this is referencing, but what exactly will become of it remains anyone's guess.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The two final chapters of the novel are scheduled to publish on May 2, a week from today, and it's possible it may also pull back the curtain on whatever's happening here. Fans are speculating that it may be <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NieRReincarnation/comments/1k7l4ym/new_nier_15th_anniversary_web_novel_chapters_14/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">leading up to some sort of port or re-release of NieR: Re[in]carnation</a>, which has been completely unplayable anywhere since it went offline last year. They're also pointing out that the chapters of the special novel, which are currently only available in Japanese (but which fans are translating), have some pretty significant tie-ins to all three other NieR games.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Screens  -  NieR Reincarnation</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're unfamiliar with Re[in]carnation, I highly recommend keeping an eye on this, especially if the end result is another opportunity to play it. Re[in]carnation is a good game in its own right that many slept on due to its being a mobile gacha game, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nier-3-has-been-in-front-of-us-all-along-per-series-creators-tease">critically, it's also the direct sequel to NieR: Automata</a>, and effectively is NieR 3, for those who have been waiting for it. Who knows? Maybe a new Re[in]carnation release could include some new content that ties the ongoing stream of loose NieR-related threads together at last.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Amazes Fans After 20-Year-Old Dupe Item Glitch Is Rediscovered]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-amazes-fans-after-20-year-old-dupe-item-glitch-is-rediscovered</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-amazes-fans-after-20-year-old-dupe-item-glitch-is-rediscovered.1174047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-amazes-fans-after-20-year-old-dupe-item-glitch-is-rediscovered<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda Game Studios and Virtuos’ <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> includes the original’s infamous Dupe Item Glitch – and fans are loving it all over again 20 years later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since the mega-hit remaster launched for PC and consoles earlier this week, Elder Scrolls veterans have been beside themselves as they revisit iconic locations and characters from Bethesda’s classic fantasy RPG. It’s a total visual overhaul that remains so faithful to the original 2006 experience that Virtuos even thought to include some of its more memorable bugs and even a few handy glitches.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In Oblivion Remastered, players have found they’re still able to use a version of the original's Dupe Item Glitch, just the same as they did nearly 20 years ago. It allows the user to duplicate nearly any item in the game, and it only involves navigating through a few menus and a barrel or storage crate. That means unlimited arrows, ingredients, and even infinite money if you’re willing to be patient and haul everything to a merchant after you’re done. You can see our explanation of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/How_to_Do_the_Dupe_Item_Glitch_(Cheat_for_Infinite_Money)"><u>how to do the Dupe Item Glitch here</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s been some debate about a few other Dupe Item Glitch exploits that seem to have been fixed, but the consensus is generally that Virtuos’ move to keep such a niche bug in some capacity is amazing. Now, in 2025, both returning and new Elder Scrolls fans can see Cyrodiil just as it was in 2006, with many important <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago">wrinkles and bumps left intact</a>, and the reaction is impossible to deny.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">To those upset that Oblivion Scroll Duping got Removed I have great news! <br>DUPES ARE BACK BABY!!! <a href="https://t.co/Y21CowLJqq" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/Y21CowLJqq</a></p>— The Spiffing Brit 🫖 (@TheSpiffingBrit) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheSpiffingBrit/status/1915357909355040786?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Haha scroll duping was the first thing I tried to do!</p>— Remonix (@remonixr) <a href="https://twitter.com/remonixr/status/1915363428526330088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Time to fill my house with succulent watermelons <a href="https://t.co/7jGrjdZBaI" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/7jGrjdZBaI</a></p>— Dukeybutt (@duke_of_butts) <a href="https://twitter.com/duke_of_butts/status/1915450671886733553?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered launched for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S Tuesday, April 22, 2025. Bethesda and Virtuos have said their goal was to maintain that classic experience from the jump, going as far as to say that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>they both still consider the re-release to be more remaster than remake</u></a>, despite <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-fans-react-to-all-the-biggest-changes-say-its-good-enough-to-be-called-a-remake"><u>the vast number of changes it offers</u></a>. Although the sentiment has not gone unappreciated, many fans have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-designer-says-bethesdas-remaster-is-so-impressive-it-could-be-called-oblivion-20"><u>still found themselves debating about whether Oblivion Remastered should have actually been called Oblivion Remake</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, you can read about the way Bethesda chose to, once again, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-is-once-again-offering-paid-horse-armor-dlc"><u>include horse armor as DLC</u></a>. You can also check in on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-mods-have-already-been-published-online"><u>how the modding community dived into the remaster just moments after it launched</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-includes-that-iconic-line-flub-from-the-original-game"><u>another iconic bug that made its way into the 2025 release</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've got a comprehensive guide to everything you'll find in Oblivion Remastered, including an expansive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/cyrodiil">Interactive Map</a>, complete Walkthroughs for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Main_Quest_Walkthrough">Main Questline</a> and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Guilds">Guild Quest</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Character_Building_Guide">How to Build the Perfect Character</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Things_to_Do_First_in_Oblivion">Things to Do First</a>, every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/PC_Cheats_and_Console_Commands">PC Cheat Code</a>, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>