<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 15:01:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Is Adding Darth Jar Jar and a Star Wars-Themed Battle Pass for Its Galactic Battle Season]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-is-adding-darth-jar-jar-and-a-star-wars-themed-battle-pass-for-its-galactic-battle-season</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-adding-darth-jar-jar-and-a-star-wars-themed-battle-pass-for-its-galactic-battle-season.1168824/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-is-adding-darth-jar-jar-and-a-star-wars-themed-battle-pass-for-its-galactic-battle-season<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">That galaxy far, far away is coming back to Fortnite in a big way on May 2.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fortnite is celebrating Star Wars in a big way as its next season - Galactic Battle - is arriving on May 2 and will feature not only a Star Wars-themed Battle Pass and a five-part saga with plenty of surprises, but also the arrival of Darth Jar Jar to the Battle Royale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The surprising yet incredible news was shared during <a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/swcj-2025-fortnite-star-wars-galactic-battle" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Star Wars Celebration,</a> and we got a tease of even more of the Star Wars fun headed our way next month, including that Force Lightning will be joining the game as an in-game ability. </p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">✔️ Star Wars Themed Battle Pass<br>✔️ Weekly Gameplay Content<br>✔️ Culminating in a Live End of Season Narrative Event<br> ➡️ Fortnite Galactic Battle arrives May 2, 2025 <a href="https://t.co/JmRStRA2Um" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/JmRStRA2Um</a></p>— Star Wars (@starwars) <a href="https://twitter.com/starwars/status/1913784597055488170?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 20, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It was also confirmed that Emperor Palpatine and mashups like Wookiee Cuddle Team Leader will be part of the Battle Pass, new Item Shop offerings will include Mace Windu, players will be able to pilot and co-pilot X-Wings and TIE Fighters, there will be themed map locations, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the Star Wars saga we will be experiencing, each week will have a "different overarching theme," and they are as follows;</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Imperial Takeover – May 2, 2025</li><li>The Pull of the Force – May 8, 2025</li><li>Mandalorian Rising – May 22, 2025</li><li>Star Destroyer Bombardment – May 29, 2025</li><li>Death Star Sabotage – June 7, 2025</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">And yes, this saga will culminate in an in-game narrative live event that will "surely have players feeling like they've got the fate of the whole galaxy in their hands."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more from Star Wars Celebration, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-mandalorian-grogus-sigourney-weaver-on-grogu-stealing-her-heart-and-more-star-wars-celebration">how The Mandalorian &amp; Grogu's Sigourney Weaver had Grogu steal her heart,</a> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hayden-christensen-on-returning-to-anakin-skywalker-in-ahsoka-and-liking-when-star-wars-goes-dark-star-wars-celebration">our chat with Hayden Christensen about returning to Anakin,</a> how and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-celebration-everything-announced-at-the-mandalorian-and-grogu-panel">all the biggest news from The Mandalorian &amp; Grogu</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-celebration-everything-announced-at-the-ahsoka-panel">Ahsoka,</a> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-celebration-everything-announced-at-the-andor-panel">Andor panels.</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Adam Bankhurst is a writer for IGN. You can follow him on X/Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst</em></a><em> and on </em><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@adambankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>TikTok.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Dragon's Dogma 2, Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii, LEGO Flowers, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-19-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-dragons-dogma-2-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-lego-flowers-and-more.1168713/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-19-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for April 19 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dragon's Dogma 2 for $30</h2><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218963"><div id="218963" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dragon's Dogma 2 - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can score Capcom's massive RPG for just $30 this weekend at Amazon. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragons-dogma-2-review">an 8/10 in our review</a>, stating, "It is a retelling and reimplementation of all of those wonderful ideas from the 2012 cult-classic, including an awesome dynamic world and some of the best combat in the genre that integrates a subtle but amazingly complex physics system."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii for $49.99</h2></div><div id="218604" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218605"><div id="218605" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest Like a Dragon game stars everyone's favorite ex-yakuza, Goro Majima, on an adventure to sail the seas as a pirate. When Majima wakes up unable to remember anything about himself, he embarks on a quest to regain his memories, and of course, in true Like a Dragon fashion, things get crazy. This is the lowest we've seen this game so far, so be sure to pick up a copy while you can.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save 55% Off The 4K Middle-Earth 6-Film Collection</h2></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218597"><div id="218597" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Middle-Earth 6-Film Collection (Extended &amp; Theatrical) (4K Ultra HD + Digital)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/06/29/the-lord-of-the-rings-trilogy-extended-edition-blu-ray-review">The Lord of the Rings trilogy</a> is simply one of the greatest experiences you will ever have. I try my best to watch through the extended editions once each year, but the fun doesn't stop there. There's also The Hobbit trilogy, which is another incredible set of films. This weekend at Amazon, you can score all six films in beautiful 4K for only $94.68. Previously, both trilogies were priced just below this separately, so this is a great deal.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin for $19.99</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218964"><div id="218964" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin is arguably one of the most unique entries in the entire Final Fantasy series. Developed by the team behind Nioh, this action RPG is one you won't forget anytime soon. There are references to numerous Final Fantasy games, with a significant link to a certain character. Oh, and expect plenty of Chaos. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Mario Party Jamboree for $44.99</h2></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218600"><div id="218600" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">With the recent reveal of Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games, it's no question that you are going to want to save anywhere you can. The Nintendo Switch 2 Edition of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-party-jamboree-review">Super Mario Party Jamboree</a> is set to cost $79.99, but you can upgrade from a Nintendo Switch copy for presumably $20. This weekend, save your cash and pick up a copy of Super Mario Party Jamboree from Woot for only $44.99.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Paradise Killer for $25</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218965"><div id="218965" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Paradise Killer - PS4</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This weekend, you can save $15 off a physical PS4 copy of Paradise Killer. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/paradise-killer-review">our 9/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Paradise Killer marries a beautifully repulsive world with a gratifyingly open-ended approach to detective work, but its real achievement is in how it ties everything you’ve learned together."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2825f7cb-7394-4294-b617-5088ae86336d" id="214399"><div id="214399" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>FINAL FANTASY I-VI Collection Anniversary Edition (2024)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection has hit a new all-time low at Woot, priced at just $39.99. The first six Final Fantasy titles paved the way for the series as we see it today. Many fans still regard both Final Fantasy IV and Final Fantasy VI as some of the best that Final Fantasy has to offer, with gripping narratives and engaging gameplay. This package includes all six <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-i-vi-collection">Final Fantasy Pixel Remasters</a>, which feature updated graphics, soundtracks, font, and more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble for $19.99</h2></div><div catalogid="1e543bac-9867-46a6-a1b6-253b329a92e1" id="214670"><div id="214670" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble Launch Edition - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble is the return to form many Monkey Ball fans have waited years for. You've got over 200 courses, tons of guest characters, and all sorts of modes—what's not to love? In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-review">our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble is a brilliant return to form. Monkey Ball has finally found its way home again with a set of 200 fantastic courses that range from delightfully charming to devilishly challenging, backed up by tight mechanics and predictable physics that put me in total control of my monkey’s fate."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save on LEGO Flowers</h2></div><div id="218966" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Sunflowers</h3></p></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218967"><div id="218967" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Daffodils</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, you can save on select LEGO Flowers this weekend ahead of Easter! If you're on the hunt for a last-minute gift, these are a perfect choice for any family member, friend, or significant other.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 19, 2025 7:10 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Car Dealership Tycoon Codes (April 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/car-dealership-tycoon-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/car-dealership-tycoon-codes-april-2025.1168656/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/car-dealership-tycoon-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">If you need some extra cash in Car Dealership Tycoon, check out these redeemable codes!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Need some cash for your Car Dealership Tycoon enterprise? Look no further. We've scoured the web for all of the currently active codes available in Roblox's car-selling sim, so you can keep your business running smoothly with some free cash injections.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/roblox-car-dealership-tycoon-header-1741915610968.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">Active Car Dealership Tycoon Codes (April 2025)</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below, you'll find all of the currently active and working Car Dealership Tycoon codes in April 2025 that you can redeem for free rewards:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>EASTER2</strong> - $80,000 (<strong>NEW!</strong>)</li><li><strong>EASTER2025</strong> - $100,000 </li><li><strong>BARNFIND04</strong> -$80,000 </li><li><strong>SEASON16</strong> - $80,000 </li><li><strong>EVENT03</strong> - $80,000</li><li><strong>ZENVOCOLLECTOR</strong> - $80,000</li><li><strong>Killasfs</strong> - $50,000</li><li><strong>Foxzie</strong> - $15,000</li><li><strong>Tstingray</strong> - $50,000</li><li><strong>IranRan</strong> - $50,000</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Car Dealership Tycoon Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following Car Dealership Tycoon codes have expired and can no longer be redeemed as of April 2025:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>SAUSAGE</li><li>PAGANISALE</li><li>VOLKSWAGEN</li><li>POLICESEASON</li><li>VWCOLLECTOR</li><li>IMMORTAL</li><li>SCAVENGERHUNT</li><li>COLLECTORCAR</li><li>COPSANDCRIMS</li><li>RETURNINGLIM</li><li>NEWLIMITED</li><li>NEWMAP</li><li>XMASUPDATE</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Codes in Car Dealership Tycoon</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/roblox-car-dealership-tycoon-redeeming-codes-1741915610967.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem Car Dealership Tycoon codes, boot up the game and, once you’re in, follow the steps below:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Look at the top of the screen. To the left of the cash counter, you'll see a <strong>settings icon</strong>. It's represented by the <strong>small gear</strong>.</li><li>Click this icon to bring up the <strong>settings menu</strong>. At the very bottom of the settings menu is the <strong>redeem code bar</strong>.</li><li>Input your code into the bar and then press the "<strong>+</strong>" icon beside it to redeem it.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Car Dealership Tycoon Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If your Car Dealership Tycoon code isn’t working, it’s likely due to one of two scenarios. The first is that the code was inputted incorrectly. Check the spelling and that the case is correct, then redeem again. You can even copy and paste the codes directly from this article over to Roblox if you want to make sure you’re inputting them correctly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other possibility is the code has expired or you’ve already used it. In this scenario, you should see an error message appear in the codes bar informing you that the code has already been redeemed or is invalid.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Get More Car Dealership Tycoon Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to hunt down some Car Dealership Tycoon codes on your own, you'll have to scout through several different social accounts for the game. The main spots you should be checking are the <strong>CDT update info </strong>channel in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/foxzie" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">game's official Discord server</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Foxzie/featured" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Foxzie's YouTube channel</a>, and <a href="https://x.com/Foxzie_RBLX" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Foxzie's X account</a>. All three will be updated from time to time with codes, so make sure you're subscribed to each to keep up to date with new code drops.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Car Dealership Tycoon in Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Car Dealership Tycoon is exactly what it says on the tin. You're offered the keys to your very own car dealership, and from there, your mission is to build it, customize it, and purchase new cars to display on the show floor. As you grow, you can take part in a variety of activities to increase your cash flow, including taking to the streets to race other players and avoiding police in high speed chases. So, do you have what it takes to cement your dealership as the go-to hub for the most luxurious rides in the city?</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Callum Williams is an IGN freelancer covering features and guides. When he's away from his desk, you can usually find him obsessing over the lore of the latest obscure indie horror game or bashing his head against a boss in the newest soulslike. You can catch him over on Twitter at @CaIIumWilliams.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Desert Detectors Codes (April 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/desert-detectors-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/desert-detectors-codes-april-2025.1168650/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/desert-detectors-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Want some free Desert Detectors rewards without having to dig a single hole? Lucky for you, we've compiled all of the free redeemable codes currently active in Roblox's popular digging simulator, so you can grab yourself some extra cash and EXP without having to do all that pesky manual labour.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/13/roblox-desert-detectors-header-1741837031231.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2">Active Desert Detectors Codes (April 2025)</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below, you'll find all of the currently active and working Desert Detectors codes in April 2025 that you can redeem for free rewards:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Pyramids</strong> - 200 EXP</li><li><strong>David</strong> - 50 EXP</li><li><strong>Allen</strong> - 70¢</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Desert Detectors Codes</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/13/roblox-desert-detectors-redeeming-codes-1741837031230.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem Desert Detectors codes, boot up the game and, once you’re in, follow the steps below:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Look at the top of the screen. You'll see two buttons: one for the <strong>Menu </strong>and one for the <strong>Shop</strong>. Select the <strong>Menu button</strong>.</li><li>It'll bring you to the menu screen. If you scroll to the very bottom of the menu, you'll see a <strong>codes bar</strong>.</li><li>Input your code into this bar and then hit enter to redeem it.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Desert Detectors Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If your Desert Detectors code isn’t working, it’s likely due to one of two scenarios. The first is that the code was inputted incorrectly. Check the spelling and that the case is correct, then redeem again. You can even copy and paste the codes directly from this article over to Roblox if you want to make sure you’re inputting them correctly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other possibility is the code has expired or you’ve already used it. In this scenario, you should see an error message pop up below the code bar informing you that the code has already been redeemed or is invalid.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Get More Desert Detectors Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to try and track down some of your own Desert Detector codes, your best bet is to head over to the game's <a href="https://discord.com/invite/9bS6p37umn" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>. The server itself is still relatively new, however, it does have a <strong>Codes channel</strong> that promises to have new codes very soon, so make sure to keep an eye out for updates.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Desert Detectors in Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Desert Detectors sends players out on a trip to a vast stretch of open desert, equipping them with nothing but a rusty shovel and a metal detector. From here, they're tasked with searching the vast plains of this barren landscape for rare items, seeking out treasures below the sand. From broken bottles to submerged tanks, they'll dig up all manner of loot that they can sell for cold hard cash, allowing them to spruce up their gear and find even rarer treasures.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Callum Williams is an IGN freelancer covering features and guides. When he's away from his desk, you can usually find him obsessing over the lore of the latest obscure indie horror game or bashing his head against a boss in the newest soulslike. You can catch him over on Twitter at @CaIIumWilliams.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rock Fruit Codes (April 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rock-fruit-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rock-fruit-codes-april-2025.1168641/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/rock-fruit-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're on the hunt for some extra drops in Rock Fruit, your search ends here. Below, we've compiled a list of all the latest redeemable codes for the One-Piece-inspired Roblox game, so you can get your hands on 2x Luck Drops and other free goodies.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/13/roblox-rock-fruit-header-1741901818905.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active Rock Fruit Codes (April 2025)</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below, you'll find all of the currently active and working Rock Fruit codes in April 2025 that you can redeem for free rewards:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>ThxForLike19K</strong> - 1 Hour of 2x Luck (<strong>NEW!</strong>)</li><li><strong>ThxForLike18K</strong> - 1 Hour of 2x Luck (<strong>NEW!</strong>)</li><li><strong>ThxForLike17K</strong> - 1 Hour of 2x Luck (<strong>NEW!</strong>)</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Rock Fruit Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following Rock Fruit codes have expired and can no longer be redeemed as of April 2025:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>ThxForLike14K</li><li>ThxForLike15K</li><li>ThxForLike16K</li><li>AizenHollow</li><li>ThxForLike12K</li><li>AnosXD</li><li>Subaru</li><li>EmiliaXD</li><li>ShadowRingXD</li><li>LVL100</li><li>SorryForDelayXD</li><li>SorryForRollback</li><li>Mita</li><li>Love</li><li>FREECODE11</li><li>Miku</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Rock Fruit Codes</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/13/roblox-rock-fruit-redeeming-codes-1741901818904.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem Rock Fruit codes, boot up the game and, once you’re in, follow the steps below:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Look at the selection of <strong>small icons </strong>on the left-hand side of the screen, just above the menu buttons. Amongst these, you’ll see one that looks like a small blue bird. It's marked by the red circle in the image above.</li><li>Click the bird icon to be taken to the <strong>Codes bar</strong>.</li><li>Type your code into the bar and then hit the <strong>Redeem </strong>button below the bar.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Rock Fruit Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If your Rock Fruit code isn’t working, it’s likely due to one of two scenarios. The first is that the code was inputted incorrectly. Check the spelling and that the case is correct, then redeem again. You can even copy and paste the codes directly from this article over to Roblox if you want to make sure you’re inputting them correctly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other possibility is the code has expired or you’ve already used it. In this scenario, you should see an error message pop up at the top of the screen informing you that the code has already been redeemed or is invalid.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Get More Rock Fruit Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">To keep up to date with Rock Fruit codes, you'll want to keep an eye on several different sources. You can become a member of the game's <a href="https://discord.com/invite/WJzq2UnXNy" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>, scan the description on the <a href="https://www.roblox.com/games/95295765150201/X30-Enchant-and-Boost-Item-NEW-Rock-Fruit" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official Roblox page</a> and visit <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@KuduroDPN666/featured" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KuduroDPN's YouTube channel</a>, where codes are often shared in <strong>videos</strong> and <strong>posts</strong>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Rock Fruit in Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Rock Fruit is a One-Piece-inspired action game where players explore an open-world ocean with the goal of growing stronger. They'll fight a variety of enemies, explore dungeons and take on towering bosses to amass experience and level up, bolstering their skills while acquiring new weapons and Devil Fruit powers, which allow them to unleash flashy special attacks that do huge damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Callum Williams is an IGN freelancer covering features and guides. When he's away from his desk, you can usually find him obsessing over the lore of the latest obscure indie horror game or bashing his head against a boss in the newest soulslike. You can catch him over on Twitter at @CaIIumWilliams.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>