<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 12:33:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Boosters Are Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remastered-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remastered-boosters-are-up-for-preorder.1021788/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remastered-where-to-buy<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's Halloween (In January)</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section><p data-cy="paragraph">Return to the plane of Innistrad, where dark alleys, looming forests, and fearsome creatures beckon. With the new <a href="https://zdcs.link/aepZXw?object_uuid=a5957ba2-5bff-42d1-a1af-a48c0dce12c8&amp;t=article&amp;_ga=1195960001.1647009307" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered sets</a>, fans of the spooky and supernatural can rediscover classic cards with fresh new twists. As luck would have it, booster boxes are on sale at Amazon before release day. Let's take a look.</p><p id="magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remas"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remas">Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Play Booster Box - 36 Packs </h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">This 36-pack Play Booster Box, discounted to <strong>$219.99</strong> from its original $251.64, is a great deal for collectors and players. Inside each pack, you'll find 14 cards, with every booster holding surprises, like <strong>Retro-frame cards</strong>, Rare or higher rarity cards, and potential art cards that showcase updated visuals for this eerie set. Each pack offers:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>1–4 Rare or higher cards</strong> with alternate art or unique border treatments for that classic Innistrad chill.</li><li><strong>1 Traditional Foil card</strong> every time, and a 20% chance of a Foil Land to add a wicked gleam to your decks.</li><li><strong>Art cards</strong> unique to Play Boosters, some with foil signatures straight from the artist's pen!</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">With 504 cards in total, this box brings back the spooky thrills of the original set while adding modern touches and rare finds for fans, old and new.</p><div id="209783" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="49af1f34-79cd-494d-8361-5c2e7c2f7cff"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Play Booster Box - 36 Packs (504 MTG Cards)</h3></p></div><p id="magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remas"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remas">Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Collector Boosters - 12 Packs</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who crave something a little more hauntingly special, the <strong>Collector Booster Box</strong> is discounted to <strong>$329.99</strong> from $359.88. This premium box includes 12 packs, each with 15 cards, and is loaded with exclusive extras:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>500 serialized Edgar Markov cards</strong> (available only in Collector Boosters) for a one-of-a-kind find.</li><li><strong>6 alternate-frame cards</strong> per pack, including Movie Poster art that reimagines Magic's iconic characters as classic movie monsters.</li><li><strong>Exclusive Retro-frame cards</strong>, high-rarity pulls, and Movie Poster treatment cards ramp up the gothic horror.</li><li></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Collector Boosters are packed with premium foils and special frames—an absolute treat for fans who want their collection to have a little extra bite.</p><div id="209784" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="49af1f34-79cd-494d-8361-5c2e7c2f7cff"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Collector Boosters - 12 Packs (180 MTG Cards)</h3></p></div><p id="magic-the-gathering-innistrad-remas"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remas">Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Collector Booster - 1 Pack (15 MTG Cards)</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Single packs are also available from the above, although they're not on sale right now. If you want to get some big savings for MTG Innistrad Remastered, a booster box preorder is the way to go!</p><div catalogid="49af1f34-79cd-494d-8361-5c2e7c2f7cff" id="209785"><div id="209785" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Innistrad Remastered Collector Booster - 1 Pack (15 MTG Cards)</h3></p></div><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>The Original Innistrad Set &amp; Remastered Enhancements</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The original Innistrad set, released in 2011, is a legend in its own right. Known for its gothic horror theme, it introduced fans to innovative mechanics like double-faced cards that allowed creatures to transform—turning villagers into werewolves, for instance, by the light of the full moon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With strong tribal mechanics for Vampires, Zombies, Spirits, Humans, and Werewolves, the set quickly became a favorite, bringing a whole new depth to Magic: The Gathering's story-driven gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Innistrad Remastered stays true to the original's essence, bringing back these memorable features while introducing fresh elements like Retro-frames, Movie Poster treatments, and modern art that pays homage to Innistrad's dark, sinister themes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The result is a stunning mix of nostalgia and innovation, giving old fans and newcomers a chance to enjoy the best of this gothic world with some modern flair.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ready to relive the chills of Innistrad and add some of its horrors to your decks? Grab these deals while they last, and add a bit of spine-tingling magic to your collection.</p><p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Magic: The Gathering - Marvel Collaboration Slideshow</h3></div></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Keep an eye out on IGN as we watch over the best <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-magic-the-gathering-mtg-deals">deals for Magic: The Gathering</a> over Black Friday and on socials via <a href="https://x.com/IGNDeals" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@IGNDeals</a>. Plus, for a glimpse into the future, take a look through our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-full-release-schedule-2024">comprehensive guide on the upcoming MTG releases</a> and a quick review of the sets already launched this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Christian Wait is a UK-based freelancer for IGN, you can follow him @ChrisReggieWait on Twitter/X.</p></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 29, 2024 10:35 am</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>