<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:26:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Previous James Bond Movie Snub, Fans Think Lana Del Rey Has Recorded The Theme Song For 007: First Light]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/after-previous-james-bond-movie-snub-fans-think-lana-del-rey-has-recorded-the-theme-song-for-007-first-light</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-previous-james-bond-movie-snub-fans-think-lana-del-rey-has-recorded-the-theme-song-for-007-first-light.1329250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Lana Del Rey looks to have gotten a second chance at recording a James Bond theme, this time for the upcoming video game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/007-first-light">007 First Light</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eagle-eyed fans on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/lanadelrey/comments/1oaryb3/lana_del_rey_has_registered_a_new_song_titled/?share_id=NmcnXgVLuzq0l8yQVVla2" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reddit</a> have spotted a fresh song titled "First Light" that has been registered by Del Rey, real name Elizabeth Grant, to the ASCAP (American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While not a full confirmation, Del Rey performing the game's theme would be a neat fit, after the singer's 2005 track "24" was snubbed for Daniel Craig outing Spectre, the franchise's 24th movie. IGN has contacted IO Interactive for more.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/20/gettyimages-2239353784-1760954344089.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Lana Del Rey. Image credit: Vittorio Zunino Celotto/Getty Images for Valentino.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Last year, Del Rey revealed she had written that track as a Bond theme, only for Sam Smith's "Writing's On the Wall" to ultimately get picked instead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I wrote that for them," Del Rey told <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cv22mmnjrnyo" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BBC News</a> previously. "Sam, you did a wonderful job. One day, maybe... But I'm going to continue to do my little Nancy Sinatra thing every now and then and just pretend it's the title track."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Bond franchise typically commissions several potential theme songs for each movie release, with numerous "lost" Bond tracks recorded by famous artists over the years. Johnny Cash recorded a theme for Thunderball, for example, while Pulp had a take on Tomorrow Never Dies. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">007 First Light screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And, like Del Ray, Radiohead also recorded a theme for Spectre (just titled "Spectre") which they also previously released.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the promising-looking 007 First Light, developer IO Interactive seems more than happy teasing details out over time — such as the long-awaited confirmation that, yes, Dexter: Original Sin's Patrick Gibson is indeed playing its fresh-faced Bond. More recently, we also learned that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/007-first-light-adds-marvel-star-gemma-chan-to-james-bond-game-cast">Marvel star Gemma Chan will also portray a character in the game</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">007 First Light has set a release date of March 27, 2026, for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S and Nintendo Switch 2.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Before then, we've got plenty more on 007 First Light, including a report on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hitman-dev-io-interactive-put-daniel-craigs-head-on-agent-47-when-pitching-for-james-bond-game-007-first-light">how Daniel Craig’s face was put into a Hitman map in order to secure the Bond rights</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/it-was-fairly-small-it-did-feel-significant-how-the-death-of-the-queen-forced-io-to-tweak-007-first-light">how Queen Elizabeth II’s passing affected First Light’s development</a>. And be sure to check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/007-first-light-is-the-hitman-and-uncharted-hybrid-i-wanted-it-to-be">extensive 007 First Light preview full of gameplay and story details</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Vittorio Zunino Celotto/Getty Images for Valentino.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/after-previous-james-bond-movie-snub-fans-think-lana-del-rey-has-recorded-the-theme-song-for-007-first-light]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Ends 'Server Slam' Playtest With Big Steam Concurrents, Suggesting Strong Launch Ahead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-ends-server-slam-playtest-with-big-steam-concurrents-suggesting-strong-launch-ahead</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-ends-server-slam-playtest-with-big-steam-concurrents-suggesting-strong-launch-ahead.1329244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> has ended its 'Server Slam' playtest with a big peak concurrent player number on Steam, suggesting a strong launch is ahead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The open Server Slam ran over the weekend on PC via Steam and Epic Games Store, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. It offered the final chance to play Embark Studios' extraction shooter ahead of its October 30 release date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On Steam, Arc Raiders hit a peak concurrent player count of 189,668, making it one of the most-played games on Valve’s platform over the weekend. That's enough to make Arc Raiders the biggest extraction shooter ever on Steam. Escape from Tarkov might have something to say about that when it finally launches on Steam in November, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders' true peak concurrent player number across all platforms will be higher than the Steam figure, but neither Epic, Sony, nor Microsoft make their numbers public.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, 190,000 on Steam for an open beta is very strong. Not Battlefield 6 strong — its open beta peaked with more than half a million players in August — but certainly strong enough to suggest Arc Raiders has a decent chance of making an impression on the gaming landscape at the end of the month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Server Slam let players test the Dam Battlegrounds map for a hands-on experience with elements of the game’s progression, crafting, and quest systems. It was designed to help Embark "challenge and fortify the game’s servers before launch," which hopefully means everything will work as it should on release day. All participants earned an exclusive 'Server Slammer' backpack cosmetic reward, unlocked when the full game launches. Progress from the Server Slam does not carry over, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Embark Studios' previous game, free-to-download competitive shooter The Finals, is still going, although its concurrent player numbers on Steam are a far cry from those during its explosive launch back in December 2023.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-ends-server-slam-playtest-with-big-steam-concurrents-suggesting-strong-launch-ahead]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>