<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:33:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phil Spencer Responds to Microsoft’s 'This Is an Xbox' Ad Campaign, Which Is Already a Meme]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/phil-spencer-responds-to-microsofts-this-is-an-xbox-ad-campaign-which-is-already-a-meme</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phil-spencer-responds-to-microsoft%E2%80%99s-this-is-an-xbox-ad-campaign-which-is-already-a-meme.1036620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/phil-spencer-responds-to-microsofts-this-is-an-xbox-ad-campaign-which-is-already-a-meme<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Console yourself.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft gaming boss Phil Spencer has responded to the launch of the company’s 'This Is An Xbox' ad campaign, which is already a meme online.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, Microsoft launched a new advertising campaign designed to hammer home the fact that you can play Xbox pretty much on any device and anywhere, sparking yet more backlash at the company’s console strategy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The ‘This is an Xbox’ campaign includes images of cats and a bento box among other devices that play video games. The idea Microsoft is trying to get across, which is in keeping with its previous messaging, is that Xbox is less about consoles these days and more about being able to play on any device capable of playing a video game. So, in this sense, a TV is an Xbox, a phone is an Xbox, etc.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/15/tiaxb-16x9-asset-r1-1-0f22101df1dfc3cb6000-1731666374471.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Microsoft's new 'This is an Xbox' advertising campaign is already a meme. Image credit: Microsoft.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That hasn’t gone down well with core Xbox fans already dissatisfied with Microsoft’s gaming strategy in recent years. Not only have they seen the Xbox console fade from importance as sales of the Xbox Series X and S collapse, but the Xbox console exclusive become extinct.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a new interview with <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/xbox-console-future-cloud-ceo-phil-spencer-1235166597/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rolling Stone</a>, Xbox CEO Phil Spencer discussed the future of the Xbox brand as well as the advertising campaign. “It’s an interesting topic because as we look at the brand, as we’re changing the brand, [it] means something different,” Spencer said. “It literally was a box when it first launched. It was the Direct X box. What it’s grown into now is more accessibility. Xbox isn’t just one device, Xbox is on your smart TV, Xbox is on your PC, Xbox is on your phone, and we’re in the middle of that transition.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to Rolling Stone, Spencer acknowledged that some fans would be turned off by the campaign. Some people “long for the simplicity of a single box, single platform, single game,” he said, before insisting “today’s largest games are bigger than any of the individual platforms.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s a nod to the likes of Fortnite and Roblox, which have become enormous platforms with monthly player counts comparable to the likes of Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo consoles. For Spencer, then, the focus is on the games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I think the thing that should really have longevity are the games, characters and world — and the platforms should enable us to experience those games where we want to play,” he said. “That’s how we think about Xbox today.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: Microsoft.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard Wondered if Starfield Should Have Delayed Buggies for Shattered Space]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/todd-howard-wondered-if-starfield-should-have-delayed-buggies-for-shattered-space</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/todd-howard-wondered-if-starfield-should-have-delayed-buggies-for-shattered-space.1036509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/todd-howard-wondered-if-starfield-should-have-delayed-buggies-for-shattered-space<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Xbox boss Phil Spencer shares one of Howard's key takeaways from the Shattered Space expansion.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Shattered Space hasn't fared terribly well among fans since releasing back in September, sitting at a Mostly Negative rating among fans on Steam. Most of the comments center around the quest's story, though there's plenty of broader criticism for Starfield itself. But Todd Howard seems to have his own theory on why Shattered Space might not have gone down as well as it should have.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with the <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/xbox-phil-spencer-blizzard-avowed-south-of-midnight" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game File newsletter</a>, Phil Spencer said "we're always learning" when talking about how to approach expansions, and mentioned a conversation he had with Howard about the release cadence for content. Howard focused in on the buggy, which was surprise released during <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a> ahead of the expansion.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Todd and I were talking about Shattered Space. Starfield is a game I put a ton of hours into and really love, but they've had this thing where they've added features throughout the year and then they had an expansion," Spencer said. “I think some of the feedback on the expansion is: ‘We wanted more features.’ And he's like, ‘Well, should we have waited to put buggies out?'"</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He continued, "And so, I think you're trying to tune both development effort and the impact of the expansion. And I think there will always be a balance to managing the game month to month. But not every game will do expansions.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ultimately, though, Shattered Space was criticized more for its lack of space content than its lack of ground content. We wrote in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfield-shattered-space-review">review</a>, "As far as I can tell there’s absolutely nothing added for spacefarers other than now you have a way to legitimately acquire Va’ruun ships instead of stealing them from Zealots who attack you in space. That’s fine, as an expansion doesn’t always have to meaningfully expand every aspect of a game – but I was surprised that there wasn’t at least a token feature thrown in for space jockeys in an expansion with 'space' in the title."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Spencer, he shares various other thoughts about Xbox's game lineup in the interview, including some of the biggest surprises (Blizzard and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/south-of-midnight">South of Midnight</a> among them) and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/avowed-we-finally-played-obsidians-first-person-rpg-and-its-fantastic">Avowed's release timing</a>. Xbox also launched a new marketing campaign today called "This is Xbox," which highlighted various items that may or may not be an Xbox.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Kat Bailey is IGN's News Director as well as co-host of Nintendo Voice Chat. Have a tip? Send her a DM at @the_katbot.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Wireless Controllers Drop to as Low as $34.99 Ahead of Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-wireless-controller-early-black-friday-deal-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-wireless-controllers-drop-to-as-low-as-34-99-ahead-of-black-friday.1036461/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-wireless-controller-early-black-friday-deal-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Choose from eight different colors and designs.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Lenovo is pushing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-deals-black-friday-what-to-expect-2024">Black Friday</a> pricing on Xbox controllers earlier than we expected. Starting today, you can pick up an official Microsoft Xbox Series X|S wireless controller for as low as $34.99 after you apply coupon code "<strong>PLAYXBOX</strong>". Seven different color schemes are on sale right now. Most of them are $39.99, however the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QODr6j?object_uuid=89f7cad3-7ec0-47ff-92e8-eff3ce8cebba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Velocity Green controller</a> is $5 cheaper than the rest at $34.99. These controllers are compatible with Xbox Series X and S consoles as well as your PC.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Controllers for $34.99-$39.99</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Aesthetics aside, these Xbox wireless controllers are identical to the one that's bundled with the Xbox Series X and S console. Standard features include textured grips, hybrid D-pad, button mapping with the Xbox app, a 3.5mm audio jack that works with any wired headset, and a Share button to upload screenshots and video.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The controller supports both Xbox wireless and Bluetooth connectivity. That means you can use it for your PC or mobile device. In fact, we think this is the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-pc-controller">the best PC controller</a> you can get. If your PC doesn't have Bluetooth, you can still use it in wired mode with a USB Type-C cable or go out and buy a Bluetooth or <a href="https://zdcs.link/68q2q?object_uuid=89f7cad3-7ec0-47ff-92e8-eff3ce8cebba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox wireless adapter</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">21% Off Xbox Controller Ghost Cipher Edition</h2><div catalogid="8fa90ed1-86ec-414d-be96-83dd906b5cd6" id="210762"><div id="210762" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox Wireless Controller Ghost Cipher Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/aMvbE1?object_uuid=89f7cad3-7ec0-47ff-92e8-eff3ce8cebba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ghost Cipher Edition</a> is an absolutely gorgeous controller, with a translucent clear top case, rubberized ash gray grips, metallic bronze triggers and D-pad, and a solid white back. The interior components are colored silver to match the overall theme.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Get the Sky Cipher Controller as Part of a Bundle Discount</h2></div><div catalogid="8fa90ed1-86ec-414d-be96-83dd906b5cd6" id="208693"><div id="208693" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K Max, Xbox Controller, and Game Pass Ultimate Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A similar looking edition is the Sky Cipher controller, which features the same trasparent casing but in blue instead of clear. It's available on Amazon as part of an <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjG45P?object_uuid=89f7cad3-7ec0-47ff-92e8-eff3ce8cebba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Cloud Gaming Bundle</a>, which includes the controller, an Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K Max, and one month of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, all for only $79.99. Better yet, this bundle will allow you to play Game Pass games without having to own an Xbox console.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3 Months of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate for $29.19</h2></div><div catalogid="d0a019c2-b31e-4e7b-afdb-2a73c34152bd" id="148732"><div id="148732" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>3 Months of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Membership</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Multiple digital codes can be stacked. Last chance!</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Woot! (which is owned by Amazon) is offering the best deal on <a href="https://zdcs.link/Ey5ky?object_uuid=89f7cad3-7ec0-47ff-92e8-eff3ce8cebba&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a>. For today only, you can get a 3 month code for only $29.19 after code "<strong>TWENTY</strong>". Earlier this year, Microsoft <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-price-hikes-were-inevitable-analysts-say">raised the price of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a> to $19.99 per month, so now you're saving 40% off a 3 month membership. Note that you can purchase multiple codes and apply them to your account, up to a maximum of 36 months. If you're an Xbox gamer, this is a great way to save a lot of money in the long run since you won't have to buy new release games individually to play them.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Gift Cards Are on Sale at Amazon</h2></div><div id="210705" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="3432ae1d-309c-45dd-8db4-0708c5b8eb3a"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>PlayStation $100 Gift Card</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>10% off deal is available on from $250 to $10 gift cards.</p></div></div><div catalogid="3432ae1d-309c-45dd-8db4-0708c5b8eb3a" id="210706"><div id="210706" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox $100 Gift Card</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>10% off deal is available on from $100 to $10 gift cards.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-black-friday-2024-when-will-the-sale-start-this-year">Amazon</a> Prime members can get 10% off Xbox gift cards and PlayStation Store gift cards. We only see this deal come around a few times a year and it's usually only for smaller denominations. This time around you can get up to a $100 Xbox gift card or $250 PlayStation gift card and still get the discount.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">When Is Black Friday 2024?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The actual date of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> in 2024 falls on November 29 this year, but the deals season will begin a lot sooner than that. Leading up to the big event, retailers will begin to open deals online. This usually <strong>starts in the last week of October</strong>, just before Halloween. Each week leading up to the event will slowly roll out more deals, which ultimately leads to massive discounts on Black Friday. Retailers will not reveal their biggest Black Friday deals until the big day, but most general deals will be available well in advance.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 15, 2024 3:15 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>