<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 16:21:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Patch Notes Sure Make It Sound Like BioWare’s Basically Done With the Game Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-patch-notes-sure-make-it-sound-like-biowares-basically-done-with-the-game-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-patch-notes-sure-make-it-sound-like-bioware%E2%80%99s-basically-done-with-the-game-now.1091094/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-patch-notes-sure-make-it-sound-like-biowares-basically-done-with-the-game-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> developer BioWare has released a new patch for the game and in the same breath suggested it’s basically done with it less than three months after launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/looks-like-dragon-age-the-veilguard-just-received-its-final-major-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a>, Patch 5 includes just one quality-of-life improvement and a number of bug fixes, but it’s the wording from BioWare that suggests this is the final major patch Dragon Age: The Veilguard will get.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Thank you all for playing Dragon Age: The Veilguard; we were so happy with the game’s stability at launch and hope you have enjoyed our Quality of Life patches since then,” <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/games/dragon-age/dragon-age-the-veilguard/news/patch-5-release-notes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BioWare said</a>. “With the game being in a stable place, we are moving to monitor for any game-breaking bugs should those occur. Dareth shiral!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Moving to monitor game-breaking bugs sounds like players shouldn’t expect any new content. And as Eurogamer points out, "dareth shiral" means "farewell" in Dragon Age's Elvish language.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Age: The Veilguard was the first new game in the fantasy RPG series in 10 years, but it came and went not with a bang but a whimper. Amid the launch <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-no-dragon-age-the-veilguard-expansion-dlc-mass-effect-5">BioWare confirmed Dragon Age: The Veilguard wouldn’t get any post-launch DLC</a>, shocking fans who had hoped for expansions as previous Dragon Age games had received.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, publisher and owner EA admitted <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-had-15-million-players-in-first-two-months-ea-expected-3-million">Dragon Age: The Veilguard had failed to meet sales expectations by a whopping 50%</a>; it had expected three million players, but the game managed only 1.5 million.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's been some smoke around Dragon Age: The Veilguard's struggles, such as it receiving a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-cyber-monday-deal-2024">significant discount just a month after launch</a> for Cyber Monday, and the departure of its director, Corinne Busche, from BioWare just last week. We've <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-bioware-finally-got-dragon-age-to-the-finish-line-after-a-tumultuous-decade">chronicled some of the game's development challenges already</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs">layoffs</a> and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-4-creative-director-left-bioware">departure</a> of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-casey-hudson-mark-darrah-to-leave-studio-all-current-projects-planned-to-continue">several project leads</a> at different stages.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mass-effect-next-chapter">Mass Effect 5</a> now appears to be BioWare’s focus, although it seems far, far away still. And what next for Dragon Age? Given how Dragon Age: The Veilguard went for EA, it seems the publisher will take some convincing to greenlight yet another sequel any time soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 14 Director Yoshi-P Threatens Legal Action Against 'Stalking' Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-director-yoshi-p-threatens-legal-action-against-stalking-mod</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-14-director-yoshi-p-threatens-legal-action-against-stalking-mod.1091088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-director-yoshi-p-threatens-legal-action-against-stalking-mod<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">In early 2025, a Final Fantasy 14 mod sparked "stalking" fears amid <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/final-fantasy/final-fantasy-14-communities-panic-as-it-turns-out-change-to-blacklisting-meant-to-help-reduce-stalking-also-lets-players-use-mods-to-track-their-alts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>reports</u></a> it was able to scrape hidden player data, including details like character information, retainer information, any alternate characters linked to a Square Enix account, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The mod, named “Playerscope,” allows users to track specific player data of anyone in the vicinity of the person using it. This information is then sent to a centralized database managed by the mod author (no matter if you are looking at a specific player, or just happen to be around other players), and tracks information that players would usually not be permitted to see via in-game tools.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Specifically, the mod offers information on “Content ID” and “Account ID,” which can be used to track players across characters. This was done by manipulating the Content ID system introduced in the Dawntrail expansion, which in turn let players blacklist others across their service account and multiple characters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The only way to prevent your account data being scraped by the tool is to join the private Discord channel for Playerscope and opt out. Theoretically, every single Final Fantasy 14 player who is not in the Discord channel is having their data scraped. Obviously this is a significant privacy risk, and the community has been vocal in its response: “the purpose is obvious, to stalk people” one commenter noted <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Shuggler123/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>on Reddit</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Several weeks ago the mod author posted on Discord that the plugin was found on Github, which led to an explosion in popularity. Due to terms of service violations, Playerscope has now <a href="https://github.com/sicakbirtebessum/PlayerScope/tree/master/PlayerScope" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>been removed from Github</u></a>, but it was allegedly mirrored on similar websites Gittea and Gitflic. IGN has verified that a Playerscope repository no longer exists on either alternative platform. Theoretically, the mod could also still be circulating in private communities.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/24/gettyimages-1232398922-1737727396150.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Final Fantasy 14 producer and director Naoki 'Yoshi-P' Yoshida. Photo by Olly Curtis/Future Publishing via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy 14 producer and director Naoki 'Yoshi-P' Yoshida has now issued a statement on <a href="https://forum.square-enix.com/ffxiv/threads/515102" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Final Fantasy 14’s official forum</u></a> regarding third-party mods, clearly referencing the emergence of Playerscope. The statement reads:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We have confirmed that there exist third-party tools that are being used to check Final Fantasy 14 character information that is not displayed during normal game play. The tool is being used to display a segment of an Final Fantasy 14 character's internal account ID, which is then used in an attempt to further correlate information on other characters on the same Final Fantasy 14 service account.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The Development and Operations teams are aware of the situation and the concerns being raised by the community and are discussing the following options:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Requesting that the tool in question be removed and deleted.</li><li>Pursuing legal action.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">"Aside from character information that can be checked in-game and on the Lodestone, we have received concerns that personal information registered on a user’s Square Enix account, such as address and payment information, could also be exposed with this tool. Please rest assured that it is not possible to access this information using these third-party tools.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We strive to offer and maintain a safe environment for our players, which is why we ask everyone to refrain from using third-party tools. We also ask that players do not share information about third-party tools such as details about their installation methods, or take any other actions to assist in their dissemination.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The use of third-party tools is prohibited by the Final Fantasy 14 User Agreement and their usage could threaten the safety of players. We will continue to take a firm stance against their usage."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the use of third-party tools is prohibited in Final Fantasy 14, the likes of Advanced Combat Tracker is regularly used by the game's raiding community and cross-referenced using websites like <a href="https://www.fflogs.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>FFlogs</u></a>. Yoshida's legal threat, however, is a significant step up in rhetoric. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">The FF14 community responds</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Final Fantasy 14 community has responded to Yoshida’s statement in damning fashion. One user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxivdiscussion/comments/1i8rn8v/comment/m8vv5ch/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said</u></a>: “fixing the game to break the mod isn’t on the list of options they’re considering I see.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another player <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxivdiscussion/comments/1i8rn8v/comment/m8w9nnq/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>added</u></a>: “or you could just see how not to expose the information on [the player’s] client side. Ofc this means extra work which they did not plan for, but is Final Fantasy 14 really on such a tight schedule and budget they can't deal with these things properly?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Kind of a disappointing statement that really fails to acknowledge the root cause of the problem,"  <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxivdiscussion/comments/1i8rn8v/yoship_forum_post_regarding_external_tools_that/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>another person said</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The author of Playerscope has yet to respond.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Olly Curtis/Future Publishing via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Mortal Kombat 1 Community Is Working Together to Try to Figure Out How to Fight Floyd — but the Exact Process Remains a Mystery for Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-mortal-kombat-1-community-is-working-together-to-try-to-figure-out-how-to-fight-floyd-but-the-exact-process-remains-a-mystery-for-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-mortal-kombat-1-community-is-working-together-to-try-to-figure-out-how-to-fight-floyd-%E2%80%94-but-the-exact-process-remains-a-mystery-for-now.1091085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-mortal-kombat-1-community-is-working-together-to-try-to-figure-out-how-to-fight-floyd-but-the-exact-process-remains-a-mystery-for-now<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Mortal Kombat 1’s big Conan the Barbarian update launched this week and with it came <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mortal-kombat-1s-secret-floyd-fight-isnt-just-a-cool-easter-egg-it-unlocks-a-brand-new-stage">the arrival of a secret fight with Floyd</a>, the pink ninja developer Ed Boon had been teasing for years. Not only that, but if you defeat Floyd you unlock cool exclusive rewards, including a coveted new stage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But how exactly do you trigger the secret Floyd fight? Players are working together to try to crowdsource the answer. This community effort, led by Mortal Kombat modder and dataminer <a href="https://x.com/thethiny" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">thethiny</a>, has done much to unravel the mystery, but the exact process remains unknown.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s what fans have worked out: a number of Floyd challenges must be completed before the fight with Floyd triggers. How many, no-one knows. Which challenges must be completed, and in which order? No-one knows that either. Worse, it appears different for each player. That’s not much help, is it?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">What is helping is thethiny’s <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Yh5hLG2oi85zvyFvLkl4cCNViDRHX83y-Qn1LdlGozg/htmlview#" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Doc</a> that lists the various challenges players have discovered and the requirements for each. When you’ve completed a challenge the Floyd icon will pop up on the left of the screen and you’ll hear a guitar riff. Requirements include taunting four times in a match, winning without jumping, and winning using sweeps only. Some of these challenges can be completed using any character, some with certain characters only. 37 Floyd clues have been discovered so far. Maybe there are more!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It appears to be the case that you do not have to complete all 37 Floyd challenges to fight Floyd. It also appears to be the case that players have different “active” challenges, so there isn’t a single process fans can rely upon. It's all a bit confusing, but the best advice right now is to do as many of these challenges as you can, and eventually, hopefully, you'll fight Floyd.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Occasionally, Floyd himself will appear at the start of the match to give you a clue (klue?) to one of your active challenges. Thethiny's data suggests it can take hundreds of ladder matches to get one of these clues from Floyd to pop up. Players are working through all this right now, and some are spending a lot of time doing so. Some are trying to increase their chances by restarting matches, but that comes with the risk of missing the Floyd clue because they only appear at the end of the match.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What is clear is that the Floyd fight has breathed new life into Mortal Kombat 1. The new stage, the field seen in Mortal Kombat 1’s announcement trailer, is gorgeous, so the reward for all this effort is a good one. And Floyd himself is sparking a deeper dive as modders try to work out the details of his moveset and which characters from the Mortal Kombat games have inspired it. It’s just a whole lot of fun to be a part of and watch unfold.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mortal-kombat-1-dev-chief-ed-boon-teases-t-1000-fatality-and-future-dlc">we’ve got the T-1000 guest character to look forward to</a>, and potentially more DLC to come, although NetherRealm has yet to confirm that. Hopefully whatever happens, the developer will throw in more secret fights over time, perhaps with Mortal Kombat’s iconic Pit stage as a reward.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Director Says Cloud and Aerith Relationship Comments Were Misinterpreted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-director-says-cloud-and-aerith-relationship-comments-were-misinterpreted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-director-says-cloud-and-aerith-relationship-comments-were-misinterpreted.1091028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-director-says-cloud-and-aerith-relationship-comments-were-misinterpreted<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</a> director Naoki Hamaguchi has said his previous comments on the nature of Cloud and Aerith's relationship were misinterpreted and that no member of Square Enix will comment officially on the character's relationship.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A December interview with <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-game-awards-interview-aerith" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Inverse</a> quoted Hamaguchi as saying "Aerith has always been this sort of sisterly character pulling Cloud along and encouraging him," leading many fans to complain or question the director about the true nature of their relationship.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy 7, both the original and the first two games in its Remake Trilogy, has always portrayed Cloud's relationship with Aerith and Tifa rather vaguely. Player choice can influence their interactions, prompting things like a date with different characters depending on how the player, as Cloud, treats  them. The "canon" relationship has long been debated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans were therefore shocked when Hamaguchi appeared to have essentially dismissed Aerith as a romantic partner in his comments, though he has now told <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/cloud-and-aerith-are-not-like-brother-and-sister-final-fantasy-vii-rebirths-director-speaks-out-about-misinterpretation-of-his-statement/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automaton</a> this was a misinterpretation and that he, nor anyone at Square Enix, would convey the nature of their characters' relationships beyond the game itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"As creators, we will continue to convey [the relationships between our characters] through our content," Hamagucho said. "For example, no one will make any official statements about who Cloud likes, who Aerith likes, and so on."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He added that the misunderstanding may have come from subtle differences in language and culture between his native Japanese and the article's publication in English.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This all comes as the modern retelling of Final Fantasy 7 hasn't concluded yet. More answers, or more questions, could emerge in the third and final part of the Remake Trilogy, though fans will be waiting a while for them as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-hoping-to-release-final-fantasy-7-remake-trilogys-finale-by-2027">Square Enix doesn't hope to release it until 2027 at the earliest</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-has-a-completed-story-at-square-enix">The story has now been wrapped up internally</a> though, and Final Fantasy series producer Yoshinori Kitase previously said he's "sure fans will be satisfied with the final chapter."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review">In our 9/10 review of the last game</a>, IGN said: "Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth impressively builds off of what Remake set in motion, both as a best-in-class action role playing game full of exciting challenges and an awe inspiring recreation of a world that has meant so much to so many for so long."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>