<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 11:51:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Patch 01.003.200 Makes a Big Balance Change Among Others, Lets You Plant Your Flag in the Face of Your Enemy, and Lots of Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-01003200-makes-a-big-balance-change-among-others-lets-you-plant-your-flag-in-the-face-of-your-enemy-and-lots-of-fixes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-patch-01-003-200-makes-a-big-balance-change-among-others-lets-you-plant-your-flag-in-the-face-of-your-enemy-and-lots-of-fixes.1243809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Arrowhead’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> updates continue with patch 01.003.200, which makes a big balance change and a number of fixes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to patch notes released by the developer, 01.003.200 reduces the time it takes for the Helldiver to regain control after ragdolling from 0.8 to 0.5 seconds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This seemingly innocuous change will have big implications for how Helldivers 2 feels to play. It’s a game that leans heavily on its physics systems and the emergent gameplay that comes from them, and that includes being blasted around the map.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As any Helldivers 2 player will know, you spend a lot of time prone on the floor recovering after being smashed into a ragdolling status. There’s a panic that sets in as you slowly pick yourself up and dust yourself off while the forces of the Illuminate, the Automatons, and the Terminids continue their assault. Those precious few milliseconds may make all the difference, especially on harder difficulties.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, the flag can now be “proudly” planted directly into enemies — dead or alive — “ensuring the eternal colors of Super Earth are never tainted, only quenched by the blood of its foes.” So, if you want that Charger to be running around with your flag on its back, now you can make it happen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are a number of balance changes worth checking out in the patch notes below.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Things are hotting up in the world of Helldivers 2, with the PC and PS5 game set to become the first PlayStation Studios-published title ever on Xbox <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-published-helldivers-2-gets-shock-release-date-on-xbox-series-x-and-s">when it launches on Series X and S next month alongside crossplay</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Helldivers 2 update 01.003.200 patch notes:</p><h2 data-cy="title1">🌍 Overview</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Balancing</li><li>Mission Fixes</li><li>Weapon Fixes</li><li>Miscellaneous Fixes</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">⚖️ Balancing</h2><h2 data-cy="title2">General</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Helldiver</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduced the time it takes for the Helldiver to regain control after ragdolling from 0.8 to 0.5 sec</li><li>Increased chest injury bleed damage from 1 to 10. Chest injuries now cause more noticeable damage, as the previous value of 1 was so low it appeared to have no effect</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>CQC-1 One True Flag</strong> </h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Thanks to some groundbreaking military research into pointier flag tips, the flag can now be proudly planted directly into enemies—dead or alive—ensuring the eternal colors of Super Earth are never tainted, only quenched by the blood of its foes. Absolute Democracy</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Primary weapons</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>AR-32 Pacifier</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Stun duration increased from 1.5 to 3 sec </li><li>Starting magazines increased from 5 to 6</li><li>Max amount of magazines increased from 7 to 8</li><li>Slight increase in stun value applied to enemies</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>SMG-72 Pummeler</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Stun duration increased from 1.5 to 3 sec</li><li>Slight increase in stun value applied to enemies</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>ARC-12 Blitzer</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Slight increase in stun value applied to enemies</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>R-2124 Constitution</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Bayonet stagger strength increased from 20 to 25</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>R-2 Amendment</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Bayonet stagger strength increased from 20 to 25</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Sidearms</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>P-92 Warrant</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Now also locks-on to Large sized enemies</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Throwables</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>G-109 Urchin</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Stagger strength increased from 0 to 50</li><li>It now staggers and affects Large sized enemies</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>G-10 Incendiary</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The amount of fuel has been increased in the grenade, resulting in longer-lasting fire duration</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>G-13 Incendiary impact</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The amount of fuel has been increased in the grenade, resulting in a longer-lasting fire duration</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Stratagems</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>A/FLAM-40 Flame sentry</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fire damage resistance increased from 0 to 95%</li><li>Cooldown reduced from 150 to 100 sec</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>GL-52 De-Escalator</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Slight increase in stun value applied to enemies</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Boosters</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Firebomb Hellpod</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Now affects the Hellpods default explosion as well </li><li>Stagger strength decreased from 80 to 15 to prevent ragdolling players</li><li>Demolition strength decreased from 40 to 20 because we now correctly also additively apply the normal Hellpod explosion</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Stun Pods</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Now affects the Hellpods default explosion as well</li><li>Stagger strength decreased from 80 to 15 to prevent ragdolling players</li><li>Demolition strength decreased from 40 to 20 because we now correctly also additively apply the normal Hellpod explosion</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Enemies</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">General</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>It’s now easier to put Large to Massive sized enemies on fire</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Terminids</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Warrior</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage needed to gib Warriors increased from 500 to 750 damage</li><li>This is how much damage is needed to explode the body without leaving a corpse behind</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Automatons</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Scout strider</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Legs armor decreased from 3 to 2</li><li>Legs durable resistance has been increased</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Illuminates</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Overseer variants</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Unarmored Torso healthzone armor decreased from 2 to 1</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title1">🔧 Fixes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Weapons Stratagems &amp; Boosters</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue with the R-2124 Constitution playing audio during the wrong instances</li><li>Fixed an issue with the draw and holster speed with the Gunslinger Armor Passive</li><li>Fixed an issue with ranged weapon grips after dropping the Entrenchment Tool</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Enemies</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where status effect damage were attempting to apply more times than intended</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title1">Missions</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that prevented stratagems from working correctly on Terminate Illegal Broadcast objectives</li><li>Fixed an issue with bad enemy pathing on military uplink objectives</li><li>Fixed an issue for the terminal and drop off point, where they became inaccessible during the Retrieve Recon Craft Intel objective</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title1">Miscellaneous Fixes</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue in first person view where some armors resulted in visible obstructions around the shoulder while using a high Field Of View</li><li>Fixed an issue during map generation that could result in missing terrain features</li><li>Fixed fall animations occasionally playing before victory poses</li><li>Extended some fonts to handle Bengali characters in player names</li><li>Fixed an error that caused some enemy models to appear in lower quality</li><li>Fixed an issue to prevent accidentally triggering jump packs or climbing on supply pods while using the interact button on controller</li><li>Fixed an issue where exiting the chat was leaving players unarmed</li><li>Fixed an issue with aiming during the draw emote</li><li>Fixed issues when exiting First Person View using emotes</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-01003200-makes-a-big-balance-change-among-others-lets-you-plant-your-flag-in-the-face-of-your-enemy-and-lots-of-fixes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Only Official John Wick Video Game Is Being Pulled From All Platforms 6 Years After Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-only-official-john-wick-video-game-is-being-pulled-from-all-platforms-6-years-after-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-only-official-john-wick-video-game-is-being-pulled-from-all-platforms-6-years-after-release.1243749/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's not what you did, son, that angers me so. It's who you did it to.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The only officially licensed John Wick video game is being removed from sale just six years after launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bithell Games’ well-received <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/john-wick-hex">John Wick Hex</a> launched in October 2019. It’s a fast-paced, action-oriented strategy game “that makes you think and strike like John Wick.” John Wick, of course, is the hugely popular action hero made famous by Keanu Reeves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fast forward six years and John Wick Hex is set for the digital scrapheap. In an update directed at the game’s community, publisher Big Fan Games (which is part of Devolver Digital) said John Wick Hex will be removed from sale on all platforms beginning July 17, 2025.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After July 17, existing owners of John Wick Hex will still be able to access the game via their digital libraries across PC and console, and of course physical copies will continue to work on console. However, new purchases of John Wick Hex will not be possible, regardless of platform or storefront.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Big Fan Games failed to say why John Wick Hex was being removed from sale, but it seems likely it's the result of the expiration of its licence with John Wick rights holder Lionsgate Entertainment. IGN has asked Big Fan for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The expiration of a licence is one of the main reasons video games end up being pulled from storefronts; you see it most often with video games that have licensed music. It happened to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/05/12/alan-wake-to-be-removed-from-stores-because-of-expiring-licenses">Alan Wake</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/renewed-concern-for-star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-as-trailers-and-tweets-are-culled">Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic remake trailers</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/spec-ops-the-line-will-no-longer-be-available-in-online-stores-2k-blames-expiring-partnerships">Spec Ops: The Line</a>, to name but a few. Video game preservationists often call for video game companies to do more to keep their products alive when this happens. Back in 2018, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/04/11/gta-4-losing-some-licensed-music-rockstar-replacing-with-new-songs">Rockstar replaced Grand Theft Auto IV song licenses that had expired</a> after the end of a 10-year deal.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Ranking the John Wick Movies</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Bithell Games, it released Tron: Catalyst last month. The game was developed in collaboration with Disney and Pixar Games, and is set within the world of Tron.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And as for John Wick, he recently cameoed in spinoff <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/ballerina"><u>Ballerina</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/john-wick-5-is-official-and-yes-keanu-reeves-is-back-to-give-johns-story-the-proper-next-step"><u>John Wick 5, once again starring Keanu Reeves, is in development</u></a>, although we're not sure when it will come out. Director Chad Stahelski recently said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-director-of-john-wick-is-still-trying-to-work-out-how-to-make-keanu-reeves-in-john-wick-5-make-sense-given-the-ending-of-4"><u>he's still trying to work out how to make Keanu Reeves in John Wick 5 make sense given the ending of 4</u></a>. Meanwhile, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/john-wick-star-keanu-reeves-reportedly-pays-a-company-a-few-thousand-dollars-a-month-to-get-tiktok-and-meta-to-take-down-imitators">Keanu Reeves reportedly pays a company a few thousand dollars a month to get the likes of TikTok and Meta to take down imitators</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lionsgate has confirmed it has a John Wick AAA video game in the works, although it has said nothing about it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-only-official-john-wick-video-game-is-being-pulled-from-all-platforms-6-years-after-release]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bomb Busters Just Won Germany's Board Game of the Year Award and Now You Can't Buy It Anywhere]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bomb-busters-just-won-germanys-board-game-of-the-year-award-and-quickly-sold-out</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bomb-busters-just-won-germanys-board-game-of-the-year-award-and-now-you-cant-buy-it-anywhere.1243581/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Continuing a legacy of hits like Sky Team, Cascadia, and Azul.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bomb Busters was recently awarded the highest honor for board games as it was named the <a href="https://www.spiel-des-jahres.de/en/award-winners-2025/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2025 Spiel des Jahres</a> in Germany, beating out Flip 7 and Krakel Orakel for the top honors this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Spiel des Jahres may not be a household name in the U.S., but it's the most prestigious and influential board game award in the world, similar to winning an Oscar for film. The Spiel des Jahres (literally "Game of the Year") has been awarded to the best overall board game by an independent jury in Germany since 1979.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This year's winner, Bomb Busters, is a strategic cooperative game for up to five players that requires everyone to work together to defuse a bomb by cutting the correct wires. It's basically the tabletop equivalent of the video game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/keep-talking-and-nobody-explodes">Keep Talking and Nobody Explodes</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-family-board-games">great game for families</a> as it's not too difficult to learn and includes 66 unique scenarios to conquer together. Typical games take around 30 minutes, making it a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-quick-playing-board-games">quick board game</a> to get to the table and play.</p><div catalogid="e5a5bbe8-0672-4715-b123-9cc1b55825bb" id="225307"><div id="225307" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bomb Busters</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Following the news of its big win, Bomb Busters is currently out of stock in the U.S. at Amazon and at the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxAjlP?object_uuid=dfe0c97b-a457-4d6b-b9b5-8d412b2b4b16&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pegasus Spiele North America</a> store with no anticipated restock date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite not having a big ceremony, winning the Spiel des Jahres is still a massive achievement and helps many board games achieve worldwide recognition. Historically, some of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-all-time">best modern board games</a> have been awarded the Spiel des Jahres, including Azul, Cascadia, Ticket to Ride, Carcassonne, and Codenames, just to name a few.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 1989, a second award was added, the Kinderspiel des Jahres, that recognized the best children's game of the year. The most recent award, the Kennerspiel des Jahres, was added in 2011 to recognize the best "connoisseur," or expert, game of the year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This year, the cake-building game Topp die Torte! won the Kinderspiel des Jahres and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games">cooperative</a> ocean exploration game Endeavor: Deep Sea won the Kennerspiel des Jahres.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more board game coverage, check out our roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-strategy-board-games">best strategy board games</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-classic-board-games">best classic board games</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-adults">best board games for adults</a> to play in 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matthew Adler has written for IGN since 2019 covering all things gaming, tech, tabletop games, and more. You can follow him on the site formerly known as Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/matthewadler" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@MatthewAdler</em></a><em> and watch him stream on </em><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/matthewadler" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Twitch</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 14, 2025 8:22 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/bomb-busters-just-won-germanys-board-game-of-the-year-award-and-quickly-sold-out]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Attack on Titan: Apocalypse Card Set Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/attack-on-titan-apocalypse-card-set-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/attack-on-titan-apocalypse-card-set-review.1243578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">One of my favorite pastimes on the playground growing up was having heated debates with my friends about which of our favorite TV or video game characters would win in a fight. While it’s been a few decades since those days on the swingset, pitting two individuals from different properties against one another in a deathmatch is no less relevant today – just look at games like Fortnite, Call of Duty, and Magic: The Gathering. One trading card game has been doing it far longer. It's called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/universus-collectible-card-game">UniVersus</a>, and the team at UVS Games has recently released the final set in their Attack on Titan line – Apocalypse – featuring cards and characters from the final arc of the manga and anime. At last, we can find out if Eren Yeager, in his final form, can take on Godzilla or the various members of Critical Role’s Vox Machina.</p><div catalogid="8a1b0961-2202-4b69-9ae2-b045db9308ec" id="225306"><div id="225306" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>UniVersus Attack on Titan: Apocalypse</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For those unfamiliar with UniVersus, previously known as “UFS - Universal Fighting System”, it's a card game akin to games like Magic: The Gathering or Yu-Gi-Oh, but whose identity is based around creating wild cross-over fights. Players construct decks, picking a Character to lead their deck, which also dictates how much life they start with and their maximum hand size. UniVersus’ mechanics are centered around checks that players make to play their various kinds of cards, from attacks to other resources. Each card has a challenge value on it that must be met or exceeded for the card to be successfully played, requiring the player to flip the card on top of their deck and compare its check value against the challenge value of the action to be played. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Successes allow the action to be taken, such as attacking your opponent, while a failure ends your turn. A player’s turn continues until either they pass or fail one of these checks, with each subsequent check increasing the challenge value. It’s an interesting system, and adds an extra element of tension with every check from the top of your deck. However, it can be a bit overwhelming at times, especially when you get to blocking attacks, which have their own set of similar checks to deal with. UniVersus as a whole, I feel, is one of the more complex card games out there on the market today.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This latest set is focused around the final arc of the Attack of Titan series. It continues to build on the previous sets that UVS released – Battle for Humanity and Origins of Power. Much like those other sets, <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q47mOX?object_uuid=cc73bee0-b622-4f94-aae0-aecac6c88b54&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Apocalypse</u></a> retains the unique manga-esque card art, with most of the artwork framed in manga panels, with brand new artwork done by series creator Hajime Isayama. While his art style may not be everyone’s cup of tea, I personally prefer the art of the anime more, but there is no denying that it is neat to have these unique prints included in the set. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">From a gameplay standpoint, not much sets Apocalypse apart from the other AoT sets UVS has released in the past year, but that isn’t really a bad thing, as I’ve enjoyed the previous sets quite a bit. I am especially fond of the double-sided Titan cards that allow characters to shift from their human form into their Titan form during the game, allowing for deeper strategies and tense moments in my games, and it feels just as good here in this final set as it did in the first. I have my fingers crossed that the team will find ways to incorporate this feature in future non-AoT sets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Coming in at over 180 cards, Apocalypse offers players roughly the same amount of new cards as the previous Origins of Power set did, so unfortunately, if you were hoping for another large set like the titanic (pun intended) Battle for Humanity and its 300+ list, you’re out of luck. It is a bit of a bummer that there aren’t more cards. One feeling, though that I couldn’t escape as I looked through this set, was how it felt more like a set aimed more at collectors than at players. Maybe it’s just my imagination, resulting from the marketing focus on the new Isayama artwork and special chrome cards, but I feel like with the set's release, and even before, I heard more about those parts of this release than specifics on new cards or abilities of the set. To Apocalypse’s credit, the cards are all very neat and the chrome cards are beautiful, but for prospective new players, I don’t know what they could really learn about the set from a quick google search about specifics outside of “look, new art” which leads into the biggest issue that continues to hound UniVersus as a whole – learning resources.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Again, this is a complicated game and on the spectrum of simple to complex card games, I would put UniVersus somewhere around 3 out of 4 mark. Even after dabbling in the game for the past year or two, there are still a number of areas – resource symbols for example – that seemingly make little sense to me. To the team’s credit, they realize the game has an <a href="https://uvsgames.com/all-news/designing-uvs-one" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>onboarding problem</u></a>. I’ve played Magic a long time, so the idea of color identity, the idea that a specific color is tied to a style of gameplay, is something that makes sense to me, and symbols are, in essence, the UniVersus version of this idea. But UniVersus has 12 symbols, with abstract things like “All”, “Good”, and “Chaos” as just a few examples. I haven’t progressed far past the idea of just using the same symbols as the character who is leading my deck, but I wish the learning resources available did far more to help explain the systems, or were presented better. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While some resources are available, examples such as the <a href="https://44595267.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/44595267/2025%20Learn%20to%20Play%20Resources/2025%20Anatomy%20of%20a%20Turn.pdf" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>phase breakdown</u></a> and <a href="https://44595267.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/44595267/2025%20Learn%20to%20Play%20Resources/2025%20How%20to%20Play%20Step-by-Step.pdf" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>play-by-play of a turn</u></a> are walls of text without a single accompanying image to help. The <a href="https://uvsgames.com/all-news/universus-design-team-learning-about-the-symbols" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>symbols guide</u></a> features outdated card art and symbol designs, and the currently available basic “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bcSojOdcJwI" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>How to Play</u></a>” video that teaches the most basic concepts of the game doesn’t touch on half of the card types that the game uses or even mention those resource symbols. In fact, they are omitted completely even from the art on the cards used in the demonstration. Thankfully, various content creators have published resources that potential new players can watch to learn the game, but the bright side of things is that they know that this is an issue and are working to address it, slowly but surely. I enjoy my time when I play, but finding good information on how to play or build decks in this game is so hard to come by that it makes UniVersus a hard sell to my card-game-playing friends.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Where to Buy</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/z7Ol4E?object_uuid=cc73bee0-b622-4f94-aae0-aecac6c88b54&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See it at TCGPlayer</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QKgApY?object_uuid=cc73bee0-b622-4f94-aae0-aecac6c88b54&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">See it at UVS Games</a></li></ul></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 14, 2025 7:56 pm</p></div><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Despite frustration around some of the rules, I do still enjoy the times I get to play UniVersus, and this Attack on Titan: Apocalypse set is fun to play. I still got a kick out of Eren taking Boimler and the crew of the U.S.S. Cerritos from Star Trek Lower Decks, or Armin busting out All Might’s Detroit Smash while having Vox Machina’s Trinket the bear helping him out. The outlandish situations and moments that UniVersus presents players is straight out of a schoolyard argument, and I love it. Attack on Titan: Apocalypse sends off the setting on a good note with a lot of new cards to play with and strategize around, adding to an already fun game, despite its shortcomings, teaching players its mechanics.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/attack-on-titan-apocalypse-card-set-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>