<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 22:18:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Massive Mass Effect Comics & Art Book Bundle Is Only $8.99 at Fanatical Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-comics-and-art-book-bundle-deal-april-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-massive-mass-effect-comics-art-book-bundle-is-only-8-99-at-fanatical-right-now.1166322/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-comics-and-art-book-bundle-deal-april-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">11 different books up for grabs.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-legendary-edition-review-part-1-mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> is one of the most beloved RPG series of all time, with many fascinated by the characters, locations, and secrets hidden throughout its universe. If you're a huge fan of the games looking for more, Fanatical just relased a new bundle featuring 11 different Mass Effect <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/comics/genre/graphic-novel">graphic novels</a> and art books. You can score almost $140 worth of items for just $8.99 with this bundle.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Mass Effect Comics &amp; Art Book Bundle Available Now at Fanatical</h2><div catalogid="ecfa7b6b-88d6-4d42-a8d8-fe82f976857a" id="218865"><div id="218865" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mass Effect Comics &amp; Art Book Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There are two tiers available in this bundle. The first will give you access to three products for $1.99, while the second offers a total of 11 different books for $8.99. Eight different graphic novels, including the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/02/17/mass-effect-evolution-2-review">Mass Effect: Evolution</a> series, are included in this bundle, each written by key members of the Mass Effect writing team. Many of the franchise's most beloved characters are featured in these comics, which makes these a must-read for any Mass Effect fan looking to peer beyond the games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to the comics, you'll also score three amazing Mass Effect art books. This includes The Art of The Mass Effect Universe, The Art of The Mass Effect Trilogy, and The Art of Mass Effect: Andromeda. If you're interested in learning how the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/mass-effect">Mass Effect games</a> were conceptualized or simply wish to look at gorgeous concept art, these art books contain over 600 pages of material to scroll through.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All books will be DRM-free and downloadable in PDF format, so you can ensure you will have access to this collection wherever you go. This bundle won't last forever, so be sure to secure yours now at Fanatical if you're interested. At only $8.99, it's a pretty cheap investment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Noah Hunter is a freelance writer and reviewer with a passion for games and technology. He co-founded Final Weapon, an outlet focused on nonsense-free Japanese gaming (in 2019) and has contributed to various publishers writing about the medium.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 16, 2025 8:41 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creator of Viral Charli XCX Apple Dance Sues Roblox for Using Dance in Dress to Impress Without Permission]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-viral-charli-xcx-apple-dance-sues-roblox-for-using-dance-in-dress-to-impress-without-permission</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/creator-of-viral-charli-xcx-apple-dance-sues-roblox-for-using-dance-in-dress-to-impress-without-permission.1166319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/creator-of-viral-charli-xcx-apple-dance-sues-roblox-for-using-dance-in-dress-to-impress-without-permission<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Kelley Heyer, a TikTok influencer and creator of a viral dance to Charli XCX's song "Apple", is suing Roblox, alleging it used the "Apple Dance" in the game and profited off her work without her permission.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're not exactly up on the hip trends of the youth, the "<a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kelley.heyer/video/7380425926393335083" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apple Dance</a>" is exactly what it says on the tin: a catchy dance conceived by Heyer and shared via TikTok to Charli XCX's song "Apple". The dance has become incredibly popular, to the point of being shouted out in Charli XCX's tour and shared on <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@charlixcx/video/7389277177629379872?lang=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Charli XCX's TikTok</a>.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/dress-to-impress-brat-update-promo-1744834699035.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">So it's unsurprising that Roblox wanted the Apple Dance as part of a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/dress-to-impress/Brat_Update_Details_and_Patch_Notes_(DTI_Charli_XCX_Collaboration)">collaboration between Charli XCX and one of the most popular games within Roblox</a>: creative fashion contest game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dress-to-impress-roblox">Dress to Impress</a>. Spotted by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/559582/charli-xcx-apple-dance-roblox-lawsuit" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polygon</a>, the lawsuit in question was filed last week in California, in which Heyer claims that originally, Robox did contact her to license the Apple Dance for the crossover event. Heyer says that she was open to the idea of the dance being licensed if the terms were right - she even <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kelley.heyer/video/7448063559411584299" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">licensed it to Fortnite</a> and Netflix via actual, signed agreements - but never reached an actual agreement with Roblox.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Heyer alleges that Robox released the Apple Dance emote for sale in the event before negotiations were ever completed and without Heyer giving her consent for its use. Heyer says that Roblox sold over 60,000 Apple Dance emotes, resulting in an estimated $123,000 in sales. The suit also argues that while the emote was a part of a Charli XCX event, the dance emote itself is unattached to the song or Charli XCX, and thus is solely Heyer's intellectual property.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The suit accuses Roblox of copyright infringement and unjust enrichment, and requests relief in the form  of the profits Roblox received from the dance plus damages as a result of Roblox harming Heyer's brand and Heyer herself, plus attorney's fees.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Update 2:15 p.m. PT: </strong>Heyer's attoney, Miki Anzai, shared the following statement: "Roblox moved forward using Kelley's IP without a signed agreement. Kelley is an independent creator who should be compensated fairly for her work and we saw no other option than to file suit to prove that. We remain willing and open to settle and hope to come to a peaceful agreement."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk Edgerunners: Combat Zone Board Game Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-edgerunners-combat-zone-board-game-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-edgerunners-combat-zone-board-game-review.1166313/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-edgerunners-combat-zone-board-game-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-edgerunners-review"><u>Cyberpunk Edgerunners</u></a> is an electrifying animated Netflix series that debuted in 2022 and left me gobsmacked. Across 10 episodes, we rip through Night City alongside protagonists David and Lucy as they confront the terrors of the concrete hellscape while stuck between two warring MegaCorps. This brilliant anime is full of potential and is too damn good to be forgotten. Thankfully, it's now been reanimated via cardboard and plastic, allowing players to explore some of the key moments of the series through a refined tabletop miniatures game that's as razor sharp as the Cyberpunk 2077 setting.</p><div catalogid="ee2f861d-896e-452c-918b-38684ca2ff50" id="217983"><div id="217983" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Cyberpunk Edgerunners: Combat Zone Board Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The setup mimics the show – one player controls Maine and his crew of merc edgerunners, and another the Arasaka paramilitary team. Players select a scenario and then craft their gang from a selection of characters based on the assigned points value for the mission. Maine’s group can include any of the main protagonists of the series, including David, Lucy, and Rebecca. Arasaka has a mixed cast of faceless grunts alongside more menacing options such as the braindance editor Jimmy Kurosaki and massive hulk Adam Smasher. You can outfit team members with various weapons and cybergear, allowing for advanced tactics and more nuanced options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the strengths of this game is that the system it uses is already seasoned. The ruleset is identical to publisher Monster Fight Club’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-red-combat-zone-tabletop-game-review">Cyberpunk Red: Combat Zone</a> miniatures game. I’ve already written many words about this excellent tabletop skirmish game, and I am more than pleased to see it return with a fresh exoskeleton. It’s really a top-notch ruleset that hasn't received the acclaim it deserves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The most interesting aspect is the activation system. Characters are allotted color-coded action tokens that are spent to roll matching dice. The stronger actions allow you to move farther or roll larger dice, such as a 12-sider, to perform various activities. The active player chooses one of their characters to activate, and then spends their assigned tokens to sprint across the board, attack their foe, or perform special actions such as netrunning or completing a scenario objective. There is added texture through leadership abilities allowing you to activate additional models out of order, or the option to react when wounded. This creates a dynamic flow to play with a controlled chaos that blends player agency with unpredictability. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This splendid system is interesting in that it evokes a sense of resource management for players to puzzle over. Each action is precious and needs to be spent for maximum gain. For instance, if Dario is being targeted by an Arasaka Point Man, do you spend her best action token for the opposed defensive roll, or do you go with a weaker action to save her best die for later in the turn? This decision process evokes a similar feel to tactical board games, such as some of the more inspired <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dungeon-crawler-board-games">dungeon crawler board games</a>. It’s more opaque than traditional miniatures games such as Kill Team or Frostgrave. This quality isn’t a total surprise, as the founders of Monster Fight Club have a long established history, having designed hit board games such as Spartacus: A Game of Blood and Treachery and Star Trek: Ascendancy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the system here is identical to Cyberpunk Red: Combat Zone, the content is certainly not. In addition to swapping out Night City gangs for edgerunner mercs and Megacorp goons, the plastic miniatures of that previous box have been abandoned in lieu of stylish acryllic standees. This style of plastic faux 3D figure has started to become popular in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-all-time">board game</a> hobby, but it hasn’t quite been experimented with on the same scale in miniatures games. Monster Fight Club is looking to spearhead this movement as these standees are incredibly appealing for both ease of play and striking aesthetics.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the reasons the acrylic standees work so well in this game is that the characters' depictions are all grounded in the anime. The artistic style of the Edgerunners series is an iconic element of the property, so carrying it forward to the miniatures game is an enormous win. The sleek tone of the figures blends well with the cyberpunk terrain and battlefield, merging for an overall enhanced visual field that is fantastic. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The standees are such an enormous benefit to the game that I can’t imagine the average wargamer opting for miniatures instead. Look, all of us that play these types of games have scads of unpainted figures occupying our shelves. This switch to illustrated acrylic standees is such a breath of fresh air, as it allows you to just dive into the game with virtually no assembly or prep time. And for many, they will look better than the average paint-job we are capable of. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The standees are such an enormous benefit to the game that I can’t imagine the average wargamer opting for miniatures instead.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, some may instead find that desire for full-blown miniatures eating away at their soul. Fret not, for an <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxX4mx?object_uuid=c3c6f68e-acb0-4a67-858d-ee5e2ed13c4b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">aftermarket option</a> does allow for a return to plastic multi-part miniatures. It’s a pricey option that will certainly increase your overall burden in entering this game, and I certainly find it entirely unnecessary, but it’s an option that’s there for collectors. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The terrain is of similar exceptional quality to the magnificent Cyerpunk Red: Combat Zone kit. Cardboard buildings, rubble, and barricades are composed of thick chipboard that slots together with ease. The surface is a sturdy mounted board similar to that found in hobby board games. There’s no paper mat needing an immediate upgrade here.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This line of Cyberpunk miniatures games are also well supported with aftermarket purchases of Monster Fight Club’s various <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7EB3G?object_uuid=c3c6f68e-acb0-4a67-858d-ee5e2ed13c4b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">plastic terrain options</a>. They have crafted some of the best cargo containers in the industry, and have expanded that series of products to include walkways, crates, and various other small scatter options. It’s incredible stuff that rivals the top-notch cardboard options in the core box.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cyberpunk Edgerunners: Combat Zone is an impressive box. It once again includes a fully featured <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-campaign-board-games">campaign</a> reminiscent of its peers such as Necromunda and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcry-heart-of-ghur-brings-big-changes-to-the-tabletop-game">Warcry</a>. Players can take their gang through multiple battles and increase their characters' potency. Eventually your gang will reach the end of their story and engage in a climactic finale that wraps up their narrative. Campaign play isn't a requirement, however, as the game performs exceptionally well in one-off skirmishes. The wide range of scenario options are exciting and varied, affording for a large amount of experimentation. Couple that with full crew options allowing players to field a wide array of rosters, and this single box set feels wholly complete.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The characters are well realized, with abilities and play-styles that reflect the Netflix series.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The attention to detail here is strong throughout. The characters are well realized, with abilities and play-styles that reflect the Netflix series. David, for instance, can really dig into cybergear and run wild. Adam Smasher is scary as hell. Lucy can netrun with the best of them. Owners of Cyberpunk Red: Combat Zone products may be pleased to find out that you can mix content across games. Since both utilize the same core ruleset, they are fully compatible for those wanting to explore anachronistic conflicts that jump across the timeline. Regardless of Combat Zone experience, this new boxed set feels singular and expansive, offering a tailored skirmish game that is fantastic in its own right.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Where to Buy</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aX2rAp?object_uuid=c3c6f68e-acb0-4a67-858d-ee5e2ed13c4b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Amazon</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/z6odK3?object_uuid=c3c6f68e-acb0-4a67-858d-ee5e2ed13c4b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Atomic Empire</a></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/a5YDp5?object_uuid=c3c6f68e-acb0-4a67-858d-ee5e2ed13c4b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Miniature Market</a></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">See more board games based on video games</h3></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 16, 2025 7:30 pm</p></div><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">This is a wonderful miniatures skirmish game that begs consideration. The switch to acrylic standees has only improved the overall gaming experience, and it’s a trend that I hope catches on with other publishers. This Edgerunners boxed set is a fully-featured and complete game that will stand the test of time. For fans of the animated series, this game is everything you’d hope for.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Builds for Last Epoch 1.2 Tombs of the Erased]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/last-epoch-1-2-builds-best</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-builds-for-last-epoch-1-2-tombs-of-the-erased.1166115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/last-epoch-1-2-builds-best<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Last Epoch 1.2 Tombs of the Erased brings a sentinel rework, Weavers endgame Faction, revamped Monolith of Fate experience, and much more. This is Last Epoch’s biggest update yet and IGN has teamed up with the ARPG experts at Maxroll to prepare detailed guides on all of the new content along with excellent builds for leveling and endgame alike. Before we get to the builds, here’s all the new stuff coming in 1.2:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">New 1.2 Tombs of the Erased Content</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/01-new-content-woven-faction-1744819698558.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Woven Faction</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the biggest changes in 1.2 is the new Woven Faction. They provide a deeper endgame experience by adding Woven Echoes to your Monolith of Fate. Begin interacting with them by finding a Cemetery of the Erased on your Echo Web, after completing the mini-boss at the end you can enter the Haven of Silk and speak to Masque to join the faction. Gain ranks with the Woven Faction by completing Woven Echoes to add points to your Weaver Tree then use these points to customize your endgame experience.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Champions &amp; Mini-bosses</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As you explore the Echo Web, you may also find some fun new surprises in the form of Champions, and new weaver mini-bosses. The Champions are larger, more powerful versions of rares, immediately visible due to their angry red glow. Defeating them is tricky but if you persevere you’re sure to be duly rewarded. There are also several new mini-bosses you can encounter in 1.2, so keep an eye out for a scary-looking boss as you explore the Monolith of Fate.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Set Item Crafting and LP Changes</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Last Epoch has an in-depth <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/resources/beginner-crafting-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Crafting System</a> where you use Affix Shards, Glyphs, and Runes to heavily customize your items. This popular system is straighforward to understand and has a fair bit of depth to master. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 1.2, crafting in Last Epoch gets even better. You can break Set items down to obtain crafting shards and then use those to craft set bonuses on your items. This gives you the best of both worlds where you have the power of a set bonus and the flexibility to craft your own gear with the affixes you need. EHG has also made a big change to how you use Unique items with Legendary Potential (LP) to craft Legendary items. In the past, when interacting with the Eternity Cache the modifiers added to your Legendary Items were chosen at random. So if you used a 1LP Unique, you get a Legendary with 1 random affix, if you use a 2LP Unique, you get a Legendary with 2 random affixes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, if you complete a Temporal Sanctum of level 2 or higher you can choose 1 affix to transfer to your Legendary! This means you get to pick what you want when using a 1 LP Unique, if you use an item with 2-4 LP, then you get to pick 1 affix and the remaining modifiers are chosen at random.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Uber Aberroth</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Last Epoch’s ultimate boss is getting even tougher with 1.2. In addition to the normal version of this encounter, there is a special Uber Aberroth encounter. Very little is known about this foe beyond the fact that he is the most dangerous being in Eterra. Challenge him at your own risk!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1.2 Tombs of the Erased Leveling Builds</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Use Maxroll’s leveling builds to cruise through the campaign with ease. Season 2 introduces the ability to switch your Mastery so you can level with the most efficient build for the campaign, then respec your mastery upon reaching the endgame. Here are the best ways to level each of the game’s 5 classes, straight from Last Epoch’s top speed runner Terek!</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/primalist-build-1744820944042.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Primalist</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The best way to level a Primalist is by playing Druid. This build has good damage, it’s very cozy as you can use transformations to spam your skills during the campaign, and gets quite tanky thanks to Werebear form.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/mage-build-1744820963651.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Mage</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The Spellblade mastery seamlessly weaves blades and spells to decimate foes using Shatter Strike. You are reliant on spells in the early game but once you get Shatter Strike most of your time is spent rotating between Shatter Strike for damage and Mana Strike to recover your resources to continue dealing damage. Don’t be fooled by the Mage’s health, you can easily generate tons of Ward just by hitting enemies.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/sentinel-build-1744820980104.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Sentinel</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Hot off the rework, Sentinel is stronger than ever. The most efficient way to level is by playing Paladin to get easy access to Resistances and Holy Aura for both offensive and defensive bonuses. Crusade your way through the campaign burning enemies in the holy fire of your Judgment!</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/acolyte-build-1744820998394.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Acolyte</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As an Acolyte you are a master of the undead and the profane. Embrace your inner darkness and become a Warlock to create rifts in reality which unleash a volley of Chaos Bolt. The Chthonic Fissure skill provides great persistent damage for clearing while your Summoned Infernal Shades melt bosses with their hellish assault.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/rogue-build-1744821018335.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h3 data-cy="title3">Rogue</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The Rogue levels with her trusty Falcon Companion, flying through levels with ease and grace. This Falconer build is easy to scale with great sustain thanks to the Melee Leech affix on gear. With a bit of investment into Health, Regen and Physical Resistance, this Rogue becomes a well-rounded beast of a build.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1.2 Tombs of the Erased Endgame Builds</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">After you complete the campaign, you enter Last Epoch’s endgame. Maxroll’s Last Epoch team has been extensively testing a wide variety of endgame builds to dominate in the Monolith of Fate. While all of these builds are powerful, you can use Maxroll’s tier lists to see how they compare across different kinds of content.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Heartseeker Marksman</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/heartseeker-marksman-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Heartseeker Marksman</a> uses a new skill which seeks enemy targets and triggers a spectacular display of Fire and Cold Projectiles that cover the entire screen. Watch your enemies evaporate as they get blasted by your Attacks and Spells!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The build revolves around dealing Damage with Heartseeker and proccing an insane amount of Dragonfire from Dragonsong. Heartseeker also triggers Burning Dagger for even more craziness. This Marksman has incredible mobility and utility thanks to Shift, Smoke Bomb, Shurikens, and unspecialized Decoy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Amazing DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Fast Clear Speed</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Deals Damage While Moving</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Insane Scaling with Gear and Uniques</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Active Playstyle</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Needs Uniques to Shine</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Survivability Relies on Gear</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Defensive Tools Require Timing</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Judgement Paladin</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/judgement-paladin-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Judgement Paladin</a> creates Consecrated Ground with Judgement, to burn enemies with holy fire. Become the Judge and cleanse your foes of impurity, as they hopelessly try to break through your immense defenses. This build is a natural continuation of the Paladin Leveling Build, making it extremely easy to play as your first character of the season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Judgement Paladin deals Fire Spell Damage Over Time with Consecrated Ground and generates Mana with Vengeance. Consecrated Ground also grants massive Healing, since multiple instances can stack on top of each other. Use Holy Aura and Symbols of Hope for great passive buffs. Healing Hands grants Ward and Healing, while acting as your Movement Skill.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Insane Tankiness</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Exceptional Sustain</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ High Single Target DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Amazing Scaling With Gear and Uniques</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Limited AoE</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Average Clear Speed</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Needs Legendaries To Shine</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Generator/Spender Playstyle</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Warpath Void Knight</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/echo-warpath-void-knight-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Warpath Void Knight</a> uses Warpath to wipe the battlefield clean of enemies. Stay spinning to increase your Damage and AoE until Warpath almost covers the whole screen. Unleash the Spin-to-Win playstyle with this build!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Warpath Void Knight specializes into Warrior's Fury to reach amazing levels of Void Melee Damage and Area of Effect. Warpath costs more Mana every second, but thanks to the Void Well Passive and Mana stacking, you can stay spinning for a long time. The Void Well Passive is mandatory when you have Warrior's Fury allocated. Devouring Orb, Anomaly, Symbols of Hope, and Abyssal Echoes grant powerful buffs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Amazing AoE</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Extreme Clear Speed</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Very Simple Gameplay</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Excellent Single Target DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Gear Dependent</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Average Tankiness</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Needs Legendaries To Shine</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Requires Mana Investment</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Tornado Shaman</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Summon the fury of the storm with this <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/tornado-shaman-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tornado Shaman Guide</a> as you strike down foes from afar. This build invokes Tornados onto the battlefield that rapidly calls Storm Bolts down on enemies in an enormous area. Speed through monoliths and destroy bosses with this outstanding build.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Place down long-lasting Tornados on the battlefield that rapidly cast Storm Bolts thanks to Charged Storm for huge Lightning damage. Gathering Storm allows you to drastically increase the damage of those storm bolts while Summon Spriggan, Warcry, and Maelstrom offer you some amazing offensive and defensive bonuses. Since you are not casting Gathering Storm manually, you can equip an unspecialized Fury Leap for mobility.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Insane Tankiness</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Exceptional Sustain</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ High Single Target DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Amazing Scaling With Gear and Uniques</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Limited AoE</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Weaker Defensively While Moving</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Optimal Play Requires Standing Still</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Summon Spriggan Dies Often And Needs To Be Resummoned</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Stygian Coal Lich</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/stygian-coal-lich-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stygian Coal Lich Guide</a> harnesses the power of undeath in the form of Stygian Beams. This Lich transforms into its horrific Reaper Form to unleash a barrage of deadly Necrotic Stygian Beams. Hit your enemies with Rip Blood to empower yourself, and generate Mana and obliterate everything around you.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Turn Drain Life into a DPS powerhouse thanks to the Stygian Coal Unique Catalyst. Death Seal provides powerful buffs and releases pulsing Waves of Death around you while it's active that kill any enemies near you. The build has great mobility thanks to Reap and Transplant.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Good Tankiness</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Exceptional Sustain</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Insane Single Target DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Deals Damage While Moving</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Limited AoE</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Mana Management</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Unique Heavy Build</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Generator/Spender Playstyle</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Umbral Blades Falconer</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/umbral-blades-falconer-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Umbral Blades Falconer</a> calls down its Falcon from the skies to spawn Umbral Blades, which are Throwing Attacks that detonate into giant Cold explosions and decimate your enemies. Watch your foes die as you swiftly cruise through the battlefield with this amazing build that focuses on maximizing the destructible power of the Twilight Strike Node inside the Aerial Assault Skill.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Thanks to the Cooldown Reduction from Free Lofting Bird, you can spam Explosive Trap to cycle through Dive Bomb and Aerial Assault almost non-stop. Smoke Bomb is your Movement Skill and Shadow generator.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Very Fast</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Amazing AoE</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Insane Burst Damage</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Multiple Defensive Layers</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Cooldown Based DPS</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Mana Management</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Can't Leech From Crits</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Requires Uniques to Shine</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Frostbite Frost Claw Sorcerer</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/build-guides/frostbite-frost-claw-sorcerer-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Frostbite Frost Claw Sorcerer</a> strides into battle wielding the potent Frost Claw as its Skill of choice. With each swift cast, Frost Claw releases a barrage of projectiles, all capable of converging upon a single target. This relentless assault not only deals Damage but also has the power to Freeze foes in their tracks. Thanks to its high Cast Speed, it can maintain a relentless offensive assault, while also accumulating Ward to fortify its Defenses.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is an Ailment-based build that scales Frostbite and Cold Damage Over Time. Its Damage primarily comes from Frost Claw, Elemental Nova, and Ice Barrage. The build also has amazing CC thanks to the ability to Freeze enemies reliably.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Pros</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Easy to Play</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Incredible CC</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ Flashy Visuals</p><p data-cy="paragraph">✔️ High Scaling Potential</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Cons</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Visual Clutter</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Average Survivability</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Requires Uniques to Shine</p><p data-cy="paragraph">❌ Mana Intensive Without Proper Setup</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Last Epoch 1.2 Tier Lists</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/15-tier-lists-1744821253223.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to see the best performing builds of the patch, here are Maxroll’s Tierlists to help you decide what to play depending on your goals and taste! The best ones stand in S-Tier and are expected to outperform others. Choose wisely, read the guides, and defeat all content!</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Corruption</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/tierlists/corruption-tier-list" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Corruption Tier List</a> categorizes the performance of all builds against any high-end challenges, taking into account all their strengths and weaknesses. Builds are compared based on their Endgame Planner Setup.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Bossing</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Use Maxroll's <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/tierlists/bossing-tier-list" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bossing Tier List</a> to see which builds excel at taking down Monolith Bosses, Dungeons Bosses, and Pinnacle Content. Maxroll considers many factors when placing the builds but mainly focuses on Overall reliable DPS. Builds are compared based on their Endgame Planner Setup.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Hardcore</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll's <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/tierlists/hardcore-tier-list" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hardcore Tier List</a> ranks a build's suitability for the optional permadeath mode “Hardcore”. Therefore the builds are primarily ranked based on their raw survivability and reliability, even on their Starting Planner Setup. Unlike the other tier lists, the early game gearing is given higher weight here, because a single death means losing your character when playing on Hardcore.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Speed Farming</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll's <a href="https://maxroll.gg/last-epoch/tierlists/speed-farming-tier-list" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Speed Farming Tier List</a> ranks a build's ability to speed through content. Naturally, speed is the main factor, which means the ability to AoE down mobs, move quickly, and maintain this speed even at high corruption. Builds are compared based on their Endgame Planner Setup.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>This article was created by IGN Staff with help from the Maxroll Last Epoch Team.</em>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anime Rangers X Codes (April 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/anime-rangers-x-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anime-rangers-x-codes-april-2025.1166109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/anime-rangers-x-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Earn yourself some Gems and Gold to get you started in Anime Rangers X.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Anime Rangers X was released on April 16th, 2025, and with its launch comes new codes. So, if you're looking for an extra boost to get some Gold and Gems, IGN has you covered! We've got the details below on the current and active codes for the experience, as well as the rewards you'll get for redeeming them.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Working Anime Rangers X Codes </h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>ARX Release!!!</strong>: 500x Gems, 5,000 Gold</li><li><strong>1K Favorites</strong>: 500x Gems, 5,000 Gold</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Anime Rangers X Codes </h2><p data-cy="paragraph">With the game just being released, there are no expired Anime X codes! Do you know what that means? You'll need to use the ones above quickly, as we never know when these codes will expire. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Anime Rangers X Code</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/16/anime-rangers-x-codes-1744819843506.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Find Anime Rangers X on Roblox</li><li>Before jumping into the game, <a href="https://www.roblox.com/communities/15009415/Learning-Disability-Group#!/about" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">go to the group's page</a> and press <strong>Join Community</strong></li><li>Play the game until you <strong>reach level 5 or higher</strong></li><li>When you're in the game, look on the right side of the screen</li><li>The bottom blue button says Code</li><li>Click this, and paste the code in</li><li>Hit Redeem and enjoy your goodies!</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Anime Rangers X Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">When a code for a Roblox Experience isn't working, it's usually because the codes have been typed in incorrectly or they're expired. Lots of codes are case sensitive, so you'll need to make sure it's exactly how it appears in this article. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We test each code before uploading them, to make sure they're active, so be sure you're copying it straight from our article (without any sneaky extra spaces) to get the right one. If it's still not working, make sure you've joined the Community, and made it to Level 5.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>