<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:02:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2's 'I Won't Do It' Dialogue Option Is a Fun, Perfectly Safe, and Very Hideo Kojima Easter Egg]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-2s-i-wont-do-it-dialogue-option-is-a-fun-perfectly-safe-and-very-hideo-kojima-easter-egg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2s-i-wont-do-it-dialogue-option-is-a-fun-perfectly-safe-and-very-hideo-kojima-easter-egg.1227870/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach">Death Stranding 2</a> has a dialogue option at the beginning of the game that fans are getting a kick out of, but while it looks like a scary choice at first, it’s just a harmless Easter egg.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Warning!</strong></em><em> Spoilers for Death Stranding 2 follow:</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Death Stranding 2 kicks off with a Far Cry-esque option at the beginning of the game where Fragile (Léa Seydoux) recruits Sam (Norman Reedus) to Drawbridge, but you get the option to refuse. Death Stranding 2 then does a Groundhog Day thing where the game keeps showing the intro over and over, and you can keep selecting "I wont do it,” but eventually the game forces you to accept the offer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This first major dialogue choice doesn’t stop you from progressing the story, nor does it do that thing some games do by rolling credits early. It’s a perfectly safe Easter egg that’s in keeping with the Hideo Kojima style, and a fun distraction before you get stuck into the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out the video below, where we show you exactly what happens when you refuse Fragile’s plea to join Drawbridge.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-review">Death Stranding 2 review</a> returned a 9/10. We called it “a triumphant sequel that emphatically delivers on the promise of its original.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-2s-i-wont-do-it-dialogue-option-is-a-fun-perfectly-safe-and-very-hideo-kojima-easter-egg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Little Nightmares 3 Has a Release Date — and There's a Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/little-nightmares-3-has-a-release-date-and-theres-a-little-nightmares-enhanced-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/little-nightmares-3-has-a-release-date-%E2%80%94-and-theres-a-little-nightmares-enhanced-edition.1227867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">There's also a comic book, a YA book, a VR title, and a stop-motion project.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bandai Namco went big on little things last night — specifically, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/little-nightmares-iii"><u>Little Nightmares 3</u></a>, confirming it'll release on October 10. And if that seems very far away, I have good news: anyone who pre-orders a digital version of Little Nightmares 3 will get to revisit the game that started it all with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/little-nightmares"><u>Little Nightmares</u></a> Enhanced Edition as an early access title between now and launch day.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also an all-new season of the Little Nightmares themed podcast series on the way, The Sounds of Nightmares, and a comic book — Little Nightmares: Descent to Nowhere — also kicking off in October. Before then, however, a young adult book called Little Nightmares: The Lonely Ones is out in September. Phew. Got all that?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The comic book? Published by Titan Comics, Little Nightmares: Descent to Nowhere, follows two parallel stories. Hush, a timid mute girl wakes up in a jail cell. Desperate to escape, she befriends another prisoner, Mono, who understands this world far better than her, they will have to find a way out of a very dark Dungeon.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The novel Little Nightmares: The Lonely Ones, on the other hand, is written by E.C. Myers and published by Scholastic. It follows Ruse, a young child, who awakens in an unfamiliar, shaking room with two other kids she doesn't know — a small girl with a frayed rope dangling from her neck and a starved-looking boy wearing a tattered mask over his mouth and nose.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And there's another surprise: Bandai Namco also revealed a teaser for a stop motion project developed in collaboration with studio Taller del Chucho. We didn't get much more information, but Bandai says more information will be "unveiled" at a later date. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Little Nightmares 3 — the first Little Nightmares game from Supermassive — is scheduled to release on to PC, PS5, Switch 2, Xbox Series X and S, and last-gen systems, including Nintendo Switch. All bar the Switch versions are available to pre-order now (the latter are coming at a "later date") — here's what you get in each edition of Little Nightmares 3 are available for pre-order:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">All Little Nightmares 3 Editions</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Standard Edition — base game</li><li>Digital Deluxe Edition, base game and the Secrets of The Spiral - Expansion Pass, and the Residents Costumes Pack</li><li>Collector Mirror Edition, which adds to the Deluxe edition content, a figurine, a metal case, a physical artbook, the OST in digital and physical format, and some stickers </li><li>Premium Collector Spiral Edition, exclusive to the Bandai Namco Store which, contains the Collector Mirror Edition figurine, enhanced with a music box base, a Nome controller/phone holder and a double-sided coin of Low and Alone.</li></ul><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/25/little-nightmares-iii-spiral-premium-edition-bundle-07212-1750850687285.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Little Nightmares 3 Spiral Edition. Image credit: Bandai Namco.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">All pre-orders will secure the Dark Six Costumes Set on all platforms as well as the early access to Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition. We also learned that The Secrets of The Spiral — Expansion Pass will include at least two additional chapters to explore. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And I'm not even finished — we <em>also</em> got to see a glimpse of all-new VR adventure called Little Nightmares VR: Altered Echoes from Iconik Studios. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We thought <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/little-nightmares-2-review"><u>Little Nightmares 2 was good, awarding it 7/10</u></a>, writing: "Little Nightmares 2 is every bit as black, bleak, and eerily beautiful as the original. It’s also just as brief, and although the reintroduction of the Six character as an AI-controlled co-op partner ultimately serves the story well, she’s not used as a vehicle to take the game’s puzzle-solving and stealth to interesting new places, which seems like a real missed opportunity."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/little-nightmares-3-has-a-release-date-and-theres-a-little-nightmares-enhanced-edition]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>