<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 10:46:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Celebrates James Gunn's Big DCU Launch With Five Free Superman Skins]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-celebrates-james-gunns-big-dcu-launch-with-five-free-superman-skins</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-celebrates-james-gunns-big-dcu-launch-with-five-free-superman-skins.1238991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's some good news for superhero-loving <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft"><u>Minecraft</u></a> fans — there's a new Superman skin pack up for grabs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And best of all, the pack — which contains skins for Superman, Lois Lane, Green Lantern, Hawkgirl, and Mr. Terrific — is <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/marketplace/pdp/oreville-studios/superman-skin-pack/90d41dd8-00c4-4327-89e7-1377197ffcb5" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available now from the Minecraft Marketplace</a> for free.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's all to tie in, of course, with James Gunn's new big-screen take on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/superman-2025"><u>Superman</u></a>, which is out later this week (July 11) and sees Superman fighting to balance his Kryptonian heritage with his human upbringing as the new DCU properly kicks off. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Superman stars David Corenswet as the titular hero — who replaces prior leading man, Henry Cavill — Rachel Brosnahan as Lois Lane, as well as Nicholas Hoult, Edi Gathegi, Anthony Carrigan, Nathan Fillion, and Isabela Merced. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/superman-2025-review-james-gunn-david-corenswet-rachel-brosnahan-nicholas-hoult"><u>Superman movie review</u></a>, we slapped it with a healthy 8/10, writing: "Superman is a wonderfully entertaining, heartfelt cinematic reset for the Man of Steel, and a great start for the DCU on the big screen."</p><p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/09/oreville-thumbnail-0-1752052798050.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Minecraft's Superhero skin pack.</figcaption></figure></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week Minecraft announced a raft of new features to make use of the copper resource — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-developer-teases-something-big-to-do-with-copper-and-fans-think-a-long-lost-mob-may-return"><u>including the long-awaited debut of copper golems</u></a>. Not only will Minecraft now let you craft copper tools and armor, the copper golem from Minecraft's 2021 Mob Vote is finally being added, after remaining a fan-favourite concept over the years. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">And don't forget that last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-vibrant-visuals-update-finally-gives-mojangs-game-a-long-awaited-visual-overhaul-but-only-on-compatible-devices"><u>Minecraft got a big graphical update courtesy of its Vibrant Visuals update</u></a> — but only on supported platforms for now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/minecraft-celebrates-james-gunns-big-dcu-launch-with-five-free-superman-skins]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City Board Game Drops to $59.99 for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-deal-prime-day-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-drops-to-59-99-for-prime-day.1238895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">That's 36% off.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Grab your cards, Samurai. CMON’s Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City is getting in on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-2025-sale-top-deals-live">Prime Day</a> savings with a nice 36% discount, making it only $69.99. Instead of trying to cram the massive video game’s story into a box, Gangs of Night City instead puts you in control of one of the universe’s various gangs (each gang having unique asymmetric abilities), and you wage war as you and the other players try to carve out more territory. </p><p id="cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City ">Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City The Board Game</h2></p><div catalogid="b1abd622-deb3-40e8-8b58-fb95dd597f8d" id="224519"><div id="224519" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City The Board Game</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>1 to 4 players take on the roles of rival gangs struggling to expand their territory in the universe of Cyberpunk 2077 with Cyberpunk 2077: Ganges of Night City The Board Game </p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This game isn’t just a bloodbath, and while you can expect some good ol’ shootouts, Gangs of Night City will reward strategic planning more. For those of you who may be hoping for some story, this does manage to inject some narrative elements into the mix, thanks to the scenarios you play with. These will mix things up for you and your fellow players with some new rules or mechanics, or even some alternative victory conditions. That said, this game is about seeing who is best at dishing out the most pain, and it just feels fun to cause some chaos with some friends over some drinks during a game night.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-based-on-video-games">Board game adaptations of popular video games</a> have become pretty commonplace these days, and we have covered a bunch, including Gangs of Night City! In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-review"><u>review</u></a>, we said, “It’s a proper board game where factions vie for turf and street cred,” so grab a few friends (the game plays 1-4 players), have everyone chip in a bit, and at this price that would only be about $20, and you have the makings for fun game night.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Other Prime Day Deals</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you are looking for more <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-2025-sale-top-deals-live">Prime Day Deals</a>, check out some other things that are on sale!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em> Scott White is a freelance contributor to IGN, assisting with tabletop games and guide coverage. Follow him on </em><a href="https://x.com/ProfessorRPG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>X/Twitter</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/professorrpg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 8, 2025 11:50 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-deal-prime-day-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Has a Ton of Great Board Game Deals for Prime Day 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-game-deals-prime-day-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-has-a-ton-of-great-board-game-deals-for-prime-day-2025.1238865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fun for the friends, and the family.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The four-day marathon that is this year’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-2025-sale-top-deals-live">Prime Day</a> is live now, running from July 8-11. There’s hardly any product category that’s <em>not</em> on sale at Amazon at the moment. But each year Prime Day is one of the best times to stock up on board games, and this year is no different. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It seems like most board games are on sale right now for Prime Day 2025, and the prices are mostly excellent. Below, we’ve highlighted our picks for the best board game deals available now – but you’ll need a Prime membership to get most of them. You can <a href="https://zdcs.link/QWYnXn?object_uuid=1137cedc-625d-4036-889e-602acc4557a0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">sign up here</a>.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Save Up to 50% Off Board Games for Prime Day</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As an added bonus, a bunch of the games are part of <em>another</em> sale that’s also going on right now that saves you $10 when you spend $40 on select items. So if your game(s) are eligible and you spend more than $40, you’ll get an additional $10 off. As a deal-focused commerce editor, I love it when you can stack a deal on top of a deal. It feels like you’re working the system.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Azul</h2><div catalogid="12ead7a7-b215-4b7d-beae-913ec532e57d" id="224507"><div id="224507" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Azul - Board Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">So what worthy board games are on sale right now? A whole lot of them. Azul is always one of our top sellers when it goes on sale, and it’s currently <a href="https://zdcs.link/av4vEP?object_uuid=1137cedc-625d-4036-889e-602acc4557a0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">on sale for $19.49</a>, which is great considering it usually hovers around the $33 range. Check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/azul-board-game-review">Azul board game review</a> for details.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City</h2></div><div catalogid="12ead7a7-b215-4b7d-beae-913ec532e57d" id="224509"><div id="224509" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Gamers may want to pick up Cyberpunk 2077: Gangs of Night City while it’s <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7O054?object_uuid=1137cedc-625d-4036-889e-602acc4557a0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">on sale for $69.99</a>. It’s “a surprisingly preem experience,” as our critic put it in his <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gangs-of-night-city-board-game-review">review</a>. A ton more are on sale, whether you’re looking for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-family-board-games">family-friendly board games</a> like Guess Who? or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-horror-board-games">horror board games</a> like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nemesis-board-game-buying-guide-expansions">Nemesis</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Jigsaw Puzzle Deals</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">This brand makes some of the coolest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzles-for-adults">puzzles for adults</a> I’ve come across on Amazon. It’s not as well-known as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-brands">Ravensburger or some of the big names</a>, but the quality definitely holds up—and the artwork is designed to be framed, not shoved back in the box.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These 1000-piece puzzles are basically ready-to-hang posters by the time you’re done. If you enjoy fandom-inspired art that actually looks good on a wall, this sale is worth a look.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right now, only four designs are included, each tied to a popular franchise. The <em>Lord of the Rings</em> and <em>Harry Potter</em> options are easily my favorites—they have a bookish, collector’s feel that works way better than most licensed puzzle art.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Is Prime Day a Good Time to Buy Board Games?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Short answer: yes. If you’re looking to pick up a few new board games or card games, Prime Day is one of the best times of the year to do it, matched only by Black Friday in terms of overall discounts and variety.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some of the deals available during Prime Day 2025 represent the lowest prices ever tracked on popular games, including modern classics, family favourites, and party staples. It’s unlikely they’ll drop any further later in the year, and by the time <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> rolls around, you’ll have missed a solid few months of potential game nights.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re unsure whether a deal is truly worth it, use a site like <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CamelCamelCamel</a> to check Amazon’s price history. It’s a quick way to confirm whether a discount is as impressive as it looks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a world filled with screens, board games offer a refreshingly analog way to spend time with friends and family, or just take a break solo. Whether you're looking for something light and fast or deep and strategic, there’s something in this year's sale worth grabbing. Just don’t wait too long, stock will disappear fast, and the best offers rarely hang around past the main Prime Day event.</p></div><p id="more-prime-day-deals"><h3 data-cy="title3" data-toc-title="More Prime Day deals">More Prime Day Deals</h3></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a commerce editor and deals expert for IGN. He also runs IGN's board game and LEGO coverage. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 9, 2025 9:37 am</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-game-deals-prime-day-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tom Clancy, Star Trek: Bridge Crew Studio Ubisoft Red Storm Lays Off 19, Citing 'Global Cost-saving Efforts']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tom-clancy-star-trek-bridge-crew-studio-ubisoft-red-storm-lays-off-19-citing-global-cost-saving-efforts</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tom-clancy-star-trek-bridge-crew-studio-ubisoft-red-storm-lays-off-19-citing-global-cost-saving-efforts.1238850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">No other studios were affected, per Ubisoft.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nineteen employees have been laid off from Star Trek: Bridge Crew and Tom Clancy studio Ubisoft Red Storm, IGN has learned.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft confirmed the layoffs to IGN in a statement as follows:</p><blockquote>Today, Ubisoft made the decision to eliminate 19 roles at Red Storm Entertainment. This step is part of our ongoing, targeted restructuring and global cost-saving efforts, and reflects the needs on the studio’s projects. While this was not an easy decision, it was a necessary one given our operational priorities. We remain committed to supporting those affected with comprehensive severance packages, extended health-care benefits, and career transition assistance. We deeply appreciate their hard work and the impact they’ve had on Ubisoft.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft PR also confirmed that no other Ubisoft locations were impacted by today's layoffs. However, the company did not respond to IGN's request for information on how many employees remain at Red Storm or the status of the company's current projects.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft Red Storm was originally Red Storm Entertainment, founded by author Tom Clancy specifically to make games based on his novels, including Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six. The studio was acquired by Ubisoft in 2000, going on to create hits such as the Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon series and assisting on other popular Tom Clancy games such as The Division. In more recent years, it has taken a backseat role as more of a VR and support studio beginning with Werewolves Within in 2016. and continuing more recently with Star Trek: Bridge Crew and Assassin's Creed Nexus VR.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Red Storm also worked on a canceled Splinter Cell VR game, and the also-canceled <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-cancels-the-division-heartland">The Division Heartland</a>. Most recently, Red Storm assisted on XDefiant, which just shut down completely last month after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-is-discontinuing-xdefiant-in-2025-new-purchases-disabled">an announcement last year</a>. At the time, Ubisoft shut down the San Francisco and Osaka studios behind the game, with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-16/ubisoft-entertainment-cuts-45-people-from-its-us-staff?embedded-checkout=true" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some layoffs occuring at Red Storm as well</a>. It is unclear what project Red Storm is currently working on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/tom-clancy-star-trek-bridge-crew-studio-ubisoft-red-storm-lays-off-19-citing-global-cost-saving-efforts]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>