<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 19:37:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond: Two Souls TV Series on the Way from Star Elliot Page]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-two-souls-tv-series-on-the-way-from-star-elliot-page</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-two-souls-tv-series-on-the-way-from-star-elliot-page.1095204/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-two-souls-tv-series-on-the-way-from-star-elliot-page<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation and Quantic Dream’s story-driven adventure game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-two-souls">Beyond: Two Souls</a> is getting a TV series reimagining from original star Elliot Page.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://deadline.com/2025/01/beyond-two-souls-video-game-television-series-elliot-page-pageboy-1236267129/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Deadline</u></a> reports that Page’s Pageboy Productions has acquired the rights from Quantic Dream in the hopes of adapting it into a television show. The project is said to be in early development and is expected to keep the video game experience’s non-linear narrative in mind as work progresses. Additional details, including casting information and release plans, have yet to be revealed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Page told Deadline that filming Beyond: Two Souls was “one of the most challenging and fulfilling acting experiences” of his career. He continued: “The story’s rich narrative and emotional depth offer us a fantastic foundation. We want to create a unique vision of the characters and their journeys that resonates with fans and newcomers.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Quantic Dream Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Pageboy head of development and production Matt Jordan Smitt elaborated on how he, Page, and the rest of the team plan to “honor the game’s legacy while inviting fresh perspectives.” He added: “Delving into questions of survival and how split-second decisions can alter not just our lives, but the lives of others, are key to telling the story.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The original Beyond: Two Souls launched for the PlayStation 3 in 2013 before eventually making its way to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/11/20/beyond-two-souls-releases-on-playstation-4-next-week"><u>PlayStation 4</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/20/quantic-dream-epic-games-store-partner-to-release-detroit-heavy-rain-beyond-two-souls-on-pc"><u>PC</u></a> in 2015 and 2019, respectively. Directed and written by Quantic Dream’s David Cage, it follows the story of Jodie Holmes, a girl with psychic powers that allow her to communicate with a spirit she calls Aiden. Aside from the non-linear narrative that explores different sections of her life, the game was known for its inclusion of big-name actors like Page and Willem Dafoe.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cage said he is collaborating with Page on the Beyond: Two Souls TV show, though the extent of his involvement is unclear.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are absolutely thrilled to collaborate again with Elliot Page on this project,” Cage said. “I was blown away by his acting performance in the game, and I couldn’t think of anyone else to tell this story with the same passion on another medium.<em> Beyond: Two Souls </em>is a very special game for millions of players around the world who were moved by the story of Jodie and Aiden, and their journey in life and beyond. I know that Elliot has all the talent and instinct to make it something really unique on TV.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It will be some time before the Beyond: Two Souls TV series makes its debut. In the meantime, you can see IGN’s original review for the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2013/10/08/beyond-two-souls-review"><u>here</u></a> and all of our Quantic Dream video game reviews <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/08/13/every-ign-quantic-dream-review-ever"><u>here</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Publisher Addresses Community Complaints About a Lack of Content, Reveals What’s Coming Down the Line]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-publisher-addresses-community-complaints-about-a-lack-of-content-reveals-whats-coming-down-the-line</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-publisher-addresses-community-complaints-about-a-lack-of-content-reveals-what%E2%80%99s-coming-down-the-line.1095198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-publisher-addresses-community-complaints-about-a-lack-of-content-reveals-whats-coming-down-the-line<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> publisher Focus Entertainment has addressed growing frustration over a lack of content and outlined what players can expect in the coming months.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 enjoyed a record-breaking launch late last year, eventually shifting 5 million copies while becoming the fastest-selling Warhammer video game of all time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In recent weeks, however, some within the game’s community have complained that developer Saber Interactive hasn’t provided enough new reasons to keep playing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a new <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/145-january-community-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post</a>, Focus Entertainment reiterated its commitment to supporting Space Marine 2 throughout 2025 and beyond, promising new skins, new PvP and PvE maps, custom lobbies for PvP, the long-awaited Horde mode, PvE prestige ranks, and new weapons all this year. Meanwhile, the Datavault update arrives in February with update 6.0.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In its statement, Focus Entertainment told players to expect updates every two months and that while it would “love to do more,” it’s focusing on delivering polished updates, “which takes time and care.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Space Marine 2 has been out for four months, and your continued enthusiasm means the world to us,” Focus Entertainment said in its statement.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We’re not done with it! You can expect updates every two months. We’d love to do more, but we’re committed to delivering polished updates, which takes time and care! Thank you for your patience, understanding, and unwavering support.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s also worth noting that Space Marine 2’s 6.0 update adds a perks rework and the long-awaited Field of View (FOV) slider for PC. “You expressed how eager you were to get a FOV slider since the launch,” Focus Entertainment said. “While implementing it has been technically challenging, we’ve finally managed to produce a slider worthy of our standards, introduced in version 6.0.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We hope this new feature will meet your expectations!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s no release date yet for Space Marine 2’s patch 6.0, but it sounds like it’s coming very soon. Continue below for everything announced so far.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/29/spacemarine2-roadmap-yearonebattleplan-3840x2160-new-1738174606365.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Space Marine 2 Year One content. Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 update 6.0:</h2><h2 data-cy="title2">NEW PVP MAP - TOMB</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">A new PvP map is about to be implemented in the 6.0 update! We already hinted that it will be set in a closed environment with many narrow passages pushing you to engage more in Closed Quartered Battles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It takes place beneath the surface of Demerium, amongst the haunting structures of in a Necron tomb. It’s a closed environment with many narrow passages. Pay extra attention because there are blind spots. There’s also a wider area to let you switch combat style.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">NEW ENEMY - BIOVORE</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Biovore is a new enemy in PvE, in all maps featuring Tyranids. It’s an Extremis enemy, a dreadful foe both in distance and melee combat. Beware of the Spore Mines ithe shoots.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Don’t forget to dodge and then aim at the Spore Mine to destroy them before impact.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Do not falter, Brother. You’ve got this.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">SALAMANDERS CHAMPION</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We announced it last month: The Salamanders Champion is here! One of the Loyalist First Founding Chapters of the Space Marines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Available for the Sniper class, with both skins for your Champion and for your Bolt Sniper Rifle: adorn that green paint, those flames and go dominate the battlefield.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">RAVEN GUARD COMING!</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Raven Guard are joining the fight! New cosmetics will soon be available with the season pass including the fan-favorite: ✨🦅 beaky helmet 🦅✨ (MK VI “Corvus”) and Raven Guard trinkets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Take a first look at it:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/29/sm2-1738174802029.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Raven Guard cosmetics are coming to Space Marine 2. Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The MK VI “Corvus” helmet comes both with and without the Raven Guard emblem, allowing you to customize your Space Marine for your convenience.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">DATAVAULT</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>The Datavault makes its entry to the Battle Barge</strong>!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In this new area, you will find unlockable information on most elements from the game in the Research Centre, as well as cosmetic rewards. To unlock them, you will need a new special currency, earned via in-game achievements (called Ordeals), in all modes (Campaign, PvE and PvP). Time to challenge yourself!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the kind of Ordeals you’ll have to complete to unlock the currency:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Complete any Mission in Operations mode on Average Threat Level or higher.</li><li>Knock back Spore Mines to kill Tyranids.</li><li>Make a Carnifex stun itself in Operations mode.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">PERKS REWORK</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In a past Community Update, we mentioned that we were not completely satisfied with the quality of perks. We’ve reworked some of them, and these enhancements will be introduced in the next update release. More changes will come on the perks in the future, and we hope this first change on the perks feel more satisfying and engaging. We’re all ears, so don’t hesitate to share your feedback!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">FOV SLIDER FOR PC</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">You expressed how eager you were to get a FOV Slider since the launch. While implementing it has been technically challenging, we’ve finally managed to produce a slider worthy of our standards, introduced in version 6.0.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We hope this new feature will meet your expectations!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">AND MORE</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>New finisher animations on Zoanthropes, Scarab Occult Terminators and Rubric Marines.</li><li>A new functionality will be added, allowing you to upgrade your Master-Crafted and Artificer Armoury Data to Relic by trading them. You can also sell your Armoury Data to get Requisition Points.</li></ul><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/29/tradearmourydata-1738174986516.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Talk to this Tech-Priest to trade your Armoury Data. Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A new difficulty mode with cosmetic rewards will be added for the braves able to successfully complete Operations in this more intense difficulty: a bloodstained Knife Combat and a new pauldron. Note that this new difficulty will only be available if you have completed at least 1 Operation in Lethal Difficulty.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Base Decals available for Right Pauldrons (This one’s for you, Deathwatch players)</li><li>A new option to share your skin between PvE and PvP modes will be added. You’ll no longer need to remake the same skin for both modes! This option also allows you to share your patterns between classes.</li><li>PvP Crossplay Toggle On/Off: allows console players to play with PC players. You now have the option to be matched with either PC players or Console players independently.</li><li>🕺 Emotes 🕺 Strengthen the bond with your fellow Brothers with the new emotes! So go ahead and use them without moderation.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect 5: BioWare Doesn't 'Require Support From the Full Studio', EA Moves Some Staff to Other Teams]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams.1095192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Mass Effect to be led by team of series veterans.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has announced it is restructuring Dragon Age and Mass Effect studio BioWare, moving a number of developers onto other projects within EA and focusing entirely on its upcoming Mass Effect game going forward.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://blog.bioware.com/2025/01/29/bioware-studio-update/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post</a> from general manager Gary McKay, he wrote that the studio is "taking this opportunity between full development cycles to reimagine how we work at BioWare."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Given this stage of development, we don’t require support from the full studio," he continues. "We have incredible talent here at BioWare, and so we have worked diligently over the past few months to match many of our colleagues with other teams at EA that had open roles that were a strong fit."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN understands that EA has already placed an unknown number of developers from BioWare into other, equivalent roles within the company. A smaller number of Dragon Age team members are also seeing their roles terminated, and are being offered time to apply to other roles within the company if they so choose.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">BioWare's structure has shifted repeatedly in recent years. The studio had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs">a round of layoffs in 2023</a>., and has seen a number of high-profile departures throughout the development of Dragon Age: The Veilguard, the most recent of which was<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-director-reportedly-exits-bioware"> director Corinne Busche</a> announcing her departure from the studio last week. It is unclear how many individuals work at BioWare today. IGN asked EA for any comment or specifics on how many individuals at BioWare are being impacted by this change, how many are facing potential layoffs, and how many will remain at the studio. EA did not provide the specifics, but a spokesperson offered the following comment:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The studio's priority was Dragon Age. During this time there were people continuing to build the vision for the next Mass Effect. Now that The Veilguard has shipped, the studio's full focus is Mass Effect.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"While we're not sharing numbers, the studio has the right number of people in the right roles to work on Mass Effect at this stage of development."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new Mass Effect in question was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/a-new-mass-effect-project-is-in-development-at-bioware-with-a-veteran-team">announced four years ago</a>, and is still in the early stages of development. IGN understands that BioWare's current strategy is to prioritize one game at a time, as some developers who had been working on Mass Effect were previously moved to Dragon Age to get the project over the finish line and are now moving back. Per the blog post, Mass Effect development is now being led by series veterans including Mike Gamble, Preston Watamaniuk, Derek Watts, and Parrish Ley.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This news comes a week after EA <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-had-15-million-players-in-first-two-months-ea-expected-3-million">announced that Dragon Age: The Veilguard missed its player targets</a> by nearly 50% and reduced its guidance for the fiscal year due to this and, more impactfully, weaker-than-expected results from EA Sports FC 25. The company will hold its Q3 earnings conference call on February 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Games for February 2025 Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-games-for-february-2025-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-games-for-february-2025-announced.1095186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-games-for-february-2025-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Payday 3, High on Life, and more.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has announced the PlayStation Plus Essential Tier games for February 2025 are Payday 3 (PS5), High on Life (PS4 and PS5), and Pac-Man World Re-Pac (PS4 and PS5).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Revealed on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-payday-3-high-on-life-pac-man-world-re-pac/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, all three games will be made available at no extra cost to PlayStation Plus subscribers on February 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Payday 3 is the struggling cooperative heist shooter from Starbreeze Entertainment that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-director-steps-down-after-disastrous-first-year">had such a disastrous launch</a> that, at least on PC where data is available, more players are online playing its predecessor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A highlight of the launch and follow up attempts to revive the game included Starbreeze releasing what it called the highly anticipated "offline mode" which<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-finally-getting-offline-mode-but-it-requires-online-to-play-and-runs-worse-than-normal"> required an online connection to access and made the game run worse than normal</a>. Starbreeze said in November <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-players-react-to-developer-starbreeze-saying-it-will-make-a-significantly-lower-level-of-investment-in-year-2-content">it will make a "significantly lower level of investment” in the game’s second year</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">High on Life, meanwhile, is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/high-on-life-squanch-games-blade-runner-muppets">a bizarre first person shooter where players take on the role of an intergalactic bounty hunter that uses living, foul-mouthed guns to fight aliens</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/comedy-shooter-high-on-life-surprise-launches-on-ps4-and-ps5">It launched first onto Xbox before joining PlayStation in 2023</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/high-on-life-review">earned an 8/10 in IGN's review</a>. "High on Life is a laugh-out-loud funny space odyssey that’s chaotic, bizarre, and a ton of fun," we said.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Pac-Man World Re-Pac is a remaster of the 1999 platformer with improved UI, fine-tuned mechanics, and updated visuals.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Pac-Man arrives home on his birthday to find the Ghosts have kidnapped Pac-Man’s family and friends and ruined his party," reads the official synopsis. "Off to the rescue, Pac-Man sets out to Ghost Island. Dodge Ghosts, solve environmental puzzles, rescue the Pac-Fam, and more in this platforming adventure."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Payday 3, High on Life, and Pac-Man World Re-Pac will be available be available at no extra cost until March 3. Those who've yet to add January 2025's PlayStation Plus games to their library — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-review">Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/need-for-speed-hot-pursuit-remastered-review">Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit Remastered</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-stanley-parable-ultra-deluxe-review">The Stanley Parable</a> — have until February 3 to do so.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons VR Game Re-Emerges With Official Name and Announcement Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-vr-game-re-emerges-with-official-name-and-announcement-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-vr-game-re-emerges-with-official-name-and-announcement-trailer.1095180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-vr-game-re-emerges-with-official-name-and-announcement-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/official-dungeons-dragons-vr-game-in-the-works">A year after it was announced</a>, Resolution Games’ official Dungeons &amp; Dragons VR game has a final name and an announcement trailer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Resolution Games, best known for digital fantasy tabletop adventure Demeo, is working with Wizards of the Coast on the first virtual reality game set in the Dungeons &amp; Dragons universe, called Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked. It’s due out on PC, consoles, and XR devices, although the platform specifics and release date are yet to be announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The trailer, below, doesn't give much away, teasing the premise of the game with a live-action set-up before a glimpse at what to expect from the art style. Resolution Games is yet to show off gameplay or any screenshots.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizards of the Coast SVP of Digital Strategy &amp; Licensing Eugene Evans said that Resolution Games is taking a different approach to Dungeons &amp; Dragons by putting the emphasis on fast, turn-based combat and pick-up-and-play mechanics.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlemarked adapts D&amp;D classes, actions, and lore to Resolution Games’ Demeo action role-playing system, which is DM-less and focuses on social strategy rather than social roleplay. This, Resolution Games said, encourages group tabletalk focused on tactics and decision-making.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“With the launch of Demeo back in 2021, we began to grow an incredible relationship with the D&amp;D player community,” said Tommy Palm, founder and CEO of Resolution Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Demeo and Demeo Battles quickly became a game night substitute for Dungeon Masters who wanted an out-of-campaign way to have fun with their groups, and for D&amp;D players to introduce their friends and family to tabletop miniatures games.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s cross-platform support for up to four players co-operatively, with two story-based campaigns at launch and additional campaigns in different D&amp;D settings planned as downloadable content in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>