<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:57:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starbreeze Cancels Co-Op Dungeons & Dragons Game Project Baxter, Lays Off Developers, and Doubles Down on Payday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/starbreeze-cancels-co-op-dungeons-dragons-game-project-baxter-lays-off-developers-and-doubles-down-on-payday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starbreeze-cancels-co-op-dungeons-dragons-game-project-baxter-lays-off-developers-and-doubles-down-on-payday.1314628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Starbreeze has canceled Project Baxter, its co-op Dungeons &amp; Dragons game, laid off a significant portion of its development team, and announced plans to double down on its Payday franchise.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-developer-starbreeze-announces-dungeons-dragons-co-op-multiplayer-game">Project Baxter was announced in December 2023</a> as an Unreal Engine 5 D&amp;D game that would “carry the signature Starbreeze cornerstones of co-operative multiplayer, lifetime commitment through a Games as a Service-model, community engagement and a larger than life experience.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The plan then was to launch Project Baxter on all major platforms in 2026 with crossplay. But news has been scarce, with a social media post showing off a single in-engine image in September 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In November last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/payday-3-players-react-to-developer-starbreeze-saying-it-will-make-a-significantly-lower-level-of-investment-in-year-2-content">Starbreeze said it was still hiring for Project Baxter</a>, with work on the game continuing “at full speed.” “Internally, we have weekly playtests of Baxter, and active discussions with a number of industry-leading players regarding potential collaborations around Baxter's development and launch,” the studio said at the time. As of November 2024, Starbreeze had 191 total employees, most of which were based at its head office in Stockholm, Sweden.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The decision to cancel Project Baxter has cost the Swedish company SEK 255 million (approx. $27.2 million) in a write-down of development costs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">CEO Adolf Kristjansson called it a “difficult but necessary decision,” but failed to mention any particular issues with the development of Project Baxter that might have factored in.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our strategy is clear: Payday is one of the most iconic IPs in gaming, with unmatched reach and potential,” Kristjansson said in a prepared statement. “By focusing our investment and talent here, we can accelerate delivery, engage players with more content, and reinforce Starbreeze’s position as the clear leader in the heisting genre. This is about sharpening our focus to create the strongest long-term value for our players, our people, and our shareholders.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Part” of the Baxter team will be redeployed across Starbreeze’s projects, mostly within Payday, but around 44 full-time employees across staff and contractors will lose their jobs. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are doubling down on what our players love – and what we do best – owning the heisting genre,” Kristjansson continued. “Payday is more than a game — it’s a genre we created and continue to lead. By redeploying talent and capital, we can bring innovation to heisting gameplay faster, while also laying the foundation for the future expansion of the genre.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Starbreeze said Payday has had more than 50 million players worldwide and generated close to SEK 4 billion (approx. $427 million) in lifetime gross revenue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“With increased focus and resources, Starbreeze will accelerate its roadmap, delivering more frequent updates, new content drops, and continuous live-engagement,” the company said. “The discontinuation of Baxter, combined with an increased focus on the Payday franchise, will enable Starbreeze to become cash-flow positive in 2026.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kristjansson added: “I want to sincerely thank the Baxter team for their passion and creativity, and express appreciation to Wizards of the Coast for their support. Though we have made the decision to not continue forward with this project, we are proud of what was achieved in Baxter, and those contributions will carry forward into Payday and the future of Starbreeze. By concentrating our efforts on Payday we give Starbreeze and all our employees the best chance to succeed.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, what does the future hold for Starbreeze? The 12-year-old Payday 2 still has significantly more players than Payday 3 on Steam, but the developer insisted Payday 3 “is being developed into a scalable live-engagement platform to engage millions of players worldwide.” The Payday 3 team will grow to about 50 employees before the end of the year “and continue to grow in line with increased player engagement.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Starbreeze said it has new heist games in the works, too, including spinoffs and narrative-driven projects, and plans to expand Payday into new platforms. Meanwhile, it’s offering its services as a work-for-hire studio.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/starbreeze-cancels-co-op-dungeons-dragons-game-project-baxter-lays-off-developers-and-doubles-down-on-payday]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>