<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:34:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil: Requiem Devs Say They Can't Tell if the Game's Actually Scary Anymore]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-devs-say-they-cant-tell-if-the-games-actually-scary-anymore</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-requiem-devs-say-they-cant-tell-if-the-games-actually-scary-anymore.1312012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We've made so many of these that we can't tell anymore until someone else plays it."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Resident Evil has been one of the video game industry's quintessential, flagship horror games for years now, delivering everything over the years from unsettling, atmospheric haunting to outright jumpscares. But as its development team continues to search for new ways to freak people out, a few of its leaders are admitting that they're not always 100% certain what elements of Resident Evil are actually scary anymore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This comes from our interview with director Koshi Nakanishi and producer Masato Kumazama at Tokyo Game Show 2025. We started by talking about Resident Evil: Requiem's new protagonist, Grace, and her <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-developers-are-still-being-coy-about-leon-kennedy">differences from the more action-oriented Leon S. Kennedy</a>. That led to a discussion of why the series was pulling back on the heavy action elements in Requiem, as Nakanishi explains:</p><blockquote>I think you can broadly classify Resident Evil titles on a scale of how much they're like Resident Evil 2 or Resident Evil 4. Resident Evil 7 was definitely on the 2 side of that, as it returned to survival horror roots and was very acclaimed for that. Resident Evil Village built on that and added in more action and gunplay and brought it toard the RE4 side of that particular scale. But if we kept going in that direction there's almost an inflation effect, where you have to keep adding more and more action to outdo the previous title, and by doing that you ultimately end up where Resident Evil 5 and 6 went, and although they're still great games, the general consensus is that they pushed Resident Evil so far in the action direction that it was no longer horror. I didn't want to have to do that with Resident Evil's ninth title where I just tried to outdo the action in Village and ended up making something I didn't want to make. Firmly swinging the scale toward the Resident Evil 2 style was our intention, and it's almost an upgrade of that Resident 2 style.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">But that led to a follow-up question where I asked Nakanishi about the other side of the coin, of trying to outdo their own scares with each new title. Nakanishi noted that their goal isn't necessarily to innovate horror, but there is a certain numbing effect that working on these games for so long has, where they really need to see audience reactions to know if what they've made is actually scary or not.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We've made so many of these that we can't tell anymore until someone else plays it," Nakanishi says. "There was actually a bit of a worry internally before we showed the [Resident Evil: Requiem] hands-off at SGF and the first hands-on at Gamescom, was this actually scary? Because we don't even know anymore. This is our bread and better, what we make every day."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I ended up asking Nakanishi if there was anything they had cut from the game for being too scary. He couldn't recall anything specific that was actually removed from the game after it had been added, but he did remember one anecdote that might make fans of Ethan Winters chuckle:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We didn't really implement it, so it wasn't cut, but- we don't know if something's scary. So we say, we'll do this, we'll do that, we keep adding on stuff, and at one point we were like, what if [Grace] gets a big gash in her leg, or her leg gets cut off, because that thing attacks her, and oh my god it's so scary, but we talked ourselves down a little bit."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So at least we know Grace probably isn't going to have the same issues Ethan did with hands. Probably.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We previewed Resident Evil: Requiem just last month, and you can <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-hands-on-preview">read our impressions of what we've seen so far right here</a>. You can also check out the rest of my discussion with Nakanishi and Kumazawa, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-on-nintendo-switch-2-wasnt-in-the-original-plan-say-developers">how Reqiuem came to the Nintendo Switch 2</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-developers-are-still-being-coy-about-leon-kennedy">what's going on with Leon Kennedy</a>. We've also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-resident-evil-requiem-interview-why-the-games-monster-got-supersized-why-its-probably-not-lisa-trevor-and-a-tease-for-areas-beyond-raccoon-city-just-dont-talk-about-leon">previously spoken to the pair</a> on a number of other topics, such as Raccoon City's return and the game's new monster design.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-devs-say-they-cant-tell-if-the-games-actually-scary-anymore]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Standout Racing Games That Let You Get Behind the Wheel of a Toyota]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/5-standout-racing-games-that-let-you-get-behind-the-wheel-of-a-toyota</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-standout-racing-games-that-let-you-get-behind-the-wheel-of-a-toyota.1311949/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">So many models in so many different games.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently held a fan-voted tournament to determine the greatest racing game of all time. There were a total of 32 entries split across four categories: Arcade Racing, Simulation, Street Racing, and Wild Card.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Mario Kart 8 Deluxe ultimately won the fan vote and was crowned champion, it isn’t exactly known for its realism. Several other entries in the tournament give you the chance to drive cars based on real-life counterparts, including a wide variety of different Toyota models.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Toyota brand has been around for almost 90 years and competes in several different racing series, meaning there are lots of different models that can be included in racing games. And some games make very good use of that. Here are five standout titles that were popular in our fan-voted tournament and also put you in the driver’s seat of Toyota cars.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Forza Horizon 5</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Forza Horizon 5 has the rare distinction of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/forza-horizon-5-review"><u>getting a 10 from IGN</u></a>, and it finished as the runner-up in our fan-voted tournament, so we think it’s safe to call this one of the best racing games ever made. One of its many strengths is the dizzying number of cars in its roster. It had more than 500 vehicles at launch, and DLCs and seasonal additions have brought that number to more than 900 in the nearly four years since it released. That includes 32 different models of Toyota, ranging from classic sports cars like the 1974 Celica GT to pickup trucks like the 2020 Tundra TRD Pro to rally cars like the 2021 GR Yaris to modern sports cars like the 2022 GR86.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gran Turismo 7</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Gran Turismo 7 won the Simulation region of our tournament and made it to the Final Four before being ousted by Forza Horizon 5. It was a very close battle between the two, so this is clearly a beloved title. And <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gran-turismo-7-review"><u>IGN gave it a 9</u></a>, so we’re big fans too. Like the game that defeated it, GT7 also sports an incredible number of different cars. It had 424 cars at launch and has since brought that number to more than 500, which includes 41 Toyota models. In addition to the kinds of sports cars, rally cars, and pickups that are present in Forza Horizon 5, there are also LMP1 cars like the TS030 Hybrid ’12 and TS050 Hybrid ’16, as well as concept cars like the FT-1 and FT-1 VGT.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Forza Motorsport 4</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Forza Motorsport 4 might be 14 years old, but it still holds up as an outstanding racing game and celebration of all things four-wheeled. It had a tough draw in our tournament, dominating its first-round matchup before having to go up against the juggernaut that is Gran Turismo 7 in the second round. IGN <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/10/06/forza-motorsport-4-review"><u>gave Forza Motorsport 4 a 9.5</u></a>, and like the two games that preceded it on this list, its vast selection of cars was a big reason why. That included 19 different models of Toyotas, highlighted by the S class 2002 Top Secret 0-300 Supra, one of the most powerful Unicorn cars in the game.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Project Gotham Racing 2</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Project Gotham Racing 2 might not have catapulted into mainstream popularity like the previous games on this list, but IGN <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2003/11/18/project-gotham-racing-2-2"><u>gave it a 9.5</u></a> and it holds a special place in our hearts, largely because of its focus on style in addition to speed. You earn Kudos points for doing things like powersliding, catching air, driving clean races, and drafting behind opponents. And many goals require that you finish with a certain number of Kudos points, meaning you have to balance driving fast with driving pretty, providing a gameplay experience that separates it from other racing games. That sense of style extended to the cars themselves, too. There were three Toyota models in the game, and they’re all classics: the 1967 2000GT, MR2 Spider, and 1996 Supra.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition Remix</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In what some might have considered a surprise, Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition Remix made it to the quarterfinals of our tournament and put up a solid fight against Forza Horizon 5. This is the updated version of Rockstar’s third game in the series, which added new vehicles, songs, races, maps, updated UI, and brought back Tokyo from Midnight Club 2. It was a marked improvement over said predecessor, and while it was never the fastest or prettiest game around, it more than made up for that with depth and variety. IGN <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2006/03/14/midnight-club-3-dub-edition-remix">gave it an 8.8</a>, and it let you drive, customize, and fine-tune the 1998 Toyota Supra Turbo.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/5-standout-racing-games-that-let-you-get-behind-the-wheel-of-a-toyota]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Build the LEGO Game Boy: Buildable Retro Gaming Nostalgia That Fits in Your Pocket]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-game-boy-set-72046</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-build-the-lego-game-boy-buildable-retro-gaming-nostalgia-that-fits-in-your-pocket.1311850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO has been crushing it with its video game sets. I honestly can't think of a single miss. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-nintendo-entertainment-system-and-it-contains-a-hidden-surprise">The LEGO NES</a>  set, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-pac-man-arcade-which-actually-moves-and-plays">LEGO Pac-Man arcade cabinet,</a> and even the recent <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-sega-genesis-controller-where-to-buy">SEGA Genesis controller</a> (which was only available as a Gift With Purchase) all paid loving homage to the source material and managed to squeeze in clever surprises and Easter eggs. I'm happy to say the LEGO Game Boy, in spite of its smaller size, still managed to sneak in a few surprises, but if you're hoping for something as elaborate as the NES Easter Egg, or the hand-crank movement and hidden '80s arcade scene of the Pac-Man set, definitely temper your expectations.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How Big Is the LEGO Game Boy?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">At 421 pieces, the LEGO Game Boy is the smallest of the available video game console sets LEGO has issued over the years, but in spite of a relatively small brick count, its efficiency of parts still makes for an exceptional whole. When it's fully assembled, it looks everything the part of the original, although it's just a touch smaller.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/29/img-6298-1759163502613.jpeg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">It also comes with bricks to build a small display stand, and a second, smaller display stand that shows off a cartridge and also serves as a place to store the extra lenticular game screens.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Its efficiency of parts still makes for an exceptional whole.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There are three game screens in all: one for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-land">Super Mario Land</a> that has Mario hitting a block to reveal a star, one for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-links-awakening-1993">Link's Awakening</a> that shows Link and Zelda gazing to the sea as gulls fly over head, and one that's just the Nintendo logo scroll when you power on the Game Boy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Swapping screens is no factor at all, you just pop off the back panel and drop it in place. It's held secure with a little lever that's easy to move and has just the right amount of give to keep it from moving without pressing so hard as to deform the thin lenticular sheets.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since this model is based on the original Game Boy and not its later revisions, the graphics are in the sickly greens of that original 160 x 144 display. They're sharp, too, and look exactly like how you remember them. They're lovely. I hope they make more.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">LEGO Game Boy We Build</h3></div></output><h2 data-cy="title2">How Long Does it Take to Build the LEGO Game Boy?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In order to get the most appropriate timing on the LEGO Game Boy as I could, I popped in my Blu-ray copy of the 1989 Nintendo feature-length commercial "The Wizard." My goal was to see if I could complete the build before Fred Savage, Jenny Lewis, and the titular Wizard made it to California.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm happy to say, in spite of having to get up to let my dogs out and then back in, I snapped the final piece into place just as Jenny Lewis stepped onto the dry soil of California on the way to the world Nintendo championships, so just about an hour after I pushed play. Not a bad build time, and again, the final results are so much better than it feels like should be possible with a set this size.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The parts on the inside evoke the look of the inside of a real Game Boy</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Since it's a 421-piece build, there are only five bags of parts inside the box, and they're small bags. I have a little organizer basket from Walmart, the sort of thing you put on a shelf to store buttons and doo-dads for crafts, and I use it to organize parts bags when I build sets. For this build, it was overkill. I still used it, but really, there was no need to. I'm just a creature of habit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I was surprised at the color selection of the bricks: lots of greens, browns, gold, and copper-colored pieces. Then it occurred to me the colors for the interior mimic the colors of a printed circuit board. That's one of the first Easter eggs. As you're putting it together, the parts on the inside you'll never see again evoke the look of the inside of a real Game Boy, or any electronic gizmo of the era. It's obviously not a 1:1 representation of the circuitry, but it's a close enough approximation that I was suitably impressed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The cartridges also follow this circuit board aesthetic on their insides, and the coolest Easter Egg in the set is in the Link's Awakening cartridge. Now, LEGO didn't need to do this at all, because again, once you put it together, you never see it again, but inside of the Link's Awakening cart is a "back up battery" piece. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you don't know, in order to keep save files on those old carts, there had to be a small coin-cell battery providing a trickle of power to keep the electrons dancing soldered onto the board. Link's Awakening was one such cart, and they went ahead and added that detail into the LEGO version, for no reason other than to please people like me. The Super Mario Land cart had no such battery back up and so the LEGO version doesn't either.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/29/img-6300-1759163502613.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The stickers for the carts are exact replicas of the ones on the originals, and I went into a state of hyper concentration to make sure I placed them exactly where they needed to be. Usually I put on LEGO decals with the same tweezers I use for scale models, but this time I just went raw dog on them and did pretty well.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">LEGO Game Boy Controls</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The power switch, D-pad, A and B buttons, contrast, and volume knobs, and start and select buttons are all functional. Well, "functional" meaning "they move." The power switch in particular feels exactly like the one on the original Game Boy. When you switch it on, it's so accurate to how you remember it feeling, you can't help but expect to hear that familiar chime. Obviously it doesn't, but your brain will fill in the details.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>When you switch it on, you can't help but expect to hear that familiar chime.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The rest of the buttons don't feel exactly like they did on the original unit, but they still provide enough tactile feedback to get the job done. After the power switch, the A and B buttons probably feel the most accurate, with a little rubber band system rigged up to give them a little resistance and travel when you press them.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">No LEGO Game Boy Tetris</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're going into the LEGO Game Boy hoping for a Tetris Easter egg, or any Tetris content at all, you're going to be disappointed. While Tetris was the original pack-in game for the Game Boy, and no doubt helped to popularize both the console and the game itself, it's nowhere to be seen here. My guess is it has to do with licensing, as Tetris wasn't a Nintendo game but was merely licensed to Nintendo back in 1989 and it was almost certainly easier to include two first-party Nintendo titles with the kit. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So if you were hoping for a little Tetris homage hiding inside, I'm sorry to say there just isn't one. Take it up with The Tetris Company Inc.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/29/img-6285-1759163502613.jpeg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The LEGO Game Boy is scheduled for an October 1 release date, but Amazon and other retailers have gone ahead and broken street date. That means a lot of people spent their weekend putting together this delightful little LEGO Game Boy kit, and between its short build time and excellent final result, I recommend picking one up if you have any nostalgia for the good old days of the 4-battery OG Game Boy. The kit is also pretty reasonably priced at $59.99, and you can <a href="https://zdcs.link/QmO545?object_uuid=e5f07918-923b-47d1-b552-43b3ea8f25b3&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">go ahead and pick it up right now</a> and get it on, or even before, its October 1 release date. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seth Macy is Senior Social Commerce Producer, and just wants to be your friend. You can find him online.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/we-build-the-lego-game-boy-set-72046]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 8 Best Spider-Man Magic: The Gathering Cards That I'm Already Chasing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-spider-man-most-popular-cards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-8-best-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-cards-that-im-already-chasing.1311847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/spider-man-magic-the-gathering-crossover-green-goblin-card-reveal"><u>The Marvel’s Spider-Man set</u></a> for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> is here after months of hype building, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-spider-man-most-expensive-cards"><u>while some cards are already climbing in value</u></a>, there’s the small matter of, well, playing the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we’ve already covered <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-spider-man-best-selling-cards-pre-release"><u>the most popular cards before launch</u></a>, these are more about the fun they bring to your side of the table when you sit down to play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s swing into it, shall we?</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Soul Stone</h2><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228496"><div id="228496" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering The Soul Stone</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Yes, people are really excited for the Soul Stone’s borderless and Infinity Foil variants, but <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRMbk1?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>the standard card</u></a> could be particularly powerful in any deck where you’re looking to resurrect creatures.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Being able to return creatures to the battlefield each turn, even in lieu of haste, is going to ruin a lot of opponents’ days.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Spectacular Spider-Man (Various)</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228497"><div id="228497" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Spectacular Spider-Man</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Borderless Costume Change cards are very popular already (and racking up the value), but any <a href="https://zdcs.link/9ZMpkD?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Spectacular Spider-Man</u></a> from the set is worth a look.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It can be cast with Flash and is essentially a Heroic Intervention on a 3/2 creature, and it only costs two mana to summon in the first place.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Eddie Brock/Venom, Lethal Protector</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228498"><div id="228498" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Eddie Brock/Venom, Lethal Protector</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/ao6pEb?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Eddie Brock/Venom, Lethal Protector</u></a> was always likely to be popular thanks to the legacy of the character, but it’s a fun card, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The design revolves around bringing low-cost creature cards back with Eddie, but sacrificing larger ones with Venom.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Gwenom, Remorseless</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228499"><div id="228499" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Gwenom, Remorseless</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aN8boX?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Gwenom, Remorseless</u></a> is looking particularly popular since you can play cards from the top of your library with a life cost attached rather than mana.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Given she’s also a 4/4 with Deathtouch and Lifelink, you’ll want to always be attacking to gain some life back, then spend it to play more cards. She could be my Commander from the set.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Opposition Agent</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228500"><div id="228500" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Opposition Agent</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A card that’s bound to be fun in big Commander games, <a href="https://zdcs.link/aBDRxJ?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Opposition Agen</u>t</a> has some Agent Venom art this time and gives you a 3/2 with flash that lets you drop it into play and use their deck against them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The artwork is awesome here, too, and I’m excited to cause some chaos with it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Multiversal Passage</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228501"><div id="228501" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Multiversal Passage</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">A land that can be any basic land is always handy, as is the option for it to enter untapped at the cost of 2 life.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Count us in for running <a href="https://zdcs.link/aM8l0q?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Multiversal Passage</u></a> in a deck or two.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Anti-Venom, Horrifying Healer</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228502"><div id="228502" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Anti-Venom, Horrifying Healer</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">An awesome card is a 5/5 that brings back a card from your graveyard, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QVEZd7?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Anti-Venom, Horrifying Healer</u></a> can also power up as it takes damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You could, in theory, end up using him as a game-ending play if it takes enough damage from other players, or you could use him in a deck that’ll have your own creatures damage him to make him a juggernaut.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Cosmic Spider-Man</h2></div><div catalogid="94c55437-918d-49ac-9622-8bd2f7aef95d" id="228503"><div id="228503" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Cosmic Spider-Man</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Keyword soup on a five-color card? We may not have got Commander decks for Marvel’s Spider-Man, but <a href="https://zdcs.link/z6D7pd?object_uuid=7630d088-2cbb-4c17-bc66-fbd8d53a1835&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Comic Spider-Man</u></a> makes a great argument to helm one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He powers up every Spider you have, giving them the same keywords, and that applies to Spider heroes, too. So, if you want to build a Spider-Verse deck, this is the way to go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Sep 29, 2025 5:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-marvel-spider-man-most-popular-cards]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hell Clock Update 1.1 Detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hell-clock-update-11-detailed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hell-clock-update-1-1-detailed.1311844/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Brazilian indie studio Rogue Snail has shared the details for today's 1.1 release of its roguelike ARPG Hell Clock. Titled "Clockmaker's Tools", the update introduces crafting mechanics, rebalances damage scaling and defense, and adds a number of quality of life improvements. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rogue Snail provided the following update notes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Introducing Crafting -</strong> Tools now drop from enemies during runs, and these crafting materials can be used in the Reliquary to change the effects of Relics, Imbue them with new powers, or risk Corrupting them for even greater rewards. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1782460/view/515221043692962978?l=english" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">More details here</a>.</li><li><strong>Major Rebalance -</strong> Changes to Defense and Damage scaling for both players and monsters, Conviction and Evasion reworks, and many more tweaks to make the game more fun and varied across the board. </li><li><strong>Better Boss Fights -</strong> All Bosses and Unique enemies now have rebalanced health and feature the Curse system, making them less bullet sponges and much more lethal. </li><li><strong>Even More Build Variety -</strong> A product of the crafting system and changes to damage scaling, many more builds are now much more viable. </li><li><strong>Quality of Life Improvements -</strong> The Reliquary now includes options to filter Relics and save Loadouts. Blessed Gear can also now be stored in a stash and saved as Loadouts. Plus much more. </li></ul><h2 data-cy="title1">Full Patch Notes</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Gameplay</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added "Clockmaker's Tools" crafting system to the game. There are 9 different currencies, and some will start dropping from the middle of the Act 1 campaign. Check our <strong>dedicated Crafting blog post</strong> for in-depth information about this</li><li>Monster Life and Damage scaling changed across the board. This is an overall decrease in monster Life and Damage scaling across the entire game</li><li>Conviction Reworked: It now has a Max value determined by your Mana. "Conviction Gain" stat replaced by "Max Conviction". Decay is now <em>drastically</em> reduced, and it decays even less as your current value gets further away from your Max value</li><li>Evasion Reworked: you can no longer Evade area effects. Basically any ground effects and any attack in the game which has a ground indicator, as well as secondary area effects from attacks (such as the Headcutter's ground slam) are no longer possible to Evade</li><li>Boss damage has been reduced across the board, but all Bosses now have the "Curse" mechanic. Getting hit by Boss attacks will inflict stacks of "Curse" that will last through the entirety of the fight. Each stack of Curse makes you take more damage from attacks. The Jailer mini-boss is the only exception and cannot inflict "Curse".</li><li>"Second Wind" has been changed in endgame. Instead of paying 1 point for 100% death protection (as in Campaign), the Oblivion Bell and Infernal Bell versions now give 25% chance to trigger per point. This means Second Wind now costs 4 points instead of 1 in endgame.</li><li>"Clock Seconds" drops are now dynamically adjusted based on how much time you have remaining. Less time on the Hell Clock increases the chances of obtaining Time drops (up to 300%).</li><li>Base Critical Chance reduced from 5% to 4%</li><li>Base Ignite damage increased from 60% to 85%</li><li>Base Ignite duration increased from 5 to 6</li><li>Bleed chance scaling with enemy Life reduced by 50% <em>(enemies having large Current Life pools relative to hit damage now impacts the Bleed chance 50% less than before)</em></li><li>Bleed chance now has a reduction floor of 10%. This means that no matter how much Life your target has, your chance to bleed on hit will never be less than 10% of your listed Bleed Chance. <em>(i.e. if you character sheet says you have 50% Bleed Chance, it can never be reduced to less than 5%)</em></li><li>Blighted attack speed reduction reduced from 20% to 8%</li><li>Player starting base damage increased from 100 to 180</li><li>Life Drain effects now count as taking damage for the purposes of gaining Vigor Stacks</li><li>*<em>For example, if your Skill shoots 3 projectiles and you have +60% Projectile Amount, it will always shoot 4 projectiles and have an 80% chance of shooting a 5th one on each use</em></li><li>Relics now yield more Soulstones when Recycled based on their Tier and on how many affixes they have</li><li>Act 2 (in all difficulties and game modes) now has approximately +25% Soulstones gained, +10% Relic drops and +15% Currency drops</li><li>Act 3 (in all difficulties and game modes) now has approximately +50% Soulstones gained, +20% Relic drops and +30% Currency drops</li><li>Reduced bonus chance to find Potions when in low quantity by 25%</li><li>Memory Level's progression curve has been changed to accommodate the changes in the Soulstone economy (in general it will take a bit more Soulstones to reach higher Levels than it did before this patch, but it should take about the same play time due to the increased Soulstone gains)</li><li>Infernal Bell (Ascension) can now only reach a maximum Skill Level of 7 (down from 8), to accommodate for the new +Skill Level items.</li><li>Minor Mana Nodes in Oblivion Bell and Infernal Bell reduced from 75 to 50</li><li>Enemy Barriers are now considered extra Life for the purposes of calculating Ailment thresholds</li><li>Enemies with Barriers are no longer immune to Ailments</li><li>Ignite and Bleed damage now bypass Barriers and deal damage straight to enemy Life</li><li>Enemy Barrier values increased across the board in endgame</li><li>Players' default Loot Pickup Range increased from 5 to 6</li><li>All Summon Damage affixes on Relics and Skill Trees increased by 40% across the board</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Hell Clock Screenshots</h3></div></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Quality of Life</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>New Feature: "Death Recap" - you can now see the damage breakdown from the last 5 hits you took before dying</li><li>New Feature: The "Blessed Stash" now stores your Blessed Gear in town!</li><li>New Feature: Added Loadouts to Relics</li><li>New Feature: Added Loadouts to Gear</li><li>New Feature: Added a "Search" function to the Reliquary and Stash</li><li>New Options added to customize how you want to handle your Blessed Gear pickups</li><li>Blessed Gear pop-up window now has protection against accidental clicks</li><li>New Item Drop labels added to make it easier to see what you are getting</li><li>Added new Relic art to represent each Tier</li><li>Improved the visuals of Relic rarities</li><li>Prayer of Vengeance's tooltip now displays accurate and up-to-date values of Crit Chance and Crit Damage, separately</li><li>You can now skip the splash screens at the game startup</li><li>Capped Resistances now show the uncapped values in parenthesis</li><li>"Additional Damage" affixes renamed to "Bonus Damage" for clarity, and tooltip explanations improved as well</li><li>Righteous Blade damage and scaling information now dynamically added to Prayer of Health's tooltip</li><li>Added new visuals and sound for item drops, including the new Tools currency drop</li><li>Improved the sound of casting the Old Bell</li><li>Improved the visual clarity of Ignite - it is now way easier to tell when an enemy has been Ignited</li><li>Added the following settings to the Options menu:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Low Life HUD Feedback</li><li>Damage HUD Feedback</li><li>Restore Life on Level Up</li><li>Restore Mana on Level Up</li><li>Use Potion on Full Pickup</li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">World Tiers</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Abyss and Oblivion completely rebalanced to provide a significantly greater challenge</li><li>Added new World Tier: Void. It contains no Constellation points and will serve as temporary "pinnacle challenge" for your builds until Endless Nightmares is released</li><li>Added the following effects to Abyss World Tier: -20% Evasion, Endurance and Anti Magic; -20% Experience Gain; +40% Crafting Tools Drop Rate;</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Skills</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Basic Attack now supports Skill Level scaling</li><li>Bombardment Base Damage increased from 1.0 to 1.45</li><li>Closed Body Conviction Gain from Max Mana reduced from 100%-290% to 40%-104%</li><li>Closed Body base cooldown increased from 15 to 30</li><li>Closed Body cooldown scaling with Skill Levels reduced to match the gain on Conviction</li><li>Closed Body Retaliation base damage increased from 100% to 250%</li><li>Closed Body Retaliation Aura base duration increased from 5 to 10</li><li>Closed Body higher Skill Levels now also increase the duration of the Retaliation Aura proportionally</li><li>Closed Body cooldown time scaling with Skill Level reduced by 50%</li><li>Double Knives base damage decreased from 0.75 to 0.55</li><li>Double Knives damage scaling with Skill Level increased from 0.225 to 0.375</li><li>Holy Rosary base damage increased from 1 to 1.2</li><li>Holy Rosary projectiles now pierce up to 3 enemies by default</li><li>Holy Rosary base Mana cost reduced from 180 to 170</li><li>Holy Rosary base projectile duration reduced from 3.8 to 3.1</li><li>Holy Rosary base damage increased from 0.45 to 0.6</li><li>Judgement Ailment Duration Global Buff increased from 3% to 4% per Rank</li><li>Judgment now has as a 9-second Base Cooldown</li><li>Judgement minimum cooldown increased from 0.2 to 0.3</li><li>Judgment Mana cost reduced from 300 to 210</li><li>Judgment base Resistances reduction decreased from 0.4 to 0.2</li><li>Judgment added effect: enemies affected by Judgement take 20% additional Ignite and Bleed damage</li><li>Matadeira base damage increased from 2.4 to 3.0</li><li>Matadeira base cooldown increased from 5 to 6 seconds</li><li>Matadeira damage scaling with Skill Levels increased from 1.0 to 1.5</li><li>Passage base cooldown increased from 3.5 to 4.8</li><li>Phantom Marksmen base damage increased from 0.8 to 1.3</li><li>Phantom Marksmen base cooldown increased from 0.5 to 1.5</li><li>Phantom Marksmen min cooldown increased from 0.16 to 0.3</li><li>Phantom Marksmen Mana cost reduced from 350 to 145</li><li>Phantom Marksmen Global Buff synergy is now "+2.2% Damage[x] per Rank"</li><li>Phantom Marksmen per-shot damage now scales linearly with Projectile Amount</li><li>Phantom Marksmen base range increased from 15 to 22</li><li>Prayer of Health base regen scaling reduced from 4%-9% to 3%-5.5%</li><li>Prayer of Vengeance base crit values reduced to be in line with the new global rebalance, new base crit chance and crit damage bonus is 18%</li><li>Reflexes Reworked: it is now called "Spectral Knives". The skill is now always active. The active effect instantly regenerates all Spectral Knives and provides a buff that gives +20% damage, attack speed and regen speed to the Spectral Knives for 5 seconds. Spectral Knives now have double the Chance to Bleed naturally.</li><li>Reflexes (Spectral Knives) base damage reduced from 0.75 to 0.5</li><li>Reflexes (Spectral Knives) base throw speed increased from 0.3 interval to 0.2 interval</li><li>Reflexes (Spectral Knives) damage scaling with Skill Levels increased from 0.375 to 0.45</li><li>Reflexes (Spectral Knives) base cooldown increased from 8 to 11</li><li>Reflexes (Spectral Knives) now has the "Spell" tag</li><li>Repeater base damage increased from 0.66 to 0.8</li><li>Summon Brute Global Buff per Rank now provides +2%[+] for both Life and Mana</li><li>Summon Brute base Life increased from 6000 to 12000</li><li>Summon Brute Life gain per Skill Level increased from 30% to 40%</li><li>Summon Brute base damage increased from 1.0 to 3.0</li><li>Split Shot base damage increased from 0.6 to 0.8</li><li>The Old Bell base cooldown increased from 0.5 to 1.3</li><li>The Old Bell base damage increased from 2.5 to 4</li><li>The Old Bell damage scaling per Skill Level reduced from 0.3 to 0.25</li><li>Veil of Quills base damage increased from 0.6 to 0.7</li><li>Veil of Quills base Mana cost reduced from 200 to 175</li><li>Veil of Quills Wither Buildup Rate Global Buff decreased from 1.5% to 0.5% per Rank</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Blessings</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduced Constitution III Life on Kill from 1.5% to 0.75%</li><li>Reduced Constitution IV Life on Hit from 3% to 1.5%</li><li>Increased Constitution IV Life to Melee Damage conversion from 2.5% to 7%. Max damage bonus from this conversion is now 500</li><li>Constitution IV Life Leech increased from 1% to 5%</li><li>Increased Spirit IV Mana converted to Spell Damage from 2% to 7%. Max damage bonus from this conversion is now 500</li><li>Bombardment's Magic Rarity "Duration" Blessing of Proficiency removed</li><li>Summon the Guard's "Attack Speed" Blessing of Proficiency reduced by about 45%</li><li>Judgement Blessing of Proficiency "Intensity" scaling reduced from 10%-80% to 10%-40%</li><li>Northerner's Belt Activation Cooldown Blessing of Proficiency removed</li><li>Feathered Dagger's Projectile Duration Blessing of Proficiency removed</li><li>Blessing of Alacrity II - Evasion reduced from 10% to 6%</li><li>Blessing of Alacrity III - Evasion reduced from 15% to 9%</li><li>Blessing of Spirit IV - Current Mana to Spell Damage ratio reduced from 7% to 6.66%</li><li>Blessing of Force III - Ignite Damage increased from 30% to 50%</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Relics</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Relics can now sometimes drop already "Imbued" with one Imbued implicit</li><li>Relics can now rarely drop already "Corrupted", always rolling with one Corrupted implicit (there's also a small chance for Relics to drop both Imbued AND Corrupted)</li><li>Grand Relics (4x1) and Exalted Relics (2x2) now roll "Major" versions of +Damage% affixes, which have increased values</li><li>Due to the changes in the Soul Stone economy, Relic Upgrade costs have been increased from Rank 3 onwards by 20-30%</li><li>Added a new Rare Affix: "Split Shot's Mana cost reduced". Can be crafted on Small Relics.</li><li>Added a new Rare Affix: "Increase Anti-Magic, reduce Max Life". Can be crafted on Large Relics.</li><li>Reduced "Life on Kill" and "Mana on Kill" affixes by about 50% across the board</li><li>"Chance to Apply Ignite" affixes increased by about 25%</li><li>"Ignite Damage" affixes increased by about 25%</li><li>Critical Chance affixes reduced by about 50% across the board</li><li>Critical Damage affixes reduced by about 30% across the board</li><li>Elemental Resistance affixes reduced by about 50% across the board</li><li>Physical Resistance affix is now 2 times rarer to roll in every Relic</li><li>Physical Resistance affixes reduced by about 50% across the board</li><li>Mana Regen affix scaling reduced from 1.1-1.3 to 1.08-1.24</li><li>Mana Regen affix upgrade scaling changed to custom scaling (this is an overall reduction in scaling)</li><li>Life on Kill and Mana on Kill can no longer be rolled in small (1x1) Relics</li><li>Life on Kill and Mana on Kill are now 3 times rarer to roll in every Relic</li><li>Attack Speed affix on small (1x1) Relics is now 4 times rarer</li><li>Chance to Bleed and Chance to Ignite affixes on small (1x1) Relics are now 2 times rarer</li><li>Rare affix "Potion gives Elemental Resistance" reduced from 10%-50% to 10%-30%</li><li>Rare affix "Potion gives Physical Resistance" reduced from 10%-35% to 8%-18%</li><li>Rare affix "All Resistances" reduced from 8%-20% to 4%-10%</li><li>Rare Bleed Chance affix changed from multiplicative additive to flat, new scaling from 4%-12%</li><li>Rare affix "Projectile Amount" changed from Multiplicative Additive to Flat</li><li>Rare affix "Projectile Amount" reduced from 10%-50% to 10%-30%</li><li>Rare affix "Evasion on hit with Marksman skills" bonus reduced from 10-35% to 10-25%</li><li>Rare affix "Take less damage from Close Enemies" scaling reduced from 5%-15% to 3%-7%</li><li>Rare Affix "Move Speed when affected by a Prayer" scaling reduced from 7.5%-17% to 5%-9%</li><li>Rare Affix "Bleed Chance" changed to "Bleed Damage"</li><li>Rare Affix "Critical Hits With Melee Skills will Leech Life" drastically reduced</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Uniques</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>(New Unique)</strong> Added new Unique to Act 2: <strong>Tiriri's Law</strong> (Exalted): <em>Gain Ignite damage. Killing Ignited monsters will make their loot always attract to you, with no range limitations.</em></li><li><strong>(New Unique)</strong> Added new Unique to Act 1: <strong>Labaredas</strong> (Grand): <em>Whenever you Ignite an enemy, gain a stack of Labaredas. For each stack of Labaredas, Split Shot gains Projectile Amount. Split Shot base damage is reduced.</em></li><li><strong>(New Unique)</strong> Added new Unique to Act 2: <strong>Headless Doll</strong> (Large): <em>Gain Summon Damage for each Summon you have active.</em></li><li>Ancestral Memory added effect: "Converts Feitor's Lash to Physical".</li><li>Ashes of Mourning base cooldown reduction increased from 2%-6% to 4%-10%</li><li>Barbed Wire reworked to "Lasso always applies Bleed. Global Bleed Duration increased by X%[+]."</li><li>Banner of Faith scaling changed to 2.5%-4%</li><li>Bead Necklace steps increased from 10-20 to 16-32</li><li>Bloodied Doll scaling changed from 4%-9% to 6.5%-8.5%</li><li>Bloodied Doll changed from base additive to Spell Damage additive</li><li>Blue Calcite reworked to "Reflexes is converted to Lighting and deals +X%[x] damage."</li><li>Blunderbuss Damage Scaling changed from 120%-160% to 140%-160%</li><li>Blunderbuss damage multiplier per projectile reduced from 150%-210% to 120%-160%</li><li>Blunderbuss added effect: "Pierces 2 additional enemies"</li><li>Bundle of Syringes damage bonus scaling reduced from 1.075-1.21 to 1.05-1.15</li><li>Burning Shackles reworked: Lash hits on Ignited monsters consume Ignite to deal X% of all pending Ignite damage as a Fire hit.</li><li>Caatinga Hunters bonus per stack reduced from 0.06 to 0.03</li><li>Death Notary changed to: "Enemies affected by Slow Time become Exposed (take +30%[x] damage from all sources). Slow Time Duration is reduced by X%[x]"</li><li>Death Notary's "Exposed" effect increased from 20% to 30%</li><li>Delicate Rosary mana recovery significantly reduced to be in line with the Reflexes rework</li><li>Disorientation Life-to-Damage scaling increased from 35%-80% to 280%-400%</li><li>Energy Box damage scaling increased from 80%-220% to 180%-300%</li><li>Feathered Dagger now pierces a maximum of 3 enemies. Damage lost per each pierce reduced from 70-50% to 40-25%</li><li>Final Reckoning damage scaling increased from 1000%-3000% to 5000-15000%</li><li>Garrisson Supplies Projectile Amount changed from Multiplicative to Flat</li><li>Holy Water Life-to-Conviction conversion reduced from 350%-620% to 180%-300%</li><li>Last Prayer base explosion damage scaling significantly increased to 300%-500%</li><li>Last Prayer base explosion radius increased by 80%</li><li>Mark of the Vulture explosion now requires 12 stacks instead of 7</li><li>Peace and Quiet reworked: "Casting Passage gives you X%-X% of your Max Conviction if there's an enemy Near you"</li><li>Poem Never Recited no longer reduces the duration on Slow Time</li><li>Powderbag damage scaling reduced from 160%-310% to 160%-260%</li><li>Righteous Blade base Life degen reduced from 0.15 to 0.05</li><li>Righteous Blade damage area now has the "Area of Effect" Skill tag</li><li>Righteous Blade damage now scales with the Skill Level of Prayer of Health</li><li>Righteous Blade life degen now scales with the Skill Level of Prayer of Health</li><li>Saviour's Shield damage reduction scaling reduced from 10%-25% to 10%-15%</li><li>Silver Bullets now add Lightning damage instead of Physical, and the added damage is now multiplied by the triggering skill's Damage%</li><li>Silver Bullets now drain 10% of current Conviction when used</li><li>Silver Bullets damage scaling is now fixed at 10% of current Conviction. New roll is a flat damage limit from 150-300</li><li>Silver Bullets can now be used by eligible Summons. It uses your Conviction value, but does not drain your Conviction when Summons use it.</li><li>Skull of the Vulture reworked: It is now a 2x1 Relic <em>(if you have the original 1x1 Relic, treasure it, because no one will be able to ever drop it after 1.1 releases)</em>. New effect is: "Shadow Dash hits on Bleeding monsters deal X% of all pending Bleed damage as a small Physical explosion. Consumes all Bleed stacks on the monster."</li><li>Spearhead Rework: changed to "Split Shot pierces 2 additional enemies. Gain +X%[x] damage per pierce"</li><li>Spiked Chains damage reduction scaling reduced from 5%-20% to 5%-15%</li><li>Stolen Weapons base damage scaling reduced from 20-44% to 18%-26%</li><li>Tempest Move-Speed-to-Damage scaling increased from 8%-34% to 10%-40%</li><li>Tempest Electric Wave damage increased from 20% to 30%</li><li>The Sacrificed now allows you to cast The Old Bell even if you don't have enough Life</li><li>The Sacrificed Life Drain reduced from 20% to 7%</li><li>The Sacrificed damage bonus is now fixed at 7% of Max Life. New roll is a flat damage limit from 120-230</li><li>Toll of the Dead cooldown penalty reduced from 3 seconds to 1 second</li><li>Toll of the Dead now summons a maximum of 4 spirits</li><li>Unshakable Faith now scales with Current Mana instead of Maximum Mana</li><li>Unshakable Faith damage bonus is now fixed at 7% of current Mana. New roll is a flat damage limit from 120-230</li><li>Voice of War changed to Multiplicative instead of Multiplicative Additive</li><li>Voice of War base damage bonus scaling reduced from 30%-80% to 15%-40%</li><li>Wheel of Death Life drain scaling reduced from 10%-5% to 5%-2.5%</li><li>Worker's Tools rework: no longer scales with Summon damage, Holy Rosary projectiles maximum Pierce is 1.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Gear</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added a new Blessed Armor archetype with Life + Mana Shield</li><li>Evasion scaling from Blessed Armor reduced from 7.5%-30% to 7.5%-25%</li><li>Evasion scaling from Blessed Headgear reduced from 3%-15% to 3%-10%</li><li>Evasion scaling from Blessed Shoulder reduced from 5%-22% to 4%-11%</li><li>Blessed Weapon base damage reduced by 20% across the board</li><li>Reduced Elemental Resistance affixes on Blessed Gear by about 30% across the board</li><li>Blessed Rings (Left) can now roll with "Chance to Bleed" instead of "Chance to Apply Ailments"</li><li>Blessed Weapons of tier 5 and above now roll "Bleed Damage" and "Ignite Damage" as separate variants instead of pure "Ailment Damage"</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Monsters</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Electric Beetle base damage reduced from 48 to 40</li><li>Electric Beetle Mini base damage reduced from 40 to 32</li><li>Reduced Loot Goblin Life scaling in Veteran difficulty</li><li>Matriarch<ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased linear projectile velocity</li><li>Reduced anticipation time for Unburrow Explosion by half</li><li>Increased Unburrow explosion arched projectile speed</li><li>Reduced anticipation time for arched projectiles</li><li>Increased Unburrow animation speed</li><li>Area damage reduced by 50% on all attacks</li></ul></li><li>Wraith<ul data-cy="list"><li>Summon: Cooldown reduced from 20s to 15s, and the Wraith can summon minions at the very start of the battle</li><li>Soul Arrow Burst: Projectile count increased from 5 to a random value between 5 and 7.</li><li>Small Homing Projectiles: Increased fire rate and added movement noise to projectiles.</li><li>Now can also attack with multiple small projectiles after teleporting</li><li>Small projectiles now apply 4 Curse Stacks per hit (was 8)</li><li>Soul Arrow hitbox size increased from 0.5 → 0.6</li></ul></li><li>Machinist<ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased Tendril attack animation speed by 20%</li><li>Tendril attacks now hit you more consistently at close range</li><li>Added a secondary tendril attack to counter "hugging" strategy</li><li>Tendril Skills: Reduced anticipation time for most tendril abilities</li><li>Added a more dangerous Tendril attack combo to the attack pool</li><li>Overload: interval between explosions reduced from 0.5s to 0.25s</li><li>Battle camera angle is now diagonal for better visibility</li></ul></li><li>Urubu's Dive Attack: Increased radius and reduced anticipation time, drastically reducing its invulnerability phase</li><li>Changed Tamarindo's shadow clones damage from Physical to Lightning</li><li>Changed Doctor's Lackey Ground Stomp damage from Physical to Fire</li><li>Reduced Doctor's Lackey Ground Stomp damage by 50%</li><li>Starved Beast area damage reduced by 50% on all attacks</li><li>Starved Beast<ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduced damage of area attacks by 50%</li><li>Reduced jump attack hitscan radius from 4 → 3.5</li><li>Removed idle delay after the second Plague Bomb projectile</li><li>Plague Bomb projectiles now apply Curse Stacks</li><li>Plague Bomb projectiles no longer deal damage after the boss dies</li></ul></li><li>Regular Vulture increased takeoff and landing speed, now fires a ranged homing attack with two projectiles</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Drops</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Global chance of Magic Relic drops reduced from 0.32 to 0.21</li><li>Global chance of Rare Relic drops reduced from 0.18 to 0.11</li><li>Relics have a 9% chance to drop already Imbued</li><li>Relics have a 4% chance to drop already Corrupted</li><li>Removed "The Sacrificed" from the Merchant drop table in Act 1</li><li>Increased the drop rates for early game build-defining Uniques in the Act 1 Merchant: Blunderbuss, Spearhead, Molten Relic, Tempest, Unshakable Faith</li><li>Act 1 Relics are now significantly more likely to drop as Tier 2 Relics in Act 2 (but the Act 2 Relics are still more common)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Constellations</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Made <strong>8 new Constellations</strong> available: <strong>Boitatá</strong>, <strong>Caipora</strong>, <strong>Ceuci Star-Mother</strong>, <strong>Irôko</strong>, <strong>Nanã</strong>, <strong>Ossain</strong>, <strong>Xangô</strong>, <strong>Yaci</strong> <strong>Yateré</strong>.</li><li>Oxumaré's "Never-Ending Cycle" now recovers 18% of active cooldowns OR 1 second (whichever is lowest)</li><li>Oxumaré's "Spell Transformation" text fixed to correctly represent what the Constellation does: gain Multiplicative Additive damage per Agility Orb (not multiplicative per Power Orb, as it wrongly stated before).</li><li>Oxumaré Spell Transformation damage bonus reduced from 10% to 7.5%</li><li>Oxumaré Projectile Transformation damage bonus reduced from 10% to 7.5%</li><li>Oxóssi Constellation Crit Chance node changed from Multiplicative to a flat +4% bonus</li><li>Oxóssi Constellation Skill Speed nodes changed from multiplicative to flat</li><li>Oxóssi flat crit damage node reduced from 20% to 12%</li><li>Oxóssi Skill Speed nodes reduced from 10% to 5%</li><li>Oxóssi's "Arrows of Oxóssi" now provides +30% Projectile Amount per Agility Orb</li><li>Child of Ogum duration increased from 2 seconds per stack to 4 seconds per stack</li><li>St. Expeditus Constellation "Quick Sagacity" Evasion node reduced from +20% to +15%</li><li>Tupã's Power Orbs base mana regen reduced from 1% to 0.5%</li><li>Caupé Critical Hit Damage nodes reduced from 15% to 7.5%</li><li>Caupé's "Critical Damage per Agility orb" node red</li><li>Oxum's Reward node reduced from +15%[x] to +10%[+]</li><li>Expeditus' Evasion node reduced from 20% to 12%</li><li>Ossain Physical Resistance nodes increased from 2% to 4%</li><li>Guaraci's capstone "The Sun" damage now scales with Lasso's Skill Level</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Fixes</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where "Elemental Damage" bonuses were not properly showing up on the Character Sheet</li><li>Fixed an issue where more Cursed Shrines than intended would spawn in Act 3 (each Act should have only 4 Cursed Shrines in total)</li><li>Fixed Holy Water Upgrade scaling using the wrong scaling multiplier</li><li>Fixed an issue with Phantom Marksmen not receiving Marksman bonuses correctly (such as projectile amount, Powder Bag triggers, etc.)</li><li>Fixed an issue with Garrison Supplies where the damage reduction was being applied with the wrong operation</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Prayer of Vengeance tooltip would display the bonus as "flat" instead of "multiplicative additive", leading to confusion</li><li>Fixed an issue where Feitor's Lash Critical Damage blessing was actually lowering the damage instead of increasing it</li><li>Fixed an issue where Rare affix "Evasion on hit with Marksman skills" would use the wrong scaling configuration</li><li>Fixed an issue where Unshakable Faith Unique was not scaling with the Skill Damage when converting Mana to The Old Bell damage</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Spirit IV and Constitution IV conversion blessings were not scaling with Skill Damage</li><li>Fixed an issue where Written Promises would roll with one less affix than it should</li><li>Fixed an issue where Skull of the Vulture would not properly scale with multiple Bleed stacks</li><li>Fixed an issue where Feitor's Lash hit detection would be inconsistent at some angles and/or target distance</li><li>Fixed an issue where some Uniques would not spawn in endgame shops</li><li>Fixed an issue where sometimes Phantom Marksmen or the Echo from Feitor's Lash would start moving around</li></ul></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hell-clock-update-11-detailed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>