<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Looks to be Significantly Bigger Than the Original Hollow Knight]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight.1277637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">More bosses, more enemies, more...?</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, we got our first real, new, meaty trailer for Hollow Knight: Silksong in several years, complete with a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-finally-has-a-release-date">September 4 release date</a>. Fans are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1mwfriy/silksong_might_be_2530_bigger_than_hollow_knight/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">already unpacking details</a> from the trailer, including pointing out that it looks like the base game of Silksong might be bigger than the base game of Hollow Knight - quite a feat for something that started out as DLC.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Evidence for this comes from the trailer above, which has text stating the game contains over 200 enemies and over 40 bosses. Compare that to Hollow Knight's launch trailer, which said over 140 enemies and over 30 bosses:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So it <em>sounds like</em> Silksong is launching with more enemies and bosses than Hollow Knight did. And though we don't know the size of the explorable area in Silksong, it stands to reason that it probably needs to be big enough to fit all those little guys, and thus its map is likely to be at least as big as the original Hollow Knight if not more. And while that may sound like a given for a sequel, it's helpful to remember that Silksong didn't start out as a sequel - it began as DLC, and then somehow morphed into something seemingly even bigger than its predecessor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, that comparison doesn't include Hollow Knight's DLC, which added tons of new enemies, areas, bosses, story, and other content. With all that included, the existing game of Hollow Knight is almost certainly larger than Silksong was at launch. That said, we learned today that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/team-cherry-says-it-has-plans-for-more-silksong-content-for-months-and-years-to-come">developer Team Cherry is still working on more Silksong for the months and years after the game's launch</a>, making it possible it will eventually surpass Hollow Knight's DLC as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you absolutely can't wait until launch to find out what some of these enemies and bosses entail, we did get to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-we-played-it-gamescom-2025">preview Hollow Knight: Silksong earlier this week</a> at Gamescom in Cologne, Germany. Funnily enough, it looks like the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-demo-at-gamescom-2025-is-a-shinier-silkier-version-of-the-same-demo-from-e3-2019">exact same demo we played back in E3 2019</a>, only with six more years of polish, illustrating how far the game has come in its lengthy development.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-looks-to-be-significantly-bigger-than-the-original-hollow-knight]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight Reaches 15 Million Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-reaches-15-million-copies-sold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-reaches-15-million-copies-sold.1277460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's a big day for Team Cherry.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As Team Cherry finally, truly nails down a release date for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong"><u>Hollow Knight: Silksong</u></a>, the studio has confirmed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hollow-knight"><u>the original game</u></a> has managed to reach 15 million copies sold.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A sales update for the bleak and beloved metroidvania title comes from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-08-21/why-silksong-team-cherry-s-sequel-to-hollow-knight-took-so-long-to-make?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc1NTc4NjYzOSwiZXhwIjoxNzU2MzkxNDM5LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUMUNMTUpHUFdDUFcwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.oTN8q1m9pNWFv7oW-n3vzq-hRWAxrDx9B7iF80RdTzk&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Bloomberg</u></a>, which spoke with Team Cherry ahead of today’s long-awaited <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-finally-has-a-release-date"><u>release date reveal</u></a>. Along with a swarm of details about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/team-cherry-says-it-has-plans-for-more-silksong-content-for-months-and-years-to-come"><u>what took the team so long to finish its sequel</u></a>, the studio confirmed that 2017’s Hollow Knight has officially sold 15 million units across PC, Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4, and Xbox One.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s proof Hollow Knight had plenty of staying power in the eight years since launch, as players have not-so-patiently awaited news for a sequel. One million of its sales were <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/07/05/hollow-knight-has-sold-more-than-1-million-copies-on-pc"><u>reached in its first year on PC</u></a>, alone, with its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/29/hollow-knight-sold-over-250000-copies-on-switch-in-its-first-two-weeks"><u>June 2018 Switch launch</u></a> and September 2018 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/09/11/hollow-knight-voidheart-edition-coming-to-ps4-and-xbox-one-this-september"><u>PS4 and Xbox One launch</u></a> only giving players more avenues to pick up a copy. More than anything, it’s clear the unending hype for Hollow Knight: Silksong news only bolstered sales of the original game in the last six years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reaching the 15 million mark is one milestone not many independent games manage to achieve, cementing its bug-filled world and crushing gameplay as a particularly important universe for gaming going forward. We’ll see more of that universe when Hollow Knight: Silksong finally launches for PC, Switch, Switch 2, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X | S September 4, 2025.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Team Cherry already has more content in the works for the sequel, so if you thought you were done waiting for more Hollow Knight content, get ready to wait some more. In the meantime, you can check out our original <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/22/hollow-knight-review"><u>9.4/10 Hollow Knight review</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-reaches-15-million-copies-sold]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>