<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 07:57:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Codemasters ‘Pausing’ Development Plans on Future Rally Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/codemasters-pausing-development-plans-on-future-rally-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/codemasters-%E2%80%98pausing%E2%80%99-development-plans-on-future-rally-games.1178403/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/codemasters-pausing-development-plans-on-future-rally-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Codemasters has confirmed that no further expansions will be released for 2023’s EA Sports WRC, and that the team has “reached the end of the road” working on the game. Unfortunately, alongside this news comes the additional confirmation that Codemasters is also “pausing development plans on future rally titles.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The veteran UK racing studio <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-wrc/wrc-24/news/wrc-development-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>published the announcement via EA.com.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our WRC partnership was a culmination of sorts for our Codemasters journey with off-road racing, spanning decades through titles like Colin McRae Rally, and Dirt,” reads the studio’s statement. “We’ve provided a home for every rally enthusiast, striving tirelessly to push the boundaries and deliver the exhilarating thrill of driving on the ragged edge. We’ve brought together incredibly talented racing developers, worked with some of the sport’s icons, and had the opportunity to share our love of rallying.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The World Rally Championship itself has <a href="https://x.com/OfficialWRC/status/1917610425153097758" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>acknowledged the news on social media</u></a>, with a largely vague comment noting the “WRC gaming franchise is going in an ambitious new direction with more news coming in the near future.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA pulling the pin on Codemasters rally games will be a bitter pill to swallow for motorsports fans following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-reportedly-attempting-to-outbid-take-twos-nearly-1-billion-offer-to-acquire-codemasters"><u>EA’s acquisition of the storied British racing studio back in 2020.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The news comes in wake of reports of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn"><u>over 300 layoffs at EA, including roughly 100 at Respawn Entertainment.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Codemasters has been at the spearhead of rallying video games for almost three decades, dating back to 1998’s iconic Colin McRae Rally. The pioneering rally simulation kicked off a series of successful and highly esteemed racing games. Following the death of Colin McRae in 2007, the series retired McRae’s name and continued its evolution as Dirt. 2009’s Dirt 2 (known as Colin McRae: Dirt 2 in Europe and other PAL game territories) marked a transitional point for the series, which was reinvented again as a hardcore simulation in 2015’s Dirt Rally. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">2023’s EA Sports WRC was the first Codemasters rally game to hold an official WRC license since 2002’s Colin McRae Rally 3. IGN’s review notes EA Sports WRC took the class-leading feel of 2019’s Dirt Rally 2.0 and stuffed it into an officially licensed World Rally Championship experience, like a steel rod in Timo Rautiainen’s backside, but its technical gremlins left it feeling like a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-wrc-review">“great racing game trying to fight its way out of an unfinished one.”</a> Subsequent updates sought to improve its screen tearing issues.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Luke is a Senior Editor on the IGN reviews team. You can track him down on Bluesky @mrlukereilly to ask him things about stuff.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[La Quimera Early Access Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/la-quimera-review-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/la-quimera-early-access-review.1178325/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/la-quimera-review-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Editor's note</strong></em><em>: La Quimera was originally set to fully release on April 25, but it was unexpectedly delayed that same day. </em><a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/2282350/announcements/detail/512957012199342082" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>A developer update on April 29</em></a><em> didn't provide a new release date, but did say La Quimera would now be launching in Early Access whenever it did arrive. This announcement came well after our review of what we were initially told would be the full game was largely complete – however, the update post indicates that the content at its new launch will be the same as what we played, so we have decided to publish this as a review of the Early Access version.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I have to admit, I’m a sucker for direct-to-video sequels. There’s something about being five Tremors movies deep where all pretense is abandoned, and we all know what we are there for: To watch some ridiculous action and give our brains a break for a bit. La Quimera reminds me a lot of popcorn flicks like that. This FPS is not particularly good-looking, well-written, or innovative. The action doesn’t do anything memorable, and its acting ranges from mediocre to terrible. There is admittedly a certain charm to be found here, especially if you bring a friend or two along to share this rocky ride in co-op. But by nearly every metric, La Quimera is about as good a game as Tremors 5: Bloodlines is a movie. Which is to say it’s not.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in the fictional South American city of Nuevo Caracas, the world is going to hell in a handbasket. Outside the city walls, some sort of robot apocalypse that’s never really explained is taking place. Inside, there are warring corporations and extreme poverty. That setup isn’t a socio-political commentary so much as a throwback to 80s sci-fi, complete with Power Loader-esque rigs that would look right at home on Ellen Ripley in Aliens. As a new PMC recruit, you and your squad get stuck in the middle of some nonspecific and uninteresting power struggle between corporations, leaving an equal mix of broken bodies and bots in your wake. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">La Quimera Early Access Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There is some legitimately cool environmental storytelling here. My favorite by far is the Bone Wall, a literal wall filled with what must be thousands of skeletons, that you get to see when one mission takes you deep through it. A voice in your ear describes the desperation that went into building the wall as all hell was breaking loose, and it’s neat to piece together how there was no time to slow down and help anyone who fell, whether that was due to exhaustion, injury, or dying from whatever encroaching threat drove the frantic construction.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In fact, La Quimera would have been better off if it let the environments do <em>all </em>the talking, because once its characters open their mouths, it is rough. The dialogue is awful, with obscenity-laced tirades that sound like someone watched a Quentin Tarantino movie once, and tried to mimic it without knowing how to make any of the lines land. The acting also ranges from a normal kind of bad to so awkward I can’t tell if it’s being purposefully campy or potentially using some sort of poorly implemented AI. Characters are very chatty too, and I found myself actively cringing on several occasions as allies shout out things like, “Oh perfect, robot dogs!”. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The dialogue is awful, and I found myself actively cringing on several occasions.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The story itself doesn’t make much sense, either. Apparently, saving a billionaire’s daughter gets your PMC conscripted because… you are afraid he will sue? Which, naturally, means the people in the PMC all have to get experimental and highly dangerous augmentations, too. I wouldn’t mind the nonsense, it’s fine enough as a vehicle to make me want to go shoot robots – but the story is so clearly unfinished, ending abruptly after just a few hours without resolving anything. Developer Reburn unexpectedly decided to delay La Quimera on the day it was supposed to launch, and then later announced its eventual release would have the Early Access label on it. Given development is largely based out of Kyiv in Ukraine, the fact that it’s still coming out at all feels like something of an achievement worth applauding. But while this campaign is planned to grow over time, the version that's here now doesn't have any semblance of a complete story. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Identity Crysis</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">La Quimera isn’t exactly shy about the influence Crysis has had on it. Early on, you and your crew gain access to exosuits, complete with energy-powered armor, cloaking, and scanning. That last bit is especially important – one quick ping allows you and your teammates to see any nearby enemies, even behind cover. That’s huge when your weapons operate like a poor man’s version of the FarSight from Perfect Dark, able to lethally penetrate shockingly thick obstacles. It’s extremely satisfying to drop a bunch of orange silhouettes in rapid succession from sight unseen. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, where Crysis tended to be more of an inverted funnel that pushed you toward open areas, La Quimera is decidedly about straight lines. Its levels are very linear, and your objective is almost always to clear enemies as you walk from point A to point B. That’s not necessarily a bad thing, as a bit of a throwback like this can be a welcome palate cleanser in a time when wide-open gameplay is increasingly the norm, but it does all start to become a bland blur. That’s because so many areas repeat the same cycle of kill the enemies, open the heavy door, kill the next enemies, open the next heavy door, and so on. There are a handful of encounters that break that trend, most notably an extended gunfight on a slowly rising elevator in a corporate office building, but they are few and far between.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The gunplay itself is extremely basic, with your weapons effectively limited to a sidearm, shotgun, or rifle. You can’t change guns mid-mission, nor pick up any temporary options like a limited-use power weapon. You are given the choice between conventional firearms and electromagnetic weapons – the former works better against humans, while the latter tears through shields and robots more quickly – but you’ll be required to bring one of each into your missions anyway. Which one gets to be the more powerful primary weapon and which is relegated to your sidearm could have added a small strategic wrinkle, but the conventional arms are <em>so</em> poor against bots that there’s only one right choice, which is too bad. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The thing I like best about the fights themselves is the ammo economy. Bullets can become scarce, especially in later missions, which means you can’t just sit in one spot and pick off every enemy by shooting through walls the whole time. I had to keep moving to either scavenge rounds off of corpses or find more ammo boxes, which was just enough to create some badly needed forward momentum during otherwise slow fights. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Time is Money</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As a PMC, you are, of course, paid for completing missions – but while there are things to buy between them, the progression is badly underbaked at this point. There aren’t enough items or upgrades for sale in the first place, and the stuff that <em>is </em>here isn’t very interesting. You could buy one of a very small number of generic guns, or invest in either of the two alternate versions of your exosuit’s head, arms, torso, and legs, each of which have differences like improved cooldowns or increased med kit capacity. But those effects are all so small that it’s hard to feel a need for any of them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The way you get money is a little weird, too. In addition to completing missions, cash can also be found in containers mid-level – but you have very shallow pockets for some odd reason, hitting “max money” far too quickly (which is a problem I can say with all honesty I have never experienced in my life). That's too bad, because collecting more would have given me a real incentive to go off the beaten path. There are some of the obligatory voice memos people seem to leave behind in every video game, but I can’t bring myself to opt into hearing more of this dialogue than I absolutely need to. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Justin's favorite military shooters</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For as down as I am on La Quimera (and, believe me, I am), I did still have a strangely fun time with it. That’s due primarily to two things: First, you can play the entire campaign (minus the tutorial) in online co-op with up to two other people. A couple of buddies is the exact thing you need to transform cringey dialogue from something you’ll roll your eyes at into a hilarious shared experience. Having another gun or two covering your back makes the combat more exciting as well, and the ability to do things like alternate who is doing scans so that you are never waiting on that ability’s cooldown keeps the fights moving at a faster pace. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The other quality that keeps its many issues from becoming downright infuriating is how short La Quimera is. It took me right around four hours to complete my first playthrough. That could certainly be a negative if you put a lot of weight on “hours played per dollar spent” or whatever, but it does make a stronger case for going in with some friends, having a ridiculous time, and then getting out in a way that lets you enjoy the handful of high points while minimizing the impact of the lows. Of course, one of the reasons for this brief length is that La Quimera is outright incomplete in parts, and it would need to be significantly fleshed out to justify spending any more time than this in Nuevo Caracas anyway.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">La Quimera is bad, but it’s also a perfect example of how even something bad can have a bit of charm. The writing is cringey, the acting is embarrassing, and the middling but serviceable action tends to follow the same basic loop on repeat – but if some friends are riding this partially derailed train with you, there is still some fun to be found here. It doesn’t quite hit “so bad, it’s good” levels of jank, but it could still be a decent candidate for an evening of goofs. That said, even going into it with the right expectations, I wish there was any story resolution whatsoever, as La Quimera is clearly unfinished in more ways than one.&nbsp;</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Video Game Cookbooks That Bring Your Favorite In-Game Recipes to Life]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-gaming-cookbooks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-video-game-cookbooks-that-bring-your-favorite-in-game-recipes-to-life.1178232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-gaming-cookbooks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Level up your cooking skills. </h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Video games and cooking go together more than you might think. Tons of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-rpgs">RPGs</a> and simulation games have some form of cooking mechanic or, at the very least, delicious-looking food. From the cozy familiarity of meals from Stardew Valley to fantastical feasts in The Witcher, I can personally say I've encountered tons of animated food I wish was real. Well, turns out it can be. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gaming cookbooks offer an opportunity to learn unique recipes while immersing yourself in the lore of a world you love. Getting the materials you need might not be as fun as in-game adventuring or farming, but the end result is more than worth it. Whether you're passionate about a specific game, are looking for gift ideas, or just love some themed recipes, here's our list of the best gaming cookbooks in 2025. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Our Favorite Gaming Cookbooks in 2025</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">One of our top picks for gaming cookbooks is The Official Stardew Valley cookbook, which features 50 recipes written in the voice of various characters as well as some adorable art. The recipes are naturally based on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stardew-valley/Cooking_Recipes">meals you can make in-game</a>, including Pink Cake, Strange Buns, and even a full Autumn's Bounty to help you power through the mines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A great gift to inspire young chefs (especially those who particularly enjoyed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-watch-a-minecraft-movie">A Minecraft Movie</a>), the Minecraft cookbook includes 40+ recipes inspired by the game's various mobs and biomes. The same goes for The Pokémon Cookbook, which focuses more on cute snacks and quick meals. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of crafting-based games, themed cookbooks are also a great way to immerse yourself in fantasy worlds. The official Witcher cookbook takes inspiration from the games as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-books-reading-order">The Witcher books</a>, with 80 recipes covering everything from a refreshing drink to an exquisite banquet. The Elder Scrolls cookbook hones in on the world of Skyrim (as opposed to the rest of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-games-in-order">Elder Scrolls games</a>) while the Fallout cookbook is great for anyone who's particularly curious about the taste of Nuka-Cola. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Elder Scrolls: The Official Cookbook</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On the tabletop side of gaming, the Heroes' Feast Dungeons &amp; Dragons cookbook is the crème de la crème for anyone trying to impress their party. Across the board, these cookbooks feature great recipes as well as interesting new bits of lore and art for dedicated fans. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Upcoming Video Game Cookbooks </h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The trend of gaming cookbooks isn't going anywhere anytime soon. Some upcoming gaming cookbooks include one inspired by Pac-Man, which, to be completely honest, is a mystery to me, as well as Borderlands, presumably part of the promotions for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a>. As someone who's long been curious about Sojiro's curry from Persona 5, I'm particularly excited about the cookbook inspired by the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-games-in-order">Persona games</a> coming out later this year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Blythe (she/her) is an SEO Coordinator at IGN who spends way too much time in character customization screens and tracking down collectibles. </em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 30, 2025 9:58 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>