<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.ign.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.ign.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:14:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get an Exclusive Sneak Peek of The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/get-an-exclusive-sneak-peek-of-the-art-of-death-stranding-2-on-the-beach</link>
            <guid>1437283</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is widely regarded as another masterpiece from Kojima Productions, with all the sweeping scope, drama, and weirdness fans have come to expect. Now those fans can delve even deeper into this unique world with the release of Titan Books' The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN can exclusively reveal a new preview of The Art of Death Stranding 2 ahead of the book's release. Check it out in the slideshow gallery below:</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Image Gallery</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is a 240-page hardcover book featuring concept art from the game. The book offers a closer look at character designs, equipment, locations, and creatures from the game, with plenty of pieces from acclaimed artist Yoji Shinkawa.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the official summary for the book:</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>The official art book for the action video game DEATH STRANDING 2: ON THE BEACH, from legendary game creator Hideo Kojima, including artwork by acclaimed artist Yoji Shinkawa.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>With DEATH STRANDING 2: ON THE BEACH, step by step, legendary game creator Hideo Kojima changes the world once again. Embark on an inspiring mission of human connection beyond the UCA. Sam—with companions by his side—sets out on a new journey to save humanity from extinction. Join them as they traverse a world beset by otherworldly enemies and obstacles.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is packed with hundreds of pieces of concept art for the characters, equipment, locations and creatures featured in the game, as well as early and unused concepts, including artwork by character and mechanical design director, acclaimed artist Yoji Shinkawa. </em></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Art of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is priced at $50 and will be released on February 17, 2026. You can <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Death-Stranding-Beach/dp/1835411975/?tag=igndeals14-20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">preorder a copy on Amazon</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In other Death Stranding 2, we learned at Sony's State of Play event that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-pc-release-date-confirmed-sony-state-of-play">the game will be hitting the PC in March 2026</a>. Check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-state-of-play-february-2026-everything-announced">everything announced at State of Play</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jesse is a mild-mannered staff writer for IGN. Allow him to lend a machete to your intellectual thicket by</em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jschedeen.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em> </em><u><em>following @jschedeen on BlueSky</em></u></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/get-an-exclusive-sneak-peek-of-the-art-of-death-stranding-2-on-the-beach]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castlevania Veteran Koji Igarashi Vows to Finish Making Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement to Honor Deceased Director Shutaro Ida's Vision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/castlevania-veteran-koji-igarashi-vows-to-finish-making-bloodstained-the-scarlet-engagement-to-honor-deceased-director-shutaro-idas-vision</link>
            <guid>1437280</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Shutaro Ida has passed away aged 52 after a one-and-a-half year battle against pancreatic cancer. The news was announced by his family via a statement on Ida’s <a href="https://x.com/CurryHermit/status/2023200658544083439?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>official X account</u></a> on February 15. Longtime colleague Koji Igarashi has vowed to finish the designer and director’s upcoming metroidvania Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement, the sequel to 2019’s Castlevania-infused Bloodstained: Ritual of the Night.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Shutaro Ida (sometimes romanized as Shutaro Iida) worked at Konami from 1996 to 2015, mainly as a programmer. His biggest contribution was to the Castlevania series. Starting with the GBA title Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow and PS2 game Castlevania: Lament of Innocence, Ida played a key role in bringing the gothic action games into the sixth and seventh console generations, even directing Castlevania: Harmony of Despair on Xbox 360 and PS3. He was also a lead programmer on Metal Gear Solid V: Ground Zeroes and The Phantom Pain.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Upon the invitation of former Castlevania series producer Koji “Iga” Igarashi, Ida joined ArtPlay, the indie dev company Igarashi co-founded. There, Ida designed and directed the crowdfunded game Bloodstained: Ritual of the Night, with Igarashi as producer. The game was well-received, and widely seen as a spiritual successor to the Castlevania series. In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/06/25/bloodstained-ritual-of-the-night-review"><u>review</u></a>, we gave it 8.8, noting it “plays and feels almost exactly like the legendary Castlevania: Symphony of the Night.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Reflecting upon two decades of making games with Ida, Igarashi noted in his <a href="https://x.com/KojiIGA/status/2023210325970129391?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>tribute:</u></a> “I’ve been working with him ever since Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow. It’s not an exaggeration to say that many games hailed as masterpieces would not have succeeded without his contributions. His talent was exceptional.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I feel that Bloodstained: Ritual of the Night’s success was also in a large part down to his incredible support," Igarashi continued. "Looking back, he’s been supporting me for over 20 years. He was the kind of person who always thought about games, tackling game development like he was burning his life away. I hope he can rest peacefully now as he was always running at full throttle.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ida’s final game, Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement is still in development and is due out later this year. Igarashi described it as an invaluable work that Ida poured himself into. “We will take on his aspirations for the game and see that it is properly completed, so as not to disappoint him.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ida last <a href="https://x.com/CurryHermit/status/2017126464664281512?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>tweeted</u></a> back on January 30, saying that he felt the end was near as he was getting weaker each day. He finished with a simple request: “Please love Bloodstained 2 and all the games I made.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://x.com/CurryHermit/status/2023200658544083439?s=20" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>statement</u></a> from Ida’s family echoed this sentiment: “Shutaro’s adventures in this world have come to an end, but his creations remain. We would be happy if people could continue to enjoy the games he made.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://youtu.be/3X_54wp1xiU?si=XHJYvYoBLUVQIPsl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement YouTube channel</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/castlevania-veteran-koji-igarashi-vows-to-finish-making-bloodstained-the-scarlet-engagement-to-honor-deceased-director-shutaro-idas-vision]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Let Us All Send This Poor Girl Positive Vibes' — Arthur Morgan Actor Roger Clark Reveals Cameo Apology Request From Man Who Deleted Fiancé's Red Dead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/let-us-all-send-this-poor-girl-positive-vibes-arthur-morgan-actor-roger-clark-reveals-cameo-apology-request-from-man-who-deleted-fiances-red-dead-redemption-2-save-file</link>
            <guid>1437277</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"At least her man knows what he did."</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Arthur Morgan actor Roger Clark has revealed a Cameo apology request from a man who deleted his fiancé's Red Dead Redemption 2 save file.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clark said that while he really enjoys sending messages to fans on Cameo, he sometimes encounters particularly special ones. Posting a screenshot of one such recent request to X / Twitter, Clark wrote: "I really am blown away by the support you guys show me on Cameo. Thank you for liking my shoutouts. I enjoy them all, but it's ones like these below that I live for. Let us all send this poor girl positive vibes. At least her man knows what he did."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For the 'occasion,' the Cameo requester wrote: "apology for deleting Red Dead saved game." In the instructions for Roger Clark, they added: "I just deleted my fiancé's saved game in Red Dead Redemption 2 by accident. She was having so much fun and made every ethical decision, had about [two-thirds] completed. Can you say some words of support for this devastating loss and let her know I am sorry?" </p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">I really am blown away by the support you guys show me on cameo. Thank you for liking my shout outs. I enjoy them all but it’s ones like these below that I live for. Let us all send this poor girl positive vibes. At least her man knows what he did. <a href="https://twitter.com/cameo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cameo</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/cameo?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#cameo</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rdr2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#rdr2</a> <a href="https://t.co/U0nHM2pLVT" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/U0nHM2pLVT</a></p>— Roger Clark (@rclark98) <a href="https://twitter.com/rclark98/status/2022059161887137920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 12, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Understandably, Clark didn't show us his Cameo video response itself, although I'll admit that I wish he had!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The replies to Clark's tweet are a mix of disbelief and empathy. Some are wondering how the save file was deleted in the first place. Others are saying a Cameo from Arthur Morgan himself will surely ease the pain. "I think if someone deleted my 100% save file with everything unlocked and every piece of clothing bought, camp completed, map and journal drawings all there, dreamcatchers murals bones exotics and cards, a shout out from Roger Clark might heal the pain," said one fan.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/before-rockstar-i-was-just-a-jobbing-actor-off-broadway-arthur-morgan-actor-roger-clark-on-the-red-dead-redemption-2-effect">IGN's big interview with Roger Clark on Arthur Morgan and Red Dead Redemption 2</a> to find out just how life-changing the iconic role was.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Red Dead Redemption 2 fans recently made progress towards solving the game's newly-discovered spiderweb mystery, and now believe they've reached its final clue following a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-discovery-in-red-dead-redemption-2-in-years-rockstar-fans-uncover-spiderweb-mystery-unnoticed-since-release-and-now-the-hunt-is-on-for-answers"><u>major new discovery within Rockstar's epic cowboy sequel, dubbed the biggest uncovering of hidden content in years</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An intricately-placed breadcrumb trail of spiderwebs was found and plotted, leading to a further set of marked telegraph poles. These then pointed to a collection of guitars within the game's Fort Wallace location, where the trail temporarily went cold. Now, however, fans have pushed forwards — to what seems like a final clue beyond the edge of Red Dead Redemption 2's map.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Roy Rochlin/Getty Images for ReedPop.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/let-us-all-send-this-poor-girl-positive-vibes-arthur-morgan-actor-roger-clark-reveals-cameo-apology-request-from-man-who-deleted-fiances-red-dead-redemption-2-save-file]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['This is Not God of War' — Franchise Creator David Jaffe Trashes Side-Scrolling Spinoff Sons of Sparta]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-is-not-god-of-war-franchise-creator-david-jaffe-trashes-side-scrolling-spinoff-sons-of-sparta</link>
            <guid>1437274</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">God of War creator David Jaffe has slammed the series' new side-scrolling spinoff Sons of Sparta for being "boring" and "an insult" both to fans of the series and its original creative team. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta">God of War Sons of Sparta</a> was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-side-scrolling-spin-off-out-today-and-god-of-war-trilogy-remake-announced-sony-state-of-play">announced and then shadow-dropped</a> on PlayStation 5 last week at the end of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-state-of-play-february-2026-everything-announced">Sony's big State of Play broadcast</a>. A Metroidvania-inspired action platformer from indie retro developer Mega Cat Studios, Sons of Sparta is designed as a prequel to the original God of War trilogy, featuring a young version of Kratos and his brother as they train together.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an initial YouTube <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=liEszJCMW-k" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> posted after playing an hour of the game, Jaffe made his frustrations with the project's concept clear: essentially, that it was too different in tone from the original trilogy, despite his initial excitment to see a side-scrolling take on the series. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"This is the kind of game I've always wanted in terms of 2.5D God of War, super into it — but this, to me, is not what I was talking about. I bought this game, it's a $30 game, I don't like it, I don't recommend it," Jaffe began, before turning his attention to the executives at Sony who decided to greenlight the project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I wanted to make a video more about what are they thinking, like what the f*** were they thinking? It's not a bad game by any means, it's fine, it controls decently... but to me the more fascinating part of this is, why is this in existence? I don't understand."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After an hour's worth of play, Jaffe said he couldn't continue with the game as its characters kept "stopping over and over [to] talk and talk." He added: "This is not God of War."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Let's just make him some generic f***ing kid, like we're watching a Kids WB TV show or something," Jaffe continued on. "It's probably some bulls*** writer going, 'Oh people want to know why, how did people become this way?' No one cares. It's a dumb idea... [Fans] wanted something like Blasphemous, in terms of it's violent, it's bloody, it's serious, it has the tone of the early God of the War games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"If you pulled God of War out of it, and you just said, 'hey, we're making a game about this kid,' most people would say 'that doesn't sound like a very compelling idea for a video game character,' because it's not."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/16/god-of-war-creator-reviews-sons-of-sparta-00-00-00-1771243564920.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">David Jaffe. Image credit: David Jaffe.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Maybe it gets better, I'm sure it does," he further continued. "There's nothing offensive about it. The only thing offensive about it is its genericism. The only thing offensive about it is its inability to reflect the license, the brand. It's like you get the John Wick license and you make a movie where he's just sitting in a coffee shop talking. Now that might work when you have Keanu Reeves as he's so compelling, and the character's interesting."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Jaffe said he had been keen to see a 2.5D God of War game more similar to titles such as Ninja Gaiden Ragebound, Neon Inferno, or Shinobi. "Why would you even put this out? All it does is leave a bad taste in God of War fans' mouths, in my assumption," he concluded. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Every time you make a new game, you don't have to go, 'You know what? Let's not go back to the great character that people love that built this franchise. Let's see him as a little kid, some generic boring little f***ing kid.' It's just insulting to the fans. It's insulting to people who worked on the games that they would think this character right here is what people want. It's crap. It's dumb. It's stupid. I would say avoid this f***ing thing."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">God of War Games in Chronological Order</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While Jaffe had said he wouldn't return to Sons of Sparta, he then went back and played a further three hours, at which point he posted an even more in-depth <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ClC7rCietLU" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> that critiques the game on a more granular level for more than 30 minutes. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Specifically, Jaffe addressed points around "confusing visual noise during combat," "gameplay breaking visual inconsistencies," a "buggy and confusing user interface," the suggestion that "level design and character motion feels off," and "kiddie level dialogue and poor voice actor performances." Ultimately, he branded the game as "not ready for release."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Late on Friday last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/theres-confusion-over-god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-having-co-op-based-on-its-playstation-store-description">God of War franchise developer Sony Santa Monica was forced to clarify God of War Sons of Sparta's two-player offering</a> following widespread fan confusion. After numerous fans assumed the game's "1-2 player" listing on the PlayStation Store referred to full co-op, the company clarified that multiplayer functionality was limited to a challenge mode unlocked after completing the game. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-is-not-god-of-war-franchise-creator-david-jaffe-trashes-side-scrolling-spinoff-sons-of-sparta]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>