<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 15:09:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World's Open World Isn't What You Think It Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is.1205670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I may only have played three hours of it, but I’m already starting to get the feeling that Mario Kart World should really be called Mario Kart Knockout Tour. The new last-one-standing race mode, really is the star of the show, adding yet another layer of tension and mayhem to the already chaotic kart racer, and such a new addition deserves to have its name up in lights. And so I find it a curious decision that Nintendo has settled on the Switch 2 launch game’s open world as the main draw. I get it on an optics level – a Mario Kart unbound from the confines of pre-determined tracks has been long desired by fans – but after getting my hands on its free roam offering recently, it sadly left me feeling underwhelmed. Let me explain why.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When thinking of an open-world racing game, it's by no means unfair to make comparisons with Forza Horizon. Developer Playground Games has mastered this specific subgenre, even earning itself an IGN Game of the Year award with its most recent effort. Each game in the series features a delicately sculpted open world that packs in challenge, wonder, and, most importantly, fun. I’d be lying if I said I found much of any of those qualities in the roughly half an hour I spent speeding around Mario Kart World’s sizeable map. It’s largely empty, lacks atmosphere, and feels bizarrely devoid of activities to get stuck into.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Much of my time in free roam consisted of dashing along expanses of flat grassland, desert, or lightly choppy seas, looking for something to do. There are some challenges to get your teeth stuck into, but I found them largely repetitive and little more than trivial distractions. They mainly consist of P Switch challenges which, when activated, create short time trials to complete. I found these fun at first, but quickly realised they’re mostly rinse and repeat efforts involving collecting a certain amount of coins or whizzing through checkpoints within a time limit. And when these rarely take more than 10 or 15 seconds to finish, they soon lose all novelty. It’s not a promising sign to walk away from a demo feeling as if you’ve already exhausted the amount of entertainment you can get from a game’s side activities. And while I do hope that a more in-depth scouring of the world reveals more hidden fun, there’s another factor that has me concerned about how it all plays out. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You do get rewarded with a shiny new sticker to place on your chosen kart when completing these P Switch challenges, but this is pretty much as far as unlockables go. It feels weird that progression is still largely locked behind the series’ long-term tradition of racing in Grand Prixs, as this open world seems the perfect opportunity to hide new characters and karts in secret corners. New outfits can be found by driving through one of Yoshi’s many restaurants on the island, but they’re just as, if not more accessible, in race scenarios.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>That sense of wonder you so often feel when discovering something off the beaten track just doesn’t seem to exist here.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Barn finds – explorative missions in Forza Horizon that involve hunting down a hidden vehicle within a section of the map like a piece of buried treasure – are some of my favourite things to do in Playground’s series. If there really isn’t anything similar in the final game (and, unfortunately, no signs at my preview event suggest there is), then it feels like a missed opportunity, especially when 3D Mario platformers are so packed with secrets. That sense of wonder you so often feel when discovering something off the beaten track just doesn’t seem to exist here; instead, the closest I ever got in this demo was stumbling across a big green warp pipe that did nothing more than send me 20 metres down the road. Why don’t these lead to hidden areas with challenges of their own to complete?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s this apparent lack of any sort of progression or meaningful activities that has me wondering how little time I’ll actually spend in this open world. Yes, there are Peach Medallions to collect, which can prove a fun challenge to reach – you’ll need to demonstrate a mastery of the new rail grinding and wall riding mechanics – but, again, they can only unlock stickers. This in itself isn’t an issue (fun for fun’s sake is largely the name of the game for Nintendo), but I can’t help but feel like I would like something more substantial to use them on, such as how excess moons can be used on cosmetics in one of Super Mario Odyssey’s many stores.</p><div id="nintendo-series-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Nintendo Series Tier List</h3><h3>Nintendo Series Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Maybe I’m just a grumpy man disillusioned with the world he lives in now that he’s hit his mid-thirties, though. Because, despite these grumbles, I do need to remind myself that kids big and small will have a great time roaming around this colourful paradise, zooming around and taking in the sights of its sandy beaches and winding city streets. Plus, I’d be lying if the seven-year-old part of my brain didn’t activate when I drove into the back of a massive truck,  took over its controls Cappy-style, and wreaked havoc by ploughing into every other vehicle and breakable coin-filled brick in sight. It was a rare moment of wonder and Nintendo creativity that seems worryingly lacking elsewhere. Yes, there’s a dynamic weather system, day/night cycle, and morphing toe-tapping soundtrack that shifts depending on what biome you’re in, but none of these delightful presentation touches truly added to the fun factor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The open world is crucial to Mario Kart World outside of its free roam mode, though, and that can’t be ignored. The way these open spaces connect tracks together is very clever, and allows for more varied course combinations to be created. Plus, the exciting new Knockout Tour just wouldn’t be the same without it. The way it snakes cross-country through the many different environments is impressive, and I could see this mode being nowhere near as fun if it took place on an extensive number of laps of the same track. This world does have its merits, it’s just not in the exploration of it. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When treated like a toy box, as opposed to an open world on the scale of Forza Horizon or even Burnout Paradise, there is some joy to be found in Free Roam. I just wouldn’t go in expecting that open world to leave a lasting impression – perhaps a hard pill to swallow considering the $80 price tag. The racing is still the highlight of Mario Kart, and the new Knockout Mode makes it feel as exciting as it has in a long time. So much so that it really deserves to be placed front and center, and not buried in its relatively underwhelming world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Simon Cardy is a Senior Editor at IGN who can mainly be found skulking around open world games, indulging in Korean cinema, or despairing at the state of Tottenham Hotspur and the New York Jets. Follow him on Bluesky at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/cardy.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@cardy.bsky.social</a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World: The Final Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview.1205667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-the-final-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Mario Kart World is just two days away, and fan expectations are rightfully high. It’s the flagship launch game for Nintendo Switch 2, the first open world in the series, the follow-up to the hugely successful Mario Kart 8 Deluxe, and on top of all that, it’s Nintendo’s first $80 game since the N64 days, which has caused no shortage of internet discourse. There’s a lot riding on this one, so I’m pleased to report that after spending roughly five hours with unrestricted access to the final build, I’m confident Mario Kart World’s thrilling racing will kick off Nintendo’s eighth generation with a rocket start, even if I’m still not completely sold on its open-world exploration.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">My <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview"><u>first hands-on preview</u></a> back in April was very limited. Steering assist was turned on, the demo was locked to 100cc, and we only got to see a couple of modes. But this time, the training wheels came off and I played what appeared to be the version you’ll be able to buy on June 5, complete with an enormous roster of characters (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-producer-says-cow-opened-the-floodgates-for-the-wacky-npc-filled-character-roster">including everyone’s favorite, Cow</a>) and freedom to choose any mode or settings I wanted.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So I first chose to play as Mario (basic, I know) and swapped between multiple karts – including the <em>incredible </em>R.O.B. bike – to try out Free Roam, which is still the biggest question surrounding Mario Kart World. In a series first, Free Roam takes the spotlight off of racing and shines it directly on exploration, allowing players to drive across the wide, interconnected highways. Nintendo promised hundreds of P Switch missions in Free Roam, and while I won’t spoil the final total, I can confirm that it only takes a few seconds of driving in any direction to spot one of these challenges. They are littered everywhere, and after worrying they’d all be too easy based on the footage Nintendo has released so far, I was pleasantly surprised that I failed a couple of the P Switch missions on my first attempt – by either running out of time or missing a key jump – and some of them felt like they demanded mastery of Mario Kart World’s new Tony Hawk-inspired parkour mechanics. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>P Switch challenges are littered everywhere, and after worrying they’d all be too easy based on the footage Nintendo has released so far, I was pleasantly surprised that I failed a couple of them on my first attempt.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One mission in the Bowser’s Castle area had me driving on walls and flipping off the side at the right moment to transform into an airplane, and the timing was genuinely tricky – but you’re thankfully given the option to retry a challenge immediately after failing rather than having to drive back to the start on your own. P Switch missions can also summon temporary objects and creatures to the terrain, like one where I had to steer my airplane around a few dinosaurs that showed up. I only tried a handful of the hundreds of challenges that await, and I’m not entirely sure the novelty will last through the time required to tackle them all, but I’ve enjoyed what I’ve seen to this point.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Mario Kart World: Character Select Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sadly, the rest of Free Roam hasn’t gripped me yet. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-open-world-isnt-what-you-think-it-is">IGN’s Simon Cardy wrote a feature sharing his concerns about the open-world mode</a>, and while I think I’m a <em>little </em>higher on it than he is so far, I agree with the general sentiment that there’s just not that much to do outside of the P Switches. There are collectibles scattered throughout by way of Peach Medallions and ? Block Panels that unlock one of hundreds of stickers you can slap on the side of your kart, but the ones I found felt neither special nor difficult to discover, and I missed the feeling of surprise and delight that other Nintendo games like Tears of the Kingdom and Super Mario Odyssey completely nailed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even driving around itself can feel a bit too slow when you go off road into grass or sand. This limitation makes sense for the racing in Mario Kart where veering off the intended path without a Mushroom has punishing consequences, but the feeling of diminished speed across tougher terrain made me less inclined to explore. I’ve still barely sunk my teeth into Free Roam, so maybe there’s a game-changing discovery waiting to be found, but I’m not counting on it. So far, Free Roam feels decidedly like a side dish rather than the meaty, transformative open-world experience many are hoping for.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And perhaps that’s fair, because the main course of Mario Kart World was always going to be the racing, which felt completely right the second I started my first lap on 150cc. The turning, drifting, and boosting all feels as tight as you’d hope, and the open-world design fully shines in this bold new take on the formula. Knockout Tour remains the star of the show, as driving cross-country against 23 other players while doing everything you can to stay out of the bottom four before the next cutoff point is <em>exhilarating.</em> Every shell I threw felt critically important, and whether I was in the front or the back of the pack, my heart was pounding as I desperately tried to qualify for the next segment. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These six-part races take place almost exclusively on the highways in between Mario Kart World’s dedicated courses, and as I passed through fun reimaginings of returning tracks like Mario Kart 7’s Shy Guy Bazaar and brand-new locations like the adventurous, Uncharted-like Great ? Block Ruins, I began to recognize the impressive amount of alternate paths that I’m excited to perfect once the full game is out. A well-timed Golden Mushroom can catapult you from the back to 1st in the blink of an eye, as some of the shortcuts presented on the highways allow you to cut a huge amount of the track. I can already tell that hardcore players (myself included) are going to have a blast finding the optimal routes and pushing these courses to their limits.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve been concerned that the long stretches of very wide straightaways – present in both Knockout Tour and the revamped Grand Prix – could be boring compared to the twists and turns of the courses, but Nintendo has covered the interstate with cars to avoid, enemies that spew projectiles, and plenty of opportunities to grind on rails and make use of the new Charge Jump technique to reach optional areas. In most straightaway sections, there was always something demanding my attention – although there were a few select times I was just holding A and not doing much else, and the wide road design made things feel a bit slow compared to the close-quarters racing on the dedicated courses. Still, my fears have <em>largely</em> been squashed, and now I’m just waiting to see how these sections will hold up over dozens of repeat play sessions.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Nintendo has covered the interstate with cars to avoid, enemies that spew projectiles, and plenty of opportunities to grind on rails and make use of the new Charge Jump technique to reach optional areas.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For all you Mario Kart purists who just want to do three laps around the 30+ courses in Mario Kart World, that classic option is one of the main draws of VS Race and Time Trials, and I was very satisfied to find that the quality track design fans have come to expect hasn’t been sacrificed in favor of the open-world elements. The reimagined Peach Beach took me through familiar waterfront straight from Double Dash before exploring an entirely new village, while DK Spaceport is a fantastic homage to the arcade game that started it all – complete with final lap music any Donkey Kong fan will feel nostalgic for. If you’ve been worried the courses wouldn’t feel as special as in past Mario Kart games, I think you can breathe a sigh of relief.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of the music, Mario Kart World might just have one of the greatest soundtracks in Nintendo history. Each course has its own dedicated theme as usual, but beyond that, the remixes that play during Free Roam and Knockout Tour make Mario Kart World feel like a proper celebration of Super Mario’s 40th anniversary. In my short time with the game I heard references to Super Mario Bros., Yoshi’s Island, Donkey Kong Country, Super Mario 3D World, Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker, pretty much every past Mario Kart, and a lot more. Each track I heard was beautifully remixed to fit Mario Kart World’s adventurous road trip vibe, and I can’t wait to hear every tune it has to offer. And I won’t have to wait long, because Mario Kart World and Nintendo Switch 2 will be here in less than 48 hours. Stay tuned later this week for our review in progress followed by our full review of Mario Kart World as we get more laps under our belts. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Logan Plant is the host of Nintendo Voice Chat and IGN's Database Manager &amp; Playlist Editor. The Legend of Zelda is his favorite video game franchise of all time, and he is patiently awaiting the day Nintendo announces a brand new F-Zero. You can find him online @LoganJPlant.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Wait for Mass Effect 5, Director Seemingly Confirms Returning Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature.1205661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-wait-for-mass-effect-5-director-seemingly-confirms-returning-feature<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Glaring omission. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As fans wait for a crumb of news on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mass-effect-next-chapter">Mass Effect 5</a>, the game's director has suggested at least one small returning feature will remain in the upcoming sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A small team at BioWare is now in the early stages of work on the next Mass Effect, following the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-ceo-says-dragon-age-the-veilguard-failed-to-resonate-with-a-broad-audience-gamers-increasingly-want-shared-world-features">disappointing launch</a> of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams">subsequent downsizing of the studio</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect">which included layoffs</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mass Effect 5 was first announced years ago, of course, via an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-mass-effect-revealed">eye-catching trailer released back in December 2020</a>. But the project has remained very much on the back burner since then, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-bioware-finally-got-dragon-age-to-the-finish-line-after-a-tumultuous-decade">The Veilguard struggled through its rocky development</a>. Now, it is BioWare's sole focus — but updates on its progress remain few and far between.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the background, then, to a fan's plea for confirmation that Mass Effect 5 would once again feature the series' bombastic lens flare. And lo, Mass Effect 5 director Mike Gamble has sought to answer this plea on social media — albeit with a single emoji.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Mass Effect 5 better stick to tradition and have an excessive amount of lens flare," wrote Mass Effect fan Specre_Gray on social media — to which Gamble responded with an "OK" emoji.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="art" dir="ltr">👌🏻 <a href="https://t.co/FNXq5S9XcD" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/FNXq5S9XcD</a></p>— Michael Gamble (@GambleMike) <a href="https://twitter.com/GambleMike/status/1928978870159683597?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 1, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Over the years, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-teased-with-a-mysterious-piece-of-concept-art-on-n7-day">BioWare has issued repeated teasers</a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-a-new-poster-teases-the-future-of-mass-effect">artwork stuffed full of Easter eggs and secrets hinting at Mass Effect 5's eventual story</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">BioWare has suggested that the game will be set hundreds of years after the original Mass Effect trilogy, with a story that spans the events of both the Milky Way and the Andromeda galaxy featured in the series' fourth main game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's no word yet on when Mass Effect is likely to launch, but with production still in its early phases, it seems likely the game is still years away. When it does arrive, however, we at least know that lens flare will be included.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Confirms State of Play PlayStation Showcase for Tomorrow, Will Last 40+ Minutes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes.1205655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-confirms-state-of-play-playstation-showcase-for-tomorrow-will-last-40-minutes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Here are all the details.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has confirmed a State of Play showcase for tomorrow, June 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/06/03/state-of-play-returns-june-4/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog post</a>, Sony Interactive Entertainment content communications manager Tim Turi said fans will get "news and updates on must-play games coming to PS5." Turi continued: “The show highlights a selection of great games from creators across the globe.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 40+ minute show begins June 4 at 2pm PT / 5pm ET / 11pm CEST.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s not much to go on, but it seems likely we’ll see more of Sucker Punch’s PlayStation 5 exclusive sequel, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>, which launches in October.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Could we also see Insomniac’s Wolverine game, or what’s next from Sony’s other development studios, such as God of War maker Sony Santa Monica, Days Gone developer Bend Studio, and Horizon studio Guerrilla, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/live-service-game-horizon-online-reportedly-guerrillas-next-project-horizon-3-might-be-a-ways-off">which is working on a multiplayer spin-off</a>?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony-owned Bungie also has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a> in development, although the extent to which Bungie will be willing to show the game off following its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-discuss-marathon-developer-bungies-future-after-yet-another-plagiarism-row-rocks-studio-make-no-mistake-this-is-an-existential-struggle-for-bungie-at-this-point">art plagiarism scandal</a> remains to be seen, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fairgame">Fairgames</a> — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-live-service-woes-continue-as-playstation-executive-jade-raymond-exits-fairgames-developer-after-external-test-sparked-concern">without Jade Raymond at the helm</a> — is still in the works. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-teamlfg-a-new-playstation-studio-spun-out-of-bungie-thats-making-a-team-based-action-game-inspired-by-fighting-games-mobas-and-frog-type-games">Sony announced a new PlayStation studio called teamLFG and teased its debut game</a>, which is a live service incubation project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We may also see games from external developers Sony has signed to publish, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phantom-blade-zero">Phantom Blade Zero</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadcam, a Found-Footage '90s-Inspired Horror Game, Announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc.1205649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deadcam-a-found-footage-90s-inspired-horror-game-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Solo developer Joure Nisser, creator of last year's Don't Scream, has announced Deadcam, a new "analog survival horror" game that uses a '90's found-footage VHS camcorder aesthetic to scare you through a series of files (i.e. encounters). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Built in Unreal Engine 5, Deadcam features three weapons in the first file: a katana, a shotgun, and a pistol. Each file is built to be completed in about one hour. There is replayability baked in, though, as there are three different endings available, but, Nisser notes, "only one unlocks the full 100% playback percentage — the 'good' ending."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Deadcam - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nisser offers this gameplay description: "Deadcam's found footage recordings see players through different stories; each file features its own setting, narrative, and gameplay mechanics tailored to the tone of the story. Across each file, retro UI elements monitor haunted activity in the area, including the size and speed of nearby enemy mobs."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Deadcam launches into Steam Early Access on June 23 with its first file, a J-horror inspired story set in an abandoned school, and four more files will be added over the course of the Early Access period. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2660830/DEADCAM__ANALOG_o_SURVIVAL_o_HORROR/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a> it on Steam if you're interested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Day, Another Hollow Knight: Silksong Steam Update — Could We Finally Get a Release Date This Week?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-%E2%80%94-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week.1205646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/another-day-another-hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-could-we-finally-get-a-release-date-this-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Another day, another Hollow Knight: Silksong SteamDB update that's whipped information-starved Hollow Knight fans into a frenzy. Could this one finally be the one?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Overnight, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong"><u>Hollow Knight: Silksong</u></a> was quietly updated on Steam, with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1030300/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>SteamDB</u></a> noting that one package received its first update in over a year (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-ignites-perfectly-reasonable-shadow-drop-hopes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Eurogamer</u></a>). It immediately sent the rumor mill into overdrive, with players speculating that something's afoot. Will we finally see more at Summer Game Fest? Could it be part of the Xbox Showcase? Or could we even get a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2</u></a> <a href="https://x.com/Papa_Kutz/status/1929773856367300618" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>shadow drop</u></a>…?!</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Hollow Knight: Silksong received updates to its packages tonight on SteamDB (one apparently receiving an update for the first time in 15 months) <a href="https://t.co/DJz9ebnffg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/DJz9ebnffg</a><a href="https://t.co/THPp2luYgp" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/THPp2luYgp</a> <a href="https://t.co/9RvHY290ez" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/9RvHY290ez</a></p>— Wario64 (@Wario64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1929769954494025999?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, fans immediately began scouring the updates for clues. And while some have been hurt before by a flurry of nothingburger, this update is particularly exciting because <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l2278w/the_game_has_been_uploaded_to_the_steam_servers/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>several</u></a> <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/342712/apps/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>fans</u></a> believe we have proof Hollow Knight: Silksong — or at least some version of it — has "been uploaded to the Steam servers."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"[Is this R]eal?" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l25j2q/comment/mvqbab1/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>asked</u></a> one fan hopefully. "Real," the OP <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l25j2q/comment/mvqbg6x/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Team Cherry has always done things on its own timescales, and is notoriously tight-lipped, leaving us speculating over the tiniest, and sometimes silliest, details. Now, however, it <em>really</em> feels like there's something coming… here's hoping we find out what it is sooner rather than later. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Team Cherry’s sequel is one of the most anticipated games in the world right now, topping the Steam wishlist charts for years. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-makes-brief-appearance-during-nintendo-switch-2-direct-to-secure-2025-release-window"><u>Silksong made a brief appearance at Nintendo’s Switch 2 Direct in April</u></a>, and soon after Team Cherry nailed down the 2025 release window, much to the relief of its very patient fans. And now, given <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-will-be-playable-in-september-2025-at-an-australian-museum">we know it will be playable for those who can be at Australia’s national museum of screen culture, ACMI, from September 18</a>, some are speculating that we could be looking at a launch before then… although nothing's confirmed as yet, of course.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently exclusively shared a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-sprite-sheet-has-players-wondering-what-calls-for-hornet-to-remove-her-cloak-like-an-exhausted-dad-home-from-work"><u>Silksong sprite sheet and… well, the internet internet-ed</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>