<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:21:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transformers: Reactivate Leaked Gameplay Reveals Bumblebee Footage Following Cancelation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/transformers-reactivate-leaked-gameplay-reveals-bumblebee-footage-following-cancelation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/transformers-reactivate-leaked-gameplay-reveals-bumblebee-footage-following-cancelation.1078380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/transformers-reactivate-leaked-gameplay-reveals-bumblebee-footage-following-cancelation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/transformers-reactivate-canceled">Transformers: Reactivate</a> gameplay seems to have leaked following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/online-action-game-transformers-reactivate-cancelled-dev-potentially-facing-layoffs">the announcement that the project was canceled yesterday</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Footage of what appears to be the early-in-development Transformers third-person action game found its way to X/Twitter just hours after developer Splash Damage revealed it had made the decision to “end development” for the project. The video, shared online by X account <a href="https://x.com/DpzLuna/status/1877095975665242277" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>@DpzLuna</u></a>, features fan-favorite Autobot Bumblebee as he blasts away enemy robots both in and out of car form. His movement options include the ability to drive around a few different city-like environments and use short, rocket-powered dashes during gunfights.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Texture-less roads, unfinished weapon effects, and more rough-around-the-edges elements suggest more work was needed on this version of the project, though it's unclear at what point in development the footage was captured. There’s also no telling whether the video we’re seeing today would have resulted in a cohesive package or which other Transformers players would have been able to control. Still, it seems some progress had been made on Transformers: Reactivate before it ultimately met its demise.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Transformers Reactivate Gameplay Unreal Engine 5<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TransformersReactivate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#TransformersReactivate</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PlayTFR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#PlayTFR</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Transformers?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#Transformers</a> <a href="https://t.co/rF707RAhij" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/rF707RAhij</a></p>— Transformers: Reactivate | DpzLuna (@DpzLuna) <a href="https://twitter.com/DpzLuna/status/1877095975665242277?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">January 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Transformers: Reactivate was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/transformers-reactivate-is-an-online-action-game-developed-by-splash-damage"><u>originally announced</u></a> as a new video game entry in the long-running robot universe back at The Game Awards in 2022. Splash Damage pitched it to players as an online action game with a “fresh, new story” for PC and consoles, but updates on its progress have been few and far between since its initial reveal. Hope for any news came to a halt yesterday when the team said it would no longer continue working on its Transformers game as it refocused resources on other projects amid fears of potential layoffs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"While not being able to see the game through to release is painful, having to say goodbye to friends and colleagues hurts even more,” Splash Damage said at the time. “We're now focused on doing everything we can to support them through this tough period, just as we are committed to caring for those who stay with us as we build a stronger Splash Damage for the future."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>