<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 03:33:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Bleach Rebirth of Souls, Resident Evil Requiem, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-november-2-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-bleach-rebirth-of-souls-resident-evil-requiem-and-more.1341796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We've rounded up the best deals for Sunday, November 2, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Bleach Rebirth of Souls for $34.99</h2><div catalogid="bc0b8383-a917-42a5-a0c7-e70dba5a3239" id="230039"><div id="230039" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bleach Rebirth of Souls</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-review">Bleach Rebirth of Souls</a> was the first major Bleach game release in many years, with Bandai Namco and Tamsoft bringing the iconic series to modern platforms as a fighter. All of the most iconic Bleach characters are here, including Ichigo Kurosaki, Rukia Kuchiki, Grimmjow Jeagerjaques, and even Coyote Stark. Save $25 off the base game this weekend with this deal at Woot.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order Resident Evil Requiem</h2></div><div id="229989" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="42e2ada8-65ab-4b9f-bede-2da0301a63e3"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Resident Evil Requiem</h3></p></div><div catalogid="42e2ada8-65ab-4b9f-bede-2da0301a63e3" id="229986"><div id="229986" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Resident Evil Generation Pack</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Resident Evil Requiem officially opened pre-orders late last week ahead of its February 27 release date next year. While a standard edition is available, the more interesting edition is the Resident Evil Generation Pack, which puts together Resident Evil 7, Resident Evil Village, and Resident Evil Requiem in one package for only $89.99. For Nintendo players who never had the chance to experience these games, this is an excellent option.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart (PC) for $26.99</h2></div><div catalogid="bc0b8383-a917-42a5-a0c7-e70dba5a3239" id="230037"><div id="230037" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart Standard - PC [Steam]</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-ps5-review">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</a> is still one of my favorite PlayStation 5 games. Insomniac Games brought endless charm with the entry, with engaging combat and a solid storyline as well. Today, you can score a Steam copy of the game for $26.99 at Amazon. If you're looking for a platformer and have yet to play Rift Apart, make it your mission to do so this weekend!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save $10 Off Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</h2></div><div id="229888" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER TACTICAL ED – PS5</h3></p></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229889"><div id="229889" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER TACTICAL ED – XSX</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater was one of 2025's most anticipated games for many, as it marks a major return to the MGS franchise for Konami. This weekend, you can save $10 off the release for either PS5 or Xbox Series X. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Between its old-school stealth-action gameplay and engaging spy-thriller story, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater largely succeeds as a faithful, visually impressive remake of the 2004 classic."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Raidou Remastered for $31.99</h2></div><div catalogid="fd3e47a3-37c7-4a01-8149-7599373fb897" id="228236"><div id="228236" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Raidou: Remastered – The Mystery of the Soulless Army Launch Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/raidou-remastered-the-mystery-of-the-soulless-army">Raidou Remastered: The Mystery of the Soulless Army</a> launched in mid June, and you can save almost 50% off a PS5 copy for this weekend at Woot. This action RPG is a remaster of the 2006 PS2 game, and there are many improvements and new features to discover. For one, UI, visuals, and voice acting have all been tweaked to refine the experience, but you can also discover more than 120 different demons.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">NBA 2K26 for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229883"><div id="229883" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>NBA 2K26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">NBA 2K26 is on sale this weekend for $39.99, just in time for the start of the NBA season. This is even lower than last weekend's sale! <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nba-2k26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, “Ball Over Everything” is a fitting description for NBA 2K26. The smooth on-court action is better than ever and MyCareer’s excellent started-from-the-bottom journey to the pros story make it so the imperfections are easier to ignore."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Final Fantasy Physical Switch Pre-Orders</h2></div><div id="229385" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="0493e958-f62a-434f-b66f-21a8c2137182"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Final Fantasy 7 &amp; 8 Remastered Twin Pack</h3></p></div><div catalogid="0493e958-f62a-434f-b66f-21a8c2137182" id="229384"><div id="229384" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Final Fantasy 9 (Switch)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Square Enix announced a few weeks ago that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-8-and-9-physical-editions-for-switch-are-up-for-preorder-where-to-buy">Final Fantasy VII and Final Fantasy VIII Remastered are heading to Nintendo Switch</a> in the form of a physical pack. While this collection was available outside of North America, this is the first time it sees an official release in the United States. A separate Final Fantasy IX physical release was also announced, following the same pattern. Both physicals are set to drop on December 9, so get your pre-orders in now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Madden NFL 26 for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="96f7581b-3dc4-438d-b9ca-2ff485911287" id="229884"><div id="229884" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Madden NFL 26 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation 5 copies of Madden NFL 26 are available for $39.99 this weekend at Amazon. This latest entry brings new updates that make a noticeable difference, particularly when compared to entries of the last few years. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-26-review">In our 8/10 review</a>, we wrote, "There’s always room for improvement, but it’s hard to overstate what a leap Madden NFL 26 feels like both on and off the field."</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 2, 2025 8:21 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-november-2-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>