<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:35:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: Destined Rivals Launch Ran Into the Same Old Issues, With Scalpers, Shortages, and Outages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages.1145028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-destined-rivals-launch-ran-into-the-same-old-issues-with-scalpers-shortages-and-outages<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop">Pokémon TCG</a> set, Destined Rivals, has been fully unveiled and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-destined-rivals-preorder-guide-2025">the first pre-orders are already underway</a>. If you've been collecting for a while, it might not surprise you that it's been a fairly chaotic launch window though, with scalpers and store issues already reportedly plaguing the new set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fully unveiled on March 24, Scarlet &amp; Violet - Destined Rivals is set to launch starting on May 30, 2025. A few factors make this a particularly sought-after set. First, it marks the return of Trainer's Pokémon cards. Those old enough to remember <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonTCG/comments/1jjbcba/mom_says_we_have_destined_rivals_at_home/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vintage Trainer's Pokémon cards</a>, like Brock's Sandslash or Rocket's Mewtwo, should take a moment to stretch their back and adjust their posture before expressing excitement for this returning archetype.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">They're popular ways of tying beloved Trainers into the actual Pokémon cards in cool ways. Additionally, Destined Rivals is also centered around Team Rocket, the bad-team faction of Pokémon's first generation. Suffice to say, much like Prismatic Evolutions and its Eevee-lutions earlier this year, Destined Rivals has the makings of a very popular set.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Destined Rivals Pokémon Center Elite Trainer Box Images</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, when the pre-orders went live, it should be little surprise that frustration quickly ensued. People trying to get into the Pokémon Center website to buy an Elite Trainer Box, a themed box of packs and other niceties that's a common pick-up for people looking to crack into a set, were <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonTCG/comments/1jiwtc5/mood/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">left staring in from the outside</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And, still unsurprisingly, scalpers immediately hit online auctions like eBay with their ETB pre-orders. Listings of several hundred dollars for the typically $54.99 box were <a href="https://x.com/TCGDannyP/status/1904219026391499227" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seen hitting the site</a>. Again, this is for a confirmed pre-order of the Pokémon Center-specific ETB. Serebii's Joe Merrick summed it up well, <a href="https://x.com/JoeMerrick/status/1904215887965511861" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">outlining his own experience</a> waiting for hours in queue to get a Destined Rivals ETB.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I truly hate this," Merrick wrote. "The way almost all Pokemon TCG content has shifted to financial. The way that people just treat it as investment. The way people just want to flip it. It's disgusting. Shame on all involved."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is, sadly, par for the course. The aforementioned <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-company-breaks-silence-on-prismatic-evolution-shortage">Prismatic Evolutions set had shortages</a>, and the Blooming Waters 151 box also came and went fast. It's not uncommon to see notifications and signal-boosts of sets <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-paradox-rift-etbs-in-stock-now-on-amazon-live-new">restocking on various retailers</a>. Already, TPC has said in a FAQ online (<a href="https://www.pokebeach.com/2025/03/pokemon-center-says-more-destined-rivals-product-coming" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">per PokéBeach</a>) that more inventory of the Destined Rivals ETB will become available later this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even on top of scalper issues, some purchases are <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/pokemon-destined-rivals-elite-trainer-box-pre-orders-are-being-cancelled/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reporting that their ETB orders are being cancelled</a>. Demand and popularity for the Pokémon TCG seem to be through the roof, but sadly, it also seems to be marring the actual hobby for most trying to just crack some packs or play some matches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-tcg-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a> offers virtual solutions for the woes of physical scarcity, it's an understandable frustration for those who'd like to simply partake in the hobby. A stroll down your local store's card aisle will, more than likely, paint a clear picture of what it's like trying to pick up some packs right now. It's doubly frustrating when these drops have been exciting ones to see. Hopefully we see some remedies soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Full Three-Volume Hardcover Skyrim Library Is On Sale for Just $49.99]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/skyrim-library-on-sale-amazon-spring-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-full-three-volume-hardcover-skyrim-library-is-on-sale-for-just-49-99.1144986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/skyrim-library-on-sale-amazon-spring-sale-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This is stunning.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Even 14 years after its launch, The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim is still one of the finest RPGs to date, with tons of deep lore to enjoy. That's The Skyrim Library, a three-volume collection of texts detailing its massive world and history, a must-buy for any avid fan. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that you can <a href="https://zdcs.link/akRE73?object_uuid=0640381f-e18b-4c6b-a81a-7daa706490e0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">buy this collection for just $49.99</a> in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025">Amazon’s Big Spring Sale</a>, your bookshelves can become even more spectacular at a bargain. Just clip the coupon on the product listing for that additional savings.</p><div catalogid="1ade7db2-e22a-4f7a-a075-d9f688f9b8dd" id="217501"><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally released in 2017 at $110.00, this The Skyrim Library brings together gorgeous volumes— I: The Histories, II: Man, Mer &amp; Beast, and III: The Arcane— into a deluxe slipcase that can either be displayed on its own or fit neatly into your larger home assortment of tomes at home.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With each of its 232 pages thoughtfully written in impeccable detail and artistically illustrated, each book promises to immerse you in Skyrim’s history, its people, creatures, and the depths of its magical roots, almost as much as the iconic 2011 game had.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Going into some of the video reviews on its Amazon page, the whole package looks especially impressive. The outer slip case carries a distinct stone aesthetic and folds out to show a very well-done illustration of what appears to be Alduin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The books themselves look just as high-quality, with embellished and raised text over the durable hardback cover—giving you that luxury feel every time you want to open one up and peek into the Skyrim universe without jumping into the game itself or checking your phone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Written by Elder Scrolls developer Bethesda Softworks themselves, such a superb set comes as no surprise. Although their games aren’t short of imperfections with bugs, Bethesda always seems to go the extra mile when it comes to books based on their worlds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re in the UK, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9YOgdl?object_uuid=0640381f-e18b-4c6b-a81a-7daa706490e0&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Skyrim Library is also on offer for just £58.30 at Amazon UK</a>—a 35% price drop at the site's equivalent sale, Spring Deal Days. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 26, 2025 8:16 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>