<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 10:16:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maxroll's Elden Ring Nightreign Guides and Database]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-elden-ring-nightreign-guides-and-database</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maxrolls-elden-ring-nightreign-guides-and-database.1203276/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-elden-ring-nightreign-guides-and-database<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Elden Ring Nightreign is upon us! Time to choose your Nightfarer and set out into Limveld in hopes of defeating the Nightlord before you’re lost to the rains. We’ve teamed up with Maxroll to bring you a variety of guides to help you get started, introduce you to each of the Nightfarers and help you navigate the dangers of Limveld.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Getting Started in Nightreign</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/getting-started/elden-ring-nightreign-beginners-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nightreign <u>beginner's guide</u></a> goes over everything you need to get started: an introduction to each of the 8 playable characters, an explanation of the game's central hub, nagivating Limveld, the basics of combat, and how to handle the Nightlords, before wrapping everything up with a bit of information on Nightreign's metaprogression systems.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Maxroll Nightreign Character Guides</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Learn more about each of the game’s Nightfarers, how their skills work, and some additional information about each of their unique playstyles.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Wylder</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-2-wylder-1748614589634.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Wylder is a well-rounded character, suitable for beginners. His Sixth Sense passive allows you to cheat death and stay up through one instance of fatal damage. As a generalist, he doesn't excel with any specific weapons, but can use most martial armaments. His favorite weapon is the Greatsword.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/wylder-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Wylder Character Guide</u></a></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Guardian</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-3-guardian-1748614612549.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Guardian is Nightreign's tank class. He's most comfortable wielding a large shield and a weapon that can be used while guarding, such as a Halberd, Rapier, or Hand Crossbow. The Guardian deals less damage than the other Nightfarers, but has immense durability and multiple ways to disrupt foes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/guardian-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Guardian Character Guide</u></a></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Ironeye</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-4-ironeye-1748614631528.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Ironeye is the bow specialist, though his high Dexterity makes him proficient with a variety of other melee weapons such as daggers and curved swords. Unfortunately, his low durability makes him a poor choice as a front-line fighter, so use melee weapons with caution. Overall, his abilities are simple to use, making him an excellent choice for beginners.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/ironeye-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Ironeye Character Guide</u></a></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Duchess</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-5-duchess-1748614659315.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Duchess is a dagger-wielding Nightfarer who excels at evasive action to weave in and out of combat. Her starting weapon comes with a potent character skill, enchanting your blade with the Magic affinity for extra damage. In addition, she can adeptly wield Glintstone Sorceries due to her high intelligence, and she has decent Faith scaling for Incantations as well. For the Duchess, look out for weapons with the Magic or Frost Affinity, and those that can trigger statuses like Frostbite or Blood Loss.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/duchess-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Duchess Character Guide</u></a></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Raider</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-6-raider-1748614679688.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Raider has high Strength and uses large/colossal weapons to smash his foes. While he can use a variety of martial armaments well, his FP is extremely low, making it difficult to use weapon skills. The Raider's inherent durability makes him difficult to stagger, helping him ensure that his blows connect.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/raider-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Raider Character Guide</u></a></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Revenant</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-7-revenant-1748614720933.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Revenant is a support class, though her high Faith allows her to use offensive Incantations with ease. However, her ability to deal damage is limited as she has no method of FP recovery. Her passive ability summons the shades of foes to fight at your side, distracting enemies and dealing damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/revenant-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Revenant Character Guide</u></a></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Recluse</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-8-recluse-1748614743897.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">A spellcaster adept who can use her character skill to restore FP, the Recluse excels at unleashing devastation from afar. Her stats favor Sorceries and Incantations, but she can use Magic, Frost, Fire, Holy, and Lightning affinity weapons. This character is a bit more difficult to play as you don't have as many defensive options, and need to manage FP in addition to your Health and Stamina. However, if you do everything correctly, she deals significant damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/recluse-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Recluse Character Guide</u></a></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Executor</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-9-executor-1748614759386.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Executor excels in single combat. He has high Dexterity and Arcane, giving him access to a majority of the game's smaller weapons. Look out for Katanas in particular, as these scale off of Dexterity while also triggering the Blood Loss status to enemies. Position carefully because the Executor has low durability.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/characters/executor-character-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Executor Character Guide</u></a></p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nightreign Map Guides</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-10-map-1748614774402.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Limveld map is teeming with points of interest to explore. Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/limveld-map-key-locations" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Limveld Map &amp; Key Locations guide</a> teaches you about the various encounters, what mob types to expect, and the rewards you can earn for clearing them. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you explore, you'll encounter random events known as <strong>Raid Events</strong> which often involve fighting a challenging foe. If you clear the raid, you earn a valuable Power for the remainder of your run; learn more with Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/raid-event-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Raid Events guide</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Defeating Nightlords unlocks Shifting Earth events. Each of these events transforms a quadrant of the map into a unique zone, frequently filled with lots of bosses to fight - and similar to Raid Events, they award a special power when cleared. Learn more with <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/shifting-earth-events" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maxroll’s Shifting Earth event guide</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nightreign Resources</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-11-resources-1748614809755.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Explore <strong>Roundtable Hold</strong>, Nightreign’s main hub area. Here, you can switch your characters, perform Relic Rites to prepare for the next expedition, test things in the Sparring ground, read up on the game with the Visual Codex, explore your character’s story at the Journal, and set out from the Table of Lost Grace to do battle against a Nightlord. Learn about all this in Maxroll's <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/roundtable-hold" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Roundtable Hold guide.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Relics</strong> and <strong>Vessels</strong> are part of Nightreign’s metaprogression system. At the end of each run, you earn Relics and Murk, which you can spend at the Small Jar Bazaar. Some Relics have random affixes that may or may not be useful, whereas others (often earned through character quests or by defeating bosses) have fixed stats and are quite powerful. As you progress in the game, you also unlock additional Vessels, letting you equip a different Relic combination on your Nightfarer. Learn more about this system with Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/relics-vessels-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Relics and Vessels guide</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many of the Sorceries and Incantations in Nightreign belong to a specific Spell School. The Spell School determines which modifiers buff your spells - for example, a Glintstone Sorcery won't benefit from bonuses to Godslayer Incantations. This isn't very clearly explained, though, so if you’re curious on how to buff your Spells, check out Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/guides/incantation-sorcery-types" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sorcery and Incantation School Guide</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Maxroll's Nightreign Database</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/nightreign-12-database-1748614846283.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Browse Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/elden-ring-nightreign/getting-started/elden-ring-nightreign-beginners-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><strong>Elden Ring Nightreign Database</strong></u></a> to learn more about the Weapons, skills, spells, Relics, Vessels, Relic modifiers, Talismans, passive traits, and Nightfarers available in the game. Each item has a page with expanded tooltip information, which you can use to discover hidden secrets about Nightreign’s weapons (or just look for fun lore tidbits).</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Armaments include Daggers, Swords, Thrusting Swords, Curved Swords, Axes, Hammers, Spears, Halberds, Staves, Seals, Fist Weapons, Bows, Crossbows, and off-hand items.</li><li>Then you have Skills, weapon arts that consume FP to trigger additional effects.</li><li>Sorceries and Incantations offer buffs, healing, and ways to unleash devastation on your foes.</li><li>Vessels and Relics are Nightreign's metaprogression systems.</li><li>Talismans, found during your run, give your Nightfarer a small bonus.</li><li>Weapon Passives and Passive Character Traits function similarly to boons in most roguelikes, adding temporary power during a run.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Written by IGN Staff with help from Maxroll.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox's Grow a Garden Towers Above Even the Biggest Steam Games — but You Probably Have No Idea What It Is]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-grow-a-garden-towers-above-even-the-biggest-steam-games-but-you-probably-have-no-idea-what-it-is</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robloxs-grow-a-garden-towers-above-even-the-biggest-steam-games-%E2%80%94-but-you-probably-have-no-idea-what-it-is.1203096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-grow-a-garden-towers-above-even-the-biggest-steam-games-but-you-probably-have-no-idea-what-it-is<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a> farming simulator <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grow-a-garden-roblox">Grow a Garden</a> is attracting millions of players across PC, mobile, and console devices, eclipsing numbers achieved by some of the most popular games on any platform – so what exactly is it?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you load up Roblox at any time on any day in the next week, there’s a good chance around 2 million people will be playing Grow a Garden in some capacity. That’s according to the official user tracker found on all Roblox experiences, which plants the colorful free-to-play game firmly atop trending charts in a variety of categories. These are numbers that see the free-to-play game leaving other Roblox projects in its dust, with the second-most-popular “Playing Now” experience, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/brookhaven-rp-roblox">Brookhaven RP</a>, showing 590,000 players at the time of this piece’s publication.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pulling 1.5 million players is an impressive feat, and it’s also on the low end for Grow a Garden.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The farming simulator <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/roblox/comments/1kucd09/grow_a_garden_at_88_million_active_players/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>peaked at more than 8.8 million active users</u></a> last weekend, annihilating only competing experiences but multiple active user records, starting when it crossed the 5 million active users mark earlier this month. The 16-year-old behind Grow a Garden released it March 25, 2025. It has since been visited 3.4 billion times.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For comparison, Counter-Strike 2, currently the most popular Steam game, reached its all-time peak just last month at just under 1.86 million players (via <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/730/charts/#3m" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>SteamDB</u></a>). PUBG: Battlegrounds holds the trophy for the highest-ever active player count on Valve’s PC storefront, and even <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/578080/charts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>its peak</u></a> topped out at 3.25 million players in 2018.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grow a Garden is still trailing behind the free-to-play battle royale megaton that is Fortnite, which boasts a peak active player count of 15.3 million from <a href="https://x.com/EpicNewsroom/status/1333954587879821314" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an event held in 2020</u></a>. Grow a Garden isn’t quite at the top of the mountain, but it is climbing – and fast. It’s at least another significant piece of evidence that the Roblox platform is one to be taken seriously, as millions continue to flock to the dense forest of content it offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What Do You Do in Grow a Garden?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In Grow a Garden, you – if you can believe it – grow a garden. There’s little complexity to the gameplay formula currently setting Roblox ablaze. It’s not yet another anime tie-in or tower-defense experience but instead a straightforward farming game with a tutorial that lays out everything you need to know in just a few seconds.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/grow-a-garden-1748620781913.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Grow a Garden lets players create vibrant plots of land. Image captured by IGN.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Each player is plopped into a server with a handful of other Roblox users, with everyone granted their own plot of land to begin their garden on. While new players are gifted 20 Sheckles, Grow a Garden’s in-game currency, to purchase simple seeds for vegetables like carrots, it’s also almost immediately clear how far you can take the premise, as other players’ fenced-in areas will often be brimming with towering trees, bamboo, lively fruits, and more. Growth takes time, but gardens will continuously flourish, even when a player is offline, until picked.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Grow a carrot and sell it, and you’ll profit a few Sheckles. Rinse, repeat, and earn enough for blueberries, then mangos, then orange tulips, then grapes, then peppers, and so on. The satisfaction comes from the tangible growth you can see in your garden – and money – in real time. It’s a far-from-unique cycle distilled into its purest form, though there is more to do for those looking to dig for it.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Customizing a garden can be as simple as organizing your yard by color, height, or type, or flavor can be added with optional cosmetic items, tools, and pets. Updates and events keep players coming back for more, as do weather modifiers that can potentially increase the value of your crops. Every gameplay wrinkle is part of the formula that has seen Grow a Garden’s player base balloon to levels unheard of in Roblox’s blocky world. Not everyone understands it, but the success is undeniable.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Who Made Grow a Garden?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The 16-year-old who first broke ground with Grow a Garden remains creatively involved in what it’s become but is no longer the only name attached. Sharing responsibilities are Roblox experience management company DoBig Studios and popular developer Janzen Madsen (a.k.a. Jandel) and his network of creators at <a href="https://splittingpoint.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Splitting Point</u></a>. These are major players in the space, but Grow a Garden stuck out to Madsen before it exploded.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The game was developed by a 16-year-old in a few days, and we saw the game when it was on about 1,000, 2,000 CCUs,” Madsen tells us, describing Grow a Garden’s active players, “and we just partnered with that developer, built in a live-ops plan, did some general updates to the game, and, pretty much, the rest is history.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was here the now-gargantuan farming experience began to plant its roots, as the 20-person team at Splitting Point began to help create a foundation for growth. That’s not to say the original, anonymous developer stopped being involved.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I actually think they’re, creatively, pretty incredible.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“I actually think they’re, creatively, pretty incredible,” Madsen said when describing how development responsibilities are shared. “I think they bring a pretty unique perspective to the game, and I think there’s maybe a generational gap between me and them. Everyone has… I would say it’s almost equal, honestly, in terms of, we get on a call, we plan an update – it’s probably not what you’d expect. Sometimes we’re planning the update week to week, you know?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Madsen can’t nail down what triggered Grow a Garden’s meteoric rise, mostly because “it happened so quickly,” but points to tight update strategies and events as reliable draws for Roblox players. Recent examples include bringing in a DJ for entertainment and organizing a mass dance party in hopes of breaking a world record. Every update presents an opportunity to create a moment that sucks players in while making them feel involved in the journey.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">This goes out to all the haters at GDC from 2022-2024 if you aren't taking Roblox seriously then you are getting left behind! <a href="https://t.co/6MeE1vVABL" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/6MeE1vVABL</a></p>— Jandel - Roblox (@jandelRblx) <a href="https://twitter.com/jandelRblx/status/1923746162697437454?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 17, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The small free-to-play project with humble beginnings eventually exploded into the biggest game in Roblox history. There’s a full-on operation maintaining its success to ensure its millions of fans continue showing up, and the developers aren’t tending to it for free. Although Madsen declined to share the details regarding Grow a Garden’s earnings past an acknowledgement of <a href="https://create.roblox.com/docs/en-us/monetize-experiences" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Roblox’s previously established cut of in-game spending</u></a>, the experience offers more than a few clear ways for players to spend real-world cash.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/30/screenshot-2025-05-30-024441-1748620952304.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Seed packs available to players in Grow a Garden. Image captured by IGN.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nearly every item of interest can be purchased with the Roblox premium currency known as Robux, Grow a Garden’s primary source of income. On PC, <a href="https://www.roblox.com/upgrades/robux" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$5 translates to 500 Robux</a>, with seed prices ranging from seven to 715 Robux and decorations like crates and campfires asking for 119 and 149 Robux. There are also seed packs and eggs that can be purchased one at a time or in packs, essentially serving as loot boxes containing special crops and pets, respectively. Most these items can still be purchased with in-game Sheckles, even if the price tag can sometimes reach numbers higher than Grow a Garden’s player average player count. It’s unclear how much players are spending to kit out their farms, but with at least 1.5 million users playing at any moment, we can guess it’s probably a lot.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Climbing the Beanstalk</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Grow a Garden is pulling attention the likes of which Roblox has never seen, but success is far from a foreign concept on this platform. New experiences flood in every day, and while many of them never reach the top of trending charts, plenty of others, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blue-lock-rivals-roblox">Blue Lock: Rivals</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dress-to-impress-roblox">Dress to Impress</a>, still boast hundreds of thousands of engaged players months after release. Roblox isn’t a gaming fresh phenomenon – it’s been here for years, and it’s only attracting more attention.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, reaching around nearly 9 million active users is so unbelievable that many have questioned the legitimacy of Grow a Garden's success. Some have suggested bots have played a role in inflated numbers and fabricated popularity, but Roblox says this isn’t the case.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Grow a Garden's global success is fueled by exceptional user retention, vibrant social interactions — with friends driving play — and strong Robux engagement,” a Roblox spokesperson told <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/grow-a-garden-roblox-interview" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Game File</u></a>. “Our preliminary analysis confirms genuine popularity, not artificial inflation, validating the game's authentic community-driven growth.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Look at AAA. No one takes big risks, you know? Every day on Roblox, there’s a new concept or a new game out – I think it’s kind of cool.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While those on the outside raise eyebrows at Roblox's attraction to gamers, Madsen says he has worked to legitimize the platform he calls home for the majority of the time he’s been in this space. He sees Roblox as both a slice of gaming that’s gone ignored and a hub for creativity.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Most people’s first impression of Roblox is, ‘This is a silly platform for kids, and there’s no depth to the gameplay or games,’ and I think legitimately some of the best game designers in the world are on Roblox making games,” Madsen explained. “It’s like, ‘Yeah, they look simple, but they’re actually like… they’re solving hard problems there in the platform. They’re pushing the boundaries.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Look at AAA. No one takes big risks, you know? Every day on Roblox, there’s a new concept or a new game out – I think it’s kind of cool. I think it’s easy to judge from the outside without really taking a few weeks to look at it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if Grow a Garden has already bloomed to its fullest extent, it’s no doubt planted the seeds for other Roblox experiences to reach or even exceed its high bar. While we wait for it to grow, you can read up on all active Grow a Garden codes <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/grow-a-garden-codes">here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>