<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:47:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima's Xbox and Sony Games Affected by Actors' Strike]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hideo-kojimas-xbox-and-sony-games-affected-by-actors-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hideo-kojimas-xbox-and-sony-games-affected-by-actors-strike.1072758/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hideo-kojimas-xbox-and-sony-games-affected-by-actors-strike<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hopes to resume production this year.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hideo Kojima has revealed the ongoing video game actors strike has affected production on his Xbox game as well as his upcoming action espionage title for Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://x.com/HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN/status/1873951232764895628" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, Kojima said that Kojima Productions was forced to suspend actor scanning and filming for the Xbox-published <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/od-a-hideo-kojima-game">OD</a> during the second half of 2024 after the Screen Actors Guild - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA) video game actors' strike began in July.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Similarly, casting for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/physint-hideo-kojima-action-espionage-project">Physint</a>, Kojima’s hotly anticipated return to the “action espionage” genre, was suspended due to the strike. Kojima added that he hopes to resume production in 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">SAG-AFTRA video game voice actors accuse gaming companies of refusing to meet their demands on artificial intelligence. Negotiations over a new contract began in October 2022 and SAG-AFTRA members approved the strike in September 2023. Check out IGN’s feature, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-the-sag-aftra-video-game-actors-strike-means-for-gamers"><u>What the SAG-AFTRA Video Game Actors Strike Means for Gamers</u></a>, for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What this means for both OD and Physint remains to be seen, with both games without an official release window. Both are video game / movie hybrids, with Nope and Get Out Director Jordan Peele collaborating with Kojima on OD. Physint was announced during a Sony State of Play broadcast, suggesting <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/could-hideo-kojimas-return-to-action-espionage-be-one-of-the-first-ps6-games">it may release on PlayStation 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Kojima is working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach">Death Stranding 2</a>, which is out at some point in 2025, and the live-action <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-movie-coming-from-a24-kojima-productions">Death Stranding film with A24</a>. In his tweet, Kojima teased “other adaptations” are underway, without saying any more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">OD and Physint aren’t the only video games affected by the SAG-AFTRA strike. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-confirms-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-character-recast-after-players-expressed-concern-about-new-voices">Activision confirmed it had recast some members of the <u>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</u> cast</a> after fans noticed much-loved Zombies characters with new voices in-game. Activision said at the time: "We respect the personal choice of these performers. Out of respect for all parties, we won’t add new commentary about the ongoing negotiations with SAG-AFTRA. We look forward to a mutually beneficial outcome as soon as possible."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is not subject to the strike because it was in development before July 25, 2024, when the strike began. However, as suggested by Activision's statement, the voice actors may have decided against signing new contracts in solidarity with striking union members. IGN has asked SAG-AFTRA for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Wiktor Szymanowicz/Anadolu via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Projected to Make Over $3 Billion in Its First Year on Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-projected-to-make-over-3-billion-in-its-first-year-on-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-projected-to-make-over-3-billion-in-its-first-year-on-sale.1072638/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-projected-to-make-over-3-billion-in-its-first-year-on-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> is projected to make an eye-watering $3 billion in its first year on sale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar’s hotly anticipated open-world crime caper is currently due out fall 2025 on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S, with no word on a PC release for now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A new report by the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/1413cdb1-aee9-422f-8b78-15aa0bf40dca" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Financial Times</a>, based on analysis by video game research group DFC Intelligence, predicts GTA 6 will exceed $1 billion in pre-orders before it even launches. Surprising no-one, GTA 6 is expected to be the biggest entertainment launch of 2025, ahead of any movie or competing video game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">DFC predicted total revenue from GTA 6’s first 12 months on sale will reach $3.2 billion. To put that into context, 2024’s highest-grossing movie, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/inside-out-2">Inside Out 2</a>, made just shy of $1.7 billion at the global box office. In 2013, it took <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto 5</a> just three days to surpass $1 billion in sales — the fastest to that figure in entertainment history.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Strauss Zelnick, boss of Rockstar parent company Take-Two, told the Financial Times: “I never claim victory before it occurs. That said, I think Rockstar Games will once again deliver something absolutely phenomenal… Certainly the anticipation is high.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The huge projected revenue of GTA 6 is up against similarly huge development costs, which the Financial Times estimates from the high hundreds of millions to as much as $2 billion. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/theres-a-lot-riding-on-gta-6-and-not-just-for-rockstar-and-take-two">There’s a lot riding on GTA 6, then, but not just for Take-Two and Rockstar</a>. In March last year, Circana analyst Mat Piscatella predicted Rockstar’s surefire hit would spark “renewed interest” in video games, before going one step further: “There's probably never been a more important thing to ever release in the industry, so no pressure.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA 6 is the kind of game that will sell consoles. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-pro-likely-out-later-in-2024-analysts-say"><u>Sony’s PS5 Pro</u></a> will no doubt benefit greatly from interest in GTA 6, too. Let’s remember: GTA 6 is not coming out on PC at launch; to play you <em>must </em>own a PlayStation or an Xbox. Beyond the point of sale, GTA 6’s GTA Online equivalent will surely come packed with microtransactions as the current GTA Online does. Microsoft and Sony will get their cut of any money spent there, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the Financial Times points out, the almost guaranteed success of GTA 6 comes amid one of the toughest periods for the video game industry in recent memory. More than 33,000 people have lost their jobs since 2022, with huge layoffs at the likes of Microsoft and Sony. Indeed, Take-Two itself has suffered layoffs and studio closures.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All eyes are on Rockstar for a firm GTA 6 release date, or, as some are predicting, a delay into 2026. While you wait to find out, IGN has much more on GTA 6 to check out, including an ex-Rockstar dev who says <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-gta-6-be-delayed-to-2026-one-ex-rockstar-dev-says-the-studio-probably-wont-be-able-to-make-that-call-until-may-2025"><u>the studio probably won’t be able to decide whether GTA 6 is delayed until May 2025</u></a>, the boss of Take-Two's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/is-gta-6-coming-to-pc-take-two-boss-has-a-coy-response"><u>coy response on whether GTA 6 is coming to PC</u></a>, and the expert opinion on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-ps5-pro-run-gta-6-at-4k60-probably-not-say-the-experts"><u>whether the PS5 Pro will run GTA 6 at 60 frames per second</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>