<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:54:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crimson Desert Is This Month’s IGN First, Check Out 11 Minutes of New Quest Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-gameplay-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crimson-desert-is-this-month%E2%80%99s-ign-first-check-out-11-minutes-of-new-quest-gameplay.1317778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Retaking the Captured Fortress.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/06/crimson-desert-gameplay-banner-1759758606289.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The wild and expansive open-world adventure, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/crimson-desert">Crimson Desert</a>, is the focus of October’s IGN First. As is tradition, we’re kicking off a month of exclusive content with a brand new gameplay video. Above, you can watch a playthrough of The Captured Fortress, one of Crimson Desert’s faction quests, in which you help Duke Wells retake his castle from rebel forces. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This 11 minute-long video showcases a number of Crimson Desert’s key features. First and foremost, of course, is combat. Ever since we <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-is-like-god-of-war-and-dragons-dogma-had-a-baby-gamescom-2024">first played Crimson Desert at Gamescom 2024</a>, we’ve known that developer Pearl Abyss has been assembling something special when it comes to battle, and here you can see protagonist Kliff making use of a wide array of abilities. Among our favourites is using a spear to pole-vault into an enemy, and the incredibly powerful, magically-charged heavy attacks. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But this demonstration mission covers more than just combat. You’ll also see how Kliff can explore the environment using magic leaps, a Spider-Man-like swing, and his Crow Wings ability, which allows him to glide through the skies towards far-off objectives. You’ll also see him using his sword to reflect light, a skill that highlights points of interest in the world and guides you towards interesting discoveries. By following the shining lights, Kliff is able to infiltrate the Duke’s captured fortress in a more stealthy manner… and discover some extra loot along the way, too. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, a Crimson Desert showcase wouldn’t be complete without a boss battle, and so this video concludes with a full, violent clash against Fortain, the Cursed Knight. This armour-clad bad lad wields a sword with a mighty, supernatural ability that you don’t want to miss. You might even be able to claim it for yourself…</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And remember, this video is just the first drop. Throughout the month of October, IGN First will take you on a journey into the world of Crimson Desert. You’ll get to see many more bosses, regions, combat abilities, and two or three exciting new things you’d never guess would be part of a medieval fantasy game. For all that, stay tuned to IGN over the next few weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Executive Editor of Features. </em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/crimson-desert-gameplay-ign-first]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Walmart Is Granting Paid Members Early Access to Pokémon TCG Restocks Today, Here's What's Up for Grabs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prime-day-elite-trainer-box-discount-walmart-plus-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/walmart-is-granting-paid-members-early-access-to-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-restocks-today-heres-whats-up-for-grabs.1317775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Grabbing Prismatic Evolutions cards at a good price has felt like a lost cause for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a> collectors, but Walmart has confirmed that its upcoming <a href="https://zdcs.link/9217my?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">October Deals event</a> will include a significant offer that seems too good to be true.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beginning on 6 October, from 7 PM ET, paid <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/walmart-plus"><u>Walmart+ members</u></a> will have early access to purchase the highly sought-after <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4PlZ?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Prismatic Evolutions Elite Trainer Box for $59.99</a>, a 50% reduction from its "regular" $119.99 price.</p><div catalogid="33f87b44-ee72-4240-98ad-021acd5d3806" id="192311"><div id="192311" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Walmart+ Membership</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>30-day free trial available. Then it's $12.95/month, or $98/year.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're not already a member, it’s admittedly a slight drag that you’ll essentially have to add $12.95 onto that $59.99 price tag; it’s still better than the $200 minimum you’ll currently find on other marketplaces like <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxxLBp?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGPlayer</u></a> for the same set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Plus, this is going to sell out FAST, and I highly doubt there will be any remaining for the general non-Walmart+ shoppers looking for a bargain. Not only that, but you're going more for your money if you're looking to grab the brand new and upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-cards-most-expensive-cards"><u>Mega Evolution</u></a> expansion, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy"><u>Phantasmal Flames</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Walmart is doing a repeat of the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp4PlZ?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Prismatic Evolutions deal preview drop</a>, but this time with preorders for the upcoming set featuring Mega Charizard X during Walmart Collector Con. The preorders will drop at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET on October 9, so you better bookmark those links and be ready to go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a big deal, and even worth dropping the $13 on Walmart+ alone, considering just the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QqReJ0?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Phantasmal Flames Elite Trainer Box is going for $160+ right now resale</a>, and Walmart will be selling for just $55! Holy smokes! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you're after Prismatic ETBs or elusive preorders at MSRP for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy"><u>Phantasmal Flames</u></a>, picking up a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/walmart-plus">Walmart+ membership</a> is undoubtedly the move this week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s also important to know that whilst Walmart+ does have a 30-day trial available, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9213Ay?object_uuid=d56a5e2b-c154-4101-a604-be23c787ddf5&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart+ hub page</u></a> states that only paid members will have access to its early deals on 6 October. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The annoying part of the Walmart+ subscription process, if you want to buy early access items right away, is that you're only given the initial option to claim the 30-day trial. <strong>However, you can get around this by starting your free trial, cancelling it, and resubscribing for paid access. </strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Walmart Deals event, scheduled for 7-12 October, is designed to compete directly with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/amazon-prime-day"><u>Amazon’s Prime Day</u></a>. However, Walmart+ members will benefit from exclusive early access starting the day prior, on 6 October. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The idea is that after that early access day, the deals will then be made available to the wider public who don’t have Walmart+. However, given how quickly almost any MSRP-priced stock for new sets in the Pokémon TCG is selling out at all retailers, we’re certain this particular ETB will be sold out within hours, if not minutes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A Walmart+ subscription is priced at $12.95 per month, or $98 annually, and offers a range of benefits beyond early shopping privileges. Members receive free delivery with no order minimum, savings on fuel, access to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/paramount-plus"><u>Paramount+</u></a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/peacock"><u>Peacock</u></a> at no extra cost, and additional perks such as pharmacy delivery and discounts at selected partners. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although we are expecting Amazon Prime Day and the upcoming Black Friday sales to offer some decent Pokémon TCG deals of their own, this is still quite frankly one of the best we’ve seen this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We don’t expect Walmart to repeat this kind of deal for the foreseeable, or Walmart to match it. Even so, there’s no guarantee you’ll be able to beat out all the other keen collectors, scalpers, and their bots who might be trying to nab one before you can. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">What we’d advise is to have your paid Walmart+ subscription set up and you be logged in on 6 October, and if you get the chance to add one of those half-priced Prismatic Evolutions ETBs to your basket, you take it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Note: Pokémon TCG pricing is incredibly volitile and any mention of sale pricing is indicative of the current market rate for the aforementioned products. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, Pokémon Elite Trainer Boxes are meant to sell for around $50-$60 MSRP, but instead retailer at around $100+ post launch.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 6, 2025 4:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prime-day-elite-trainer-box-discount-walmart-plus-early-access]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aliens: Fireteam Elite 2 Pops Up on ESRB Website]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-pops-up-on-esrb-website</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-pops-up-on-esrb-website.1317670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A listing for the unannounced Aliens: Fireteam Elite 2 has appeared online.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The website for the Entertainment Software Rating Board has a <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40680/aliens-fireteam-elite-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">listing</a> for Aliens: Fireteam Elite 2, which is set for release on Windows PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S. Its publisher is listed as Daybreak Game Company LLC, which owns Cold Iron Studios, developer of the first game. As you’d expect, Aliens: Fireteam Elite 2 is rated M for Mature 17+ by the ESRB, with “Blood and Gore, Strong Language, and Violence.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/aliens-fireteam-elite">Aliens: Fireteam Elite</a> is a cooperative third-person survival shooter which drops players into the role of a Colonial Marine aboard the USS Endeavor, recently tasked with answering a distress call from the outer colonies. It was well-received upon its 2021 launch, earning a 7/10 from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/aliens-fireteam-elite-review">IGN’s review</a>. We said: “There's plenty of wild shootouts with swarms of xenomorphs in Aliens: Fireteam Elite, but some awkward pacing and repetitive level design prevents it from being a classic.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-1-lineup">Aliens: Fireteam Elite recently hit Xbox Game Pass</a>, expanding its audience. It was a well-timed addition, with the critically acclaimed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/alien-earth">Alien: Earth</a> TV show set to hit FX and Hulu at the time. This sequel, while so far unannounced, looks like a sure thing.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/aliens-fireteam-elite-2-pops-up-on-esrb-website]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>