<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:03:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls 6 Dev Says 'We're Going to Take Our Time and as Long as It Needs to Be Great,' Points to GTA 6 Delay as 'The Smartest Thing They Cou]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-dev-says-were-going-to-take-our-time-and-as-long-as-it-needs-to-be-great-points-to-gta-6-delay-as-the-smartest-thing-they-could-do</link>
            <guid>1385227</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"What do fans really want?"</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda developers including chief Todd Howard have issued an update on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi">The Elder Scrolls 6</a> — but stopped short of confirming a release date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When the six-year anniversary of The Elder Scrolls 6 announcement arrived in June last year, even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-teaser-is-now-6-years-old-and-even-todd-howard-paused-to-say-oh-wow-that-has-been-a-while"><u>Howard himself paused to say, "oh wow, that has been a while."</u></a> The Elder Scrolls 6 is at least in production, with Bethesda confirming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-officially-in-early-development-but-dont-expect-to-hear-about-it-soon"><u>it had entered "early development" in August 2023</u></a> and "early builds" were available in March 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, amid increasing pressure from fans for some information on the game, Howard said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/im-preaching-patience-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-warns-fans-teases-potential-shadowdrop"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 wouldn’t be out for some time yet</u></a>. In an interview with <a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/article/fallout-4-anniversary-todd-howard-interview" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GQ magazine</u></a> to celebrate the release of Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition, Howard said The Elder Scrolls 6 is “still a long way off,” adding: “I’m preaching patience. I don’t want fans to feel anxious.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, speaking to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/interview/2025/12/16/bethesda-gives-us-an-update-on-the-elder-scrolls-vi-development" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game Informer</a>, Howard — who is The Elder Scrolls 6 director and executive producer — and other Bethesda developers issued a more detailed update. Let’s start with Howard, who said of The Elder Scrolls 6:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It’s progressing really well. The majority of the studio’s on 6, but I’ll say this: we always overlap. So, we’re very used to overlapping development. And we have long pre-productions on things so that we feel good about them. And it’s a process. We all wish it went a little bit faster — or a lot faster — but it’s a process that we want to get right.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Taking the time to get The Elder Scrolls 6 right is a sentiment shared by studio design director Emil Pagliarulo, who pointed to GTA 6’s high-profile delays as the “smartest thing they could do.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“What do fans really want?” he asked. “Do they want a game that comes out before it should and doesn’t meet their expectations? Or do they want the turkey that is in the oven for long enough to be delicious when it finally comes out of the oven, you know? That’s what I think people are going to want. So, we’re going to take our time and as long as it needs to be great.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And finally, studio director Angela Browder hyped up the technological advances that make The Elder Scrolls 6 “this endless set of possibilities that is really, really exciting as a developer, but really, really exciting as someone who really likes to think about how far everything has come in our industry. It’s gonna be dope. It’s dope! [laughs]”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alas, there remains no release window, which is what fans are waiting to hear right now. And fans are getting increasingly desperate for news. Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/this-honestly-might-be-the-best-piece-of-evidence-we-have-for-a-release-date-fans-think-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-out-in-2027-because-of-a-speech-skill-in-a-live-action-skyrim-trailer">some thought Bethesda teased The Elder Scrolls 6’s release year in a live-action Skyrim trailer because one of Santa’s elves raised their speech level to 27</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can understand why patience might be difficult for some though. In January this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-announcement-is-now-as-old-as-skyrim-was-when-the-elder-scrolls-6-was-announced"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 announcement became as old as predecessor Skyrim was when The Elder Scrolls 6 was announced</u></a>. Skyrim was released on November 11, 2011, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/11/e3-2018-the-elder-scrolls-vi-announced-at-bethesda-press-conference"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 was revealed on June 10, 2018</u></a> — 2,403 days afterwards. It is now seven-and-a-half years since the announcement, and we’re no closer, it seems, to the release of the game.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Elder Scrolls Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the GQ article, Howard once again admitted that it had taken too long to get The Elder Scrolls 6 out the door, but did tease a The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered-style shadowdrop — without confirming anything.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I do like to have a break between them, where it isn’t like a ‘plus one’ sequel,” Howard said of making The Elder Scrolls games again. “I think it’s also good for an audience to have a break — The Elder Scrolls has been too long, let’s be clear. But we wanted to do something new with Starfield. We needed a creative reset.” Bethesda is currently playtesting The Elder Scrolls 6, Howard revealed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I like to just announce stuff and release it,” Howard continued. “My perfect version — and I’m not saying this is going to happen — is that it's going to be a while and then, one day, the game will just appear.” The Oblivion Remastered shadowdrop was “a test run,” Howard teased. “It worked out well.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this year it was confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-will-feature-a-memorial-character-for-a-much-missed-fan-following-85000-donation-to-make-a-wish"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6 will include a character designed in memory of a much-missed fan</u></a> after a remarkable charity campaign that raised more than $85,000 for Make-A-Wish.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-6-dev-says-were-going-to-take-our-time-and-as-long-as-it-needs-to-be-great-points-to-gta-6-delay-as-the-smartest-thing-they-could-do]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian CEO Responds to Divinity Gen AI Backlash: 'We Are Neither Releasing a Game With Any AI Components, Nor Are We Looking at Trimming Down Teams to]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/larian-ceo-responds-to-divinity-gen-ai-backlash-we-are-neither-releasing-a-game-with-any-ai-components-nor-are-we-looking-at-trimming-down-teams-to-replace-them-with-ai</link>
            <guid>1385224</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">AI is "something we are constantly discussing internally through the lens of making everyone's working day better, not worse."</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">This morning, the news broke that Larian Studios, developer of Baldur's Gate 3 and the upcoming, just-announced Divinity, is apparently using generative AI behind the scenes for things like concept art and placeholder text. The backlash has been swift and loud from the gaming community, and now Larian founder and game director Swen Vincke is responding to clarify his remarks, affirming that Larian is "neither releasing a game with any AI components, nor are we looking at trimming down teams to replace them with AI," and that AI is "something we are constantly discussing internally through the lens of making everyone's working day better, not worse."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The original news comes from a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-12-16/-baldur-s-gate-3-maker-promises-divinity-will-be-next-level?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc2NTg5MzY2NSwiZXhwIjoxNzY2NDk4NDY1LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUN0Q4ODFLSVAzSTkwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.D26Cs7X_5kH5HuJT2frcX_AMIXyuXWefzz5NK2VlXEI" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg interview</a> with Vincke. In it, Vincke admits that Larian is "pushing hard" [Bloomberg's phrasing] on generative AI, even though it hasn't led to big gains in efficiency. Specifically, the studio is using the technology to "explore ideas, flesh out PowerPoint presentations, develop concept art and write placeholder text." [Bloomberg's phrasing].</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Vincke reassures that there won't be any AI-generated content in the final version of Divinity. "Everything is human actors; we're writing everything ourselves." But it sounds like this approach isn't going over smoothly with everyone. Bloomberg's piece acknowledges that some internally at Larian have pushed back, though Vincke says, "I think at this point everyone at the company is more or less OK with the way we're using it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This news hasn't gone over super well with the community, though. On Bluesky, Larian is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me/post/3ma4d2dzp5225" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">being lambasted</a> by a number of individuals across the game development community, including some former Larian employees. "consider my feedback: i loved working at @larianstudios.com until AI," <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/anoxicart.bsky.social/post/3ma4kiiuu5s2g" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">writes Selena Tobin</a>, an environment artist and former Larian employees. "reconsider and change your direction, like, yesterday. show your employees some respect. they are world-class &amp; do not need AI assistance to come up with amazing ideas."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Divinity and Baldur's Gate 3 communities have a somewhat more divided reaction, with some defending its use for concepting, though there's still a significant amount of backlash. A few commenters have pointed out that games <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-alters-developer-confirms-it-used-generative-ai-text-and-translations-promises-updates">such as The Alters</a> suffered from significant fan anger over discovered generative AI use, but are willing to forgive Larian for the same offense.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In response to this backlash, Vincke has issued IGN a lengthy follow-up response, which we've published here in full:</p><blockquote>We’ve been continuously increasing our pool of concept artists , writers and story-tellers, are actively putting together writer rooms, casting and recording performances from actors and hiring translators.</blockquote><blockquote>Since concept art is being called out explicitly - we have 23 concept artists and have job openings for more. These artists are creating concept art day in day out for ideation and production use.</blockquote><blockquote>Everything we do is incremental and aimed at having people spend more time creating.</blockquote><blockquote>Any ML tool used well is additive to a creative team or individual’s workflow, not a replacement for their skill or craft.</blockquote><blockquote>We are researching and understanding the cutting edge of ML as a toolset for creatives to use and see how it can make their day-to-day lives easier, which will  let us make better games.</blockquote><blockquote>We are neither releasing a game with any AI components, nor are we looking at trimming down teams to replace them with AI.</blockquote><blockquote>While I understand it's a subject that invokes a lot of emotion, it's something we are constantly discussing internally through the lens of making everyone's working day better, not worse.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Vincke then followed up further with a post on Twitter/X:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Holy fuck guys we’re not "pushing hard" for or replacing concept artists with AI.</p><p>We have a team of 72 artists of which 23 are concept artists and we are hiring more. The art they create is original and I’m very proud of what they do.</p><p>I was asked explicitly about concept art…</p></div>— Swen Vincke @where? (@LarAtLarian) <a href="https://twitter.com/LarAtLarian/status/2001011042642505833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">December 16, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The post reads:</p><blockquote>Holy fuck guys we’re not "pushing hard" for or replacing concept artists with AI.<p>We have a team of 72 artists of which 23 are concept artists and we are hiring more. The art they create is original and I’m very proud of what they do.</p><p>I was asked explicitly about concept art and our use of Gen AI. I answered that we use it to explore things. I didn’t say we use it to develop concept art. The artists do that. And they are indeed world class artists.</p><p>We use AI tools to explore references, just like we use google and art books. At the very early ideation stages we use it as a rough outline for composition which we replace with original concept art. There is no comparison.</p><p>I talked about how we use ML here if you would like to know more:
<a href="https://t.co/41KPNjaqI7" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-embraces-machine-learning-for-tasks-that-nobody-wants-to-do/1100-6531123/</a></p><p>We've hired creatives for their talent, not for their ability to do what a machine suggests, but they can experiment with these tools to make their lives easier.</p></blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">This discussion comes amid a slate of interviews with Vincke <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yup-that-weird-statue-was-teasing-a-new-divinity-game-the-game-awards-2025">following the announcement of Larian's next game, Divinity</a>, at <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">The Game Awards</a> last week. We had our own interview with Vincke, which you <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/if-you-like-baldurs-gate-3-this-is-gonna-be-great-larian-boss-swen-vincke-reveals-what-to-expect-from-divinity-in-first-interview-since-the-game-awards-announcement">can read in full here</a>, and elsewhere Vincke has confirmed Divinity <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/divinity-like-baldurs-gate-3-is-a-turn-based-rpg-larian-confirms">will in fact be a turn-based RPG</a>. We've been slowly compiling <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-is-divinity-larian-studios-baldurs-gate-3">everything we know about Divinity so far right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/larian-ceo-responds-to-divinity-gen-ai-backlash-we-are-neither-releasing-a-game-with-any-ai-components-nor-are-we-looking-at-trimming-down-teams-to-replace-them-with-ai]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4 December 2025 Patch Makes a Number of Fixes, Sorts 'A Few Key Pain Points for Players']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-4-december-2025-patch-makes-a-number-of-fixes-sorts-a-few-key-pain-points-for-players</link>
            <guid>1385218</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda has released a December patch for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a> just in time for the holidays.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/377160/view/599671687785481608" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a>, Bethesda thanked players of its 10-year-old role-playing game for their feedback, which “helped us sort through a few key pain points.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, storage expansion on console will have to wait until 2026. “It was a goal of ours to launch storage expansion on console this year, knowing it's been one of the top requests from players,” Bethesda said. “While the team has made progress, we need a little more time to roll this out for console players and will need to wait until the new year.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The patch comes after last month’s release of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-4-anniversary-edition"><u>Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-sparks-backlash-as-disgruntled-fans-use-steam-reviews-to-express-their-disappointment">a backlash from players over technical problems and pricing</a>. It also arrives just in time for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-season-2-prime-video-premiere-release-date-brought-forward-in-surprise-move-by-amazon">the start of Fallout Season 2 on Prime Video</a>, which kicks off today, December 16 and will surely spark a surge in players of all things Fallout, as Season 1 did.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Fallout 4 December 2025 patch notes: </h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Save/Load and Content Handling</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed issues with the missing Creations Bundle add-on for Steam</li><li>Game now recognizes Creation Club content upon loading a save file from an older build. </li><li>Correct warning dialogue is shown when Creations are disabled but not deleted. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>General UI/UX Improvements</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved visibility and interaction in the Category List, fixed overlapping boxes, and ensured button prompts display correctly on all platforms (including ROG Ally and Steam Deck). </li><li>Fixed issues with missing or broken UI elements, such as missing button layouts, gallery image enlargement, and empty titles in “My Library”. </li><li>Improved sort menu transparency and restored the 'Best Results' sort option. </li><li>Addressed keyboard input loss and cursor visibility issues in the Creations menu. </li><li>Fixed prompt and navigation issues when rapidly re-entering the Creations Store or using the PS Store overlay. </li><li>Creations removed from the storefront can now be individually deleted from the Load Order. </li><li>Banner carousel/category rows no longer endlessly scroll when opening the Purchase Credits menu. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Crash &amp; Stability Fixes</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed crashes related to downloading all Creations, data reloads, idling in menus, profile sign-out, and leaving the Creations menu (especially on PS4/PS5). </li><li>Fixed rare crashes after store purchases, during scrolling/viewing in the Creations menu, and when starting a new game with Creations enabled. </li><li>Improved error handling for rapid menu actions and ensured the game no longer hangs on quit. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ultrawide, Steam Deck, and Platform-Specific Fixes</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Workshop menus and reset screens are now optimized for ultrawide and super ultrawide monitors. </li><li>Fixed performance hitches and UI alignment issues on ultrawide </li><li>Addressed platform-specific issues such as button prompts, misplaced UI </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Text, Localization, and Miscellaneous</strong> </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Apostrophes and other special characters now display correctly in the in-game Creations menu. </li><li>Prompt for Anniversary Upgrade now fits correctly in German, French, and Spanish localizations.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-4-december-2025-patch-makes-a-number-of-fixes-sorts-a-few-key-pain-points-for-players]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>