<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:27:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Sidekicks Are Here, Epic Confirms You Can Customize the Appearance of Your Pet Just Once and It's Permanent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-sidekicks-are-here-epic-confirms-you-can-customize-the-appearance-of-your-pet-just-once-and-its-permanent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-sidekicks-are-here-epic-confirms-you-can-customize-the-appearance-of-your-pet-just-once-and-its-permanent.1340182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>'s Sidekicks, the adorable little pets that accompany you on your Fortnite adventures, have caused quite a stir with Fortnite fans — and not necessarily for all the right reasons.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As described by Epic Games, Sidekicks are new pals in Fortnite that join your adventures in Battle Royale, Fortnite Save the World, Fortnite Festival (your Sidekick will stay backstage), LEGO Fortnite, and developer-made experiences (Sidekicks can only tag along with you if the Island Developer has enabled Sidekicks in their island). They let you "enjoy their company as they react to the world around you." You can design them yourself, including their personality and physical traits, all of which will be locked in as "permanent" details, but you'll be able to change their name and accessories — think hats, hoodies, that kind of thing — at any time. And no, they do not offer a gameplay advantage of any kind, nor can be hurt or killed in combat. (Phew!)</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/31/fortnite-sidekicks-1761909420805.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Fortnite Sidekicks are here. Image credit: Epic Games.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The first is Peels, the super sweet pup made of bananas, who'll unlock with tomorrow's (November 1) Battle Pass. More, including Bonesy, Spike, and Lil' Raptor, are set to drop on November 7, with something for cat lovers coming "not long after." Bonesy will be granted to players who own the Bonesy Back Bling on the same date. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So far, so cute, right? The bit that's really raising eyebrows, however, is the cost. As shared on the Fortnite <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1okk24y/sidekick_prices_have_been_revealed_and/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>subreddit</u></a>, prices will differ, with Lil' Raptor and Spike costing 1,200 V-Bucks, and Flopsticks and Cuddle Team Jr. a little more expensive at 1,500. As some are <a href="https://x.com/FortnitePV2/status/1984116283064119765" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>pointing out</u></a>, this is a pretty steep price for the new feature, with the Fishstick-themed Sidekick, Flopstick, costing more than the original 1,200 skin.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Bro… The Sidekick costs more than the original skin. <a href="https://t.co/HUi9oqa9N4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/HUi9oqa9N4</a></p>— Fortnite Leaks | Pluto V2 (@FortnitePV2) <a href="https://twitter.com/FortnitePV2/status/1984116283064119765?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 31, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It gets even worse, though. Epic has cofirmed you can customize the appearance of your Sidekick one time and it's permanent (you can unlock clothes for them, though and can change those whenever you want). This means that if you want to change your pet's colors after making that initial, permanent one-time change, you have to buy the same pet again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"You can customize the Appearance of your Sidekick <strong>one time</strong> after obtaining it," <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/help/en-US/fortnite-battle-royale-c-202300000001636/gameplay-c-202300000001721/how-do-i-customize-the-appearance-of-my-sidekick-a202300000021343" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Epic said</a>. "You can purchase a Sidekick multiple times and give them different Appearances; however, each Sidekick customization you own in your Locker must be unique. Duplicate Appearances are not allowed." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The fact they locked customization behind needing to buy the same pet multiple times is probably the greediest thing Epig [sic] has ever done. Which honestly is a huge accomplishment for this company," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1okk24y/comment/nmbdws5/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said</u></a> one unhappy player.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"[This is] the death of reasonable microtransactions in Fortnite," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1okk24y/comment/nmbpiqu/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a> another. "Remember when they released Wraps, and unlike most games where you needed to unlock skins for each gun individually, wraps could be used on anything? Now we're getting customization locked on bought items. No reason for this, except greed."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Either make them this price and have all styles selectable or lock the styles and put them at 500-600," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1okk24y/comment/nmb9vu1/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>suggested</u></a> someone else. "If you do both nobody is gonna bother."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/fortnite/The_Simpsons_x_Fortnite_Mini_Season_Details"><u>Don't forget that Homer, Marge and co. are coming to Fortnite on November 1, 2025</u></a>, with a mini-season that brings Springfield to the battle royale. Not much is known about it, other than the villainous alien duo, Kang and Kodos, will be wreaking havoc on the Fortnite map once Fortnitemares 2025 comes to an end, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/fortnite/The_Simpsons_x_Fortnite_Mini_Season_Details"><u>here's everything we know so far, including including start times in your local area, current teasers, and what to expect</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-sidekicks-are-here-epic-confirms-you-can-customize-the-appearance-of-your-pet-just-once-and-its-permanent]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Hidden Room Discovery has Players Developing Theories and Searching for Easter Eggs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-hidden-room-discovery-has-players-developing-theories-and-searching-for-easter-eggs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-hidden-room-discovery-has-players-developing-theories-and-searching-for-easter-eggs.1340128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> players are trading theories about Easter Eggs and future updates after one fan discovered a mysterious hidden room in the firing range.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speculation about EA and Battlefield Studios’ secret room began after Reddit user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ok2yig/hidden_room_in_the_shooting_range/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mobile_Cyberdemon_as shared footage</a> of their character clipping into a previously undiscovered, hidden area. The unlit space is tucked behind the cramped weapon testing room, with only a sealed door — which features a red “keep door closed” sign — hinting at its existence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After a few minutes of trying (and lots of awkward crouching) on PlayStation 5, we were able to recreate the moment seen in the clip and confirm the hidden Battlefield 6 room exists. We can also confirm this mysterious hiding spot is, unfortunately, pretty boring, as it only features little more than a workbench and an empty gun rack.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s easy enough to see areas like this and assume they are simply unfinished assets left on the cutting room floor, but fans have other ideas.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield 6 launched just weeks ago, so there’s no telling what BF Studios could have had planned for this room when sneaking it behind the firing range. However, some details have given players more than enough ammunition to start crafting theories about what the hidden room was — and what it could be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Judging by the gates, it's a vehicle hangar in the works,” one <a href="https://x.com/youfi_7/status/1983986648217248180" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>fan theorized</u></a>. “I hope they eventually add a real shooting range, not just one room.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other Battlefield 6 fans have also <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ok2yig/comment/nm7oq32/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>proposed theories related to a firing range expansion</u></a>, hoping that, if the hidden room wasn’t an official vehicle testing area, it could become one in the future. It’s an add-on the community has shown interest in for some time, as players spent the weeks since launch using precious helicopter and jet spawns just learning how to leave the ground.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Another <a href="https://x.com/GhostofMahvel/status/1984023775466418583" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">popular theory suggests</a> the room could could have served as a slightly smaller firing range upgrade that allows players to quickly experiment with different weapons and attachments. Commenters have even <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ok2yig/comment/nm7pr1q/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">toyed with the idea of bringing the flashlight attachment into the hidden room</a> to look for any Battlefield Easter Eggs BF Studios might have secretly placed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many of the ideas related to the Battlefield 6 mystery stem from desires players would like to see fulfilled. The firing range enigma could absolutely be an Easter Egg, unfinished feature, or future content update, but there’s also the possibility that players have been looking at the room long before Mobile_Cyberdemon_as made their discovery.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You can see that stripey background in that customize weapon screen,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ok2yig/comment/nm7ri9z/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>popular fan theory said</u></a>. “I guess that's why the firing range loads so fast, because you're actually in it the whole time.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“That's my assumption is when you're in the menus you're actually just in that room with your view locked to a UI and with different walls or areas serving as backdrops for certain screens in the menu system,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ok2yig/comment/nm89lb1/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>player added</u></a>.</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">i think i did wrong <a href="https://t.co/RCoynmuMoM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/RCoynmuMoM</a></p>— Twenty (@TwentyFPS1) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwentyFPS1/status/1984001301789937936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">October 30, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">For now, the hidden firing range room doesn’t seem to be much more than an extra space to run around in. While Battlefield 6 fans inevitably search every dark corner for Easter Eggs, you can see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-map-blackwell-fields-in-the-firing-line-as-players-report-being-killed-from-as-far-away-as-enemy-hq-spawn-points">how the the online community feels about the first Season 1 map, Blackwell Fields</a>. You can also check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-alongside-battlefield-6-season-1-with-battle-royale-gauntlet-and-portal-modes-heres-everything-you-need-to-know">everything you need to know about Battlefield REDSEC and battle royale</a>, and you can learn about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps">why some Battlefield 6 fans are far from happy with EA's new standalone experience</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/All_Multiplayer_Maps"><u>full list of all currently available Battlefield 6 multiplayer maps</u></a>. Those looking to brush up on their online skills can also read <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/battlefield-6/Multiplayer_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>our multiplayer tips and tricks guide</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-hidden-room-discovery-has-players-developing-theories-and-searching-for-easter-eggs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>