<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 16:58:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I've Found 25 Pokémon TCG 151 Cards That Cost Less Than Amazon's Booster Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ive-found-25-pokmon-tcg-151-cards-that-cost-less-than-amazons-booster-bundle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ive-found-25-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-151-cards-that-cost-less-than-amazons-booster-bundle.1170426/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ive-found-25-pokmon-tcg-151-cards-that-cost-less-than-amazons-booster-bundle<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Why gamble? Almost every chase card from 151 is cheaper as a single.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve been eyeing the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-22-2025">Scarlet &amp; Violet: 151 set</a> — one of the most nostalgia-fueled Pokémon TCG releases in years — chances are you’ve come across the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpX010?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">151 Booster Bundle on Amazon</a>. At $66.65 for just six packs, it might seem like a harmless splurge. But that price? It's more than double the MSRP.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A standard six-pack bundle should cost around $29.99 to $34.99, making Amazon’s markup not just steep, but straight-up bad value. Despite the flashy marketing and glowing reviews, there's no guarantee you’ll pull anything even close to worth that price. You’re basically paying premium for the privilege of disappointment.</p><p id="151-booster-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="151 Booster Bundle">Pokémon TCG 151 Booster Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="e029409f-0020-43ce-95ac-88650ab348d6" id="219043"><div id="219043" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet - 151 Booster Bundle</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Current pricing is over twice the MSRP</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The upside? Prices for singles from the 151 set are dropping fast. So instead of gambling on blind packs, you can pick up exactly the cards you want — from heavy hitters like Charizard ex to stunning collector pieces like the alt-art Pikachu — for way less.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re after nostalgia, go ahead and crack some packs from the wallet-busting 151 bundle. But if you're building a competitive deck or just chasing standout cards like Blastoise ex, the smart move is investing in singles. Sites like <a href="https://zdcs.link/zj4OA2?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGplayer</a> offer great value, and buying directly means no dud pulls, no wasted cash, and just the cards you care about.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best 151 Illustration Cards to Collect</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aoXAqe?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Blastoise ex (200/165)</a> is currently the crown jewel of the 151 illustrated rares, and for good reason. Priced at about $66, it features a serene riverside scene of Blastoise at rest, a far cry from typical action poses. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The artwork feels more like a Ghibli frame than a trading card, which is why collectors are paying top dollar for it. It’s a grail card that you’d be extremely lucky to pull from a booster pack, let alone multiple copies.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/QWwV8d?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Venusaur ex (198/165)</a> isn’t far behind. Retailing around $60, it showcases the Grass-type legend lounging among blooming flowers in a dreamy forest scene. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These Illustration Rares are printed with unique texturing and alternate art styles, offering depth and color palettes that set them apart from standard ex cards. If your collection leans toward display-worthy art, this is an easy pickup.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then there’s <a href="https://zdcs.link/QmX4qn?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charmander (168/165)</a>, a fan favorite that combines cuteness and nostalgia in one of the most beloved alt-art designs in recent memory. Despite its popularity, you can currently snag it for under $50, which is less than the price of the booster bundle and a far better emotional return than pulling a non-holo Caterpie.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best 151 Cards for Competitive TCG Decks</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">While the illustrated rares turn heads, the set also includes powerful cards for players looking to improve their competitive decks. <a href="https://zdcs.link/aM6Zb4?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charizard ex (183/165)</a> can cause a massive 160 damage with just one fire energy thanks to Brave Wing, just make sure it gets knocked around a bit first. It’s one of the few viable Charizards in standard play and it’s only about $39 as a single card.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Blastoise ex (184/165) also deserves a second mention, not just as a collector card but a solid battlefield tank. Its Solid Shell passive reduces incoming damage and Twin Cannons can hit for 140 per Water energy discarded, making it lethal in the late game. And if you don’t need the full-art version, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QbxKqj?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Alt Art ex is going for just $13</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, <a href="https://zdcs.link/98LXld?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mew ex (193/165)</a> offers unmatched versatility. Its Restart ability gives you a once-per-turn card draw boost and its Genome Hacking attack can copy an opponent’s attacks with ease. That makes it ideal for control decks and rogue strategies. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For under $27, it’s a tactical addition that gives you flexibility without wrecking your wallet. <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxXDjO?object_uuid=b735faa7-3b50-473f-b54f-d56d0f7913ad&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mew ex - (205/165</a>) has the same moveset but is only $13.49 at the time of writing, so you can slide double the Mews into your Psychic deck for the same price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 22, 2025 2:13 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>