<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:18:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts Missing-Link Mobile Game Cancelled, But It's Not All Bad News As Square Enix Teases It Is 'Hard at Work on Kingdom Hearts 4']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-missing-link-mobile-game-cancelled-but-its-not-all-bad-news-as-square-enix-teases-it-is-hard-at-work-on-kingdom-hearts-4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-hearts-missing-link-mobile-game-cancelled-but-its-not-all-bad-news-as-square-enix-teases-it-is-hard-at-work-on-kingdom-hearts-4.1188786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-missing-link-mobile-game-cancelled-but-its-not-all-bad-news-as-square-enix-teases-it-is-hard-at-work-on-kingdom-hearts-4<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We are truly sorry to have to make this announcement."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-hearts-missing-link#:~:text=Summary,grand%20battle%20against%20the%20Heartless."><u>Kingdom Hearts Missing-Link</u></a>, the GPS-based action-RPG for mobile, has been cancelled — but it's not all bad news for Kingdom Hearts fans, as Square Enix confirmed it is still "hard at work" on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-hearts-iv"><u>Kingdom Hearts 4</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kingdom Hearts Missing-Link would have taken us to the realm of Scala ad Caelum in a new, original story in the grand battle against the Heartless on mobile devices, and had been originally slated to release in 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, in an unsigned <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1922543388831719643" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>statement</u></a> posted to the game's X/Twitter account, Square Enix wished to "convey [its] heartfelt apologies to everyone who have been looking forward" to it, but cancelled the project because it was "determined that it would be difficult [...] to offer a service that players would find satisfactory over a long period of time." The statement did not elaborate on what, exactly, was proving difficult.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We wish to convey our heartfelt apologies to everyone who has been looking forward to the start of service," the statement said. "Although we worked hard on developing and adjusting the game in the hope that it would enjoyed by lots of players, we determined that it would be difficult for us to offer a service that players would find satisfactory over a long period of time, leading us to the decision to cancel development.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We would like to take this opportunity to express our thanks to everyone who gave us their support and assistance with the multiple closed beta tests. We are truly sorry to have to make this announcement."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right at the end of the statement, however, Square Enix assured fans the "Kingdom Hearts series will continue," and hinted "we are hard at work on Kingdom Hearts 4, and hope you'll continue to support the series as you keep an eye out for further updates."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the first official mention of the highly-anticipated sequel fans have had in months, the last being a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tetsuya-nomura-drops-a-cryptic-kingdom-hearts-4-tease-on-birth-by-sleeps-15th-anniversary"><u>tiny, cryptic tease for Kingdom Hearts 4 back in January</u></a>. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-4-and-kingdom-hearts-missing-link-announced-at-the-series-20th-anniversary-event"><u>Despite being revealed in September 2022 with a full cinematic trailer</u></a>, developer Square Enix has since gone incredibly quiet since and, in series tradition, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-4-fans-pine-for-update-on-2nd-anniversary-of-its-announcement"><u>left fans pining for more</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kingdom Hearts series director Tetsuya Nomura has however hinted that Kingdom Hearts 4 will, after 22 years and a whopping 18 games, finally <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/after-22-years-and-18-games-kingdom-hearts-4-will-move-the-story-towards-its-end"><u>shift the Kingdom Hearts narrative towards its conclusion</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>