<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:03:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Source Blames Switch 2 Holiday Sales Slowdown on the Economic Landscape and the 'Absence of a Major Western Game' — Despite the Release of Me]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-source-blames-switch-2-holiday-sales-slowdown-on-the-economic-landscape-and-the-absence-of-a-major-western-game-despite-the-release-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1400950</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> sales over the holidays reportedly fell short of those recorded by the console's predecessor back in 2017, during its first end-of-year season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As revealed by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A_NUBDTG8_4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Game Business</a>, Switch 2 sales in the US and within key markets in Europe fell behind the equivalent pace of Switch 1 — something an unnamed senior Nintendo source blamed on a "complicated" economic climate today, and the "absence of a major Western game" during the year-end period.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That particular analysis will likely raise eyebrows among Nintendo fans, as the company launched the long-awaited <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> during the period — albeit to a more muted critical response than the franchise's beloved original trilogy. Nintendo has so far made no announcement on how that game has fared.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Game Business reports that US Switch 2 sales over the holiday period were down around 35% versus the Switch 1's sales performance back in 2017. In the UK, a similar comparison saw Switch 2 lagging Switch 1 by 16%. Even in Nintendo's homeland of Japan, Switch 2 holiday sales couldn't match Switch 1, and were down by 5.5% over the year's final nine weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In France, 2025's final tally of Switch 2 sales was down by "over 30%" versus the amount Switch 1 notched up back in 2017, meanwhile.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While these numbers may take some of the shine off of a successful first year for Switch 2 overall, it's not all doom and gloom. Switch 2's lifetime sales in Japan are still above what Switch 1 managed in its first year, with less time on sale. And in the UK, Switch 1 continued to sell well enough that it made up Switch 2's holiday sales deficit. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking ahead, Nintendo has a smattering of first-party games already planned for 2026, including Mario Tennis Fever, Yoshi and the Mysterious Book and Fire Emblem: Fortune's Weave, as well as Switch 2 upgrades for Super Mario Wonder and Animal Crossing: New Horizons. There's also the FromSoftware exclusive The Duskbloods to look forward to, and the promising-looking Pokémon Pokopia life sim.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Animal Crossing: New Horizons – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But as the Switch 2 prepares to celebrate its first anniversary in June, all eyes will be on Nintendo to roll out a truly new blockbuster entry in one of its biggest franchises. Back in 2017, Switch 1's first year was marked by the launch of both Super Mario Odyssey and The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild. Nintendo has not released a major new 3D Mario platformer since, while it will soon be three years since the arrival of 2023's The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 1's other top-selling titles include Super Smash Bros. Ultimate and Animal Crossing: New Horizons — and for now, there's no suggestion a big new entry in either franchise is forthcoming. Smash Bros. series boss Masahiro Sakurai has only just finished work on Kirby Air Riders, while Nintendo is opting to update New Horizons for Switch 2 this year, as previously mentioned. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Could we see a new 3D Mario in 2026? Nine years on from Super Mario Odyssey, now feels like the right time. And then there's Pokémon, which celebrates its 30th anniversary next month. Could we get a glimpse soon of the series' long-awaited 10th generation? The arrival of these titles would certainly help Switch 2 keep its momentum, following last year's explosive launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-source-blames-switch-2-holiday-sales-slowdown-on-the-economic-landscape-and-the-absence-of-a-major-western-game-despite-the-release-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows for PS5 Is Back to Its Lowest Price Yet at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-for-ps5-is-back-to-its-lowest-price-yet-at-amazon</link>
            <guid>1400842</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">These next few months of winter are a great time to settle in with big games until spring arrives. Recently, Amazon's been offering some great discounts on a variety of options to help you stock up your library this January for a little less than usual. Among some of the games on sale right now is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> for PS5 (<a href="https://zdcs.link/QPx3MD?object_uuid=1cc99e98-64c5-4d89-93be-1f57a3552d72&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0D47WTKPM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it here at Amazon</a>), which has dropped back to its <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0D47WTKPM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lowest price so far</a> of $34.99 at the retailer.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Assassin’s Creed Shadows (PS5) for $34.99</h2><div catalogid="160be1b0-9cc7-4c95-b743-858848ce966d" id="234293"><div id="234293" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Assassin’s Creed Shadows - Limited Edition (Amazon Exclusive), PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This makes for a huge 50% discount from its usual list price of $69.99, which is an excellent offer to make a move on. This limited edition Amazon Exclusive copy also comes with the Sekiryu Character Pack, which gets you a gear and weapon set for Naoe, the Sekiryu Beast​, and a Dragon Tooth trinket alongside the base game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We think it's a game well worth picking up, too. Our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-review">review</a> gave it an 8/10 score, with writer Jarrett Green saying it, "takes a flashing blade to the series’ established norms, trimming them to a more precise form in lieu of chopping them down outright."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The review continues on to say that, "Combat is aggressive and requires more intentional parrying and skill management than in the past, and exploring the gorgeous provinces of Sengoku-period Japan is encouraged thanks to the revamped map that deemphasizes collecting icons and checking off lists." Not to mention, "Naoe and Yasuke are well-realized and memorable protagonists, even though most of the story they drive follows pretty predictable paths."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If it's been on your radar, now is a great time to grab it while Amazon still has it on sale. Looking for even more options that are discounted right now? Amazon's also offering deals on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-delightful-astro-bot-for-ps5-is-back-to-its-best-price-at-amazon-and-walmart">Astro Bot</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-slashes-50-off-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-as-a-little-new-years-treat">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a>. And outside of Amazon, you can <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-has-dropped-to-just-40-in-the-new-year-sales">save on Battlefield 6 right now at Walmart, too</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 8, 2026 2:55 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-for-ps5-is-back-to-its-lowest-price-yet-at-amazon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>