<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:44:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster Release Date and Features Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-release-date-and-features-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-release-date-and-features-revealed.1141206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster-release-date-and-features-revealed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Time for a SHODAN.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/system-shock-2-25th-anniversary-remaster">System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster</a> launches on June 26, 2025, developer Nightdive Studios has announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The modernized version of the much-loved, 1999 sci-fi horror action role-playing game is set for release on PC and, for the first time, consoles. Expect a launch on Windows PC via Steam, GOG, the Epic Games Store, and the Humble Bundle Store, and on PlayStation 4 and 5, Xbox One and Series X and S, and Nintendo Switch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nightdive Studios rebuilt System Shock 2 for modern platforms using its proprietary KEX Engine. As you’d expect, it has improved visuals, enhanced gameplay, improved performance, cross-play co-op multiplayer, and mod support, among other modern video game features.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb on System Shock 2:</p><blockquote>Set 42 years after the events of the first System Shock, antagonist SHODAN and her army of merciless mutants infest the starship Von Braun. Players embody a soldier who awakes from cryo-sleep with cybernetic implants grafted to his flesh. As he sets out to unravel the horrifying mystery of the derelict starship, he’ll need to hone his upgradable skills and utilize powerful weapons and paranormal psionic abilities to survive the monstrous creations of SHODAN — and endure her narcissistic god complex. </blockquote><h2 data-cy="title2">System Shock 2: 25th Anniversary Remaster features:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Unknowable Horrors, In High Definition:</strong> Completely remastered visuals, extending to cutscenes and character and weapons models, with up to 4K 144 FPS support on PC and up to 120 FPS on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S</li><li><strong>Might As Well Make Your Death Comfortable:</strong> The game includes settings for an adjustable FOV, post-processing effects, and ultra-widescreen support</li><li><strong>Armed Forces:</strong> Choose from an O.S.A., Marine, or Navy background to experiment with different playstyles</li><li><strong>Misery Loves Company:</strong> Drag your friends into the hell that is the Von Braun starship in cross-play co-op multiplayer</li><li><strong>Interface This:</strong> Play from the comfort of your couch with gamepad support, then celebrate with an ice-cold medical stim when you unlock 50 new Trophies/Achievements</li><li><strong>If You Want Something Done Right:</strong> Full mod support on PC and the ability to implement community-made missions at launch</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>