<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 19:37:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpongeBob Tower Defense Codes (March 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/spongebob-tower-defense-codes-march-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spongebob-tower-defense-codes-march-2025.1144530/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/spongebob-tower-defense-codes-march-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Redeem these codes to help you protect Bikini Bottom!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for SpongeBob Tower Defense codes? This is where we'll serve them up! You won't find any Krabby Patties here, but you <em>will</em> find working codes that you can redeem for double XP, coins, chests, conches, and more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Working SpongeBob Tower Defense Codes (March 2025)</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below are all the active codes we've found for SpongeBob TD as of this month:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>DoubleIt</strong> - (2) x2 EXP, (2) x2 Gems, (2) x2 Coins</li><li><strong>LetsRide</strong> - 10 Magic Conches</li><li><strong>PiratesLife4Me</strong> - 25 Epic Chests</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Expired SpongeBob Tower Defense Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, you've missed the chance to use the codes below, as they've now expired:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>StacksonStacks</li><li>WPatchChat</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem SpongeBob TD Codes</strong></h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/25/spongebob-tower-defense-1742901438704.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Log in to the SpongeBob Tower Defense experience on Roblox</li><li>You'll need to play the game until you <strong>reach Level 10</strong> before you can unlock the codes feature</li><li>On the <strong>left</strong> side of the screen, you'll see several colorful boxes</li><li>The <strong>purple box with the clam icon</strong> on the bottom left corner is for codes</li><li>Click Codes and then copy and paste your code into the box</li><li>Redeem it and enjoy the rewards!</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My SpongeBob TD Code Working?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are two main reasons why your code might not be working when you submit it. Some codes are for Roblox are case-sensitive, so you'll want to make sure you're copying it directly from this article and pasting it in. We test each and every one of the codes before adding them here, to make sure they're working. Just be sure when you are copying them from here, that you're not accidentally including any extra spaces. If one has snuck in there, just remove them and try the code again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're taking them directly from the article, and they're <em>still</em> not working, the other possibility is they're expired. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More SpongeBob Tower Defense Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We check daily for new Roblox codes, so be sure to come back here regularly to see if new SpongeBob TD codes have dropped. Alternatively, you can drop by the <a href="https://discord.gg/krustykrew" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Krabby Krew Discord server</a> and scan for codes yourself. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is SpongeBob Tower Defense in Roblox?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox has its fair share of Tower Defense games, and even SpongeBob is included in the action. Whether you choose to play as Sponge, Patrick, or Squidward, you'll need to protect Bikini Bottom at all costs. Just like other TD games, you'll unlock new units, pick your favorites, and unleash them on waves of enemies as they try to attack. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Coziest LEGO Animal Crossing Set Just Hit an All-Time Low Price on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-animal-crossing-set-deal-amazon-spring-sale-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-coziest-lego-animal-crossing-set-just-hit-an-all-time-low-price-on-amazon.1144527/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-animal-crossing-set-deal-amazon-spring-sale-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Miniature K.K. Slider and Isabelle included.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Animal Crossing: New Horizons is one of my overall favorite games. I first started playing it back in 2020 like everyone else and have been started up a new island several times since then. The series is just so cozy and stress-free, and LEGO has done a great job of capturing that aesthetic. LEGO has released quite a few Animal Crossing sets as it continues to build up the<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-lego-nintendo-sets"> LEGO Nintendo brand</a>, but the one that I personally like the most has just dropped to its lowest ever price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The LEGO K.K.'s Concert in the Plaza set has dropped down to only $41.20 as part of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/amazon-spring-deal-days">Amazon Spring Deal Days Sale</a>. That's a 48% discount that drops the price lower than we've ever seen it before.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Best LEGO Animal Crossing Deal at Amazon Today</h2><div catalogid="0bdc76fd-be10-44de-9f3f-c12803224a29" id="217094"><div id="217094" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> LEGO Animal Crossing K.K.’s Concert in The Plaza</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This LEGO Animal Crossing set was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-lego-sets-august-2024-and-beyond">first released back in August 2024</a> alongside the Fly with Dodo Airlines set and various new LEGO Mario options. Tthe price has only recently started to drop, and with this discount it's <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0CV2F9R81" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lower than it has ever been before</a> on Amazon. It's unlikely we will see a lower price than this, even for Prime Day or Black Friday, so right now is a great time to buy if you've already been considering it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The set itself is only 550 pieces, so it can be easily put together in an afternoon. The centerpiece of the set is the classic Plaza and Resident services where Tom Nook is usually located, but it also comes with K.K's driveable camper van, a café, and a little tree permanently stuck in fall. You also get a little minifigure K.K. Slider (guitar included), Isabelle, and Audie. Although <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/animal-crossing-new-horizons/K.K._Slider_Song_List_and_Requests_Guide">K.K. Slider songs</a> are not included, you could always have them play in the background while you put it together.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">See more LEGO Animal Crossing sets</h3><h2 data-cy="title2">Are There Any Upcoming LEGO Animal Crossing Sets in 2025?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO has been fairly consistent in releasing new Nintendo sets each year. Last year there were several months where new LEGO Animal Crossing sets came out, and most recently we had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-lego-sets-for-january-2025-grogu-and-more">three new sets arrive in January 2025</a>. That being said, there are currently no new Animal Crossing sets that have been announced for this year. More may arrive in the second half of the year, but right now, there are still only 10 sets featured on the <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/themes/animal-crossing" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LEGO Animal Crossing page</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 25, 2025 5:25 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>