<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:12:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Investigating Star Wars Jedi: Survivor Issues on PlayStation 5 Pro]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-investigating-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues-on-playstation-5-pro</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-investigating-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues-on-playstation-5-pro.1039299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-investigating-star-wars-jedi-survivor-issues-on-playstation-5-pro<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA is currently investigating issues with the PlayStation 5 Pro version of Star Wars Jedi: Survivor but fell short of revealing when fans who spent $699.99 on Sony's latest console can expect a fix.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following reports yesterday that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-star-wars-jedi-survivor-among-several-games-with-ps5-pro-issues">Star Wars Jedi: Survivor was one of several games with issues on PS5 Pro</a>, alongside the likes of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6, Silent Hill 2, and Alan Wake 2, EA has confirmed it is at least aware of the issue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We’re aware of issues with Star Wars Jedi: Survivor on PlayStation 5 Pro and are actively investigating," it said on <a href="https://x.com/EAStarWars/status/1858635462577172846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Game Enhanced for PS5 Pro So Far</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cb9iM1N9Bz8&amp;t=406s&amp;ab_channel=DigitalFoundry" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry</a> discovered what it called "severe image quality problems" in the PS5 Pro version of Star Wars Jedi: Survivor. "There are severe image quality concerns when elements like foliage interact with ray tracing," it said. "The end result is a strobing image quality downgrade that makes this Pro patch difficult to recommend."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PS5 Pro arrived November 7 as Sony's now standard mid-generation upgrade. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-among-over-50-ps5-pro-enhanced-games-confirmed-by-sony-to-be-ready-for-launch">More than 50 games received PS5 Pro specific patches</a> upon its launch but, as this list includes Alan Wake 2 and Black Ops 6 among others receiving complaints, it's worth proceeding with caution.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-pro-review">In our 7/10 review of the PS5 Pro</a>, IGN said: "The PlayStation 5 Pro is an impressive console with noticeable boosts in performance and graphics for games that take advantage of its powerful hardware. But for $700, you’ll need to think twice about whether or not the upgrade is worth the price tag."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Sony in Talks to Buy Kadokawa, Owner of Elden Ring and Dark Souls Developer FromSoftware]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/report-sony-in-talks-to-buy-kadokawa-owner-of-elden-ring-and-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-sony-in-talks-to-buy-kadokawa-owner-of-elden-ring-and-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware.1039173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/report-sony-in-talks-to-buy-kadokawa-owner-of-elden-ring-and-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Wants to add to its entertainment portfolio.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony is reportedly in talks to buy Kadokawa, whose subsidiary FromSoftware is behind smash hit <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a>, the Dark Souls and Armored Core games, and PlayStation exclusive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/bloodborne">Bloodborne</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/sony-talks-buy-media-powerhouse-behind-elden-ring-sources-say-2024-11-19/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reuters</a> reports that Sony is looking to add to its entertainment portfolio. Kadokawa’s business extends into areas that fit into Sony’s broader entertainment offering, which includes anime, manga, TV, and film. Kadokawa is a prolific publisher of anime, and Sony already owns anime streamers Crunchyroll and Funimation. As well as FromSoftware, Kadokawa owns Danganronpa developer Spike Chunsoft, Octopath Traveler developer Acquire, and RPG Maker and Pixel Game Maker developer Gotcha Gotcha Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Talks between Sony and Kadokawa are reportedly ongoing. If the talks are successful, Reuters said, a deal could be signed in the coming weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony and Kadokawa declined to comment when asked by Reuters.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN FromSoftware Game Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Kadokawa is the majority owner of FromSoftware, with around 70% of the company. Sony already owns around 14% of FromSoftware, with Tencent owning around 16%. FromSoftware has yet to announce its next game to follow this year’s Elden Ring DLC, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Piers Harding-Rolls, Research Director at Ampere Analysis, told IGN that news of a potential deal isn’t that surprising. "Sony’s interest in Kadokawa’s games publisher FromSoftware was made more concrete in 2022 when it acquired a ~14% share of the company following up on its long-time collaboration with the company," Harding-Rolls said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"At the time, Sony mentioned a broader interest in cross-media development of anime and games IP to support its other media businesses. So, in that sense any deal for the parent company Kadokawa, which also operates extensively in manga and anime, is a natural extension of this earlier deal. These other areas align nicely with Sony’s anime businesses.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The market conditions for acquisitions have changed dramatically over the last two years but Sony will always be looking for opportunities that can fuel its growth and that bolster its IP portfolio, and that represent value. There may also be a defensive element to this move. FromSoftware is an important partner for Sony’s games business, and it will not want a competitor taking control of Kadokawa and potentially disrupting that relationship. It helps that Kadokawa is also active in areas which are a strong fit with Sony’s wider business."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For Sony, its gaming business has already suffered significant layoffs this year and the closure of multiple studios, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-says-it-should-have-done-user-testing-and-internal-evaluation-earlier-on-concord">Concord developer Firewalk</a>. In February, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-significant-playstation-layoffs-affecting-900-staff-london-studio-to-close"><u>it announced a</u> <u>round of layoffs</u></a> affecting 900 staff, or about 8% of its global PlayStation workforce. The layoffs impacted a number of PlayStation studios, including Insomniac, Naughty Dog, Guerrilla, and Firesprite, but PlayStation's London studio was hit hardest with a notice of closure. Since then, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/destiny-developer-bungie-cuts-220-staff-some-of-the-most-difficult-changes-weve-ever-had-to-make-as-a-studio">Sony-owned Bungie has also suffered devastating cuts</a> as Destiny 2 struggles to find commercial success.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>