<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:12:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Summer 2025 State of Play Breaks Viewing Record for Sony]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/summer-2025-state-of-play-breaks-viewing-record-for-sony</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/summer-2025-state-of-play-breaks-viewing-record-for-sony.1209195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/summer-2025-state-of-play-breaks-viewing-record-for-sony<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The bumper State of Play June 2025 showcase set a peak concurrent viewership record for Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony kicked off the summer reveal season with a bang, presenting a smorgasbord of new games to whet our appetites going into Summer Games Fest Week, including peeks at <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-june-2025-everything-announced"><u>007 First Light</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls">Marvel Tokon: Fighting Souls</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles"><u>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/romeo-is-a-dead-man"><u>Romeo is a Dead Man</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-f"><u>Silent Hill f</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to <a href="https://streamscharts.com/news/sony-playstations-state-play-record" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Streams Charts</a>, this week's State of Play peaked at over 2.2 million live viewers for the first time in the series’ history. According to data compiled by the website, State of Play now ranks as the third most-popular gaming or tech showcase of 2025 by peak concurrent viewership. Only two Nintendo Direct presentations pulled in bigger numbers (understandably, Nintendo's Switch 2 reveal is top by a long way).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As spotted by <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/06/ps5s-brilliant-new-state-of-play-breaks-records-for-sony" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Push Square</u></a>, the State of Play wasn't Sony's most-watched livestream ever — that honor goes to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-reveal-everything-announced-all-games"><u>PS5 reveal event</u></a>, which currently boasts <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RkC0l4iekYo&amp;pp=0gcJCbIJAYcqIYzv" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>44 million views</u></a>. The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/horizon-forbidden-west">Horizon Forbidden West</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Forbidden Dawn</a> presentations were also astonishingly popular, clocking up <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lq594XmpPBg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>15</u></a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4-FCsiF5x4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>10</u></a> million views, respectively. But Tuesday's livestream remains hands-down the most popular State of Play showing ever.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The State of Play focused on third-party — and particularly Japanese developers — with strong announcements from the likes of Capcom, Grasshopper Manufacture, Konami, ArtPlay, Square Enix, and Team Ninja. There were surprisingly few first-party titles in the presentation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also felt very much like this year's summer presentation was focused on committed gamers, too. There seemed to be a propensity of action games, many of which will likely come with mature/18+ ratings. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Need to catch up? We've got you covered — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-june-2025-everything-announced"><u>here's everything announced at PlayStation State of Play 2025</u></a> earlier this week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2's Best-Selling eShop Launch Games Revealed — and Those $10 Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom Upgrades Are Right Up ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-launch-games-revealed-and-those-10-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-upgrades-are-right-up-there</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-launch-games-revealed-%E2%80%94-and-those-10-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-upgrades-are-right-up.1209192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-launch-games-revealed-and-those-10-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-upgrades-are-right-up-there<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">24 hours into the life of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, it's time to look at what's selling best on the new console's eShop — and get a sense of just how popular those rather minimal-looking Zelda upgrades have been.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Top of the Switch 2 eShop charts at the time of writing is, of course, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> — the console's flagship launch title that many (most?) owners will have picked up alongside the console. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's no surprise to see this in the top spot, and anyone who bought the Switch 2 bundle with Mario Kart World included will have contributed to its placing here, as you'll have had to redeem an eShop code and download its digital version.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Next up, perhaps surprisingly, is Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition. Developer CD Projekt will no doubt be delighted to see its latest game doing so well on Switch 2, after it previously skipped Nintendo's last-gen console. With the power to run Cyberpunk's Night City now available, Switch 2 owners look to have jumped at the chance to catch up with the open-world RPG. Earlier this week, IGN chatted with CD Projekt to find out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-cd-projekt-red-got-cyberpunk-2077-running-on-switch-2">how the developer managed to get Cyberpunk 2077 working on Switch 2</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Third is Nintendo's own <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Switch 2 Welcome Tour</a>. This is the $10 collection of mini-games and tech demos that many fans believe should have been offered for free (and after an hour with the game myself last night, I am inclined to agree). Part instruction manual, part interactive museum exhibit, Welcome Tour is at least fairly cheap. (Just remember <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-which-everyone-thinks-should-be-free-requires-95-of-accessories-and-a-4k-tv-for-100-completion">you'll need a camera and a separate controller/grip with GL/GR buttons to play everything included in it</a>.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The fourth best-selling game on the Switch 2 eShop right now is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a>, a game which you may not have heard of. This fast-paced sci-fi racer is an interesting addition to the console's launch line-up, as developer Shin'en Multimdia previously released the similar Fast RMX as a launch title for the original Switch, back in March 2017. Why is this series popular with Nintendo fans? Well, because it is essentially F-Zero. And without a new F-Zero from Nintendo anytime soon (if ever again), hardcore Nintendo fans love it.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Fast Fusion Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The fifth biggest game on the Switch 2 eShop is not actually a game, but an upgrade — yes, it's the $10 upgrade to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>. It's interesting to see this chart so highly, as Nintendo Switch Online subscribers do get this add-on included as part of their membership. But perhaps fans have decided they want it to keep? Or maybe they haven't realised. Regardless, the fact this upgrade is so popular clearly shows Nintendo was right to assume people would pay up for some improved visuals (something you get free in upgrades to other titles, such as Pokémon Scarlet and Violet), plus access to a new mobile app.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sixth on the Switch 2 eShop right now is Deltarune, which just launched its latest chapters this week. Seventh is the $10 upgrade pack for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild">Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> (as an older game, perhaps fewer people are still playing it compared to Tears of the Kingdom). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In eighth place is relaxing role-player Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition, while ninth place goes to Square Enix's Bravely Default Flying Fairy HD Remaster. This is followed by Yakuza 0 and Street Fighter 6 Years 1-2 Fighters Edition. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">After these, the full Switch 2 Editions of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom and Breath of the Wild sandwich Hitman World of Assassination. And lastly in the chart is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a>, whose Switch 2 version features a number of graphical upgrades. A $10 upgrade for this Harry Potter prequel RPG is also available if you owned the game on the original Switch.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Finally, here is the Switch 2 eShop launch day chart as a handy list:</h2><ol data-cy="list"><li>Mario Kart World</li><li>Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition</li><li>Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</li><li>Fast Fusion</li><li>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom - Upgrade Pack</li><li>Deltarune</li><li>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Upgrade Pack</li><li>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time</li><li>Bravely Default Flying Fairy HD Remaster</li><li>Yakuza 0</li><li>Street Fighter 6 Years 1-2 Fighters Edition</li><li>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom - Switch 2 Edition</li><li>Hitman: World of Assassination</li><li>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Switch 2 Edition</li><li>Hogwarts Legacy</li></ol><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Developer FromSoftware Concludes Server Maintenance Designed to Improve Matchmaking]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-developer-fromsoftware-concludes-server-maintenance-designed-to-improve-matchmaking</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-developer-fromsoftware-concludes-server-maintenance-designed-to-improve-matchmaking.1209141/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-developer-fromsoftware-concludes-server-maintenance-designed-to-improve-matchmaking<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> developer FromSoftware has concluded a fresh round of server maintenance designed to improve matchmaking.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">During the game’s launch weekend, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-matchmaking-not-working-fromsoftware-has-some-suggestions">FromSoftware acknowledged Elden Ring Nightreign matchmaking issues and offered suggestions to players affected</a>, including restarting the matchmaking process and, specifically on PlayStation 4 and 5, checking their NAT type.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, following server maintenance conducted on June 6 “to improve expedition matchmaking with an active Remembrance,” online functionalities have been restored, and fans are hoping for a better experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Thank you for your patience, Nightfarers,” <a href="https://x.com/ELDENRING/status/1930932964931645630" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FromSoftware said</a>. “Limveld awaits.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite these issues, Elden Ring Nightreign sold 3.5 million copies after just five days on sale. Elden Ring was a massive hit, selling 30 million since going on sale in 2022, and it seems unlikely that Nightreign will come close to matching that success. For better context, the Shadow of the Erdtree expansion sold 5 million copies within three days of its release in 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nightreign has also seen its Steam user review rating improve from 'mixed' to 'mostly positive.' Much of the initial negative sentiment revolved around Nightreign’s brutal solo experience, its lack of duos co-op, lack of voice chat, and other archaic mechanics.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But on Monday, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-patch-1011-nerfs-solo-mode-difficulty-fixes-bugs-and-makes-more-balance-changes">FromSoftware released a patch to make solo play much easier</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-duo-expeditions-on-the-way-fromsoftware-confirms-as-sales-jump-to-35-million">has confirmed Duos mode is on the way</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN FromSoftware Game Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So, what happens next? FromSoftware also said that in addition to the DLC releasing later this year, new additions will be “gradually implemented,” including enhanced fights against existing Nightlords starting this month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreigns-director-has-soloed-every-boss-without-relics-and-wants-players-to-know-its-very-possible-to-see-everything">Elden Ring Nightreign's director revealed he had soloed every boss without Relics</a>, and wanted players to know it's "very possible" to see everything.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve got plenty of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>Nightreign tips and tricks</u></a> to help you take down <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Nightlord_Boss_Guides"><u>all the eight Nightlord Bosses</u></a>, and if you’re wondering how to unlock the two locked <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/Nightfarers_-_List_of_Character_Classes"><u>Nightfarer Classes</u></a>, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Unlock_the_Revenant"><u>How to Unlock the Revenant</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Unlock_the_Duchess"><u>How to Unlock the Duchess</u></a>, plus <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring-nightreign/How_to_Change_Characters"><u>How to Change Characters</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening Hit Nearly 100,000 Concurrent Players on Steam — and It's Not Even Properly Out Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-hit-nearly-100000-concurrent-players-on-steam-and-its-not-even-properly-out-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-hit-nearly-100-000-concurrent-players-on-steam-%E2%80%94-and-its-not-even-properly-out-yet.1209138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-hit-nearly-100000-concurrent-players-on-steam-and-its-not-even-properly-out-yet<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dune-awakening"><u>Dune: Awakening</u></a> isn't even properly out yet, but it has already set a concurrent player record on Steam of almost 100,000 players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to Steam's official stats, Dune: Awakening peaked at 93,634 concurrent players yesterday, June 5, even though the game only released for "head start" (read: early access) players who bought either the $69.99 Deluxe Edition or the $89.99 Ultimate edition. For everyone else, the game goes live on June 10, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Concurrent players isn't the only metric we should use when measuring how successful a game is, of course, but it's a good starting point, even though it doesn't account for players on other platforms (not that Dune: Awakening is available on other platforms just yet; the PS5 and Xbox Series release will follow at a later date).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Historically, weekends are usually when most players opt to jump into a game, so it's possible Dune: Awakening will hit an even higher peak concurrent count before official launch on June 10. Of the thousands of games currently on sale on Steam, it's currently 195th in the chart of the highest-ever concurrent peaks. Not bad for a game that's not even out yet. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We haven't yet had chance to review Dune: Awakening, but we did have take an extended peek when the beta was live. "As a longtime fan of Dune, it also just feels so good to explore and learn more about a world that I’m quite fond of, and Funcom has clearly put a ton of effort into worldbuilding and lore, even despite taking quite a bit of creative liberty by placing Awakening within a parallel reality and canon than the books/movies," we wrote in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakenings-first-20-hours-are-damn-impressive-despite-loads-of-bugs-closed-beta-impressions"><u>IGN's Dune: Awakening closed beta impressions preview</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There are little details that have a massive impact on gameplay. I won’t go into spoilers, but this kind of attention to detail touches just about every aspect of the world, including the factions and characters you meet along the way, which should be a treat for any fan of the setting."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out details on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-dev-says-its-release-date-is-the-full-launch-and-while-theres-no-subscription-there-will-be-optional-dlcs"><u>the MMO's business model and post-launch plans</u></a>. We've also got the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dune-awakening-global-release-times-including-early-access-confirmed"><u>global release time schedule for Dune: Awakening</u></a> right here for you, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>