<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 11:18:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bend Studio Dev Says 'We Still Plan on Creating Cool S**t' After Sony Live Service Cancelation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bend-studio-dev-says-we-still-plan-on-creating-cool-st-after-sony-live-service-cancelation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bend-studio-dev-says-we-still-plan-on-creating-cool-s-t-after-sony-live-service-cancelation.1087149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bend-studio-dev-says-we-still-plan-on-creating-cool-st-after-sony-live-service-cancelation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">What next for PlayStation Studios?</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The developer of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/days-gone">Days Gone</a> has said it still plans to create “cool s**t” after parent company Sony canceled its unannounced live-service game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games">Sony canceled two unannounced live-service games that were in development at Bend Studio and Bluepoint Games</a>. The Bluepoint game was reportedly a live-service God of War game, according to Bloomberg’s <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lfvfm2febc2e" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Jason Schreier</u></a>. Bend Studio’s live-service game remains unknown.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A Sony spokesperson confirmed the cancellations to Bloomberg, adding that neither studio will be closed and that it will work with each to determine next projects.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony's live-service push has struggled significantly. While Arrowhead’s Helldivers 2 was a breakout hit, becoming the fastest-selling PlayStation Studios game of all time with 12 million copies sold in just 12 weeks, Sony’s other live-service games were either canceled or suffered disastrous launches.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, Sony’s Concord is one of the biggest video game disasters in PlayStation history, lasting just a couple of weeks before it was brought offline amid drastically low player numbers. Sony later decided to kill the game entirely and shut its developer. The Concord flop came after Sony had already canceled Naughty Dog’s The Last of Us multiplayer game. Last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-wouldve-tried-to-resist-sonys-live-service-push">former PlayStation executive Shuhei Yoshida said he would have tried to resist Sony’s controversial live-service video game push</a>, were he in the position of current Sony Interactive Entertainment Studio Business Group CEO Hermen Hulst.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://x.com/vikingdad278/status/1880403782976307623" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, Bend Studio community manager Kevin McAllister issued a short message to the developer's fans: “Thanks for the love and support everyone, especially to those that have reached out. P.S. We still plan on creating cool shit.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As it stands, Bend Studio's last release was 2019’s Days Gone on PlayStation 4. It launched on PC in 2021.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a recent financial call, Sony president, COO and CFO Hiroki Totoki said the company had learned lessons from both the record-breaking launch of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii"><u>Helldivers 2</u></a> earlier this year and Concord’s failure. On Concord specifically, Totoki said Sony should have run its development gates such as user testing or internal evaluation “much earlier than we did.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Currently we are still in the process of learning,” Totoki admitted. “Basically, with regards to new IP, of course you don’t know the result until you actually try it. So for our reflection, probably we need to have a lot of gates, including user testing or internal evaluation, and the timing of such gates, we need to bring them forward. We should have done those gates much earlier than we did.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The suggestion here from Totoki was that Sony should have noticed and reacted to Concord’s issues earlier in the development process, presumably so that it could have improved the game before launch — or canceled it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Totoki then went on to point fingers at Sony’s “siloed organization” and Concord’s release window, which may have caused cannibalisation. Concord launched in August, not long after smash hit Black Myth: Wukong hit PS5 and PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We have a siloed organization, so going beyond the boundaries of those organizations in terms of development and also sales, I think that could have been much smoother,” Totoki said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then going forward, in our own titles and in third-party titles, we do have many different windows. And we want to be able to select the right and optimal window so that we can deploy them on our own platform without cannibalisation, so that we can maximize our performance in terms of title launches.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">During the same financial call, Sony senior vice president for finance and IR Sadahiko Hayakawa compared the launches of Helldivers 2 and Concord, saying lessons learned would be shared throughout the business.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We launched two live-service games this year,” he said. “Helldivers 2 was a huge hit, while Concord ended up being shut down. We gained a lot of experience and learned a lot from both.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We intend to share the lessons learned from our successes and failures across our studios, including in the areas of title development management as well as the process of continually adding expanded content and scaling the service after its release so as to strengthen our development management system.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We intend to build on an optimum title portfolio during the current mid-range plan period that combines single-player games — which are our strengths and which have a higher predictability of becoming hits due to our proven IP — with live-service games that pursue upside while taking on a certain amount of risk upon release.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking to the future, a number of PlayStation live service games remain in the works, including Bungie’s Marathon, Guerrilla’s Horizon Online, and Haven Studio’s Fairgame$.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>