<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:06:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Know About James Gunn's DCU Video Game Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-know-about-james-gunn-dcu-video-games-rocksteady-batman-superman</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-know-about-james-gunns-dcu-video-game-plans.1246023/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a bird! It’s a plane! It’s the very first movie in James Gunn’s revamped DC Universe! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that Superman has hit theaters, James Gunn’s DC Universe is fully underway… Or is it? While Gunn has now released a movie, a TV show (Peacemaker), and an animated series (Creature Commandos) under his stewardship, there’s still a missing piece of the DC Universe puzzle: video games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunn told fans back in 2022 that his master plan for an interconnected DC Universe includes video games. But unlike on the movies and TV side of things, there have been no official announcements regarding what the first DC Universe video game will be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An absence of reveals doesn’t mean we don’t have a reasonably clear picture of what to expect, though. Across multiple interviews and press events, Gunn and co-studio head Peter Safran have explained their plans, including the fact that while they don’t technically oversee Warner Bros.’ gaming division, there’s now a much deeper collaboration between WB Games and DC Studios that could dramatically alter the way future DC video games are made. With that in mind, let’s analyze what the future of games will look like in the new DCU era.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gunn Takes Over DC</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The first time we learned that video games factored into Gunn’s DC plans was shortly after he and producer Peter Safran were announced as co-heads of DC Studios on October 25, 2022. While answering fan questions on X, Gunn responded to one user who asked if games would be connected to the DCU alongside films and TV. To this, he <a href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1596921811374964736" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>simply replied, “Yes.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It wouldn’t be until a few months later that <a href="https://www.dc.com/blog/2023/01/31/the-next-generation-of-dc-movies-and-tv-has-arrived" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Gunn revealed</u></a> what movies and shows were in development as part of Chapter 1: Gods and Monsters, which is the DCU’s equivalent of the MCU’s Phase 1. And while video games were conspicuously missing from the Chapter 1 roadmap, Gunn told members of the press, “Television, movies, and games all intertwine within the same universe. We’re going to cast actors who are going to be able to play the characters in [animation and TV], as well as in other things.” This was the first clear indication from Gunn that video games were indeed a part of his plans for the DCU.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Confirmed DCU Projects</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">One important thing to know is that Gunn’s job as head of DC Studios doesn’t include control over any of Warner Bros’ video game studios, which include developers like Avalanche Software (Hogwarts Legacy), NetherRealm Studios (Mortal Kombat), Rocksteady Studios (Batman Arkham), and TT Games (Lego). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Under the current Warner Bros. Discovery corporate structure, Warner Bros. Games exists separately from DC Studios and is overseen by Warner Bros. Discovery's CEO of global streaming and gaming, JB Perrette. But after Gunn and Safran were named DC co-heads in 2022, Perrette appears to be deferring to the new DC bosses when it comes to matters of comic book video games.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>The Walls Break Down Between WB Games and DC Studios</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/warner-bros-video-games-live-services-dc-game-of-thrones-1235888944/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Variety</u></a> in 2024, Perrette revealed, “Frankly, there hasn’t been as close a relationship between the studio and the games business as there should have been. And James [Gunn] is actually a gamer, so having someone who’s passionate about it is super helpful.” Perrette added that the games departments are now “actively working with [Gunn and Safran] on the core franchises within the DC Universe.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Based on this interview, it appears there was once a wall that divided WB’s gaming division from the movie and TV studios. And according to Perrette, it was only after Gunn and Safran took over DC Studios that a newfound sense of collaboration was achieved.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>“Whether it’s NetherRealm or whether it’s Rocksteady, [we] sit with them and talk about characters and stories that we’re interested in and that they’re interested in.”</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This dividing wall was confirmed a year later during a DC Studios Presentation held on February 24, 2025. During the event, James Gunn and Peter Safran confirmed Perrette’s statements regarding the separation between the two WB divisions and how that relationship has changed since they took over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We work incredibly closely with JB Perrette, who runs that division, and it’s really the first time ever it’s been this way at Warner Bros,” Safran confirmed. “It’s been great, and we’ve enjoyed it enormously. Everything had been so siloed, and now that’s completely broken down, and it’s been great. Because it also applies to consumer products and experiences, and everything that DC touches runs up through us now, which is awesome.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“James [Gunn] and I sit with literally the guys that run the studios underneath JB,” Safran added. “Whether it’s NetherRealm or whether it’s Rocksteady, [we] sit with them and talk about characters and stories that we’re interested in and that they’re interested in.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s funny that Safran mentions Rocksteady, as it was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rocksteady-reportedly-working-on-single-player-batman-game-monolith-productions-wonder-woman-in-trouble"><u>reported earlier this year</u></a> that the studio is developing a new single-player Batman game. While it may be too soon to tell, at least according to Gunn and Safran, there will likely be some input from their side of things at DC Studios.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We see designs for the projects in their very earliest stages,” Gunn said at the event. “When they’re talking about what the story might be, we say, ‘Well, maybe you want to go this way because we’re planning on maybe doing something with this character and so forth and so on,’ and help deal with that.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/16/screenshot-2025-07-14-at-12-01-37-pm-1752682573383.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Gunn replies to fans on X. Credit: X.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Does this mean Gunn will be fully in charge of the next Rocksteady Batman game? Not quite. Gunn confirmed that <a href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1597360208824569856" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>“not all”</u></a> games will be connected to the DCU’s overarching story when another fan on X shared their concern about losing standalone experiences like Rocksteady’s Arkham series. So, depending on where Rocksteady wants to take its next single-player Batman game, there’s a chance it could be incorporated into the DCU, or treated as a separate universe like Matt Reeves’ The Batman movies.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Furthermore, Perrette said in the aforementioned Variety interview that WB’s game studios will still be making projects based on what’s best for the studios and gamers, saying, “We’re not going to launch a Superman game purely because we feel obligated. We have to do something that makes sense for the gaming strategy and for fans and for the consumer.”</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How James Gunn’s DCU Is Already Shaping Games</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if DC’s full gaming plans remain a mystery, we’re already seeing Gunn’s unified vision for DC play out in several games right now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our characters can move in and out of animation or jump into a game or onto the big screen, but they will remain consistent throughout: same character, same history, same actor,” Gunn said during the <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/james-gunn-creature-commandos-dc-studios-annecy-1235922754/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>press tour for Creature Commandos</u></a> last year — a couple months after Peacemaker was added to Mortal Kombat 1 as a DLC character on February 28, 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as Gunn said, NetherRealm enlisted John Cena to reprise his TV and movie role as Peacemaker in Mortal Kombat 1. Not only is his likeness and design identical to the version of the character that appears in the HBO series and The Suicide Squad movie, but even his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uO_skSl0MDI" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Victory Pose </u></a>in Mortal Kombat 1 is a direct reference to Peacemaker’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mrr3UNALww" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>glam rock-themed opening credits</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Similarly, this month’s Superman-themed content for Fortnite features skins for Superman, Mr. Terrific, and The Engineer, which are all based on the likenesses of their movie counterparts. So, rather than a comic-book version of these characters, you’re playing as David Corenswet’s Superman, Edi Gathegi’s Mr. Terrific, and Maria Gabriela de Faria’s Engineer. Like Peacemaker, it seems that any appearance by a DCU character in a video game will be identical to their movie and TV counterpart, just as Gunn promised (with the exception of those standalone projects Gunn also promised, of course.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Since taking the reins, our true north has been to bring DC film, TV, animation, and gaming into alignment under a single banner and bring a sense of unity and consistency into the DCU as a whole,” Gunn said ahead of the premiere of Creature Commandos. “This frees us to create a range of products that are diverse and compelling, and deliver great stand-alone entertainment experiences on every medium, while also being part of a larger story that we’re telling within our unified DCU.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s been a rough couple of years for DC games under Warner Bros.. Between the closing of Monolith Software and the cancellation of a Wonder Woman video game, to Rocksteady’s Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League’s lackluster release, the future of DC video games appeared to be in major flux. Warner Bros. even considered<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-wb-discovery-looking-to-sell-off-games-other-divisions-to-prevent-total-breakup" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u> selling off its gaming business entirely.</u></a> </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And while WB Games’ fortunes have changed with the massive success of games like Hogwarts Legacy, there’s still no official word yet on the future of DC video games. But it’s clear based on statements from Gunn, Safran, and Perrette that Warner Bros. Games and DC Studios are collaborating deeply when it comes to any upcoming video game starring DC’s caped heroes. Although the basic expectation is that if a character from DC’s movies and shows appears in a game, it will feature the same actor, the full plans for DC video games, especially from developers like Rocksteady, remain to be seen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out our full list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-dc-movies-and-tv-shows-2025-release-dates-and-beyond">upcoming DC movies and TV shows</a>, as well as our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/superman-2025-review-james-gunn-david-corenswet-rachel-brosnahan-nicholas-hoult">Superman review</a> for our full DC coverage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-we-know-about-james-gunn-dcu-video-games-rocksteady-batman-superman]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Addresses Concerns Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds Will Be Sold As a Game-Key Card on Nintendo Switch 2, Confirms The 'Full Base Game' Will Be Included]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included-on-the-64gb-cartridge</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included.1246020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sonic-racing-crossworlds"><u>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds </u></a>will be sold as a physical Nintendo Switch game with the "full base game" included on a 64GB cartridge.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 2 Game-Key Cards are physical cards that contain a key to download your chosen game. That means there’s no actual game data on the card you insert into your Switch 2, and you’ll instead need to download the full game once the card is inserted. Every Game-Key Card case should be appropriately labeled on the front of the box, but the practice <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-key-cards-a-little-disheartening-the-thing-remastered-dev-says"><u>has been troubling some gamers</u></a>, especially those who prefer to physically own their games, not just license them digitally.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is particularly good news for Sonic fans because there had been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1lmsid4/sonic_racing_crossworlds_might_be_a_game_key_card/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>confusion and conflicting reports about CrossWorlds in particular</u></a>. Now, however, Sega has removed all doubt, confirming in a new <a href="https://www.sega.com/news/sonic-racing-crossworlds-nintendo-switch-2-faq" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>FAQ</u></a> that "the physical version will feature the full base game on a 64GB cartridge." </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The FAQ also confirmed that crossplay will be available for Nintendo Switch 2 players, progress will carry over from the original Switch to the newer edition, and yes, there will be a $10 upgrade pack for anyone hoping to upgrade to the Switch 2 version in the future. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">By contrast, Square Enix was criticised by fans earlier this week for confirming there would be "no upgrade path" for its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-1-2-hd-2d-remake-first-impressions-classic-dq-has-never-looked-so-good">Dragon Quest 1 &amp; 2 HD-2D Remake</a> on Switch 2, and that its save files would not be compatible across platforms. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega has said CrossWorlds will feature a huge roster of over playable characters, if you include DLC. Characters you’d expect to see, such as Sonic, Dr. Eggman, Knuckles, Shadow, and Tails are present and correct, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-racing-crossworlds-reveals-nickelodeon-collaboration-that-adds-spongebob-squarepants-avatar-and-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-guest-characters"><u>but now you can add the likes of SpongeBob SquarePants, Avatar, and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles into the mix</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">CrossWorlds is, of course, going up against Switch 2 exclusive kart game Mario Kart World, which has so far resisted adding guest characters from outside Nintendo's portfolio. Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is set for release on both the Switch and the Switch 2, so it looks like we’ll be set for some old-fashioned Mario vs. Sonic kart racing rivalry when Sega's effort launches in September.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently went <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-racing-crossworlds-hands-on-preview"><u>hands-on with Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</u></a> and came away impressed. “It’s a vibe,” we said, “and one that I’ve enjoyed and will look forward to drifting through.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/sega-addresses-concerns-sonic-racing-crossworlds-will-be-sold-as-a-game-key-card-on-nintendo-switch-2-confirms-the-full-base-game-will-be-included-on-the-64gb-cartridge]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox's New Safety Features Include an AI That Will Guess Your Age Based on a Video Selfie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie.1246017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The company claims new features will help keep teens on platform, where conversations can be moderated.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox has announced a new range of safety features directed specifically at teenagers ages 13-17, including a new age estimation technology that uses AI to guess a user's age based on a video selfie they submit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/07/advancing-safety-on-roblox-with-age-based-communication" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Today's announcement</a> reveals several new features being implemented in Roblox that the company claims will improve teen and child safety on its platform. At the core of the announcement are new features specifically for teens ages 13-17, giving them more freedom on the platform than younger children but still less than adults. Teens will be able to designate "trusted connections" on Roblox, with whom they will be able to chat on the platform without filters. Per Roblox, the goal is to better monitor conversations teens are having on Roblox rather than having them lured to third-party platforms where unmonitored conversations could become inappropriate.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Trusted connections are intended to be set between users who know one another well, and if a teen intends to set someone 18+ as a trusted connection, they can only do so using a QR code scanner or a contact importer.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the past, Roblox has relied on the submission of a government ID verifying that users are 13+ or 18+ to unlock certain platform chat features. However, it is now implementing an alternative verification method. Individuals can submit a "video selfie" to Roblox, and an AI will determine if it believes the person in question is 13+ by analyzing it against "a large, diverse dataset." Google began <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/02/12/google-to-test-using-ai-to-determine-users-ages.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">testing a similar feature earlier this year</a>, as did <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/09/instagram-teen-accounts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meta the year prior</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to these changes, Roblox is also adding new tools such as online status controls, a do not disturb mode, and parental controls for parents who have linked their accounts to a teenage's account.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Roblox has long been in an uncomfortable spotlight regarding its handling of children's safety. In 2018, it made headlines when <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-bans-players-who-gang-raped-a-seven-year-olds-avatar" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a mother reported her seven-year-old daughter's Roblox character was violently sexually assaulted</a> by other players in-game, and separately a six-year-old girl playing Roblox was <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2018/06/05/girl-6-invited-sex-room-playing-childrens-video-game-roblox-7605376/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reportedly invited into a "sex room"</a>. In 2021, People Make Games published a report on the ways in which <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_gXlauRB1EQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Roblox's business model allegedly exploits child labor</a>. In 2022, Roblox faced <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/lawsuit-accuses-roblox-of-enabling-sexual-exploitation" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a San Francisco lawsuit accusing it</a> of enabling the financial and sexual exploitation of a 10-year-old girl. In 2023, it was sued both for <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-accused-of-facilitating-illegal-gambling-ring-for-minors" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">allegedly facilitating</a> "an illegal gambling ecosystem" and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-faces-new-lawsuit-claiming-it-lacks-child-safety-measures" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more generally</a> for having lax child safety protocols that allegedly led to financial loss and children's exposure to adult content. Just last year, Bloomberg published a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">damning report highlighting the prevalence of child predators on the platform</a>. That same year, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-reported-over-13000-incidents-to-the-national-center-for-missing-and-exploited-children-in-2023" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the platform claimed</a> it reported over 13,000 incidents of child exploitation to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children in the year 2023, resulting in the arrest of 24 individuals who allegedly preyed on children through the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Safety has always been foundational to everything we do at Roblox," said Roblox chief safety officer Matt Kaufman in a statement alongside today's new feature news. "Our goal is to lead the world in safety and civility for online gaming. We are dedicated to supporting experiences that are both deeply engaging, and empowering for players of all ages, while continuously innovating how users connect and interact."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/robloxs-new-safety-features-include-an-ai-that-will-guess-your-age-based-on-a-video-selfie]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala Are the FC 26 Cover Stars — and Fans Are Now Wondering if the 'Madden Curse' Has Spread to Soccer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-%E2%80%94-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer.1246014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s that time of the year again and EA has revealed the cover stars of its next soccer game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ea-sports-fc-26">FC 26</a>. But this go around there’s concern that the infamous 'Madden curse' has spread to EA’s soccer series, after joint cover stars Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala suffered significant injuries that left them facing lengthy spells on the sidelines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It’s really nice to share this moment with Jamal, as a reflection of how far we’ve come,” said Real Madrid and England midfield star Bellingham in a comment accompanying the announcement.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I remember our times rooming together in the England Youth team, we’d play the game all the time. Where I’m from, everyone knows the game, everyone plays it and talks about it so much. I’m grateful to be given the opportunity to be on the cover again.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And here’s a comment from Bayern Munich and Germany forward Musiala: “When I found out I’d be on the cover of FC, it was such a crazy feeling. I thought, how could I tell my little brother? He’s a big fan of the game, so this will be a nice surprise for him. It’s something I always wanted growing up and it’s such a big part of football culture. Who knows, maybe I can still beat Jude at FC.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The problem is, both players are injured and are set to miss a significant chunk of the next season. Let’s start with Bellingham. The 22-year-old just had surgery on a long-standing shoulder injury that’s set to keep him out of the game for up to four months. That means he’s going to miss the start of next season and may not return until November.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worse for Musiala, though. He suffered a horrible injury playing at the Club World Cup that rules him out for between four and five months. After breaking his leg and dislocating his ankle in the same incident, the 22-year-old is set for a long absence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All this means FC 26 launches in September with both its cover stars unable to play the game. One potentially won’t play again until 2026. Hardly ideal for the marketers at EA Sports, who must be wondering whether they are now cursed.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/17/image001-1752748823131.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Jude Bellingham and Jamal Musiala both face lengthy spells on the sidelines. Image credit: EA Sports.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Madden curse fan theory suggests any athlete who appears on the cover of Madden NFL suffers a downturn in their career, either from an injury or generally underperforming. The long-standing Madden curse most recently afflicted Madden NFL 25 cover star Christian McCaffrey of the San Francisco 49ers, who was shifted to the injured reserve list due to calf tightness and achilles tendinitis one month after he graced the cover of the latest American football entry from EA Sports, which arrived August 13, 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.cbssports.com/nfl/news/does-madden-nfl-cover-curse-still-exist-a-look-back-at-25-years-of-covers-after-christian-mccaffrey-nod/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>CBS Sports</u></a> analyzed the history of the Madden curse upon McCaffrey's announcement as 2024's cover star, deeming that, between 2000 and 2024, 58% of players struggled after appearing on the cover.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA’s FIFA series — now FC — has a long way to go before a ‘FIFA curse’ spreads online, but perhaps FC 26 has started something new. FC 26 launches across PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X and S, Xbox One, PC, Amazon Luna, Nintendo Switch, and Nintendo Switch 2 on September 26, 2025, with early access through the Ultimate Edition beginning September 19, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/jude-bellingham-and-jamal-musiala-are-the-fc-26-cover-stars-and-fans-are-now-wondering-if-the-madden-curse-has-spread-to-soccer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>