<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 06:36:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza Staff Had Tense Watermelon-Eating Session to Create the Nintendo Switch 2 Exclusive's Digging Sound, Producer Reveals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-staff-had-tense-watermelon-eating-session-to-create-the-nintendo-switch-2-exclusives-digging-sound-producer-reveals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananza-staff-had-tense-watermelon-eating-session-to-create-the-nintendo-switch-2-exclusives-digging-sound-producer-reveals.1305045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Released back in July for the Switch 2, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> lets you go bananas as Nintendo’s giant ape character Donkey Kong. Players can explore and find goodies by freely punching, smashing and digging their way through bizarre and colorful open-world levels. The game’s quirkiness and fruit-obsession extends to the varied sound effects — many of which were made by the staff themselves. Apparently, a lot of biting and eating was involved…</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a recently published interview with <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202509/50508" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Famitsu</u></a>, Donkey Kong Bananza’s producer Kenta Motokura explained: “The noise you hear when digging is actually the sound of someone eating watermelon. The sound team actually bought watermelons and recorded those sounds.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, apparently this was not exactly a relaxing snack break: “Since they couldn’t do many takes, the recording sessions were apparently very tense,” one of the game’s directors, Wataru Tanaka, revealed.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://www.ndw.jp/dkbananza-interview-250820/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Nintendo Dream Web</u></a>, sound director Naoto Kubo went into even more detail about the level of dedication that went into capturing and manipulating foley sounds to create Donkey Kong Bananza’s satisfying noises.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He noted that the team “recorded a huge variety of (real-life) sounds,” which were then adjusted and readjusted before being added into the game. “We spent years creating things like rock destruction sounds, investing that much time and effort in meticulous adjustments,” Kubo explained, adding that the in-house sound team created all the effects you hear in the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong Bananza employs a variety of sound effects depending on what you are making Donkey Kong interact with. The sound when you punch watermelons in-game was actually made by smashing actual watermelons. However, Kubo recalled that this was a tough one to get right.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“By the time I got around to recording them, summer was already over,” he explained. “There just weren’t any good watermelons left,” adding that he was able to capture the watermelon smashing sound the following year. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Donkey Kong Bananza: DK Island and Emerald Rush DLC Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For the sound effect when you interact with an apple, the team “kept biting into all sorts of things and recording it,” Kubo explained. This included apples, cookies, celery and even hard candies (ouch!). However, in the end they decided that the sound of biting into a real apple was the best. On the other hand, the sound effects for the in-game gold were produced by experimenting with metals brought from a DIY store.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other effects were created using a mixture of sounds. The team mixed some of the watermelon-smashing recordings into the sound that plays when you break a hamburger patty in Donkey Kong Bananza, because, as Kubo said, “You don’t get a very good sound when you actually bite into a hamburger patty.” The satisfying “boing” sound that rocks make when you smash through them was likewise created by mixing in a cicada chirp.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more in-depth insider info about Donkey Kong Banaza’s development, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/our-big-bananas-interview-with-the-developers-of-donkey-kong-bananza"><u>our interview</u></a> with Motokura and Takahashi, and find out why the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-review"><u>scored 10/10 in our review</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-staff-had-tense-watermelon-eating-session-to-create-the-nintendo-switch-2-exclusives-digging-sound-producer-reveals]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kojima Productions Beyond the Strand Livestream: Everything Announced (Updating Live)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kojima-productions-beyond-the-strand-10th-anniversary-livestream-everything-announced-hideo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kojima-productions-beyond-the-strand-livestream-everything-announced-updating-live.1305042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hideo Kojima and Kojima Productions are celebrating the studio's 10th anniversary with a big Beyond the Strand livestream that promises to "offer a glimpse into future projects" in development at the studio behind the first two Death Stranding titles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We'll be covering this event live and updating this article with all the big news and reveals! </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Hideo Kojima Reveals First Trailer for Xbox Game Studios Title OD</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">During the Beyond the Strand livestream, Hideo Kojima and Xbox head Phil Spencer helped share <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hideo-kojima-reveals-first-trailer-for-xbox-game-studios-title-od">the first trailer for OD,</a> Kojima Productions' Xbox Game Studios horror project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The footage begins with an ominous red door and a red card being used to try to unlock it. We then get some redacted text that reads: Ten years since the [REDACTED] Horror [REDACTED], "[REDACTED]." The Cursed [REDACTED] Have Once Again [REDACTED] Into the Forbidden.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We then see the back of the card, which says, "Light the Fires to Celebrate Their [REDACTED] [REDACTED].</p><p data-cy="paragraph">More Text: This Building Was [REDACTED] From a 3D Scan of an [REDACTED] Found in an [REDACTED]. And then, [REDACTED] Were [REDACTED] In a Sinister Ritual.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">More gameplay was shown of someone entering a room on a stormy day. There is a shrine of sorts, and the character pulls out a match from a box that says "missing." They then proceed to light candles, including one that looks like a baby. When they light that last one, a baby starts crying. They then light another candle shaped like another young person's head and it starts bleeding. We then see our character, who is played by Honor Among Thieves' Sophia Lillis, and she looks absolutley terrified as something approaches her from behind and then grabs her.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It then cuts to credits and we see OD will star Lillis, Hunters' Udo Kier, and Euphoria's Hunter Schafer. Oh, and that it is for "all players and screamers."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Furthermore, it looks like OD will have a subtitle of Knock and an exploration of the "fear of the knock." Kojima also noted that Jordan Peele will be focusing on another fear for his OD project, but that fear of the knock will be one of Kojima's focuses. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">He also said he wants to go all around the world to scary places and even "scan a ghost for the first time and get an awards for that." </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Hideo Kojima Reveals New Details on PlayStation's Physint</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/23/g1gdnwqaaaaa5o7-1758606163369.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">While Kojima said he was still in the conceptual phase and working on characters and stories, he was still able to help share a few new details on his <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hideo-kojima-reveals-debut-poster-for-playstation-exclusive-physint-first-cast-announcement">upcoming action espionage project for PlayStation called Phyisnt.</a> We started by seeing a poster of Physint with a male character shrouded in darkness and holding a gun. Along with the character who hasn't been revealed yet, we have the words, "Here comes the feeling." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was also shared that Charlee Fraser (Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga), Don Lee aka Ma Dong-seok (Eternals), and Minami Hamabe (Godzilla Minus One) will be joining the cast of Physint. To end the segment, he shared a look at Hamabe's character in the game's engine.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Death Stranding: Mosquito Is the Working Title for a New Animation Project, Trailer Revealed</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hideo-kojima-shows-off-first-look-at-death-stranding-animated-film-mosquito">Kojima announced Death Stranding: Mosquito,</a> which is the working title for a new animation project from director Hiroshi Miyamoto (ABC Animation Studio) and writer Aaron Guzikowski. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The team wants to differentiate the look of the animation film project and the games, and we got to see this in action in a teaser trailer you can see above. It was also revealed the main character, who is not Sam Porter Bridges, will have the ability to "suck something really important" that isn't blood, and that's why they went with the working title of Death Stranding: Mosquito.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was also revealed that Death Stranding: Mosquito is being animated in a very unique style that begins with hand-drawn lines that are then digitally used to create the animation itself. The backgrounds of the film are also being done by Studio Easter, who has previously worked on Dandadan.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Kojima and A24 Give a Brief Update on the Death Stranding Movie</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Kojima and A24 took the stage to give a few updates on the upcoming Death Stranding film. The movie's director, Michael Sarnoski, also was on hand to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/death-stranding-movie-will-tell-a-story-you-havent-seen-in-that-world-director-confirms">share a bit about how they are envisioning this adaptation.</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">"With this project we really want to capture the soul of the game, capture the themes of the game, but we also want to tell a story that you haven't seen in that world and explore characters you haven't seen before," Sarnoski said. "Also, we want to find all of that scope and all of those incredible real locations, but also find all of those nuanced characters and just do justice to this on a micro and macro scale."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The team wants the film to tell a new story in Death Stranding's world that will be familiar to those who have played the game but also not confusing to those who never have. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Kojima Productions Partnering With Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group On a Credit Card</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Hideo Kojima and Kojima Productions are collaborating with Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group on a brand-new credit card that is aiming to be released in the second half of 2026. This card will also have a smartphone app and digital card to make payments, and it will let users accumulate points and exchange them for merch and goods. The team is working on what themed goods and merch can be used alongside game characters and themes for the card itself. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Kojima Productions and Shimizu Seizaburo Shoten Are Teaming Up for a Zaku Ludens Sake</h2><blockquote data-theme="light">— KOJIMA PRODUCTIONS (Eng) (@KojiPro2015_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/KojiPro2015_EN/status/1970359826405572730?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 23, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Kojima is teaming up with Shimizu Seizaburo Shoten to produce a branded sake called Zaku Ludens.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Kojima Discusses the 20-Year Plan for Kojima Productions</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Kojima discussed a bit more about the 20-year plan he set out for Kojima Productions, and it is very much reminiscent to the building and launching of a spaceship into the stars.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>First Phase (2015-2019)</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Goal:</strong> "Build a spaceship, assemble a crew, install engines, and head for the outer space creating our own new IP."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Details: </strong>This also included Death Stranding, "focusing on connections with fans," merchandising, a fan event, and an anniversary event. The spaceship is the office. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Second Phase (2019-2025 and to 2030)</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Goal:</strong> "Transfer to the long-range spacecraft and head into space."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Details:</strong> This includes Death Stranding: Director's Cut and Death Stranding 2: On the Beach and the team wants to enhance its own IP, go into "multi-platform, film, anime, comic, novelization, and music," further adventures and challenges | beyond the universe," create new IP and transcend the "boundries between film and games," and expand the connections with fans.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Celebrating 10 Years of Kojima Productions</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond the Strand began with a look back at Kojima Productions, including a timeline of the studio, which you can see below;</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>December 12, 2016:</strong> Kojima Productions Established</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2016:</strong> Official Mascot "Ludens" Revealed</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2016:</strong> New Office Established in Shinagawa</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2016:</strong> Death Stranding Revealed</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2019:</strong> Death Stranding Special Stage at Tokyo Game Show 2019</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2019:</strong> Launch of Death Stranding</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2020:</strong> Fellowship Award at the BAFTA Games Awards</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2021:</strong> Launch of Death Stranding Director's Cut</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2022:</strong> Partnership with Xbox Game Studios</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2022:</strong> New Office Completed</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2022:</strong> Death Stranding 2: On the Beach Announced</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2023:</strong> Praying For a Safe Production With Microsoft at Kanada Myojin</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2023:</strong> OD Announced</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2024:</strong> Physint Announced</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>2025:</strong> Launch of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Developing...</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/kojima-productions-beyond-the-strand-10th-anniversary-livestream-everything-announced-hideo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Devs Announce Farming Sim Spin-Off, Palworld: Palfarm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-devs-announce-farming-sim-spin-off-palworld-palfarm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-devs-announce-farming-sim-spin-off-palworld-palfarm.1304943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Old McPalworld has a farm.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Palworld is getting its first-ever official spin-off game from developer Pocketpair, and it's looking just a little bit cozier than the original game. It's called Palworld: Palfarm, and as the name implies, you and your gaggle of Pals will be farming, crafting, and living a life on the land together on an adventure that looks far more Harvest Moon or Stardew Valley than Palworld.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pocketpair announced the game today with a brand new trailer, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4031890/Palworld_Palfarm/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a Steam page</a>. These reveal that Palfarm will be a slice-of-life farming and crafting sim set on the Palpagos Islands where familiar Pals will join you to build a dream farm. Alongside growing plants, you can cook with Pals, shop at their stores, give them gifts, and- no, no you can't eat them. Of course not. Not this time. They're farming buddies. Not food.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Palworld: Palfarm First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Well, most of them. Some Pals will apparently come raid your farm, and you'll have to fight them off. And then maybe when they die, they might drop stuff that looks like food. Okay, maybe you can kind of eat Pals in Palfarm too. Don't think about it too hard.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Palfarm does seem to be more focused on the cuddlier aspects of life with Pals, including allowing the player to pet Pals and even get married to other humans (with Pals matchmaking and officiating), it's not without its edges. The trailer includes a look at a black market where you can, yes, get a gun. What would you do with a gun in a cozy game like this? Don't think about it too hard!!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Notably, the trailer showed off a number of Pals that can join you to help on the farm, including what seems to be one unannounced new Pal, Sekhmet, that's working with Anubis as a blacksmith. The Steam page also makes it clear that multiplayer will be an option.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Palfarm doesn't have a release date just yet, and so far only appears to be in development for PC via Steam, though given Palworld's trajectory it's possible other platforms are in the cards for later on. Palworld itself is currently still in early access, but Pocketpair has said it's planning a small update in December, and is working toward a big 1.0 launch sometime next year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-devs-announce-farming-sim-spin-off-palworld-palfarm]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Reveal Highlights Include Futuristic Tech, 18 Maps, and Travis Scott]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-reveal-highlights-include-futuristic-tech-18-maps-and-travis-scott</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-reveal-highlights-include-futuristic-tech-18-maps-and-travis-scott.1304886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision and Treyarch have published a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7"><u>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</u></a> multiplayer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pGFYtZD53ZA" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>reveal trailer</u></a> and <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/09/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-deep-dive" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>deep dive blog post</u></a> that shows players everything they need to know ahead of its upcoming beta test.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The developers behind Call of Duty 2025 offered a multiplayer breakdown in a new post published on the series’ website today. It comes with information about every last map, weapon, and mode fans can expect in Black Ops 7, both during the beta and at launch, while showing off a sneak peek at what it all looks like in motion with today’s trailer. You can see the Black Ops 7 multiplayer reveal trailer, with Travis Scott and Playboi Carti’s FE!N providing the musical backdrop, below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Today’s Black Ops 7 multiplayer reveal trailer hits the highlights for those who have about two and a half minutes to spare. While players can be seen darting around corners, sliding and shooting at enemies, and even wall-jumping to reach high-up areas, the footage serves as a reminder that this year’s Call of Duty lets players take advantage of near-future technology. These can be seen in futuristic tools like the Echo Unit hologram decoy as well as Scorestreaks, such as the D.A.W.G. quadruped robot and the remote-controlled Rhino soldier.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Classic Call of Duty Scorestreaks like the RC-XD, UAV, Care Package, and more are back, too, with players now able to unlock Overclock upgrades that can improve their usefulness in unique ways. The UAV, for example, has Overclock options that equip it with a flare for missile defense and lower its score cost, while the Rhino gains access to an improved radar and extended runtime.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Treyarch, of course, still has more up its sleeve, but today’s Black Ops 7 multiplayer reveal really pulls back the curtain on what players can expect when beta early access begins October 2 and at launch. While the beta will only allow access to a limited selection of the content available when Black Ops 7’s November release date arrives, we at least know which of the 18 launch maps players can try out in a few weeks.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Scorestreaks</h3></div></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Maps, Modes, and More</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 7 will launch with 16 Core 6v6 maps. Six from that lineup will be included in the beta, with three returning from 2012’s Call of Duty: Black Ops 2. You can see the full list of Core maps, as well as the two 20v20 Skirmish maps, below.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Core 6v6 Maps</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Blackheart (Beta)</li><li>Cortex (Beta)</li><li>Exposure (Beta)</li><li>Imprint (Beta)</li><li>The Forge (Beta)</li><li>Toshin (Beta)</li><li>Colossus</li><li>Den</li><li>Flagship</li><li>Homestead</li><li>Paranoia</li><li>Retrieval</li><li>Scar</li><li>Express (Returning from <em>Black Ops 2</em>)</li><li>Hijacked (Returning from <em>Black Ops 2</em>)</li><li>Raid (Returning from <em>Black Ops 2</em>)</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Skirmish Maps</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Mission: Edge</li><li>Mission: Tide</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Maps</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As per usual, a new Call of Duty means fan-favorite modes have been refreshed, with new modes for players to look forward to, too. Multiplayer mainstays like Team Deathmatch, Domination, Kill Confirmed, and Hardpoint will be available to play during the beta, with Free-For-All, Gunfight, Kill Order, Control, and Search and Destroy following at launch. There are also Face Off versions of many of these modes, giving players an option to experience classic modes while tuning down the chaos thanks to disabled Scorestreaks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The main new mode given the spotlight today is Overload. Also available during the beta, the multiplayer option will see players tasked with bringing an Overload Device to control zones. It flips respawns on as teams guard their device carrier, suggesting teamwork will be an important element in order to achieve victory.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 7 sticks with tradition by offering new and returning modes, but there are even more gameplay-focused changes for longtime fans to learn, too. The three-Perk system, for example, is getting a facelift with a tweak called Hybrid Combat Specialties.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">These are activated when pairing Perks from different categories, allowing players to flex their creative muscles by mixing and matching different Perks for unique upgrades. Some examples laid out by Treyarch include the red-and-blue Scout Specialty, which keeps players’ position temporarily concealed after a bullet elimination, as well as the blue-and-green Operative Specialty, which charges Field Upgrades with stealth kills. Treyarch’s Black Ops 7 multiplayer reveal breakdown also includes a first look at a feature that allows friends to share weapon builds with each other with Build Codes, while also granting the ability to access Gunsmith within the Firing Range in Multiplayer itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 has a release date of November 14, 2025, for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X | S. Those hoping to for a closer look at how Treyarch has updated its formula for this year’s Call of Duty can pre-order to play the early access beta from October 2 – 5, with the open beta following for all from October 5 – 8.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, you can read up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/every-major-game-faces-this-issue-activision-steps-up-war-on-pc-cheaters-ahead-of-black-ops-7-launch"><u>how Activision plans to tackle cheaters</u></a> when Black Ops 7 launches in a few months. You can also see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/treyarch-confirms-some-black-ops-6-skins-will-carry-forward-to-black-ops-7-as-call-of-duty-players-debate-loss-of-cosmetics-just-because-of-a-few-cartoon-skins-people-complained-about"><u>how skins unlocked in past entries can carry over</u></a> to this year’s entry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-reveal-highlights-include-futuristic-tech-18-maps-and-travis-scott]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>