<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:57:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hellraiser: Revival Dev Plans to Go as Extreme 'As the People That Make Rules Will Let Us Go']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hellraiser-revival-dev-plans-to-go-as-extreme-as-the-people-that-make-rules-will-let-us-go</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hellraiser-revival-dev-plans-to-go-as-extreme-as-the-people-that-make-rules-will-let-us-go.1294791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The developers of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/clive-barkers-hellraiser-revival">Hellraiser: Revival</a> intend to push its M Rating as far as it can with the upcoming video game adaptation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival is a story-driven, single-player survival horror action game set in the Hellraiser universe. It's developed by Boss Team Games, creator of the recently delisted Evil Dead: The Game, and is due out on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC via Steam.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hellraiser, for the uninitiated, is a cult classic horror franchise made up of 11 films and various comic books, all based on The Hellbound Heart novella by English author Clive Barker. The star of the show is Pinhead, a ‘Cenobite’ who harvests human souls to torture in sadistic experiments. And you can see that in action in the trailer, which — content warning! — contains as much sex as it does body horror.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Hellraiser: Revival is not for the faint of heart. If you’re wondering just how extreme the game gets, be sure to check out IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hellraiser-revival-is-resident-evil-for-sickos">hands-on Hellraiser: Revival preview</a> for all the gory details. But in short, expect body horror, sex, no holds barred nudity, nightmarish scenes, and a healthy dose of hell.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s 'Resident Evil For Sickos,' we said coming out of our time with Hellraiser, but just how extreme can the developers at Saber Interactive take it? In an interview with IGN, Saber development chief Tim Willits said the studio plans to push Hellraiser as far as the people who make the rules around an M Rating will let them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We are going to go as far as we possibly can, as far as the people that make rules will let us go,” Willits insisted. “And I hope that we can make one version, but we are willing to go as far as we possibly can go.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Hellraiser: Revival - gamescom 2025 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, what we’ve seen of Hellraiser: Revival so far is in keeping with Clive Barker’s cult classic Hellraiser movies, so tonally, there’s no real difference. But there’s something unique about seeing and doing all this horrific stuff from a first-person perspective that’s a bit more in your face than watching a film in a theater or at home.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We want to be a responsible publisher / developer, but we are going to push it as far as we possibly can in the context of the game and the movie.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clive Barker is working with Saber on Hellraiser: Revival to ensure it fits with his vision for the universe. This back and forth should result in a game fans of the movies will get a real kick out of, Willits added.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“He's come back and said, ‘Yeah, Pinhead wouldn't do that,’” Willits explained. “And he's come back and said, ‘Yeah, you got to tweak this a little bit.’ Because this is his world and he knows stuff that we don't even think about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And he's been really fast too. Sometimes when you work with famous people you throw something over and then six months later they come back and they complain about something. No, he’s that on it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Doug Bradley, the original actor behind the Cenobite leader Pinhead, has reprised his role for the game, adding to the authenticity of the project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb:</p><blockquote>Discover the tale of Aidan, who must unlock the dark powers of the Genesis Configuration, a mysterious puzzle box, to help his girlfriend from a hellish abyss. As Aidan, you’ll harness the box’s infernal abilities to survive your pact with the sinister Pinhead and battle against the twisted cult that worships him and the Cenobites. Fail, and your suffering will be legendary, even in Hell.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Hellraiser was thrust back into the public consciousness in 2022 with a franchise reboot film. IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hellraiser-review-2022-hulu">Hellraiser review</a> returned an 8/10. We said: “Hellraiser is a reinvigorated reboot that gets the blood pumping, starting with Jamie Clayton’s worthy Pinhead performance that sets a fresh tone with immense reverence paid to Clive Barker's works.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/hellraiser-revival-dev-plans-to-go-as-extreme-as-the-people-that-make-rules-will-let-us-go]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Was Shadowheart a Dark Eldar All Along? New Warhammer 40,000 Drukhari Model Gets Baldur’s Gate 3 Fans’ Attention]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/was-shadowheart-a-dark-eldar-all-along-new-warhammer-40000-drukhari-model-gets-baldurs-gate-3-fans-attention</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/was-shadowheart-a-dark-eldar-all-along-new-warhammer-40-000-drukhari-model-gets-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-fans%E2%80%99-attention.1294788/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s been a big week for Drukhari fans after Games Workshop finally remembered the Dark Eldar exist and announced two new models for the faction as well as a new codex and Combat Patrol. But one of the models in particular has caught the attention of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> fans, many of whom think she looks very much like God's Favourite Princess.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The Drukhari have been biding their time in the depths of Commorragh, but it’s finally time to launch the raid and drink deep of the galaxy’s misery — Codex: Drukhari is on its way!” Games Workshop said in a post on the <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/5jk5xmlb/lady-malys-stands-tall-over-the-new-codex-drukhari/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Warhammer Community</a> website earlier this week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“At the fore is a character long known for her quicksilver intellect and violent tendencies, who now steps onto the battlefield with a wicked weave of schemes and strategies to confound her prey.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Give it up for the Archon of the Poisoned Tongue — Lady Malys.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/11/image1-1756899954-a9cqxpnbho-1757597029789.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Lady Malys, a brand new model coming to the Dark Eldar. Look familiar? Image credit: Games Workshop.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Look familiar? If you’re thinking of Shadowheart from Baldur’s Gate 3, then you’re one of many with the same opinion. Ever since Lady Malys was revealed, the conversation around the model has involved comparisons to the much-loved Baldur’s Gate 3 companion, which is as much to do with the similar hairstyle and color and sort of similar facial features as it does her imposing demeanor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb on Lady Malys:</p><blockquote>Lady Malys is as deadly with her wit as she is with her slender blades, fighting with a barbed longsword known as the Lady’s Blade and a fan of razor sharp knives. Her knowledge of poisons can render her unit’s attacks even deadlier than usual, and opponents are always caught off guard when Kabalites they thought they had sussed out are suddenly spirited elsewhere before the battle even begins.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“It legit is Shadowheart,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Drukhari/comments/1nbofea/comment/nd395l8/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said redditor Sliversix</a>. “I was just tempted to get her model because of how gorgeous it looks.” “FR. Someone in the mini making department has been playing too much BG3,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Drukhari/comments/1nbofea/comment/nd3fz5d/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">replied Sufficient_Quit353</a>. “Yeah, this is GW making a good looking female head, and this is Shadowheart if she became a Dark Justiciar and then took things to space,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Drukhari/comments/1nbofea/comment/nd3nlug/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">added lycantrophee</a>. “That's definitely very similar. I want one!” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldar/comments/1nboqmw/comment/nd4afag/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">declared OftenSarcastic</a>. “I want a second head so I can make a ‘Selunite’ Craftworld version as well.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some Warhammer 40,000 fans who are saying the Lady Malys model is <em>too</em> Shadowheart, or too “cute” to be a Drukhari, who are meant to be ultra evil slavers who delight in torture and sucking the souls right out of their victims. They should look more like a twisted form of the Eldar, Warhammer 40,000’s space elves, than Eldar in gnarly armor.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Am I the only one who feels her face looks wrong for a Drukhari?” asked Perversoris. “Like way too light and closer to Craftworld than Drukhari appearance imho.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Drukhari shouldn’t be cute!!! <a href="https://t.co/STQueb3OQ8" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/STQueb3OQ8</a></p>— Marius Gage (@For_Macragge) <a href="https://twitter.com/For_Macragge/status/1965437243721744681?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 9, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Whatever your take, Drukhari fans are finally having <em>a moment</em> after years spent in the wilderness, looking on enviously at their Space Marine-loving brethren. It’s fair to say the Dark Eldar haven’t been on top of Games Workshop’s to-do list when it comes to new Warhammer 40,000 models, so whenever Lady Malys and co hit store shelves, the Drukhari fandom will have plenty to sink their teeth into.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And perhaps they’ll bring a few Baldur’s Gate 3 players along for the ride. All we need now is a Karlach World Eater...</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/was-shadowheart-a-dark-eldar-all-along-new-warhammer-40000-drukhari-model-gets-baldurs-gate-3-fans-attention]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Patch 2.31 Adds AutoDrive Upgrade and Photo Mode Adjustments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-patch-231-adds-autodrive-upgrade-and-photo-mode-adjustments</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-patch-2-31-adds-autodrive-upgrade-and-photo-mode-adjustments.1294782/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The post-launch support for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> continues, this time with an AutoDrive upgrade and Photo Mode adjustments via Patch 2.31.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/51794/patch-2-31" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As confirmed on developer CD Projekt’s website</a>, Patch 2.31 is rolling out on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, Mac, and Nintendo Switch 2 today, September 11, 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2.31 follows <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-23-contents-and-release-date-confirmed-although-nintendo-switch-2-owners-will-have-to-wait">Cyberpunk 2077’s significant Patch 2.3</a>, co-developed with support studio <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/400-people-at-this-massive-support-studio-worked-on-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-but-you-probably-dont-know-they-exist">Virtuos</a> to add the AutoDrive feature, which lets you drive vehicles hands free.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Is 2.3 the final major update for Cyberpunk 2077? CD Projekt has said previously released patches drew a line under the near five-year-old game, so perhaps there is more to come. Could Cyberpunk 2077 go out with a bang this December with a new update to coincide with its five-year anniversary?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the longer term, CD Projekt recently confirmed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-cyberpunk-2-enters-pre-production-and-yes-cd-projekt-is-officially-calling-it-cyberpunk-2-now"><u>Cyberpunk 2 has moved into the pre-production phase of development</u></a>. But don’t hold your breath — the developer has suggested it won't release until late 2030 or even early 2031. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/johnny-silverhand-actor-keanu-reeves-says-he-absolutely-wants-to-be-in-cyberpunk-2">Johnny Silverhand actor Keanu Reeves, however, has told IGN he’d love to reprise the role for Cyberpunk 2</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Cyberpunk 2077 Update 2.31 Patch notes:<br>
<strong>Vehicles</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated AutoDrive. When driving to a selected point, the vehicle now drives smoothly, overtakes blocking vehicles, and no longer stops at traffic lights. Free Roam mode has also been upgraded to follow traffic rules and navigate the city more reliably.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Johnny always spawned in the passenger seat when using the Delamain Cab service.</li><li>Fixed an issue where applying CrystalCoat to the Yaiba ARV-Q340 Semimaru caused its wheels to flash in different colors.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Photo Mode</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Most of the new poses introduced in Update 2.3 now work with any gender.</li><li>Disabled NPC collision, which will make it easier to position NPCs on top of other objects with collision (e.g. on car hoods).</li><li>Fixed an issue where some of the poses didn't work for Royce.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Quests &amp; Open World</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><em>Freedom </em>- Fixed the journal entry that appears when the player chooses not to steal the Rayfield Caliburn "Mordred."</li><li><em>Motorbreath </em>- Fixed an issue where, after V fails to pursue and stop Semimaru and receives a text from River saying he'll contact V soon, the follow-up message never arrives.</li><li><em>Motorbreath - </em>Fixed an issue where the Yaiba Semimaru could flip over during the chase, preventing the player from entering it.</li><li><em>Motorbreath - </em>It's no longer possible to trigger the quest if River died during <em>The Hunt</em>.</li><li><em>Motorbreath </em>- Players can now acquire the Yaiba ARV-Q340 Semimaru through AUTOFIXER even if they failed <em>The Hunt</em>, which normally unlocks the side quest where the vehicle is obtained.</li><li><em>Nitro (Youth Energy)</em> - Fixed a game crash that could occur in certain circumstances after leaving the Yaiba showroom event.</li><li><em>Nitro (Youth Energy)</em> - Fixed an issue where the proxy interface UI in the Yaiba showroom is cut off when the "Larger HUD Elements" setting is enabled.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed several localization and lipsync issues in various languages.</li><li>Added a toggle to disable vignette. It can be found in Settings → Graphics → Basic.</li><li>Fixed an issue on PC and Mac where Ray-Traced Reflections might not display correctly when enabled under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed several issues with displaying text messages from Delamain.</li><li>Various fixes for fluff vendors.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>PC-specific</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where NVIDIA Reflex could be disabled while DLSS Frame Generation was enabled, causing the screen to turn pink.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Path Tracing didn't activate properly in certain scenarios.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Mac-specific</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue where changing graphics presets on Mac set Screen Space Reflections to a higher setting compared to the equivalent presets on PC.</li><li>Fixed an issue causing a permanent white screen when Frame Generation is enabled while entering the braindance in <em>The Information</em>.</li><li>Selecting "Defaults" in Video Settings no longer turns HDR Mode off.</li><li>Fixed the inverted behavior of the "Mute Game in Background" toggle in Settings.</li><li>Removed the outdated "(Requires Game Restart)" disclaimer from the mouseover description of the "Disable Spatial Audio" setting.</li><li>Fixed an issue on the App Store version that caused the game to become stuck on the “Press Space to continue” breaching screen.</li><li>Various stability and performance optimizations.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-patch-231-adds-autodrive-upgrade-and-photo-mode-adjustments]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-review.1294776/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">My passion for looter shooters has burned quite brightly for over 15 years and Borderlands is the flame that lit the fuse. With Borderlands 4, Gearbox proves it still knows how to bring the boom. After fizzling somewhat with Borderlands 3, it felt like this series had begun to fall behind in the genre it pioneered, but breaking away from segmented levels and embracing an honest-to-goodness open world allows 2025’s Borderlands to surprise us again. Drastically improved movement makes it one of the best-feeling first-person shooters out there, the story takes a refreshingly grounded approach that pays off, and the expanded buildcrafting options like healing items, throwing knives, and weapon enhancements are all fantastic ideas. But taking these swings also comes with some unfortunate downsides, like how exploration is quite literally held back by invisible walls and awkward surfaces that refuse to be trod upon, not to mention fairly rocky technical performance (at least on the PC version provided for review) and numerous bugs. But those rough <s>edges</s> borders did little to keep me from once again falling head over heels for my first looter-shooter love, and blasting through hordes of psychos with a friend or three feels as awesome as it ever has.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re new to the absolute insanity that is Borderlands, it’s a series where the weird enemies you mow down drop increasingly bizarre weapons that you then use to mow down even weirder enemies in an endless cycle of looting and shooting. How bizarre? It’s stuff like an assault rifle that shoots tiny rockets, can call in an airstrike, and explodes like a grenade when you reload and toss it. Or maybe you’ll luck into a sniper rifle that fires off ammo like a gatling gun and stops consuming ammo while overheated, or a grenade that screams absurd (and occasionally horny) things as it bounces up and down, spewing acid. Borderlands 4 keeps that feeling fresh by continuing to iterate on the silly weapons it gives you, which can cross-pollinate across different weapon manufacturers for even weirder outcomes.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Borderlands 4 Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The other distinctive bit of style that’s set its best games apart from the crowd is that despite always having been filled with lowbrow dick jokes to match its hand-drawn graphic novel look, Borderlands has never been afraid to surprise with sharp turns toward genuinely touching story moments. (Heck, it’s a universe that’s supported a Telltale-made Tales from the Borderlands game and its Gearbox-developed sequel, so it’s not all about run-and-gun action.) Borderlands 3 notably didn’t have a lot of those, though, so it was a relief when this followup finally ditched the original planet of Pandora and many of its legacy characters who’d started to wear out their welcome to tell a completely new tale on a world called Kairos that’s been dominated by a malevolent, brainwashing dictator named the Timekeeper. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Borderlands 4 is much more than just a breath of fresh air, bordering on what almost seems like a soft reboot at times. It immediately adds some memorable characters to its cast, like the fancy and charming Levaine, who has a somewhat messy dating history with your fellow Vault Hunters – but then every once in a while it takes a welcome dip back into the nostalgia pool to have Claptrap rattle off a few jokes. (Yes, the sassy little bot is back; love him or hate him, it wouldn’t be Borderlands without him.) With a few neat twists in store and a compelling plot about trying to free this planet, I ended up liking the story quite a bit, even if it doesn’t hit the highs of Borderlands 2 (especially in terms of its iconic villain).</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Borderlands 4 is a proper open-world game.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Most of the action itself is what you’d expect from this series, but number four (or six, if you count The Pre-Sequel and Tiny Tina’s Wonderlands) makes a number of pretty huge changes that shake up your vault-hunting expedition. The biggest by far is the fact that Borderlands 4 is a proper open-world game (as opposed to the traditional approach of large zones separated by loading screens) that’s filled with side quests, timed activities, collectibles, and puzzles to seek out. You also have a whole bag of tricks to aid you in the exploration of Kairos’ four diverse regions, like a grapple hook that lets you get to areas normally out of reach, a glider to soar over large swaths of land, and a vehicle you can summon on command to zip over hills and through deserts without having to hoof it to a Catch-A-Ride station first. Aside from a very limited few (such as The Division 2 or Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League), fully open-world games are pretty rare in the looter shooter space – none of which are in first-person.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN Borderlands Review</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That might not seem like a big deal at first, but it’s hard to overstate how different this makes Borderlands 4 from its predecessors, not just because you’ve got so many new ways to get around, but because progressing through the story and leveling up your character is so much less linear now. Sometimes I’d spend a few hours just exploring a new region of the map, clearing the fog of war away and completing any activities I encountered along the way, while other times I’d race from place to place, focusing on one part of the main story quest line before pivoting to another part of it in a different region. That story took me about 40 hours to complete, but that was with plenty of distractions, and I’ve spent another 20+ after the credits rolled with lots still left to do. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s also awesome that you don’t have to worry so much about sticking next to your teammates this time. They can be leagues away doing their own thing, and if they need help with something you can just pull up your map and warp to them instantly. Open-world activities are more diverse than I was expecting as well, and range from proper story-focused side quests to an activity where you have to fix a giant crawler to claim a vehicle upgrade to one where you fight loads of madmen at a drill site to earn some badass loot. The fact that you can do all that free-wheeling exploration and discovery alongside a group of friends in a way that’s never inconvenient makes it that much better and impressive.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Some areas are filled with invisible walls that you’ll unsatisfyingly slap into.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">There is one major issue with this new open-world philosophy, however, which is that the physical terrain of Kairos doesn’t always rise to the occasion of these free-roaming ambitions. For example, some areas are filled with invisible walls that you’ll unsatisfyingly slap into while you’re trying to glide over a hill or mantle up a ledge. Borderlands has always had issues with its environments being a bit wonky, but it feels so much more noticeable in an open world where you naturally assume you’re meant to explore every nook and cranny, and most games come up with natural barriers like mountains or oceans to make it clear that you can go no farther. Instead, you quickly find the limitations of that exploration and they feel artificial. Although I eventually learned to recognize when a surface was probably not something I was going to be allowed to interact with, it still bums me out that there isn’t just some kind of “out of bounds” warning when going places I wasn’t meant to.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One other major area of evolution is combat, which not only has tighter, more responsive gunplay than any Borderlands game before it, but comes packed with a frankly silly number of new movement options that make battles much more dynamic. In addition to the existing ways to get around like running and sliding, you can now double jump, glide, grapple hook, dash in any direction, and even swim (that’s right, water no longer instantly kills you, praise Moxxi). It actually took me quite a while to remember all the new ways I was expected to navigate combat encounters, but with the help of some enemies that smartly push you to make full use of your options, I eventually learned to master them. By the end, I was soaring across the map, dodging attacks like a pro and raining hell down upon my enemies. It became wonderfully satisfying stuff once I got the hang of it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox has also heaped an impressively high volume of new things to shoot into this game. While other Borderlands sequels reused many of the same enemy types dating back to the 2009 original, Borderlands 4’s change of planetary venue means it has to significantly expand its menagerie. Sure, the masked psychos that serve as the series’ poster boys (they’re like a disturbing version of the Minions from Despicable Me, and they managed to hitch a ride off of Pandora somehow), but there are also little mechanical spiders that reflect all the bullets you send their way when they to spin their legs rapidly, creatures covered in crystals that are immune to damage until you shoot those crystals off and quickly destroy the floating orbs they turn into, and many others that I hadn’t seen before. Those caused me to stop and adapt to their tactics in interesting ways, and that was always a memorable moment.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Rest assured, the major bosses usually step up their game pretty noticeably.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Even better are the boss fights, which have evolved pretty significantly in that they usually involve some special mechanics you have to learn in order to beat them. These are often pretty simple things, like picking up and throwing a toxic bomb onto one boss to peel his armor off, or having to juggle yourself in the air with grappling and gliding after the floor becomes hazardous for a phase of another fight. Granted, they don’t come close to the mechanical complexity of something you’d find in a Destiny raid, but those are often kind of over-the-top and this is a significant step up from some of the basic “dodge and shoot it until it dies” battles we’ve seen in Borderlands past. It’s a happy medium, and that makes these bosses a lot less forgettable. That’s not to say there aren’t any basic fights, but it’s fair to say that those can be an entertaining excuse to turn off your brain and blast something to bits and serve as a contrast to the ones with an extra element to them. Rest assured, the major bosses usually step up their game pretty noticeably.</p><div id="borderlands-vault-hunters-ranked" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Borderlands' Vault Hunters, Ranked</h3><h3>Borderlands' Vault Hunters, Ranked</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s also neat that you’ll start encountering enemies with various modifiers as you get further into the adventure and unlock higher difficulty settings via the endgame grind. These might be things like Elemental Eater, an effect that means enemies aren’t just resistant to a specific type of attack but healed by it, or Centripetal, which causes a black hole to form where an enemy with this trait dies, pulling everything in range into its center and dealing massive damage. It’s not all new, groundbreaking stuff for Borderlands – these are similar to effects found in Borderlands 3’s Mayhem Mode, for instance – but they’re now a central part of Borderlands 4, and that makes combat more interesting and has you staying a little more aware even of enemies you’ve seen a lot of already. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">One huge pain point, though, is that the full descriptions for each of these modifiers’ effects don’t appear to be listed anywhere, so you’ve just gotta figure them out on your own – or look them up on the guide that IGN’s team is already cooking up for you. I can’t tell you how long I spent accidentally healing a bad guy before realizing I was doing something very wrong, and it would have been nice to have a codex somewhere with more info.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Combat has you staying a little more aware even of enemies you’ve seen a lot of already.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If the fact that I’ve gone this long without even getting to discussing the entirely new batch of Vault Hunters in Borderlands 4 doesn’t tell you there’s a lot going on here, I don’t know what will. It mostly sticks to tradition, but puts some pretty neat spins on the series’ existing classes. There’s the Siren, Vex, who uses her space magic to deal elemental damage and has some awesome life-stealing options; Rafa, the Exo-Soldier who can summon all sorts of DigiStructed weapons, from shoulder-mounted turrets to melee arm blades (as though Borderlands didn’t have enough weapons already!); Harlowe, a Gravitar with an assortment of gravity-manipulation abilities that can trap enemies in bubbles, among other things; and Amon, a massive, cybernetically enhanced warrior called a Forgeknight, who has a bunch of melee options at his disposal. Each one feels pretty good, with unique tools that make them all viable choices for endgame activities without feeling especially overpowered. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While I’ve been pretty high on it so far, I do have some complaints to lodge as someone who tends to play this kind of game more than once, and with an eye toward making each of those playthroughs feel distinct.  After a few dozen hours with it, it strikes me that Borderlands 4’s buildcrafting hasn’t pushed this series into the realm of something like Diablo or – dare I say it – Path of Exile, given that there are a few branching paths to choose from in each Vault Hunter’s skill trees that you can then can optimize with gear to excel at a handful of specific things like dealing loads of elemental damage or healing yourself when getting kills, but not enough customization options to really go wild.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, the three different trees each character does have each at least add a little bit of variety to how every class can play, meaning more than one person on your team can use the same Vault Hunter while having a different set of buffs and abilities that can make them work well together. For example, for the first half of my playthrough I focused on Vex’s Spectral Summoning tree to deploy ghostly doppelgangers onto the battlefield, but after finding a legendary item that worked well for a different kind of build, I respec’d into the elemental DPS tree that focused on casting powerful spells instead of summoning others to do my bidding. If those two different characters worked together side by side, there’d be little overlap in what they’re bringing to an up-to-four-person team.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ah yes, teams! Although Borderlands 4 feels great to play solo as well, for sure the best way to play is when among friends, but those who play together should expect to experience bugs together. The vast majority of my time in Borderlands was spent with friends, and we encountered just about every issue in the online-multiplayer book: lag and desyncing from combat if you’re not the host, enemies sometimes becoming immune to damage or teleporting around the map, and non-host players losing progress or getting locked out of quest lines because something didn’t track properly, just to name a few.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Borderlands 4 is a fairly buggy ride in general.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Some of this, like the fact that you don’t uncover the map in your own save file while exploring with friends, seems like it might be intentional, but is still deeply annoying and disincentivizes teaming up. Other issues, like equipment-selling vending machines that consistently offered no wares at all for any of us while in co-op, are just head-scratching pains in the neck. There were times when I hit enough issues in succession where it became preferable to just play solo, and others where it created friction when deciding who would be the group’s host because we knew that person would see the fewest problems. That’s definitely not the kind of dynamic you want in your co-op game, and it caused my group no small amount of grief as we discovered the various ways in which things feel not so great when playing together, despite gunplay and synergizing our builds with one another otherwise being really awesome. Granted, some of this is the result of playing a short time before launch and there will certainly be at least a few fixes by the time you play it – but if history is any lesson it will be a minute before all of this is ironed out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Playing solo is smoother, but there’s no escape from all of the problems because Borderlands 4 is a fairly buggy ride in general. It seems like there are as many bugs as there are guns, and the longer you play the more likely you are to see things like infrequent but severe framerate hitching, or your backpack suddenly deciding you have way less space for equipment than you should until you back out to the menu and reload. Two of my crew even found themselves locked out of the endgame grind when different steps in the questline broke, blocking their progression and making it so we couldn’t run the activities we wanted to do together. It’s a testament to just how fun exploring Kairos is that, even with all of that laundry list, I still couldn’t wait to play more even after dozens of hours. You’ve gotta take these complaints in context.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">TieGuyTravis' Borderlands Rankings</h3><p>Borderlands is a series that's always been very dear to my heart, and here's my ranking of them all.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of the endgame grind, Borderlands 4 appears to come pre-loaded with one of those (though hey, I said the same thing about Diablo 4 – you can’t call them all right, but I’m feeling optimistic). There are three activities you’re expected to complete weekly: a more challenging version of a story mission that has a bunch of tricky modifiers, like one where all enemies explode into a black hole of damage and another where enemies heal themselves when dealing damage to your team, a repeatable boss fight that mostly just seems like it’s there to give you a straightforward enemy to kill as many times as you’d like for great loot, and a hidden vending machine that moves around each week and sells guaranteed legendary loot. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you grind these activities, you’ll also unlock the more advanced world tier difficulties that offer better loot, but these are gatekept behind incredibly challenging quests with loads of modifiers that are the ultimate test of your loadout and shooting skills. At this point, none of these things are particularly deep or time-consuming since you just run them all each week and then are basically done, but even if that’s not your thing there’s still a massive map that has lots of side activities for you to complete out of the “box.” (Are there still boxes?) Beyond that, we have promises that Gearbox has a fairly good track record of delivering on, courtesy of a post-launch roadmap which includes plenty of content on the way. I have a lot of hope that Borderlands 4 will have legs for quite some time.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Borderlands 4 is a badass open-world evolution of a wonderfully unhinged looter-shooter series that needed to try something new, and it largely nails the biggest swings it takes. Combat is slicker than ever thanks to exciting new movement options and some interesting enemy designs, and the entertaining story takes things in a fresh direction while still tying neatly into existing lore. The transition to an open world isn’t the smoothest, especially when troubling terrain with a few too many invisible walls can make it feel like these environments are all for show, but that’s more than worth putting up with in exchange for being able to chart your own path and freely explore the wacky, violent world of Kairos. The bugs my crew and I encountered were bad enough to occasionally sour our co-op groove, but in between them we had a great time, and my friends and I have found ourselves utterly at the mercy of its loot grind. The Borderlands series feels like it has been a bit stuck in the mud for some time now, and especially after a few patches, Borderlands 4 is exactly the kick in the pants it has needed.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Hotfix 10.1 Stops the Heroic Cadians From Tanking the Trygon Prime]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-hotfix-101-stops-the-heroic-cadians-from-tanking-the-trygon-prime</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-hotfix-10-1-stops-the-heroic-cadians-from-tanking-the-trygon-prime.1294773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> developer Saber Interactive has released a hotfix that makes a number of important fixes and balance changes following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-10-goes-live-and-this-is-the-big-one-with-playable-helbrute-power-axe-weapon-chaos-spawn-enemy-and-a-lot-more">the release of the huge 10.0 patch</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As well as buffing the new and very popular Power Axe, and an increase for the amount of Accolades rewarded for daily Stratagems, there is a fix for a bug that had caught the community’s eye and even sparked a number of memes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the fix in question:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a bug causing the Trygon Prime to leave the boss arena to attack Cadians in Stratagem mode.</li></ul><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Stratagem mode, a new PvE mode introduced with 10.0, has various Battlefield Conditions that change every day and week and make each operation different. These modifiers, which can help or hinder your progress, include Cadia Stands, which makes Imperial Guard soldiers spawn on levels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans have loved seeing Guardsmen help out in Stratagem mode, which not only increases the sense of epic scale for battles, but also leans on the beloved Cadian Shock Troops — perhaps Warhammer 40,000’s best-known human soldier force.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cadia was the setting of one of the most important moments in Warhammer 40,000 history, and the origin of the rousing ‘Cadia Stands’ battle cry. Cadia was destroyed when Abaddon the Despoiler crashed a Blackstone Fortress into the planet during his 13th Black Crusade, causing the planet to tear itself apart, and triggering the expansion of the Eye of Terror into the Great Rift, which split the Imperium. The destruction of the ancient Necron pylons on Cadia, which had kept the Eye of Terror stable, unleashed raw warp energy into real space, dooming the planet and reshaping the galaxy. The Warhammer 40,000 setting has spent recent years dealing with the fallout.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And so, Warhammer 40,000 fans love a plucky Cadian, especially while stomping around as a Space Marine. Therefore, when patch 10 introduced a quite wonderful bug that saw a Cadian soldier sometimes attract the attention of a monstrous Trygon Prime (one of the toughest Tyranid enemies in the game) to the point of obsession, Space Marine 2 players absolutely loved it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some wonderful clips showing how Cadians were able to lead the Trygon Prime to its doom simply by attracting its attention, perhaps causing it to fall to its doom as in the clip below. Cadia stands, after all!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alas, no more. From now on, it’s the Space Marines who will have to deal directly with the Trygon Prime, with the Cadians in their traditional cannon fodder role once more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The massive balls of the guardsmen had a gravitational pull on that nasty worm,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Spacemarine/comments/1ne40e5/comment/ndlsyvo/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">commented redditor Suter_Templar</a>, reacting to the patch. “I love seeing them fight against monsters beyond their comprehension like nobody's business. Honestly they should be permanent always in operations.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The patch notes, <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/271-hotfix-10-1-patch-notes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">per publisher Focus Entertainment's website</a>, are below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Hotfix 10.1 Patch Notes:</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Melee (PvE only)</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Power Axe:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Slash Momentum and Discharge perks places are switched.</li><li>Whirlwind attacks are widened and damage is increased by 50%.</li><li>Power Step attack damage is increased by 66%.</li><li>Slash Momentum perk description is showing correct numbers now.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Combat Knife:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Heroic Combat Knife version “Power Gladius” bonus damage for perfect dodge increased to 120%.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Note that description is still incorrect, the bonus damage affects all attacks, not light attacks only.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Bulwark:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Shield Rush attack can no longer stun lock Terminus enemies.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Stratagems</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased rewards for daily Normal and Hard Stratagems to 10 and 15 respectively.</li><li>Suboptimal State Battlefield Condition HP penalty is reduced from 75% to 66%.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Multi-Melta:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The interval between shots is now enforced when transitioning to the standing position. </li><li>Additionally, the rate of fire from hip fire has been increased from 35 to 50 rounds-per-minute.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">CUSTOMISATION</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lots of minor customisation fixes.</li><li>Mark VIII Errant Helmet without decorations is now available for purchase. (<em>Mark VII without decorations will be available later as well).</em></li><li>Ultramarines Champion Armour Parts are now correctly locked by the Ultramarines Champion Pack DLC.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>LEVELS</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Operation Vortex: </strong>Armoury Data is correctly rewarded for killing the Vortex Beast.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">GENERAL FIXES</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed a bug causing the Trygon Prime to leave the boss arena to attack Cadians in Stratagem mode.</li><li>Fixed a bug with the Emperor's Vengeance perk (Tactical) not restoring Melta Charges for Heroic Bolt Rifle version (Combi-Melta).</li><li>Fixed: Stratagems didn't work when offline.</li><li>Fixed an rare issue in Helbrute Onslaught game mode causing a black screen after selecting a class. </li><li>Minor localization fixes.</li><li>Lots of minor bug fixes.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">TECH</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Crash fixes and general stability improvements.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">KNOWN ISSUES</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>More than 4 Battlefield Conditions can currently be active in a single Stratagem mission, but the selection menu will only show 4 of them. Will be fixed and limited to 4 in an upcoming hotfix.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, Focus lifted the lid on Space Marine 2's second year of DLC, confirming patches 10 all the way up to 15, which takes us up to the end of the second quarter of next year (June 2026). On the way is a new Battle Barge expansion and a new Siege map coming Q2 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Throughout the year, the Season Pass II will grant players nine new DLCs, with new Champion skins, armour pieces, and heraldry markings. While existing Chapters like the Blood Angels and Salamanders are to receive new cosmetics, fan-favorite Chapters like the Raptors, Iron Hands, and Carcharodons will get their due time in the spotlight.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-hotfix-101-stops-the-heroic-cadians-from-tanking-the-trygon-prime]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>