<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 23:47:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Players Have Run Into Some Wildly Low-Poly Monsters, and Now They're Posting Their Favorites]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-have-run-into-some-wildly-low-poly-monsters-and-now-theyre-posting-their-favorites</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-players-have-run-into-some-wildly-low-poly-monsters-and-now-theyre-posting-their-favorites.1025793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-have-run-into-some-wildly-low-poly-monsters-and-now-theyre-posting-their-favorites<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">More Minecraft than Monster Hunter.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom officially unleashed the Monster Hunter Wilds beta test for everyone on Thursday, and some players are finding that its creatures are a bit…flat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Monster Hunter series is known for many things, but its history of delivering creative, detailed monsters is easily one of its biggest draws. While the franchise’s next major entry, Wilds, will surely be no different when it launches early next year, those who hopped into its pre-release beta yesterday are finding that its monsters don’t look quite as they expected. Specifically, many creatures currently sport low-poly models that make them look like they just hopped straight of a PS1 game.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Wilds beta seems to be struggling with its polygons</p><p>Here's a thread of any comically low-poly <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MHWilds?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#MHWilds</a> images I come across that are too funny to ignore🧵:</p><p>Feel free to drop your own low-poly encounters</p><p>Starting off with a low poly Seikret <a href="https://t.co/ilbAUb7cet" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ilbAUb7cet</a></p></div>— TeaCommonShark (@khitwins) <a href="https://twitter.com/khitwins/status/1852264130734100559?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It's unclear what exactly is causing these low-poly monsters to infest the Monster Hunter Wilds beta, but it appears that PC players are being affected the most. While an issue as widespread as this would be a concern for players who just picked up a finished game, there are those who can’t help but find the fun in this visual glitch during this pre-launch test. Many, including X/Twitter user @khitwins, have taken the opportunity to collect their findings in <a href="https://x.com/khitwins/status/1852264130734100559" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a thread of posts</u></a> while asking others to do the same. Reddit user 5centipersecond took things a step further by creating <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1gh6d74/rey_dau_in_mhwildspc_style/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>fan art of a monster that looks more like a futuristic motorcycle</u></a>.</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">I had a terrifying low-poly Doshaguma encounter! <a href="https://t.co/1EzRAq0HIg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/1EzRAq0HIg</a></p>— Lemmy Laurent (@LaurentLemmy) <a href="https://twitter.com/LaurentLemmy/status/1852396183643164873?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Low poly Chatacabra <a href="https://t.co/do7Rhqv1HL" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/do7Rhqv1HL</a></p>— TeaCommonShark (@khitwins) <a href="https://twitter.com/khitwins/status/1852264132684451929?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The monsters are the cream of the crop – it really only gets funnier as you scroll through – but the angular models don’t stop at everyone’s favorite huntable creatures. Hunters and even fish have fallen ill to the polygonal virus as well, with players finding more than a few instances of flat people wandering around Monster Hunter Wilds, too.</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Screenshot taken by my friend while we were watching the cutscenes <a href="https://t.co/nHHoqXTioO" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/nHHoqXTioO</a></p>— 👹Itz_JustUkra👹 (@ItzUkra) <a href="https://twitter.com/ItzUkra/status/1852349220927184988?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">i thought it was my 2060 that was causing the issue 😭 <a href="https://t.co/j627WowoJl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/j627WowoJl</a></p>— bnuy (@SceledrusZER0) <a href="https://twitter.com/SceledrusZER0/status/1852401453769314599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">My start was a bit angular 😂😅 <a href="https://t.co/KdZ6NIbuuO" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/KdZ6NIbuuO</a></p>— Odder Autter (@Autter17) <a href="https://twitter.com/Autter17/status/1852388867665441136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">For now, Capcom has yet to comment on glitch. Let’s hope a fix arrives before launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds launches for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S on February 28, 2025. Despite the technical hiccups keeping players from seeing the monsters in all of their glory, the beta is off to a remarkably strong start. Today, we reported that it had reached <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-beta-is-off-to-a-wild-start-on-steam"><u>a peak of 463k players on Steam alone</u></a>, with the possibility to reach an even higher number on the way as the weekend rolls on. You can <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-reveals-trailer-and-open-beta-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-x-and-s-and-pc-next-week"><u>dive in for yourself</u></a> on any of the aforementioned platforms before the beta concludes Sunday, November 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Black Ops 6 November 1 Patch Fixes Troublesome Black Screen Glitch and Other Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-november-1-patch-fixes-troublesome-black-screen-glitch-and-other-issues</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-november-1-patch-fixes-troublesome-black-screen-glitch-and-other-issues.1025712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-november-1-patch-fixes-troublesome-black-screen-glitch-and-other-issues<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fixed exploits and squashed bugs arrive alongside Nukedown today.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Treyarch and Raven Software have published a small update for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 that fixes a number of issues across its Multiplayer and Zombies modes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision posted <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/10/bo6-preseason-patch-notes#nov1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>the patch notes on its website</u></a> today, bringing a list of changes ahead of Season 1’s launch later this month. This is the third patch to arrive since last weekend’s release and adds a host of tweaks and fixes for glitches big and small. Although the update largely focuses on Multiplayer and Zombies, it also includes a trio of universal touch-ups, including the removal of that pesky black screen glitch that has bothered players when trying to load into a match.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/09/codblops6-1725926226920.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 update brings fixes for Multiplayer and Zombies.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 6 Multiplayer adjustments include the removal of Lowtown from the Infected map pool while adding the same mode to Private Match’s list of available modes. Players will now find that the Shotgun Slug attachment deals the correct amount of damage, too. Stability improvements have also arrived to address hiccups revolving around the UAV Scorestreak, Infected medals, and the Vigilance Perk.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s typical for some players to take advantage of map exploits shortly after launch, and it’s also typical for the team at Activision to move quickly when squashing these exploits. Today’s update is no different, as it comes with a few patched exploits in the Zombies mode. Specifically, enjoyers of the round-based game mode will no longer be able to re-activate timed GobbleGums for extra use. Additionally, the Tactical Raft can no longer be used to block zombie paths on Terminus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 6 launched last Friday and has already positioned itself as one of the most successful Call of Duty games of all time. Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella said the release was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-biggest-call-of-duty-launch-ever-sets-new-single-day-game-pass-sub-record"><u>the series’ biggest launch ever</u></a> earlier this week. Call of Duty GM Matt Cox added, “Black Ops 6 is an amazing game, and the response from the Call of Duty community has been incredible. This is only the beginning.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Following the launch of the updated Nuketown map today, players can expect to dive into <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-gets-nuketown-this-week-as-activision-reveals-season-1-plans"><u>Black Ops 6 Season 1 when it launches November 14</u></a>. For more, you can check out our reviews for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-review"><u>Campaign</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-review"><u>Multiplayer</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-zombies-review"><u>Zombies</u></a> modes. As for the entry’s single-player offering, we gave it a 9/10, saying, “An excellent string of missions that offer variety and flexibility come together to make Black Ops 6 the best Call of Duty campaign in many, many years.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see the full patch notes from today’s update below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 November 1, 2024 Patch Notes</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">GLOBAL</h3>Stability <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where some players may encounter a black screen when loading into a public or private match for both Multiplayer and Zombies. </li></ul>Settings <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue when trying to select DLSS or DLAA in the upscaling options. </li></ul>UI <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue with the unlock notification for Diamond Mastery Badges.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">MULTIPLAYER</h3>Maps<ul data-cy="list"><li>Removed Lowtown from Infected map pool.</li></ul>Modes <ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Infected to Private Match mode select. </li><li>Resolved an issue in Free-For-All where scoring was based on total score rather than the number of elimination points.  </li><li>Resolved an issue in Search and Destroy where players could slide too far while defusing or planting the bomb. </li></ul>Weapons <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue with the Slug attachment on Shotguns dealing incorrect damage. </li></ul>Progression <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue where challenges requiring Dive Kills were not awarded properly.</li></ul>Stability <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue with stability when using the UAV. </li><li>Resolved an issue with stability in Infected when earning medals. </li><li>Resolved an issue with stability when using the Vigilance perk.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">ZOMBIES</h3>Gameplay <ul data-cy="list"><li>Closed an exploit that allowed players to re-activate timed GobbleGums. </li></ul>Enemies <ul data-cy="list"><li>Specials and Elites killed by scorestreaks will no longer drop items. </li></ul>Terminus <ul data-cy="list"><li>Closed an exploit that allowed players to block zombie pathing with the Tactical Raft. </li></ul>Liberty Falls <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue that prevented Scorestreaks from being used after completing the Main Quest. </li><li>Resolved an issue that would leave the player in spectator mode when dying after completing the Main Quest. </li></ul>Stability <ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue with stability when changing field upgrades. </li><li>Added various server-side stability fixes. </li></ul>UI <ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted round UI limit to 999 from 256. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>