<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 12:14:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Game Closures and a Declining Audience, Call of Duty Is in a Rough Spot — So What’s Next?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-game-closures-and-a-declining-audience-call-of-duty-is-in-a-rough-spot-so-whats-next</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-game-closures-and-a-declining-audience-call-of-duty-is-in-a-rough-spot-%E2%80%94-so-what%E2%80%99s-next.1193844/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-game-closures-and-a-declining-audience-call-of-duty-is-in-a-rough-spot-so-whats-next<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty fans are still digesting the news that Activision is walking away from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile">Warzone Mobile</a>, the game that was meant to lead the battle royale into a new era.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the weekend, Activision pulled Warzone Mobile from iOS and Android app stores, with the scope of the game being “streamlined" and an admission it had not met expectations. While servers will remain online for now, no new content or updates will be issued to the game, and players can no longer spend real money in it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We're proud of the accomplishment in bringing Call of Duty: Warzone to mobile in an authentic way, [but] it unfortunately has not met our expectations with mobile-first players like it has with PC and console audiences,” Activision said.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a brutal end for a game that clearly struggled right out of the gate. Warzone Mobile launched in March 2024 on iOS and Android as a Warzone-specific Call of Duty mobile experience that offered battle royale for up to 120 players, as well as cross-progression with the PC and console Warzone, Modern Warfare 2 and 3, and, later in the year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-review"><u>Call of Duty Warzone Mobile review</u></a> returned an 8/10. We said: "Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile includes all the best elements of Warzone, while speeding up and streamlining matches and using cross-progression to make this a meaningful extension of the traditional experience."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision’s hope was that Warzone Mobile would make a splash in the competitive mobile shooter market, where the hugely successful Call of Duty Mobile, developed by Tencent-owned TiMi Studio Group, is already established. With Call of Duty Mobile, which has seen 1 billion downloads since launch, revenue is shared between Activision and Tencent. Warzone Mobile, on the other hand, was developed entirely in-house at Activision, and so the company received a bigger slice of the money pie every time a player dropped cash on a battle pass or a cosmetic.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Top 10 Call of Duty Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But Warzone Mobile, which requires more powerful mobile phones than Call of Duty Mobile to work well, failed to meet Activision’s expectations, and its development team was scaled down when, in September last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-layoffs-hit-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-which-didnt-hit-as-big-as-hoped">Microsoft-wide layoffs hit across the games business</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Call of Duty fans, especially those who <em>did</em> play Warzone Mobile, have lamented the state of the game and indeed the franchise.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This game simply came out too early and wanted to be too greedy,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WarzoneMobile/comments/1kqdosx/what_a_huge_waste_i_feel_sorry_for_those_who/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said redditor Maddafragg</a>. “It could be seen on the Reddit videos, a lot of gameplay was not fluid with weird graphics, it could be seen that even if the game is playable, the device struggles to run it. The world of mobile gaming is cursed, it's not just Warzone that's dying. Dead by Daylight mobile and Star Wars hunter will also close the doors.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Turns out mobile games need to be optimized on most devices to be successful, you can't just cater to high end devices and hope your game succeed — it won't,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WarzoneMobile/comments/1kocpnv/warzone_mobile_is_officially_dead_now_what/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">added piegeamorue</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Greed is a dangerous thing. Activision was too greedy and when it leaked that they planned on killing CODM in favor of WZM they essentially turned tens of millions of people against the game. It became ‘us vs them’ and CODM is vastly more accessible than WZM — the loss was guaranteed.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What's next for Call of Duty, which appears to be in a tricky spot right now? Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/has-xboxs-call-of-duty-game-pass" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Game Business</a> reported that while Black Ops 6 launched big late last year, the Call of Duty franchise saw its users decline afterwards, and “more sharply” than in recent years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the relevant blurb:</p><blockquote>... the reality is that despite a strong start, Call of Duty has struggled to engage players to the degree it has in the past. According to Ampere, in March 2025, Call of Duty had 20.6 million players. That is still a huge number, but it’s slightly less than March 2024, which had 20.8 million players, and well down on March 2023, which saw 22.4 million players.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/verdansk-has-given-call-of-duty-warzone-a-shot-in-the-arm-and-its-developers-say-its-not-going-anywhere">The return of the much-loved Verdansk to Warzone did give the battle royale a much-needed shot in the arm</a>, but with the honeymoon period over and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/as-call-of-duty-warzone-cheating-complaints-ramp-up-following-the-return-of-verdansk-activision-insists-its-caused-chaos-in-the-cheat-marketplace-by-disrupting-over-150-cheat-resellers">accusations of rampant cheating once again dominating the narrative</a>, all eyes are on Activision and this year’s Call of Duty game to see if the still-huge first-person shooter franchise can reinvent itself once again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Related, there are a number of apparent datamined gameplay videos doing the rounds that show wall-running and even jet packs working in Black Ops 6. This, some believe, indicates this year's Black Ops 7 will ditch Activision’s ‘boots on the ground’ mantra for gameplay reminiscent of Black Ops 3.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">They also added jetpacks lol <a href="https://t.co/ZrFxLVfQkj" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ZrFxLVfQkj</a></p>— Bikou (@Kivikou) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kivikou/status/1924643962159030591?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 20, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">🚨‼️WALL RUNNING CONFIRMED FOR BO7‼️🚨<br>There is wall running in BO6 currently It is unclear if it's leftover from BO3 that managed to make it's way into a glitch through BO6 or if it's from BO7 and is left in the BO6 files. <a href="https://twitter.com/charlieINTEL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@charlieINTEL</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@ModernWarzone</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Dexerto?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Dexerto</a> <a href="https://t.co/0FJ0guUIEH" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/0FJ0guUIEH</a></p>— peter (@viipeter_) <a href="https://twitter.com/viipeter_/status/1924313756395360577?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 19, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Activision told IGN its teams are busy and moving forward on a variety of work, so hopefully we’ll see the fruits of that soon. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-confirms-xbox-games-showcase-2025-for-june-plus-the-outer-worlds-2-direct">Microsoft’s annual June Xbox showcase is around the corner</a>. Perhaps Call of Duty will turn up there. And, meanwhile, Call of Duty: Mobile is going strong, but, as we’ve pointed out, it’s not as lucrative a business for Activision, despite being bigger.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision Blizzard’s recent mobile struggles also call into question Microsoft’s $69 billion acquisition of the company itself, given Xbox boss Phil Spencer has made no secret that the decision was in part motivated by Xbox’s lofty mobile ambitions (Activision Blizzard owns King, the maker of phenomenally popular mobile game Candy Crush). Indeed, Microsoft plans to launch an app store of its own, taking on Apple and Google in the lucrative mobile game space.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Heart of Democracy Update Finally Brings the Illuminate Invasion to the Streets of Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth.1193802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> finally has Super Earth maps to fight on as part of the Heart of Democracy major update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-playstation-leak-suggests-players-will-fight-against-the-illuminate-on-super-earth-itself-next-week-and-now-gameplay-of-super-earth-mega-cities-has-leaked-too">As had leaked last week</a>, the Heart of Democracy update — out now across PC and PlayStation 5 — sees the Illuminate invasion reach Super Earth. You can now select missions on our home planet in Mega Cities and fight back alongside SEAF soldiers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The city biomes include operations that work towards liberating the cities, which, developer Arrowhead said, have “a significant impact on planetary campaigns.” This is a part of Helldivers 2’s ongoing Galactic War, a community-driven meta narrative that Arrowhead orchestrates behind the scenes.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The Illuminate have reached the Heart of Democracy. </p><p>Our Mega Cities are under siege. Liberty now hangs in the balance. The Ministry of Defence has authorised arsenal upgrades and placed SEAF soldiers on active duty. Today, we fight for the future of Super Earth! <a href="https://t.co/GxkrAQCmKD" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/GxkrAQCmKD</a></p></div>— HELLDIVERS™ 2 (@helldivers2) <a href="https://twitter.com/helldivers2/status/1924753084095307848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 20, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb, per the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/20/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-live-brings-the-fight-to-the-streets-of-super-earth/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>:</p><blockquote>The Helldivers are tasked with a new objective: to repel the Illuminate invasion by gaining ground over the squids as they fight to control areas where the fleet is landing. It won’t be a walk in the park, divers. Like a game of intergalactic tug-of-war, you will struggle against the incoming forces, gaining and losing control quickly.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">You can activate Planetary Defense Cannons and take down the Illuminate fleet, as shown in the trailer. And, as mentioned, SEAF troops will help join the fight to defend the cities. These small squads will fight enemies on their own, or they can be ordered to follow Helldivers and provide temporary backup as you navigate toward objectives. You do, however, need to be mindful of civilians who are still roaming the streets; Helldivers 2 is as much about friendly fire management as it is blowing aliens up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Heart of Democracy update is part of Arrowhead's long-term committment to keeping Helldivers 2 going for years to come following its record-breaking launch last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-our-main-focus-and-will-be-for-a-loooong-time-arrowhead-boss-insists-as-long-as-you-keep-playing-and-buying-super-credits-we-can-keep-it-going">Arrowhead CEO Shams Jorjani addressed player concern that the studio might leave the game behind to focus on its next project</a>, dubbed "Game 6."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Nah. It's ALL Helldivers 2 for now," he insisted. "A very, very small team will spin up something later this year and go at it sloowly. Helldivers is our main focus and will be for a loooong time."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, how long does Jorjani expect content updates for Helldivers 2 to last?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"As long as you folks keep playing and buying Super Credits we can keep it going," Jorjani said, pointing to Helldivers 2's virtual currency that's used to buy Premium Warbonds. "Last summer we were kinda screwing the pooch so it looked like we wouldn't be able to keep the train going for a long time - but we turned the ship around, you support us a lot so it's looking bright."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life Writer Marc Laidlaw Never Expected His 40-Year-Old Cyberpunk Story Would Be Turned Into a Love, Death and Robots Episode for Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix.1193739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc Laidlaw wrote 400 Boys in 1981 aged 21, long before he ended up Valve’s lead writer and one of the chief creators of the Half-Life games. The short story was published in Omni magazine in 1983, before it was picked up for Mirrorshades: The Cyberpunk Anthology and enjoyed a wider audience. <a href="https://www.marclaidlaw.com/online-fiction/400-boys/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On Marc’s website</a>, at the bottom of the short story itself, he points out 400 Boys has probably been read by more people than anything else he’s written, except perhaps Dota 2 seasonal ad copy. Yes, the video game world knows Marc Laidlaw as the lead writer of the Half-Life series. But he’s done a lot more than video games. It’s funny how things work out.</p><blockquote>In a post-apocalyptic city where warring gangs follow a bushido-like code of honor, a new gang, the 400 Boys, forces them to unite. A blend of beauty and brutality from Canadian director Robert Valley, whose LDR episode “Ice” won the Emmy for Outstanding Short Form Animation.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">“The inspiration for it just came out of walking around,” Marc remembers. “I lived in Eugene, Oregon and there was always the phone poles with the names of bands that were playing in town, and it was just name after name of super cool bands, and I just wanted a way to do that. I just wanted to make up lots of band names. So I came up with the idea of, if I have all these gangs in the story, I can come up with names for all these different gangs and that would be fun. And it was funny. That was kind of the thing that drove a big part of the story, just wanting to make band names.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/marc-laidlaw-1747728952628.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Marc Laidlaw is done with Half-Life, but not, it seems, the internet. Photo credit: Mimi Raver.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, over 40 years after 400 Boys was first published, it’s an episode of the fourth season of Netflix’s hugely popular animated anthology series <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/love-death-and-robots">Love, Death and Robots</a>. The episode was directed by Robert Valley, the director of Zima Blue in Season 1 and Ice in Season 2. Tim Miller wrote it. The voice cast includes John Boyega, who famously played Finn in Star Wars. All of a sudden, 400 Boys is having its big moment. Marc Laidlaw never expected this.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The story kind of faded out, but cyberpunk kept going and I didn't really think about it that much,” Laidlaw tells me over a video call just days before Season 4 of Love, Death and Robots kicks off on Netflix.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">40 years. That’s a long time for anything to be turned into something, isn’t it? But it might have happened earlier, around 15 years ago, when Tim Miller from Blur (the company that does all those fancy video game cutscenes and, these days, so much more), got in touch about maybe turning 400 Boys into something. It didn’t happen. Like so many projects, it fell apart following studio changes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then Love, Death and Robots exploded onto the scene in March 2019. This edgy, adult-oriented animated anthology was unlike anything we’d seen on the streamer. Some episodes were challenging, some were weird, some were weirdly challenging. Whatever they were, you couldn’t help but watch. And, Marc noticed, Tim Miller from Blur was involved. “I always say, I can't imagine anybody else who would've turned The Drowned Giant, this J. G. Ballard story, into an episode of an animated feature,” Marc says. “So I had a lot of respect for Tim just from that.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/400-boys-1747656689255.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">400 Boys is now an episode of Love, Death and Robots on Netflix. Image credit: Netflix.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc moved to Los Angeles in 2020 and, as the pandemic eased, met Tim a few times at various events around town. He didn’t want to push 400 Boys, but maybe, <em>just maybe</em>, if this Love, Death and Robots thing kept on going, maybe it would come back around. Then, a year ago, Marc got the ‘would you be interested in us optioning 400 Boys?’ email. It was finally happening.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc spoke with Tim, who took over the script, about the story itself. He says the episode is faithful to the source, but there’s some new stuff that helps sell the story visually. He had a couple conversations with Robert Valley, the director. He pointed him to the 400 Boys audiobook, which Marc narrated (“I did a reading of this back in the pandemic when everybody was trying to entertain people by posting audio books of their fiction and stuff on YouTube”).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But really, Marc wasn’t that involved. “It just was fun to sit back and not have to be involved in the trenches on something for once,” he says. “And I just kind of wanted to enjoy it when it was done and see what they made of it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And Marc has seen the episode, as you’d expect. “John Boyega and the characters and the accents and the setting is just so cool to me. I mean, they made the story just so much more fun visually, I think.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">400 Boys is, as Marc describes it, from “a different me from lifetimes ago.” Of course it is, he wrote it over 40 years ago when he was a young man. “I'm still pretty happy with it considering how young I was when I wrote it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then there was a long time of not much happening,” he says. And then, as we all know, Marc got into the games industry in 1997, into Valve as it was making Half-Life. “And that whole thing happened…”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Laidlaw “retired” from Valve in 2016, but it came across as a hard retirement from everything. In truth, he’s in a comfortable enough position to be able to do what he wants, pick his own projects and share them when they're done. “I think I retired too hard,” he admits. He never wanted to stop being creative. He wanted to get back to writing, but the publishing industry sort of disappeared while he was working on video games. Forget new video games, too. “I can't do games without a bunch of people. I can't make a game myself.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So Marc makes music now. He got a boost in audience after Valve’s Half-Life 2 anniversary documentary came out last year and he released a lost development video from the early days on his YouTube channel. “I'm like, I'm in the wrong business!” Marc jokes. “I should just be leaking information about my old employer.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Did it feel weird looking back at Half-Life all these years later for the Valve documentary, I wonder? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Yeah, it was good for me to just kind of process and put a bow on that stuff, see a bunch of old friends, think about that, the whole thing,” Marc says.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I hadn't talked to or seen a lot of those people for a long time. I still stay in touch with a few folks, but they're also not really there anymore. I don't know what's going on there right now, but it was fun to hang out with people and talk it over and it was therapeutic.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Half-Life and Half-Life 2 anniversary documentaries done and dusted, the only Valve game Marc might be asked to reminisce over now is Dota 2, which, ominously, is 12 years old. Perhaps in eight years Valve will come calling. “I could speak to Dota. That's the only thing left.” Unless, of course, Valve fancies doing something on Alien Swarm (“I did a little bit on Alien Swarm”).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is impossible, I find, to talk to Marc Laidlaw without talking about Half-Life. With those Valve documentaries out in the wild, there isn’t much left to say about the past. But maybe (hopefully?!) Half-Life has a future, and it’s that thread I want to pull on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There is no point asking Marc if he knows whether Half-Life 3 is in the works. As he says, he doesn’t really know the people still left at Valve, but even if he did, he’s not about to announce the game here in our interview. Can you imagine the email Gaben would send if he did?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It is a better use of our time, I think, to ask Marc if he’d ever write for a video game again. Marc says he is, generally, still open to writing for a video game, and suggests Hideo Kojima should perhaps have given him a call. “When Death Stranding came out, I just was grinding my teeth. Like, does he know I'm available? I'd be happy to help do the last polish of dialogue on your script and not wreck anything, but just make it lines that actors would sound better coming out of their mouth.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc, as he alluded to earlier, “retired really hard,” and he thinks that because of that, the industry doesn’t think to ask him to do anything. “When I see the Miyazaki stuff, the From studio stuff, of course you go to George R. R. Martin first if you could. Nobody needs my name on their project to sell copies. But I mean, that kind of thing to me is exciting.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The lack of interesting offers post-Valve came as something of a surprise, Marc says. “I did kind of expect more interesting offers of stuff to do afterward and was kind of like, ‘this is weird: somebody wants me to write their synopsis for their mobile phone laser tag game.' It's like, they don't know what I do.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wait, really? Someone actually asked Marc Laidlaw to write a mobile phone laser tag game after he left Valve? “Those are the kind of things I would get,” Marc admits. “I'm like, ‘I don't know that I have much to offer you guys, but I mean, I don't really like to say no to stuff.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc continues: “I haven't really heard any interesting game offers that seemed right for me. People think of me as, you can come in and write a bunch of stuff for a game. I'm like, 'do you notice how little writing there was in Half-Life?' Sort of the point of it was I hated reading in games.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And then the inevitable interview-closer: if Valve gave Marc Laidlaw a call and said, ‘we want to get the band back together for Half-Life 3,’ would he answer that call?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I would not do that,” he replies, matter of factly. “I can definitely say I would not do that. Even when I was there, I started to feel like, ‘Oh, now I'm the old guy shooting stuff down.’ I think at some point you need to let the people who are the fans and the creators who've come in because of what they learned from you maybe, and let them have that. We need new stuff. We didn't need me going, ‘Well, the G-Man wouldn't do that in my day.’ And I found I had to restrain myself. People would get enthusiastic about stuff, and I felt like it was becoming a negative force on some of the creative process.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I haven't played the VR Half-Life: Alyx, so I don't really feel like I can. I don't know what's going on with anything. And it is not really my place. God knows what it's doing in terms of creative process of how to get a great experience that will surprise people. And you have to be right at the edge of what you can do in a moment. And I'm not on that edge anymore. That's not what's interesting to me at this point. So I don't think I'd be good.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Plus, I'm one of the older guys, maybe not the oldest, but it's so much work. I mean, I don't think I could do that anymore. I get into my own things, but it's not on anyone else's schedule. And yeah, I'm pretty much done. I mean, maybe not done with games altogether, but definitely the Half-Life part of my life is way behind me.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, that’s that. Half-Life is done with Marc Laidlaw, and Marc Laidlaw is done with Half-Life. But there’s a lot more he’s done in the past that’s relevant now. Just look at Netflix making 400 Boys, 40 years later. Maybe, at some point in the future, Netflix will knock on Valve’s door and ask to turn Half-Life into something. Then Marc Laidlaw can go through all this all over again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The fact that I got into the cyberpunk thing before it was called cyberpunk, and then I came across this sort of beginning game company that ended up making Half-Life… I've been lucky to be a part of these things that just kind of become phenomena.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deliver At All Costs Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deliver-at-all-costs-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deliver-at-all-costs-review.1193736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deliver-at-all-costs-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As far as package-shipping simulators go, Deliver At All Costs more closely resembles drunk driving than it does <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-stranding">Death Stranding</a>. There's no need for complicated weight management or careful navigation through its 1950s small-town USA setting; instead, this kooky courier quest loads your pickup truck with increasingly quirky cargo and sends you careening through road signs, fences, shopfronts, and countless pedestrians, with almost every dispatched delivery quickly devolving into a full-on destruction derby. It’s a riotously good time for a while, but it soon starts to sputter out and eventually breaks down well before it reaches the end of its 10-hour journey when its nonsensical sci-fi story fails to pay off and this world turns out to be far more rewarding to reduce to rubble than it is to actually explore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There is a plot connecting all of its street-shredding shipments, but honestly the less said about it, the better. You’re Winston Green, a likeable fresh hire at the We Deliver corporation who’s seemingly on the run after a mysterious incident in his past. Though it begins as a sort of goofy workplace comedy it soon makes jarring tonal shifts into corporate crime conspiracies and eventually a preposterous tale of time travel, before crashlanding into a fast-tracked climax that left me feeling about as hollow as someone who’s tried to make a meal out of packing peanuts. Deliver At All Costs’ story is a bit like a box of flatpacked furniture delivered from IKEA; it’s full of interesting parts to pore over, but once you’ve put it all together it seems noticeably wonkier than you expected and it’s clear that there’s more than a couple of screws loose.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Deliver At All Costs Review Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The real star is the staggering destructibility of its world, which is viewed from your choice of two top-down angles. Pretty much everything above ground can be satisfyingly smashed asunder as you tear around in your delivery truck turning every apartment block into a potential Jenga tower. There’s admittedly an overly fragile and weightless feel to it all – it’s a bit like crashing through houses made of cards rather than bricks and mortar because you rarely feel the impact or lose momentum – but punching my own shortcuts through everything from hotel lobbies to tennis courts and tombstone-covered graveyards kept me consistently amused for at least the first half of the drive. I gleefully sped around chewing through scenery like I was Nicholas Cage in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/faceoff-1997">Face/Off</a>. Pretty much the only time I pumped the brakes was when I had to keep something from spilling out of my truckbed, or whenever I hit one of the abrupt loading screens that separates each district of the three cities that make up its decently sized open-world map. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Can’t Hardly Freight</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Deliver At All Costs’ 20-mission-long chain of violent cargo hauls aren’t so much door-to-door as they are wall-through-wall, but that’s not to say I didn’t face some resistance along the way. Different challenges are introduced in keeping with the object that’s dumped into the back of your truck or dragged behind you with a winch, and a few entertainingly wacky work orders had me laughing out loud. In one mission reminiscent of Pixar’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/up">Up</a>, I was hired to transport a bouquet of helium balloons, which meant that even the smallest bump in the road launched me into a clumsy aerial drift that left me struggling to stay on terra firma like a mailman on the moon’s surface. In another, I had to steer around a leaking tank of napalm that was igniting a growing wall of fire behind me, turning a simple pick-up and drop-off into a citywide game of Snake that blew me to smithereens if I attempted to double back on my delivery route.Then there was the time I had to drag a new statue of the local mayor towards the town square without it getting bombed by the swooping seagulls dropping their own special deliveries. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I gleefully sped around chewing through scenery like I was Nicholas Cage in Face/Off.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, though, there are almost as many duds in the mix as there are standouts. Being asked to drive recklessly to scare a limousine full of crooked executives doesn’t really come as a break from the norm when you’ve been otherwise hurtling around like a madman during each and every other job, for example. A mission to photograph a series of cows being abducted by a UFO can be passed simply by mindlessly spamming the camera button. Meanwhile, the on-foot retrieval of your stolen truck from under the nose of a patrolling security van becomes less of a daring infiltration into a scrapyard and more of a walk in the park because Deliver At All Costs’ stealth system is non-existent, to the point where you can just stroll in there unopposed with minimal thought or effort. That’s not to say the rest of the on-foot action is much better – pretty much whenever you’re forced to leave your car for more than a moment it becomes a dull stretch of basic platforming where your only actions are walk, jump, climb, and shove. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Haul or Nothing</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere in Deliver At All Costs there’s rarely any substantial consequences for your actions, and that makes it start to get dull sooner than it seems like it should. If you accidentally flip your car over it will automatically right itself. If you bust a tyre you can hop out and instantly repair it with the tap of a button. If you bring down an entire building because you’re doing doughnuts through all four corners of its foundations you will almost certainly draw the attention of the police (who, the intro movie explains, are all but non-existent in this island town), but you can instantly lose that heat by leaving your truck and diving into a dumpster – even without necessarily breaking the line of sight. In fact, even if you’re caught, you just instantly respawn with no punishment served anyway. On the one hand, the general lack of rules or repercussions gave me the freedom to drive as recklessly as I wanted to, but it also meant that almost everything felt noticeably low in stakes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sometimes, in fact, Deliver At All Costs is so forgiving that it completely sucks any tension out of the task at hand. Steering your delivery truck from one side of the city to the other with an armed atom bomb couched in its cargo bed shouldn’t just have you flirting with danger, but buying danger a drink, beckoning danger onto the dance floor, and giving danger an open-mouthed kiss. But in practice, it’s surprisingly lacking in intensity: there’s no ticking clock to pressure you into keeping your foot clamped down on the accelerator, allowing you to take things as slow and steady as you like. That means the only challenge here is to <em>not</em> drive like a maniac. Even when I did accidentally bump into a car and blow myself to bits, generous checkpoints meant that I was back on the road with my unstable payload with minimum penalty to my progress. I don’t want a game to be overly punishing, but there’s a happy medium to be struck that this one never manages to nail.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Sometimes Deliver At All Costs is so forgiving that it completely sucks any tension out of the task at hand. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, and despite the consistently impressive amount of environmental detail to be found throughout its toy town world from Christmas tree-lined main streets to a giant drive-in theater projecting black and white films, there’s not a great deal of interesting activities to amuse yourself with when you’re off the clock. There are a further 10 side missions to be found dotted around the map, but few of them are particularly memorable. There’s a basic circuit race to place first in and a couple of missing persons to track down, but there’s little here to match the more creative courier tasks found in the main story path. Well, there’s one enjoyable exception that had me piloting a satanic sports car straight out of Stephen King’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/christine">Christine</a>. Deliver At All Costs could’ve used a lot more like her to make its map call me back for more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are other unique vehicles to track down too, but these are uniformly disappointing on a number of counts. For one, their locations are clearly marked on the map from the outset, so you’re not provided with the same thrill of discovery of, say, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon</a> barn find. You also don’t have a garage to store them in, and nor can you use them for a delivery mission, so they’re mainly there for a brief joyride before being ditched in favour of a return to your trusty We Deliver truck. Worse still, they don’t provide any real point of difference to make them even remotely worth the minimal effort to uncover – they each handle more or less the same, and there are no unique emergency missions to undertake in the ambulance or dessert drops in the ice cream van to trigger like you might find in a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto</a> game. They’re just sort of… there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another underwhelming factor is the upgrades you can weld onto your truck using spare parts found throughout the world (as ridiculous as it may be to open a giant chest to find someone has stashed a single roll of duct tape in it). They seem like they should open up new possibilities for mayhem and creativity in a world that’s as eager to be knocked down as this, but these, too, are disappointingly limited in their use. The crane is handy for the job that sees you load a giant marlin onto your truck and then literally fishtail your way to a drop-off point, but both it and the winch you get access to afterwards can’t actually be used outside of a mission to mess with objects at will. You can’t, say, attach the winch’s tow cable to a random car or pedestrian and drag them around town just for kicks like you can in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/saints-row">Saints Row</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/just-cause">Just Cause</a>. You can supercharge your car horn to blast the windows out of shopfronts, but you can't use the cargo bed catapult at all outside of a handful of specific story moments. There’s a lot of potential for Deliver At All Costs to achieve the same sort of freeform fun that we see in games like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/goat-simulator">Goat Simulator</a>, but it just doesn’t give you enough flexibility to really revel in it after you’ve grown tired of blasting into people’s living rooms like a Kool-Aid Man on wheels.
</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Tristan's Favourite Destruction Games</h3><p>Break @#$% like you're Fred Durst!</p></div></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">In its best moments, Deliver At All Costs is as entertaining as it is uneven. For every truly creative cargo haul twist there’s another that’s uninspired or lacking in intensity and urgency, and although there’s certainly fun to be had crashing through its many structures like a bully through a sand castle, the novelty wears off long before it ends and all you’re left with is an impressively realised 1950s world with depressingly little else to do in it. Throw in a silly, slapdash story and some toys for your truck you’re largely forbidden from playing with, and Deliver At All Costs is one shipment that’s far from the complete package.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Developer Naughty Dog Working on a Second, Unannounced Game Other Than Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Neil Druckmann Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms.1193721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Naughty Dog chief Neil Druckmann has revealed the studio has a secret, unannounced second game in the works other than <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p08x7kb5" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Press X to Continue podcast</a>, Druckmann discussed his ongoing roles at Sony-owned Naughty Dog. On Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Druckmann works with two game directors: Matthew Gallant and Kurt Margenau, and is co-writing the game with narrative director Claire Carré. Druckmann did not say which director is working on the second game, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There’s another game that’s being worked on at Naughty Dog where I am more of a producer role and I get to mentor and watch this other team and give feedback and be like the executive in the room,” he said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I enjoy all those roles, and the fact I jump between one to the next, it makes my job very exciting and always feeling fresh. I’m never bored.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is unclear at which stage each game is in production. Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is announced, so you’d imagine it’s further along. But what is the second game?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some obvious candidates. Could it be The Last of Us 3? Druckmann has expressed his uncertainty in the past about being able to make the game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/if-there-is-no-the-last-of-us-3-would-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-keep-the-tv-show-going-past-the-games">but has said he has an ending in mind for what the game would be</a>. Based on Druckmann’s comments about having more of a producer role on this mystery second game, it doesn’t sound like it’s The Last of Us 3, as you’d imagine he’d want to be heavily involved and take on a director role for that game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alternatively, it could be another Uncharted game. There hasn’t been a brand new Uncharted game since 2017’s The Lost Legacy. Could it finally be time for a return? And there’s always a chance this second game could be a brand new intellectual property, as Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that there’s always a chance this second game never comes out, or is never properly revealed by Sony. Naughty Dog has endured a tumultuous time in recent years, with the cancelation of its The Last of Us multiplayer game to focus on single-player games coming amid an apparent pull-back of live service titles at Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-game-cancelled-will-focus-on-single-player-games-going-forward"><u>Naughty Dog stopped development on The Last of Us Online</u></a> in December 2023, saying it would have needed to put all its resources into post-launch content for years to come — an approach that would have severely impacted its ability to develop future single-player games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Historically, Naughty Dog has struggled to work on two big games at the same time, with one tending to end up top of the tree internally. The studio hasn’t released a brand new game since 2020’s The Last of Us 2, with remakes and collections in the interim.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/gettyimages-2208060751-1747724906242.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Neil Druckmann says Naughty Dog is working on a second game. Photo by Rich Polk/Deadline via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, it features a star-studded cast that includes Tati Gabrielle from the Uncharted movie as protagonist Jordan A. Mun, and Kumail Nanjiani of Marvel's Eternals as a man called Colin Graves. It is not expected to release until 2027 at the earliest. It’s a pretty long wait, but speaking to IGN on the red carpet ahead of The Last of Us Season 2 premiere, Druckmann said that Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is not only playable right now, but “really good.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I will say we are playing it at the office and it's incredible,” Druckmann teased. “It's really good. I'm so excited to finally put gameplay out into the world and show people about it, because we just showed you the very, very, very tip on the iceberg. The game goes pretty deep beyond that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Rich Polk/Deadline via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>