<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.ign.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.ign.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:35:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Players Stunned After Exploit Hotfix Results in Widespread Reports of a New Inventory Glitch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-stunned-after-exploit-hotfix-results-in-widespread-reports-of-a-new-inventory-glitch</link>
            <guid>1433080</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders"><u>Arc Raiders</u></a> players have gathered to applaud Embark Studios after it took just one day to tackle new duplication and infinite ammo exploits – even though reports of a new inventory glitch have already popped up in their place.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The developer behind the successful extraction shooter published a hotfix addressing a variety of issues today, defying the expectations of fans who thought the latest exploits would be around for nefarious players to take advantage of for days, if not weeks. Initially, at least, it resulted in a wave of positive comments from fans.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">🛠️Attention, Raiders!<br>We've just deployed a new hotfix to address additional reported issues:<br>• Fixed an inventory slot mechanic duplication glitch<br>• Fixed an infinite ammo weapon glitch<br>• Fixed an issue where some quests were missing from the Headwinds update<br>• Fixed an… <a href="https://t.co/xv0k1dIQ1t" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/xv0k1dIQ1t</a></p>— ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/2021602130323227105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 11, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">“Say what you want about embark,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1r1zvfy/comment/o4t6g0y/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user commented</u></a>, “but this was QUICK!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Dude I was literally in firing range, tried it (successfully), went back to Speranza to grab a bobcat and give it a 100 round mag in practice range, and it just stopped working,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1r1zvfy/comment/o4t953g/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Insane work Embark, I didn't even restart my client.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders has suffered from those looking to take advantage of dupe exploits since its launch in October, and Embark has played whac-a-mole with cheaters and exploiters since. This was the case earlier this week, when the Stockholm-based studio launched <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-gets-pve-focused-event-and-new-rewards-as-embark-squashes-duplication-bug-in-new-update"><u>an update</u></a> fixing the latest dupe glitch only to find reports of a new one cropping up shortly after.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s an annoyance for players, who are often forced to confront Raiders who have earned their items and in-game currency through illegitimate means, and it’s apparently keeping Embark up at night, too. As players – and even popular streamer <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/theburntpeanut/clip/KnottyFineSwallowSaltBae-7izWpIHRKvqiEVO6?filter=clips&amp;range=24hr&amp;sort=time" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>TheBurntPeanut</u></a> – began showcasing examples of the latest glitches, the developer launched the new hotfix, bringing adjustments just one day after its last patch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to fixing the inventory slot mechanic duplication glitch and infinite ammo weapon glitch, the update tackles two bugs related to quests. Embark says it is “dedicated to investigating and squashing exploits” in Arc Raiders and will “keep you in the loop” regarding future issues. The problem is, these issues are already here, with what appears to be hundreds of players already taking to various Arc Raiders social media accounts to share that they’ve been impacted by a new problem.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🚨BREAKING 🚨 Since today's hotfix to fix the infinite ammo glitch, there are many reports of Raiders losing their loot when they extract. Be careful out there!</p><p>🎥u/hellfire13 <a href="https://t.co/zyO56MAydV" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/zyO56MAydV</a></p></div>— ARC Raiders PVP (@ArcRaidersPVP) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArcRaidersPVP/status/2021659705484226879?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 11, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Reports related to a separate glitch, which seemingly robs players of their topside inventory when extracting, appeared moments after today’s hotfix went live. It’s unclear if this is an ongoing issue or if the lost loot bug is only affecting those who were mid-raid while the hotfix was published. The confusion has been enough to see fans directly ask Embark for their loot to be returned, while others worry a new topside run could result in them losing their gear, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Embark,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1r20hlf/since_the_infinite_ammo_hotfix_players_are_now/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>player said</u></a>, “come on guys.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Damn, they fix one thing and break something else entirely,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1r20hlf/comment/o4tekrs/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>replied</u></a>. “Good lookin out!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's unclear how the Embark team plans to handle the latest Arc Raiders glitch. For now, at least, it seems some of its community managers are working with fans to determine the cause.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Arc Raiders team can’t catch a break, at least when it comes to cheaters and exploits. Since laying out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-promises-significant-changes-after-players-report-widespread-issues-with-cheaters">a plan to deal with widespread reports of cheaters</a> last month, the studio has done its best to keep players coming back with frequent gameplay adjustments, new content, and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-roadmap-promises-a-new-map-more-arcs-and-even-a-little-love-for-scrappy-by-april-2026"><u>four-month roadmap</u></a>. Its post-launch plan currently has it sitting in the middle of its Headwinds update, with its next chapter, Shrouded Sky, set to bring a new map condition, a new Arc threat, and more later this month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, you can check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-arc-raiders-interview-embark-boss-patrick-sderlund-talks-live-service-plans-banning-cheaters-and-the-secret-sauce-of-pve"><u>our interview with Embark CEO Patrick Söderlund</u></a>, where we talked about the past, present, and future of Arc Raiders. During our chat, we also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/huge-success-of-arc-raiders-gives-embark-financial-security-and-employment-stability-75-million-budget-estimate-not-too-far-off"><u>learned more about what’s next for the company following its extraction shooter’s success</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-stunned-after-exploit-hotfix-results-in-widespread-reports-of-a-new-inventory-glitch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight: Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-30th-anniversary-spotlight-everything-announced-updating-live</link>
            <guid>1433077</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Blizzard Entertainment tied a bow on its Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight after showing off how the Warlock class will take over <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/diablo-iv">Diablo 4</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/diablo-immortal">Diablo Immortal</a>, and even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/diablo-ii-resurrected">Diablo 2: Resurrected</a> in 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 40-minute presentation came to a close after giving fans a sneak peek at a dungeon’s worth of updates across its three Diablo pillars. Highlights include the reveal that the Warlock is coming to Diablo 4 and Immortal in April and June, respectively, and it’s out for Diablo 2: Resurrected with The Reign of the Warlock DLC right now. While new content definitely stole the show, the Blizzard team still made sure to offer deep dives into some of the quality-of-life updates players have been expecting, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you’re looking to learn more about the Lord of Hatred expansion or revisit a beloved early 2000s action RPG, we’ve gathered all of the highlights from today’s show. You can see everything announced at the Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">The Warlock Class Is Coming to Diablo 4, Diablo Immortal, and Diablo 2: Resurrected</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Players expected the Warlock to come to Diablo 4, but they didn't expect this. In addition to Diablo 4: Lord of Hatred, the Warlock is coming to Diablo Immortal and, yes, even Diablo 2: Resurrected. It's an unexpected update that brings the class to all three of today's games, with the full spotlight detailing how each offers different playstyles for different kinds of action RPG fans.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Blizzard Is Summoning the Reign of the Warlock for Diablo 2: Resurrected</h2><blockquote data-theme="light">— Diablo (@Diablo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Diablo/status/2021721334435205162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 11, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Blizzard’s 2021 reimagining might be a mostly faithful remake of a classic game, but that doesn’t mean it can’t add to it. To celebrate the 30th anniversary of the franchise, Diablo 2: Resurrected is getting a new expansion called Reign of the Warlock – and it’s out today for PC (including Steam), PlayStation, and Xbox for $24.99.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The content adds the demon-summoning Warlock as an all-new class not present in the original experience. It allows players to summon, bind, and devour demons, shaking up the Diablo 2 formula for the first time in 25 years.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Blizzard Talks Terror Zones in Diablo 2</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">With Reign of the Warlock comes a few tweaks to Terror Zones. Specifically, players can now be stalked by hunters called Heralds of Terror when playing on Hell difficulty. Terrorized bosses beaten on the same difficulty mode also now unveil statues, with players encouraged to combine five of them to access new endgame bosses called the Colossal Ancients.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Quality-of-Life Adjustments Add Loot Filers, Advanced Stash Tabs, and More to Diablo 2: Resurrected</h2><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">The new quality of life changes in Reign of the Warlock give you sharper tools for even the darkest of journeys. <a href="https://t.co/yOWzcZ9my6" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/yOWzcZ9my6</a></p>— Diablo (@Diablo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Diablo/status/2021717067406487856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 11, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Now, time for what most fans expected when they heard Diablo 2: Resurrected would be featured at the Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight: quality-of-life changes. Blizzard now allows players to create, share, and check out community loot filters, all without the use of mods. The update also comes with the ability to stack stash items alongside the addition of dedicated tabs for materials, gems, and runes. Finally, The Chronicle is an item tracker for players who like their Diablo experience to be nice and organized.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">A First Look at the Warlock in Diablo Immortal</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/11/diablo-immortal-warlock-1770852504435.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Diablo Immortal Warlock Class. Image courtesy of Blizzard.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This June, Blizzard is bringing the Warlock to Diablo Immortal. This version of the summoning class utilizes demon skull, a sacrificial blade, and a beast known as the Soulgorger. The Warlock will get her own origin quest explaining her backstory at an unspecified point in the future.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Lut Gholein Joins the Warlock in Diablo Immortal</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">That previously teased location coming to Diablo Immortal is none other than Lut Gholein. Players will find the iconic location has been split between its Common Ward and High Ward districts, with Blizzard explaining that it pulled inspiration from real-world Moroccan cities when bringing it back to life.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Return of the Demon Queen Andariel</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Diablo Immortal's next "big bad" is the Maidan of Anguish, Andariel. She's sporting a new look, too, with associate art director Emil Salim describing her as "domineering, equal parts regal, and sadistic," adding that "she's driven by nothing less than a desire for dark godhood."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Diablo Immortal Roadmap Sets Fire to 2026</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/11/diablo-immortal-roadmap-1770852022171.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Diablo Immortal Roadmap 2026. Image courtesy of Blizzard.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Diablo Immortal team has big plans for 2026. A roadmap shared during the 30th Anniversary Spotlight showed off just a few of the updates players can expect in the coming months, with some examples including a new battleground event and updates to classic zones. Expect a new subzone, along with new monsters and bounties, every quarter, too.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Yes, the Second Diablo 4: Lord of Hatred Class is the Warlock</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If the leaks and rumors weren’t enough to give it away, the Warlock is officially confirmed to join the Paladin when Lord of Hatred launches for PC, PlayStation, and Xbox April 28. Blizzard plans to share more about the new Diablo 4 class during a developer update that’s set to take place March 5.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Lord of Hatred Is More Than Just a Class Expansion</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight gave fans a first look at how Lord of Hatred expands on Diablo 4 with Skovos and its many mountains and temples. Today’s presentation focuses on Temis, the location’s capital city and an area that holds more information about the Askari, the Prime Evils, and the origins of Santuary.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Skill Trees and the Talisman System</h2><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Forge a brand new path through Sanctuary with the all-new skill tree system coming to Diablo IV: Lord of Hatred 🌳 <a href="https://t.co/UBMf4gX5wl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/UBMf4gX5wl</a></p>— Diablo (@Diablo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Diablo/status/2021718519596097808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 11, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Major changes are coming to Diablo 4, regardless of whether you choose to pick up Lord of Hatred. Referring to a running joke that has seen players calling the game’s skill trees “skill twigs,” associate game director Zaven Haroutunian unveiled a closer look at the skill tree rework launching with the expansion this April.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Blizzard team says it’s about giving players “meaningful choices and options” from the get-go, calling it a “major disruption to the current class system.” One example shown during the presentation highlights the Sorcerer’s Hydra skill, which players can fine-tune to increase attack speed, launch explosions, and even use frost projectiles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Talisman, meanwhile, is a new itemization system with Lord of Hatred that brings back charms and sets. Footage of the foundational update teases more ways for players to customize their builds to their playstyle.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">“They’re going to freak out…”</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Game director Brent Gibson closed out the Diablo 30th Anniversary Spotlight with a tease of what’s to come. In a tongue-in-cheek moment just before the event reached its conclusion, Gibson says, “Oh, my god. They’re going to freak out at BlizzCon when we announce—.” There’s no telling what exactly Diablo fans have to look forward to, but it at least sounds like Blizzard has plans to pull back the curtain when BlizzCon takes place September 12 - 13.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-30th-anniversary-spotlight-everything-announced-updating-live]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Secretlab Presidents Day Sale Is Your Chance to Score a Great Deal on the Ultimate Gaming Chair]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-presidents-day-sale-gaming-chair-deals-february-2026</link>
            <guid>1432948</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/QqJ72D?object_uuid=ba24a8d5-2b80-4ea6-b5a4-ff6451792eaf&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Secretlab Presidents Sale</a> has officially commenced and with it are a couple of different promotions that are running concurrently (some are stackable). For starters, you can save up to $139 off across Secretlab's lineup of Titan Evo gaming chairs and Magnus gaming desks, including themed editions from One Piece, Jujutsu Kaisen, Star Wars, Demon Slayer, and more. Secretlab's highest-end gaming chair, the Titan Evo Nanogen, has also ben discounted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to these instant discounts, you can get extra tiered savings by hitting a certain order amount for each category. These should be stackable with the instant discounts, although some themes are excluded.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Extra $40 off Chair orders of $850+ with code "<strong>SLEV-MINCPRES26</strong>"</li><li>Extra $50 off Desk orders of $1,489+ with code: "<strong>SLEV-MINDPRES26</strong>"</li><li>$100 off all orders of $1,999+ with code: "<strong>SLEV-MINSWPRES26</strong>"</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Secretlab's Genshin Impact themed gaming chairs gets some love of its own. The Ninguang and and Xiao inspired gaming chairs are on sale as well, to coincide with the Lantern Rite event that's going on right now in-game.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save $50 off Secretlab Titan Evo gaming chairs</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Titan Evo is Secretlab's most iconic and best selling chair.  Over 70 different styles are currently on sale, with prices ranging from $529 to $634 after a $50 off instant discount across the entire lineup. It's available in small, medium, and large sizes, which is great for smaller people because most gaming chairs sold here in the United States are huge. Discounted upholstery optioins include Neo Hybrid leatherette and SoftWeave Plus fabric.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Signature features include a solid steel frame with aluminum wheelbase, firm and supportive cold-cure foam upholstery, adjustable four-way lumbar system, full length backrest with 165 degrees of recline, full metal 4D armrests with magnetically attached PU cushions, and a memory foam headrest pillow. Check out our own <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-titan-evo-2022-review">glowing Titan Evo review</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Genshin Impact themed chairs see their first discount ever</h2><div id="235414"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="235414" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Titan Evo Genshin Edition (Xiao)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="235415"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="235415" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Titan Evo Genshin Edition (Xiao)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Genshin Impact's annual <a href="https://www.hoyoverse.com/en-us/news/162178" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lantern Rite in-game event</a> is going on right now, coinciding with the actual Chinese New Year, which lands on February 17. In celebration of the event, Secretlab has discounted two Genshin themed chairs inspired by Liyue characters: Xiao, an anemo adeptus, and Ningguang, the geo-wielding Tianquan of the Liyue Qixing (she's basically a royal). This is the first time a Genshin chair has gone on sale, so if you're a Hoyoverse superfan, don't miss it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Secretlab's flagship Titan Evo Nanogen is also on sale</h2></div><div id="210628"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="210628" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Titan Evo Nanogen Edition</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjGqGP?object_uuid=ba24a8d5-2b80-4ea6-b5a4-ff6451792eaf&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Titan Evo Nanogen Edition</a> is Secretlab's highest end chair and is rarely discounted. It normally sells for $799 at Secretlab direct, but both the white and black colors have been discounted by $50 during the Presidents Day Sale. If your budget can accomodate it, this is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-gaming-chairs">the best gaming chair</a>. In our recent <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-titan-evo-nanogen-edition-review">Titan Evo Nanogen Edition review</a>, Chris Coke wrote that "the Secretlab Titan Evo Nanogen Edition deserves every bit of the overwhelming praise I’ve given... The Titan Evo Nanogen Edition is class-leading, and is hands-down the most comfortable gaming chair I’ve ever used."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Sadly, Titan Evo Pokemon Edition preorders aren't discounted</h2></div><div id="234674"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234674" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Titan Evo Pokemon Eevee Edition</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="234675"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234675" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Titan Evo Pokemon Gengar Edition</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="234676"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234676" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Titan Evo Pokemon Pikachu Edition</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Secretlab's recently announced <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/now-you-can-show-off-your-favorite-pokmon-on-a-secretlab-titan-evo-gaming-chair">lineup of Pokémon gaming chairs</a> is, not surprisingly, still listed at full price. Even so, these chairs are so cool that they're worth a mention. These chairs showcase one of three iconic Pokémon - Gengar, Pikachu, and Eevee - with ostentatious use of color, patterns, and figures. My personal favorite is the Eevee edition, with its detailed embossing of Eevee's myriad evolutions; it also seems to be the top seller, since it's already on its third wave of preorders.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unusual for a collab, Secretlab opted to go with its Softweave Plus fabric instead of leatherette, and I for one am happy with that decision. Fabric ages more gracefully, feels softer, and doesn't stick to your sweaty skin on hot days.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save $30 off the Titan Evo recliner add-on (it's worth it)</h2></div><div id="210629"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="210629" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Titan Recliner Add-On</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Also on sale for the first time, Secretlab's <a href="https://zdcs.link/QGVkVV?object_uuid=ba24a8d5-2b80-4ea6-b5a4-ff6451792eaf&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">new recliner add-on</a> is $30 off for Christmas. This is a nice upgrade for anyone who already owns the Titan Evo chair. In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-ergonomic-recliner-add-on-review">recliner add-on review</a>, Chris Coke wrote that "while both comfort and value are subjective things, the recliner is able to take the Titan Evo and transform it from one of the best racing style gaming chairs to standing head and shoulders above the competition at its price point."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Secretlab Magnus deals are also on sale, including Genshin</h2></div><div id="210619"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="210619" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Magnus</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="206780"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="206780" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Magnus Pro</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="235416"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="235416" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Secretlab Magnus Pro Genshin Edition</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Liyue themed Desk Mat is included</p></div></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Not only are the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbnqnr?object_uuid=ba24a8d5-2b80-4ea6-b5a4-ff6451792eaf&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Magnus</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yw7w2?object_uuid=ba24a8d5-2b80-4ea6-b5a4-ff6451792eaf&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Magnus Pro</a> discounted for Presidents Day, you also get the desk mat topper (your choice of style) free of charge. The Magnus is a traditional fixed-frame gaming desk while the Magnus Pro ups the ante with practical electric sit-stand functionality. Both desks feature a metal desktop surface, solid steel frame, and clever cable management, but the Magnus Pro has some unique features including a power cable that runs internally inside one of the telescoping legs and an in-line control panel. Check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-magnus-pro-standing-desk-review">Magnus Pr0 review</a> review for hands-on impressions.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Secretlab has the best "racing-style" gaming chairs</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">It's no secret that we love our Secretlab gaming chairs. Three of the eight chairs in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-gaming-chairs">best gaming chair</a> roundup are Secretlab models. Of all the gaming chairs we covered in our "<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/the-best-gaming-chairs-early-2023-budget-to-best">Budget to Best</a>" roundup video earlier this year, my colleague Akeem Lawanson considered the Secretlab Titan Evo to be the most comfortable. No good chair comes cheap and Secretlab chairs definitely cost a premium, but we think the craftsmanship, materials, and customizability are worth it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/secretlab-presidents-day-sale-gaming-chair-deals-february-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>