<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 23:57:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Holstin: 5 Reasons to Play This Phenomenal Pixel-Art Survival Horror Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/holstin-5-reasons-to-play-this-phenomenal-pixel-art-survival-horror-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/holstin-5-reasons-to-play-this-phenomenal-pixel-art-survival-horror-game.1206210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/holstin-5-reasons-to-play-this-phenomenal-pixel-art-survival-horror-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I don’t think I’ve hungered for a game this year as much as Holstin. This survival-horror immediately caught my eye with its gorgeous pixel art, perspective-shifting gameplay, and eerie Polish setting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So I felt super lucky to get hands-on with an all-new, two-hour PC demo, sliced right out of Holstin’s ominous beginnings. While the previous Steam demo captured Holstin’s “feel” through mocked-up puzzles and a firing-range weapons tutorial, this new build puts it all together with a meaty (pun intended) story. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">My friends, you’ve gotta keep an eye on Holstin – here are a few reasons why.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Holstin Screenshots</h3></div></output><h3 data-cy="title3">#1: “Disgusting” Has Never Looked So Good</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s the first thing you’ll notice – Holstin is really, really good-looking, right from your sudden drop into a dilapidated train station overgrown with some weird, pulsing yellow substance. The art looks already great in screenshots, but you need to see and feel Holstin in motion to truly understand what an accomplishment these graphics are. Even the title screen is amazing.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Even the title screen is amazing.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">What looks like 2D top-down pixel art becomes truly impressive 3D once you learn that you can move the camera around, with slick, seamless transitions through eight different angles. Even if you’re aware of this before you begin playing, swinging around for the first time is honestly one of Holstin’s most surprising moments – yes, right up there with enemy encounters!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">(As a side note, the top-down movement in Holstin lends itself really well to twin-stick action on a controller, but it plays perfectly on mouse and keyboard as well.)</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Holstin Demo Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While most players won't necessarily be choosing Holstin because of its technical proficiency, it’s what really makes this aesthetic work. There’s a reason why graphics like this aren’t manifold in the industry – it’s built on the studio’s custom in-house technology, which makes it likely to cement Holstin as a standout game graphically.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">#2: Mind-Blowing Perspectives</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Okay, so you can spin that third-person, top-down camera around and view the world from multiple angles – but that’s not just an awesome-looking gimmick. Those angles go hand-in-hand with Holstin’s environmental puzzles. If you’re not looking behind boxes or checking around corners to find alleys, you may – and probably will – miss things that will help you find your path forward in Holstin’s strange world. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But wait! There’s more! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are aggressive mutated people everywhere. That means you need to shoot them. But unlike other twin-stick shooters, you won’t be staying in that fixed-camera view to ready your sights. Entering aim mode transitions you into an over-the-shoulder third-person view, freeing your camera to enable pinpoint precision for your headshots.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">These two very different views really add to the suspense – for instance, while in top-down view, you might miss the enemy lurking quietly around a corner. I found myself constantly on my guard, switching between both viewpoints even out of combat. (And sometimes even that didn’t save me from being pounced on and grappled down by some grisly horror of a human.) The only part of combat that initially confused me was melee, as that isn’t in aim mode – but I got used to it quickly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Holstin plays with other camera perspectives too, though more for atmosphere than for gameplay reasons. Think: a god’s-eye view in an eerily silent, unpopulated area. Your cursor disappears, suddenly removing your primary sense of defense. You might not be switching into aim mode here, but you’ll sure feel like some ominous force is watching your every move.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">#3: Meat, Tentacles, and Gore Galore</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Survival horror fans will want to know how gruesome the strange environment can get, but don’t worry – the squelchy mainstays of the genre are definitely represented in Holstin. The overall goal in this demo is to find your way to a slaughterhouse, after all. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The town’s dissolution into its kind of otherworld first emerges in the form of “Plasmodium,” the aforementioned yellow substance. At first, it looks like someone went wild with foam spray – but when you approach, tentacles will rise and wiggle at you. Are they saying hi or taunting you? Either way, it’s suitably icky and adds to a pervading sense of unease.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And then there are the mutant enemies. Imagine glowing orange orbs taking over your body, their tendrils taking the place of your tendons. Imagine those same orbs buried in the Plasmodium, which slowly spreads through streets and parks like an aggressive, menacing fungus.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Something I also found unsettling was the implied gore. While you don’t see the actual slaughterhouse in this demo, you will learn how it figures into the overall narrative through conversational dialogue and scribbled scraps scattered through the world. Something wicked is going on in that place, and you know it’s not going to be pretty when you finally get there.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">#4: Adventure Gaming Puzzles That Don’t Suck</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As a gamer who grew up with classic point-and-click adventures, I was very impressed by Holstin’s approach to its puzzles. Maybe I’m getting old and crotchety, but I’ve been disappointed in recent years with how linear puzzling has become in adventure-adjacent games. Receive an objective, figure out how to solve the objective, then receive the next objective. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Figuring out which are solvable in any given moment is almost a puzzle in itself.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Though Holstin is strongly narrative-driven, it never feels like a linear story with disparate puzzles slapped on top. In fact, I’d almost forgotten how challenging a well-designed puzzle tree can be. In Holstin, you won’t be completing objectives in the order they’re listed. You can work on multiple objectives at once, and figuring out which are solvable in any given moment is almost a puzzle in itself. You might have to retrace your steps, which feels realistic (like searching your house thrice for your car keys).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And as for the puzzles themselves – they make sense (well, as much as something can make sense in this mad world). Survival horror fans are all familiar with some of the genre’s most inane challenges – ranging from the dreaded sliding puzzle through to needing an intimate knowledge of Shakespeare to shelve books correctly in order to obtain a door code (*cough* Silent Hill *cough*). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">None of that nonsense here. Holstin’s asks of you are simple: How are you going to get this trapdoor open? What twisting path through town will you need to forge in order to reach the playground? How you solve these problems feels organic, and really encourages you to explore your environs thoroughly.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">#5: 1990s Poland Is a Trip</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The Polish setting forms the bones of quite a specific – and unique – narrative. It’s not exactly a great tourism ad for Poland, but even covered with the weird tentacled Plasmodium, the town of Jeziorne-Kolonia still feels like a distinctly foreign experience compared to other games set in more vague locations.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This demo only has Polish voiceover, and as an English speaker myself, I found that this added to the believability and atmosphere – like watching a foreign flick. Though I don’t have the context of how the Polish language is structured, the voice acting sounded dead-on. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s the suicidal woman, her voice filled with defeat as she hands her gun over to you. The large, childlike man, squealing, talking in riddles, and just one plot twist away from losing it entirely. The cast of weirdos here is a lot wider than your usual survival-horror game – but their convincing creepiness doesn’t detract from the suspense at all. (I sure wished they would help me out in combat, though.)</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And while Holstin set in the 1990s, it’s not exactly boy bands and GeoCities. For instance, your save checkpoints are decrepit-looking phone booths – and you’ll need to find physical telephone cards to actually make your save (just like the real-life anachronism of digging for change to do your laundry). Our hero Tomasz definitely does not have a cell phone for tracking objectives. Expect all the inconveniences in the pre-internet era – yet another stumbling block in your strange journey through this horrifying town.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All in all, this demo honestly blew me away – and I say that very rarely of any game. If the rest of Holstin is as polished and carefully crafted, it will be considered a survival horror classic in a decade’s time. I’m that impressed by what I’ve seen and played of it so far.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demeo X Dungeons & Dragons: Battlemarked Reveals Debut Gameplay Trailer, Confirms Release Window and Launch Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-reveals-debut-gameplay-trailer-confirms-release-window-and-launch-platforms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-reveals-debut-gameplay-trailer-confirms-release-window-and-launch-platforms.1206093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-reveals-debut-gameplay-trailer-confirms-release-window-and-launch-platforms<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Resolution Games has revealed a debut gameplay trailer for Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked, and confirmed a late 2025 release window and launch platforms.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Resolution Games, best known for digital fantasy tabletop adventure Demeo, is working with Wizards of the Coast on the first virtual reality game set in the Dungeons &amp; Dragons universe, called Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked. It’s due out on PC via Steam, and PlayStation 5, with a VR version available on PlayStation VR2, Steam VR, and Meta Quest 3.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlemarked adapts D&amp;D classes, actions, and lore to Resolution Games’ Demeo action role-playing system, which is DM-less and focuses on social strategy rather than social roleplay. This, Resolution Games said, encourages group tabletalk focused on tactics and decision-making.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“While the world of Demeo is rich with lore, our previous titles focus primarily on tactical action over motivation and narrative,” said Tommy Palm, founder and CEO of Resolution Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Resolution Games is working with story designer Matt Sernett as the project’s narrative lead. Sernett previously worked as a designer of the Dungeons &amp; Dragons tabletop game and contributed to Dungeons &amp; Dragons video games including Baldur’s Gate, Baldur’s Gate 2, and Icewind Dale.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“When Dungeons &amp; Dragons launched fifth edition back in 2014, the first adventure that many players went on ventured into Neverwinter Wood, and I can think of no place better for Battlemarked players to begin their journey,” said Sernett.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The first adventure in Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked will take players to familiar locations including Cragmaw Castle and Mount Hotenow. The world of D&amp;D is just as much a part of the story as its characters, and we can’t wait for players to immerse themselves in its dangers and delights.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlemarked’s second adventure, which will be included at launch, will be revealed later this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>