<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 11:41:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BAFTA Games Awards 2025: The Full List of Winners]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bafta-games-awards-2025-the-full-list-of-winners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bafta-games-awards-2025-the-full-list-of-winners.1159131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bafta-games-awards-2025-the-full-list-of-winners<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Astro Bot and Still Wakes the Deep the night's biggest winners.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/astro-bot"><u>Astro Bot</u></a> has once again won big at an awards show, this time securing five gongs at the 2025 BAFTA Games Awards, including Best Design, Best Family Game, and Best Game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The BAFTA Games Awards — the UK's independent arts charity celebrating excellence in games — took place overnight on Tuesday, April 8, 2025, in London, UK. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii"><u>Senua's Saga: Hellblade 2</u></a>, Astro Bot, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/still-wakes-the-deep"><u>Still Wakes the Deep</u></a> led the charge with 11, eight, and eight nominations, respectively. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/thank-goodness-youre-here"><u>Thank Goodness You're Here!</u></a> also received seven nominations, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/black-myth-wukong"><u>Black Myth: Wukong</u></a> six, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii"><u>Helldivers 2</u></a> was up for five awards.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— BAFTA Games (@BAFTAGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/BAFTAGames/status/1909728843289485740?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Accepting the award, Astro Bot director Nicolas Doucet paid tribute to the game developers of the past, who paved the way for Sony-owned Team Asobi and other current studios to find success in the modern era.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whilst Astro Bot was the night's most-crowned game, The Chinese Room's impressive Still Wakes the Deep secured three wins — including both performer awards — and Helldivers 2 won two BAFTAs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Thank Goodness You're Here!, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/balatro"><u>Balatro</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metaphor-refantazio"><u>Metaphor: Refantazio</u></a> were also among the winners. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">BAFTA Game Awards 2025 winners:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Best Animation:</strong> Astro Bot</li><li><strong>Artistic Achievement:</strong> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/neva"><u>Neva</u></a></li><li><strong>Audio Achievement: </strong>Astro Bot</li><li><strong>Best Game:</strong> Astro Bot</li><li><strong>Best British Game: </strong>Thank Goodness You're Here!</li><li><strong>Best Debut Game: </strong>Balatro</li><li><strong>Best Evolving Game:</strong> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/vampire-survivors"><u>Vampire Survivors</u></a></li><li><strong>Best Family Game: </strong>Astro Bot</li><li><strong>Fellowship:</strong> Yoko Shimomura</li><li><strong>Game Beyond Entertainment: </strong><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tales-of-kenzera-zau"><u>Tales of Kenzera: Zau</u></a></li><li><strong>Best Game Design:</strong> Astro Bot</li><li><strong>Best Multiplayer:</strong> Helldivers 2</li><li><strong>Best Music: </strong>Helldivers 2</li><li><strong>Best Narrative:</strong> Metaphor: Refantazio</li><li><strong>Best New Intellectual Property: </strong>Still Wakes the Deep</li><li><strong>Best Performer in a Leading Role: </strong>Alex Newman (Still Wakes the Deep)</li><li><strong>Best Performer in a Supporting Role: </strong>Karen Dunbar (Still Wakes the Deep)</li><li><strong>Best Technical Achievement:</strong> Senua's Saga: Hellblade 2</li></ul><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bafta-games-awards-2024-winners-the-full-list"><u>2024 BAFTA Game Awards winners</u></a> included <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii"><u>Baldur's Gate 3</u></a>, which secured five wins, including Best Game, with other wins for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/alan-wake-ii"><u>Alan Wake 2</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-bros-wonder"><u>Super Mario Bros. Wonder</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/viewfinder"><u>Viewfinder</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bafta-announces-the-most-influential-video-game-of-all-time-and-its-a-real-head-scratcher"><u>BAFTA recently revealed that the most influential video game of all time</u></a>, according to the public, is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/shenmue"><u>Shenmue</u></a>, which left the internet somewhat puzzled.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">BAFTA polled the public to discover that while games like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-gba"><u>GTA</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tetris-ea"><u>Tetris</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/world-of-warcraft"><u>World of Warcraft</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/minecraft"><u>Minecraft</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/doom"><u>Doom</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/half-life-2"><u>Half-Life 2</u></a> <em>did</em> make the list, the top as ranked by the number of votes received was Sega's 1999 action-adventure game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Appears to Accidentally Confirm Iconic Track for Mario Kart World]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-appears-to-accidentally-confirm-iconic-track-for-mario-kart-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-appears-to-accidentally-confirm-iconic-track-for-mario-kart-world.1159125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-appears-to-accidentally-confirm-iconic-track-for-mario-kart-world<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, we reported that the Korean Nintendo website had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/did-nintendo-just-accidentally-reveal-an-unannounced-character-in-donkey-kong-bananza">accidentally revealed an announced character</a> coming to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza"><u>Donkey Kong Bananza</u></a> (spoilers!), and now the website has confirmed an iconic track is making a return for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world"><u>Mario Kart World</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Warning</strong></em><em>! Potential Mario Kart World spoilers follow:</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As with the Donkey Kong snafu, the guilty images were removed speedily from the official website, but not before someone snapped them and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/mariokart/comments/1jqrwq8/rainbow_road_has_finally_been_found_it_seems_it/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>posted them to Reddit</u></a>, of course.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As the images are pretty fuzzy — and there's no accompanying text — this is essentially all we know so far. With a little cross-checking, it looks as though a hidden Rainbow Road track will sit just below Princess Peach's Stadium on the four-way intersection in the bay area (thanks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-leak-confirms-iconic-tracks-return" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Eurogamer</u></a>), although it's unclear if it's a secret track or some kind of unlockable extra.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/mariokart/comments/1jqrwq8/comment/mlfp1xz/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>It's also got some fans wondering</u></a> if <em>every</em> four-way intersection could be the location of a hidden course.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On Monday, Nintendo justified <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-costs-80-30-cheaper-if-you-buy-it-bundled-with-the-nintendo-switch-2"><u>Mario Kart World's shock $80 price tag</u></a> in response to controversy over the $10 hike for some Switch 2 games. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/our-big-nintendo-switch-2-interview-with-nintendo-of-americas-bill-trinen"><u>IGN interviewed Nintendo of America's Vice President of Product and Player Experience, Bill Trinen</u></a>, at a recent Switch 2 preview event in New York, and asked about Nintendo’s pricing strategy (albeit ahead of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-delays-switch-2-pre-order-date-in-the-us-to-assess-impact-of-trumps-tariffs"><u>Nintendo’s announcement about delaying Switch 2 pre-orders in the U.S. due to the potential impact of tariffs)</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I would say it's less about the strategy of pricing Mario Kart World, it's more just whenever we look at a given game, we just look at what is the experience, and what's the content, and what's the value?” Trinen said at the time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As IGN has reported, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-fans-fear-impact-of-tariffs-on-switch-2-price-i-shouldnt-as-an-average-person-be-priced-out-of-this">some Nintendo fans have expressed concern that they may be priced out of the next-generation</a> if the company goes even higher than the already controversial prices for the Switch 2 and its games such as Mario Kart World due to the tariff situation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Commandos: Origins Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/commandos-origins-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/commandos-origins-review.1159062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/commandos-origins-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether twiddling their thumbs during the decades since Commandos 3 or calmly hiding in a hedge waiting to knife a nosey Nazi in the neck on his next stroll past, if there’s one thing Commandos fans are known for it’s lurking patiently. Good things come to those who’ve waited, and Commandos: Origins fits that bill. Slow-paced, challenging, and consistently satisfying when all your plans come together, its brand of isometric stealth action is intact and has never looked better. I’ve sunk nearly 60 hours into it over the last week and a half just to see out the missions, and there are potentially dozens more hours available should I return to play through some of them again with the intention of leaving no stone unturned and no soldier unslain. The only major issue is the assortment of bugs I’ve had to become accustomed to in order to keep enjoying myself. Like a peskily placed German sniper, some of these I learnt how to avoid entirely, but there were others I just needed to find a way to neutralise.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For those of you who skipped basic training, Commandos is a classic series of real-time tactics stealth ’em ups set during the Second World War that goes all the way back to the late ’90s. Picture a crew of elite but generally crabby commandos crawling around on their bellies behind enemy lines, driven by a whole lot of mouse clicking, and you’re most of the way there. For a modern comparison, it’s a lot like The Ministry of Ungentlemanly Warfare, only filmed exclusively from a drone (and without Guy Ritchie’s wit or Henry Cavill’s perfectly curled cookie duster). Or the BBC’s Rogue Heroes with 90% less swearing and 100% less AC/DC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, while its cheesy yet otherwise stony-faced approach may lack the outright humour of those crackling British Special Forces capers, Commandos: Origins is arguably the best version of the series’ concept to date. It’s a familiar yet modern experience for grizzled veterans, and also an intuitive and approachable one for new players who are ready to test themselves against a steadily escalating difficulty curve.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where eagles stare</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Like any great stealth game, Origins is as much a game about tactics as it is a salvo of deadly puzzles to solve. It essentially boils down to analysing every upcoming encounter, inspecting each enemy soldier’s vision cone, and finding a way to dispatch them that won’t bring the whole German army down on your squad’s heads. A large part of my time with Origins has been spent simply staring at the screen, surveying my prey like an ambush predator. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>A large part of my time with Origins has been spent simply staring at the screen, surveying my prey like an ambush predator.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Each of the six commandos on your team has a set of unique tools and abilities. For the most part, Origins curates the characters available for each mission, tailoring the action for their skills. There are only two instances where all six soldiers will be on the same battlefield at once, which is kind of a shame because those are real highlights. That said, I probably would’ve played a huge amount of Origins exclusively using the Marine’s throwing knives and harpoon gun had I had the chance, so forcing me to expand my approach by sidelining him sometimes was probably wise and almost certainly kept things from becoming stale. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of sidelining, I actually don’t miss the inventory management of the previous games, though I feel like I wouldn’t have removed the ability to pick up and use enemy weapons for the Green Beret in particular. The argument here is that Origins is more about thoughtful stealth at all times – and less about spraying lead from scavenged MP40s at anything with a swastika on it. Thoughtful stealth, luckily, is empowered by the coolest part of Origins: Command Mode. Riffing on similar modes in the late, great Mimimi’s Desperados 3 and Shadow Gambit: The Cursed Crew, Command Mode allows you to freeze time indefinitely and queue up individual actions for each of your commandos. Back in real time, they’ll execute those simultaneously on your say so. Nailing the timing on a set of Command Mode instructions is powerfully satisfying, whether it’s simply two crawling commandos stabbing a distracted pair of soldiers from the side, or a more complicated and elaborately choreographed ballet of harpoons, blades, and bullets.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Commandos: Origins Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s all quite a slow process to do well, but it’s a truly rewarding one when you figure out the solution to taking on what initially may seem like too many meticulously positioned soldiers to tackle. Maybe your first choice of target is impossible to kill quietly because he’s always in sight of one of his other comrades, and maybe that very squadmate is always in view of a third, and so on. But there’s fun in uncovering who should be the first domino to fall throat-first onto a Fairbairn–Sykes combat knife. Some enemies will leave their posts to investigate strange sounds, like the Sapper’s whistle or the Green Beret’s radio – or inspect the Driver’s burning packets of cigarettes. Some will only temporarily turn and face a distraction, giving you precious moments to slip by them. Experimenting with which routes and tools work best is a task that tapped into a compulsive part of my brain.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There’s fun in uncovering who should be the first domino to fall throat-first onto a Fairbairn–Sykes combat knife.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The opportunities are always there; it’s just on us to find them – and the fact that they’re not telegraphed or signposted makes every victory feel like you’ve outfoxed the developers. At one point I spotted a tiny gap in the view cones of four soldiers on a small set of stairs in the water. It allowed me to not only get behind them to wipe them out, but also to bring three other squadmates via boat to the rear of my main objective. Was that there on purpose? Probably, but maybe not. Leaving it ambiguous as to whether you’ve gone about an encounter in the precise way Claymore Game Studios surreptitiously left ajar for us – or succeeded with an unpredictable sequence of moves the dev team perhaps never saw coming –  is just good design.  Either way, the encouragement to explore every corner of the maps for the best opportunities is thoroughly baked in.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In large part, that’s because these levels are all exceedingly detailed dioramas, sprawling and dense, and every one feels like I’m playing a high-stakes game of toy soldiers on the kind of miniature map exhibits you might see tucked behind glass at a war museum. Missions take place all across Europe and North Africa, too, so the variety of backdrops is terrific – from snowy Scandinavia to lush, soggy fields and baking deserts. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The huge environments are also rendered entirely in three dimensions and you can enter buildings seamlessly, and the fact that I felt the need to say that should give you an idea of how long it’s been since we’ve had a proper Commandos game. You can make fine camera rotations in any compass direction, so getting the right angle to spot a gap in security is easy. That said, scrolling around too fast sometimes introduces a bit of temporary choppiness, but it’s a short-lived gripe. It’s otherwise great looking overall.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There is, unfortunately, some occasional clumsiness when navigating particularly complex, multi-storey structures. Over the course of the campaign I encountered a few enemies that appeared to be sharing a floor with me, but who were actually on a different level entirely and should’ve been hidden from view at that moment. I also had the misfortune of placing down a beartrap that became irretrievable because it wasn’t on the same platform I wanted to leave it, and being shot through a solid container that apparently wasn’t really there is never any fun. There were also occasional instances where my commands were being misinterpreted and my men were setting off to unintended areas and directly into enemy sight lines, due to an apparent disconnect between what floors are being displayed and what floor Origins <em>thinks </em>I’m clicking on. These aren’t major frustrations, though, and remedying them typically just required some minor zooming, or panning the camera slightly. That, or a quick reload to bring back the prematurely deceased.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Saving dyin’ privates</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In the trial-and-error world of tactical games like Commandos, quick save is your friend – and Origins is no exception. The ability to pick up directly where you left off after doing something risky and/or stupid is what actually gives us the freedom to experiment with different approaches in the first place. Make no mistake, quick save well and truly saved my bacon (and quickly!) on many occasions – but, unfortunately, this essential feature also seems to provoke some of Origins’ most bothersome bugs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For instance, loading a save you made while one of your commandos was climbing a wire – or perched high on a climbable pole – appears to leave the poor bastard marooned on an invisible level above the map, fruitlessly crawling or moonwalking into oblivion. The solution, naturally, is to simply resolve to never save while one of your men is climbing anything. That wasn’t the end of my issues, though. After another reload I noticed my Marine was no longer in his boat, but walking on water back to the marker I’d placed. This bug eventually resolved itself, but one where my Sapper simply disappeared off the map and became unselectable did not. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That kind of issue could’ve become game-breaking, but Origins – seemingly aware that it has a few technical landmines for you to step on – keeps a queue of several quick saves. For the most part, if something goes awry, there’s a strong chance you’ll have a slightly older save you can revert too. In this instance, though, I’d sadly filled all my saves without noticing my Sapper was no longer present. The only solution was restarting the mission entirely, which was over an hour lost.</p><div id="rank-these-world-war-ii-men-on-a-mission-movies" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rank these World War II 'men-on-a-mission' movies</h3><h3>Rank these World War II 'men-on-a-mission' movies</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One weird issue, and one I can’t tell whether it’s related to the quick saves or not, is the occasional instance of enemies falsely detecting one of your commandos in a bush they’re no longer hiding in – and getting locked in an alert state about it. They’ll subsequently circle it and blast it to hell to no avail. It wasn’t so bad because I was able to either skirt around it or totally exploit it by stabbing all the soldiers while they were busy slaughtering the unfortunate shrubbery, but it definitely wasn’t supposed to happen. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I wouldn’t necessarily call the enemies smart overall, and it would’ve been nice if they displayed a little more of the initiative we see in other modern stealth games. Instead of callously ignoring dead bodies after an alert phase resets, for instance, they might want to drag their kaput companions off to a predefined location, à la Hitman. They make up for their dim bulbs by being extremely dangerous, though – and they’re just unpredictable enough to keep you on your toes when you think you’ve got their patterns figured out. They won’t inspect the nearest hiding places in the same order after a reload, for instance, so you’d better have a backup plan – or at least make sure nobody’s climbing a telephone pole when they come looking.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Season 2 Cast: Who's New and Coming Back to the HBO Show?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-cast-whos-new-and-coming-back-to-the-hbo-show</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-2-cast-whos-new-and-coming-back-to-the-hbo-show.1158954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-cast-whos-new-and-coming-back-to-the-hbo-show<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The long-awaited second season of The Last of Us is set to premiere on April 13, 2025, and it will bring along some new faces alongside returning favorites. Much like the first season, there will be some major characters from the games brought to life, like Kaitlyn Dever's Abby, but it will also be introducing some mysterious new people like Catherine O'Hara's Gail. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help get you ready Season 2 of The Last of Us, we've created this guide of the cast members you need to know before Joel and Ellie's adventure in this fascinating yet terrifying post-apocalyptic world continues this month.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Last of Us Season 2 Cast: Who's New and Coming Back to the HBO Show?</h3></div></output><h2 data-cy="title2">The Last of Us TV Show Season 2 New Cast</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Kaitlyn Dever as Abby</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/kaitlyn-dever-1743772954939.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The biggest question everyone had going into Season 2 of The Last of Us was who was going to play Abby? Thankfully, HBO finally gave us the answer when it revealed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hbos-the-last-of-us-season-2-finds-its-abby-in-kaitlyn-dever"><u>Booksmart and Justified’s Kaitlyn Dever will be playing her.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Abby is one of the playable characters in The Last of Us Part 2 and has a huge role to play in the upcoming story. While we won’t spoil too much here, Abby is a member of the Fireflies who crosses paths with Joel and Ellie early in the second game. HBO has described Abby as a “skilled soldier whose black-and-white view of the world is challenged as she seeks vengeance for those she loved.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our casting process for season two has been identical to season one: we look for world-class actors who embody the souls of the characters in the source material," series co-creators Craig Mazin and Neil Druckmann said in a joint statement. "Nothing matters more than talent, and we’re thrilled to have an acclaimed performer like Kaitlyn join Pedro, Bella and the rest of our family."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Abby in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Laura Bailey</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Young Mazino as Jesse</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/young-mazino-1743772976889.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hbos-the-last-of-us-season-2-has-found-who-will-play-jesse"><u>Beef star Young Mazino will be joining Season 2 of The Last of Us as Jesse,</u></a> a “pillar of the community who puts everyone else’s needs before his own, sometimes at terrible cost.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Jesse was first introduced in The Last of Us Part 2 and is a leader of the patrol groups in Jackson, Wyoming, a community Joel, Ellie, and Tommy call home at the beginning of the second game. He is a friend of Ellie and is also an ex-boyfriend of Dina.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Young is one of those rare actors who is immediately undeniable the moment you see him," Mazin and Druckmann said. "We’re so lucky to have him, and we can’t wait for the audience to see Young shine in our show.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Jesse in The Last of Us Part 2 Game? </strong>Stephen Chang</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Isabella Merced as Dina</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/the-last-of-us-season-2-official-trailer-warner-bros-uk-ireland-0-38-screenshot-1743773003490.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Dora and the Lost City of Gold and Transformers: The Last Knight’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hbos-the-last-of-us-season-two-will-feature-isabela-merced-as-dina"><u>Isabella Merced is playing Dina in The Last of Us’ second season.</u></a> For those unfamiliar, Dina is another member of the community of Jackson and is Ellie’s partner who plays a pivotal role in the story. Her relationship with Ellie evolves and grows in many ways throughout the game and she is one of the strongest voices in her life. Does she always listen to that voice? You’ll have to wait to find out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Dina is warm, brilliant, wild, funny, moral, dangerous and instantly lovable," said Mazin and Druckmann. "You can search forever for an actor who effortlessly embodies all of those things, or you can find Isabela Merced right away.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Dina in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Shannon Woodward</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Catherine O'Hara as Gail</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/gnjwfm1agaes32i-1743774717461.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">We don't know much about Catherine O'Hara's Gail as she is a new character that was created for the series. However, it's clear she will be playing an important role as she appears to be Joel's therapist and looks to be helping him cope with his big decision from Season 1.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Jeffrey Wright as Isaac</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/the-last-of-us-season-2-official-trailer-max-1-16-screenshot-1-1743775212851.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans of The Last of Us Part 2 will be happy to know that Westworld and The Batman's Jeffrey Wright will be reprising his role from the game as the ruthless Washington Liberation Front leader Isaac. He sets events in motion in a very big way in the game, and we expect this character to be just as integral in Season 2 of the Max series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Isaac in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Jeffrey Wright</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Danny Ramirez as Manny</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/manny-1743774324680.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Falcon and the Winter Soldier's and Top Gun: Maverick's Danny Ramirez is playing Manny Alverez, one of the members of the Washington Liberation Front and a former Firefly. He is a friend of Abby and is considered one of the best soldiers by the leader of the WLF, Isaac Dixon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A loyal soldier whose sunny outlook belies the pain of old wounds and a fear that he will fail his friends when they need him most," the official HBO description of Manny reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Manny in The Last of Us Part 2 Game? </strong>Alejandro Edda</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Ariela Barer as Mel</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/ariel-1743774324679.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Runaways' Ariela Barer will take on the role of Mel, a medic in the Washington Liberation Front who was a also a member of the Fireflies. She is a friend of Abby and is in a romantic relationship with Owen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A young doctor whose commitment to saving lives is challenged by the realities of war and tribalism," the official HBO description of Mel reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Mel in The Last of Us Part 2 Game? </strong>Ashly Burch</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Tati Gabrielle as Nora</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/the-last-of-us-season-2-official-trailer-max-1-31-screenshot-1743773049091.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Chilling Adventures of Sabrina and Uncharted's Tati Gabrielle is set to play Nora in Season 2 of The Last of Us on HBO. Nora is another member of Abby's 'Salt Lake Crew' alongside Owen, Manny, and Mel. Additionally, she was a medic who worked with Dr. Jerry Anderson.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A military medic struggling to come to terms with the sins of her past," the official HBO description of Nora reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Nora in The Last of Us Part 2 Game? </strong>Chelsea Tavares</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Spencer Lord as Owen</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/spenmce-1743774324680.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer Lord, who has appeared in Family Law, Heartland, and The Good Doctor, is taking on the role of Owen, a member of the 'Salt Lake Crew' who was a former Firefly and is now a soldier in the WLF. He is currently dating Mel but was once in a relationship with Abby.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A gentle soul trapped in a warrior’s body, condemned to fight an enemy he refuses to hate," the official HBO description of Owen reads.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Owen in The Last of Us Part 2 Game? </strong>Patrick Fugit</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Joe Pantoliana as Eugene, Robert John Burke as Seth, and Noah Lamanna as Kat</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/returning-1743778162561.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">HBO recently announced six more actors that will be part of The Last of Us Season 2's cast, but we don't know too much about them yet. What's exciting is that three of them are smaller characters from the games that will expanded stories and three are brand new characters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Joe Pantoliano (Memento, The Matrix), Robert John Burke (RoboCop 3), and Noah Lamanna (Star Trek: Strange New Worlds) and they will all be playing the characters that were first introduced in the games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pantoliano will be playing Eugene, who was Dina's pot-smoking friend in The Last of Us Part 2. He was only in the game for a quick moment, but he will be much more important this time around. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I get excited when I see these opportunities,” showrunner Neil Druckmann said. “I’m like, ‘Oh, I don’t know Eugene that well!’ The story we told [in the game] was somewhat superficial. The way this character comes in really gets to the heart of Joel and Ellie and their relationship.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Burke will be playing TLoU Part 2's bar owner and bigot sandwich-giver Seth and Lamanna will step into the shoes of Kat, who is said to have dated Ellie before the second game's story began. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image Credits: John Pantoliano (Theo Wargo/Getty Images), Robert John Burke (Jim Spellman/FilmMagic), and Noah Lemanna (Jeff Kravitz/FilmMagic for HBO)</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Alanna Ubach as Hanrahan, Ben Ahlers as Burton, and Hettienne Park as Elise Park</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/new-1743778162560.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Alanna Ubach (Euphoria, Bombshell), Ben Ahlers (The Gilded Age, Chilling Adventures of Sabrina), and Hettienne Park (Don't Look Up) have recently joined the cast of The Last of Us Season 2 as newly created characters Hanrahan, Burton, and Elise Park, respectively. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image Credits: Alanna Ubach (Monica Schipper/Getty Images), Ben Ahlers (Jeff Kravitz/FilmMagic for HBO), Hettienne Park (Mark Sagliocco/Getty Images)</em></p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Last of Us TV Show Season 2 Returning Cast </h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Pedro Pascal as Joel</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/pedro-pascal-1743773559742.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Pedro Pascal will once again be returning as Joel in the second season of The Last of Us. When we last left Joel, he had just gone on a murderous rampage against the Fireflies to save Ellie. Marlene explained to Joel that while the procedure to see if Ellie’s body could actually lead to a cure would kill her, it would be for the greater good. Joel clearly didn’t agree this was the right option and rescued Ellie, taking her away from there. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The final scene saw him lying to Ellie and telling her the Fireflies had already failed to develop a cure for the cordyceps infection and that they didn’t need her anymore. He also chose not to reveal the bloodshed he left behind. When he swore to Ellie that what he said was true, Ellie just gave him an uneasy, “Okay.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Joel in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Troy Baker</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Bella Ramsey as Ellie</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/bella-ramsey-1743773559742.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Bella Ramsey will be returning as Ellie in The Last of Us’ second season and will once again star alongside Pedro Pascal’s Joel. As with Joel, the last time we saw Ellie was when she was lied to by Joel about what happened with the Fireflies at that fateful hospital. Ellie was under anesthesia as she was getting ready for a procedure that would kill her but hopefully find a cure for the cordyceps infection. She didn’t know she was going to die. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Joel wasn’t OK with that and rescued her while killing many along the way, yet Ellie was unconscious the whole time so didn’t have a choice in the matter. We don’t know exactly what Ellie thinks after Joel lies to her at the end of the season, but Season 2 will no doubt dive deep into that and what it means for their relationship.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Bella in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Ashley Johnson</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Gabriel Luna as Tommy</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/04/gabriel-luna-0-1743773542270.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Tommy is Joel’s brother and Gabriel Luna will be making a return in Season 2 as the character played a big part in The Last of Us Part 2. We last saw him in Jackson with his wife, Maria. Joel had initially asked Tommy to take Ellie to the Fireflies after he admitted he wasn’t strong enough to do it and couldn’t after the loss of his daughter, Sarah. However, he changed his mind after speaking with Ellie and the two left Tommy behind in Jackson, but not before Tommy said they always had a home there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Who Voiced Tommy in The Last of Us Part 2 Game?</strong> Jeffrey Pierce</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rutina Wesley as Maria</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/01/18/a-1705593742040.PNG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Rutina Wesley’s Maria is a leader of the Jackson community and Tommy’s wife. We last saw her in Jackson when she was cutting Ellie’s hair and telling her to be careful who to trust. Wesley will be back for Season 2 and we can't wait to see what role she has to play.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Will Marlene or Tess Appear in Season 2 of The Last of Us?</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Merle Dandridge as Marlene</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/01/18/1291366-1671638935821-1705593137796.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Merle Dandridge’s Marlene was killed by Joel in the final episode of The Last of Us’ first season, so we won’t be seeing her in the present time of Season 2. However, she did appear in flashbacks during The Last of Us Part 2 and very well may show up again this next season in that fashion.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Anna Torv as Tess</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/01/18/thumb-1920-1291371-1671638876860-1705593137796.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Anna Torv’s Tess was a smuggler and close friend of Joel in Boston who was with him when Marlene gave them the mission to get Ellie out of the city and to the Fireflies. Unfortunately, Tess sacrificed herself to save Joel and Ellie after she was bitten, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-fans-are-divided-over-that-clicker-moment-in-episode-2-of-hbo-series"><u>she was controversially killed by a Clicker who “kissed” her with disgusting mouth tendrils. </u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Tess didn’t appear in The Last of Us Part 2, it’s not out of the realm of possibility that we could get another flashback to Joel and Tess’ life before she died in the show to flesh out their story.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Will Nick Offerman’s Bill and Murray Bartlett’s Frank Return in The Last of Us?</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/01/18/the-last-of-us-prequel-series-1704717529762-1705593258838.jpeg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">It doesn’t sound like it…</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Last of Us’ episode which focused on the story of Nick Offerman’s Bill and Murray Bartlett’s Frank was one of our favorite of the show’s first season. In fact, we loved it so much that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-episode-3-review"><u>we gave it a rare 10/10.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Nick Offerman and Murray Bartlett take on leading role duties with elegance, leaving an unmistakably beautiful mark on the show as we’re shown a side of humanity that makes what Joel and Ellie are fighting for worth saving,” IGN’s Simon Cardy wrote. “It’s an episode, just like love, that lives long in the memory after experiencing it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While their love story has sadly ended, there was hope we could see them again in another flashback. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-nick-offerman-prequel-series-ideas"><u>Offerman even said there were ideas for a potential spin-off prequel series</u></a> focused on the characters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-2-wont-return-to-bill-and-frank-executive-producer-craig-mazin-says"><u>Mazin has shut down that idea</u></a> and said Offerman was just joking about the prequel. “I’m very proud of the episode we did with Bill and Frank,” Mazin said. "There won’t be more Bill and Frank. Nick was joking about a prequel, that was kind of a joke. We are very happy with what we achieved."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hbos-the-last-of-us-season-1-burning-questions-and-ending-explained">our breakdown of the ending of The Last of Us Season 1,</a> our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-predicting-season-2">The Last of Us Season 2 predictions,</a> and The Last of Us HBO creators on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-hbo-creators-answer-whether-or-not-joel-was-right-to-save-ellie">whether or not Joel was right to save Ellie.</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Note: This story was updated on April 8, 2025, to add Catherine O'Hara (Gail) and Jeffrey Wright (Isaac).</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Adam Bankhurst is a news writer for IGN. You can follow him on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst</em></a><em> and on </em><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Twitch.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>