<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 04:55:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Fans (And Trolls) Are Racing To Claim Pixels in Wplace]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/game-fans-and-trolls-are-racing-to-claim-pixels-in-wplace</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-fans-and-trolls-are-racing-to-claim-pixels-in-wplace.1267578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm looking at a map of my city, Kansas City, right now, and wondering what I should do for fun this coming weekend. Should I visit the giant purple Zoroark stomping over downtown? If I want to see the Superman with the glowing red eyes in the suburbs to the south, I first have to pass Ralsei Deltarune sitting atop the highway, smoking an enormous blunt. I could go visit the Northland, but there is an enormous United Airlines plane straddling the Missouri River, which might make transit a bit confusing. Hmm. Options, options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That probably sounded like nonsense if you're not aware of <a href="https://wplace.live/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wplace</a>, a delightful new time waster in the form of a world map where users can draw a single pixel in a color of their choice, wherever they like, once every 30 seconds. If that sounds familiar, you're probably thinking of one of its main inspirations: /r/place, the Reddit game with a blank canvas that let users similarly place one pixel at a time. Though /r/place closed a few years ago, wplace has rapidly gained popularly in the last few days, to the point where just about wherever you live or wherever you look, you can find detailed collaborative drawings, silly graffiti, inside jokes, and more doodled all over the map. And unshockingly, a lot of those doodles are gaming references.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like most people, I checked out my own city first before exploring wplace more widely. Kansas City is indeed covered with gaming characters. At a glance, I can see several Pokemon, characters from Rain World, Deltarune, OneShot, Metroid, Final Fantasy, Mario, Earthbound, Among Us, Angry Birds, and plenty more can be spotted amid the city's roadways and rivers. There are also lots of other pop culture icons, like SpongeBob and various Transformers, sprinkled in with political messages, sports team logos, various flags, location-specific graffiti, and other random doodles. Some people just wrote their names.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/11/capture-1754943131032.PNG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">wplace at the time this piece was written, hovering over Kansas City</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But KC is far from the most interesting city on wplace. There's one particular screenshot of Baltimore that's gone viral that might unfortunately be a bit too crass to share here (<a href="https://x.com/jeracerx/status/1954494549465702807" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">you can click here to see</a>, if you want!) But other fun goofs are a little more innocent:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">having such a good time aimlessly scrolling around wplace and finding treasures <a href="https://t.co/NBR2Q4VvXT" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/NBR2Q4VvXT</a></p>— dan (@Dansplainer) <a href="https://twitter.com/Dansplainer/status/1953569824376029401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 7, 2025</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Found a snoopy island in wplace and I think it's endearing <a href="https://t.co/lLALupJxzB" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/lLALupJxzB</a></p>— ‏️‏️ (@yattaCEO) <a href="https://twitter.com/yattaCEO/status/1953627521393864814?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The Undertale and Deltarune fanbases seem to be especially enjoying wplace, as just about every single location I've looked at has had an inordinate number of characters from these two games.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">WHY IS TOBY FOX BLOCKING THE SUEZ CANAL <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/wplace?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#wplace</a> <a href="https://t.co/3Zr15EGXLw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/3Zr15EGXLw</a></p>— DPC-Art@🟦☁️ (@DPC_Art) <a href="https://twitter.com/DPC_Art/status/1953552092208959682?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 7, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Fan-favorite character Spamton is especially common, to the point where people are complaining that it's not even exciting to see a Spamton drawn near your house, because he's near everyone's houses.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>i was playing around wplace and no matter where u go in the world, no matter the culture, spamton will be there. </p><p>papa spamton at the vatican, mexico city spamton, atlanta spamton, tokyo spamton- spamton is worldwide <a href="https://t.co/vGHj0zNkaN" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/vGHj0zNkaN</a></p></div>— ølive 🫐 ψ ⊬ (@blurryirizi) <a href="https://twitter.com/blurryirizi/status/1953456579321176262?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 7, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">But other fanbases are getting in on it too. For instance, Blizzard's offices in irvine, CA are covered in a giant Heroes of the Storm logo, with various other WoW property art doodled nearby:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/11/capture-1754943720931.PNG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image source: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mn7mk7/blizz_hq_in_irvine_on_wplace/">https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mn7mk7/blizz_hq_in_irvine_on_wplace/</a></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Over in the Dragon Age community, fans are a little less positive lately. After the news today that we're <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-has-there-never-been-a-dragon-age-origins-remaster-bioware-exec-explains-past-plans-and-continued-difficulties">probably never getting a Dragon Age: Origins remaster</a>, some fans have been doodling all over Kirkwall with messages of...protest? General Dragon Age love?</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">This is how Kirkwall (Orkney) looks in Wplace. I love the Dragon Age community. <a href="https://t.co/X2IavMzvGo" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/X2IavMzvGo</a></p>— Void (@Scar3crowss) <a href="https://twitter.com/Scar3crowss/status/1954560684559065413?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 10, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">I was admittedly expecting more Silksong nonsense in Adelaide, South Australia where developer Team Cherry's offices are located, but there is a Knight wearing a top hat and a number of messages written around the city that all say variations of "Silksong Tomorrow".</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Half the fun of wplace is seeing what elaborate doodly mischief people have gotten up to in major cities, but the other half is finding obscure areas where hardly anyone's drawn anything. If you explore carefully, you can find hidden drawings in Antarctica, or in the middle of various oceans.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">just somewhere in the pacific ocean LMAO!<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/wplace?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#wplace</a> <a href="https://t.co/9x69QDCAvW" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/9x69QDCAvW</a></p>— Blood Aura🩸 (@Blood_Aura_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Blood_Aura_/status/1953885999513178197?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">If you're bored or need to kill some time at work, wplace is an excellent way to do just that. You may even be able to add art of your own if the servers are working, which is questionable at any given time. Who knows, you may just be able to find Spamton lurking near your house!</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/game-fans-and-trolls-are-racing-to-claim-pixels-in-wplace]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horrified: Dungeons & Dragons Is a Scary Good Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/horrified-dungeons-and-dragons-is-a-scary-good-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horrified-dungeons-dragons-is-a-scary-good-time.1267575/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The city of Waterdeep just can’t catch a break. Despite the various adventurers that call it home and stop to rest at the Yawning Portal Inn, the city and its citizenry find themselves under assault by dangerous and powerful monsters, leaving everyone Horrified. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest rendition of Ravensburger's popular <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games">cooperative</a> series, Horrified: Dungeons &amp; Dragons, crosses over with Wizards of the Coast's legendary tabletop RPG. The result is a game that my friends and I thoroughly enjoyed and were eager to play again, despite a few stumbling blocks.</p><div catalogid="d6f233e8-bd4d-4b71-9c36-c72486a907f5" id="226288"><div id="226288" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Horrified: Dungeons &amp; Dragons</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://zdcs.link/QL8jXm?object_uuid=6ec8716a-8fd3-41d4-ae12-392dc5a9d851&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">original Horrified</a> was released back in 2019, and this new Dungeons &amp; Dragons edition is the series’ sixth iteration. The basic premise each game shares is that up to five players work together to vanquish a selection of monsters by racing around the map, collecting resources, escorting civilians to safety, and beating back the monsters. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To win, each monster has to be dealt with. But players will lose if the monster deck is depleted or if the terror track ever hits seven (it's raised whenever a citizen is killed, hero is knocked out, or an effect triggers it). The extra fun part is taking out the monsters. How you deal with each monster is unique, with each one having its own sort of mini-game associated with it that players have to work through before they are gone for good.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Being <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-play-dungeons-and-dragons">Dungeons &amp; Dragons</a> themed, this version of Horrified features some of the most recognizable creatures from its pantheon, including the Displacer Beast, a Mimic, the Beholder, and of course, a big red dragon. As a longtime fan and player of D&amp;D, I was instantly intrigued by the box art and the board – but it was the monsters and how they operate that really drew my friends and me in. The developers really managed to work in how these creatures behave according to D&amp;D lore when designing their challenges.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Red Dragon, for instance, has a treasure you have to claim before you can vanquish it upon its treasure horde. The Mimic, for its part, is hidden and off the board until the party manages to finally reveal it. My favorite, by far, was the Beholder, which requires you to take out its 10 eye tendrils first, before going after its large central eye, each with a unique and powerful effect they could hit you with, dictated by a die roll. And yes, of course, there are dice rolls here; you can’t have Dungeons &amp; Dragons without some sort of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-dice-rolling-board-games">dice-rolling goodness</a> involved, and it doesn’t stop with just eye lasers either. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players assume the roles of staple D&amp;D classes, including the Fighter, Rogue, Cleric, Bard, or Wizard. For the most part, each character plays identically, with the exception of their special actions, which require you to roll a 20-sided die (one is included with the game in case you don’t have a small dice horde like yours truly). </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>That’s just how it goes when you’re rolling d20s.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Taking your special action can result in one of five possible outcomes, with the various classes behaving differently. For instance, bards can allure other players and citizens towards themselves. The fighter can rush to the nearest monster to do battle, and the cleric helps during monster attacks by letting you re-roll dice. We had some especially funny moments where our resident Wizard teleported the Beholder monster straight to the spot where our cleric just so happened to be – twice in a row. We had a good laugh about that (at least most of us), but that’s just how it goes when you’re rolling d20s.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Admittedly, we did homebrew and tweak the cleric a bit, however, allowing her to “stock” her special actions (basically using actions on her turn to hold rolls for actions), allowing her to use her beneficial skills during any monster phase up until her next turn. This lets the character feel more cleric-y, helping her teammates, as opposed to the as-written rules, which only let her use those skills on her turn’s monster phase. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Horrified, in general, isn’t an overly complex board game. In my testing, first-time players were usually able to grasp the flow of the game within a turn or two. Taking actions is straightforward, and the monster cards that dictate how many new items are spawned, any events that take place, citizens that appear, and what monsters activate, are equally so. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some of the wording on how monsters behave caused some confusion and debate, such as whether the mimic monster moved the number of spaces indicacted on the monster card’s movement space, or just a single space when it is activated. But overall, we figured it out (whether our decision was correct or not) and it worked out for us.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unique to this version of Horrified is the ability to reduce the terror track, which gives players a hand, pushing them further back from defeat. This is done whenever a monster is defeated, and I found it to be a great addition to use – especially when first introducing new players to the game, as Horrified games can be a bit challenging and require strategy to win. I also appreciate that it is easy enough <em>not</em> to use, so Horrified veterans can simply ignore this feature if they find it lessens the challenge too much.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One aspect that I am a bit disappointed by with Horrified: Dungeons &amp; Dragons is its small pool of monsters you can pick from. With “easy” games asking players to pick from two monsters and the standard challenge requiring three, it means you'll be replaying these monsters frequently. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other versions featured six or seven monsters, with only the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QbbBNw?object_uuid=6ec8716a-8fd3-41d4-ae12-392dc5a9d851&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Cthulu-themed Horrified</a> offering just four monsters. And with so many other classic D&amp;D monsters left on the table, it’s a shame we couldn’t have gotten a couple more in the box. Where are my Gelatinous Cubes and Owlbears, or heck, throw something wild like Vecna, the terrifying Lich, into the mix. I can only hope that Ravensburger adds more monsters or classes with future expansions.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Where to Buy</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/92xB1E?object_uuid=6ec8716a-8fd3-41d4-ae12-392dc5a9d851&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it at Target</a><em></em></li></ul></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 11, 2025 9:42 pm</p></div><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Horrified: Dungeons &amp; Dragons is one of those games that I find easy to recommend to anyone who enjoys the tabletop RPG and even has an inclination to play board games. It does a wonderful job blending the realms of the Horrified and D&amp;D worlds together for a fun game night title that is approachable but offers avenues for strategy and cooperation. For fans of Horrified, if the idea of a new random dice rolling element doesn’t turn you off, I think you will have a great time with this new iteration as well. It’s more Horrified, after all.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/horrified-dungeons-and-dragons-is-a-scary-good-time]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh No, Everyone in World of Warcraft Is Falling for the Hot, Evil Lady Who Will Definitely Try and Kill Us Later]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/oh-no-everyone-in-world-of-warcraft-is-falling-for-the-hot-evil-lady-who-will-definitely-try-and-kill-us-later</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-no-everyone-in-world-of-warcraft-is-falling-for-the-hot-evil-lady-who-will-definitely-try-and-kill-us-later.1267533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Oh no, the latest World of Warcraft patch has us teaming up with an evil cosmic void being who has tried to kill us many times already and will <em>definitely</em> stab us in the back later...but we're all kind of okay with it? Partially because we have no choice but also because she's hot and sarcastic?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm talking about Xal'atath. You know, this lady. <strong>Heads up, I'm going to talk in this article about spoilers for World of Warcraft: The War Within leading up to the events in Patch 11.2, Ghosts of K'aresh that dropped last Tuesday.</strong> If you haven't started playing the patch yet and don't want to know what's happening, maybe don't keep reading.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/11/the-war-within-official-cinematic-shadows-beneath-world-of-warcraft-2-17-screenshot-1754926715062.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if you're a lapsed World of Warcraft player, you might know this lady if you've dipped in as recently as World of Warcraft: Legion. Xal'atath first appeared in that expansion in the form of a dagger artifact weapon wielded by Shadow Priests, which would occasionally whisper creepy evil stuff to them about N'Zoth and the Old Gods and all that malarky. At the time, <em>some</em> folks grew rather fond of her unsettling whispers, even affectionately referring to her as "knaifu". The dagger, with the rest of the expansion's artifact weapons, was used to drain the corruption from the giant sword that Sargeras stuck in the planet at the end of the expansion. Normal stuff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we naively thought we wouldn't hear from Xal'atath ever again, what was once one weapon among a giant stack of them turned out to be hugely plot-relevant. Xal'atath was passed around from place to place in the interim expansions, finally regaining her power and emerging from the dagger in the form of a void-infused high elf, all the better to corrupt people with. She bopped around Azeroth for a while, manipulating the underground giant bug people and some dragons before she finally made herself known as something called the "Harbinger of Dimensius," basically a herald of a super powerful void lord bent on destroying reality. Again, normal stuff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the start of our current expansion, The War Within, Xal'atath appears to be the main villain. She opens the expansion by causing the destruction of Dalaran (again), and she's responsible for the events that lead us to fighting both the Nerubians and the goblin Gallywix. She's spent a lot of time popping up here and there and taunting our ally Alleria Windrunner, she nearly kills Khadgar, and she's obsessed with this void artifact she's been carrying around called the Dark Heart, which she keeps using to corrupt and empower and manipulate. All of this is to say, she seems pretty evil to me! She serves the void and is clearly very interested in destroying us, our buddies, and probably all of Azeroth! Nothing she has done so far seems good, at all!</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>And yet.</em></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In patch 11.2, Xal'atath <em>joins us.</em> The short explanation is that she actually betrayed Dimensius in the past, but he's coming back, and he's probably pissed off at her. If he shows up, she's done for. Out of a sense of self-preservation, she's been trying to beef up the Dark Heart to <em>stop</em> his return rather than accelerate it, and was messing around with the Nerubians and the Goblins in an effort to get that done. But at the end of patch 11.1, she accidentally (and sort of stupidly) loses the Dark Heart, forcing her to team up with Alleria and the player as a back-up plan. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">What this actually means, in practice, is that Xal'atath follows us around while questing and occasionally proposes we do things that sound horrible and dangerous, like turn ourselves into an energy being and fill someone with void energy so they can hear the planet sing to them (normal stuff!). But, you know, we can't stop Dimensius without her. She knows his weaknesses, and is pretty much the only path to getting close enough to him to do something about his encroachment. So the murdery knife-elf gets to come along.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/11/capture-1754938789710.PNG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image Source: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mkdb1y/tone_matters_magni/">https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mkdb1y/tone_matters_magni/</a></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The thing is, Blizzard has done such a lovely job writing Xal'atath, and Claudia Christian does such a great job voicing her, that most players are...kind of enjoying her presence. The first few days of the new patch last week saw the community subreddit flooded with cheeky, obsessive posts about Xal'atath. Sure, she's evil, but apart from being gorgeous, she's also clever, funny, powerful, and dare I say, kind of sultry? Her banter with the player is almost flirtateous at times, referring to us again and again as "my champion", while simultaneously reminding us that she could snuff us out on a whim. She spends a <em>lot</em> of time needling Alleria Windrunner and, as the ever-wise Ve'nari puts it, "floating around and making sarcastic remarks." And irritatingly enough, she's also correct a lot of the time about the behaviors and motivations of the other people who claim to be Alleria's allies (looking at you, Locus-Walker) and the ways in which they aren't exactly behaving righteously, either.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Love for Xal'atath has reached such a point that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mkv7jh/mommy_xalatath_addon/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">someone even made a mod (add-on) for World of Warcraft</a> that has Xal'atath whisper praise to the player every time they exit a combat scenario...though notably in these messages, Xal'atath refers to herself as "mommy". So download that at your own risk, I guess.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, this lady is <em>definitely</em> going to turn on us. And while plenty of players are enjoying the twist of her temporary allegiance and the opportunity to get to know her a little better, others are (rightfully!) recognizing that Xal'atath is definitely a hot mess we're going to regret partying with sooner or later:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/11/capture-1754939255090.PNG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image Source: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mj3014/the_story_so_far/">https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1mj3014/the_story_so_far/</a></figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It's an interesting move by Blizzard to build Xal'atath up for, technically, five expansions, introduce her as the <em>seemingly</em> big bad of this one, only to form an alliance of convenience in the final act of The War Within with the promise that she's definitely going to keep on being evil in future expansions. With Xal'atath's dark and void theming, it seems likely she might play a major role in the next expansion, Midnight, which will be fully revealed at Gamescom in just a few weeks. The long game Blizzard's playing here is especially potent given that some of its other storylines that similar took several expansions of setup did not go over so well, such as <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23015539/world-of-warcraft-sylvanas-windrunner-story-explainer-battle-for-azeroth-shadowlands-novel/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">whatever was going on with Sylvanas and the Jailer</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Anyway, trust Knaifu at your own risk, and enjoy her while you can. Manaforge Omega, the new raid, opens tomorrow and will bring with it another chapter of The War Within's story as we inch closer to the Midnight reveal and what I can only assume is Xal'atath's inevitable re-betrayal.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/oh-no-everyone-in-world-of-warcraft-is-falling-for-the-hot-evil-lady-who-will-definitely-try-and-kill-us-later]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Magic: The Gathering Funko Pops Are On Their Way, And Amazon Preorders Are Open]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/more-magic-the-gathering-funko-pops-are-on-their-way-and-amazon-preorders-are-open</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-magic-the-gathering-funko-pops-are-on-their-way-and-amazon-preorders-are-open.1267419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizards of the Coast has been putting out non-cardboard <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> merchandise for a while now, but it’s been a little while since we’ve had new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/funko-pop"><u>Funko Pops</u></a> based on the property to collect.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve already seen iconic Planeswalkers like Liliana Vess, Chandra Nalaar, Garruk Wildspeaker, and Ajani Goldmane brought to life, but that was more than a decade ago. If you’ve been looking to add to your setup, though, two new characters have been remade in plastic.</p><div><ul><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a href="https://zdcs.link/Q47oeL?object_uuid=902d9df5-351d-4491-b7a3-25f0fa877d96&amp;t=article" data-cy="catalog-dealItem" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Yawgmoth Funko Pop<!-- --> </a><span> - <!-- -->$14.99</span></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a href="https://zdcs.link/aRnOXy?object_uuid=902d9df5-351d-4491-b7a3-25f0fa877d96&amp;t=article" data-cy="catalog-dealItem" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Urza Funko Pop<!-- --> </a><span> - <!-- -->$14.99</span></li></ul></div><h2 data-cy="title2">New Magic: The Gathering Funko Pops Hit Shelves Soon</h2><div catalogid="b225afdc-0be3-404f-b6f5-3d76915ebec0" id="226740"><div id="226740" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Yawgmoth Funko Pop</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Over at Amazon, two new listings have been added for <a href="https://zdcs.link/aRnOXy?object_uuid=902d9df5-351d-4491-b7a3-25f0fa877d96&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Urza</u></a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q47oeL?object_uuid=902d9df5-351d-4491-b7a3-25f0fa877d96&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Yawgmoth</u></a>. Both are available to preorder for $14.99, with release planned for November 9.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The two have fought a long war between the former’s plane of Dominaria and the latter’s Phyrexian plane, but curiously, Mishra (Urza’s brother) is nowhere to be seen this time around.</p></div><div catalogid="b225afdc-0be3-404f-b6f5-3d76915ebec0" id="226741"><div id="226741" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Urza Funko Pop</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As someone sat next to a few of the older Funkos from the Magic set, I must say I am somewhat tempted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Away from Funkos, it’s been a busy year for Magic: The Gathering. The game’s fifth set of the year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-edge-of-eternities-where-to-buy">Edge of Eternities</a>, is currently in full flow, having launched on August 1.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The next set, focused on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/spider-man-magic-the-gathering-card-reveal-spoiler-spider-verse"><u>Marvel’s Spider-Man</u></a>, will add new cards as well as a crossover with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/spider-man-magic-the-gathering-card-reveal-spoiler-spider-verse"><u>Marvel Legends figures</u></a>. So, if Funko Pops aren’t your thing, they could be worth a look instead.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 11, 2025 5:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/more-magic-the-gathering-funko-pops-are-on-their-way-and-amazon-preorders-are-open]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>