<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:06:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Dev Larian’s Huge 2023 Profits Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larians-huge-2023-profits-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-dev-larian%E2%80%99s-huge-2023-profits-revealed.1044369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larians-huge-2023-profits-revealed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">While the mainstream success of Dungeons &amp; Dragons role-playing game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> is undeniable, developer Larian has yet to announce a sales figure. But after financial records for last year were made public, we finally have an idea of just how big Baldur’s Gate 3 really was.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Confirmation comes from financial records posted by the Dublin, Ireland holding company for Larian, which is ostensibly based in Belgium, and controlled by majority shareholder, founder, and CEO Swen Vincke. (Ireland is one of the world’s most significant tax havens, with corporate tax revenues exploding in the country over the last decade.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to a paywalled report by the <a href="https://www.independent.ie/business/irish/dublin-firm-behind-baldurs-gate-game-posts-249m-profit-after-runaway-success/a2033961431.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Irish Independent</a>, Larian posted a €249 million (approx $260.9 million) pre-tax profit for 2023, which included the August release of Baldur’s Gate 3. Revenue for the year hit €427 million (approx $447.5 million).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Larian has never announced a sales figure for Baldur’s Gate 3, although publishing director Michael Douse <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/1761874915752325387" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">indicated in February</a> that the game had sold well over 10 million copies, and Hasbro, the parent company of Dungeons &amp; Dragons owner Wizards of the Coast, said in March that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-has-made-90-million-for-hasbro">Baldur's Gate 3 had earned it $90 million due to its licensing deal with Larian</a>. The Irish Independent reported that Baldur’s Gate 3 had sold around 15 million copies and paid out a €28 million dividend this year as a result.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Larian’s bumper 2023 financial results are in stark contrast to the company’s 2022, which saw a loss of €214,000 (approx $224,100) off the back of just €22.7 million (approx $23.7 million) in revenue. Baldur’s Gate 3’s wild success, then, was a game-changer for Larian, and that’s without taking into consideration the ongoing sales Baldur’s Gate 3 has pulled in so far in 2024. Indeed, Douse has said that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-player-numbers-are-up-compared-to-last-year-seemingly-due-to-mods">Baldur’s Gate 3 has 20% more active daily users this year than last</a>, with mods helping to fuel seemingly never-ending interest in the RPG.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Vincke told IGN in September that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-one-year-later-larian-interview">the success of Baldur’s Gate 3 meant Larian was now in a “luxurious position,”</a> and could “pick our own destiny and our own path.” The developer shocked the video game world when it announced plans to make brand new games outside the Dungeons &amp; Dragons universe, rather than follow Baldur’s Gate 3 with DLC or a sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Irish Independent confirmed that while Vincke owns virtually all the ordinary shares in Larian’s Dublin holding company, Chinese megacorp Tencent owns a “large chunk” of preference shares in the firm via its Tencent Cloud Europe division.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Baldur’s Gate 3 isn’t Larian’s only hit game, of course, but its success is a magnitude higher than that of its previous RPGs, including Divinity: Original Sin 1 and 2. Larian opened multiple development studios around the world to aid with the development of Baldur’s Gate 3 as part of its “following the sun” concept of 24-hour game development, with teams handing off work to the next time zone at the end of their work day to speed up development. In addition to Dublin, Larian has studios in Kuala Lumpur, Barcelona, Guildford, Quebec, Warsaw, and its original home of Ghent.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stalker 2’s First Post-Launch Patch Includes Crash, Main Quest Progression, and Graphics Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2s-first-post-launch-patch-includes-crash-main-quest-progression-and-graphics-fixes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2%E2%80%99s-first-post-launch-patch-includes-crash-main-quest-progression-and-graphics-fixes.1044366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2s-first-post-launch-patch-includes-crash-main-quest-progression-and-graphics-fixes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a> developer GSC Game World has outlined its first post-launch patch, which aims to make a number of key fixes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC’s post-apocalyptic first-person horror shooter has enjoyed a big launch, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-has-already-sold-1-million-copies-with-many-more-playing-on-xbox-game-pass">with over one million copies sold since going on sale last week</a>. But it's dragged down by significant bugs and crash issues (check out IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-review">Stalker 2 review</a> for more).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, the developers have <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1643320/view/4455843903878203415" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">revealed</a> what players can expect from the first update, due out this week on both PC and the Xbox Series X and S versions of the game. Highlights include much-needed crash fixes, main quest progression fixes, graphics fixes, and adjustments to NPC behavior. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC said future updates will make analogue stick dead zone bugfixes and A-Life system bugfixes. Free in-game content is also coming to the game - expect more on that when GSC shares its roadmap later in December.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To help you survive in the Zone, we've got a list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>Essential Stalker 2 Tips and Tricks</u></a>, plus a guide on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Things_to_Do_First_in_Stalker_2"><u>Things to Do First in Stalker 2</u></a> to help you through the early game, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Things_Stalker_2_Doesn%27t_Tell_You"><u>Things Stalker 2 Doesn't Tell You</u></a> - everything we wish we knew before we started playing. Save time scouring the wasteland with our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Artifacts_List_and_Locations"><u>Artifacts checklist and locations guide</u></a>, and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/stalker-2/Stash_Locations_and_Rewards"><u>Stash location</u></a> we've found so far.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Stalker 2 suffered a number of understandable delays, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-delayed-again-this-time-by-2-months-so-the-dev-can-fix-more-unexpected-anomalies"><u>most recently in July</u></a> when the game was due out in September. GSC said at the time that the extra two months would give the developers the chance to fix "unexpected anomalies," aka bugs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GSC has also been vocal about the challenges the studio faced getting Stalker 2 up to scratch after a mixed reaction to its debut public showing last year. At gamescom 2023, GSC addressed what some had called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stalker-2-devs-discuss-imperfect-gamescom-2023-demo-address-downgrade-debate"><u>a “downgrade” sparked by Stalker 2’s then latest gameplay trailer</u></a>. At the time, GSC told IGN it was still targeting a visual quality and level of polish suggested by Stalker 2’s eye-catching 2021 trailer despite <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-stalker-2-developers-say-the-war-in-ukraine-russian-hackers-and-death-threats-wont-break-them"><u>the horrendous conditions suffered by the staff amid the war with Russia</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornoby’s first post-launch update patch notes:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Crash Fixes, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Issues and memory allocation failures, which previously caused the game to exit unexpectedly, particularly around rendering, skeletal meshes, and quest-related cutscenes.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Main Quest Progression Fixes, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Several bugs blocking the main quest progression, NPCs getting stuck in objects, incorrect quest markers, and issues with quest cutscenes.</li><li>Revision of the main quests (like Visions of Truth or A Minor Incident) to ensure smooth transitions, avoiding rare cases of players not being able to proceed further.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Gameplay &amp; Balance Adjustments, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixing the price of the weapons with upgrades installed compared to their value without attachments.</li><li>NPCs behavior, including the way they act when lacking a shelter during the Emissions.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Cutscenes &amp; Visual Fixes, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Rarely missing facial animations, misplaced NPCs, and visual inconsistencies like detached heads and clothes clipping.</li><li>Quality and stability improvements of the visual effects.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Softlock Fixes, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Issue where players were unable to close the trade screen after putting ammo in a wrong slot while playing on a gamepad.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">User Interface Improvements, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Quest notifications now showed correctly during dialogues.</li><li>Corrected texts and missing interaction prompts.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Noted to be addressed in future updates:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Analogue sticks dead zones bugfixes.</li><li>A-Life system bugfixes.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>