<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 23:35:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Reportedly Closing in on $50 Billion Deal to Go Private]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-reportedly-closing-in-on-50-billion-deal-to-go-private</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-reportedly-closing-in-on-50-billion-deal-to-go-private.1310259/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">An agreement could be announced as soon as next week.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA is reportedly closing in on a $50 billion deal to go private in what could become the biggest leveraged buyout of all time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Details on what could be a monumental shift for the Madden and Battlefield publisher come from a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/deals/ea-private-deal-buyout-video-game-maker-808aefec?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAjQVqc7Ys8ur1V0XaDQ1feWC6NLookO3FmRygjywRaGOhyMYxk3NvqUvbkQX1Y%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68d6f7b7&amp;gaa_sig=Yqer2GoUIIKplyT6XCdJjqyiUw5J0fyvE9LzjJAVeicL1hBZCqRW6czzbP4v6vXmdLDTUDfNyeABpx__hTWJ6A%3D%3D" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Wall Street Journal</u></a> report. The site’s sources say investors include private-equity firm Silver Lake and Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund (PIF). Affinity Partners, an investment firm led by Donald Trump’s son-in-law, Jared Kushner, is also said to be in the mix.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Should the alleged deal be made official, an announcement could be made as soon as Monday. EA had a market value of about $43 billion before Wall Street Journal’s story was published. That jumped nearly 15% to around $48 billion since word of a move to go private first arrived.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A $50 billion deal to remove EA from the public stock exchange would be about $18 billion more than <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/markets/txu-agrees-to-be-acquired-for-318-billion-idUSN26267870/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>the $31.8 billion buyout of Texas power company TXU</u></a>, which occurred in 2007. Should the EA deal go through, it would likely stand as the largest leveraged buyout of all time (without adjusting for inflation).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">PIF’s supposed involvement in the buyout would see Saudi Arabia strengthen its already deep roots in the gaming industry. It currently has a 10% stake in EA, and in 2022, it <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-5-percent-owned-by-saudi-arabia"><u>became one of the largest Nintendo shareholders</u></a> with 5.01% ownership. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-go-director-talks-new-ownership-says-saudi-backing-wont-see-demands-such-as-cristiano-ronaldo-added-to-the-game-yeah-thats-a-little-bit-not-our-vibe"><u>Pokémon Go</u></a> developer Niantic also announced that it had <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-go-dev-moves-to-reassure-players-after-35-billion-sale-to-monopoly-go-company-is-confirmed"><u>sold its library of games</u></a> to mobile games maker Scopely, which is controlled by Savvy Games and PIF, earlier this year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft faced backlash after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-mirage-getting-free-saudi-arabia-dlc-later-this-year"><u>announcing Assassin’s Creed Mirage DLC set in Saudi Arabia</u></a> last month. The content was announced following a report from French outlet <a href="https://www.lesechos.fr/tech-medias/hightech/letonnant-deal-dubisoft-avec-larabie-saoudite-2144626" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Les Echos</u></a>, which shared details regarding a deal between the publisher and PIF. Ubisoft employees had also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-staff-reportedly-raised-concerns-about-saudi-arabia-deal-for-assassins-creed-mirage-dlc-as-company-insists-it-maintains-creative-control"><u>raised concerns about a partnership with the controversial entity</u></a>, according to <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/ubisoft-assassins-creed-mirage-saudi-arabia" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GameFile</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Silver Lake, meanwhile, has partial ownership in game engine tech company, Unity. Should the deal with EA go through, it would see PIF, Affinity, and Silver Lake as new owners as EA goes private.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The publisher’s list of recently released games includes a number of EA Sports titles, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ea-sports-fc-26"><u>EA Sports FC 26</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/madden-nfl-26"><u>Madden NFL 26</u></a>, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/skate"><u>Skate</u></a>. Next month, EA developer DICE will release <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6"><u>Battlefield 6</u></a>, which has been poised a particularly important moment both for the series and the publisher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has reached out to EA for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-reportedly-closing-in-on-50-billion-deal-to-go-private]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards Are Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-are-up-for-preorder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-are-up-for-preorder.1310148/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's some good news. Wizards of the Coast has announced that new Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy cards are heading our way, and they're available for preorder now (<a href="https://zdcs.link/z31jbM?object_uuid=8497b018-f022-4be1-b52f-7a2e9f33fa09&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see them at Amazon</a>). We have a new Chocobo Bundle, a new Commander Deck, and four new Scene Boxes. There's a lot to cover, so let's dive in.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">New MTG: Final Fantasy Cards</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">All the new bundles and packs are in the carousel above, so scroll on over to the item(s) of your choice.</p><p id="chocobo-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Chocobo Bundle">MTG: Final Fantasy - Chocobo Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228457"><div id="228457" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Chocobo Bundle</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 1 Chocobo Booster, 10 Play Boosters, 1 Alt-Art Promo Card, 1 Scene Card, 32 Basic Lands, 1 Click Wheel, and more.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Chocobo Bundle comes with 1 Chocobo Booster, 10 Play Boosters, 1 alt-art promo card, 1 Scene card, 32 basic lands, 1 click wheel, and more. </p></div><p id="commander-deck-game-edition"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Commander Deck - Game Edition">MTG: Final Fantasy VII - Commander Deck - Game Edition</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228458"><div id="228458" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy VII Commander Deck - Game Edition</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes Limit Break Commander Deck, Exclusive Promo Card, Final Fantasy VII Video Game Download Code, and Accessories.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Game Edition Commander Deck is a Limit Break Commander Deck that includes an exclusive promo card, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-vii">Final Fantasy VII video game</a> download code, and accessories.</p></div><p id="scene-box-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Scene Box Bundle">MTG: Final Fantasy - Scene Box Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228459"><div id="228459" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Scene Box Bundle - All 4 Scene Boxes</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes Garland at The Chaos Shrine, Children of Fate, The Siege of Alexandria, and Camp Comrades Scene Boxes.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This bundle gets you all four Scene Boxes. That means you get Final Fantasy: Garland at The Chaos Shrine, Final Fantasy VIII: Children of Fate, Final Fantasy IX: The Siege of Alexandria, and Final Fantasy XV: Camp Comrades. Read on to buy them separately, or to see what comes in each one. Note that there's no discount for buying the bundle: $167.96 is exactly the same price you'd pay if you bought them all individually.</p></div><p id="garland-at-the-chaos-shrine-scene-bo"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Garland at The Chaos Shrine Scene Bo">MTG: Final Fantasy - Scene Box - Garland at The Chaos Shrine</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228460"><div id="228460" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Scene Box - Garland at The Chaos Shrine</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters + 1 Display Easel.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Garland at the Chaos Shrine Scene Box is based on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy">original Final Fantasy game</a>, which originally came out on NES in 1987. It comes with 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters, and 1 Display Easel.</p></div><p id="children-of-fate-scene-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Children of Fate Scene Box">MTG: Final Fantasy VIII - Scene Box - Children of Fate</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228461"><div id="228461" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy VIII Scene Box - Children of Fate</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters + 1 Display Easel.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Children of Fate Scene Box is based on Final Fantasy VIII, which originally came out on PS1 in 1999. It comes with 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters and 1 Display Easel.</p></div><p id="the-siege-of-alexandria-scene-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="The Siege of Alexandria Scene Box">MTG: Final Fantasy IX - Scene Box - The Siege of Alexandria</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228462"><div id="228462" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy IX Scene Box - The Siege of Alexandria</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters + 1 Display Easel.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Siege of Alexandria Scene Box is based on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/final-fantasy-ix">Final Fantasy IX</a>, which came out on PS1 in 2000 (they used to really crank these games out, didn't they? It includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters and 1 Display Easel.</p></div><p id="camp-comrades-scene-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Camp Comrades Scene Box">MTG: Final Fantasy XV - Scene Box - Camp Comrades</h2></p><div catalogid="98d23e9c-6f20-4d70-bf7a-311e0d797348" id="228463"><div id="228463" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy XV Scene Box - Camp Comrades</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters + 1 Display Easel.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">And finally, the Camp Comrades Scene Box is based on Final Fantasy XV, which came out in 2016. It includes 6 Foil Borderless Scene Cards, 6 Art Cards, 3 Play Boosters, and 1 Display Easel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a commerce editor and deals expert for IGN. He also runs IGN's board game and LEGO coverage. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Sep 26, 2025 7:22 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-are-up-for-preorder]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>