<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:09:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Dev Says Hero Shooters Need a Really Strong Hook to Convince Fans to Ditch the Game They’re Already Playing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-says-hero-shooters-need-a-really-strong-hook-to-convince-fans-to-ditch-the-game-theyre-already-playing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-dev-says-hero-shooters-need-a-really-strong-hook-to-convince-fans-to-ditch-the-game-they%E2%80%99re-already-playing.1058079/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-dev-says-hero-shooters-need-a-really-strong-hook-to-convince-fans-to-ditch-the-game-theyre-already-playing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Concord "didn’t bring any unique value proposition."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The director of Marvel Rivals has discussed the difficulty of successfully entering the packed hero shooter market, pointing to failures like Concord as evidence of the increasing need to have a strong hook that helps convince players to ditch the game they're already invested in for something new.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony’s Concord is one of the biggest video game disasters in PlayStation history, lasting just a couple of weeks before it was brought offline amid eye-wateringly low player numbers. Sony later decided to kill the game entirely, and shut its developer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Concord was the latest in a string of recent hero shooter flops, which includes Rocksteady’s Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League. Post-launch content for that game comes to an end early 2025, just a year after launch, having left a $200 million hole in publisher Warner Bros.’ finances.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">NetEase’s Marvel Rivals, however, appears to have avoided a similar fate. It is a free-to-play live service hero shooter in the Overwatch style and benefits from the power of the Marvel brand, but it clearly clicked with the audience, hitting an impressive 10 million players in just three days.</p><div id="marvel-rivals-tier-list-best-heroes" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Marvel Rivals Tier List: Best Heroes</h3><h3>Marvel Rivals Tier List: Best Heroes</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to <a href="https://www.videogamer.com/news/marvel-rivals-dev-concord-failed-it-didnt-bring-any-unique-value/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VideoGamer.com</a>, Marvel Rivals game director Thaddeus Sasser said Concord “didn’t bring any unique value proposition,” which contributed to its failure. But speaking more generally about the hero shooter market, Sasser said live service games need a hook to convince players of already successful hero shooters to jump ship having already invested their time and money in those games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There’s a switching cost,” Sasser said. “I’ve already invested in Overwatch, I’ve got 15 skins for Pharah, I’m not going anywhere.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ultimately, Sasser said, the market is incredibly difficult to predict, and game developers never know how popular their game will be until it’s actually out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“As a game developer you’re always worried until the audience has responded,” Sasser continued. “The truth is that I don’t think anybody can accurately predict this or the game industry would be radically different today. There’s a lot of games that come out that people are like, ‘It’s going to do well,’ then it flops or people come out and go, ‘It’s going to flop,’ and it succeeds amazingly. So, I think it’s really hard to tell ahead of time and you’re always worried about that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Marvel Rivals, Sasser suggested its superhero factor is the reason fans are willing to leave their favorite games behind to give it a shot.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I don’t know about you, but when I heard the concept of the game I was like, ‘Oh my God I want to go be Storm in a game, I want to go be Doctor Strange in a game. I want to be those heroes in the game, that sounds awesome.’ And of course my mind immediately leapt to all the cool possibilities you could have with that. That’s what I think will pull people in as well too. If we’ve done our jobs well, they’ll love what they play and they’ll want to play some more.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For NetEase, it will be hoping not only to keep Marvel Rivals’ player count as high as possible for as long as possible (something that’s proved particularly tricky for live service games of late), but to make enough money from players to meet the company’s internal revenue projections. To that end, Marvel Rivals sells a battle pass and premium skins, but are they convincing players to open their wallets? Early signs suggest they are — Marvel Rivals is the second top-selling game on Steam by revenue, behind only Grinding Gear Games’ action RPG <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/path-of-exile-2"><u>Path of Exile 2</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Keep an eye on the latest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-codes">Marvel Rivals codes</a> for free skins, and vote on the strongest Marvel Rivals characters in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/marvel-rivals/Marvel_Rivals_Characters">community tier list</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Reveals Free Expansion Coming to Astro Bot This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-reveals-free-expansion-coming-to-astro-bot-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-reveals-free-expansion-coming-to-astro-bot-this-week.1057983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-reveals-free-expansion-coming-to-astro-bot-this-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has revealed that PlayStation 5 exclusive Astro Bot is getting a free expansion tomorrow, December 12, which adds a whole new level called Winter Wonder to the beloved platformer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/11/astro-bot-winter-wonder-update-out-tomorrow/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a> post revealed the expansion arrives at 6pm Pacific / 9pm Eastern, meaning 2am on December 13 in the UK. It's available at no extra cost to anyone who owns Astro Bot but requires completion of the base game to play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Since releasing Astro Bot earlier this year on PlayStation 5, we have been submerged by lovely comments from you and the PlayStation community, and we are delighted with the critical response to the game all over the world," said Nicolas Doucet, studio director of developer Team Asobi.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/12/11/astro1-1733929925771.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Winter Wonder in Astro Bot (Image Credit: PlayStation)</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"From the bottom of our hearts, thank you so much for showing your appreciation. It truly means a lot to us. As our way of saying thank you, it is my pleasure to announce that a whole new piece of free additional content is coming to Astro Bot. Indeed, the little robotic elves of Team Asobi have been very busy preparing a whole new level called Winter Wonder."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Doucet didn't share much on what fans can expect of the new level, though a single screenshot shows a festive world with a large Christmas tree at its centre.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Since we want it to remain a little surprise, we will not say too much, but you should expect a fun-filled level with shiny presents, a good dose of jingle bells, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-players-expect-more-dlc-as-unreleased-bots-still-remain-in-the-credits">brand-new special bots to add to your crew</a>," Doucet said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This winter update was made with every user in mind, meaning it is a celebration enjoyable for children and adults alike. So, no hair-pulling challenge this time," he added, likely referencing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-confirms-astro-bot-post-launch-speedrun-levels-and-special-bots-release-schedule">the previous series of speedrun challenges released as downloadable content</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-exclusive-astro-bot-sells-15-million-in-2-months">Astro Bot sold 1.5 million units in its first two months</a> on sale and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/astro-bot-review">earned a 9/10 in IGN's review</a>. "A fantastically inventive platformer in its own right, Astro Bot is particularly special for anyone with a place in their heart for PlayStation," we said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>