<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 11:30:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kaiju No. 8 The Game is Out on August 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kaiju-no-8-the-game-is-out-on-august-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kaiju-no-8-the-game-is-out-on-august-31.1265394/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Take control of members of Japan’s Defense Force and wreck impossibly large foes.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Akatsuki Games has announced that its game based on the hugely popular manga and anime series Kaiju No. 8 will be released globally for Android and iOS on August 31st (JST), with a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3393070/KAIJU_NO_8_THE_GAME/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>PC version</u></a> to follow later.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/kaiju-no-8"><u>Kaiju No. 8</u></a> tells the story of Kafka Hibino, a member of the crews that clean up after kaiju threats have been eliminated in greater Tokyo, but who longs to be a soldier in the Japan Defense Force (JDF), and actually be on the front lines. With goofy humour, slick action, an endearing protagonist and some pretty wild twists and turns, it’s a fun series. Its second season is airing now, but you can read <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kaiju-no-8-season-1-review"><u>our review of season one here</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Kaiju No. 8 The Game will let you take control of a host of fan favourite members of the JDF including Kikoru Shinomiya, Reno Ichikawa, Mina Ashiro, Gen Narumi and Soshiro Hoshina, and form them into four person squads to do battle against a new kaiju threat. What’s going on? Strange Dimensional Gates are opening up all over the place and otherworldly kaiju are flooding in. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The game also introduces a special unit named CLOZER, which exists to deal with the Dimensional Gates, and is commanded by a brand new character – Kikoru Shinomiya’s sister, Sagan Shinomiya. Other new characters introduced in the game include Chester Lochburn, CLOZER’s strategist who is able to wield a wide range of weapons, and Suited, the brains behind CLOZER’s weapons development.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Kaiju No. 8 The Game Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Kaiju No. 8 The Game features a turn-based battle system that lets your squad work together to expose the core of the kaiju you’re facing in order to dispatch them, and fights scale all the way from confrontations with smaller Yoju through to skyscraper-sized beasts capable of razing cities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Can this free-to-play live service title capture the intensity of the source material’s battles? And when will it be set in the timeline? Find out on August 31.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Cam Shea headed up Australia’s editorial team for many years but these days mostly lives and breathes craft beer.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/kaiju-no-8-the-game-is-out-on-august-31]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse: 1999 Brings Assassin’s Creed Legacy Characters and Story Content in Its First Globally Synced Collaboration]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/reverse-1999-brings-assassins-creed-legacy-characters-and-story-content-in-its-first-globally-synced-collaboration</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reverse-1999-brings-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-legacy-characters-and-story-content-in-its-first-globally-synced-collaboration.1265334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Free-to-play time-traveling strategic RPG Reverse: 1999 just launched its biggest collaboration yet, its first to ever launch simultaneously worldwide, and it teamed up with another time-jumping franchise to do it: Assassin’s Creed. The collab adds new story chapters and popular characters Ezio, Kassandra, and Alexios, all three of whom will be playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reverse: 1999 first launched in 2023 and has seen global success in the time since. It’s been downloaded more than 30 million times worldwide and stands at “very positive” with more than 2,500 reviews on Steam. Those fans have been clamoring for this collab since it was first announced earlier this year, and there’s been particular excitement about the addition of Ezio — as you can see from the 270,000 views and hundreds of comments on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=brCaA-vcDmQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>his official trailer</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While the characters and story content might be the headliners of this collab, there’s a lot more to it than that. You can see Assassin’s Creed inspirations in the UI, music, and garments that have been added. Plus, there are free goodies being given away (including Alexios), extra prizes in the gacha system designed to make it easier to pull the new characters, and both online and offline events to celebrate.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s get into the details, shall we?</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/offline-events-1754590432413.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Familiar Faces in a Journey Through History</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Reverse: 1999’s story takes you through different eras of history, and that trend continues with this crossover, whose new content will be released in two phases. Phase 1 is live right now and will run until September 18. It adds a story chapter that brings you to Florence, Italy, where you’ll meet the legendary Ezio Auditore da Firenze from Assassin’s Creed II.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gS2PNVbI9hs" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>collaboration trailer</u></a> hints at how the story of Phase 1 will bring you into contact with Ezio. Mr. APPLe, one of the important characters of Reverse: 1999, is mistaken for a fabled Apple of Eden and must be protected. He’s nearly dissected by Leonardo da Vinci, another character from Assassin’s Creed II who plays a significant role in the Phase 1 story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=brCaA-vcDmQ" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Ezio’s character trailer</u></a> shows some of the memories from his journey in Assassin’s Creed II — his assassinations, gathering feathers for his brother, the tragic execution of his family — materializing into different weapons, which references the unique ability he brings into Reverse: 1999. He can wield several different primary and secondary weapons and can swap them out as needed, so he’s always ready for any situation.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/ezio-skills-1754588499590.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Like all other 6-star characters, Ezio comes with two garments, the second of which is unlocked after increasing his Insight level. His first garment is the assassins’ classic white robe, and his second (featured in the photo of him above) is the Armor of Altair from Assassin’s Creed II, which was built by and named after the hero of the original Assassin’s Creed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kassandra and Alexios will join in on the fun when the story shifts to Ancient Greece in Phase 2 of the collab, which will run from August 28 to September 18. Like Ezio, Kassandra will get a unique ability designed to make her adaptable: She has three skill trees (Hunter, Warrior, and Assassin) and can switch between them.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/kassandra-skills-1754588518136.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond the characters and plot, Assassin’s Creed fans will notice other references. The level selection interface adopts the genetic sequence design of the Animus, and music — including the familiar song “Ezio’s Family” — has been pulled from the Assassin’s Creed series. The Into the Shadows mode will let you see the villa in Monteriggioni and complete events in Florence and Venice to experience the Renaissance assassin life like Ezio.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/animus-ui-1754588548609.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Dress Up for the Special Collab</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">It wouldn’t be a Reverse: 1999 update without new garments, and this collab is no exception. Four characters have new garments inspired by Assassin’s Creed and Greek mythology (pictured below). Hissabeth’s new look is inspired by Medusa, the famous snake-haired Gorgon from Greek myth who put up a hell of a fight in Assassin’s Creed: Odyssey. The art showing off her new garment shows her dancing between Medusa’s two sisters frozen in stone, the crown she wears pays homage to Assassin’s Creed: Odyssey’s Medusa design, and the artifact she’s holding resembles an Apple of Eden.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marcus’s new garment draws from the myth of the musician Orpheus, who traveled to the underworld and used his music to convince Hades to let him take back his deceased wife Eurydice, on the condition that he not look back at her until they reached the surface. During their ascension, Orpheus was overcome with doubt and couldn’t help looking back, and Eurydice was taken from him forever. Marcus’s art recalls this moment of legend, as she glances back and offers her hand to guide her fallen friends to the gates of the underworld.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Vila gets a new garment inspired by the Sirens of Homer’s Odyssey who would lure sailors to their deaths with their beautiful song. Her artwork shows her standing among violet waves and singing as storms gather around her, and the Poseidon statue beside her is pulled directly from Assassin’s Creed: Odyssey.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last but certainly not least, APPLe’s new garment turns him gold, and you can see how Leonardo da Vinci and other characters in Florence would mistake him for an Apple of Eden, the symbol of desire and temptation. And best of all, APPLe’s new garment is free for all players during the collaboration event.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/new-garments-1754588582161.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>A Celebration with Free Goodies</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">APPLe’s new garment isn’t the only thing that’s free. In this collab version, every player can get a free monthly pass that allows them to get 2,700 Clear Drops in total, which is 15 free gacha pulls. Additionally, free resources given out during the collaboration will make it possible to have at least 43 pulls on the event banners. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">During Phase 2, everyone can recruit Alexios for free by taking part in the collaboration’s events. Plus, to celebrate the partnership with Assassin’s Creed, players can receive additional collaboration characters after 100/160/220/280 pulls. And there are other log-in and event rewards that you can see in the image below.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/event-rewards-1754588619674.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>There’s Always More to Learn</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">You can download Reverse: 1999 for free right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3092660/Reverse_1999/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Steam</u></a>, the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/reverse-1999/id1672933190?source_caller=ui&amp;shortlink=o8b6chbd&amp;c=GlobalLaunch_Website_ios&amp;pid=Website&amp;af_xp=custom" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>iOS App Store</u></a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bluepoch.m.en.reverse1999&amp;source_caller=ui&amp;shortlink=ujn2ppo2&amp;c=GlobalLaunch_Website_android&amp;pid=Website&amp;af_xp=custom" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Google Play</u></a> and <a href="https://re1999.bluepoch.com/en/home/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Windows PC</u></a>. The Assassin’s Creed collaboration is live now, and with all the goodies being given away for free, there’s never been a better time to jump in.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want more info about the existing characters of Reverse: 1999, you can check out the <a href="https://re1999.bluepoch.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>official website</u></a> for details. You can also follow the game and join the community on <a href="https://x.com/Reverse1999_GL" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Twitter</u></a>, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@reverse1999_official" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>TikTok</u></a>, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/reverse1999" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Discord</u></a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/reverse1999global" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Facebook</a>, or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@Reverse1999" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>YouTube</u></a>.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/reverse-1999-brings-assassins-creed-legacy-characters-and-story-content-in-its-first-globally-synced-collaboration]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims Board Game Nobody Asked for Was Quietly Released at Target Last Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-board-game-nobody-asked-for-was-quietly-released-at-target-last-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-board-game-nobody-asked-for-was-quietly-released-at-target-last-month.1265292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has flat out said that fans <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-isnt-considering-the-sims-5-right-now-because-its-not-player-friendly-to-expect-fans-to-give-up-all-of-the-content-that-youve-purchased-over-the-years">shouldn't expect The Sims 5 anytime soon</a>. But if you're looking for a new release from the franchise, you'll be happy to know a new Sims game actually did just come out July. Did you somehow miss this momentous news? I certainly did, and that's because it's actually just a board game. The Sims Board Game arrived at Target on July 20, 2025 and it seems to have gone largely unnoticed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Which makes a lot of since to me. It's been a long time since I've <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-play-the-sims-4-for-free">played The Sims 4</a>, but having spent a decent amount of time in that game I can't really conceptualize how it would effectively transition to a tabletop experience. The board game itself is a collaboration with Goliath that was <a href="https://toybook.com/goliath-toy-fair-the-sims/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced back in February</a> and garnered a bit of news coverage from various gaming outlets, but now that it's available to buy nobody seems to be talking about it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">The Sims Board Game Is Now Available</h2><div catalogid="cdfb0e74-d1e7-4aeb-ae61-69db2d44034c" id="226620"><div id="226620" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Sims Board Game</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I have no plans on ever purchasing or playing this game, but for the sake of this article I <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QhJRd7kETJg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">watched the official how to play video</a> recently published on the Goliath YouTube channel. It's about five and a half minutes long and after sitting through the whole thing, I'm still not sure how to categorize this game or even how to actually play it. The gameplay and rules seem unnecessarily confusing despite the narrator suggesting just "tossing out the rulebook" early on in the video. The main theme of the game is that each player tries to earn points by completing aspirations and various actions throughout play. The first player to eight points wins, with the bonus option of playing to 10 points instead to make the game longer.</p><p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/07/81xkkoo1k2l-ac-sl1500-1754608096208.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The full set up</figcaption></figure></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As confusing as the gameplay seems, what turns me off to this game the most about this game is that it's meant for 2-5 players. That immediately removes the thing about playing The Sims I enjoyed the most: That I got to do it by myself. Introducing one or more players into the experience seems like a recipe for disaster. It's being marketed as a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-family-board-games">family board game</a>, but I could never imagine trying to play this with my actual family.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although it initially launched at Target, The Sims Board Game is currently available to preorder from Amazon with an August 15 release date. If you feel like giving it a try, it is actually pretty reasonably priced at $19.99.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 7, 2025 11:18 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sims-board-game-nobody-asked-for-was-quietly-released-at-target-last-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>