<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 13:45:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The New Oblivion Looks Like a Remake but Plays Like a Remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-new-oblivion-looks-like-a-remake-but-plays-like-a-remaster</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-new-oblivion-looks-like-a-remake-but-plays-like-a-remaster.1174437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-new-oblivion-looks-like-a-remake-but-plays-like-a-remaster<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">When Bethesda finally revealed Oblivion Remastered earlier this week, I could hardly believe my eyes. Somehow 2006’s trip to Tamriel, known for its weird, potato-faced characters and smeary stretches of low-res verdant grasslands, is now the best-looking Elder Scrolls game ever made. A long history of HD overhauls has conditioned me to expect underwhelming results from remasters – Mass Effect Legendary Edition and Dark Souls Remastered are barely indistinguishable from their Xbox 360 parents, for instance – and so to see the Imperial City that I explored nearly 20 years ago rendered in Unreal Engine 5 with ray tracing was momentarily unbelievable. Not only that, but the game has been enhanced with upgrades to combat, RPG systems, and a multitude of other details. All that considered, I wondered if Bethesda and the project’s developer, Virtuos, had got the title wrong. Surely this is Oblivion <em>Remake</em>, not remastered? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It turns out I wasn’t alone in that thinking. Numerous <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-fans-react-to-all-the-biggest-changes-say-its-good-enough-to-be-called-a-remake">fans have declared it a remake</a>, and even Bruce Nesmith, the senior game designer on the original Oblivion project, has said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-designer-says-bethesdas-remaster-is-so-impressive-it-could-be-called-oblivion-20">“I’m not sure [the word] remaster actually does it justice.”</a> But while I doubted Bethesda and Virtuos’ remaster claim at first, after playing several hours it’s actually pretty clear – Oblivion Remastered may look like a remake but it plays like a remaster.    </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are plenty of reasons why Oblivion looks like a remake and they can be easily summed up: Virtuos has done a huge amount of work, with "every single asset redesigned from scratch." In terms of what you physically see on screen, it is all brand new. Every tree, every sword, every crumbling castle. This means Oblivion lives up to modern graphical expectations. Not only is it beautifully textured, it also has gorgeous lighting and a whole new physics system that ensures every arrow and weapon strike affects the world realistically. And while all who you meet in the game are recognisably the same folks you crossed paths with back in 2006, every single NPC model is a brand new creation. It’s a hugely impressive overhaul that rejects the idea of making something that “looks like you remember” and instead aims for something that’s great by 2025 standards. It’s the best a Bethesda Game Studios RPG has ever looked, and if I had seen it before the remaster rumours began I’d probably have believed that it was The Elder Scrolls 6.   </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s not just visuals, though. Combat has been overhauled, and so swinging a longsword no longer feels like fencing with a balloon. The third person camera is now actually functional thanks to the addition of a reticule. Every menu, from the quest journal to dialogue to the lockpicking and persuasion minigames, have all had refreshed interfaces. The original, horrific levelling system has been replaced with a much more logical hybrid of Oblivion and Skyrim’s approaches. And <em>finally </em>you can sprint. With so many visual and gameplay upgrades, surely we are firmly in remake territory? </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>If I had seen Oblivion Remastered before the rumours began I’d probably have believed that it was The Elder Scrolls 6.   </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The big issue here is not so much one of technology, game changes, or project scope, but semantics. There are no industry-defined parameters for remakes and remasters, and publishers recklessly throw the terms around. Rockstar’s “Definitive Edition” remasters of the Grand Theft Auto trilogy are unmistakably blocky PlayStation 2-era games with upscaled textures and modern lighting effects. But the Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy, also branded a remaster, sports all-new graphical assets and looks like a game from the modern era. Things are even muddier when we get to remakes: Bluepoint’s Shadow of the Colossus and Demon’s Souls both rebuild their respective games from the ground up, but are faithful, 1:1 recreations of the original experiences. Resident Evil 2, meanwhile, sticks more-or-less to the original blueprint in terms of structure, but completely redesigns the way you interact with the survival horror icon. And then we have Final Fantasy 7 Remake and Rebirth, which radically overhaul the design, script, and even story beats of the original games. All five of these examples are considered remakes, but there’s very little shared philosophy between them. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At one point in time, the general consensus seemed to be that if the game had been rebuilt from scratch in a modern engine, it was considered a remake. Remasters, meanwhile, were more limited upgrades performed within the scope of the game’s original technology. Such a definition is clearly becoming fast outdated, though. Today, it seems more fitting to say that a remaster is a graphical overhaul that preserves the design of the original game (bar a few quality of life gameplay upgrades), while a remake redesigns a game from scratch. Such a definition would “downgrade” Demon’s Souls and the upcoming Metal Gear Solid: Delta to remasters, and ensure the remake term only applies to games that genuinely feel like new takes on old ideas. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/oblivion-remastered-1745587732759.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">New lighting, fur, and metallic effects are just the tip of the iceburg of Oblivion Remastered's changes. Image credit: Bethesda / Virtuos</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So if we accept these proposed definitions, is this new version of Oblivion a remake or a remaster? As anyone who’s played even just an hour of it can plainly see, Oblivion Remastered absolutely has the correct name. Yes, those new assets and Unreal Engine 5 ray tracing effects make it look brand new, but beneath that glowing skin is a collection of 20-year-old bones, organs, and muscles, all roughly stapled and taped together in that unmistakably Bethesda way. As the studio explained, “We looked at every part and carefully upgraded it. But most of all, we never wanted to change the core. It’s still a game from a previous era and should feel like one.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The hallmarks of that previous era are everywhere. It's in the loading screens that hide behind almost every single door. It’s in the baffling persuasion minigame that still, despite the interface upgrade, barely makes sense and feels utterly disconnected to your conversations. It’s in the design of the cities, which have the simplistic design of theatre stage sets rather than the complex, knotty arrangements of authentic population centres. It’s in the NPCs, who wander like awkward automatons and talk with all the grace of an AI trained on a “how to be society” manual. It’s in the combat, which even after a significant upgrade still feels detached and unwieldy. And it's in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago">long list of bugs and glitches</a> that still remain, reverently preserved in the name of upkeeping the original’s quirky charm. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The granular details of Oblivion are clearly grey and long in the tooth.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Just a couple of months ago we were treated to Obsidian’s Avowed, which offered a vision of the future for some of The Elder Scrolls’ key building blocks. Its kinetic combat is practically space-age compared to Oblivion Remastered’s, while its approach to rewarding exploration makes the rolling hills and grotty caves of Cyrodiil feel very much a relic of yesteryear. Such modern systems help put Oblivion Remastered into context. That’s not to say that this revised classic has nothing to offer in 2025 – far from it. The magic of its world still sparkles brightly, its Rohan-like open fields filled with dozens of mysteries and oddities. Much of its ambition remains intact even two generations later, such as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-the-unpredictable-goblin-wars-of-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-i-introduced-controlled-chaos-whenever-i-could" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dynamic goblin wars</a> that wage between its NPC clans, or the narratively-satisfying questing structure that remains head-and-shoulders above Skyrim’s many “visit a draugr-filled dungeon” missions. Many of its old-school ideas around player freedom feel refreshing in an age where we now reject the hand-holding nature of games from the 2010s. But the granular details of Oblivion are clearly grey and long in the tooth. There’s no finesse in its dialogue, nor elegance in the way its systems interconnect. And the level design, be it cave, castle, or the cursed lands of Oblivion itself, feels positively ancient. A remake’s job would be to update all those ideas, but this project is all about reliving the old. As such: Oblivion <em>Remastered</em>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Video games have historically leant on terminology from other mediums. In the world of movies, remakes are brand new productions with fresh casts, crews, scripts, and sets. Remasters are existing films that are enhanced as far as possible to match modern picture quality standards. But an old film is still an old film; the 4K restorations of Jaws and The Godfather look incredible, but they are clearly products of the 1970s. You can see it in the direction, the delivery, the effects work. It’s in the texture of the film grain. Oblivion is like those blu-ray restorations of classic films. It pushes visual quality as far as it possibly can, which thanks to the more malleable medium of video games means recreating the project’s “exterior” in a brand new engine. But beneath that shell, Oblivion is unmistakably a product of the 2000s. Alex Murphy, executive producer at Virtuos, had the perfect analogy during the reveal stream: "We think of the Oblivion game engine as the brain and Unreal 5 as the body. The brain drives all the world logic and gameplay and the body brings to life the experience that players have loved for almost 20 years."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Oblivion Remastered is exactly what it says it is, and that shouldn’t be seen as downplaying its achievements. Instead of insisting that it's a remake, we should actually be using it as the quality bar by which we judge remasters from other titan-scale AAA companies. This is what Mass Effect Legendary Edition should have been, rather than a cleaned-up re-release. This is what Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy should have been rather than an incredibly cynical-feeling cash grab. Because there’s nothing cynical about Oblivion Remastered. It looks like a remake crafted by passionate hands but plays like a remaster preserved by loving fans, and that’s exactly how it should be. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maxroll’s Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Branch with Guides, Codex, and Planner]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-clair-obscur-expedition-33-branch-with-guides-codex-and-planner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maxroll%E2%80%99s-clair-obscur-expedition-33-branch-with-guides-codex-and-planner.1174299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/maxrolls-clair-obscur-expedition-33-branch-with-guides-codex-and-planner<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is a new RPG and debut title from the French studio, Sandfall Interactive. With a blend of immersive storytelling and challenging gameplay, there’s nothing else quite like it. Maxroll has been hard at work on helpful guides for Expedition 33. There are guides to help you get started, teach you game mechanics, find valuable loot, and hone your builds. Maxroll’s Codex has weapons, skills, Pictos, and Lumina to help you prepare for the challenges you will face on the continent. If you’re the theorycrafty type, you can use <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/planner" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maxroll’s Expedition 33 Planner</a> to make your own build, then share it on their Community Builds Section.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Getting Started</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Get started in the world of Expedition 33 with character guides, beginner resources, and Pictos guides from Maxroll. If you're looking for a step-by-step companion guide to keep up as you play, check out IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Walkthrough">Expedition 33 Walkthrough</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Beginner’s Guide</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll’s comprehensive <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/getting-started-in-clair-obscur-expedition-33-beginners-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Beginner’s Guide for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> introduces the game’s core mechanics like exploring the world, doing battle against Nevrons, each of the playable characters and their unique mechanics, plus introduces the game’s progression systems like weapons, attributes, Pictos and Luminas. Also check out IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Tips_-_Things_Clair_Obscur_Doesn't_Tell_You">10 Things Expedition 33 Doesn't Tell</a> You for a shorter guide of some easily-missed things you should know. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Combat Guide</h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Learn more about defeating dangerous Nevrons with IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Combat_Guide">Combat Guide</a>. This is a beginner's guide with some tips and tricks, including advice for how to use Lune and Maelle. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Weapons, Attributes and Upgrades</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-4-weapon-upgrades-1745597510492.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Weapons are a core part of building your team in Expedition 33. Each weapon (and character skill) deals different types of elemental damage, some of which are more effective than others against different Nevrons. Each character has a variety of different weapons that have increased attribute scaling as you level them, plus unlock special bonuses at levels 4, 10, and 20. Read more about <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/weapon-attributes-upgrades-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Weapons, Attributes and Upgrades</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pictos and Luminas</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-5-pictos-and-luminas-1745597543961.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Pictos are equippable items that give stats and a variety of unique effects. Each character can equip 3 Pictos, but you can use the Lumina system to gain even more special effects. If you’re struggling on an encounter, consider changing up your Pictos to gain more defenses, add damage or buff your team with things like Shell or Powerful. Learn more about <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/pictos-lumina-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pictos and the Lumina system</a>, a core progression feature in Expedition 33, and keep track of what you have and where to find them with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/All_Pictos_List_and_Effects">IGN's Pictos checklist</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Early Game Pictos Guides</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-6-early-game-pictos-1745597566812.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pictos system provides a lot of room to customize your party and build each character the way that you want, but there are a few Pictos which stand out as especially powerful during the early game. Keep an eye out for <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/how-to-get-dead-energy-ii-and-critical-burn" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dead Energy II and Critical Burn</a>, complete side-content for the “lone wolf” style <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/hidden-gestral-arena-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Last Stand Pictos</a> and use <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/how-to-get-recovery" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Recovery</a> to turn one character into a super-tank!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Characters</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Learn about each playable <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Characters">character</a> in Expedition 33, their unique mechanics, and skills with Maxroll’s Character Skill Guides.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/gustave-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gustave</a> </li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/lune-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lune</a> </li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/maelle-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maelle</a> </li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/sciel-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sciel</a> </li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/verso-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Verso</a></li><li><a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/monoco-skills-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Monoco</a> </li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">More Guides</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-7-more-guides-1745597607254.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll also has a few more guides suitable for the midgame and endgame. These go into detail on how to unlock areas of the map, defeat certain enemies more easily, or which Pictos are the best.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Unlock all of Esquie’s Traversal Abilities</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Esquie can break through obstacles, swim, fly, and even dive under the ocean. Learn how to unlock all of <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/how-to-unlock-diving-and-esquies-other-abilities" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Esquie’s Abilities</a> as you progress through the game. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Enemy Strengths and Weaknesses</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Learn about the <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/enemy-weakness-resistance-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Strengths and Weaknesses</a> for the enemies you encounter across the Continent. Abuse enemy weaknesses to deal 50% more damage, and avoid using elements they absorb, as those heal the enemy instead of damaging them!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Zone Progression</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re feeling lost after completing the game’s story, Maxroll has you covered with a <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/expedition-33-zone-progression-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zone Progression Guide</a>, which gives some recommendations on when to complete different optional zones. IGN also has a list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Side_Quests">Expedition 33 side quests</a> with their rewards, so you can determine which ones are worth completing. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Best Pictos</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Learn the <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/guides/best-pictos-guide" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Best Pictos</a> to equip in both the early game and the endgame. Maxroll’s guide details Pictos that provide generic power along with those that have more niche uses, empowering new build archetypes.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Codex</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-8-codex-1745597631958.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Maxroll’s <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/codex" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Expedition 33 Codex</a> has information on all of the different Weapons, Pictos, Luminas, and Skills available in the game. You can even adjust the level at the top to see how Weapons/Pictos scale.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Planner and Community Builds</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-9-planner-community-builds-1745597655224.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Plan out your build using <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/planner" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maxroll’s Expedition 33 Builder</a>, then share it using the <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/planner/community-builds" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Community Builds section</a> ! Let’s go over a few of the planner’s key features:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/25/clair-obscur-img-10-planner-breakdown-1745597676329.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are the features to keep in mind when using Maxroll’s Expedition 33 Planner.</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Select your characters and set up the active party. If you want to create different teams (with unique setups for each character) you can also do so here. At the top select an optional tag like “Story” or “Post-Story.” You use this section to navigate between each of the characters on your team to change their setups.</li><li>Pick your weapon, then adjust the level. As you do the power and scaling change but attributes are not currently factored in.</li><li>- Select the 6 skills you’re using on the character. <ul data-cy="list"><li>NOTE: Gradient Skills are excluded here but you can learn more about them in the <a href="https://maxroll.gg/clair-obscur-expedition-33/codex" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Codex</a>! </li></ul></li><li>Pick your Pictos, you can use each Pictos once across your entire team. Select the correct level to display the stats added by each.</li><li>Add Luminas here, the point count is displayed at the top.</li><li>Allocate attributes, maybe use something your weapon scales off of?</li><li>Your stats are displayed here, based on Pictos, Attributes, and base weapon damage.</li><li>Add some notes, tell people about your skill rotation or where you found some of the cool stuff you’re using.</li><li>Set your build to public to share it with the community.</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Tomorrow Comes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s it for Maxroll’s new guides for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33. Why not head over to the build planner and start theorycrafting? </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Written by IGN Staff with contributions from Tenkiei and Snail.</em><br>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered Update Adds Unexpected Visual Issues as Bethesda Works on a Fix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix.1174239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-update-adds-unexpected-visual-issues-as-bethesda-works-on-a-fix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Stop right there!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered"><u>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</u></a> PC players ran into trouble after a surprise update launched today, but Bethesda says a fix is on the way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players woke up to find that Virtuos’ massive re-release received an unexpected update earlier today. With no patch notes or clear answer as to what the update addressed, most proceeded with their play sessions as normal. Others, however, quickly found that the first Oblivion Remastered update was causing more problems than it fixed</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Twon. (@Web3Twon) <a href="https://twitter.com/Web3Twon/status/1915794767478247930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 25, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">“Can't change the upscaling methods anymore,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/oblivion/comments/1k7lsaz/comment/moz0mwp/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user pointed out</u></a>. “It's set to ‘off’ and while the arrows are clickable nothing happens. So I closed the game, disabled fluid motion in the NVidia app (was testing something before the patch came) and started the game again. Loading times for my save are long again and still can't change upscaling settings lol.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Now I am stuck with 40-60 fps in high settings with a 5800X3D and a 5080. Nice patch :D”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While some players haven’t noticed much of a change in performance, others are reporting new struggles related to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/oblivion/comments/1k7lsaz/comment/moz2o4t/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">low framerates</a>. Many have also noted that upscaling settings have been completely closed off, leaving fans with major visual issues ahead of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-launches-big-on-steam-and-its-only-going-to-get-bigger"><u>Oblivion Remastered’s first weekend in players’ hands</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda finally attempted to address concerns with <a href="https://help.bethesda.net/?linkId=100000361536740#en/answer/69841" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post</a> published on its official support page. As for what today’s Oblivion Remastered update was meant to fix, the post explains the patch simply included “a few backend tweaks and nothing directly impacting game play.” Unfortunately, it seems those who own Oblivion Remastered through the Microsoft Store are the ones running into problems with their upscaling and anti-aliasing options.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Any graphic settings adjusted prior to the Microsoft Store hotfix are still enabled and function normally," Bethesda clarified. "However, you will temporarily be unable to adjust those settings due to the issue with the settings UI. The team is taking a look and working out a resolution, we will share more info as soon as we can."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">For now, there’s no telling when exactly a resolution for what was originally supposed to be an under-the-radar hotfix will arrive. In the meantime, it appears players on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X | S consoles can continue playing with no issue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion launched for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X | S earlier this week. For more on Bethesda’s shadow-drop re-release, you can check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>why Bethesda and Virtuos aimed to maintain the jank of the original game</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yes-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-still-has-all-the-bugs-glitches-and-memes-fans-know-and-love-from-20-years-ago"><u>why some players still love it all these years later</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>