<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 12:44:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pragmata Aims to Break the Rules of Third-Person Shooters | gamescom 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pragmata-aims-to-break-the-rules-of-third-person-shooters-gamescom-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pragmata-aims-to-break-the-rules-of-third-person-shooters-gamescom-2025.1275429/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">After a period of time, video game genres tend to calcify. They establish firm rulesets that are difficult to break. This leads to familiarity and, eventually, repetition. How many third-person shooters have you played that all kind of felt the same? Capcom is trying to break the rules with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pragmata">Pragmata</a>, a sci-fi shooter in which you have to hack every enemy before you can do any damage to them. It’s a smart idea – one we first got to grips with at this year’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pragmata-hands-on-preview">Summer Game Fest</a>, and have now had a chance to explore further at gamescom 2025. But while it produces a combat experience quite different to anything I’ve played before, I’m left wondering if that same level of ingenuity will be felt in Pragmata’s exploration and level design, too. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the past decade or so, perhaps the most popular method to spice up shooters has been increased speed and movement – see games like Vanquish, Titanfall, and Doom: Eternal. Pragmata twists the dial in the opposite direction, slowing the tempo right down in favour of making each individual combat engagement longer and more complex. Hugh, your armoured astronaut, cannot put a dent in the enemy robots until your mysterious synthetic child sidekick, Diana, hacks through their firewall. This is done via a quick minigame – aiming at a foe displays a grid on which you must draw a line, passing through damage-increasing blue tiles on the way to an end point. Succeed, and you’re weapons free to pump your target full of lead.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Pragmata - Preview Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The hacking challenge varies depending on your targets. Flimsy flying drones are protected by a mere three-by-three grid, while big chunky mechs have a larger five-by-five grid that may also feature blockers that must be avoided as you snake towards the finish line. Acquiring hacking nodes during your travels will also populate the grid with additional tiles that, when passed through, apply additional effects such as lowering an enemy’s defence, allowing you to deal greater damage upon the hack’s completion. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While all this initially requires some mental recalibration to get to grips with, after chewing through three or four enemies it became second nature… and perhaps a little too easy. At least during the demo’s sample section, enemies only arrived in ones and twos – certainly a concession to the fact that you have to solve a puzzle in real-time as an android tries to rip you apart. But by the mid-point of a short half-an-hour demo I was already eager for an increased challenge – be that via increased enemy numbers, more complex hacking challenges, or ideally a mix of both. I fully expect that’s the thesis behind Pragmata’s difficulty curve, but I hope it doesn’t take too long to find the right balance. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The best example of where things may be headed is the SectorGuard boss battle, the demo’s explosive finale. This big boy bipedal bot is armed with multi-missile launchers that cause the entire arena floor to light up with warning beacons as warheads fly through the air. The challenge, of course, is to avoid the incoming rockets while simultaneously hacking through the robot’s firewalls. And since this is a boss, a single hack won’t do – you’ll need to repeatedly burn through different layers of security as the battle rages on. <em>This </em>is the kind of multi-tasking juggling act that I hope Pragmata can continually deliver as the campaign opens up.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The hacking mechanic creates a functioning symbiotic relationship between Hugh and Diana – they simply cannot survive without each other.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The SectorGuard battle also introduces one of Pragmata’s flashier abilities. Diana has a sort of “ultimate” hack called Overdrive Protocol which stuns all enemies around you and opens them up to damage. Triggering this requires filling a meter that <em>sloooowly</em> builds each time you perform a regular hack. I expect such a skill will be utterly invaluable when facing a room full of relentless enemies, but a single boss wasn’t the ideal testing ground – especially when I could hold it in place using a stasis gun that deploys a large disabling dome.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While I’d have liked a fiercer sampling of what this new combat system is capable of, it certainly sparks my imagination. The hacking mechanic also creates a functioning symbiotic relationship between Hugh and Diana – they simply cannot survive without each other, and I hope that theme becomes something meaningful as the story progresses. Unfortunately the gamescom demo was light on narrative, only divulging that Hugh is stranded in a damaged lunar base and must find his way back to Earth. We’ll have to wait and see if this new dynamic duo has any substance in their relationship – and if their adventure will be quite as reality-shattering weird as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-pragmata-capcom-release-date-2022">Pragamata’s debut trailer</a> was, back in 2020. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The other thing I’m curious to see more of is Pragmata’s wider exploration and adventure design. This demo featured minimal combat engagements and so often I was running through the station without an enemy in sight. That meant the focus for long stretches was entirely on navigating the environment, done so via some light platforming. I appreciate how each character’s combat abilities are re-purposed here; Hugh’s suit thrusters, used to dodge attacks, are here utilised to leap further or hover over long drops. Diana’s hacking skills can rewire the facility’s mechanised components, raising or retracting pillars in Pragmata’s equivalent of moving crates around. It’s a fine starting point, but I’d have liked the exploration to have its own interesting mechanical quirk to mirror the efforts made with combat. There are terminals to hack and obstacles to power down that make use of a couple of bespoke-but-basic minigames, but at least in this section they don’t feel like a cohesive part of the experience in the same way the combat hacking does. And considering the even balance of battle and exploration in this demo, I think both halves need to be equally interesting. With any luck, those environmental hacks will develop over time to unlock a more interesting approach to level design.    </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another issue is that navigation is marred by an environment that looks near-identical no matter what room you’re in, resulting in a bit of involuntary backtracking and accidentally running in circles. My goal through the demo was to restore power by hacking five different terminals, each hidden somewhere in the base, but as I explored there was no telling if I was in an engineering bay, a server room, or a command centre. This is visually unfulfilling, but more crucially it makes it difficult to plot the space out in your head. I’d be less concerned if the demo had been more linear, but the openness of the area meant I had to scratch my head a couple of times while searching for the next terminal – especially as there’s no map. My hope is that, as Hugh and Diana delve deeper into the facility’s bowels, the “NASA in the year 3,000” aesthetic evolves to create more distinct, readable playspaces.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom has been on an almost <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-golden-age-the-rise-and-fall-resident-evil-monster-hunter-wilds">decade-long winning streak</a>, but that streak has been rooted in smart approaches to its legacy games. Where it has tripped up recently is with brand new, original ideas – 2023’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/exoprimal">Exoprimal</a> has already faded from memory. I hope that’s not the fate for Pragmata – it’s a bold thing to rethink the fundamentals of a genre as traditional as the shooter, and I’d really love to see its hack-and-blast design soar. But I can’t deny that this demo’s simple combat engagements and exploration left me feeling detached from a concept I really want to engage with. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Executive Editor of Features. </em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pragmata-aims-to-break-the-rules-of-third-person-shooters-gamescom-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Onimusha: Way of the Sword Skilfully Sharpens a PS2 Classic for a New Generation | Gamescom 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-skilfully-sharpens-a-ps2-classic-for-a-new-generation-gamescom-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-skilfully-sharpens-a-ps2-classic-for-a-new-generation-gamescom-2025.1275426/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s safe to say we’re currently living through a golden age for swordplay games. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sekiro-shadows-die-twice">Sekiro</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a> lead a pack of accomplished duelers where every strike, lunge, and parry feels supremely satisfying. Hoping to find a place among them is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/onimusha-way-of-the-sword">Onimusha: Way of the Sword</a>, Capcom’s long-awaited return to a series slumbering since the PS2 days. And, based on a small sample I’ve been able to play at gamescom 2025, I’d say its chances are looking very good indeed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in a dark fantasy reimagining of Kyoto during the Edo period of Japan, Onimusha: Way of the Sword has you take up the sharpened blades of Miyamoto Musashi, a swordsman sporting both the face of the late legendary actor Toshiro Mifune and a talking gauntlet that eats the souls of dead enemies. That second point is the more pertinent one; fallen foes drop souls, represented by flames that float around the battlefield before being sucked up by your hungry jewelry. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right, before you get any wrong ideas, Onimusha may have <em>souls </em>but it is absolutely not a <em>Soulslike</em>. On its default “action” difficulty setting, Way of the Sword is not particularly punishing, at least not in this 30-minute demo (which, admittedly, does feel plucked from very early in the story). It certainly requires skill to get the most out of the enjoyably flashy combat, but generous parry windows, a block that protects from all angles, and cushioned enemy attacks mean Onimusha seems on track to be one for all action fans, not just the FromSoft fanatics. And while I would have liked to have faced a steeper challenge in this demo, the foes I faced – especially the end-of-level boss – felt well-judged.    </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/15/onimusha-cross-swords-1755259896921.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Onimusha's swordplay has the potential to compete with the best in the business. | Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’m particularly impressed by how combat is built on a foundation of both health and stamina. Enemies are, of course, defeated by bottoming out their health bars, but each time you strike or deflect their attacks, you erode away their stamina bar. If that hits zero, the foe becomes exhausted, quite literally pausing to catch their breath. This is, of course, the perfect time to strike – a single button press triggers a “Break Issen” move that violently dismembers your target. The animations are gloriously extravagant and can be chained together if a couple of enemies have been exhausted at the same time. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For regular enemies, breaking their stamina spells instant death. And because parries quickly exhaust fodder, you’re rewarded for honing that skill – you take less damage <em>and </em>get to witness cool kills. I’m deeply amused by how you can deflect arrows back at archers who then, winded by their own projectile, stand around simply awaiting their fate of single-click decapitation. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But things change when it comes to boss fights. The demo’s final clash against the exuberant Sasaki Ganryu – a tall, gangly samurai powered up by his own Oni gauntlet – is a much fiercer affair in which you’ll deplete his stamina bar at least once before being able to deal the final blow. In this situation, an alternative version of “Break Issen” plots two marks on your target: strike the red one and you’ll be rewarded with a burst of extra damage, hit the purple to generate a bonus batch of souls. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There’s almost certainly a secret science to nailing the feel of when steel lands on steel, and Capcom has absolutely cracked it.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">And that brings us back to souls. These flickering flames are colour coded; red souls are used to purchase upgrades, while blue souls feed your Oni Power Gauge, which when full can be used to unleash special attacks. Yellow souls, meanwhile, are rarer and replenish your health. All three are vital, not just for their individual properties, but for how they form a cycle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For instance, in the demo Musashi was equipped with the Two Celestials, a twin-dagger special weapon that reaps yellow souls from fallen enemies. It can only be used when the Oni Power Gauge is topped off. As it’s a powerful attack that requires resources, it’s sensible to use it against tougher opponents who, naturally, deal more damage. Killing such foes with the Two Celestials basically refunds damage you take thanks to the yellow souls the attack creates. And so there’s the cycle - you kill foes to gain blue souls, which powers up the ability to use special attacks, which cause enemies to drop yellow souls, which instantly heal you from the wounds sustained during that fight. It perhaps doesn’t feel quite that elegant in-game, but there’s a clear system upon which battle thrives. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are other examples of that, too. Successful parries generously build a diamond-shaped meter that eventually causes your blade to temporarily erupt with damage-buffling blue sparks. Hitting that mark feels fantastic – the animation alone makes it feel as if the battle has been hit by a shot of adrenaline – but if you can continue a successful chain of deflects, you can sustain that buff seemingly indefinitely. It’s another smart system that rewards consistent skill with your blade.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/15/onimusha-souls-1755259911833.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Your Oni Gauntlet can absorb enemy souls and use them to power abilities, heal wounds, and buy upgrades. | Image credit: Capcom</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s only when I came to write this preview that I realised that Onimusha is very much a game about managing gauges and meters. You need to deplete health bars and stamina meters, build power gauges, and keep other buff-providing vessels topped up. On paper, that may sound dull and overly mathematical for a game about supernatural samurai fighting through demon-infested feudal Japan, but in practice it works well. That’s entirely down to the fact that the implement for juggling those meters – your sword – feels fantastic to wield. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The parry window may be wide, but the ringing clang of a deflect is supremely satisfying, especially because the subsequent counter attack animation is so extravagantly slick. Slicing through the amusingly gross regular “Genma” enemies, which range from mutant swordsmen to what I can only describe as demonic floating Furby heads, feels great, but it’s the boss fight that really sold me on Onimusha’s swordplay credentials. There’s almost certainly a secret science to nailing the feel of when steel lands on steel, and Capcom has absolutely cracked it – there’s an energetic flow each time the warrior’s blades meet and push each other away. And while the duel against Ganryu doesn’t feel destined to go down as an all-timer – it is, ultimately, too easy to enter those halls – I think it acts as a decent enough promise that, further into the campaign, there will be something that stands up to the very best of Ghost of Tsushima. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The gamescom demo may have been short – little more than some winding paths and a boss fight in a temple – but it’s more than enough to convince me that Onimusha: Way of the Sword is built on rock-solid swordplay fundamentals. I’m genuinely excited to master them and take on its campaign’s toughest challenges. But it’s also made me curious about several other things. As a tutorial-styled section, the demo had no real exploration opportunities, so it’s currently unclear what kind of scope the environments will work with. Then there’s the story, which caught me off-guard with its humour. There’s hints of an amusingly rocky relationship between Musashi and the voice inside his Oni gauntlet, and the pre-boss battle banter was just on the right side of goofy. I’m fascinated to see where Capcom has drawn the line between a dark samurai tale and sparky anime humour. But even if that line ultimately ends up drawing an uneven balance, I’m confident Onimusha’s razor-sharp combat will more than make up for a few bad jokes. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Executive Editor of Features. </em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-skilfully-sharpens-a-ps2-classic-for-a-new-generation-gamescom-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Project Spectrum Is Looking Extremely Weird and More Than a Little Creepy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/project-spectrum-is-looking-extremely-weird-and-more-than-a-little-creepy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/project-spectrum-is-looking-extremely-weird-and-more-than-a-little-creepy.1275285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A game of phantom and mouse.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As a general rule, any first-person game where you’re walking around derelict areas and pointing a camera at things is probably going to be super creepy, and upcoming asymmetrical shooter Project Spectrum certainly seems like it will reinforce this tried-and-true guideline. The brief eight-minute hands-off demo of this suspenseful shooter left me with as many questions as I got answers, with lots left unexplained about how exactly this weird idea will work, but it also showed signs of a fairly new take on the asymmetrical multiplayer genre that’s become one of my favorite pastimes in recent years. Taking a page out of fellow supernaturally inclined monster slaying game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hunt-showdown-1896"><u>Hunt: Showdown 1896</u></a>, you and your friends explore the map and take down dangerous creatures as you hunt the boss in each area for a final confrontation – in this case, using your camera to track the source of the reality-warping ghostly corruption that plagues the world. But instead of competing against rival crews, you’re being hunted yourself by player-controlled, bizarre looking monstrosities with frightening abilities, adding a bit of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/evolve"><u>Evolve</u></a>-like flavor to the mix.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">From the few bits of story I was able to glean, Project Spectrum has you playing as special paranormal hunters entering areas affected by a supernatural entity called Ember Zones where you’ll track down the source of the corruption and kill them dead. Mixing horror elements, like zombies rushing at you and spooky investigation sequences where you’re looking over your shoulder while snapping a photo of some strange anomaly, with more traditional FPS gameplay where you’re shooting humans in a rundown mansion and crafting improvised trip mines to keep would-be interlopers at bay, will hopefully make for a nice pairing of action-packed combat and tense creepy sections that could be a match made in heaven, even if I didn’t get the impression that story was a major focus (though it’s hard to tell from such a short demo).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There was also a pretty clever crafting system where you could do things like scavenge a soda pop can from the ground and convert it into a silencer for your pistol with a bit of good ol’ survival game ingenuity. I still have a lot of questions about how crafting works, since at one point they crafted a trip mine using a grenade and wire that they got seemingly out of nowhere, but it was still a nice touch.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The most interesting part of the demo, though, came when a powerful multi-armed creature suddenly popped out of nowhere and started hunting the players, and it was revealed to be controlled by another human.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The most interesting part of the demo, though, came when a powerful multi-armed creature suddenly popped out of nowhere and started hunting the players, and it was revealed to be controlled by another human. As a freaky-looking ball of smoke with dangerously flailing limbs, this player hopped on top of the mansion the human players were exploring and hunted them down one-by-one, leaping from place to place when they were separated from one another to pick them off. I wasn’t able to get a sense of what the creature’s abilities might be, or what it might feel like to play as them, but seeing it crawl on top of buildings, stalking unaware players down below definitely sounds like my idea of a good time.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some pretty big things I’m still not entirely clear on, like what the meta progression looks like, for example. The developer didn’t say if Project Spectrum will have a traditional story-driven campaign, or will be limited to one-off matches on a preset map where you’re making progress in some other way. Since it’s a free-to-play game with a multiplayer focus that has a lot in common with Hunt: Showdown, my guess is it’ll be the latter, but with a lot of focus on worldbuilding, it’s a bit hard to say for sure.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And although there were some neat ideas, like the crafting system and the ability to play as a creepy monster hunting players, there’s a bit too many unanswered questions for me to get excited just yet. For example, the gunplay looked a bit basic, with generic pistols and assault rifles that seemed a tad boring in a game about hunting ghosts, and melee gameplay looked a bit sloppy as well. Also, there was one part where a character revived another player, and the animation for doing so was grabbing a whole med kit and rotating it around their own arm like they were applying gauze, which broke my brain for a minute. It seems pretty likely to me that this is a very early look at a game that is likely to change quite a bit before we’re able to understand how it’s taking shape.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Project Spectrum - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ll need to see more (and hopefully get my hands on it) before I get my hopes up, but a new IP with some interesting new ideas and the chance to scare the pants off my friends as an interdimensional monster certainly is welcome news. Here’s hoping we get the chance to take a closer look at Project Spectrum in the coming months.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/project-spectrum-is-looking-extremely-weird-and-more-than-a-little-creepy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders – The First Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-the-first-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-air-riders-%E2%80%93-the-first-preview.1275282/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Buckle up for the unlikely sequel that has heaps of zany charm.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After zipping around in Kirby Air Riders for maybe an hour, I rushed back to my apartment to get in a round of Mario Kart World just to <em>see. </em>In the game’s Direct earlier this week, director Masahiro Sakurai said (even if he was just being cheeky) his unlikely GameCube sequel was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sakurai-says-kirby-air-riders-is-basically-mario-kart-in-extremely-smash-bros-style-direct"><u>“basically Mario Kart</u></a>.” And yeah, if you compare the two on the level of “a bunch of guys from decades of Nintendo games race around and/or duke it out” then sure, I guess. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In every other way, Kirby Air Riders is so extremely not just a Mario Kart redux that riding around 150cc matches at home felt practically quaint. Wall rides and bar grinds? That’s cute. In Kirby Air Riders, I’m drifting corners so screamin’ fast that I barely had time to blink. Whirlpool traps and gentle river runs? How serene. Air Riders’ Waveflow Waters race course has <em>violent</em> vortexes and corridors of walls made of water to punch through. Oh, and brace yourself for a gigantic meteor shower of fireballs that reign down during City Trials too! </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the time I spent with Air Riders, I got through a good chunk of tutorials, raced through two Air Rider courses (Floria Fields and Waveflow Waters, both of which were featured in the Direct), and crushed three rounds of City Trials, the topographical brawler and power-up collection zone that ends in a challenge of your choosing. Getting through the checklist of lessons to get a handle on maneuvering, as patronizing as they may seem for a game that now relies on two whole buttons (up from one!), was actually quite nice. Because once an Air Ride or City Trial started, it was buckle-up time and not as easy as it might seem on paper. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>As for the expanded cast of characters, I only got to mess around with a few, but Bandana Waddle Dee with his spear flurry is my early frontrunner for favorite. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Part of that boils down to each of the many machines having distinct characteristics that aren’t just a matter of alleged differences in weight and handling that a chart claims when I’m picking it. The way, say, a tank drives, which is heavy and super directionally flexible, is wildly different from Meta Knight’s soaring shadow glider, and I think a lot of the fun will be in the trial-and-error of those. As for the expanded cast of characters, I only got to mess around with a few, but Bandana Waddle Dee with his spear flurry is my early frontrunner for favorite. (I wanted to love Starman, but I need some more time for him to grow on me.)</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Like my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0xFE6aoTQYA" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>NVC host colleagues have already called out</u></a> about Kirby Air Ride (2003), City Trials is still the standout game. It’s also the most derived from Sakurai’s Super Smash Bros. directorial sensibilities, from its brawler nature down to the selection screen and slow-mo KO animations. It is, however, utter pandemonium, like the aforementioned meteors that you’ll need to avoid or sudden calls to zoom over to a highlighted area to fight in a dust-up, if you so choose. The five-minute countdown breezed by as I attempted to manhandle my gliders to collect power-ups, food items that were practically copy-pasted from the real world into the dreamy palette of Kirby Air Riders, and also wreck some other players. Was I excelling at any of this? Not really, but the game didn’t make winning feel like it was the priority (which I guess is quite different from Smash Bros., where loser characters look onto the winner with existential anguish). It was more important to simply have fun, and it’s easy to imagine anyone from grade schoolers to college kids and cool adults (ahem) turn Kirby Air Riders into a shouty party game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The maximalism of Kirby Air Riders is its core charm; it feels brewed from impish, chaotic-neutral alchemy. Even Nintendo is calling this a “vehicle action game,” not a kart racer, which honestly seems apt – a silly genre distinction for a purposefully unserious game. It might not have been the sequel the people were clamoring for, but I’m glad that it exists. </p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-the-first-preview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>