<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:04:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Blade Zero Is a PlayStation 5 Console Exclusive for 12 Months]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-playstation-5-console-exclusive-for-12-months</link>
            <guid>1383271</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Release date set for PS5 and PC.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phantom-blade-zero"><u>Phantom Blade Zero</u></a> is a PlayStation 5 console exclusive for 12 months.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">S-GAME Studio's Wuxia action RPG launches on September 9, 2026 across PS5 and PC. Much like other initially PS5 console-exclusive games, such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-2-remake"><u>Silent Hill 2 Remake</u></a>, Phantom Blade Zero won't be available on "other consoles until at least 12 months after release date." This means Xbox Series X and S or Nintendo Switch 2 versions will have to wait until at least September 2027, if they are in indeed in S-GAME Studio's plans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">PS5 console exclusivity comes from the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q89X4nOzxGw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>teaser video</u></a> added to the official PlayStation YouTube channel, which has a familiar blue notice at the end (thanks, <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/phantom-blade-zero-console-exclusive-ps5-12-months" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MP1st</a>).</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/15/screenshot-2025-12-15-at-10-23-22-1765794856738.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Phantom Blade Zero won't appear on non-PS5 consoles until 12 months after launch.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Phantom Blade Zero follows Soul, an assassin framed for a murder trying to uncover the truth of what happened. Its release date was announced at The Game Awards alongside the launch of a new trailer, below, which has generated a great deal of excitement. Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">We've seen Phantom Blade a number of times since its original announcement, both in the form of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pc-and-ps5-action-rpg-phantom-blade-zero-gets-slick-trailer-but-still-no-release-date">trailers</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-plays-more-like-ninja-gaiden-than-dark-souls">hands-on previews</a>. In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-delightfully-punishing-action-rpg">most recent look at Phantom Blade Zero this past October</a>, we found the game to be delightfully difficult, with our previewer saying: "It never felt cheap; it just demanded more from me. In just over an hour of play, I was easily ten times the player I was when I started. It’s a feeling of achievement that is reserved for the very best action games on the planet. If the rest is anything like what I played at TGS, I feel like there’s a real chance that Phantom Blade 0 might be one of those games."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-playstation-5-console-exclusive-for-12-months]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Version of Indie Horror Hit Phasmophobia Confirmed for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-version-of-indie-horror-hit-phasmophobia-confirmed-for-2026</link>
            <guid>1383265</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Indie hit ghostbusting game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phasmophobia">Phasmophobia</a> is coming to Nintendo Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Developer Kinetic Games used The Game Awards to announce a 2026 release window for Phasmophobia on Switch 2 without offering a firm release date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On Switch 2, up to four players can team up to conduct paranormal investigations across 14 terrifying maps and yes, Switch 2 players will be able to join pals on other platforms thanks to crossplay. The five-year-old game is also due to finally exit early access next year, too.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We’re over the moon to reveal that Phasmophobia is coming to Nintendo Switch 2. It’s something both our community and all of us at Kinetic Games have wanted for a long time, so we’re really happy this long-kept secret is finally out there," said Kinetic Games CEO and director, Daniel Knight. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"With 1.0 on track for 2026, it’s an exciting time to have new players get to experience the game. We're so glad that Switch 2 players will be able to join us for everything that’s coming, as well as jump into the wealth of content we’ve added throughout 2025."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It has indeed been a big year for Phasmo fans, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/phasmophobia-official-grafton-farmhouse-rework-trailer"><u>map reworks</u></a> and the release of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-everything-we-know-so-far-about-phasmophobias-terrifying-new-map-nells-diner"><u>all-new location, Nell's Diner</u></a>. We also found out Phasmophobia <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horror-hit-phasmophobia-the-next-game-to-get-a-hollywood-movie-adaptation-from-blumhouse"><u>is getting the Hollywood treatment in July</u></a>. Horror specialist <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/producer/blumhouse-productions"><u>Blumhouse</u></a> — the credits of which include <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/five-nights-at-freddys"><u>Five Nights at Freddy's,</u></a> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/the-conjuring"><u>The Conjuring</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/m3gan"><u>M3gan</u></a> — has partnered with the UK developer to create a feature film adaptation. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Phasmophobia Grafton Farmhouse Map Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the moment, nothing else is known, so we're not yet sure who'll be writing or directing it, let alone starring in the movie, but in an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/phasmophobia-the-big-interview-with-kinetic-games-as-revamp-for-fan-favorite-grafton-farmhouse-map-goes-live"><u>interview with IGN</u></a>, we asked art director Corey J. Dixon for his thoughts on how horror production company Blumhouse will translate Phasmophobia's genre-defining gameplay to the big screen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We've got a really good partnership with Blumhouse. It's brilliant," Dixon said at the time. "It will be a Phasmophobia film, it won't just be a ghost hunting film — we're going to make sure it's a film that fans want to watch, and we're going to work with them really closely."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-version-of-indie-horror-hit-phasmophobia-confirmed-for-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Dragon Quest I & II HD-2D Remake, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-december-14-2025</link>
            <guid>1383088</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We've rounded up the best deals for Sunday, December 14, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save $20 Off Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</h2><div catalogid="6283ceb2-e56b-4339-b983-32e22e470c4a" id="233626"><div id="233626" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>DRAGON QUEST I &amp; II HD-2D Remake (NSW)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the most anticipated RPGs of 2025, Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake, is down to $39.99 this weekend. This remake transforms the original two Dragon Quest games into gorgeous experiences with numerous updates and tweaks to modernize the experience. The Nintendo Switch physical copy contains the game on the cartridge, so Switch 2 owners can rest assured about any Key-Card concerns.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">PS5 Pro for $648.99</h2></div><div catalogid="6283ceb2-e56b-4339-b983-32e22e470c4a" id="233625"><div id="233625" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>PlayStation 5 Pro Console</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">PS5 Pro is on sale this weekend for $648.99, saving you just over $100 off Sony's most powerful console. Even if you already own a PS5, the PS5 Pro can still be a solid upgrade, providing enhanced performance and frame rates for numerous games. Newcomers to the PlayStation ecosystem can expect the best PS5 has to offer with this one.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 for $35</h2></div><div id="233627" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6283ceb2-e56b-4339-b983-32e22e470c4a"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6283ceb2-e56b-4339-b983-32e22e470c4a" id="233628"><div id="233628" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - Cross-Gen Bundle - Xbox Series X and Xbox One</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 7 is the latest Call of Duty, with the game releasing just a few weeks ago. Despite this, it's already on sale at Amazon for half-off, which may be a record for the fastest CoD to hit this price point. If you skipped out on the game at launch, this is a great deal for $35. Black Ops 7 contains a large amount of content, including a new Zombies mode.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">ASUS ROG Xbox Ally for $489.99</h2></div><div catalogid="8e5067fe-4808-4588-9d90-1c4689f9836b" id="233408"><div id="233408" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>ASUS ROG Xbox Ally</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has the Asus ROG Xbox Ally on sale for $489.99, which is even lower than Black Friday! You can save $110 on this portable PC equipped with everything you need to play or stream your Xbox games.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds for $37.99</h2></div><div catalogid="6283ceb2-e56b-4339-b983-32e22e470c4a" id="233624"><div id="233624" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds Amazon Exclusive Edition - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The fan-favorite Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is on sale for $37.99 right now following its nomination at The Game Awards. CrossWorlds pits together many iconic characters in the Sonic franchise, in addition to characters outside of it like Hatsune Miku, SpongeBob, and even Joker from Persona 5. If you're in the mood for a new racing game, look no further than CrossWorlds this weekend.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Star Wars Outlaws for $29.99</h2></div><div catalogid="8e5067fe-4808-4588-9d90-1c4689f9836b" id="233403"><div id="233403" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Star Wars Outlaws - Gold Edition, Nintendo Switch 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 version of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">Star Wars Outlaws</a> is on sale this weekend for $29.99, which is a steal for one of the hybrid system's best third-party games. This version of Star Wars Outlaws is the Gold Edition, packing in all the DLC and updates that released.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Cronos: The New Dawn for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="8e5067fe-4808-4588-9d90-1c4689f9836b" id="233405"><div id="233405" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Cronos: The New Dawn - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">2025 had numerous horror games released, and if you missed out on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/cronos-the-new-dawn">Cronos: The New Dawn</a>, now is the time to buy, as Amazon has the game discounted $20. Cronos puts you in the shoes of The Traveler, who is sent back in time in areas where a virus has ravaged humanity. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Ghost of Yotei Limited Edition DualSense for $64.99</h2></div><div catalogid="8e5067fe-4808-4588-9d90-1c4689f9836b" id="233406"><div id="233406" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>DualSense Wireless Controller for PlayStation 5 - Ghost of Yōtei Limited Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Target has the exclusive Ghost of Yotei Limited Edition DualSense on sale for $64.99 this weekend. Normally $84.99, this controller sports a unique design, featuring a gold brushed design all over the front. In my opinion, this is one of the best limited edition DualSense controllers PlayStation has released, only behind the 30th Anniversary and Astro Bot models.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Astro Bot for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="a2199802-8325-4135-9414-442cfc7366d7" id="231329"><div id="231329" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Astro Bot - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Astro Bot is a must-own game for any PlayStation 5 owner for many reasons. The fun platforming adventure is a trip across PlayStation's iconic history of games, with cameos from many of the beloved characters that shaped each console generation. Today, you can score Astro Bot for $39.99 at Amazon, which is the lowest we've seen it so far.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Super Mario Odyssey for $39.99</h2></div><div catalogid="8e5067fe-4808-4588-9d90-1c4689f9836b" id="233409"><div id="233409" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Super Mario Odyssey - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Super Mario Odyssey is one of the best Nintendo Switch games, and if you missed out on Nintendo's Black Friday sale, you can still score a discounted copy of Odyssey this weekend. Join Mario and his new friend Cappy on an adventure across Kingdoms to stop Bowser's plans to marry Princess Peach.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 14, 2025 8:56 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-december-14-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>