<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:11:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Top Deals For Today: Best Places to Buy Pokémon Cards and Magic Boosters Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-4-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/my-top-deals-for-today-best-places-to-buy-pok%C3%A9mon-cards-and-magic-boosters-right-now.1261413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">TCGplayer is absolutely crushing it today. I’ve been watching prices across Amazon and the secondary market as usual, and it’s not even close. The latest Pokémon products like <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObZOj?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">White Flare Binder box</a>, while older set products like <a href="https://zdcs.link/9l30GE?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Destined Rivals Tripple Blister is $8 cheaper</a>, especially the <a href="https://zdcs.link/91jddk?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Elite Trainer Box running about $3 cheaper</a> than <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-1-2025?_cache=pass">Amazon’s lowest price last week. </a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-1-2025">Scarlet and Violet 151 is still shifting fast</a> too. Charizard ex, Blastoise ex, and Venusaur ex are climbing, but the Illustration Rares of Charmander, Bulbasaur, and Squirtle have dipped, which makes this a solid time to grab those before prices settle again. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over in Magic, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJmnY?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Fallout Commander Deck bundle is cheaper at TCGplayer</a> by around $4, with the other commander decks saving around $10 per deck, which really adds up if you’re <a href="https://zdcs.link/QP8NZy?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">grabbing the full set</a>.</p><p id="best-deals-for-today"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title=" Best Deals For Today">TL;DR: My Best Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of trading cards, there’s some fun stuff dropping today. I’ve already preordered the Vault Boy Fallout Pop Vinyl, but I’m tempted to pick up the rest of the lineup now that they’re all available for $14.99. If you’re into mini PCs, there are a couple of solid builds going for under $175. They’re perfect for work-from-home setups, light gaming, or just keeping your desk tidy.</p><p id="pokmon-tcg-price-check"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG Price Check">Pokémon TCG Price Check</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whilst there's a couple of savings on Amazon today, TCGplayer is knocking big box retailers out of the water. The White Flare binder box is a couple of dollars cheaper on Amazon, but looking at older sets like Destined Rivals show a clear gap in market value and the notorious Amazon mark ups of 2025. Destined Rivals Elite Trainer Box is currently sat at <a href="https://zdcs.link/91jddk?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$85 on TCGplayer</a>, for example, which is cheaper than the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-1-2025?_cache=pass">Amazon sale price last week of £88</a>.</p><p id="pokmon-tcg-crashers-and-climbers"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG Crashers and Climbers">Pokémon TCG Crashers and Climbers</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Scarlet and Violet 151 card prices continue to shift, with <a href="https://zdcs.link/aAgkqp?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charizard ex</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/a036gm?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Blastoise ex</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QWYW1n?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Venusaur ex SIRs</a> climbing steadily thanks to standout artwork, competitive playability, and high collector demand. Charizard has jumped to $210, Blastoise is up 28% to $84.99, and Venusaur is up 27% to $69.99. <a href="https://zdcs.link/9l3GPE?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Zapdos ex</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QdbVn2?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Alakazam ex</a> are also on the rise, with Alakazam seeing the biggest gain of 35% to $44.98. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the other hand, prices for Kanto starter Illustration Rares like <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gbpMy?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charmander</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9YWmNj?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Bulbasaur</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/av40e2?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Squirtle</a> have dipped as more product floods the market. Charmander is down 14% to $44.44, Bulbasaur is down 18% to $32.20, and middle evolutions like <a href="https://zdcs.link/985m2w?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charmeleon</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QP85YO?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wartortle</a> are following the same trend. While the final evolutions remain the most sought-after, now is a good time to pick up the earlier stages at a more reasonable price.</p><p id="magic-the-gathering-deals"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Magic: The Gathering Deals">Magic: The Gathering Deals</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Once again it's TCGplayer and the secondary market values saving MTG players and collectors a small fortune over Amazon. Even sale pricing of the<a href="https://zdcs.link/aNJmnY?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> Fallout Commander Deck - Science! is $4 cheaper</a>, with my favorite deal in this lineup being for the four pack bundle of Fallout Commander Decks. Amazon works out at $47.07 per deck, with <a href="https://zdcs.link/QP8NZy?object_uuid=2b716754-e160-45db-8a8f-491877303a3d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGplayer massively undercutting here at $41.56.</a> That's well over $10 saving per deck, with even more savings compared to Amazons single pricing overall.</p><p id="fallout-funko-pop-preorders"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Fallout Funko Pop Preorders">Fallout Funko Pop Preorders</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dropping throughout December 2025, these Fallout Pop Vinyls focused on the Fallout TV series should drop around the same time as Season Two. There's also chances to get a random rare variant, which is about as much Funko hype as I can handle. I've preordered Vault Boy already, but I might get the whole lineup before preorders run dry.</p><p id="mini-pc-deals"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Mini PC Deals">Mini PC Deals</h2></p><div><div id="226348" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Intel Twin Lake N150(Turbo 3.6GHz), 16GB RAM, 1TB M.2 SSD</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>ACEMAGIC Vista Mini V1 Mini PC</h3></p></div><div id="226349" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div><p>Intel Twin Lake N150 (4 Cores, up to 3.6GHz), 16GB DDR4 RAM, 512GB M.2 SSD</p></div><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>KAMRUI Mini PC</h3></p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Mini PCs are great for a work from home setup, a bit of light gaming or just saving some space. Both of these models have decent specs whilst being good enough to run Minecraft and your day-to-day productivity apps. Plus they're dirt cheap, so there's nothing to loose.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 4, 2025 11:47 am</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-4-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tekken 8 Reveals Armor King Gameplay and Its First Original DLC Character: Miary Zo From Madagascar]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tekken-8-reveals-armor-king-gameplay-and-its-first-original-dlc-character-miary-zo-from-madagascar</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tekken-8-reveals-armor-king-gameplay-and-its-first-original-dlc-character-miary-zo-from-madagascar.1261407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bandai Namco has revealed a first look at the upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tekken-8">Tekken 8</a> DLC character Armor King, and announced a brand new character.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the Evo fighting game tournament, fans got an in-depth look at Armor King, the next DLC character coming to the game, in an all-new gameplay trailer, below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Armor King hits Tekken 8 on October 16, with 72-hour early access for Season 2 Character &amp; Stage Pass and Season 2 Character Pass holders beginning 13 October.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The trailer also revealed the final DLC character for Season 2, introducing new fighter Miary Zo. Hailing from Madagascar, Miary Zo joins the roster in Winter 2025 as the first original DLC character for Tekken 8. The Winter DLC also includes a new stage set in Miary Zo’s home country.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb on Armor King:</p><blockquote>Thirsting for revenge, the jet black villain Armor King returns to the Tekken ring. The “Dark Supernova” now sports a fiery mane, and as showcased in the trailer, brings back his arsenal of explosive moves and devastating combos. His addition to Tekken 8 grows the game’s roster to 39 fighters.</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/04/tekken-1754305712243.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Miary Zo is the first original DLC character coming to Tekken 8.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And here’s the blurb on Miary Zo:</p><blockquote>Even as they prepare to play Armor King, fans can already look forward to the next fighter, Miary Zo — the first original DLC character coming to Tekken 8. Miary Zo’s brief reveal included glimpses of a new level coming with her as part of the Winter DLC. The trailer showcased environments set in her historically rich homeland of Madagascar, featuring the island nation’s recognizable architecture and iconic baobab trees basked in the glow of a setting sun. Bandai Namco will reveal more information about Winter DLC content in the coming months.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/tekken-8-reveals-armor-king-gameplay-and-its-first-original-dlc-character-miary-zo-from-madagascar]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls PS5 Closed Beta Ends 2 Days Before 2XKO's Closed Beta Starts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-tkon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-ends-2-days-before-2xkos-closed-beta-starts</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-t%C5%8Dkon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-ends-2-days-before-2xkos-closed-beta-starts.1261401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hotly anticipated fighting game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls">Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls</a> launches a PlayStation 5-exclusive closed beta September 5-7, which ends just two days before the closed beta for Riot’s upcoming League of Legends fighting game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/2xko">2XKO</a> starts on PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Developed by Guilty Gear maker Arc System Works, Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls is a 4v4 Marvel fighting game published by Sony on PS5 and PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store at some point in 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It includes iconic Marvel heroes and villains such as Captain America, Iron Man, Spider-Man, Doctor Doom, Storm, Ms. Marvel, Star-Lord, and Ghost Rider (Robbie Reyes) – each with Arc’s unique twist on their character designs and gameplay styles.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls closed beta includes six playable characters, online matches, spectator mode, a training tutorial, and more. You can register on PlayStation’s website.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls closed beta playable characters:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Captain America</li><li>Iron Man</li><li>Ms. Marvel</li><li>Star-Lord</li><li>Storm</li><li>Doctor Doom</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">If you receive an “Invalid Link” error when signing up for the Closed Beta, it is because you’ve previously signed up for the PlayStation Beta program and you’re all set for Closed Beta registration.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s looking like a stacked time for fighting games, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-can-quickhack-like-shes-in-cyberpunk-2077-heres-how-it-looks-in-gameplay">existing entries releasing further DLC</a> and a number of upcoming newcomers set to go up against each other.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls, which was announced at the State of Play in June. Riot has 2XKO, and Microsoft is leading the charge with Invincible VS (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-omni-man-is-a-playable-character-in-invincible-vs-heres-our-first-look-at-gameplay-and-some-info-on-how-he-works">which just announced Omni-Man</a>), although the latter is due out multiplatform. Sega has a new Virtua Fighter game in development too (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes">and very good it looks indeed</a>).</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-tkon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-ends-2-days-before-2xkos-closed-beta-starts]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Delay Rumors, Nintendo Recommits to 2025 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch.1261296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As fans continue to wait for a final release date, Nintendo has reaffirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> is still on track for 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After a long and bumpy development that has stretched much of the past decade, fans are eager to hear when the highly-anticipated Switch and Switch 2 exclusive will arrive. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But as the months roll on and gossip spreads of the game needing more time than initially expected, Nintendo has now re-stated that Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will still launch before the end of the calendar year.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, in a news <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post</a> advertising the company's upcoming preseence at Fan Expo Canada, Nintendo has stated that Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will be playable there ahead of it becoming "available later in 2025."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's unclear if this hands-on opportunity is a new demo, or the one made available to members of the public who attended the Switch 2's pre-launch tour. Still, it's a positive sign the game and its launch are in Nintendo's sights — and still coming at some point within the next five months.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The statement comes amid online discussion surrounding the fact that Nintendo has not released new details on the game or fresh footage of it for a little while. The last new Metroid Prime 4: Beyond trailer uploaded to the Nintendo of America YouTube account comes from the company's Nintendo Switch 2 full console reveal back in March. Since then, the biggest news about the game's launch has been the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/confused-nintendo-fans-spot-giant-metroid-prime-4-beyond-advert-stating-that-the-game-is-out-now-sparking-hopes-of-an-imminent-release">advertising slip-up that saw the game promoted as being "Out Now" in a billboard on the London Underground</a>. If only!</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 - Metroid Prime 4 Beyond</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the same time, Nintendo leaker <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1mfxizw/kiwitalkz_gives_one_last_update_on_what_he_knows/?share_id=riXz3o7YuwdEAKqEAIBlG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KiwiTalkz</a> had prompted concern among fans that the game was originally due sooner, closer to the Switch 2's launch, but has been held up due to last-minute snags. This, just days after Nintendo's recent third-party focused Partner Direct (where Metroid Prime 4 would not have featured anyway) has contributed to a sense of unease among fans over the game's arrival.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It has been a long wait for a new 3D Metroid game, lengthened further by Nintendo taking the decision to reboot the project's development back in 2019 after an earlier incarnation being made by Bandai Namco did not meet Nintendo's expectations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo's current Switch 2 release schedule for the remainder of 2025 includes Drag x Drive (August 14), Kirby and the Forgotten Land — Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star-Crossed World (August 28) and Pokémon Legends Z-A (October 16), plus Kirby Air Riders and Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, which do not have set dates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtua Fighter 6's Combat Gameplay First Look Has Old Martial Arts Movie Vibes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes.1261293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Virtua Fighter 6 has its first proper gameplay video, and the fighting game continues to look amazing on the graphics front.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega has only released <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-new-look-wolf-hawkfield-has-more-than-a-whiff-of-ganondorf-about-him-and-impressive-muscle-jiggle-physics">reveal videos</a> and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-fans-hope-the-new-game-comes-close-to-matching-this-incredible-in-engine-concept-video">tech demo</a> for its upcoming 'New Virtual Fighter Project,' so this new trailer, revealed during the EVO fighting game tournament, shows us just how impressive the visuals and animations are shaping up to be in actual gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We see series stalwart Akira, wearing an outfit fans of Donnie Yen’s Ip Man film series will know well, going up against new character Stella on the Training Stage.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢</p><p>New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project</p><p>Combat Gameplay First Look<br>-Training Stage</p><p>◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢</p><p>Check out the latest <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewVF?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#NewVF</a> trailer that just premiered at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EVO2025?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#EVO2025</a>.<br>More info coming at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TGS2025?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#TGS2025</a>.</p><p>Follow the official global VF account… <a href="https://t.co/jPzmsSUKwt" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/jPzmsSUKwt</a></p></div>— VIRTUA FIGHTER (@VF_SEGA) <a href="https://twitter.com/VF_SEGA/status/1952147917000823025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">In truth, the gameplay here doesn’t look that far off the eye-catching tech demo that was shown at Nvidia’s CES event in January. At the time, Sega released what it called a “pre-development concept video” for Virtua Fighter 6, but made clear it did not reflect how the upcoming fighting game would look and play when it eventually comes out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The video, below, shown during Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen Huang’s keynote speech at CES 2025, features incredibly realistic and fluid animations for a fighting game. We see an Akira mirror match with the kind of combat usually reserved for a martial arts movie.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But this new video, which Sega is calling a ‘Combat Gameplay First Look,’ shows buttery smooth animations and cool transitions, with a slow-motion effect for whiffs that makes Virtua Fighter look much more realistic than its fighting game rivals.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No infinite juggles, no crazy magic, no stupid invincible ex, no stupid rage art, no spamming rage drive, focus attacks etc. Just pure fighting, I like that,” commented one fan on YouTube.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“VF6 is feeling like those old martial arts films,” added another. “No drive impact, no heat system, no rev system, just straight up hands. I cannot wait for this to drop.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We do see some sort of debilitating effect in the gameplay, where Stella appears to suffer damage to her face, but overall it’s a very clean, back to basics approach for video game fighting.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/04/screenshot-2025-08-04-094427-1754297084498.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Stella emerged victorious over Akira in the first Virtua Fighter 6 gameplay video.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Virtua Fighter 6 is in development at Yakuza / Like a Dragon studio Ryo Ga Gotoku and is without a release window or target platforms. Virtua Fighter hasn’t seen a mainline release in years, leaving mini-game appearances in Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio’s Yakuza games and the 2021 release of Virtua Fighter 5 Ultimate Showdown to tide fans over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Expect more on the battle system at the Tokyo Game Show in September. There is no release date yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>