<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:32:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 and PC Single-Player Action Game Lost Soul Aside Delayed 3 Months to Add Polish]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish.1177416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-delayed-3-months-to-add-polish<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Fall 2025 looking pretty busy indeed.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lost-soul-aside">Lost Soul Aside</a> is delayed three months, from May 30 to August 29, 2025, its developer has announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After roughly a decade in development, the PC and PlayStation 5 single-player action game was finally scheduled for llaunch next month, but a statement from developer Ultizero Games revealed the delay to late September to add polish.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We are truly grateful for the positive response we've received from players all over the world since we announced Lost Soul Aside," Ultizero Games said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We remain committed to delivering a high-quality game experience. To match the standards Ultizero Games have set for ourselves, we are going to take some additional time to polish the game. Lost Soul Aside will now release on August 29, 2025. We want to express our heartfelt thanks to our fans waiting for the launch."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Originally the passion project of solo developer Yang Bing, Lost Soul Aside has grown to become a major Sony-published title under the company's China Hero Project, with Bing now the founder and CEO of Shanghai-based studio Ultizero Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-and-pc-single-player-action-game-lost-soul-aside-the-big-interview">IGN recently had the opportunity to sit down with Yang Bing to discuss the long road to launch</a>. So many years of development went into Lost Soul Aside, escalating from a solo creator's vision to a trailer reveal at Sony's State of Play broadcast. Through it all the hype has built up, with some calling Lost Soul Aside an exciting mix of Final Fantasy characters and Devil May Cry combat — even from the moment Yang Bing's initial reveal video went viral in 2016.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The main character Kesar wields a shape-shifting weapon you can swap between, which changes your playstyle, and you have a dragon-like companion named Arena who can summon abilities to support Kesar.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like its inspirations, Lost Soul Aside emphasizes aerial dodging, precision timing, combos, and countering along with large-scale boss fights. The game blends its sci-fi premise with a variety of contemporary aesthetics that fit into a campaign that takes you across multiple dimensions. Although it's tough to glean where the story is going based on its trailers, Bing describes Kesar's journey as one of "redemption and discovery."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Actor’s Dramatic Pokemon Save Data Loss Goes Viral, Triggering Traumatic Memories and Sympathy From Fellow Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/japanese-actors-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/japanese-actor%E2%80%99s-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers.1177413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/japanese-actors-dramatic-pokemon-save-data-loss-goes-viral-triggering-traumatic-memories-and-sympathy-from-fellow-gamers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Even if save data disappears, the memories remain!"</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Regardless of age, every gamer remembers when they suffered their first save game data loss, be it a corrupted console/PC harddrive, or a PS1 memory card suddenly showing blue blocks of damaged data. Japanese gamers were reminded of these painful feelings on April 30, when actor Shinya Okada’s dramatic reaction to losing all his original Pokemon Red save data from 1996 was captured in a YouTube video. The actor’s stunned facial expressions and fans’ outpourings of sympathy even led the incident to be featured on <a href="https://www.crank-in.net/news/165828/1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Japanese entertainment news outlets</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A familiar face in Japanese TV dramas, 77-year-old actor Shinya Owada is also a huge Pokemon fan, regularly playing through various games from the series on his YouTube Channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@shinyaohwada" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>“Shinya Owada’s Hideout.”</u></a> Often accompanied by his trusty Squirtle plushie (that he <a href="https://x.com/oowadashinya/status/1887780979852673211" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>recently took on an adorable trip to the aquarium</u></a>), Owada’s warm-hearted enthusiasm for the games, plus his dramatic narration of the dialogue has earned the veteran gamer over 56.4K subscribers.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/30/japan-1746009732056.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Japanese actor Shinya Owada lost his Pokemon Red save data. Image credit Shinya Owada / YouTube.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In his latest “Let’s Play” <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJH3njE-ezY" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>video</u></a> posted on April 29, Owada’s cheerful enthusiasm to continue his Pokemon Red adventure gradually morphs into disbelief as the game asks him if he wants to start from the beginning. Owada’s startled reactions of “wait? what?” as he realizes that all the hours he has put into capturing and training Pokemon have vanished are palpable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Owada also <a href="https://x.com/oowadashinya/status/1917172028580434361" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>took to X </u></a>to share his feelings on the matter in a post that quickly amassed 4.4 million views and over 200 comments: “My Pokemon Red Game Boy cartridge save data has vanished. In my remaining lifetime, I will find another adventure to embark on.” Although he had previously streamed Pokemon Red, he announced that he plans to stop playing the game for now.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="ja" dir="ltr">【ご報告】<br>ゲームボーイソフト<br>ポケットモンスター 赤🟥の<br>冒険のセーブデータが<br>消えてしまいました^_^<br>人生の限られた時間の中で<br>また新しい旅を探します<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%83%9D%E3%82%B1%E3%83%A2%E3%83%B3?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ポケモン</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%82%B2%E3%83%BC%E3%83%A0?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ゲーム</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%81%AC%E3%81%84%E6%B4%BB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ぬい活</a> <a href="https://t.co/uofsbpsYDR" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/uofsbpsYDR</a></p>— 大和田 伸也 (@oowadashinya) <a href="https://twitter.com/oowadashinya/status/1917172028580434361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 29, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Owada’s unfortunate data loss experience attracted many sympathetic comments, with people reminiscing about the sadness they felt when they lost valuable saves when they were children, often on cartridge-based systems like the Game Boy and N64, or PS1 and PS2 memory cards. As many commenters suggested, it seems likely that the battery in Okada’s Game Boy cartridge of Pokemon Red finally died, thus deleting his precious save data. Without the benefits of cloud-based storage back-ups, it was quite easy to lose all the data on your cartridge or memory card if the contacts wore out, you took it out of the console too quickly, or even looked at the console in the wrong way (this writer swears that this is how she lost her 90 hours of Final Fantasy IX gameplay back in 2001...).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Losing save data is also losing life,” stated one commenter on Owada’s YouTube video, drawing stark attention to the hours of effort and grinding that vanish into oblivion when you lose a save (something that all Simmers, Citybuilders, and RPG fans can attest to). Others were more philosophical: “even if save data disappears, the memories remain!” Comments also showed fans’ fondness for Owada, with one user adding: "If this happened to any other video game streamer, I would laugh at how ridiculous it is, but with Mr. Owada, it's a different story."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If all this has strangely inspired you to go back to Game Boy-era Pokemon games, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-version/walkthrough"><u>IGN’s comprehensive walkthroughs</u></a> for Pokemon Red, Blue and Yellow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit Shinya Owada / YouTube.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals For Today: Pokémon TCG ETBs Are Back In Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-30-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-etbs-are-back-in-stock.1177410/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-30-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/score-60-off-a-sams-club-membership-today-only-and-secure-sold-out-pokemon-tcg-sets-at-a-discount">Pokémon TCG</a> fans are getting a strong lineup today, with multiple <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-surging-sparks-booster-bundle-shining-fates-amazon-restock-latest">Elite Trainer Boxes</a> on sale. That includes an early discount on the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-journey-together-preview">Journey Together</a> set, which is rare this soon after release. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Regardless of being in it for the promos or looking to crack packs, this is a great time to grab sealed product, not ot mention singles dropping in value across the board. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's also a deal on Iono’s Bellibolt Premium Collection, and the Iron Leaves ETB from the Temporal Forces expansion is holding steady at a fair price.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside the world of cards, <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5YZbd?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">AirPods Pro 2</a> are available for $169, a significant drop from their usual $249 price tag. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you just picked up a Switch 2, there’s also a <a href="https://zdcs.link/QORvDY?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">quick-install screen protector available</a> for under $10. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Humble has a 17-title <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbxd1G?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">XCOM bundle starting at just $10</a>, and the <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPpqym?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IGN Store</a> is offering a limited <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-review">Oblivion</a> collectible ingot for pre-order, perfect for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-online">Elder Scrolls</a> fans and collectors.</p><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violetjourne"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Journe">Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219777"><div id="219777" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/98LMB8?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Journey Together Elite Trainer Box</a> is seeing a notable early discount at $64.95, down from its usual $97.99 price. With 9 booster packs, a full-art promo card featuring N’s Zorua, and 65 matching card sleeves, this is a solid pickup for collectors or competitive players looking to expand their deck.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re also getting Energy cards, a player’s guide, dice, and other accessories packed in a themed storage box. With singles from this set trending down in price, picking up sealed product offers better value if you're after specific chase cards.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Journey Together Rare Cards</h2></p><p id="pokmon-tcg-ionos-bellibolt-ex-pr"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title=" Pokémon TCG: Iono’s Bellibolt ex Pr">Iono’s Bellibolt ex Premium Collection</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219778"><div id="219778" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> Pokémon TCG: Iono’s Bellibolt ex Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/zJ2mdk?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">This Premium Collection</a> features Iono’s Bellibolt ex as a full-art foil promo, plus a foil Iono’s Tadbulb card and six booster packs. At $53.23, it’s a modest discount off the typical $55.88 price (for Amazon).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’ll also get standees, a photo sticker, and a backdrop display themed around Iono and Bellibolt. With several playable cards in this set seeing markdowns on the singles market, this box is a good option for collectors or those hoping to pull value.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Journey Together IRs</h2></p><p id="the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remast"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remast">Oblivion Gates</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219779"><div id="219779" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered - The Oblivion Gates by Ingot</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPpqym?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">limited edition Oblivion Gates statue</a> from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">Elder Scrolls IV</a> is available now for pre-order at $39.99. It’s officially licensed, limited to 5,000 units, and includes a display stand in a collectible box.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The detailed design captures the fiery gates seen in-game and measures 110 x 76mm. Scheduled to ship in October 2025, this is a good pick for fans of the series looking to add a unique item to their collection.</p></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-and-violet-tem"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet: Tem">Temporal Forces: Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219782"><div id="219782" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet and Violet: Temporal Forces: Elite Trainer Box: Iron Leaves</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9wXDeD?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Temporal Forces Elite Trainer Box</a> featuring Iron Leaves is holding at $55.42. It includes booster packs, Energy cards, themed sleeves, and tools for competitive play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This expansion brings back ACE SPEC cards and features both Ancient and Future Pokémon ex, including Walking Wake ex and Raging Bolt ex. With singles from this set also seeing price drops, sealed boxes may offer better pull value for players chasing newer cards.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Temporal Forces Chase Cards</h2></p><p id="xcom-complete-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="XCOM complete Bundle">XCOM Complete Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219784"><div id="219784" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>XCOM complete Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Humble is offering a full <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qbxd1G?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">XCOM franchise bundle starting at just $10</a>. That unlocks 17 titles, including XCOM 2, Enemy Unknown, Chimera Squad, and multiple DLCs with a combined value of $269.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is a rare chance to pick up nearly the entire series in one package, and part of your purchase supports the Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson’s Research. Whether you're new to the franchise or filling gaps in your library, it's worth a look.</p></div><p id="auto-alignment-screen-protector-for"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Auto-Alignment Screen Protector for ">Screen Protector for Nintendo Switch 2</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219785"><div id="219785" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Auto-Alignment Screen Protector for Nintendo Switch 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This <a href="https://zdcs.link/QORvDY?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">2-pack screen protector for the Switch 2</a> uses amFilm’s latest auto-alignment system for quick, bubble-free installation in under 30 seconds. It’s currently down to $9.99, a 23% savings off its usual $12.99 list price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re getting tempered glass rated at 9H hardness, plus anti-fingerprint coating and responsive touch sensitivity. A smart add-on for anyone who's preordered Switch 2 and wants protection without hassle.</p></div><p id="apple-airpods-pro-2"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title=" Apple AirPods Pro 2 "> Apple AirPods Pro 2 </h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219786"><div id="219786" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> Apple AirPods Pro 2 </h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/airpods-pro-2nd-generation">Apple’s AirPods Pro 2</a> with the updated USB-C case are <a href="https://zdcs.link/a5YZbd?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">available for $169</a>, which is $80 off the standard price of $249. That’s one of the lowest prices we’ve seen this month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These wireless earbuds offer active noise cancellation, adaptive audio modes, personalized spatial audio, and a secure fit with multiple tip sizes. They’re also IP54-rated for water and dust resistance, making them a reliable option for both everyday listening and workouts.</p></div><p id="id-software-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="id Software Bundle">id &amp; Friends Humble Game Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219655"><div id="219655" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>id &amp; Friends Humble Game Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I think calling this a bundle is almost underselling it. You are getting <a href="https://zdcs.link/a0nyre?object_uuid=de449b4c-29aa-4403-98aa-d40193e96ad8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">DOOM, Wolfenstein, DOOM Eternal, and a coupon toward DOOM: The Dark Ages</a>, just to name a few. It is a lot of chaos and a lot of catharsis for not a lot of money. Steam ratings are strong across the board if you care about that kind of thing, but honestly, DOOM 1993 still sells itself.</p></div><p id="surging-sparks-booster-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Surging Sparks Booster Box">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Surging Sparks Booster Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219656"><div id="219656" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet - Surging Sparks Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Six booster packs in one bundle sounds good on paper, but in my opinion, the smarter move right now is to look at singles. Prices for this set are dropping fast, and if you are chasing specific cards, buying them outright is probably cheaper and less soul crushing than another box full of commons. </p></div><p id="pokmon-tcg-scarlet-violettwilig"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilig">Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilight Masquerade Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219744"><div id="219744" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Scarlet &amp; Violet—Twilight Masquerade Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Greninja ex SIR, that is all. In all seriousness, this is a brilliant set that's often overlooked. Whilst the price is a little over MSRP, it's worth getting just for the booster packs included. Plus the promo, sleeves and dice look great in this particular ETB. Following the trend, Twilight Masquerade single cards are also crashing in price, so make sure to check if you can just buy the cards you're after for less.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Twilight Masquerade Single Cards</h2></p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Surging Sparks Single Cards</h2></p><p id="shining-fates-collection"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Shining Fates Collection">Pokémon TCG: Shining Fates Collection Pikachu V Box</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219657"><div id="219657" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Shining Fates Collection Pikachu V Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">kachu gets a lot of oversized cardboard love in this box with a promo card, a giant version, and four Shining Fates booster packs. It is a decent pickup if you like opening packs, but single card prices are slipping hard right now. I think it makes more sense to hunt down the exact cards you want unless you are feeling reckless.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Shining Fates Single Cards</h2></p><p id="dark-brotherhood-medalion"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Dark Brotherhood Medalion">The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered Dark Brotherhood Medallion</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219658"><div id="219658" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Elder Scrolls IV Oblivion Remastered Dark Brotherhood Medallion</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">In my opinion, this is one of those collectibles that you either want immediately or not at all. It is an officially licensed Dark Brotherhood medallion, limited to 5000 pieces, finished in black and gold, and somehow still cheaper than most novelty keychains. Ships later this year, assuming you survive the wait</p></div><p id="paldean-fates-booster-bundle"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Paldean Fates Booster Bundle">Pokémon TCG Paldean Fates Booster Bundle</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219659"><div id="219659" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG Paldean Fates Booster Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Paldean Fates brings back shiny Pokémon in a big way, and this bundle gives you six booster packs to chase them. I want to be excited about it, but again, single card prices for Paldean Fates are not holding up well. If you just want a shiny Charizard ex SIR without the suspense, the singles market is sitting there quietly judging your pack opening addiction.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Paldean Fates Single Cards</h2></p><p id="azure-legends-tin"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Azure Legends Tin">Pokemon TCG: Azure Legends Tin - 5 Packs</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219660"><div id="219660" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokemon TCG: Azure Legends Tin - 5 Packs</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Includes 2 x Surging Sparks Booster Packs</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I like a good tin, especially one with five booster packs packed inside, but getting a random Kyogre, Xerneas, or Dialga promo card feels a little like gambling with slightly better odds. It is a solid pickup for the price if you do not mind leaving your promo fate to the RNG gods. If you are only after one specific chase card though outside of the included two Surging Sparks boosters, it might save your blood pressure to just buy it separately.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Surging Sparks Single Cards</h2></p><p id="lexar-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Lexar Sale">Lexar Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219661"><div id="219661" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lexar Sale</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Up to 54% off Micro SDXCs, Portable SSDs, M.2 SSDs, Sata III SSDs and RAM </p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Lexar is finally giving some breathing room on pricing with this Amazon sale, and the Armor 700 is a standout. You are getting 4TB of rugged storage with serious transfer speeds for about 100 dollars off the typical price. It is water resistant, dust resistant, and a lot more durable than whatever junk is sitting at the bottom of your backpack right now.</p></div><p id="pokmon-game-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Game Sale">Pokémon Game Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219557"><div id="219557" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon Legends: Arceus</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Click through for the full Woot gaming sale</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Woot is offering a solid spread of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/pokemon">Pokémon</a> games today, and I want at least three of them. Brilliant Diamond, Legends: Arceus, Let’s Go, Eevee!, and a few others are sitting between $39.99 and $44.99, which feels right for anyone catching up before Switch 2 changes the landscape again. In my opinion, it is a smart time to grab them while prices are behaving themselves. Everything here is fully playable now and will likely get performance bumps once Nintendo's next system arrives.</p></div><p id="msi-sale"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="MSI Sale">MSI Desktops &amp; Components Sale</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219558"><div id="219558" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>MSI Desktops &amp; Components Sale</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Click through for the full Woot gaming sale</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">MSI’s factory-reconditioned gaming desktops are quietly one of the best parts of today's sale. Machines like the AEGIS R 13NUE-448US are going for $1,129.99, and RTX 4060 GPUs are under $300. I want to be responsible, but this pricing makes it harder than it should be. If you have been thinking about rebuilding your setup, this is exactly the kind of deal you hope not to miss.</p></div><p id="samsung-512gb-microsdxc"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Samsung 512GB MicroSDXC">Samsung Pro Plus 512GB MicroSDXC + Reader</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219560"><div id="219560" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Samsung Pro Plus 512GB MicroSDXC + Reader</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/publisher/samsung">Samsung</a> PRO Plus 512GB microSD card with a USB reader for $29.99. I think it is a good fit if you are adding games to your Switch, Steam Deck, ROG Ally, or anything else still using microSD storage. It is fast enough for quick transfers, big enough for most libraries, and cheap enough that you do not have to think too hard about it. Just know it is not built for Switch 2, in case you're planning ahead.</p></div><p id="8bitdo-xbox-edition-keyboard"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="8BitDo Xbox Edition Keyboard">8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard (Xbox Edition)</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219562"><div id="219562" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard (Xbox Edition)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/8bitdo-retro-mechanical-keyboard-review">8BitDo Retro 87 Mechanical Keyboard</a> is down to $99.99 at Amazon. I think it is one of the best-looking keyboards out right now if you want something that works and does not scream “boring office equipment.” It has Kailh Jellyfish X switches, a top-mount design, fast response, and Xbox-inspired styling that actually looks good on a gaming desk. I probably do not need another keyboard. I am thinking about it anyway.</p></div><p id="8bitdo-mouse-xbox-edition"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="8BitDo Mouse Xbox Edition"> 8BitDo Retro R8 Mouse (Xbox Edition)</h2></p><div catalogid="85730312-bd7b-47fe-8925-a7f92b6aba21" id="219563"><div id="219563" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> 8BitDo Retro R8 Mouse (Xbox Edition)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon also has the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/8bitdo-retro-mechanical-keyboard-review">8BitDo Retro R8 Wireless Mouse</a> on sale for $58.68. It feels like the natural companion to the Retro 87 Keyboard, but it also stands fine on its own. It packs a PAW 3395 sensor, programmable buttons, a 4K polling rate, and a charging dock that doubles as a signal booster. I want one for a low-key gaming setup that does not look like it is held together with RGB lighting and prayer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 30, 2025 10:41 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titanfall Fans React to Extraction Shooter Cancelation — Is This the Final Nail in the Coffin for Titanfall 3 and the Franchise?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/titanfall-fans-react-to-extraction-shooter-cancelation-is-this-the-final-nail-in-the-coffin-for-titanfall-3-and-the-franchise</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/titanfall-fans-react-to-extraction-shooter-cancelation-%E2%80%94-is-this-the-final-nail-in-the-coffin-for-titanfall-3-and-the-franchise.1177305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/titanfall-fans-react-to-extraction-shooter-cancelation-is-this-the-final-nail-in-the-coffin-for-titanfall-3-and-the-franchise<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/titanfall"><u>Titanfall</u></a> fans are reeling from the news <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted"><u>EA has canceled another incubation project at Respawn Entertainment</u></a>, and simultaneously <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn"><u>laid off a number of individuals across its incubation, Apex Legends, Star Wars: Jedi, and EA Experience teams.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Bloomberg</u></a> reported the canceled game, codenamed R7, was an extraction shooter set in the Titanfall universe. And while that is not the Titanfall 3 sequel fans have been clamoring for, some are devastated that the fan-favorite <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/titanfall-2">Titanfall 2</a> is still without a sequel almost a decade later. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I just fell to my knees at Walmart," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kaw6s6/comment/mpptt7r/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said</u></a> one player, while another simply <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kaw6s6/comment/mppxaaj/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>wrote</u></a>: "I CAN'T TAKE THIS ANYMORE."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"How many more times will this happen before they finally give it up and leave us to our sorrow?" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kaw6s6/comment/mpqmw98/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>lamented</u></a> another.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not all fans are taking it as bad news, however, as some think an extraction shooter based in the Titanfall universe could have failed, killing the franchise for good.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Best thing that could've happened as far as the continued existence of this franchise is concerned," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kawz7p/comment/mppt97v/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>posited</u></a> this redditor. "A Titanfall extraction shooter would probably flop and the c-suite executives would say 'see, the people just don't like Titanfall anymore,' instead of the obvious reason being nobody asked for a Titanfall XTS."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I’m fine with this one being canceled," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kawz7p/comment/mppvfsm/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>responded</u></a> someone else, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kawz7p/comment/mppsmp4/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>followed</u></a> by: "Extraction shooter lmao. Good riddance."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"So sick and tired of 'extraction shooters'. They're so formulaic and boring. I don't want to loot bunch of useless shit and camp in an attic or sit in a bush for 20 minutes or risk getting shot moving thru big open fields. Give me quick matches, wallrunning and titans blastin'," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kawz7p/comment/mppyk45/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>suggested</u></a> this fan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Got sad. Read extraction shooter. Was literally okay," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1kawz7p/comment/mpq4ni4/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>summarized</u></a> someone else.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The roughly 100 jobs impacted at Respawn included individuals in development, publishing, and QA workers on Apex Legends, as well as smaller groups of individuals working on the Jedi team and two canceled incubation projects, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project"><u>one of which we reported on back in March,</u></a> and the other thought to have been the aforementioned extraction shooter set in the Titanfall universe.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These cuts follow a number of other layoffs over the last few years at EA. Earlier this year, it restructured BioWare, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams"><u>moving developers to other projects</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect"><u>laying off others</u></a>. It also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs"><u>eliminated 50 jobs at BioWare</u></a> in 2023 and an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/f1-developer-codemasters-suffers-round-of-layoffs"><u>unknown number more at Codemasters</u></a>, and in 2024 a larger restructuring that resulted in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-to-lay-off-around-670-to-advance-the-way-we-work"><u>670 workers</u></a> laid off company-wide, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-hit-by-layoffs-amid-eas-ongoing-reductions"><u>around two dozen workers at Respawn.</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">In 2023, it emerged that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-worked-on-titanfall-3-for-10-months-before-pivoting-to-apex-legends-ex-dev-reveals">Respawn Entertainment worked on Titanfall 3 "in earnest" for 10 months before ditching it for Apex Legends</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mohammad Alavi, who became narrative lead designer on Titanfall 3 before it was cut, told <a href="https://youtu.be/bIZXzkDpto4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Burnettwork</a> that much work on the sequel had been done.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Titanfall 2 came out, did what it did, and we were like, ‘Okay, we’re gonna make Titanfall 3,’ and we worked on Titanfall 3 for about 10 months, right? In earnest, right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We had new tech for it, we had multiple missions going, we had a first playable, which was on par to be just as good if not better than whatever we had before, right? But I’ll make this clear: incrementally better, it wasn’t revolutionary. And that’s the key thing, right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And we were feeling pretty decent about it, but not the same feeling as Titanfall 2 where we were making something revolutionary, y’know what I mean?”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, what happened? According to Alavi, it was a combination of the multiplayer team having issues making an experience that didn’t burn players out quickly, and the explosion of the Battle Royale genre with the release of PUBG in 2017.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The multiplayer team was having a hell of a time trying to fix the multiplayer, because a lot of people love the multiplayer. People love Titanfall 2 multiplayer,” Alavi said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“But the people who love Titanfall 2 multiplayer is a very small number of people. And most people play Titanfall 2 multiplayer and think it’s really good, but it’s just too much. It’s cranked up to 11, and they burn out a bit fast. And they’re like, ‘That was a great multiplayer, that’s not something I continually play a year, two years,’ right?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So we were trying to fix that. We were trying to fix that from Titanfall 1 to 2, trying to fix it from Titanfall 2 to 3, the multiplayer team was just dying.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then PUBG came out.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Respawn developers were seemingly more interested in playing a Battle Royale map with Titanfall 3 classes the team had put together, than any of the standard Titanfall multiplayer modes they were working on. This prompted a realisation: ditch Titanfall 3, which may or may not have ended up a better game than its predecessor, to create a Battle Royale that was wonderful.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And at the time, I had just literally become [the] narrative lead designer on Titanfall 3. I had just pitched the story, the whole game, that me and Manny [Hagopian] had come up with. We made this big presentation and then we went off at break, and came back from break, and we talked about it and we were like, ‘Yeah, we need to pivot. And we need to go make this game.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We literally canceled Titanfall 3 ourselves ’cause we were like, ‘We can make this game, and it’s going to be Titanfall 2 plus a little bit better, or we can make this thing, which is clearly amazing.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And don’t get me wrong, I will always miss having another Titanfall. I love that game. Titanfall 2 is my most crowning achievement, but it was the right call. That is a crazy cut. Such a crazy cut that EA didn’t even know about it for another six months until we had a prototype up and running that we could show them!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Randy Pitchford Insists Borderlands 4’s Early Release Date Decision Was ‘Literally 0% About Any Other Product’s Actual or Theoretical Launch Date’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/randy-pitchford-insists-borderlands-4s-early-release-date-decision-was-literally-0-about-any-other-products-actual-or-theoretical-launch-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/randy-pitchford-insists-borderlands-4%E2%80%99s-early-release-date-decision-was-%E2%80%98literally-0-about-any-other-product%E2%80%99s-actual-or-theoretical-launch-date%E2%80%99.1177302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/randy-pitchford-insists-borderlands-4s-early-release-date-decision-was-literally-0-about-any-other-products-actual-or-theoretical-launch-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">GTA 6? Marathon? Neither, apparently.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox development chief Randy Pitchford has insisted <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-launch-brought-forward-by-11-days-what-could-it-mean-for-the-gta-6-release-date">the decision to release Borderlands 4 earlier than planned</a> had nothing to do with any other game’s release date, amid speculation the shooter might have moved due to games such as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">Grand Theft Auto 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Co-op focused FPS Borderlands 4 was due out September 23, but will now release on September 12 across PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and Nintendo Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This 11-day shift sparked speculation that GTA 6’s release date had come into focus and that parent company Take-Two, which also owns GTA developer Rockstar, had shuffled its pack in a bid to give Borderlands 4 more breathing room. GTA 6 is currently still down to launch in the fall of 2025.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There was also talk that Borderlands 4 might have moved due to a clash with Bungie’s Marathon, a co-op focused extraction shooter. Marathon is a crucial game for Bungie, which is owned by Sony, and was set to go up against Borderlands 4 by releasing on the same day, September 23, 2025. Borderlands 4 is getting its own PlayStation State of Play broadcast today, April 30, at 2pm PT / 5pm ET / 11pm CEST.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But in a <a href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1917393753456664966" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, Pitchford denied any game’s release date influenced the decision to bring Borderlands 4 forward, insisting it had to do with “confidence” and “development trajectory.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Borderlands 4 shipping early is 100% the result of confidence in the game and development trajectory backed by actual tasks and bug find/fix rates,” Pitchford said. “Our decision is literally 0% about any other product’s actual or theoretical launch date.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While many games have brought their release dates forward, it remains an unusual occurence (delays are more likely). Chris Dring, Editor-In-Chief and Co-Founder of The Game Business, said that if other games' release dates really did have nothing to do with bringing Borderlands 4 forward, then the decision is "a bit odd."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"They’ve gone out with a date," <a href="https://x.com/Chris_Dring/status/1917461525175980361" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dring tweeted</a>. "It’s on calendars, market materials, social assets... Put ‘Borderlands 4 release date’ into Google and it still says Sep 23. There’s surely got to be a good commercial reason to shift a date."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In a video message apparently published early yesterday, Pitchford revealed the surprise Borderlands 4 release date news. “Everything is going great, actually,” he said. “In fact, everything is going kind of the best-case scenario. The game is awesome, the team is cooking, and so the launch date for Borderlands 4 is changing. We’re moving it forward. The launch date is now September 12.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“What?! This never happens you guys! This never happens! We’re moving the launch date forward! You’re gonna get Borderlands 4 earlier!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that Borderlands 4 is published by 2K Games, which is owned by Take-Two. Gearbox itself and the Borderlands IP are also owned by Take-Two. Meanwhile, Take-Two is the parent company of GTA developer Rockstar. At a high enough level, right up to CEO Strauss Zelnick, there will be a knowledge of all the company’s games, where they’re at in development, and a desire to give them all the best chance of success.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with IGN in February, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/boss-of-gta-6-and-borderlands-4-owner-take-two-says-it-will-time-its-releases-to-respect-the-consumers-need-to-spend-a-lot-of-time-playing-these-hit-games-before-they-go-on-to-the-next">Zelnick said Take-Two is planning its releases to avoid a risk of cannibalization</a>, insisting launch timing is driven by a desire to “respect the consumer's need to spend a lot of time playing these hit games before they go on to the next.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No, I think we will plan the releases so as not to have that be a problem,” Zelnick said. “And what we found is when you're giving consumers hits, they tend to be interested in pursuing other hits. In other words, I've said this many times, even when the hits aren't ours, they're a good thing for the industry. In this case, we hope that the hits will largely be ours. So we feel really good about it and I think that we will time our releases so as to respect the consumer's need to spend a lot of time playing these hit games before they go on to the next.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amid all this speculation is of course the prospect that GTA 6 will be delayed either into early winter, or at some point in the first quarter of 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Look, there's always a risk of slippage and I think as soon as you say words like absolutely, you jinx things," Zelnick responded when IGN asked how confident he was that Rockstar would hit fall 2025 for GTA 6. "So we feel really good about it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Diablo 4 Launches Season 8, Blizzard Responds to Roadmap Criticism, Reveals Plans to Update the Skill Tree, and Explains Controversial Battle Pass ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/as-diablo-4-launches-season-8-blizzard-responds-to-roadmap-criticism-reveals-plans-to-update-the-skill-tree-and-explains-controversial-battle-pass-changes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/as-diablo-4-launches-season-8-blizzard-responds-to-roadmap-criticism-reveals-plans-to-update-the-skill-tree-and-explains-controversial-battle-pass.1177299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/as-diablo-4-launches-season-8-blizzard-responds-to-roadmap-criticism-reveals-plans-to-update-the-skill-tree-and-explains-controversial-battle-pass-changes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4-season-8-updated-features-and-build-guides-for-belials-return">Diablo 4 has launched Season 8</a> and with it kicked off a series of free updates that will, eventually, lead into the action role-playing game’s second expansion, due out at some point in 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But not all is well within Diablo 4’s ravenous core community. It is a player base hungry for significant new features, reworks, and fresh ways to play the near two-year-old game, and it’s not shy about letting Blizzard know how it feels. Yes, Diablo 4 is more than its core community, with a significant number of casual players who just like to blast monsters without too much thought on how they’re doing it. But the foundation of Diablo 4’s community is made up of veteran fans who play week in, week out, fuss over meta builds, and want Blizzard to give them much more to think about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps it’s no surprise, then, that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-blizzard-tells-ign-whats-coming-to-diablo-4-in-2025-and-2026-including-new-expansion-new-ranking-system-and-finally-leaderboards">Diablo 4’s recently released 2025 roadmap</a> — the first Blizzard has released for the game — suffered a backlash. In the wake of the roadmap’s release, Diablo 4’s community expressed concern about what's coming up in 2025, including Season 8, and questioned whether there’s enough new content to keep them coming back.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/d4-roadmap-r7-fp01-1-1743949275184-1745959814620.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Diablo 4's 2025 roadmap touches on 2026. Image credit: Blizzard Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The debate online got to the point where a Diablo community manager <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/diablo4/comments/1juiw91/comment/mm3yj10/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>stepped into the main thread on the Diablo 4 subreddit to address the complaints</u></a>: “We added fewer details to the later parts of the roadmap to accommodate for things the team is still working on,” they insisted. “This isn't all that's coming in 2025 :)” Even Mike Ybarra, former president of Blizzard Entertainment and corporate boss at its parent company, Microsoft, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4s-2025-roadmap-hasnt-gone-down-well-with-hardcore-fans-and-even-the-former-president-of-blizzard-isnt-sure-where-the-game-is-going">waded into the debate with a few choice words</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 8 launches not only with all this in mind, but with a number of controversial changes of its own. Chief among them is a significant change to Diablo 4’s battle pass to bring it more in-line with Call of Duty’s, offering players the chance to unlock items in a non-linear fashion. But the battle pass now pays out less virtual currency than before, leaving players with less currency to put towards subsequent battle passes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In this sweeping interview with IGN, Diablo 4 lead live game designer Colin Finer and Diablo 4 lead seasons designer Deric Nunez respond to the reaction to the roadmap, confirm plans to update Diablo 4's skill tree (something players have wanted for some time now), and explain those changes to the battle pass.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: How is the team feeling about the rollout of Season 8? Are there any challenges you're predicting that you might have to tackle?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> Season 8, we're feeling really good about it. The thing we're really looking out for is anything crazy that happens in the first week. We're looking to see if there's anything that's gonna be underperforming as part of the boss powers, which is the big marquee seasonal thing that we've introduced in this season. So anything that might be underperforming, we're looking to make buffs. To anything that's massively overperforming, that's just breaking the game in terms of, you get one boss power and now everything is easy, we're probably gonna be toning down.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's nothing that we’re too scared about. We find on Diablo the harder something is to balance, the more fun it is. So I think it's in a pretty good spot. We're excited for this season to come out and really have players become bosses.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/dia-div-s8-content-infographic-enus-1920x1080-gg01-1745959897748.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Everything new in Diablo 4 Season 8. Image credit: Blizzard Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Has the team's philosophy around buffing and nerfing following a season rollout changed over the course of Diablo 4’s lifetime?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> Absolutely has evolved and changed, and a lot of it has been revolving around what we try and uphold and respect, which is player time investment and where players are having fun and meeting them there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So just to give a history on it, in the very first season of Diablo 4, we made a bunch of changes, sweeping nerfs to the game because we wanted it to fit more within our launch vision of the game, where combat was a little bit slow and methodical, and you're gonna take monsters one-on-one, and bosses are gonna be really challenging and difficult. Obviously, that didn't go super well because it felt like were defining what the fun of the game was for the players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over time we've become a lot more hands off once a season goes live. We don't want to necessarily make any big changes in the middle of a season, for example, to nerf or do big buffs to classes, because we again want to respect player time investment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a while we had a thought after Season 1 where it was like, ‘OK well, we won't nerf at the start of a season, but we will make big nerfs in the middle of a season, or will make big buffs in a season.’ As we saw progression became more deep and we added more ways to min-max your characters, we felt like doing big sweeping changes in the middle of a season would disrespect player time investment. You might work your way up to a really powerful Necromancer build with tons of minions, you've tempered your gear, you've masterworked it, and then if we found that it was too powerful in the middle of a season, it was way overperforming, if we nerf that, that meant all that time you put into that character was essentially being thrown away. So we didn't like that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And we didn't like the other part where we were going to massively buff a class, for example, in the middle of the season, because you might have wanted to play that. But now, now that you haven't invested in that build, now it presents this obnoxious challenge where it's like, ‘Well, I wanted to play this, it wasn't strong at the start of a season, and now it's this big climb to get to that point where you've unlocked this new build for me.’</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In Season 8, what we're really looking at now is being a little bit more reactive early into a season and then taking a step back. What that changes now in terms of our philosophy is if we see something in the start of a season that is crazy or overperforming — and how we define overperforming is that it's just short-cutting a lot of the challenge and progression of the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 7, to give you a clear example of that, we felt like Blood Wave Necromancer was doing this, where you get one unique item on the Necromancer, and now all the bosses in the game are falling over. You're one-shotting everything in the game. We like getting to that point. We like when players can become God-like powerful. We don't like when it's cheapened by one item or one interaction that invalidates everyone else's journey to get to that spot.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So we're going to be looking in Season 8 for early outperformers like that, taking S-plus builds to just an S. And if there's anything new that we've added — for example, we've added this really cool unique item on the Sorcerer that allows you to fan out Ice Shards — if, for example, that underperforms we will also be buffing those early into a season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So it's really just being a little bit more reactive earlier into a season and then taking a step back and letting players have fun with all the stuff that we've added.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I'm big into Diablo lore, and so it's exciting to see Belial arrive in Diablo 4 as part of Season 8. Why Belial now? And for Diablo lore fans, is there anything meaningful here they should keep an eye out for?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer: </strong>Absolutely. Diablo, the genre and the IP, greater and lesser evils always have a way of somehow coming back into Sanctuary, right? You thought you had banished them, like Lilith was banished to the abyss but she somehow came back. So Belial is another great example of that. In Diablo 3, he took over Caldeum, throughout the Iron Wolves, which you now see in the outskirts of Diablo 4, and they've been cast out. They're sort of outcasts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In terms of why Belial now? In Vessel of Hatred, Mephisto is walking the earth in his human form, all hell has broken loose, and Belial, who's a lesser evil, obviously can't pass up this opportunity to try and wreak havoc, take advantage of the chaos, take advantage of the fact that the gates of hell are open, Mephisto is walking the earth. And this felt like the proper time for someone like Belial, who's such an incredibly cool villain, incredibly cool demon, to want to come in and take advantage of this chaos.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So overall, the narrative that we're really pursuing and interested in is that Diablo 4 is evolving with these expansions and the Vessel of Hatred kicked off this... you never know who's going to come back. So we have a ton of big bads up our sleeves who are looking and eager to come back into Sanctuary to take advantage of this madness.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/dia-div-s08-end-game-belial-1745961666217.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Belial is finally in Diablo 4. Image credit: Blizzard Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: You'll obviously be keenly aware of some of the reaction to the roadmap among the core community. I think it's fair to say there's been some mixed reaction there. Were you surprised by some of the reaction about what was coming to the game this year?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> I don't know it was necessarily surprising. You know, if you ask our fans, 'What is it you want more of?' It's more details, more content, more things. So we know we have an obligation and we're in service of the player in terms of really getting them a fantastic experience and adding and evolving Diablo 4 over time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What we are talking about more on is ensuring that the players understand that this is just a starting point and that it is a conversation with the player base. Part of the seasonal model that we really enjoy is that seasons are a place for us to try really big, crazy, bold new ideas that we then can use community interaction and conversations to validate what's working for them, to then bring it into the eternal game and to evolve Diablo 4 over time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So a good example, if you think back to our past, we did this crazy Blood Harvest in Season 2 where all these vampires were running around, it was all hell broken loose on the overworld, and we took a lot of those lessons learned and things that players really enjoyed and pulled that straight into Season 4 with our updates to Helltides. So we're always looking to have a conversation with the community and hearing their thoughts on what's working for them and to pull that back into the broader game of Diablo 4 to make it feel like it's evolving over time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Part of this was, we have Nightmare Dungeons and Infernal Hordes, we have a couple of features called out on the roadmap, and again, it's a starting point. We'd love to hear some of the community thoughts and feedback when they see these things in terms of like, ‘Oh, I wish this thing was changed in Infernal Hordes,’ for example. That gives us a lot of great validation in the direction that we're heading on that particular feature.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Deric Nunez:</strong> My initial reaction to the reactions of the roadmap, it was all definitely very fair feedback. We see the roadmap as the kickoff for a conversation that we're looking to have with the player base. Obviously things get a bit more obfuscated the further out we get. We're really excited that some element of what the fans are looking for will definitely be revealed as we get further along. When it's all said and done, I think we'll be in an overall very strong place for Diablo 4, as we make the road towards the next expansion and refining that foundation and seeding in the new seasonal fun that we'd like to inject season after season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The fact we're getting so much feedback from a broad spectrum of the player base, the hardcore blasters and the casuals alike, is definitely all very important for us as we make decisions moving forward, and also validating some of the decisions and directions that we're already taking with the roadmap yet to be revealed.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I play a lot of Diablo and I play a lot of Call of Duty, and it looks like Diablo 4’s new battle pass has taken some inspiration from Call of Duty with the way you can now pick what you’re working towards. Can you talk about why you’ve changed it in this way?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> We are updating the battle pass in Season 8 with a new system called Reliquaries. A lot of this was driven by, the battle pass just felt like a pretty long and tedious grind through 150 levels to get the things that you wanted. And we felt like that wasn't necessarily servicing our players in the best way that we could.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Diablo, there's a lot of different ways to target or get chances at the types of loot that you want in the game. There's a lot of control, there's a lot of ways for players to manipulate the odds, or target something they want, just like the Lair Boss system where maybe there's a specific boss you want and you can farm that boss to get the unique item of your dreams.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Reliquary system aims to inject some of that choice and allow players to drive and work towards the things that they actually want out of the battle pass. The high level was, how do we get players more in the driver's seat in terms of claiming some of the stuff that they actually want out of the battle pass? We think it's just a lot more flexible now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: I’ve seen negative feedback to some of the changes to the battle pass where you get less virtual currency back from it now than before. That won’t have passed you by. Can you talk about the reasoning behind those changes?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> Yeah, I think it's definitely fair reaction. We're always listening. I think the thing that we think works a lot better as part of the system is, again, you're able to really work towards and pick the things you want out of the system. I believe also the Platinum that you gain out of the entire system is available to everyone now. So you don't even need to buy the battle pass necessarily to gain some of those things back. So it's a net win for everybody overall, in that sense.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/dia-div-s08-season-journey-02-1745960335290.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Diablo 4 Season 8 journey. Image credit: Blizzard Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: For Season 9, is there anything on the roadmap that people can expect might change either as a result of feedback or because things have become clearer internally? Or is everything on the roadmap that we're seeing now still what people can expect? I'm talking about Season 9 there but that can extend to Season 10 as well.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> At a high level, it really sets the expectation for what is the big major thing that we're gonna work on. But just like Season 8, how it has tons of quality of life changes, tons of updates, tons of details, each future season is also going to have that level of detail, content, and variety.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'll give you a great example: because it was the Season of Bosses in Season 8, we thought what better time and opportunity do we have to actually update a lot of the bosses that exist in our game? So we took a look at Duriel. He's been in the game for quite a while. We've completely changed the fight. We've added some new attacks. We've added a lot of fun new ways for him to eat you and kill you. Those level of details all coalesce into one really solid, incredible package for a season that the roadmap just isn't really able to capture at this point. Because it's really just trying to say, 'We're going to be investing and looking into Nightmare Dungeons... how do we level up that system and feature?' And there's just going to be so much that goes into it that really is hard to sell with just a few bullet points in terms of telling players where we're actually heading.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Deric Nunez:</strong> The devil will definitely be in the details when we reveal more. There's a lot more beyond the veil, the broad stroke of what was revealed.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/dia-div-x1-spiritborn-skill-tree-1-1745960380755.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Blizzard is working on a Diablo 4 skill tree update. Image credit: Blizzard Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>IGN: Generally, there is a desire from players for brand new skills and build variety. What's the thinking there about whether or not to do it either way?</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Colin Finer:</strong> This is a really meaty question, so I'll dive into a couple sections. Our goal every season is to completely refresh the meta and make it feel like there's tons of exciting new ways to play the game. A great example of this is you might have played a Whirlwind Barbarian last season, but you can still play it this season, and our hope that the boss powers that we've added that are unique to this season have ways to actually make that Whirlwind Barbarian feel completely different and get you to care about different things, and to have it change the way you play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So a great example is one of the boss powers has essentially a power that when you're channelling, it's going to fire a death laser beam. It's the Wandering Death. If you fought that one, you get to rip the power out of it, and now while you're Whirlwinding it's going to shoot that death laser. So that's a really cool way for you to have a really big impact on your overall build while still having a similar playstyle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As far as the skill tree changes, I can confirm we are talking about updates to the skill tree, but I don't have any details. It's something the team is taking very seriously, and we are talking about, what is a major change that we think would create more build variety and more build diversity going forward?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The reason why it's going to take us quite a while is it's kind of a big problem to entangle. So right now, just to dive into some of the details, Legendary aspects are two parts that we consider problematic. It's both customization, which is like, 'I want my — for example, if you played Rogue — Twisting Blades to orbit around me.' We think that's a really cool thing and really cool playstyle customization choice.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But because it's a Legendary item, it also has what we call power growth, which is, now Twisting Blades deals more damage. And what that means is if you want to play a Twisting Blades Rogue, you have to play with the Twisting Blades orbiting around you playstyle, right? We've just sort of said because there's both power on this as well as customization, this is the only way you're allowed to play Twisting Blades Rogue.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So we want to separate some of that out. We want to pull more of the customization into the skill tree and allow aspects to be more power growth. That's a lot to entangle and that's why it's a lot of conversations that we're having right now. And it's a lot of work on us to make sure we get it right, so that we release it into a high quality state. That's just like a little insight into the philosophy that we're working towards as part of that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The TL;DR to that is we do want to do something to the skill tree, no plans that I can share now, but it's something that we're definitely talking about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Diablo 4 Season 8 is live now.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>