<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:55:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double Fine’s Tim Schafer Rules Out More Sequels for Now, So You Can Forget About Brütal Legend 2 and Psychonauts 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/double-fines-tim-schafer-rules-out-more-sequels-for-now-so-you-can-forget-about-brtal-legend-2-and-psychonauts-3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/double-fine%E2%80%99s-tim-schafer-rules-out-more-sequels-for-now-so-you-can-forget-about-br%C3%BCtal-legend-2-and-psychonauts-3.1278222/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Light at the end of the tunnel.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Double Fine is poised to release a brand new game called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/keeper">Keeper</a> in October, but what comes after that? According to development chief Tim Schafer, he’s working on multiple projects at the Microsoft-owned studio, none of which are sequels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Keeper is an atmospheric puzzle adventure in which a long-forgotten lighthouse is awakened and goes on a journey. It’s led by Double Fine’s Lee Petty, which means Tim Schafer is hands-off and free to work on other things.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">What are those other things? Speaking to IGN at gamescom 2025, Schafer of course wouldn’t divulge Double Fine’s upcoming games, but did say the studio has multiple projects in the works and they’re all original IP.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I'm working on other stuff,” he confirmed. “The studio is doing multiple projects right now and they're all original IPs, because we did Psychonauts 2 and that will hold us for sequels for a while."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, that rules out Psychonauts 3 or — and this was always an unlikely one — Brütal Legend 2, at least in the short to mid-term. As game developers are fond of saying, never say never, but Schafer’s rather definitive comment gives us an idea of what to expect from Double Fine in the coming years — and that is the unexpected.</p><div id="xbox-games-series-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Xbox Games Series Tier List</h3><h3>Xbox Games Series Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Psychonauts 2 was Double Fine’s first release following Microsoft’s acquisition of the company in 2019. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/psychonauts-2-double-fine-xbox-game-studios-acqusition">Schafer has spoken before about how Double Fine had to cut boss fights from the game due to budget concerns</a>, but the Microsoft buyout meant it had the resources to add them back in. Schafer described Keeper as smaller-scale compared to Psychonauts 2, but with an impressive level of quality.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Psychonauts 2 eventually came out in 2021. Now, four years later, Double Fine is about to release its next game. Keeper comes out October 17, 2025, on PC and Xbox Series X and S.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Christian Petersen/Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/double-fines-tim-schafer-rules-out-more-sequels-for-now-so-you-can-forget-about-brtal-legend-2-and-psychonauts-3]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>