<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - ign_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/ign_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for ign_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:36:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Is Officially a Hit With Over 4 Million Copies Sold and a Peak Concurrent Player Count of 700,000 Across All Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-is-officially-a-hit-with-over-4-million-copies-sold-and-a-peak-concurrent-player-count-of-700000-across-all-platforms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-is-officially-a-hit-with-over-4-million-copies-sold-and-a-peak-concurrent-player-count-of-700-000-across-all-platforms.1349692/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> has now sold over 4 million copies worldwide less than two weeks since its release date, cementing its commercial success.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Publisher Nexon confirmed the milestone in a glowing <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000421.000014847.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>press release</u></a>, which also revealed that the extraction shooter had reached a huge concurrent count of 700,000 players across all platforms.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Within a day of its release, Embark Studio's shooter <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-is-already-one-of-the-biggest-extraction-shooters-ever-on-steam"><u>hit a Steam concurrent peak player count of 264,673</u></a>, making it one of the biggest extraction shooters ever on Valve's platform. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-breaks-its-own-steam-concurrent-peak-once-again-this-time-nearing-half-a-million-simultaneous-players"><u>That record was smashed again over the weekend</u></a> when Arc Raiders hit a concurrent peak of 462,488 players according to Valve's official figures. and now we know that, combined with users on consoles, the true figure is closing in on three-quarters of a million players.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nexon added that Arc Raiders has "maintained its number one spot on Steam's global sales rankings" ever since it released on October 30, and congratulated developer Embark, writing: "We are deeply impressed by the enthusiasm shown by our player community and look forward to building on that excitement with our content plans, including new maps, ARC vehicles, weapons, and quests, which will be available starting this month."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I thought I was only going to play five or six hours of Arc Raiders on launch day before sitting down to write this initial review in progress, but after just a handful of matches, I suddenly couldn’t pull myself away – and before I realized it, I’d been playing for 10 hours," we wrote in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-review"><u>IGN's Arc Raiders review-in-progress</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This is without question the most hooked I’ve found myself on an extraction shooter (and I’ve played a lot of them), with clean and tense gunplay, a progression system that’s been incredibly satisfying so far, and a loot game that has me sweating over what to put in my backpack and what to leave behind."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Jumping into Arc Raiders? Check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Best_ARC_Raiders_Settings">best settings</a>, find out what <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Skill_Tree_and_Best_Abilities">skills we recommend unlocking</a> first, and see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/How_to_Deliver_Field_Depot_Crates">how to earn loot by delivering field depot crates</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-is-officially-a-hit-with-over-4-million-copies-sold-and-a-peak-concurrent-player-count-of-700000-across-all-platforms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei Sells 3.3 Million Copies in Its First Month on Sale, Sony Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-sells-33-million-copies-in-its-first-month-on-sale-sony-confirms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-sells-3-3-million-copies-in-its-first-month-on-sale-sony-confirms.1349605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Exclusive news.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a> has sold 3.3 million copies in its first month on sale, Sony has confirmed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As part of its latest financial results, Sony said Sucker Punch’s PlayStation 5-exclusive action adventure sold 3.3 million units in the 32 days since going on sale on October 2 — so sales up to and including November 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony announced the figure without any commentary, so it’s hard to know whether the company is happy with the result. However, there is a great deal of context we can add that helps us paint a picture of Ghost of Yotei’s commercial success.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The first comparison we should make is to its predecessor, Ghost of Tsushima. It sold 2.4 million copies in its first three days after going on sale exclusively on PlayStation 4 on July 17, 2020, then hit 5 million after 118 days (just shy of four months). It’s now up to 13 million copies sold, including sales of the PC and PS5 Director’s Cut.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So it’s worth remembering that while we don’t have a figure for a comparable period of sales, it looks like Ghost of Yotei is selling about as well as Ghost of Tsushima before it, a suggestion backed up by sales data <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yoteis-us-launch-was-perfectly-fine-not-amazing-not-bad-says-analyst-but-the-true-test-will-be-in-the-months-ahead">from the U.S.</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sales-of-ps5-exclusive-ghost-of-yotei-in-line-with-ghost-of-tsushima-in-europe-new-data-reveals">across Europe</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But is that good enough? We need to consider that Ghost of Tsushima came out on the PS4, which in the summer of 2020 had a much bigger install base than the PS5 does today, and amid the stay-at-home gaming boom fueled by lockdowns. Ghost of Yotei also sold for $70, which means its dollar sales are greater compared to the cheaper Ghost of Tsushima, whose standard edition launched at $60.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best PS5 Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The timing of each release differs also in that Ghost of Tsushima came out in the summer, and Ghost of Yotei came out in the fall. Yotei has the crucial holiday season coming soon, and it will surely be a popular pick for those buying a PS5 for the first time or upgrading to the PS5 Pro.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And finally, multiplayer add-on Ghost of Yotei: Legends comes out at some point in 2026, which will undoubtedly give Ghost of Yotei a shot in the arm next year. And we all know that Ghost of Yotei, like Ghost of Tsushima before it, will eventually launch on PC in Director’s Cut form. Perhaps there will even be a PS6 version, whenever that console rolls around.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, Ghost of Yotei has some way to go before it matches the total sales figure of its predecessor, but is has plenty of opportunity to catch up. And, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m3wthi4twc2u" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as Circana’s Mat Piscatella said last month</a>, its launch sales were “perfectly fine... Not amazing, not bad.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for what’s next from developer Sucker Punch, in an interview with <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sucker-punch-will-remain-a-single-project-studio-after-ghost-of-yotei-boss-suggests/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>VGC</u></a>, co-founder and studio head, Brian Fleming, said the studio will decide its next project once Ghost of Yotei: Legends comes out. But, he suggested, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/if-we-were-good-at-juggling-four-projects-yeah-wed-have-a-remaster-ghost-of-yotei-dev-sucker-punch-says-it-will-remain-a-single-project-studio"><u>don’t expect a flurry of games from the relatively lean developer — it’s one project at a time</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we wait to find out, check out IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-review"><u>Ghost of Yotei review</u></a>. We’ve also got a cool story about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/atsus-sword-drawing-technique-in-ghost-of-yotei-may-look-impossibly-cool-but-according-to-japanese-martial-arts-experts-it-is-kind-of-doable-in-real-life"><u>Atsu's sword-drawing technique, which Japanese martial arts experts have said is kind of doable in real life</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ready to master Ghost of Yotei? Check out our comprehensive guides, which cover everything from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Things_to_Do_First_in_Ghost_of_Yotei"><u>things to do first</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/10_Best_Skills_to_Get_First"><u>best skills to unlock</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Advanced_Combat_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>advanced combat tips</u></a>, getting the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/How_to_Get_the_Armor_of_the_Undying_(Best_Early_Game_Armor_Set)"><u>best early-game armor set</u></a>, and uncovering every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Altar_of_Reflection_Locations"><u>Altar of Reflection location</u></a>. Our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Walkthrough"><u>Walkthrough</u></a> also provides <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>essential tips</u></a> and strategies for defeating every boss, and our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-yotei/Secrets,_Easter_Eggs,_and_Cheats"><u>secrets and easter eggs guide</u></a> ensures you never miss another hidden reference again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-sells-33-million-copies-in-its-first-month-on-sale-sony-confirms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>