<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 03:53:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameCube Coming To Nintendo Switch Online A Matter Of “When, Not If”, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-when-not-if-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-%E2%80%9Cwhen-not-if%E2%80%9D-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1151667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-when-not-if-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-107323">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Nintendo GameCube games could be coming to Nintendo Switch Online sooner rather that later. During <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fuxJOnR2awY&amp;t=667s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">his latest podcast</a>, known leaker Nate The Hate touched on what could be shown during the Nintendo Switch 2 direct on April 2. One area he focused on was Nintendo Switch online and whether GameCube games could be part of the event.</p>



<p>“I think it’s also going to be a good venue for them to go over Nintendo Switch Online enhancements and new platforms that will come to the Switch 2 and, likely, even the Switch itself in the future—maybe within that first launch year,” Nate The Hate said. “And I think GameCube is very likely. </p>







<p>“I’ve heard GameCube will be coming to NSO [Nintendo Switch Online]. It’s just a question of when, not if. And maybe you give a nice little roadmap of some of the titles that would come to the GameCube NSO app.”</p>



<p>As always, until this information is confirmed independently by Insider Gaming or announced by Nintendo itself, please take any rumors with a grain of salt. Luckily, it won’t be long until fans find out if GameCube games will be added as part of the Nintendo Switch 2 launch or not.</p>



<p>Do you think Nintendo GameCube games will come to Nintendo Switch Online? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read what Take-Two Interactive’s CEO had to say about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-says-lack-of-gta-6-news-is-to-create-enormous-anticipation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lack of updates surrounding Grand Theft Auto 6</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-watch-nintendo-switch-2-direct-event/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-watch-nintendo-switch-2-direct-event/">
                                How To Watch The Nintendo Switch 2 Direct Event                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Nintendo Switch 2 full reveal is here, and this is how you can watch the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct when it airs at 9am ET/6am PT.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-will-the-nintendo-switch-2-direct-last/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-will-the-nintendo-switch-2-direct-last/">
                                How Long Will The Nintendo Switch 2 Direct Last?                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Nintendo is holding its Nintendo Switch 2 Direct event on Wednesday, April 2, and one question people are wondering is how long will it be?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-rumors-heat-up-with-new-ff9-website-launch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-rumors-heat-up-with-new-ff9-website-launch/">
                                Final Fantasy 9 Remake Rumors Heat Up With New FF9 Website Launch                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The 25th anniversary celebration of Final Fantasy 9 has resulted in a new website for the game, and remake rumors have intensified again.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/developers-say-nintendo-switch-2-dev-kits-dont-have-4k-output/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/developers-say-nintendo-switch-2-dev-kits-dont-have-4k-output/">
                                Developers Say Nintendo Switch 2 Dev Kits Don’t Have 4K Output                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Despite rumors that the Nintendo Switch 2 will support 4K, developers have told Insider Gaming that the dev kit doesn’t include 4K output.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pred Signs With Vegas Falcons Following OpTic Departure]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure.1151604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fresh off his release from OpTic Texas, reigning Call of Duty League champion Amer “Pred” Zulbeari has signed with Vegas Falcons. While OpTic may be joking about roster moves on April Fool’s Day, Falcons aren’t screwing around after a tough start to their time in the CDL.</p>



<h2 id="h-pred-joins-a-falcons-roster-still-looking-for-its-first-win-in-call-of-duty-league">Pred Joins a Falcons Roster Still Looking For Its First Win in Call of Duty League</h2>



<p>Pred was removed from the OpTic starting roster at the end of March, after a turbulent 2025 that followed a superb 2024 season. The product of Australian CoD joined OpTic before the start of the 2024 campaign, and a promising start cascaded into a CDL championship, the first for the OpTic brand since the League’s inception.</p>



<p>But months after OpTic lifted the elusive CDL world championship, Pred moved to the inactive roster, needing a break to “handle personal issues” and work on his mental health. In his stead, Cuyler “Huke” Garland returned to the starting roster for 2025, but Pred came back in February, though OpTic’s results continued to worsen. A struggling Kenneth “Kenny” Williams chose to step down before the Stage Two Major, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-texas-repeats-history-drops-pred-for-huke-again/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OpTic chose to swap Huke in for Pred again</a>, but this time permanently.</p>



<div><article><p><span>A World Champion has arrived in Vegas. It’s time to make a statement.

Welcome, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/Pred" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Pred</a><span> 🦅💚 </span></p></article></div>



<p>Pred now joins a Vegas Falcons team that is in desperate need of some positive momentum. The Vegas franchise was sold to Saudi Arabian organization Team Falcons after the 2024 season ended, and the organization chose to stick with a Saudi roster going into 2025, with former champion James “Clayster” Eubanks joining as coach. But the roster just has been unable to keep up with the talent in the league, and went completely winless throughout all of Stage 1 and Stage 2.</p>



<p>With the signing of Pred, the Vegas Falcons are making their first big splash on a non-Saudi player. Will it be enough to secure the team’s first win in CDL, or are more moves on the horizon? Let us know which one is your favorite in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/faker-biggest-esports-star-50-million-won-donation/">Faker made a 50 million Won donation to charity</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov’s Next Major Change Could Drastically Alter How Bosses Work]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-next-major-change-bosses/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov%E2%80%99s-next-major-change-could-drastically-alter-how-bosses-work.1151517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-next-major-change-bosses/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov fans are neck-deep in the Labyrinth, an all-new map added as a surprise during the latest in-game event. It has been dubbed one of the best things Battlestate Games has ever done, and despite it being an insane challenge, it has pleased a vast portion of the player base.</p>



<p>Following the successful rollout of the Labyrinth event, the next major Escape from Tarkov change could be something very different and <strong>seriously </strong>drastic. It doesn’t <strong>seem like </strong>it could be an April Fool’s joke, either.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-bold-changes">Bold Changes</h2>



<p>On the Tarkov community forum, user ‘my89user’ made a suggestion a week ago about <a href="https://tarkov.community/posts/2407/boss-spawn-rotation-and-hot-loot-rotation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">how bosses and loot could work</a>. They proposed a rotating schedule that would see certain maps adopt a 100% boss spawn rate for a few days before rotating to the next map, and so on.</p>



<p>They also proposed that ‘hot loot’ map rotations could be introduced as well. Each week, a designated map would have a 50% increased loot pool for high-value items.</p>



<p>By doing this, the hope is that certain maps become targets for players more focused on PvP and high XP runs, while other maps would quiet down and offer a lower chance of running into bosses and geared players.</p>



<p>Surprisingly, the ‘Lead of Game Design’ accepted the suggestion as ‘Planned’ and said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Good idea, I think we will do it after the ‘Labyrinth’</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The suggestion had secured 441 votes before it was accepted by the team at Battlestate Games, and the feedback was mostly positive.</p>



<p>Escape from Tarkov is in a tentative place right now. It’s no big secret that the game still has an issue with cheaters, but the Labyrinth event has been such a rampant success that players have overlooked that for the time being.</p>



<p>In a couple of months, we’ll likely be shaping up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-wipe/">next <strong>wipe</strong> in Tarkov</a>. That doesn’t affect me, though, as I’m a PvE main… Yes, <em>I know</em>.</p>



<p>Do you think this change would be a win in Escape from Tarkov? Let me know in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-cod-fans-six-million-devs/">all the COD players who found Helldivers 2</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six Million COD Players Bought Helldivers 2, and the Devs Didn’t Know How To Respond]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-cod-fans-six-million-devs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/six-million-cod-players-bought-helldivers-2-and-the-devs-didn%E2%80%99t-know-how-to-respond.1151514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-cod-fans-six-million-devs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a recent interview, the CEO of the developer behind Helldivers 2 sat down to talk about the last year of success, growth, and the struggles that the game went through to hit lofty peaks. Arrowhead had a tumultuous year in 2024, and from a stint of review bombing to being nominated for prestigious awards, it was nothing short of an intense twelve months.</p>



<p>It was revealed by Shams Jorjani, the CEO of Arrowhead, that an influx of ‘unintended’ players from so many different communities left the team scratching their heads over how to respond.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-different-voices-screaming">‘Different Voices Screaming’</h2>



<p>During a chat with The Game Business’ Christropher Dring, Shams Jorjani walked through the last year at Arrowhead. He stepped in to secure the CEO role less than a year ago, picking up the position when things were looking awry for Helldivers 2.</p>



<p>He explained that it was thanks to a constant stream of meaningful updates that the paltry user score of 19% was able to flip entirely to 94% in a matter of weeks. Eventually, Helldivers 2 became one of the most popular and awarded games of 2024.</p>



<p>One interesting tidbit came when Jorjani was talking about the audience that gravitated towards Helldivers 2 and how diverse it was. I can’t say for sure where he got his numbers from, but he explained:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We did not make Helldivers for <strong>six million Call of Duty players</strong>. We absolutely didn’t. But six million Call of Duty players bought our game. And they are interested in different things compared to, say, the audience that comes from Escape From Tarkov or Arma, which were some of our more influential games.</p>



<p>The summer of pain, or whatever we want to call it, was painful in part because it was hard for us to reconcile how to stay true to the studio fundamentals, while dealing with the business realities of having <strong>so many different voices screaming at us</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Helldivers 2 turned out to be a strong success for Arrowhead, even if it took one heck of a journey to get there. In January, it was confirmed that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-dev-next-game-concept/">concept for the next game</a> for the studio was being fleshed out, but nobody knows what that’ll look like.</p>



<p>Did you play Helldivers 2? Let me know in the comments, or hit up the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/atomfall-rebellion-most-successful-launch/">Atomfall is Rebellion’s most successful game ever</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>