<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:58:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Has Beaten Almost Every Call of Duty Game Ever Made on Twitch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-beaten-almost-every-cod-game-twitch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-has-beaten-almost-every-call-of-duty-game-ever-made-on-twitch.1264884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Battlefield 6 beta commenced earlier today, and it has been skyrocketing all day in social and streaming circles. The game has become one of the most highly anticipated first-person shooters to emerge in several years, and it’s looking like a strong turning point for a series that has found itself on rocky ground for almost a decade.</p>



<p>As the beta unravels, scores of fans are taking to Twitch and YouTube to watch streams as they await the <strong>open portion </strong>of the beta to kick off. As I write this, almost 850,000 people are watching the beta on <strong>Twitch alone</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-huge-numbers">Huge Numbers</h2>



<p>Battlefield 6 is being played by some of the most prolific streamers in the world right now, and they’re pulling in gargantuan numbers. At the time of publishing, the Battlefield 6 beta had 830,000 live viewers, which is something of a stunning record for the series.</p>



<p>Not only is it the most-watched Battlefield game ever released (not that it’s released yet), but it’s also effortlessly beating the peak viewership count for <strong>every major Call of Duty game ever</strong>, bar Call of Duty: Warzone.</p>



<p>Only the battle royale game stands between Battlefield 6 and total dominance.</p>



<p>For reference, here’s the ranking for peak viewer counts on Twitch:</p>



<ul>
<li>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III – 444,866</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 – 481,586</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops Cold War – 705,050</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II – 751,937</li>



<li><strong>Battlefield 6 – 844,723</strong></li>



<li>Call of Duty: Warzone – 1,613,626</li>
</ul>



<p>As the weekend approaches, could we see Battlefield 6 threaten Warzone’s record?</p>



<p>It’s worth stressing that Battlefield 6’s highest peak has also topped Rainbow Six Siege (583,166), Overwatch (634,296), Escape from Tarkov (566,684), and PUBG (597,663).</p>



<p>This is one heck of a high-performing game, and we’re on the first day of the beta. The sky might just be the limit for Battlefield 6.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/contraband-development-stopped-at-xbox/">Contraband’s development has been halted</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-beaten-almost-every-cod-game-twitch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Owners Having Issues With Madden 26 Access]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-owners-having-issues-with-madden-26-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-owners-having-issues-with-madden-26-access.1264878/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Madden 26 is out now for Deluxe Edition owners, but Xbox users are having issues getting access to the game. </p>



<p>A quick search on social media—or a visit to my DMs—shows a number of players don’t have access to the game they purchased if they got it as part of the EA Sports MVP Bundle that included both Madden 26 and College Football 26. </p>



<p>The specific issue is that the game is showing as unowned. </p>



<p><strong>“For our Xbox MVP Bundle owners, we’re aware of an issue some are experiencing where they’re unable to access the game,” </strong>the <a href="https://x.com/MaddenNFLDirect/status/1953495214695338229" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Madden team posted</a>. <strong>“We’re working closely with Microsoft and plan to resolve this as soon as possible.”</strong></p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>For our Xbox MVP Bundle owners, we’re aware of an issue some are experiencing where they’re unable to access the game.</p><p>We’re working closely with Microsoft and plan to resolve this as soon as possible.</p><p>Updates will be threaded below as needed!</p></div>— MaddenNFLDirect (@MaddenNFLDirect) <a href="https://twitter.com/MaddenNFLDirect/status/1953495214695338229?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>One work around is that if you have EA Play, you can download the 10-hour trial. After that download completes, it <em>should </em>show that you own the full game and you’ll be all set. </p>



<h6 id="h-more-madden-26-madden-26-soundtrack-features-chappell-roan-dmx-green-day-and-more">More Madden 26: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-soundtrack/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Madden 26 Soundtrack Features Chappell Roan, DMX, Green Day, and More</a></h6>



<p>If you don’t have EA Play or the workaround doesn’t work, you’ll have to simply wait for an update from EA and Microsoft on the matter.</p>



<p>Madden 26 is also available for PlayStation 5, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2. Those who bought the Standard Edition of the game have to wait until August 14 to play.</p>



<p>Have you had any issues accessing Madden 26 on Xbox or other consoles? Let us know down below, and take the discussion further in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about Sony&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-admits-live-service-games-smoothly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">admitting its shift to live service games</a>&nbsp;hasn’t been going “smoothly”. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-owners-having-issues-with-madden-26-access/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is Bringing Proximity Chat to Battle Royale, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-proximity-chat-battle-royale/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-bringing-proximity-chat-to-battle-royale-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1264797/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-138241">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>A new claim states that proximity chat is coming to Fortnite’s battle royale mode. </p>



<p>With Fortnite introducing a brand new season for Chapter 6, Epic Games has a boatload of content for players to try out. The Shock ‘N Awesome season goes live today, introducing the highly anticipated <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-power-rangers-collaboration-confirmed-in-new-teaser/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Power Rangers collaboration</a>, along with brand new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-shock-n-awesome-season-details-revealed-new-enemies-weapons-pois-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">weapons, enemies, POIs</a> and more. The latest development reveals that Fortnite might have more in store for us. </p>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-is-reportedly-bringing-proximity-chat-to-battle-royale">Fortnite is Reportedly Bringing Proximity Chat to Battle Royale</h2>



<p>The update about Fortnite’s proximity mode comes from a <a href="https://x.com/Wensoing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Wensoing</a> and <a href="https://x.com/Loolo_WRLD" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Loolo_WRLD</a> (corroborated by <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1953377603588345984" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HYPEX</a>). Their latest post on X (formerly Twitter) states that this feature is being developed for the battle royale mode. Epic Games has seemingly separated some “Creative Proximity Chat files” so that they can be incorporated into the battle royale mode. The feature will also include a setting to deactivate or activate it according to the player’s preference. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Proximity chat will introduce another layer of chaos and strategy to Fortnite’s battle royale mode. For those who are unfamiliar, this feature enables players to hear the voices of other players in the lobby, depending on their in-game proximity. Proximity chat has been an integral factor in creating numerous viral content pieces for games like Call of Duty and Among Us, as it enables interactions that were previously impossible in the base game. </p>



<p>In other news,<span>&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-ceo-debunks-report-that-fortnites-new-disney-mode-is-delayed-by-slow-decision-making/" target="_blank">Epic Games’ CEO has refuted a report</a>&nbsp;that stated Fortnite’s new Disney mode is delayed due to</span> slow decision-making. What are your thoughts on Fortnite introducing proximity chat to battle royale? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-soundtrack/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Madden 26 soundtrack featuring the likes of Chappell Roan, DMX, Green Day, and more</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-party-announced-for-september-release/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-party-announced-for-september-release/">
                                Lego Party Announced For September Release                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Publisher Fictions and developer SMG Studio have announced that Lego Party is scheduled for a release on all platforms in September.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-soundtrack/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-soundtrack/">
                                Madden 26 Soundtrack Features Chappell Roan, DMX, Green Day, and More                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With the game’s release here, EA Sports has released the full soundtrack for Madden 26, featuring a collection of artists new and old.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dice-clarifies-how-bots-work-in-battlefield-6-beta/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dice-clarifies-how-bots-work-in-battlefield-6-beta/">
                                DICE Clarifies How Bots Work In Battlefield 6 Beta                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With the Battlefield 6 beta starting, DICE has clarified how AI bots will work and appear in matches for the time being. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ally-x-release-date-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ally-x-release-date-revealed/">
                                Asus ROG Xbox Ally X Release Date Has Been Revealed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a known data miner, the release date for the Asus ROG Xbox Ally and Xbox Ally X has been found to be in October.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-proximity-chat-battle-royale/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Party Announced For September Release]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-party-announced-for-september-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-party-announced-for-september-release.1264794/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The next party game coming for the Mario Party crown has an official release date as Lego Party is set to launch on September 30. </p>



<p>The game will be available for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, and PC via Steam.</p>



<p>Lego Party is your standard party board game, featuring customizable Lego characters, 60 minigames, and multiplayer with up to four players locally or private online games no matter the platform. What it won’t have, however, is online matchmaking with random players.</p>



<p>Lego Party is presented like a game show where you’ll travel around the board, avoiding obstacles, and playing mini games to collect Golden Bricks. The player with the most Golden Bricks at the end of the game wins. And don’t worry, there aren’t any bonus bricks at the end of the game that will snatch defeat from the jaws of victory.</p>



<p>In our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-party-hands-on-preview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">preview of the game</a> from hands-on time at Summer Game Fest, I called Lego Party a game with all of the <strong>“makings of being the next great party game”.</strong> </p>



<p><strong>“Throughout the entire Play Days event, the LEGO Party booth was the loudest and most active among all of the games being shown. That’s a good sign when the goal is to bring people together.”</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="LEGO Party! Hands-On Preview – A Real Mario Party Rival?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EZsj0_ZBX0E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Are you excited about Lego Party now that we have it’s September release date? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the leaked&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ally-x-release-date-revealed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for the Asus ROG Xbox Ally</a>&nbsp;and Xbox Ally X. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-party-announced-for-september-release/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>