<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:33:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Roblox Deep Blue Codes & Rewards—Every August 2025 Active Code]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-roblox-deep-blue-codes-rewards/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-roblox-deep-blue-codes-rewards%E2%80%94every-august-2025-active-code.1273128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p id="block-d59fc5fe-b095-48f1-9552-8b1eceb99a77">Deep Blue is an open water exploration game in Roblox. Here is every active reward code in the Roblox game so far.</p>



<p id="block-27dcb43a-3815-41d9-a096-68bf9eb60a4c"><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/8-best-roblox-games-to-play-this-summer-holiday/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roblox</a> Deep Blue is a game that sees the player stranded in the middle of the ocean, and to help them survive the vast expanse, the game has started making use of reward codes.</p>



<p id="block-5ba00f8e-104d-4fe9-8548-c13fd208d392">Below, we’ll reveal every active reward code in the game, and we’ll also keep track of all expired codes, so you’ll always know which ones are ready to use.</p>



<h2 id="block-da9187f0-5260-4436-9b0d-2d8743108b97">Every Active Roblox Deep Blue Code &amp; Reward (August 2025)</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Players need to work together to survive. Image credit: Roblox Corporation</figcaption></figure>



<p id="block-bbb6d5db-4a28-44e0-9d04-e0d5344e6525"><strong>Below, you can find all of the active codes in Deep Blue</strong> <strong>for August 2025.</strong></p>



<p id="block-5faf391a-c45d-4193-87f9-1547a2afd1d8">Use these codes before they eventually expire, as most codes in Roblox do.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Code</th><th data-align="center">Reward</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>ALPHA</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 15 Credits</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>SECRET</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 15 Credits</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>MONEY</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 20 Credits</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>TIRING</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 20 Credits</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>BADBUGGYGAME</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 10 Credits</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>BALANCE</strong></td><td data-align="center">Redeem for 15 Credits</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="block-da1c171d-e28c-4ec7-8647-6ed6ce818ea2">How to Redeem Roblox Deep Blue Codes</h2>



<p id="block-840e5ff2-682e-4a86-b78a-dbd5011ad922">To redeem codes in <strong>Roblox Deep Blue</strong>, just follow these easy steps:</p>



<ol id="block-cec654f7-7a68-448e-bd71-e65dc6a8b74b">
<li>Launch<strong> Roblox, then the Deep Blue</strong> game.</li>



<li><strong>Click on the ‘Codes’ option</strong> on the <strong>left side of the screen</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Now, click the ‘Insert Code’ option.</strong></li>



<li><strong>Type in the code you want, and press ‘Redeem’</strong>.</li>
</ol>



<p id="block-afb0834b-f90d-418a-8e7e-4013ea4d181e">If the code is still active, then you’ll receive the reward.<strong> Remember, each code can only be used once per user account.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-1062c7a4-c337-43f7-a066-93c202d5d633">All Expired Roblox Deep Blue Codes</h2>



<p id="block-58d0f0ab-0072-47a0-a23a-1ca672cfbaf8"><strong>As of August 2025, there are no expired codes.</strong></p>



<p id="block-34c39cbb-2bac-4504-b7fb-fdd3005995b0">However, that’s unlikely to be the case forever, so this is where we’ll keep track of expired codes when they run out of time.</p>



<h2 id="block-832a28a8-2cb4-4554-bf29-a8966f3fb762">Where to Find Roblox Deep Blue Codes</h2>



<p id="block-5e94dd15-7e3b-446d-8bb9-44b52e05e677">Be sure to <strong>bookmark this page</strong> if you want to always know which codes are active. That’s because we’ll be sure to update it when new codes come in.</p>



<p>You can also check out the game’s <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Sps2bTjt7p" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Discord channel</a> to be first in line for new codes.</p>



<hr id="block-3d65722b-354e-4ab5-86e7-635e58ff23ad">



<p id="block-a5d5640c-b2c4-4819-98a5-e5a54d7815f7">Do you love the adventure games in Roblox? Then be sure to check out our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>,&nbsp;where you can start up some fun new discussions about the best games.</p>



<p id="block-af576a45-7eed-4bff-8b1c-486e9482b333">While you’re here, you can also check out our other Roblox adventure game guides:&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-roblox-flashpoint-codes-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flashpoint Worlds Collide</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-roblox-lost-currents-codes-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lost Currents</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-roblox-one-touch-codes-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">One Touch</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/all-roblox-deep-blue-codes-rewards/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Gift Code Teases Release Coming Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-code-gift-tease-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-gift-code-teases-release-coming-soon.1273086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlestate Games has released a new gift code for Escape from Tarkov players, and it offers a hint regarding the game’s imminent graduation into a fully released game. For almost a decade, Escape from Tarkov has been a beta product, but in the coming months, it’ll transform, and the latest Escape from Tarkov reward code is teasing exactly that.</p>



<p>The latest Tarkov code offers a stack of free items, but more importantly, it tells us that the game’s full release is <strong>coming soon</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-latest-tarkov-code-gives-free-kit">Latest Tarkov Code Gives Free Kit</h2>



<p>If you want to redeem the latest Escape from Tarkov code, you’ll need to head to <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/promo/activate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s website</a>, sign in, and click on ‘Activate Promo Code’. Then, type in this code: RELEASECOMINGSOON.</p>



<p>It’s worth stressing that you can only redeem these free Tarkov items on a PvP account and <strong>not </strong>on a PvE account. If you’re only tied to the latter, you won’t even be able to claim the code, period.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Here’s everything you get when you redeem the new Escape from Tarkov gift code:</p>



<ul>
<li>Tactical Sport Headset</li>



<li>Fleece Beanie</li>



<li>TGlasses</li>



<li>AFAK</li>



<li>Esmarch x 2</li>



<li>Ultimag x 3</li>



<li>Zarya Flashbang</li>



<li>SJ6</li>



<li>7.62 PP x 60</li>



<li>7.62 PS x 120</li>



<li>RGD-5 x 2</li>



<li>Propital</li>



<li>Morphine</li>



<li>CALOK-B</li>



<li>CMS</li>



<li>Vaseline</li>



<li>A18 Skanda Armoured Rig</li>



<li>AKMN (fully kitted)</li>
</ul>



<p>The AKMN assault rifle you get with the new Tarkov code is a beaut, boasting the red hex components that are guaranteed to make it stand out.</p>



<p>You’ll notice that when you head to Escape from Tarkov to collect the rewards, you’ll be met with a message from System that simply reads ‘Soon.’</p>



<p>It’s indicative <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-tarkov-1-0-being-released/">of Tarkov’s 1.0 release</a>, which might drop before the year is out (but more likely it’ll come in 2026).</p>



<p>Let me know if you’re excited about Escape from Tarkov’s imminent full release on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-feature-16-6v6-maps-at-launch-its-claimed/">how many maps Black Ops 7 will have at launch</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-code-gift-tease-release/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is The Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Review Embargo Date?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review-embargo-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review-embargo-date.1273008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>One of 2025’s biggest and most important titles is a remake—Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater. It’s a full remake of MGS3, and the review embargo will tell us if it’s lived up to the original game’s legend, or if it’s fallen flat on its face in Tselinoyarsk mud.</p>



<p>Metal Gear Solid is an all-time franchise. Its stories still stand the test of time, and there are gameplay ideas that had they not been done previously would be unthinkable in 2025—although looking at the back of the game case would be slightly problematic in the digital era. I don’t think there’s a finer example of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-3-boss-fights-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MGS than Snake Eater</a>.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-a-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater remake</a> is a fitting first reimagining. Even though Hideo Kojima isn’t at the helm of the project, we still expect this to be a hit. So let’s check out its review embargo details.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Fans will hang onto the word of reviews. Credit to Konami</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Several sources have quoted August 22 as the game’s review embargo date, with a release time of 12:01 AM PT.</strong></p>



<p>Many outlets and critics already seem to have gotten their hands on Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater. You can see from Destin Legarie’s <a href="https://x.com/DestinLegarie" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> page that this is the case.</p>



<p>Destin is quoted as saying: “I’ve played Metal Gear Solid Delta on PS5 and PC. Embargoed for Friday, August 22nd, 2025 as 12:01am PT. Coverage beyond me fanboying will be live at embargo.”</p>



<div><article><p><span>I’ve played Metal Gear Solid Delta on PS5 and PC.

Embargoed for Friday August 22nd, 2025 as 12:01am PT

Coverage beyond me fanboying will be live at embargo.</span></p></article></div>







<p><strong>Expectations for Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater are sky-high, and I expect the reviews to follow suit with a Metacritic score in the region of 90-95.</strong></p>



<p>A telltale sign that Konami is confident about Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is that review copies are already out weeks in advance. The other sign is the review embargo date being a week before launch. Companies only do this if they’re confident about their product.</p>



<p>I would suggest Konami is more than happy with the state of Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater. This is great news when you consider 2004’s original Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater has a <strong>91/100 rating</strong> on Metacritic. As long as the remake builds upon existing greatness and adds some modern-day quality of life changes, it’s hard to see the score dropping below 91.</p>



<p>Using my reasoning, I don’t think a <strong>92 or 93</strong> score is out of the question.</p>



<hr>



<p>The wait for the Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater review embargo will be more excruciating than Naked Snake using CQC to battle a crab. Let me know what score you think the Snake Eater remake is going to score. Be sure to check out the Insider Gaming forum for more MGS discussions.</p>



<p>Be sure to read abourt <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-remake-original-mgs-snake-eater-3-differences-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Remake &amp; OG Snake Eater 3 differences</a> and the complete <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-trophy-list-all-achievement-trophy-differences-in-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophy List</a> for more MGS content.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review-embargo-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>