<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 12:57:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign Could be Getting an Endless Ranked Mode, Datamine Reveals]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-could-be-getting-an-endless-ranked-mode-datamine-reveals/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign-could-be-getting-an-endless-ranked-mode-datamine-reveals.1264302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new Elden Ring Nightreign datamine reveals that developers are working on an endless ranked mode called ‘Deep of Night’. </p>



<p>Elden Ring Nightreign’s developers, FromSoftware, have been constantly churning out new content for the game for players to immerse themselves in. They recently added the highly requested <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-1-02-patch-notes-july-31-update-duos-finally-added-along-with-relic-filter-feature/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Duos mode</a> and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-next-set-of-everdark-sovereigns-arrive-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new set of Everdark Sovereigns</a>. Interestingly, the latest development reveals that FromSoftware could be cooking a brand new game mode for the title. </p>



<h2 id="h-elden-ring-nightreign-s-endless-ranked-mode-has-skill-based-matchmaking">Elden Ring Nightreign’s Endless Ranked Mode Has Skill-Based Matchmaking </h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-nightreign-dataminers-have-uncovered-plans-for-a-new-endless-mode-with-armored-core-6s-rank-system-and-skill-based-matchmaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a>, a new post on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Adminisitrator/comments/1mh908l/elden_ring_nightreign_new_mode_deep_of_night/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reddit</a> talks about Elden Ring Nightreign’s upcoming endless ranked mode, which was datamined from the duos mode patch. The upcoming game mode is called ‘Deep of Night’ and it will be added to the Expeditions menu. The description states that players will not be able to choose these targets, and “difficulty increases with depth”. The player’s rating will increase with every victory, allowing them to proceed to “even greater depths”. The last statement says, “The boundless dark stretches out unto infinity.” </p>



<p>The player ratings in Elden Ring Nightreign’s endless ranked mode will be recorded through ‘Depth’. Victories will increase the player’s Depth rating, and losses will decrease it. There are 5 Depth Tiers to progress through: Depth 1 (Rating 0-999), Depth 2 (Rating 1000-1999), Depth 3 (Rating 2000-3999), Depth 4 (Rating 4000-5999), Depth 5 (Rating 6000+). Once a player is promoted to a higher tier, they cannot be demoted. Also, players will be matched with others of the same Depth; however, if there aren’t enough players in the same Depth, then the pool will be expanded.  </p>



<p>Regardless, players should take this information with a grain of salt as it doesn’t come from an official source and wait for an announcement from FromSoftware. </p>



<p>In other news, Elden Ring Nightreign and the Shadow of the Erdtree DLC hit <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-and-shadow-of-the-erdtree-hit-new-sales-milestones/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new sales milestones</a> recently. What are your thoughts on Elden Ring Nightreign receiving an endless ranked mode? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-bungie-befre-march-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony confirming that Marathon is still scheduled to release by March 2026</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-could-be-getting-an-endless-ranked-mode-datamine-reveals/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>