<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:22:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Omelet You Cook Devs Fear Slay the Spire 2 Will Steal Spotlight]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/omelet-you-cook-devs-fear-slay-the-spire-2-will-steal-spotlight/</link>
            <guid>1419238</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The team behind Omelet You Cook, a cooking roguelike, is worried about the release of Slay the Spire 2, which could take away all the buzz the game could have.</p>



<p>Roguelike games are plentiful in 2026, but Slay the Spire arguably stands head and shoulders above the rest in the genre. Omelet You Cook, published by SchuBox Games, offers a unique take on the genre and is currently available on Steam Early Access. However, it’s scheduled to leave early access on February 8, giving the game only one month before Slay the Spire’s long-awaited sequel comes out and dominates the roguelike discussion.</p>







<h2 id="h-slay-the-spire-2-hits-early-access-in-march-2026">Slay the Spire 2 hits Early Access in March 2026</h2>



<p>In September 2025, Mega Crit announced that the sequel to the massively popular 2019 roguelike deck builder would be hitting Early Access in March, following a delay. </p>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/roguelike/slay-the-spire-2-pulls-a-silksong-scares-indie-devs-into-releasing-roguelike-ahead-of-schedule-in-fear-of-losing-players-to-an-absolute-juggernaut-in-our-own-genre/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+, </a>Dan Schumacher noted that they originally assumed they would not have to compete with the massive title because they believed it was still set to release in late 2025. </p>



<p>However, as it turns out, they missed the delay announcement. Schumacher even joked that he won’t have time to finish his own game because he’ll be too busy playing that</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“There was no way we could release at the same time as an absolute juggernaut in our own genre,” he says.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He encourages audiences to be kind to the title as it leaves early access in February, noting that it’s a big jump, but they want the chance to have a wider audience play the game.</p>







<p>You can pick up Omelet You Cook right now on Steam and Early Access for $15. There’s a free demo, as well.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you excited about either of the upcoming roguelikes? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/omelet-you-cook-devs-fear-slay-the-spire-2-will-steal-spotlight/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Elden Ring Nightreign TTRPG Is Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/an-elden-ring-nightreign-ttrpg-is-coming/</link>
            <guid>1419190</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-172824">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Group SNE is adapting another video game into a tabletop RPG. This time, it’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/studios/fromsoftware/" id="87617">FromSoftware’s</a> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/elden-ring-nightreign/" id="2260" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign.</a></p>



<p>Group SNE has adopted many games for tabletop RPGs, including Armored Core 6, Dark Souls, and the original Elden Ring. The next TTRPG is scheduled for release in the spring of 2026. Elden Ring Nightreign is a twist on the original Elden Ring concept, turning the game into a three-player co-op game.</p>



<figure></figure>







<h2 id="h-elden-ring-nightreign-recently-got-its-first-dlc-drop">Elden Ring Nightreign Recently Got Its First DLC Drop</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to FromSoftware</figcaption></figure>



<p>In December 2025, The Forsaken Hollows DLC launched for Nightreign. That DLC launched two new character classes, new bosses, and more. So far, the game has sold over 5 million units, and the DLC has also secured millions of sales.</p>



<p>For more Nightreign, learn about how you can familiarize yourself with the lore of the game via a 400-page book. Learn more about the upcoming movie adaptation of the popular video game here. For more, check out how to complete <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-complete-all-elden-ring-nightreign-remembrances/" id="121392">all remembrances in the game.</a></p>







<hr>



<p>Are you excited for a tabletop RPG adaptation of Elden Ring Nightreign? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-declines-microsoft-earnings/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-declines-microsoft-earnings/">
                                Xbox Revenue Declines As Microsoft Reports FY26 Q2 Earnings                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft delivered strong FY26 Q2 earnings, but Xbox struggled as hardware revenue dropped 32% and content growth slowed.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-game-studios-head-christoph-hartmann-leaving/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-game-studios-head-christoph-hartmann-leaving/">
                                Amazon Game Studios Head Christoph Hartmann Leaving Company                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new report, Amazon Game Studios head Christoph Hartmann is leaving the company after eight years.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-censors-switch-2-version-of-dispatch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-censors-switch-2-version-of-dispatch/">
                                Nintendo Censors Switch 2 Version Of Dispatch                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With Dispatch coming to Nintendo Switch 2, it’s been discovered that Nintendo policies have resulted in the game being censored in areas. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-ps5-upgrade-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-ps5-upgrade-revealed/">
                                Kingdom Come: Deliverance PS5 Upgrade Revealed by PlayStation Store                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The PlayStation Store seems to have inadvertently confirmed an incoming Kingdom Come: Deliverance PS5 upgrade.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/an-elden-ring-nightreign-ttrpg-is-coming/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Revenue Declines As Microsoft Reports FY26 Q2 Earnings]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-declines-microsoft-earnings/</link>
            <guid>1419109</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Microsoft had another big quarter on paper. Xbox, however, did not.</p>



<p>In its second quarter fiscal year 2026 (FY26 Q2) earnings report, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/Investor/earnings/FY-2026-Q2/press-release-webcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Microsoft announced</a> a 17% year-over-over jump in revenue to <strong>$81.3 billion</strong>, with growth once again driven by cloud and AI. Microsoft Cloud revenue hit <strong>$51.5 billion</strong>, Azure jumped <strong>39%</strong>, and most of the company’s major business lines continued to trend in the right direction.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/xbox" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox</a> was the clear exception.</p>







<h2 id="h-xbox-revenue-fell-across-the-board">Xbox Revenue Fell Across The Board</h2>



<p>Within Microsoft’s report, the company said that Xbox content and services revenue <strong>fell 5% year over year</strong>. Microsoft didn’t disclose specifics on the Xbox content regarding the revenue for services like Xbox Game Pass, but did say that the decline can be attributed to last year benefiting from “strong first-party content performance”. Still, the slowdown is hard to overlook as Xbox content growth continues to cool, at least for the time being. </p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-tops-ps5-to-lead-hardware-sales-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hardware</a> was an even bigger concern.</p>



<p>Microsoft confirmed that <strong>Xbox hardware revenue dropped 32%</strong> during the quarter. As usual, the company did not provide console sales numbers or much added context, but the direction is clear. Xbox console sales continue to slide, even as Microsoft positions the brand as more of a service-driven ecosystem than a traditional hardware platform.</p>







<p>Recent quarterly data shows how quickly things have changed. Xbox content and services revenue <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-q1-2026-drop-113m-year-over-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted strong gains throughout much of FY25</a>, including multiple quarters of double-digit growth. That momentum has now faded, with FY26 Q2 marking a shift into negative territory.</p>



<p>Despite the Xbox decline for the quarter, other parts of the earnings helped soften the impact. <strong>Windows OEM and Devices revenue grew 1%</strong>, while <strong>search and news advertising rose 10%</strong>, underlining just how much Xbox is lagging behind Microsoft’s other consumer-facing businesses.</p>



<p>For Microsoft, the overall earnings picture remains strong. For Xbox, the concerns are piling up. With hardware revenue falling sharply as the Xbox Series X|S ages out and content growth seemingly slowing, Microsoft’s long-term plan for the platform is becoming a bit murkier. </p>



<p>What do you think of Xbox revenue falling in FY26 Q2? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more gaming news, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-game-studios-head-christoph-hartmann-leaving/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head of Amazon Game Studios leaving the company</a>. And for even more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-declines-microsoft-earnings/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>