<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:33:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight is Coming to Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-nintendo-switch-2-announcement-2026/</link>
            <guid>1384201</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The 2017 indie Metroidvania, Hollow Knight, is making its way to Nintendo Switch 2. A port of the game was announced by Team Cherry alongside <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a free DLC expansion</a> for Hollow Knight: Silksong.</p>



<p>Released in 2017, Hollow Knight started as a Kickstarter before becoming the game it’s known as today. As the nameless Knight, you’ll tackle a multitude of hard bosses and explore the bug-infested world of Hallownest. Known for its brutal difficulty and beautiful visuals, the Team Cherry title has become one of the most successful indies of the 2010s. Its spinoff, Hollow Knight: Silksong, released in 2025 and went on to receive multiple awards and nominations, including <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-winners/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">several Game of the Year nods</a>. Now, the team is bringing the world to a new console: the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>







<h2 id="h-hollow-knight-nintendo-switch-2-edition-announced-free-upgrade-for-nintendo-switch-owners">Hollow Knight: Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Announced, Free Upgrade for Nintendo Switch Owners</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/holiday2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a blog from Team Cherry</a>, the team announced that <strong>a Nintendo Switch 2 version</strong> of <strong>Hollow Knight</strong> is <strong>in the works</strong>. The game will feature a bevy of additions, like <strong>high frame-rate modes and resolutions</strong>, as well as <strong>new graphical effects</strong>. <strong>No release date for the edition was revealed</strong> outside of a 2026 release window. Screenshots of the game can be found above and on the blog.</p>



<p>Additionally, <strong>all those who own Hollow Knight for the Nintendo Switch can upgrade to the Nintendo Switch 2 edition for free</strong>. An update bringing new features and bug fixes will launch on current consoles around its release. The news comes after Hollow Knight: Silksong was announced to get a new DLC expansion, Sea of Sorrow. Both Hollow Knight: Nintendo Switch 2 Edition and Sea of Sorrow will launch in 2026.</p>



<p>The Nintendo Switch was one of the first consoles to get Hollow Knight back in June 2018, months before PlayStation and Xbox. Originally, Silksong was planned as DLC for the title, but shifted to its own game. Now, fans can enjoy both series titles on the Nintendo Switch 2, enhanced and with new content to enjoy for free.</p>







<p>What do you think of Hollow Knight getting a Nintendo Switch 2 edition? Are you eligible for a free upgrade? What console did you play it on? What did you think of Silksong? Leave a comment below and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Hollow Knight, check out coverage on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-3-team-cherry/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Team Cherry’s next game</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-out-of-far-fields-in-hollow-knight-silksong-flexile-spines-wish-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silksong guides</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-nintendo-switch-2-announcement-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Free Expansion Coming 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-2026/</link>
            <guid>1384186</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new DLC expansion for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, called Sea of Sorrow, is officially in the works. Furthermore, it will be free and releasing sometime in 2026.</p>



<p>Hollow Knight: Silksong is the long-awaited spin-off to the acclaimed 2017 indie Metroidvania, Hollow Knight. Playing as Hornet, you’ll take down many hard bosses and explore the bug-infested land of Pharloom. Its release had been anticipated by many for years since being announced in 2019, before finally launching in September 2025. The game was met with critical praise from fans and outlets, even earning several year-end awards, including Best Action/Adventure Game at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-winners/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards</a> last week. Now, Team Cherry has revealed what’s next for Hornet with a small but intriguing tease.</p>







<h2 id="h-hollow-knight-silksong-sea-of-sorrow-dlc-expansion-announced-by-team-cherry-coming-in-2026">Hollow Knight: Silksong – Sea of Sorrow DLC Expansion Announced by Team Cherry, Coming in 2026</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Sea of Sorrow Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qDFEeeLy6ws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/holiday2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a blog on Team Cherry’s website</a>, the team revealed new plans for the Hollow Knight series. High among those was the announcement of a <strong>new DLC expansion</strong> for <strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong>, titled <strong>Sea of Sorrow</strong>. The announcement teaser can be found above. As of writing, no specific release date was given outside of 2026. However, <strong>the DLC will be free for all owners of the title</strong>. According to the blog, the expansion will give Hornet <strong>an all-new sea-themed area to explore</strong> with <strong>new tools and new bosses to fight</strong>. More information will be revealed before its release.</p>



<p>The news comes after Hollow Knight: Silksong’s win for Best Action/Adventure Game at The Game Awards 2025. Silksong was up for multiple awards, including Game of the Year, but lost a majority of them to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-broke-all-time-the-game-awards-record/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">record-breaking Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>. Still, for the amount of hype the title generated and delivered on is huge, and it won’t be surprising that many are pumped for Sea of Sorrow.</p>







<p>What do you think of Hollow Knight: Silksong getting a free expansion? Excited to see more of Sea of Sorrow? Think it needed DLC? Do you prefer Silksong over Hollow Knight? Leave a comment below and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Hollow Knight: Silksong, check out coverage on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-shadow-drop-release-was-callous-says-hell-is-us-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its sudden release</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-3-team-cherry/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Team Cherry’s next game</a>. Don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-expansion-sea-of-sorrow-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>