<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 05:32:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Announces Tokyo Game Show 2025 Lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tokyo-game-show-2025-lineup/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-announces-tokyo-game-show-2025-lineup.1280346/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ahead of Tokyo Game Show (TGS) 2025 in September, PlayStation has announced its lineup for the expo. The convention, held yearly, has already shown promise this year with contributors like Capcom and Koei Tecmo showing up with huge games. Now, PlayStation has joined in on the fun with two of its biggest upcoming titles.</p>



<p>This is the company’s second year in a row showing up to TGS after being absent from 2020-2023.  Last year, the biggest games were Monster Hunter Wilds and the GOTY winner Astro Bot. Death Stranding 2: On The Beach also held a showcase, where a new trailer was unveiled. While no showcases are revealed just yet, the two titles on display are sure to make fans happy.</p>



<h2 id="h-ghost-of-yotei-and-marvel-tokon-fighting-souls-headline-playstation-s-tgs-main-booth">Ghost of Yotei and Marvel TOKON: Fighting Souls Headline PlayStation’s TGS Main Booth</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - &quot;Song of Vengeance&quot; Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FM08YoziYJs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As of right now, only two brand-new titles will be available for attendees to play on the show floor. Those titles, according to <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/sony-interactive-entertainment-announces-preliminary-tgs-2025-lineup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the press release</a>, are Sucker Punch’s Ghost of Yotei and ARC System Works’ Marvel TOKON: Fighting Souls. More games will be announced closer to the expo’s start on September 25th, 2025. </p>



<p>This marks the first public demo of Ghost of Yotei, which launches a week after TGS on October 2nd. Meanwhile, many fans at EVO got their hands on Marvel TOKON: Fighting Souls, with many more when the closed beta comes on September 6th. Still, both games are some of the studio’s and are sure to make a splash with attendees.</p>



<p>Are you excited for what PlayStation is bringing to Tokyo Game Show 2025 next month? Let us know in the comments and on the forums!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more on PlayStation, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-new-trailer-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei’s latest story trailer</a> and details on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-tokon-ps5-closed-beta-details-revealed/">Marvel TOKON’s beta</a>. As always, make sure to subscribe to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/">our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tokyo-game-show-2025-lineup/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Flag Gets Surprise Limited-Time Steam Demo]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/last-flag-limited-time-steam-demo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/last-flag-gets-surprise-limited-time-steam-demo.1280307/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>As part of the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/category/action_tps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam TPS Fest</a>, the multiplayer 5v5 shooter Last Flag released a surprise demo today. The fest, which celebrates Third-Person games with sales and demos, started today. While many demos were already available, like Star Wars Outlaws, Last Flag is one title nobody expected to see. </p>



<p>Last Flag, scheduled for 2026 for Steam (with console versions in the works), is a 5v5 multiplayer shooter by Night Street Games based on the infamous Capture the Flag mode. With a unique 70s art style and fun gameplay, it definitely stands out from other titles like Call of Duty and Battlefield. Therefore, the surprise release of a limited-time demo is sure to get some attention, especially after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-record-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s success</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-last-flag-s-free-demo-lasts-from-august-25th-to-september-1st">Last Flag’s Free Demo Lasts from August 25th to September 1st</h2>







<p>As per a press release, a free demo for Last Flag is available now on Steam for players to try. The demo will only be up for a week, ending September 1st. To get the demo, head over to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2721340/Last_Flag/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official Steam page</a> and download the demo. </p>



<p>With multiple characters to choose from, with a wide range of abilities, you’ll work together with your team to hide the flag and capture it. In addition, music for the game has been worked on by Dan Reynolds (Imagine Dragons), Grammy-nominated producer/writer JT Daly (Benson Boone), and Dave Lowmiller (Call of Duty: Modern Warfare). It seems like the perfect mix for players to create an unforgettable experience on and off the battleground.</p>



<p>Do you plan on playing Last Flag this week? If you have, how are you liking it? Let us know in the comments and on the forums!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more multiplayer news, check out our articles on Call of Duty: Black Ops 7’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-avalon-map-campaign/">campaign merger</a> and Battlefield 6’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-datamine-reveals-larger-maps-and-new-vehicles/">map selection</a>. As always, make sure to subscribe to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our weekly newsletter</a> for more!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/last-flag-limited-time-steam-demo/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kojima Has ‘Written The Concept’ For Death Stranding 3, But He Won’t Be Making It]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kojima-written-concept-death-stranding-3-wont-make/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kojima-has-%E2%80%98written-the-concept%E2%80%99-for-death-stranding-3-but-he-won%E2%80%99t-be-making-it.1280172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It has been two months since Death Stranding 2: On The Beach was released, with Hideo Kojima delivering big on yet another cinematic masterpiece that turned heads worldwide. In the short time that has followed, Kojima has busied himself promoting every angle of the game on social media and at the world tour events set up to showcase the game.</p>



<p>Many have wondered where the series goes from here, especially given the increasingly large window between releases. The first Death Stranding title dropped in 2019, and it took <strong>six years </strong>to produce a second game. Will Kojima be around for the third game? He has written a concept, but doesn’t think it’ll be him who makes Death Stranding 3.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-hideo-kojima-make-another-death-stranding-game">Will Hideo Kojima Make Another Death Stranding Game?</h2>



<p>The Death Stranding series is equal parts emotional, action-packed, and bizarre. To outsiders, it represents a kind of walking or delivery guy simulator, but to those who have experienced it, Death Stranding is something phenomenal, tumultuous, and mind-bending.</p>



<p>That’s a touch of the sentiments handed down by fans over the last two months, anyway.</p>



<p>During <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/AwQDoD9TK6w?t=3114s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a recent appearance</a> on the ‘World Strand Tour’, Hideo Kojima and his team stopped off in Saudi Arabia to further promote Death Stranding 2: On The Beach. In one segment, the interviewer asked the crowd, ‘Who wants Death Stranding 3?’</p>



<p>That prompted a telling response from Kojima:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I’m not planning to do that at the moment, because the ending of Death Stranding 2 was my finale of 1 and 2, but I already wrote the concept of DS3, so I have that in data.</p>



<p>I hope that someone will create it for me.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/open-world/hideo-kojima-says-hes-already-written-a-concept-for-death-stranding-3-but-he-wants-someone-else-to-make-it/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar</a> for the spot)</em></p>



<p>Kojima went on to dive into the creation of Death Stranding 2, stressing that the COVID-19 pandemic threw a major spanner into the works, something that he has mentioned plenty of times in the past.</p>



<p>In June, Hideo Kojima spoke frankly about his health and the future of his company, Kojima Productions. He stressed that if his team tries to outright replicate his work when he has passed on, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-company-fail-replicate-work/">the company will fail</a>. For the last few years, Kojima has been stressing acute awareness of the fragility of life, showing a vulnerability that has made him more endearing, if nothing else.</p>



<p>Do you want to see Death Stranding 3? Let me know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/replaced-delayed-spring-2026-trailer/">REPLACED has been delayed to 2026</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/kojima-written-concept-death-stranding-3-wont-make/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter Star Teases Ken Look in New Photo]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-noah-centineo-ken-tease/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-star-teases-ken-look-in-new-photo.1280151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>We may have gotten our first look at Noah Centineo’s Ken in the upcoming Street Fighter film. Last week, we got <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-photo-teases-wwe-superstar-cody-rhodes-as-guile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a shadowy glimpse</a> at Cody Rhodes’ Guile on set. While we didn’t see much outside his lore-accurate hair, it was enough for fans to go crazy. Now, a new picture, thanks to Noah Centineo’s social media, shows us what his Ken may look like.</p>



<p>Legendary’s Street Fighter, directed by Kitao Sakurai (Bad Trip, Twisted Metal), started filming earlier this month. After it announced the loaded cast, including Warrior’s Andrew Koji as Ryu, Aquaman’s Jason Momoa as Blanka, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-has-reportedly-lined-up-chun-li-balrog-actors/">50 Cent as Balrog</a>, many were cautiously optimistic about the adaptation. While no official release date is set yet, it’s not stopping some teases on set on social media, like with Noah Centineo.</p>



<h2 id="h-street-fighter-s-noah-centineo-teases-first-look-at-ken-masters">Street Fighter’s Noah Centineo Teases First Look at Ken Masters</h2>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DNxvvKO3MG8/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In a new photo from the Black Adam actor, Noah Centineo shows off his muscles in his trailer. We can also see that his hair, unknown if real or fake, is down and dyed yellow. To further confirm it’s Ken, Centineo captioned the post “Road brawler”, which is a cheeky hint at the title Street Fighter. Considering how Ken looks in the games, he does seem to resemble the American-born rival of Ryu rather well. </p>



<p>Of course, it’s one thing to look the part and another to act it out. Though considering Centineo’s burgeoning action career with The Recruit, he may be a perfect fit for Ken Masters. Regardless, it’ll be interesting to see if more set photos regarding Street Fighter will be seen as they film in Australia. The fighting franchise is no stranger to adaptations, but many are hopeful that Legendary’s take will succeed.</p>



<p>What do you think about Noah Centineo’s Ken Masters look? Are you excited for Legendary’s Street Fighter film? Let us know in the comments and on the forums!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more on Street Fighter, check out our articles on the return of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-2-kingdom-hearts-composer-returns-for-street-fighter-6-after-30-years/">an iconic composer</a> for Street Fighter 6 and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-6-swimsuit-skins-are-live-with-the-sagat-update/">recent Sagat update</a>. Make sure to subscribe to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/">our weekly newsletter</a> for even more Insider Gaming news!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-noah-centineo-ken-tease/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>