<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 17:58:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Minecraft Movie Launches “For Your Consideration” Awards Campaign]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-awards-campaign-warner-bros-oscars/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-minecraft-movie-launches-%E2%80%9Cfor-your-consideration%E2%80%9D-awards-campaign.1335250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A Minecraft Movie is officially launching an awards campaign for consideration for upcoming ceremonies like the Academy Awards and Golden Globes. Yes, you read that right, and yes, it is official from Warner Bros. itself.</p>



<p>Released earlier this year, A Minecraft Movie brought the blocky world of Minecraft to live-action and the results were rather decent. However, the real success came from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-mine-craft-movie-biggest-ever-video-game-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its large box office</a>, which came as a result of successful marketing and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-minecraft-movie-has-added-a-disclaimer-warning-viewers-not-to-throw-popcorn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">internet memes</a>. Now, there is now a chance we could hear “Steve’s Lava Chicken” sung on the Oscars stage or Jack Black thank ‘Chicken Jockey’ at his Golden Globes acceptance speech.</p>



<h2 id="h-a-minecraft-movie-campaigning-for-all-major-categories-including-best-picture-and-actor">A Minecraft Movie Campaigning for All Major Categories, Including Best Picture and Actor</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Warner Bros. Pictures</figcaption></figure>



<p>Warner Bros. has launched campaigns for many of its films to be considered for end-of-year awards like the Academy Awards and Golden Globes. While some films, like the smash-hits Weapons, One Battle After Another, and Sinners, are among the names, one is a bit out-there: <a href="https://www.wbawards.com/screenings/film/?film=aminecraftmovie" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">A Minecraft Movie</a>. It’s not out there for movies, even okay ones, to do award campaigns, as it could snag some nominations if it’s lucky. However, Warner Bros. is putting everything up for the film, including it’s main cast and director.</p>



<p>The full list of contested categories can be <a href="https://www.wbawards.com/screenings/film/?film=aminecraftmovie" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">found here</a>. Notable ones include Best Picture, Jared Hess for Best Director, and Jack Black for Best Actor. Will it get any of those? Seeing how the race is, definitely not. However, personally, it does have a shot at Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Production Design, and Best Visual Effects. Depending on how some future movies do, you could even put “I Feel Alive” up there for Best Original Song. </p>



<p>While a weird campaign, it’s not surprising for Warner Bros. to do so. As mentioned before, A Minecraft Movie had a meteoric rise at the box office. In fact, it’s currently the <a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/year/world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">third-highest-grossing film of 2025</a> behind Lilo &amp; Stitch and Ne Zha 2. A sequel is already greenlit and in production as of earlier this month. Regardless, it’ll be interesting to see if it leads anywhere and, if it does, it will be quite entertaining for sure.</p>



<p>Do you think A Minecraft Movie could get nominated for an Academy Award? Golden Globes? If so, what category? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Minecraft, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-realm-verneath-opened-by-slipknot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Slipknot’s server</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-players-can-use-supermans-abilities-in-new-dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Superman DLC</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-awards-campaign-warner-bros-oscars/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EGX and The Death of the UK Gaming Expo]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/egx-death-uk-gaming-expo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/egx-and-the-death-of-the-uk-gaming-expo.1335157/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The United Kingdom’s relationship with the video game expo scene has crumbled. Once upon a time, the nation boasted showcases like the Insomnia Gaming Festival, WASD, and EGX, but they’ve all disappeared into the shadows over the years.</p>



<p>The Insomnia Gaming Festival went bust (and is trying a half-hearted resurgence), WASD shut down, and EGX has become a pitiful, almost unbranded corner in the larger MCM Comic Con in London. I attended EGX over the weekend, and I’m sad to say that it’s no longer worth keeping alive.</p>



<p>EGX’s disappearance marks the death of the UK gaming expo circuit.</p>



<h2 id="h-uk-gamers-are-left-to-dream-hack">UK Gamers Are Left to Dream(Hack)</h2>



<p>Next year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dreamhack-coming-to-the-uk-in-2025-call-of-duty-dota/">DreamHack returns</a> to the United Kingdom for the first time in <strong>ten years</strong>, which is a saving grace of sorts for gamers across the territory. In some places, the courageous efforts of more grassroots events like EPIC.LAN are trying to get some wheels turning, but the most iconic expos in the business have now faded into nothingness.</p>



<p>In 2024, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insomnia-gaming-festival-review/">Insomnia Gaming Festival</a> imploded after 25 years of entertaining visitors, thanks to financial woes brought on by the lingering impact of the COVID-19 pandemic. It’s trying to make a grand return in 2025, but <strong>it’s not looking good</strong>.</p>



<figure><figcaption>One of the final Insomnia Gaming Festival events, and while it was bustling, nobody knew it was about to collapse.</figcaption></figure>







<p>Also in 2024, the WASD showcase, a more intimate event in London that was one of my favorite events in the world, was shut down as the event’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/">organiser entered liquidation</a>.</p>



<p>Now, I’m sad to report that EGX is done and dusted.</p>



<h2 id="h-farewell-egx">Farewell, EGX</h2>



<p>Formerly known as the Eurogamer Expo, EGX was once the shining star of the UK gaming scene, a monumental event that drew international acclaim and hosted a showfloor featuring the biggest names in the business.</p>



<figure><figcaption>This was EGX in 2014 after a rebrand from ‘Eurogamer Expo’. It was a massive event that was once seen as the UK’s E3.</figcaption></figure>







<p>The COVID-19 pandemic wasn’t kind to EGX, but in the years that followed the devastation of the virus, EGX seemed to be getting back on an even keel. That growth has ebbed away into nothing, and EGX is now an unrecognizable corner of the larger MCM Comic Con event.</p>



<p>I attended EGX (for the last time) this year, and baulked at what was on display. It was almost impossible to spot any EGX branding, and what I did find was a few scattered indie games and a lone LAN area featuring a few rigs with a mix of playable titles on them. No big names, no exclusive demo opportunities, and almost <strong>nothing </strong>in the way of gaming activations.</p>



<figure><figcaption>The cracks in EGX started showing in 2023 (Image Credit: Later Levels Blog)</figcaption></figure>







<p>In 2024, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/egx-mcm-comic-con-same-event/">EGX and MCM joined forces</a>, but the showcases were separated, and EGX still enjoyed a standalone profile that was represented in the branding of the event. This year, EGX has all but disappeared, leaving MCM standing tall – but even that has issues.</p>



<p>As I walked around MCM, I was greeted by vast swathes of market-style stalls selling anime body pillow covers, mystery bags, animatronic furry tails, AI-generated art prints, and plastic toys aplenty. Amid a sea of half-baked cosplays and bored-looking event employees, I found none of my people; the gamers had failed to show out for EGX, what little of it there was.</p>



<h2 id="h-barely-an-expo">Barely an Expo</h2>



<p>The PR folks backing the event were offering me nothing but film and TV opportunities, and despite there being the likes of Troy Baker, Ben Starr, Chris Judge, Doug Cockle, Neil Newbon, and Elias Toufexis in attendance, nothing came up in a gaming capacity.</p>



<p>I made a conscious effort to request <strong>some kind of connection </strong>from the staff running the meet and greet area, and was palmed off with a ‘Sorry, they don’t have time for that,’ by a go-between messenger of an employee who failed to get me any traction from a nearby manager. I should stress that the manager who had ‘no time’ for me was plainly standing on the spot doing nothing.</p>



<figure><figcaption>You never know you’re in the good times <strong>when you’re in them</strong>. This was one of the first Eurogamer Expos in London</figcaption></figure>







<p>With no games to play, no big-named exhibitors occupying the show floor, and there being nothing in the way of gaming activations, I was reduced to wandering the stalls and trying to get excited about merchandise (spoiler alert: <strong>I didn’t</strong>).</p>



<p>The panels were visited by a half dozen people every time someone was on the stage, the security staff were lacklustre and weren’t doing their job properly, and the busiest portion of the event seemed to always be the ‘food court’.</p>



<p>I can see EGX vanishing entirely next year, and while MCM will persist, it too has been reduced to something almost unworthy of a spot in your calendar. All eyes are now on Gamescom, an utterly phenomenal event that continues to expand year after year. I’ve been to Gamescom twice and can stress that it’s the <strong>ultimate event </strong>in the world for gamers, and I just praise that it’s only a short flight away for me.</p>



<p>Elsewhere, gamers around the world can still enjoy events like Summer Game Fest, PAX, DreamHack, Tokyo Game Show, and other localized, regional events. If you want a regular expo in the UK, you’re out of luck and will need to travel.</p>



<p>Do you agree that the United Kingdom needs to do better in the gaming space? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/twitch-ceo-dan-clancy-responds-emiru/">Twitch’s CEO has responded to the Emiru assault</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/egx-death-uk-gaming-expo/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Wordle #1591: Hints And Answer For October 27, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1591-hints-answer-october-27-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/today%E2%80%99s-wordle-1591-hints-and-answer-for-october-27-2025.1335154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Get ready for an easier Wordle answer than the past few days. Wordle challenges players to guess a fresh five-letter word each day in six tries or fewer. Whether you’re a beginner or a daily player, today’s tips and strategies can help you solve it faster and maintain your streak—if you’re open to a little extra help. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Wordle, don’t worry, you’ll find some <strong>helpful hints and even the answer for Wordle Game #1591 for October 27, 2025</strong>.</p>



<p>To play today’s Wordle, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to the game’s website.</a> If you want to go right to today’s answer without any tips or tricks, you <strong><a href="#h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1591-on-october-27-2025">can click right here</a>.</strong> If you’ve missed any days, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle Answer Archive</a> for every past answer.</p>



<p><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> The following information includes spoilers on today’s</em> and yesterday’s editions<em> of Wordle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure></figure>



<h2>How To Play Wordle</h2>



<p>Wordle is a simple but addictive word puzzle. Each day, players have to <strong>guess a five-letter word answer</strong> in no more than six attempts. After each guess:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Green letters</strong> are correct and in the right position.</li>



<li><strong>Yellow letters</strong> are correct, but in the wrong position.</li>



<li><strong>Gray letters</strong> are not in the word at all.</li>
</ul>



<p>The goal is to guess the word in as few tries as possible. Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p>Wordle can only be played on the New York Times website. There is currently no app for you to download the official game.</p>



<h2 id="h-wordle-hints-for-today-october-27-2025">Wordle Hints For Today, October 27, 2025</h2>



<p>The Wordle answer for game #1591 ups the difficulty from Sunday’s puzzle. According to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/26/crosswords/wordle-review-1591.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NY Times Wordle</a> review, today’s answer takes an average of 4.6 guesses out of 6 to get. That means it’s the same as the 4.2-guess average on October 26.</p>



<h3 id="h-general-wordle-hints-for-october-27">General Wordle Hints For October 27</h3>



<p>Without giving today’s Wordle answer completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> The word contains <strong>two different vowels</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> It <strong>starts with F</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong> It describes something <strong>unpleasant to the nose</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 4:</strong> It means <strong>foul-smelling</strong>. Think rotten or rancid.</li>
</ul>



<p>Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving <strong>Wordle #1591 for October 27, 2025</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-starter-words-for-october-27-2025">Starter Words For October 27, 2025</h3>



<p>If you want help getting started without having today’s Wordle answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you figure out some included letters. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul>
<li>DEFTS</li>



<li>FIRED</li>



<li>TIDED</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1591-on-october-27-2025">Today’s Wordle Answer For Game #1591 On October 27, 2025</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answer to today’s Wordle below.</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> FETID</p>



<p>If you solved today’s Wordle without our answer, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-yesterday-s-wordle-answer">Yesterday’s Wordle Answer</h2>



<p>If you missed the previous game, here’s yesterday’s Wordle answer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1590-hints-answer-october-26-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game #1590 on October 26, 2025</a>:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> PLUMP</p>



<p>While not always the case, looking at previous words can sometimes give you insight into common patterns or letter usage in Wordle puzzles. Reminder, you can check out every past Wordle answer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our official archive</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-wordle-game-after-1591">When Is The Next Wordle Game After #1591?</h2>



<p>Wordle games are <strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before to give players a heads up. The game on <strong>October 28</strong> will be <strong>Wordle Game #1592</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-wordle">What Is Wordle?</h2>



<p>Wordle is a daily word puzzle created by Josh Wardle. Initially developed as a prototype in 2013, it wasn’t fully released until 2021. The game tasks players with guessing a five-letter word in six tries or fewer, using hints from each attempt to narrow down the answer. Its straightforward concept, accessibility, and the thrill of solving a new puzzle each day helped it surge in popularity by late 2021. The success of Wordle inspired numerous spin-offs and social media challenges, leading to its acquisition by The New York Times in early 2022.</p>



<hr>



<p>Need more help with other daily games? Let us know what games you’d like tips and clues for in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1591-hints-answer-october-27-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite x South Park Collab Coming Soon, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-collab-coming-soon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-x-south-park-collab-coming-soon-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1335118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It has been claimed that a Fortnite collaboration is coming with <strong>South Park</strong>, the animated show that has been running since the late 1990s. On social media, a claim emerged alongside a source, with the uploader suggesting that someone <strong>at Paramount </strong>corroborated the leak.</p>



<p>Fans quickly busied themselves imagining how it would work, given that South Park characters are fairly diminutive in stature and stand all of about a few feet tall.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-south-park-coming-to-fortnite">Is South Park Coming to Fortnite?</h2>



<p>On social media, <a href="https://xcancel.com/SamLeakss/status/1982196155606786464" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SamLeakss claimed</a> that South Park is coming to Fortnite in a crossover event.</p>



<p>Far from being the most unlikely thing in the world, players have accepted that this is gospel and have started assembling theories to explain how the collab would work. One user quickly shared an outfit that <strong>might just work</strong>:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Others suggested that Epic Games would be throwing Cartman into a Mech Suit, while others demanded the arrival of Mr. Hanky as a Back Bling item. Those familiar with the South Park universe pointed out that ‘anime versions’ of the characters could be used, but that’s perhaps a little too niche to be a commercial success.</p>



<p>We know nothing beyond the original claim, unfortunately.</p>



<p>In recent Fortnite news, it was revealed that the developers of the Roblox game ‘Steal a Brainrot’ <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steal-a-brainrot-developers-sue-fortnite-copycat/">are trying to sue</a> Fortnite UGC developers who have allegedly ripped off their creation. This is being taken pretty seriously, as Steal a Brainrot has become one of the most popular Roblox games in record time in recent months.</p>



<p>Also, <strong>The Simpsons </strong>are <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-simpsons-springfield-map-coming-crossover/">coming to Fortnite</a> with a themed map.</p>



<p>Do you want to see any particular South Park characters surface in this collaboration with Fortnite? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/40-minutes-wreckreation-gameplay-leak/">Wreckreation gameplay has leaked online</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-collab-coming-soon/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[40 Minutes of Wreckreation Gameplay Leaks Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/40-minutes-wreckreation-gameplay-leak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/40-minutes-of-wreckreation-gameplay-leaks-online.1335115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A recent YouTube video has revealed 40 minutes of gameplay from Wreckreation, the open-world sandbox racer. Eagle-eyed gamers spotted the upload and have been poring over the gameplay, which shows a halfway-decent racer with destruction elements and arcade-like racing mechanics.</p>



<p>Wreckreation is set to drop on October 28, and I’m hoping for a solid day-one patch, as there are more than a few bugs in the gameplay video uploaded by ‘Flotutu’ on YouTube.</p>



<h2 id="h-burnout-in-the-big-2025">Burnout in the Big 2025</h2>



<p>We’ve not seen a new Burnout game for more than 15 years, which feels pretty harrowing. Once upon a time, Burnout offered a high-octane, energetic racing experience punctuated with visceral crashes and takedown systems.</p>



<p>Wreckreation comes <strong>from the creators </strong>of the Burnout series, and it’s an all-new adventure set in a massive open-world map with sandbox mechanics. The game is designed to be pretty open-ended, offering multiplayer gameplay, stacks of customization, and some construction features that allow you to flex your imagination.</p>



<p>Here’s the video featuring the 40 minutes of Wreckreation gameplay that was uploaded recently:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="WRECKREATION🚓 v1.1 Gameplay Découverte FR en 4K sur PS5 🎮 Le Burnout où TU construis tout ! 🏗️" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/taEd4HPhN_w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>As the gameplay unravels, prospective fans will spot a few bugs involving the game’s physics and destruction-based elements. At one point, the player crashes into a truck and glitches inside it, clipping like crazy until the game forces a cutscene.</p>



<p>It’s relatively safe to assume that a day-one patch will drop on October 28 alongside the launch of the game to address some of these lingering issues. That’s the problem with playing a game early; it’s often not representative of the final product.</p>



<p>It looks good enough, though. It’s mostly unlicensed and focuses more on high-speed, arcade action than realism, but that’s what people <strong>want </strong>from former Burnout developers.</p>



<p>Do you think you’ll be investing in Wreckreaction? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spike-pve-mode-2025/">PvE has made Marvel Rivals skyrocket</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/40-minutes-wreckreation-gameplay-leak/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Battle Royale RedSec Will Have Duos and Squads at Launch, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-redsec-duos-squads-launch-claim/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-battle-royale-redsec-will-have-duos-and-squads-at-launch-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1335040/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6 RedSec Battle Royale will only be available in Duos and Squads at launch, one insider claims. Once known as Firestorm, we reported that it has changed its name to RedSec and will be shadow dropping on October 28th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, another story has emerged that may confirm a pretty interesting addition to the mode. While nothing is yet confirmed, the leaker in question has leaked many details about the upcoming mode, including <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-is-battlefield-6s-new-battle-royale-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the name</a> and mode itself.</p>



<h2 id="h-duos-and-squads-are-only-team-options-for-battlefield-6-redsec-claims-insider">Duos and Squads Are Only Team Options for Battlefield 6 RedSec, Claims Insider</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🚨 BF6 BR LAUNCH PLAYLIST 🚨</p><p>EXCLUSIVE: Duos (2) and Squads (4) is currently planned to be the ONLY team sizes available at launch for the Battlefield 6 Battle Royale / RedSec.</p><p>So with 100 player count max thats a total of 25 teams of 4 or 50 teams of 2 in every match of RedSec <a href="https://t.co/Uy2D7vlCUh">pic.twitter.com/Uy2D7vlCUh</a></p></div>— ModernWarzone (@ModernWarzone) <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone/status/1982171308839276707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 25, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In a post from <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone/status/1982171308839276707?t=p0lnGa3QMgZbPQs634JShw&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ModernWarzone</a>, which we reported on yesterday for the name RedSec, they claim that Battlefield 6’s battle royale mode will only be available in Duos and Squads. That means only groups of two and groups of four will be the only formations playable. Fortunately, the insider claims it will only be for launch, so future builds may expand that number. As they point out, the 100 player count could be made of 50 teams of two and/or 25 teams of four.</p>



<p>With 100 players, it’s sure to be quite the spectacle. The popularity of EA’s military shooter <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-biggest-launch-series-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has only grown</a> since its release earlier in October. While the surprise shadow drop isn’t going to be exactly how they may have planned it, it’s no doubt going to hit big. Other titles like Fortnite and Call of Duty have done the genre, so it’s natural that Battlefield is going there. Still, it may be a bit disappointing for some who wish to go in by themselves or with a group of five or more.</p>



<p>What do you think of the Duos/Squads matching in Battlefield 6: RedSec? Do you think it’s true? If so, have you already decided who you’ll venture out with? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Battlefield 6, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-1-patch-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new patch notes</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-datamine-reveals-larger-maps-and-new-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another datamine leak</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-redsec-duos-squads-launch-claim/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Steam Player Count Spikes With New Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spike-pve-mode-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spikes-with-new-mode.1335004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new mode for Marvel Rivals has caused a major player spike on Steam, its highest in a while.</p>



<p>Released in December 2024, the free-to-play multiplayer superhero shooter has been going steady. With the release of Season 4, which added <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-showcases-daredevils-duelist-moves-in-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Daredevil</a> and Angela, the game has seen a decent, stable player base. While not as high as when its first season dropped, touting a 644,269 player count, it still ranks as one of the most popular games on Steam. In any case, earlier this week, the numbers rose quite a bit, heading into numbers only seen for the beginning of a season. Well, a new mode, one fans have been asking for for quite a while, has been added.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-pve-marvel-zombies-mode-almost-doubles-marvel-rivals-usual-player-count">New PvE Marvel Zombies Mode Almost Doubles Marvel Rivals’ Usual Player Count</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2767030/charts/#1w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, earlier this week, Marvel Rivals kept at a usual 75k-80k player count, decreasing from the start of Season 4.5 with Daredevil. However, on October 23rd, the game spiked into the high 120k, almost double what it was the previous day. It continued into yesterday and today. The reason? The addition of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-pve-zombies-mode-arrives-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Zombies PvE mode</a> lets players fight against AI enemies. Based on the comic and new animated series, the limited-time Halloween-based mode brings it to life with droves of zombies and perilous fights with friends. </p>



<p>A quick look at Reddit supports the rise quite well, as many fans have praised the mode a ton. Some, like <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rivals/comments/1oeqvfe/holy_fucking_shit_is_the_marvel_zombies_game_mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Living-Ad102</a>, want it to be a permanent addition to the game. Given that PvE has been asked for since the game’s release, the massive spike isn’t too surprising. If anything, it’s clear that NetEase may want to do more of these events. Either way, if you want in on the fun, best to do it before mid-November while Marvel Zombies lasts. </p>



<p>Have you played the Marvel Zombies mode in Marvel Rivals yet? If so, how is it? Would you like to see PvE added permanently to the base game? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-cross-progression-season-5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the upcoming cross-progression addition</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-marvel-rivals-season-5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 5 details</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-steam-player-count-spike-pve-mode-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#868)—Clues and Answers for Sunday, October 26]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-26-868/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-868-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-sunday-october-26.1334977/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s a sleepy Sunday, but it’s also time to wrap up your week with another round of NYT Connections hints and solutions. Today’s puzzle will be easy for some, including <strong>boxing fans</strong>, but I’ve still provided the best hints around so that you can get things finished as fast as possible, then get on with the rest of your weekend.</p>



<p>Read on to get the full scope of today’s NYT Connections hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-october-26">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (October 26)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #868:</p>



<ul>
<li>BEE</li>



<li>BUTTERFLY</li>



<li>FLOAT</li>



<li>STING</li>



<li>BRASS</li>



<li>PERCUSSION</li>



<li>STRING</li>



<li>WIND</li>



<li>BEAUTY</li>



<li>POPULARITY</li>



<li>STARING</li>



<li>TALENT</li>



<li>DOGGY</li>



<li>DROPLET</li>



<li>KITCHENETTE</li>



<li>STARLING</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think orchestra sections! These are categories of musical instruments</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>These all describe creatures or actions associated with light movement or flight</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>These words relate to qualities often judged or admired in people or performances</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>This group plays with diminutives or cozy-sounding words</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, October 26.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-october-26-868">NYT Connections Answers for Today, October 26 (#868)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– BRASS, PERCUSSION, STRING, WIND</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BEE, BUTTERFLY, FLOAT, STING</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BEAUTY, POPULARITY, STARING, TALENT</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – DOGGY, DROPLET, KITCHENETTE, STARLING</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-26-868/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>