<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:32:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei New Game Plus Date Revealed, Adds New Trophies & Content Replay Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-new-game-plus-date-revealed-adds-new-trophies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-new-game-plus-date-revealed-adds-new-trophies-content-replay-feature.1358065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Sucker Punch has given you all the time to breathe. By now, you’ve probably finished Ghost of Yotei and need a fresh challenge, which is where New Game Plus comes in handy.</p>



<p>New Game Plus is a great way to extend the shelf life of any game. Moreover, it offers new challenges and usually adds extra options and features into the mix for good measure. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-could-make-new-sly-cooper-infamous-game-after-ghost-of-yotei/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei</a>‘s sun isn’t setting anytime soon, and the November inclusion of New Game Plus will be a game-changer.</p>







<h2 id="h-new-game-plus-coming-to-ghost-of-yotei-on-november-24">New Game Plus Coming To Ghost of Yotei On November 24</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Aim true, you’ll need to. Screenshot from PlayStation</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ghost of Yotei is getting New-Game-Plus capabilities from November 24, and this isn’t all.</p>



<p>An official <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/19/new-game-plus-comes-to-ghost-of-yotei-november-24/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Blog</a> revealed more bits, from New Game Plus to new gear and extra PlayStation Trophies. The original <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-trophy-and-achievement-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei trophy list</a> was generous, but now you have an additional two trophies to fight for.</p>



<p>On top of this, New Game Plus behaves as it does in every game: Once you’ve finished the story, you can begin the adventure again from scratch, but your progress rolls over, and there’s a new, harder difficulty setting for the sadistic samurai in all of you.</p>







<p>Here are some other features that will feature in the New Game Plus update:</p>



<ul>
<li>New currency: Ghost Flowers (Used on a new vendor packing many cosmetics).</li>



<li>A new tier of upgrades for armor sets and weapons.</li>



<li>You can replay content from the main game.</li>



<li>New accessibility features, such as button remapping and fresh Photo Mode tweaks.</li>
</ul>



<p>Check out the New Game Plus trailer below, giving you a glimpse into the game’s future.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - New Game+ | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vY8MXfksWuw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Is there an aspect of the Ghost of Yotei New Game Plus update that has you ready? As usual, let us know what it is through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>If you’ve not already, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-best-games-like-ghost-of-yotei/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 Best Games Like Ghost of Yotei You Must Play Once You’re Finished</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-new-game-plus-date-revealed-adds-new-trophies/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>