<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:22:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is The Vampire Diaries Coming To Fortnite? Crossover Rumor, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/vampire-diaries-fortnite/</link>
            <guid>1437775</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Another Fortnite crossover is in the rumor mill, and it’s The Vampire Diaries. The show was a teenage dream with spectacular-looking humans (and vampires), captivating audiences for eight seasons.</p>



<p>It’s conceivable that every franchise in gaming, TV, and movie history could arrive in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/fortnite/" id="46" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite</a>. That said, a The Vampire Diaries crossover would’ve been quite low down the Fortnite crossover list. Let’s see if there’s any bite to the rumor.</p>







<h2 id="h-will-the-vampire-diaries-come-to-fortnite">Will The Vampire Diaries Come To Fortnite?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It couldn’t, could it? Credit to Outerbanks Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>A Fortnite and Vampire Diaries crossover is a rumor and nothing more right now, and it appears to be one source claiming that it’s happening.</strong></p>



<p>It’s incredible how quickly speculation can spread like wildfire. There are many leakers in the world of Fortnite, but even the major ones, for the time being—haven’t outed a The Vampire Diaries and Fortnite crossover.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-season-1-week-11-quests/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1 Week 11 Quests &amp; How To Complete Them (February 12)</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Does this mean it’s not happening? Nope, but the evidence isn’t strong enough to confirm the fascinating collaboration.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-fortnite-amp-the-vampire-diaries-rumor">What Is The Fortnite &amp; The Vampire Diaries Rumor?</h2>



<p><strong>Content creator Incitable posted to Facebook <strong>on February 16</strong> saying: “FORTNITE x VAMPIRE DIARIES is COMING!”</strong></p>



<p>Arguably, the biggest sources for Fortnite rumors and leaks are Shiina and HYPEX, neither of which has said The Vampire Diaries is coming to Fortnite; this could be significant.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-has-a-kingdom-hearts-collab-in-development-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite Has A Kingdom Hearts Collab in Development, It’s Claimed</a></li>
</ul>



<p>HYPEX has even outed lots of upcoming crossover leaks, but it doesn’t mention anything about vampires.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>EXPECTED FORTNITE COLLABS THIS SEASON</p><p>• LUNA &amp; MAGIK → Likely Valentine's Day<br>• HONKAI STAR RAIL → February 26<br>• RESIDENT EVIL REQUIEM → Early March<br>• SOLO LEVELING → Likely Next Update<br>• KERNEL HEARTS → ??<br>• OLIVIA DEAN EMOTE → ??<br>• 1-3 MORE COLLABS → ?? <a href="https://t.co/Bp1lEG058t">pic.twitter.com/Bp1lEG058t</a></p></div>— HYPEX (@HYPEX) <a href="https://twitter.com/HYPEX/status/2020906649301479642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 9, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Incitable says a lot of The Vampire Diaries content is on the way, including Damon Salvatore and Stefan Salvatore skins:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Damon and Stefan Salvatore are officially coming to Fortnite as part of the Fortnitemares update scheduled for Fortnitemares 2026. It was heavily rumored collab, but has seemed to gain traction and it is in the works along with the Twilight collab which many players are hyped for!”</p>
</blockquote>



<figure><figcaption>Nom. Credit to Incitable</figcaption></figure>



<p>The crossover could happen, and it might be confirmed sooner rather than later. Until it is, take the news with a pinch of salt, as no one can confirm if the image is real.</p>



<p>If you know more about The Vampire Diaries coming to Epic’s shooter, please reach out to Insider Gaming. Furthermore, if you want to keep up with the latest IG content or chat with the community, make sure to check out the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For now, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/honkai-star-rail-fortnite-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Honkai: Star Rail and Fortnite</a> collab.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/vampire-diaries-fortnite/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Update Finally Lets You… Jump?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-update-jump/</link>
            <guid>1437751</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ubisoft isn’t finished with Assassin’s Creed Shadows, which dropped last year to a positive reception and a few controversies, particularly those concerning historical inaccuracies. It became a talking point within the Japanese government, amongst other things, which was pretty insane to see.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, February 17, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/ubisoft/" id="26">Ubisoft</a> will release title update 1.1.8 for Assassin’s Creed Shadows, kick-starting a special, limited-time parkour challenge, and adding a feature that many think should have been there the entire time.</p>



<p>Yes, that’s the ability to <strong>jump</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-manual-jump-coming-to-assassin-s-creed-shadows">Manual Jump Coming to Assassin’s Creed Shadows</h2>



<p>Forced automatic parkour will be a thing of the past in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/assassins-creed-shadows/" id="1478">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> with update 1.1.8. Ubisoft is encouraging those still playing the game to participate in a social-driven parkour challenge, creating an unedited shot that they can share to showcase their freerunning abilities in Feudal Japan.</p>



<p>There are prizes up for grabs, but only the cleanest routes will be in with a chance of winning.</p>



<p>To facilitate the challenge, Ubisoft has added <strong>manual jumping </strong>to Assassin’s Creed Shadows. That now means that, at the press of a button, you can <strong>jump</strong>. How’s about that for an update?</p>



<p>If you want to enable manual jumping, you’ll need to hop into <strong>Advanced Options </strong>in the gameplay settings menu and switch the feature <strong>on</strong>. Otherwise, you’ll still be locked in a creative box by automatic parkour.</p>



<p>Elsewhere, Ubisoft is adding a detailed statistics page <strong>and </strong>new ‘visual feedback’ for crit hits landed in combat.</p>



<p>Next month, Claws of Awaji, the game’s major expansion, will be released on Nintendo Switch 2. Then, on March 20, the game’s first anniversary rolls around, and Ubisoft has promised something of a small celebration.</p>



<p>Tomorrow’s update will drop at 14:00 UTC and will measure up to 15.77 GB for Xbox users, and as little as 1.7 GB for PS5 users.</p>







<p>Are you looking forward to making some sweet parkour content in Assassin’s Creed Shadows with <strong>manual jumping? </strong>Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-to-go-offline-in-two-months/">Call of Duty Warzone is going offline</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-update-jump/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K26 MyGM Features Extended Season and New Match Types]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-mygm-features-extended-season-and-new-match-types/</link>
            <guid>1437679</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/wwe-2k26-2/" id="174969">WWE 2K26</a> brings a new MyGM draft format, additional playable GMs, expanded match types, and more, as a deeper level of control takes center stage.</p>



<p>WWE 2K has released a new <a href="https://wwe.2k.com/2k26/ringside-report/mygm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ringside Report, </a>giving players an in-depth look at the changes coming to the popular game mode. Major changes include more match types for players to select, a longer season mode than ever before, and new choices for the authority figure on your show.</p>







<h2 id="h-default-seasons-are-now-50-weeks-in-wwe-2k26-mygm">Default Seasons Are Now 50 Weeks in WWE 2K26 MyGM</h2>



<p>WWE 2K26 features 50-week seasons by default in MyGM. Also, starting budgets have increased and now range from $3 million to $7 million. Everyone’s budget is $5 million by default. </p>



<p>It is expected that higher budgets will increase the average roster size per brand by up to 35 Superstars. There’s also a new difficulty setting, Immortal, for experienced players looking for a new challenge.</p>







<h2 id="h-players-can-choose-to-double-book-stars">Players Can Choose to Double-Book Stars</h2>



<p>Another new feature is the ability to double-book wrestlers in both promos and matches on a single show. This means players will need to manage their roster members’ stamina more closely and pay closer attention to the show’s format, but it adds more realism.</p>



<p>Speaking of promos, invasion promises are new to WWE 2K26. Players can now send a star to attack the opposing brand when playing against friends. A good promo will earn you fans; a bad promo will make your brand look bad and could cost you fans.</p>



<p>As for match types, players can now book wrestlers for a variety of options, including the new 3 Stages of Hell. There’s also now support for 5-way, 6-way, and 8-way matches.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-legendary-gms-are-added-in-this-year-s-game">New Legendary GMs Are Added in This Year’s Game</h2>



<p>This year, MyGM Mode added new playable general managers, including the legendary Bobby “The Brain” Heenan, Stacy Keibler, and the Anonymous General Manager from 2011. They join Eric Bischoff, Adam Pearce, Mick Foley, and Ava.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you excited to play through MyGM Mode in WWE 2K26? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-mygm-features-extended-season-and-new-match-types/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#982)—Answers for Tuesday, February 17]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-17-982/</link>
            <guid>1437625</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>How has your week started? Let’s hope you’re on a high note and the rest of the week is looking great. We’ve got another batch of NYT Connections hints and solutions for you to dig into below. If you want to finish today’s puzzle as quickly as possible, look no further than this guide.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections answers for today’s puzzle – just scroll down!</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-play-nyt-connections">How to Play NYT Connections</h2>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing lineup of the New York Times titles. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on desktop devices or in</span> a mobile app.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words can have double meanings, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty, from least to most.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-february-17">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (February 17)</h2>



<p>Here are the words from today’s NYT Connections puzzle:</p>



<ul>
<li>PLUM</li>



<li>LEAF</li>



<li>FLASH</li>



<li>BUSTLE</li>



<li>THUMB</li>



<li>OYSTER</li>



<li>FLOPPY</li>



<li>ZIP</li>



<li>SKIM</li>



<li>SOY</li>



<li>DART</li>



<li>BOMBAY</li>



<li>SPEED</li>



<li>FLIP</li>



<li>HOISIN</li>



<li>MISSUS</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– Ways to describe moving quickly</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – Words that you might associate with Chinese food</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> –<em> </em>Words to describe flipping through a book</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – Look at the first half of the word for ways to fail</li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, February 17:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-february-17-982">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, February 17 (#982)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– DART, FLASH, SPEED, ZIP</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – HOISIN, OYSTER, PLUM, SOY</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – FLIP, LEAF, SKIM, THUMB</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BOMBAY, BUSTLE, FLOPPY, MISSUS</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-17-982/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile to Go Offline in Two Months]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-to-go-offline-in-two-months/</link>
            <guid>1437607</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/activision/" id="190">Activision </a>is sunsetting Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile.</p>



<p>Activision has announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/games/call-of-duty/" id="3373">Call of Duty</a>: Warzone Mobile’s servers will go offline on April 17, two months from now. The game was officially removed from stores in May 2025 following several service changes, including an end to delivering new seasonal content and gameplay updates.</p>



<p>The final step is underway, and the game will go offline on April 17. In a statement, Activision thanked players for their passion and feedback.</p>



<p>“We are deeply grateful to the community that supported Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile and to the developers who brought the experience to life. Player passion and feedback continue to shape the future of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/call-of-duty/" id="32">Call of Duty®</a> franchise, and we look forward to delivering meaningful seasonal content and updates to Call of Duty: Mobile,” they stated.</p>







<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-existed-for-2-years">Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile Existed For 2 Years</h2>



<p>Warzone Mobile went live on March 21, 2024. Players currently have Call of Duty: Mobile as their mobile experience.</p>



<p>Call of Duty: Mobile recently launched its first season, titled “Frozen Abyss.” The season, which launched on January 14, boasts new rewards earned across a variety of events, including a Street Fighter-themed event. </p>







<p>Call of Duty: Mobile also features a Battle Royale mode, giving Warzone Mobile players access to a beloved feature. There’s also Zombies, Multiplayer, and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>Do you have any fond memories of Warzone Mobile? Do you currently play the standard version of Call of Duty: Mobile? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-to-go-offline-in-two-months/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>