<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:29:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playground Games’ Founder on Preserving Fable’s True Spirit]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playground-games-founder-on-preserving-fables-true-spirit/</link>
            <guid>1413790</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Playground Games’ Ralph Fulton spoke about the origins of Fable’s return and ensuring the game kept the core spirit of the original series, which debuted a quarter of a century ago.</p>



<p>Fable has returned for the first time since 2018 and is set to release its first mainline game in the franchise in over a decade since Fable 3 in 2010. With Playground Games currently at the helm of the franchise, Fulton can now reflect on how the success of Forza Horizon 3 and the desire to grow as Developers sowed the seeds for Fable’s return. </p>



<p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/weve-been-working-on-this-game-for-a-really-really-long-time-the-big-fable-interview-with-microsoft-developer-playground" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Speaking with IGN, </a>Fulton expanded on what he thinks led to this opportunity for the team of developers.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I think that as a developer, you should always be trying to challenge yourself and expand your skill set. So, that’s where the idea came from. And obviously because we’d been working with Xbox for really since our inception as Playground Games, we had great relationships with them. We knew a lot of people there. The obvious first conversation for us was with them where we said, “Hey, look, we’re looking to build a second team. We want to work in a new genre.” We felt like the transferable skills that we had from the Horizon games were an open world. We had learned a lot about building open worlds technically in terms of streaming, in terms of game design and game flow and all that good stuff. And in lots of ways that are maybe surprisingly car-agnostic. There’s a ton of things about Horizon games that are about the cars, but there’s a ton of principles that we’d learned there, which we felt were transferable. And I don’t remember who said the word Fable first, but as soon as I heard it, I was like, “That has to be it. That fits so perfectly.” It’s a series that we adored here and still do.</p>
</blockquote>







<h2 id="h-playground-wanted-to-make-sure-fable-maintained-its-core-elements-including-its-britishness">Playground Wanted to Make Sure Fable Maintained Its Core Elements, Including Its Britishness</h2>



<p>When rebooting such a beloved franchise from the ground up, the team at Playground wanted to ensure certain core elements remained intact. Ralph Fulton says the three pillars of Fable games they landed on were “Freedom,” “Fairytale,” and “Britishness.” For developers, these three pillars formed the core of Fable’s DNA.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We actually wrap that up into the word “freedom” because it’s about the freedom to choose, the freedom to make the choices and then have to live with the consequences of your choices. It’s the freedom to go where you want, do what you want, be the hero you want to be. And that right there is at the heart of our game. We want you to be the hero you want to be. So, freedom is absolutely central to it.</p>



<p>We landed on two other tonal pillars, I think. And the first is fairytale. And we actually inherited this from Lionhead. We had this treasure trove of documents which had been in storage, that came originally from Lionhead. And one of them had this incredibly neat little bit of direction, which was Fable is a fairytale, not fantasy, which I just think is brilliant, incredibly incisive and speaks to really tonally what Fable is…</p>



<p>Finally, it’s about Britishness. And again, why was it important to Xbox that a British studio continued with Fable? Because Fable is this quintessentially British game, and not just because Albion is medieval Britain through a filter, if you like. And not just because the characters are British and have British accents. There’s a sensibility to the games, there’s a tone of voice, a way of thinking about things, a way of reacting to things. It’s very British. And those things combined are for us the DNA of Fable. If you don’t hit those things, if you’re not true to those things, you’re not making a Fable game. So, that was something that we decided right at the start.</p>
</blockquote>







<p>For the first time ever, Fable has the freedom to release on PlayStation, and the game will be coming to PlayStation 5 on the same day it’s released on Xbox platforms. Learn more about that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fable-release-window-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>How do you feel about the next game in the beloved series? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/playground-games-founder-on-preserving-fables-true-spirit/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Human Cost: Ubisoft’s Next Cost-Cutting Measure Could See Another 2000+ Jobs Lost]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-human-cost-ubisofts-next-cost-cutting-measure-could-see-another-2000-jobs-lost/</link>
            <guid>1413652</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Yesterday’s Ubisoft announcement of its massive restructuring has made headlines across the industry for cancelling projects, closing down studios, and delaying projects, but one of the biggest announcements, for the most part, has been overlooked by many.</p>







<p>I am, of course, talking about the human impact of the recent restructuring and recently announced cost-cutting measures aimed to save the publisher an additional 200 million euros by the end of March 2028, which could result in thousands of more developers losing their jobs.</p>



<p>According to Ubisoft, this will be the “third and final phase” of its cost-cutting, and will end by March 2028. Ubisoft is still going through its second phase, which started four years ago and was a 300 million euro cost-cutting measure.</p>



<p>In that time, Ubisoft has decreased its headcount from 20,729 (as of September 2022) to 17,097 (as of September 2025), a reduction of 3632 developers. Ubisoft London, Osaka, San Francisco, Leamington, Halifax, and Stockholm have all closed their doors. More layoffs at the company will also be announced on February 12, 2026.</p>



<p>It doesn’t take a genius, then, to see that an additional 200 million euros in cost-cutting will lead to yet more studio closures and layoffs. Ubisoft’s third cost-cutting measure will be two-thirds of the second round, so with that round seeing 3632 jobs lost and using similar proportions, we can calculate that the next round could see approximately 2400 jobs lost by the end of March 2028.</p>



<p>On top of that, Ubisoft is set to enforce a return-to-office mandate of 5 days a week, while offering “annual allowances” for working from home. It’s a move that Ubisoft says will help with “efficiency, creativity, and collective success,” but many developers see it as another attempt to force yet more employees to leave the company as part of cost savings.</p>







<p>It’s part of Ubisoft’s strategy to prevent announcing mass layoffs (for the most part) to avoid negative press. Over the last few years, Ubisoft has continued to reduce its headcount through similar ploys, including not renewing contracts, giving developers nothing to do in the hopes they’ll leave, and enforcing RTO mandates.</p>



<h2 id="h-a-bigger-change-is-needed">A Bigger Change is Needed</h2>



<p>Ubisoft has been on a downward trend for a number of years (despite having a great future pipeline of games), but the constant mismanagement, structural changes, and lack of ownership from higher-ups have led to one of the most horrible environments for developers to work in in the games industry.</p>



<p>How are developers meant to get excited about their work and be productive and creative when they know thousands more of their colleagues will likely be gone in the next couple of years? When the same mistakes from leadership continue to happen year after year without accountability? When another restructuring and more cost-cutting measures will happen in the coming years?</p>



<p>It’s pretty evident that Ubisoft’s big restructuring needs to happen from the top and not the other way around.</p>



<p>We all know what needs to happen, but stubbornness is worse than witchcraft.</p>



<hr>



<p>Both current and former employees can contact me securely and anonymously at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection" data-cfemail="8df9e2e0f9e2e0e5e8e3e9e8fffee2e3cdfdffe2f9e2e3e0ece4e1a3eee2e0">[email&nbsp;protected]</a> if you would like to weigh in on current events, or share your story.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-beyond-good-evil-2-survives-ubisofts-project-purge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 surviving</a>&nbsp;the announced restructuring at Ubisoft. And for more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>










        <div>
                  <p>
                    Tom Henderson is Insider Gaming's Co-Founder and Editor-In-Chief. When he's not running one of the industry's leading independent video game websites, he's probably playing an FPS like Call of Duty,…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/tomhenderson/">
                    More from Tom Henderson                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-human-cost-ubisofts-next-cost-cutting-measure-could-see-another-2000-jobs-lost/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>