<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 04:57:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surgent Studios Unveils Tales of Kenzera: Project Uso]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/surgent-tales-of-kenzera-uso/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/surgent-studios-unveils-tales-of-kenzera-project-uso.1018881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/surgent-tales-of-kenzera-uso/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Surgent Studios, the creator behind Tales of Kenzera: ZAU, has unveiled Project Uso, the next game in the multimedia universe pioneered by the creative mind of Abubakar Salim. In a release issued by Surgent today, it was confirmed that Project Uso will be ‘darker and more visceral than our debut game.’</p>



<p>It’s a return to Kenzera but in a completely alternate aesthetic. Project Uso will be centred around a ‘vampiric android’ that’s designed to house the spirits of the deceased. It’s set to be a crossover between a choice-driven RPG and an ‘electrifying’ beat-em-up.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-next-chapter">The Next Chapter</h2>



<p>Recently, Surgent Studios was in the news following the revelation that the games branch of the firm had been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/surgent-studios-game-division-redundancies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">put on notice of potential redundancy</a>. This news came amid financial struggles and a lack of funding for future projects – including Project Uso.</p>



<p>The press release published by Surgent Studios to mark the announcement of Project Uso bore that message:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Surgent Studios has developed a fully-functional prototype of PROJECT USO and is actively seeking a partner to bring it to life.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In a statement attached to the press release, Surgent’s founder, Abubakar Salim, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Project Uso is set to be darker and more visceral than our debut game. Where ZAU is about dealing with death in a healthy way, USO is about letting your fear of death consume you. Inspiration struck following the birth of my daughter, when I grappled with a crisis of identity as I took on the role of parent for the first time.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Similarly, the concept for Tales of Kenzera: ZAU came about when Salim was wrestling with the untimely loss of his father and trying desperately to figure out how to cope with the grief that followed.</p>



<p>In Uso, players will assume control of a unique RPG system created by Surgent. They’ll have ‘the powers of an android and a god at their disposal’, given that the protagonist houses the spirit of Eshu, ‘the god of chaos’. </p>



<p>At first blush, it sounds a little deeper than ZAU in terms of gameplay mechanics, and the choice-based features should add a little more variety and replayability, whereas ZAU was much more linear and one-track. Project Uso is also set ‘decades’ after ZAU, so the world is much more advanced.</p>



<p>Here’s hoping Surgent manages to find a partner to help produce Project Uso.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-update-devlog/">our breakdown of Gray Zone Warfare’s next major update</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>