<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:35:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive – Maximum Football Gameplay “Further Along” Than Expected]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-gameplay-further-along-than-expected/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-%E2%80%93-maximum-football-gameplay-%E2%80%9Cfurther-along%E2%80%9D-than-expected.1025499/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-gameplay-further-along-than-expected/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Maximum Football heads to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1691280/Maximum_Football/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Early Access on Steam</a> on November 7, and the game’s director is happy where the gameplay stands as it gets set to launch.</p>



<p>In an exclusive upcoming interview with Insider Gaming, Maximum Games Game Director Micah Brown says that the gameplay is even further along than what he expected at this point.</p>



<p>“I’m feeling really good,” Brown said about the state of things as the game heads to early access. “The gameplay is where we want it to be. It’s further along than I thought it would be.</p>



<p>“Honestly, it plays very, very well. It’s very, very smooth.”</p>



<p>Brown did say that there are still some animations that are being smoothed out, with some coming after launch. However, as a whole, the game is playing exactly how they want it to be at this point in development.</p>



<p>“The multiplayer we’ve been testing is working well,” he continued. “The customization is absolutely amazing and the gameplay is running very well. So I’m really excited. I can’t wait till we launch and see what everybody says.</p>



<p>“It’s going to be wild.”</p>



<p>Brown’s comments on gameplay come as part of a nearly 30-minute sit down talking Maximum Football. Other topics in the upcoming interview include the game’s pricing structure, plans surrounding future updates, encouraging players to try the game, and much more.</p>



<p>When it releases in early access, the base game of Maximum Football will be free for all players. Those who wish access to more modes and options can upgrade to either the Dynasty Edition for $19.99 or the Legend Edition for $39.99.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for the full interview here at Insider Gaming, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">on our YouTube channel</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the latest updates surrounding the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-gives-update-on-all-of-its-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">games in development at Remedy Entertainment</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘There is No Place on Twitch For Hatred’, Says CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/no-place-on-twitch-hatred-ceo-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98there-is-no-place-on-twitch-for-hatred%E2%80%99-says-ceo.1025364/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/no-place-on-twitch-hatred-ceo-says/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Twitch, a platform known for high levels of toxicity and scandal, is not a place for hatred of any kind, CEO Dan Clancy has insisted. In a recent blog post discussing updates to the platform’s community guidelines, the somewhat eccentric CEO stated that ‘Twitch is, and always will be, about belonging.’</p>



<p>In the last few months, Twitch has made several community-led changes to the platform’s guidelines, many of which have been well received by the wider audience. However, it’s a drop in the ocean when lined up against years of issues, struggles with hate raids and bot behaviour, and questionable content making it to the platform.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-we-work-hard">‘We Work Hard’</h2>



<p>Dan Clancy was fiercely outspoken against hatred in all forms in <a href="https://blog.twitch.tv/en/2024/11/01/hate-and-harassment-have-no-place-on-twitch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a recent blog post on Twitch</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Over the past few weeks, we’ve seen members of the community voice concerns about how we handle potentially harmful content. There is no place on Twitch for racism, hatred, or harassment of any kind, including antisemitism and Islamophobia.</p>



<p>Twitch is, and will always be, about belonging. Each day, people come together on our service to build communities around shared interests, and to express themselves authentically. For this to be possible, we work hard to ensure that our community is a safe place.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He went on to say that <strong>some content </strong>might seem objectable to members of that worldwide community, but regardless, it’s allowed on the platform. In recent weeks, Twitch landed in hot water for ‘permitting’ Frogan, an inflammatory streamer, to wish death and suffering on soldiers in the US military.</p>



<p>This partnered Twitch streamer eventually landed a 30-day ban, but for some, that wasn’t even close to being enough. </p>



<p>For years, Twitch has been in a to-and-fro battle with what’s permitted on the site and what’s considered ‘bannable’. From hot tub streamers to those glorifying bullying and hateful behaviour, the site has edged into the realms of being a toxic cesspool at times.</p>



<p>Clancy is adamant that things are still changing for the better:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We’re grateful for the feedback and input from our community. Our safety approach continues to build and evolve, as our service grows. We want to ensure that anyone can find their place on Twitch, and remain committed to ensuring that hate and harassment have no place here.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Do you think Twitch is improving in terms of toxicity and hateful content? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-pc-enhanced-edition-changes/">GTA Online is getting an enhanced edition boost</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>