<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:10:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shuhei Yoshida Says Japan Studio Was Closed Because PlayStation “Didn’t Want AA Games”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shuhei-yoshida-says-japan-studio-was-closed-because-playstation-didnt-want-aa-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shuhei-yoshida-says-japan-studio-was-closed-because-playstation-%E2%80%9Cdidn%E2%80%99t-want-aa-games%E2%80%9D.1147653/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shuhei-yoshida-says-japan-studio-was-closed-because-playstation-didnt-want-aa-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It’s been a long time since many fan-favorite PlayStation franchises have been seen. This has a lot to do with Japan Studio’s closure in 2021 and Shuhei Yoshida’s departure as president of SIE Worldwide Studios.</p>



<p>Sony is fixated on delivering high-energy, big-time blockbuster games for PlayStation owners. Examples of this strategy include <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">God of War</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/guerrilla-games-1-million-players-horizon-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Horizon</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-release-ghost-of-tsushima-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Tsushima (and Ghost of Yotei)</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-showrunners-address-spores-returning-for-season-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Last of Us</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/yuri-lowenthal-spider-man-3-claim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spider-Man</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/returnal-developer-housemarque-teases-mystery-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Returnal</a>. However, it means a less-driven approach toward AA game development.</p>



<p>The gap between indie titles and AAA giants is larger than ever, and part of this is due to Shuhei Yoshida stepping down as SIE Worldwide Studios’ president, which in turn caused Japan Studio to close.</p>



<h2 id="h-sony-playstation-no-longer-wanted-aa-games-on-ps4-or-ps5">Sony PlayStation No Longer Wanted AA Games on PS4 or PS5</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The studio had a Knack for games. Credit to Japan Studio</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a translated interview with <a href="https://av.watch.impress.co.jp/docs/series/rt/2001799.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">AV Watch</a>, Yoshida explained: “I was in charge of the first party, so I was asked to make a game that was powerful enough to sell hardware. When you make something like that, the company pushes you a lot. The company wanted such things, and while we had to make them, the scale of development and the sales required were getting bigger and bigger.”</p>



<p>He added that company creators were coming up with great ideas, and while they were “very creative and interesting,” they were ultimately deemed AA. He said that “Japan Studio ceased to exist” soon after he stepped down as president—an event brought on by PlayStation’s corporate restructuring.</p>



<p>“At that time, the JAPAN studio was a team that was good at making AA, and it was a studio. In that case, it probably doesn’t match what the company and first party are looking for,” explained Yoshida.</p>



<p>Japan Studio was part of the most lauded titles in PlayStation’s catalog: Everybody’s Golf, Ape Escape, LocoRoco, Knack, Patapon, Gravity Rush, and many more. While other studios might pick up these franchises—like Bandai Namco has done with the new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-everybodys-golf-hot-shots-announced-releases-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Everybody’s Golf Hot Shots</a> title—some of these games are now consigned to history.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo May Have Accidentally Revealed ‘Switch 2 Edition’ Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-edition-games-accidentally-reveal-leak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-may-have-accidentally-revealed-%E2%80%98switch-2-edition%E2%80%99-games.1147545/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-edition-games-accidentally-reveal-leak/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Nintendo has been dominating the news over the last couple of days on account of the impending Nintendo Switch 2 Direct and the recent (and final) Switch Direct. There is a stacked deck of games on the horizon, and the new hardware release is imminent, filling fans worldwide with a sense of anticipation.</p>



<p>Recently, eagle-eyed fans discovered a reference to something that’s yet to be covered by Nintendo, and that’s ‘Switch 2 Edition’ games. The reference was found on an official Nintendo site, and it immediately makes us think that remasters and re-releases are inbound.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-enhance-it">Enhance It</h2>



<p>On <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/virtual-game-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a new Nintendo page</a> hosted to explain how the new ‘virtual game cards’ will work, the term <strong>Switch 2 Edition games </strong>was coined. It was written in a legal disclaimer tucked away at the bottom of the page, but that’s enough for speculation to be running rampant:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Compatible systems must be linked to a Nintendo Account to use virtual game cards. Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive games <strong>and Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games</strong> can only be loaded on a Nintendo Switch 2 system. To move virtual game cards between two systems, you must pair the systems via local wireless and an internet connection, but only when pairing the systems for the first time. Up to two systems total can be linked per Nintendo Account.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://www.dualshockers.com/nintendo-legal-fine-print-leaks-switch-2-edition-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dualshockers</a> for the spot)</em></p>



<p>Differentiating between <strong>exclusive </strong>Switch 2 games and Switch 2 <strong>Edition </strong>games is enough to get me envisioning a range of remasters and re-releases, which isn’t a far-fetched concept. The likes of PlayStation and Xbox have done similar things in the past when new generations of hardware have been released.</p>



<p>Everyone’s thoughts now turn to how these Switch 2 Edition games could operate. Will they be free upgrades for those who have already purchased the game on the Nintendo Switch, or will they be paywalled with a fresh price tag and packed with extra features?</p>



<p>It’s hard to tell, but I’m willing to bet it’d be the latter option.</p>



<p>We’ll likely know more on April 2 when the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct takes place.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dog-working-on-unannounced-game-three-years/">Naughty Dog has apparently been working on a secret game for three years</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog Has Been Working on an Unannounced Game For Three Years, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dog-working-on-unannounced-game-three-years/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dog-has-been-working-on-an-unannounced-game-for-three-years-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1147539/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dog-working-on-unannounced-game-three-years/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Naughty Dog was most recently in the news after Neil Druckmann <strong>kind of </strong>suggested that there might not be another Last of Us game. He later expanded on those comments by stressing that he’ll take each project as it comes and that, right now, the team is focused on delivering Intergalactic, an all-new IP.</p>



<p>However, a recent claim from an insider might point to Naughty Dog working on something else <strong>in secret</strong>. Per a recent report, it seems Naughty Dog has a game in the works that has been taking shape for more than three years, and it’s being led by Shaun Escayg, who formerly directed Uncharted: The Lost Legacy.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-are-they-cooking">What Are They Cooking?</h2>



<p>The claim that Naughty Dog is working on an unannounced game that has been in development for three years comes from <a href="https://x.com/DanielRPK" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DanielRPK</a>. The report was posted on their Patreon (paywalled) and since shared more publicly by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/naughty-dog-new-unannounced-game-uncharted-director-shaun-escayg-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>. It reads:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Naughty Dog has a second project (not The Last of Us III), directed by Shaun Escayg. It’s been in development for three years now.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Naughty Dog’s Neil Druckmann explained after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/not-another-last-of-us-game-druckmann-ambiguous-suggest/">his ‘don’t bet on it’ comments</a> that even The Last of Us (2013) felt so definitive that he didn’t foresee making a follow-up title. We may see The Last of Us Part III in the future, but like the man said, it would need ‘the stars to align’ for that to happen.</p>



<p>In the meantime, Naughty Dog is allegedly working on something new and unknown, and it’s being led by someone with strong ties to Uncharted.</p>



<p>The last major Uncharted game was Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End, released back in 2016, and The Lost Legacy surfaced a year later as a standalone DLC. It was a similar operating model employed for The Last of Us and the Left Behind expansion.</p>



<p>It hasn’t been suggested that something related to Uncharted is in development, <strong>but </strong>there were rumours recently regarding a game starring Cassie Drake, Nathan Drake’s daughter in the series. Cassie was played in previous titles by Kaitlyn Dever, who, coincidentally, is still tied to Naughty Dog by way of her role as Abby in the upcoming second series of HBO’s The Last of Us.</p>



<p>What do you think Naughtyt Dog could be working on? Let me know in the comments what you think.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-the-labyrinth-map/">Tarkov’s players have found a new secret map</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>