<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:52:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tim Cain Returns To Obsidian For New Project]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tim-cain-returns-to-obsidian-for-new-project/</link>
            <guid>1374400</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Legendary game developer Tim Cain has returned to the gaming industry spotlight to team up with Obsidian Entertainment once again, and they’ve confirmed that they’re working on a new game already.</p>



<p>If you didn’t know, Tim Cain helped mastermind the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todd-howard-revealed-what-makes-fallout-special/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fallout</a> franchise and co-directed The Outer Worlds, amongst other work. The developer semi-retired several years ago, but has announced that he’s back into the swing of things with Obsidian, and is developing a mystery game.</p>







<h2 id="h-tim-cain-working-on-new-obsidian-entertainment-project-that-no-one-will-guess">Tim Cain Working On New Obsidian Entertainment Project That No One Will Guess</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Back again. Credit to Obsidian</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a December 5 ‘Cain On Games Update’ on his YouTube channel, Cain discussed what was happening in his life regarding game development and the next steps:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I’m back at Obsidian. I’m there, full-time employee, and in person. So not remote. I’m not a contractor anymore.”</p>
</blockquote>







<p>Cain explained that while he will have his name attached to at least one other game coming up—due to his relaxed contractor status in recent times—he is now firmly on Obsidian’s books. Cain explained that he’s not at liberty to discuss the new project, and it gives more questions than it does answers:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I also can’t talk about the project I’m working on at Obsidian, just because that’s covered under NDA. Don’t bother guessing, you’re not gonna guess right.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Cain explains that he’s “A lot less retired now,” and this new game will likely be the center of his focus moving forward.</p>



<p>Here’s the full video and everything said by Cain about the life change.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cain On Games Update" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kCVWRZqyroA?start=173&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The Outer Worlds and The Outer Worlds 2 have been the two main games Cain has worked on in the last 10 years. It’ll be interesting to see what the new title is, but it’s hard to imagine it’s not something to do with an RPG!</p>



<p>What do you think Cain is working on? Is it an old IP being brought back to life? Or is Obsidian cooking up yet another franchise? Head over to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> and start your conspiracy theories.</p>



<hr>



<p>Also, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netflix-set-to-buy-warner-bros-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Netflix Set To Buy Warner Bros In 2026</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cast-outs-reveal-trailer-drops-features-developers-from-closed-sony-london-studio-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cast Outs Reveal Trailer Drop</a> for more hot gaming news.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tim-cain-returns-to-obsidian-for-new-project/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Running With Scissors Cancels Postal: Bullet Paradise Within A Day]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/running-with-scissors-cancels-postal-bullet-paradise-within-a-day/</link>
            <guid>1374307</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Running With Scissors has canceled its upcoming game Postal: Bullet Paradise roughly 24 hours after it was revealed. </p>



<p>On December 3, the publisher announced the new “bullet-heaven shooter” from developer Goonswarm Games. After the reveal trailer went live, fan feedback was negative, with claims that it used a number of AI-generated assets. </p>



<p>That quickly led to a decision to pull the plug on the game just over a day after it was announced.</p>



<p>In a statement provided to press and shared online, Running With Scissors founder Vince Desi says that the decisions comes after being <strong>“overwhelmed with negative responses”</strong> from fans of the series.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>After revealing&nbsp;POSTAL: Bullet Paradise, a title Running With Scissors was planning on publishing but not developing, we’ve been overwhelmed with negative responses from our concerned&nbsp;POSTAL&nbsp;Community. The strong feedback from them is that elements of the game are very likely AI-generated and thus has caused extreme damage to our brand and our company reputation.</p>



<p>We’ve always been, and will always be, transparent with our community. Our trust in the development team is broken; therefore, we’ve killed the project. We have a lot of good things coming (some you know and some you don’t).</p>



<p>Since forming Running With Scissors in 1996, we’ve always said that our fans are part of the team. Our priority is to always do right by the millions who support the&nbsp;POSTAL&nbsp;franchise. We are grateful for the opportunity to make the games we want to play, and will continue to focus on our new projects and updates coming in 2026 and beyond.  We can’t wait to share more! </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Currently, Running With Scissors is working on a remake of 2003’s Postal 2, called Postal 2 Redux. The studio ran a Kickstarter for the game, which raised $638,574 against a target goal of just $250,000. It’s the second remake in the franchise after Postal Redux was released back in 2016. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming has attempted to contact Goonswarm Games, but no response has been received. Should that happen, it will be added to this story and shared on Insider Gaming’s social media channels.</p>



<p>You can check out the trailer for Postal: Bullet Paradise for yourself, below. And leave your thoughts on this whole situation down in the comments or in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="POSTAL: Bullet Paradise | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/515aI5lr-ec?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out everything that was announced during&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-show-most-wanted-everything-announced/">Thursday’s PC Gaming Show: Most Wanted</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/running-with-scissors-cancels-postal-bullet-paradise-within-a-day/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>