<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 16:55:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Accused Of Using Gaza War Photos For Battlefield 2025 Artwork]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ea-accused-of-using-gaza-war-photos-for-battlefield-2025-artwork/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-accused-of-using-gaza-war-photos-for-battlefield-2025-artwork.1087047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ea-accused-of-using-gaza-war-photos-for-battlefield-2025-artwork/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-84719">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>EA and DICE have been accused of using photos from the war in Gaza in artwork for Battlefield 2025. </p>



<p>Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/emadalden_/status/1881045891009929516" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">EmadAlden</a> spotted the similarity when looking at the promotional artwork. Another user, <a href="https://x.com/DANNYonPC/status/1881050549455659026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DANNYonPC</a>, made the claim that the company is using photos from attacks on Gaza in the imagery. </p>



<p>“Damn, DICE is using pictures from attacks on Gaza in their BF2025 artwork,” the post reads. It then shows the photo in question from a bombing in Gaza dated May 12, 2021 taken by Reuters.</p>



<p>You can see the images yourself below for comparison.</p>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<p>While it’s unlikely it was done with intent or malice, it’s no question a decision that many could view as questionable. Insider Gaming has reached out to multiple contacts at EA for comment on the claims and the usage of real conflict for its artwork. Should a response be received, this story will be updated accordingly. </p>



<p>What do you think of EA and DICE using images that appear to be from the war in Gaza for new Battlefield 2025 artwork? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-and-fallout-4-are-also-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">claims that Starfield and Fallout 4</a> are also coming to Nintendo Switch 2. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-is-working-on-a-new-cipher-series-controller-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-is-working-on-a-new-cipher-series-controller-its-claimed/">Xbox is Working on a New Cipher Series Controller, It’s Claimed&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Xbox is reportedly working on a Red Cipher Wireless controller, which is expected to be announced in January 2025. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours/">Marvel Snap Developer Hopes to be Back Online Within 24 Hours</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Marvel Snap’s developer, Second Dinner, is hoping for the game to return within 24 hours. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/">Marvel Rivals Comic Book Set to Arrive in April 2025</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Marvel is releasing a new comic book based on the events of Marvel Rivals in April 2025. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-and-fallout-4-are-also-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-and-fallout-4-are-also-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">Starfield and Fallout 4 Are Also Coming to Nintendo Switch 2, it’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>An insider has shared several more games making their way to Nintendo Switch 2 later this year.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Look at the Biggest Class Skill Changes in Diablo 4 Season 7]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-look-at-the-biggest-class-skill-changes-in-diablo-4-season-7/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-look-at-the-biggest-class-skill-changes-in-diablo-4-season-7.1087044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/a-look-at-the-biggest-class-skill-changes-in-diablo-4-season-7/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-84717">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Every new season of Diablo IV brings about monumental changes that completely alter the game’s meta. We usually wind up with colossal skill nerfs, pushing one class down the tier list and bumping another up. Well, the Season of Witchcraft proves no different, as we have class updates for each to contend with on release. It’s not all bad, though. My beloved Barbarian is getting a buff!</p>



<h2 id="h-class-skill-buffs-and-nerfs-in-diablo-4-season-of-witchcraft">Class Skill Buffs and Nerfs in Diablo 4 Season of Witchcraft</h2>



<p>If you want to take a gander at the <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/article/24171214/diablo-iv-patch-notes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">full Diablo IV Season of Witchcraft patch notes</a>, well, I certainly won’t stop you. I will warn you, however, that they’re absolutely massive. You’ll scroll for a day and a half to reach the end. But I’m primarily interested in how the class skills change in the season:</p>



<h3 id="h-spiritborn"><strong>Spiritborn</strong></h3>



<p><strong>The Seeker</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Scaling increased from 30% to 40%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Harmonious Seeker</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – The Seeker’s first hit Knocks enemies Down for 4 seconds and the second hit is a guaranteed Critical Strike.</li>



<li>Now – The Seeker’s first hit Knocks Down enemies for 4 seconds. Both its first and second hits are guaranteed to Critically Strike.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-barbarian"><strong>Barbarian</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Hammer of the Ancients</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 80% to 90%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Furious Hammer of the Ancients</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Critical Strike Chance and Damage per 10 Fury increased from 3% to 5%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Whirlwind</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 18% to 22%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Iron Maelstrom</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Damage while Healthy/Injured scaling bonus reduced from 80 to 60%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Prime Iron Maelstrom</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Critical Strike Damage increased from 40% to 50%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Supreme Iron Maelstrom</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Dealing direct damage to an enemy after swapping weapons reduces Iron Maelstrom’s Cooldown by 1 second.</li>



<li>Now – Swapping weapons reduces Iron Maelstrom’s Cooldown by 1 second.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-druid"><strong>Druid</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Lacerate</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Critical Strike Damage scaling bonus reduced from 40 to 30%.</li>



<li>Can now be cancelled when using the skill again.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Raging Shred</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Poisoning damage increased from 30[x] to 150%[x].</li>
</ul>



<h6 id="h-related-when-does-diablo-4-season-7-start-season-of-witchcraft-start-date-and-time">Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-season-7-start-date-and-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">When Does Diablo 4 Season 7 Start? – Season of Witchcraft Start Date and Time</a></h6>



<h3 id="h-necromancer"><strong>Necromancer</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Enhanced Bone Spear</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Bone Spear breaks into 3 bone shards when it is destroyed, dealing 25% damage each.</li>



<li>Now – Bone Spear makes the first enemy hit Vulnerable for 3 seconds and breaks into 3 bone shards when destroyed, dealing 25% damage each.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Supernatural Bone Spear</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Bone Spear makes the first enemy hit Vulnerable for 3 seconds and deals 30% increased Overpower damage.</li>



<li>Now – Bone Spear deals 40% more Overpower damage and restores 5% Maximum Life after Overpowering.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Army of the Dead</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Skeleton Mage and Golem Damage scaling bonus reduced from 80 to 40%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Blood Wave</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Damage scaling reduced from 60% to 30%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Bone Storm</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Critical Strike Damage scaling bonus reduced from 40 to 30%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Supreme Bone Storm</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Your Critical Strike Chance is increased by 20% while Bone Storm is active.</li>



<li>Now – Your Critical Strike Chance and Attack Speed are increased by 20% while Bone Storm is active.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-sorcerer"><strong>Sorcerer</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Ice Shards</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Damage to Frozen enemies increased from 25% to 50%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Mystical Frost Nova</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Frost Nova makes enemies Vulnerable for 4 seconds, increased to 6 seconds against Bosses.</li>



<li>Now – Frost Nova makes enemies Vulnerable and increases the damage they take from you by 15%[x] for 4 seconds, increased to 8 seconds against Bosses.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Shimmering Frost Nova</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Frost Nova grants 3%[+] Dodge Chance per enemy hit for 8 seconds, up to 15[+]. Dodging while this effect is active restores 20 Mana. Hitting a Boss with Frost Nova grants the maximum Dodge Chance Bonus.</li>



<li>Now – Casting Frost Nova grants 15%[+] Dodge Chance for 8 seconds and restores 10% of your Missing Mana for every enemy hit. Hitting a Boss with Frost Nova restores 100% of your Mana.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Invoked Ice Blades</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Your Ice Blades gain 10% Attack Speed per active Ice Blade.</li>



<li>Now – You and your Ice Blades gain 10% Attack Speed per active Ice Blade.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Deep Freeze</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – Encase yourself in ice, becoming Immune for 4 seconds, continually dealing damage, and Chilling enemies for 14%. When Deep Freeze expires, it deals an additional 183% damage.</li>



<li>Now – Encase yourself in ice and become Immune for 4 seconds, Chilling surrounding enemies for 14% and continuously dealing damage to them. When Deep Freeze ends, you explode for 183% more damage.</li>



<li>Additionally, the final explosion will now happen no matter how Deep Freeze ends.</li>



<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Vulnerable Damage scaling bonus reduced from 40 to 30%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Supreme Deep Freeze</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Previous – When Deep Freeze ends, surrounding enemies are made Vulnerable for 5 seconds and your Non-Ultimate Cooldowns are instantly reset.</li>



<li>Now – Deep Freeze’s initial hit makes surrounding enemies Vulnerable for 5 seconds. After it ends, your Non-Ultimate Cooldowns are instantly reset and your Frost Skills deal 25% increased damage for 5 seconds.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Inferno</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus
<ul>
<li>Previous – Enemies within Inferno are Vulnerable.</li>



<li>Now – Enemies within Inferno are continually made Vulnerable for 5 seconds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-rogue"><strong>Rogue</strong></h3>



<p><strong>Disciplined Dance of Knives</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Pierce chance increased from 20% to 35%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Supreme Death Trap</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Damage to enemies who resist its Pull In increased from 120% to 180% of its damage.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Shadow Step</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Cleave area increased when using Shadow Step Cleaves Tempering affix.</li>



<li>Radius increased by 15%.</li>



<li>Angle increased by 33%.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Rain of Arrows</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rank 5 Bonus: Damage to Distant Enemies scaling bonus reduced from 100 to 80%.</li>
</ul>



<p>Which class do you intend to play first in Diablo 4 Season of Witchcraft? Let us know in the comments, or start a discussion on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Can this new season of Diablo 4 elevate the ARPG to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top most-played games on Steam</a> alongside its competitor, Path of Exile 2?</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-season-7-start-date-and-time/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-season-7-start-date-and-time/">When Does Diablo 4 Season 7 Start? – Season of Witchcraft Start Date and Time</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Here’s what you should know about the Diablo 4 Season 7 start date and time, along with a quick look at what’s new!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam/">What Are the Most Played Games on Steam?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Here’s a look at the most played games on Steam currently, with Counter-Strike 2 leading the charge by a huge sum!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/">You Can Score Free Items With These Dead by Daylight Codes</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It’s always nice getting free items and cosmetics in your favorite game, even if that means it’s a bloody mess, like with these Dead by Daylight codes!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">Avowed Release Date &amp; Platforms</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian’s big year starts with Avowed, and we have its release date, launch time, and every platform you can find the ambitious ARPG.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Does Diablo 4 Season 7 Start? – Season of Witchcraft Start Date and Time]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-season-7-start-date-and-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-does-diablo-4-season-7-start-%E2%80%93-season-of-witchcraft-start-date-and-time.1087026/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-season-7-start-date-and-time/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I’m ready for a grind. I want to lose many hours this week, to forget about the winter storm and all of life’s other challenges rearing their ugly heads daily, and that grind comes from Diablo 4 for the foreseeable future. With the upcoming Diablo 4 Season 7 start date, we’ll dive into Season of Witchcraft, with brand-new powers, new enemies, cosmetics, a battlepass, and some of the best quality-of-life features, like a class quest update and the Armory! Here’s when you can play Diablo 4 Season of Witchcraft!</p>



<h2 id="h-diablo-4-season-of-witchcraft-start-date-and-time-details">Diablo 4 Season of Witchcraft Start Date and Time Details</h2>



<p>By the time this guide goes live, you won’t have to wait long to jump into the new season of Diablo 4. It begins on January 21, early in the day, and everyone should expect some downtime as the servers shut off for the big switch. We’ll likely see a few hiccups at the start, what with so many people jumping into the new content on day one, so be patient!</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>January 21 at 10 AM PST</strong></li>



<li><strong>January 21 at 12 PM CST</strong></li>



<li><strong>January 21 at 6 PM GMT</strong></li>



<li><strong>January 22 at 5 AM JST</strong></li>



<li><strong>January 22 at 5 AM AEDT</strong></li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>







<p>Season of Witchcraft primarily revolves around the Witches of Hawezar, a powerful coven that hunts down heads for the Tree of Whispers to prevent corruption from rapidly spreading across Sanctuary. You’ll help them throughout the seasonal journey, earning new rewards and powers, like the four schools of Witchcraft: Eldritch, Psyche, Growth &amp; Decay, and Psyche.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Schools of Witchcraft: Eldritch, Psyche, Growth &amp; Decay, and Psyche</strong></li>



<li><strong>New Enemy – Headrotten</strong></li>



<li><strong>New Event – Headhunts</strong></li>



<li><strong>Enhanced Whispers</strong></li>



<li><strong>Occult Seasonal Gems</strong></li>



<li><strong>The Armory</strong></li>



<li><strong>QOL Updates</strong></li>



<li><strong>New Uniques &amp; Legendaries</strong></li>



<li><strong>New Runes</strong></li>



<li><strong>Battlepass</strong></li>



<li><strong>New Pet</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>What class do you intend to play first? Let us know in the comments, or start a thread on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Whether this is your first season in the game or you’re a returning player after an extended break, you probably want to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-diablo-4-difficulty-levels/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">know more about the new difficulty levels</a> and how they work!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Are the Most Played Games on Steam?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam.1087005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-most-played-games-on-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-84686">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>2025 is already shaping up to be a massive year in video game releases, what with Assassin’s Creed Shadows, Avowed, Civilization VII, and countless indie titles ranging from boomer shooters to real-time strategy hits. Despite the slew of new releases, many players continue returning to old favorites, like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-beginners-guide-tips-and-tricks-for-new-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Counter-Strike 2</a>, which retains its massive population.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Biggest Video Game Releases of January 2025</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Biggest Video Game Releases of February 2025</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-march-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Biggest Video Game Releases of March 2025</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-the-games-everyone-plays">The Games Everyone Plays</h2>



<p>Sometimes, you don’t know what to play. It happens to all of us. Once we finally have some free time, we sit at our computers, staring at our Steam libraries, with no clue how to proceed. But if you want a multiplayer game with a massive community to immerse yourself in, these games continuously retain players monthly!</p>



<p>It’s important to note that these player numbers change frequently. You’ll find that looking at the charts one minute provides a very different result from within the next five minutes. That said, we can still focus on ballpark numbers to give us an idea of what everyone around the world is playing regularly, as the top most played games on Steam rarely change:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Counter-Strike 2</strong> – 1.4 Million</li>



<li><strong>PUBG: Battlegrounds</strong> – 707,500</li>



<li><strong>Dota 2</strong> – 702,000</li>



<li><strong>Marvel Rivals</strong> – 466,000</li>



<li><strong>Path of Exile 2</strong> – 290,000</li>



<li><strong>Grand Theft Auto V</strong> – 194,000</li>



<li><strong>Naraka: Bladepoint</strong> – 178,000</li>



<li><strong>Rust </strong>– 179,000</li>



<li><strong>Wallpaper Engine</strong> – 134,000</li>



<li><strong>Palworld </strong>– 133,000</li>



<li><strong>Delta Force</strong> – 132,000</li>



<li><strong>Apex Legends</strong> – 125,000</li>



<li><strong>Stardew Valley</strong> 116,000</li>
</ul>



<p>Of the many top games on Steam right now, what are you currently playing? Let us know in the comments below, or visit the General Gaming section of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Speaking of Valve’s digital storefront, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-steam-sale-steam-sale-dates/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when is the next Steam Sale</a>? We’re excited but hiding our wallets because we’ll spend way too much money on games we won’t play this year!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/">You Can Score Free Items With These Dead by Daylight Codes</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It’s always nice getting free items and cosmetics in your favorite game, even if that means it’s a bloody mess, like with these Dead by Daylight codes!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">Avowed Release Date &amp; Platforms</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian’s big year starts with Avowed, and we have its release date, launch time, and every platform you can find the ambitious ARPG.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-throwback-joker-balatro/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-throwback-joker-balatro/">How to Unlock Throwback Joker in Balatro</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Throwback Joker is a high-risk and high-reward card in Balatro, but buying it mid-game could be one of the best things you do.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-tiktok-in-the-app-store/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-tiktok-in-the-app-store/">Is TikTok in the App Store?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>TikTok and the App Store have had a great relationship for years, but is the social media platform no longer downloadable?</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox is Working on a New Cipher Series Controller, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-is-working-on-a-new-cipher-series-controller-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-is-working-on-a-new-cipher-series-controller-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1087002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-is-working-on-a-new-cipher-series-controller-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A reliable leaker has claimed that Xbox is working on a Red Cipher Wireless Controller.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to a report by <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/une-nouvelle-manette-xbox-en-edition-speciale-bientot-disponible-59870" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dealabs</a>, Xbox’s next wireless controller is the Red Cipher, the latest instalment to the Cipher series. Previously, the manufacturers released the Sky Cipher and Ghost Cipher controllers. The Red Cipher announcement is expected to be announced in January 2025 and will be available only through the Microsoft store.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-red-cipher-controller-price-nbsp">Xbox Red Cipher Controller Price&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The exact release date for the Xbox Red Cipher controller is currently unknown. However, the pricing details have been revealed. The upcoming controller is expected to cost the same as the other controllers in the series, €69.99 / $69.99 / GBP 64.99.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Apart from the pricing, we also know the colour palette for the Xbox Red Cipher Controller. The controller will feature a translucent design, similar to the Sky and Ghost instalments. The buttons will be bright red, and the back will be garnet red.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Apart from the red controller, the report also mentioned the Xbox <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-could-be-bringing-haptic-motors-to-xbox-controllers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sebile</a> controller, which was leaked through FTC documents some time ago. The controller is said to feature haptic feedback tech similar to Sony’s DualSense controllers, and <a href="https://tech4gamers.com/microsoft-patents-movable-haptic-controller/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tech4Gamers</a> recently spotted a patent for it. However, no new information has been revealed about the Sebile controller.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-6-xbox-series-s-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ESRB rating suggests</a> that Resident Evil 6 is coming to Xbox Series X/S. Also, a report claims that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-purchase-hasnt-helped-xbox-game-pass-report-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Activision’s purchase hasn’t helped</a> Xbox Game Pass. What are your thoughts on the upcoming Xbox Red Cipher controller?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Snap developer hoping to return online within 24 hours</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Score Free Items With These Dead by Daylight Codes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes.1086972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-score-free-items-with-these-dead-by-daylight-codes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-84672">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>I used to play a lot of Dead by Daylight, with hundreds of hours under my belt, but I wasn’t around when they started going hard into the whole cosmetics and items scene. It seems like the team pumps out content now, with numerous DLCs, character packs, cosmetic outfits, player badges, and charms to customize your killer gameplay. Here are the currently available Dead by Daylight codes to unlock free badges and charms in your game!</p>



<h2 id="h-free-charms-and-badges-with-dead-by-daylight-codes">Free Charms and Badges With Dead by Daylight Codes</h2>



<p>If you’re a fan of customizing your in-game experience with various cosmetics, most of which (hopefully) won’t break the game, including a handful of charms and badges for your player profile, Dead by Daylight has you covered with a wide assortment that is always available. They also have limited-time monthly codes.</p>



<p>The following codes are currently active for January 2025:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>IFLOOKSCOULDCHILL</strong>&nbsp;– Frosty Eyes Killer cosmetics</li>



<li><strong>REDDIT1MIL&nbsp;</strong>– 8-bit Crow badge</li>
</ul>







<p>The following codes for Dead by Daylight will never expire. You can activate them at any time, allowing you to acquire the player badge or charm completely free:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>BDGPRIDE</strong>&nbsp;– Pride player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGPRG</strong>&nbsp;– Progress Pride player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGL</strong>&nbsp;– WLW player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGM</strong>&nbsp;– MLM player badge</li>



<li><strong>KINDRD&nbsp;</strong>– Glance of Pride charm</li>



<li><strong>CAWCAW&nbsp;</strong>–&nbsp;Feathers of Pride charm</li>



<li><strong>PRIDE&nbsp;</strong>–<strong>&nbsp;</strong>Rainbow Flag charm</li>



<li><strong>PRIDE2022&nbsp;</strong>-Progress Pride Flag charm</li>



<li><strong>WARRIORPUPPERS&nbsp;</strong>–&nbsp;Warrior Puppers charm</li>



<li><strong>LETSROLL&nbsp;</strong>–<strong>&nbsp;</strong>Dwight Miniature charm</li>



<li><strong>BDGB</strong>&nbsp;– Bisexual player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGP</strong>&nbsp;– Pansexual player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGT</strong>&nbsp;– Trans player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGGQ</strong>&nbsp;– Genderqueer player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGGF</strong>&nbsp;– Genderfluid player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGNB</strong>&nbsp;– Non-binary player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGIS</strong>&nbsp;– Intersex player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGAG</strong>&nbsp;– Agender player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDG2S</strong>&nbsp;– Two-spirit player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGPA&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;– Polyamory player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGAS</strong>&nbsp;– Asexual player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGAR</strong>&nbsp;– Aromantic player badge</li>



<li><strong>BDGDM</strong>&nbsp;– Demisexual player badge</li>



<li><strong>POLYFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– Polyamory flag charm</li>



<li><strong>DEMISFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– Demisexual flag charm</li>



<li><strong>AROMFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– Aromantic flag charm</li>



<li><strong>TWOSFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– Two-spirit flag charm</li>



<li><strong>FLAGL</strong>&nbsp;– WLW flag charm</li>



<li><strong>MFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– MLM flag charm</li>



<li><strong>FLAGB</strong>&nbsp;– bisexual flag charm</li>



<li><strong>FLAGP</strong>&nbsp;– pansexual flag charm</li>



<li><strong>FLAGT</strong>&nbsp;– transgender flag charm</li>



<li><strong>ISFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– intersex flag charm</li>



<li><strong>AFLAGG</strong>&nbsp;– agender flag charm</li>



<li><strong>GFLAGF</strong>&nbsp;– genderfluid flag charm</li>



<li><strong>NBFLAG</strong>&nbsp;– non-binary flag charm</li>



<li><strong>GFLAGQ</strong>&nbsp;– genderqueer flag charm</li>



<li><strong>AFLAGS</strong>&nbsp;– asexual flag charm</li>
</ul>



<p>Who is your favorite killer in Dead by Daylight? Let us know in the comments below, or just/start the discussion at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Developer Behaviour Interactive is working tirelessly to expand the Dead by Daylight brand with numerous spin-offs and other projects associated with the world. But it’s not all sunshine. The studio’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-by-daylight-spinoff-project-t-cancelled-due-to-poor-reception/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent spinoff, Project T, was canceled following poor reception</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/">Avowed Release Date &amp; Platforms</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian’s big year starts with Avowed, and we have its release date, launch time, and every platform you can find the ambitious ARPG.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-throwback-joker-balatro/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-throwback-joker-balatro/">How to Unlock Throwback Joker in Balatro</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Throwback Joker is a high-risk and high-reward card in Balatro, but buying it mid-game could be one of the best things you do.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-tiktok-in-the-app-store/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-tiktok-in-the-app-store/">Is TikTok in the App Store?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>TikTok and the App Store have had a great relationship for years, but is the social media platform no longer downloadable?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-is-tiktok-back-up-who-brought-it-back-explained/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-is-tiktok-back-up-who-brought-it-back-explained/">Why is TikTok Back Up? Who Brought it Back, Explained</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Social media app TikTok swiftly returned after its temporary ban, but how is it back after it was supposed to be banned in the US?</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Snap Developer Hopes to be Back Online Within 24 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours.1086939/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-developer-hopes-to-be-back-online-within-24-hours/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-84671">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Marvel Snap developers are hard at work getting the game back online, and according to the latest developments, it may return within a day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Marvel Snap was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-taken-down-in-u-s-due-to-governments-tiktok-ban/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">banned</a> along with TikTok yesterday and is currently unavailable to play in the United States. The game was banned because the company that developed TikTok also owns Marvel Snap publisher Nuverse. However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-snap-gets-surprise-us-suspension-as-stateside-tiktok-ban-takes-effect" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a> spotted that the developers of Marvel Snap, Second Dinner recently took it to <a href="https://x.com/seconddinner/status/1881154403333521795" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> to reveal that they have been “working around the clock” to bring the game back and&nbsp;“hope to have it back online within 24 hours.”</p>



<p>Players who are missing out on content while waiting for Marvel Snap to return shouldn’t worry too much. The developers have <a href="https://x.com/seconddinner/status/1881099521310269578" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">assured</a> that they will compensate all players fairly for the lost time. They have also <a href="https://x.com/seconddinner/status/1881135534548107414" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">advised</a> players unable to play Marvel Snap to check out content creators.</p>



<p>Currently, the game isn’t available on the Google Play Store or the Apple App Store. If you try to log in to Marvel Rivals through any device in the United States, you are met with a message stating, “A law banning Marvel Snap has been enacted in the U.S. Unfortunately, that means you can’t use Marvel Snap for now.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Marvel Rivals will receive a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">comic book in April 2025</a>. Also, Rivals will receive a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-red-hulk-mystery-skin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mystery skin</a> to celebrate the release of Captain America: Brave New World. Do you think Marvel Snap will return within 24 hours?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-writer-sets-the-story-straight-for-recent-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 writer setting the story straight for recent claims</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/">Marvel Rivals Comic Book Set to Arrive in April 2025</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Marvel is releasing a new comic book based on the events of Marvel Rivals in April 2025. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-and-fallout-4-are-also-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-and-fallout-4-are-also-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/">Starfield and Fallout 4 Are Also Coming to Nintendo Switch 2, it’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>An insider has shared several more games making their way to Nintendo Switch 2 later this year.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-writer-sets-the-story-straight-for-recent-claims/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-writer-sets-the-story-straight-for-recent-claims/">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Writer Sets the Story Straight for Recent Claims&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s writer, Daniel Vávra recently set the story straight about the game being banned in Saudi Arabia. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-6-xbox-series-s-x/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-6-xbox-series-s-x/">ESRB Rating Suggests Resident Evil 6 is Coming to Xbox Series S|X</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new ESRB rating suggests that Resident Evil 6 may soon be coming to current-generation consoles.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Release Date & Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-release-date-platforms.1086915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-release-date-platforms/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Avowed is a new IP from the big brains at Obsidian Entertainment. The ARPG is a diverse experience taking the best bits from action games and the depth of role-playing titles. It comes in a busy year for the company, so let’s check out Avowed’s release date, and where you can find the release.</p>



<p>Obsidian Entertainment is all hands on deck in 2025. The developer is preparing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Outer Worlds 2 sequel</a>—another ARPG—whereas Avowed takes on a more magical feel. It’s fresh, looks exciting, and it’s the sort of magical fun the world needs. Spells, weapons, swords, and axes are part and parcel of this jaw-dropping, semi-open-world release. </p>



<p>There are big expectations, and rightly so, and we’re here to see what Obsidian is cooking up for launch.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-avowed-s-release-date">When is Avowed’s Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The big, bad bear. Credit to Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Avowed launches on February 18, meaning the full release date is almost here.</strong></p>



<p>February and March are always a competitive period for gaming. Companies are keen to capitalize on the quieter January and post-Xmas lull. If you check your calendar, you’ll notice Avowed is only a few days after Valentine’s Day, making it a perfect late present. </p>



<p>Keep the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-delay-confirmed-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed release date</a> in mind if you need gift ideas!</p>



<h2 id="h-avowed-release-time">Avowed Release Time</h2>



<p><strong>Avowed doesn’t have a special launch time yet, meaning a midnight launch is likely.</strong></p>



<p>Very few games come with unique launch windows. Avowed also looks to be heading this way—unless Obsidian intervenes and ruins my theory—so you can ready yourself for midnight in your region. </p>



<p>New Zealand users get their usual benefit of first access due to the time difference. Make sure to keep off of social media until Avowed is installed and ready to go on your format.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-avowed-platforms">All Avowed Platforms</h2>



<p><strong>Xbox Series X|S and PC are the only platforms you can find Avowed for now.</strong></p>



<p>Avowed is published by Xbox Game Studios, meaning it’s a <strong>Microsoft-exclusive title</strong>. So bizarre is the gaming landscape in 2025 that I wouldn’t rule out Avowed coming to PS5. Exclusivity means a lot less than it used to—with Sony publishing exclusive games on PC too—and the PlayStation and Xbox crossover is only getting stronger.</p>



<p>Reports are abound that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-2-and-gears-of-war-are-also-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hellblade 2 and Gears of War are coming to PS5</a>. There are rumors about Halo dropping too. If this is all possible, an Avowed PlayStation port doesn’t seem beyond the realms of possibility.</p>



<hr>



<p>Does Avowed catch your eye in 2025? Or is it a standalone interest, is The Outer Worlds 2 also sending you to space? Let us know your thoughts on both games.</p>



<p>For more on Avowed, we know its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heres-your-look-at-the-avowed-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">system requirements</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pre-order-details-and-game-editions-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">different editions</a>, and a cool tidbit about the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-game-director-reveals-new-details-about-companions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">companions</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>