<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 19:20:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 Launch To Be “Worst When It Comes To Availability”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-launch-to-be-worst-when-it-comes-to-availability/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-launch-to-be-%E2%80%9Cworst-when-it-comes-to-availability%E2%80%9D.1089009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-launch-to-be-worst-when-it-comes-to-availability/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you are looking to get a brand new Nvidia RTX 5090 or RTX 5080 at launch, it may be tougher than you expected. According to multiple rumors circulating, the release of the next-generation of graphics cards from Nvidia is gearing up to be the “worst when it comes to availability” in the company’s history.</p>



<p>One board partner, Zotac, confirmed supply issues in an <a href="https://tagtag.co.kr/article/notice/1/18681/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">message online</a>. The AIC says that their card won’t be available on January 30 as expected, instead it will be coming in early February. Still, Zotac says that “due to external factors” there’s the chance the card may not come until mid-February.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://benchlife.info/amd-radeon-rx-9070-xt-rx-9070-launch-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Benchlife</a>, they state that “communication issues” between Nvidia and its various AIC partners have resulted into limited supply for consumers.</p>



<p>Said gaming PC builder <a href="https://x.com/PowerGPU/status/1881758554836877675" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PowerGPU</a>, “Warning you all now. The launch of the RTX 5090 will be the worst when it comes to availability. Already being told to expect it to be that way for the first 3 months.”</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Nvidia for comment on these claims. Should a response be received, this story will be updated accordingly.</p>



<p>The Nvidia RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-announces-geforce-rtx-50-series-graphics-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">were revealed during CES</a> in early January. In addition to the two high-end graphics cards, Nvidia is set to release the RTX 5070 Ti and RTX 5070 sometime in February. An exact date, however, has yet to be announced by the company.</p>



<p>What do you think of the claims that launch availability for the Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 will be the worst in the company’s history? &nbsp;Let us know in down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming tech, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-sees-20-performance-increase-over-last-gen-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumored performance increase</a> for the RTX 5090 over last generation,&nbsp;and check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-pointing-to-a-new-steam-console-from-valve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumors surrounding a potential return</a>&nbsp;of Steam Machines. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Highly Recommended Strategy Games Armchair Generals Shouldn’t Miss]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/5-highly-recommended-strategy-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-highly-recommended-strategy-games-armchair-generals-shouldn%E2%80%99t-miss.1089006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/5-highly-recommended-strategy-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>With the ongoing Steam festival focusing on real-time strategy games, now’s the perfect opportunity to score a few titles you could potentially spend hundreds of hours playing. There’s a fair number of discounted RTS games I have personally spent up to 1,000 hours playing, and some are just too good of deals to pass up. Here’s a look at five highly recommended games on Steam’s Real-Time Strategy Fest!</p>



<h2 id="h-best-games-worth-buying-on-steam-s-rts-fest">Best Games Worth Buying on Steam’s RTS Fest</h2>



<p>If you’re a fan of the strategy genre, you’re in luck because there are countless releases annually, many of which shine. Despite the new releases and innovative indie studios taking a chance at refreshing the genre, a few old standbys tend to keep most players’ attention. With the current Steam Fest, now’s a good time to jump in for yourself!</p>



<h3 id="h-hearts-of-iron-iv">Hearts of Iron IV</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Have you ever watched a documentary or read a history book about WW2 and thought, “I could do it differently?” If so, then <strong>Hearts of Iron IV</strong> is your game, as it allows you to take economic, political, and military command of an entire nation, prepare for the upcoming war by building weapons and cementing alliances, and then fight in a global conflict. It’s challenging, rewarding, and expansive!</p>



<h3 id="h-stellaris">Stellaris</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Like Hearts of Iron IV, but in space, with more operatic moments and interesting setpieces. I mean, look at the screenshot above as a science vessel scans a planet with a red sun in the background. <strong>Stellaris </strong>is beautiful and one of the most straightforward Paradox titles for new players. It allows you to tell a grand story of a space-faring empire, which speaks to many!</p>



<h3 id="h-warno">Warno</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>If taking command of an entire nation or galactic empire isn’t quite your speed, <strong>Warno</strong> offers a more grounded approach to real-time strategy by placing you in charge of a fighting force full of tanks, armored vehicles, infantry, helicopters, and even fighter jets. You’ll conquer territory on the map, fighting small-unit skirmishes and endure large-scale bombardments alike, for a bombastic and entertaining RTS experience!</p>







<h3 id="h-they-are-billions">They Are Billions</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><strong>They Are Billions</strong> proves to be a highly challenging yet rewarding strategy game that took me by surprise. I didn’t think I’d spend hundreds of hours trying to survive the zombie apocalypse in a city-building survival and real-time strategy game, but this one kept me playing. You are the last bastion of humanity, surviving seemingly endless waves of the undead as they attempt to wipe humanity from the planet.</p>



<h3 id="h-total-war-rome-2">Total War: Rome 2</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>While there are certainly newer entries in the long-running Total War franchise, I will always retain a soft spot for <strong>Rome 2</strong> as one of my favorite historical strategy games in the series. It’s expansive, grand, and memorable, allowing players to restore the glory of Rome by conquering the Gauls to the north or moving into Greece to the east. The world is your oyster, so long as you have the coin and men to take it yourself!</p>



<p>Do you have a favorite strategy game everyone should check out? Let us know in the comments below, or <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">visit the Insider Gaming forums</a> to talk strategy!</p>



<hr>



<p>Prepare yourself, strategy gaming fans! <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-goes-gold-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization 7 has gone gold ahead of release</a>, and it’s almost upon us!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM: The Dark Ages Gameplay Footage Leaks Online Ahead of Xbox Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-leak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-footage-leaks-online-ahead-of-xbox-developer-direct.1088970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-leak/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Some new footage of DOOM: The Dark Ages has leaked online ahead of the Xbox Developer Direct on January 23.</p>



<p>The footage was uploaded by YouTube Gougaru, who seemingly has recorded some footage of DOOM: The Dark Ages at a behind-the-scenes presentation. You can watch the gameplay below:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="MORE NEW DOOM:THE DARK AGES FOOTAGE HAS BEEN LEAKED!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NogvFk4gmI4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><br>The gameplay footage gives a brief walkthrough of some of the locations in the game. Still, while the footage leaked before the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developer-direct-announced-for-january-23/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox developer direct</a>, it’s understood that the gameplay originates from a tech demo of some kind, likely showcasing the latest series of graphics cards.</p>



<p>Speaking with sources who have seen a preview of DOOM at the Xbox Developer Direct, the in-depth look will show more gameplay instead of map overviews.</p>



<p>Yesterday, DOOM: The Dark Ages <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-may/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked to be released on May 15, 2025</a> for the Xbox Series S|X, PC, and PlayStation 5. DOOM: The Dark Ages marks the game as one of Microsoft’s first “exclusives” to release day and date on PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>As for what else to expect during the Xbox Developer Direct, Xbox has announced that South of Midnight and Expedition 33 will also be having in-depth showcases, while a fourth “unknown” game will also be revealed.</p>



<p>“You are the DOOM Slayer, the legendary demon-killing warrior and the super weapon in this never-before-seen dark and sinister medieval war against Hell,” the official DOOM: The Dark Ages description reads.</p>



<p>The game is narratively set as a prequel to the 2016 DOOM title, which sold 2 million copies by July 2017 (before Microsoft’s acquisition of Bethesda, where the game released multiplatform). </p>



<p>Will you be playing DOOM: The Dark Ages on launch? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-organisation/">Shroud might start a Marvel Rivals team</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-goes-gold-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization 7 Goes Gold Ahead Of Release</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Story Trailer Releasing Thursday]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-story-trailer-releasing-thursday/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-story-trailer-releasing-thursday.1088967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-story-trailer-releasing-thursday/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-85156">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Ubisoft <a href="https://x.com/assassinscreed/status/1882112264179753028" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">has announced</a> that it is releasing the Assassin’s Creed Shadows story trailer on Thursday. The trailer release comes the same day that media embargoes lift for those who previewed the game. </p>



<p>The trailer is set to go live at 9am PT/12pm ET/6pm CET on January 23. You can watch the trailer when it premieres, below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows: Story Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SHaN4MIGqpo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows is currently scheduled to release on March 20. The game was originally scheduled to release on November 15, 2024 before being delayed to February 14, 2025. The game was delayed again earlier this month to it’s, hopeful, final release date.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/_Tom_Henderson_/status/1881793638923149513" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming’s Tom Henderson</a> has heard that there is “a lot of positive buzz” around the game after the delays allowed developers to polish the game in various areas.</p>



<p>Aside from Assassin’s Creed Shadows, Ubisoft is working on a number of Assassin’s Creed projects such as Hexe, a Black Flag remake, it’s Fall Guys-like game, and more. Ubisoft is also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-and-guillemot-family-considering-new-venture-with-ubisoft-assets/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">still in talks with Tencent</a> about the future of the company. There have been discussions of taking the company private as its shares have continued to fall in recent years. Ubisoft also say the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-xdefiant-shutting-down-in-june/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">end of its free-to-play Call of Duty competitor XDefiant</a> after it failed to make enough money for the company to keep it going.</p>



<p>Are you excited for the Assassin’s Creed Shadows story trailer? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/store-listing-says-new-3d-mario-legend-of-zelda-remake-coming-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what games a store listing claims</a>&nbsp;are coming to Nintendo Switch 2 in 2025.. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insomniac-games-founder-and-president-ted-price-is-retiring/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insomniac-games-founder-and-president-ted-price-is-retiring/">Insomniac Games Founder And President Ted Price Is Retiring</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Insomniac Games founder and president Ted Price has announced he is retiring from the gaming industry this year.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-dlss-4-games/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-dlss-4-games/">Nvidia DLSS 4 Will Be Available for 75 Games At Launch</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new announcement, Nvidia’s DLSS 4 capabilities will be arriving for 75 games and apps at launch. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-2-trailer-gives-more-details-on-maps-modes-and-more/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-2-trailer-gives-more-details-on-maps-modes-and-more/">Black Ops 6 Season 2 Trailer Gives More Details On Maps, Modes, and More</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has released a new trailer for Black Ops 6 Season 2, giving some more information on what players can expect.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-increases-external-storage-size-support/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-increases-external-storage-size-support/">Xbox Increases External Storage Size Support</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft has announced a new update for Xbox users that increases its support for external storage on the console.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Insomniac Games Founder And President Ted Price Is Retiring]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/insomniac-games-founder-and-president-ted-price-is-retiring/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/insomniac-games-founder-and-president-ted-price-is-retiring.1088916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/insomniac-games-founder-and-president-ted-price-is-retiring/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ted Price, founder and president of Insomniac Games, is retiring from the company he started in 1994. The news comes via an <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/news/blog/ted-price-announces-retirement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">announcement</a> on Sony’s website.</p>



<p>Price is set to leave his position in March after 31 years.</p>



<p>“I actually made this decision last year,” he said. “For me, after over 30 years of leading Insomniac, I felt it was simply time to step aside and let others pave the way for our team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“During the past year, I had the opportunity to work with the senior leadership team at Insomniac to create a succession plan that I know will provide the continuity, stability and strong leadership necessary to deliver more of what our fans cherish over the next several decades.”</p>



<p>With Price leaving the company, Insomniac Games will be lead by three new Co-Studio heads: Chad Dezern, Ryan Schneider, and Jen Huang.</p>



<p>“I believe strongly that for us to continue our success, we need leaders at the top who are intimately familiar with how we do things, leaders who have helped build our culture and our processes, and who have earned people’s trust,” Price said.</p>



<p>“There is no way that I would ever consider handing the reins to a team I didn’t trust to take care of Insomniacs and lead us to even greater heights. Chad, Jen and Ryan are that team. For those who may not be familiar, please take a moment to get to know them here.”</p>



<p>In a statement on the official <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/22/whats-next-for-insomniac-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation blog</a>, Dezern, Schneider, and Huang expressed gratitude for the opportunity to head the studio moving forward.</p>



<p>“Our shared intention is to preserve what has made Insomniac special for 30-plus years while exploring how we can strategically evolve to succeed for decades to come,” they said. “We’ll continue prioritizing our studio culture, built around transparency and collaboration. We strive for a workplace where employees can do the best work of their careers.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>First started in 1994 as Xtreme Software, Insomniac Games is known for franchises such as Spyro the Dragon, Ratchet &amp; Clank, and, more recently, the Marvel Spider-Man games. The studio is currently working on a number of projects, including Marvel’s Wolverine. Insomniac was acquired by Sony in 2019.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ted Price retiring from Insomniac Games?&nbsp;Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/store-listing-says-new-3d-mario-legend-of-zelda-remake-coming-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what games a store listing claims</a> are coming to Nintendo Switch 2 in 2025.. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>