<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:20:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Censors Switch 2 Version Of Dispatch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-censors-switch-2-version-of-dispatch/</link>
            <guid>1418833</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/dispatch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dispatch</a> is set to release soon on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, and with that comes some concessions…and censorship.</p>



<p>Releasing on the console on January 29, Dispatch features moments of vulgarity and nudity during the story. While there is an option to self-censor the game should you not want to hear or see those moments, it appears that Nintendo has made the decision for players.</p>







<p>In a statement provided to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-switch-switch-2-censored-adhoc-comment" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Adhoc Studios confirmed the censorship, but says that the overall narrative and experience will remain the same.</p>



<p><strong>“Different platforms have different content criteria, and submissions are evaluated individually,”</strong> AdHoc said in a statement. <strong>“We worked with Nintendo to ensure the content within the title met the criteria to release on their platforms, but the core narrative and gameplay experience remains identical to the original release.”</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Talking Dispatch With The Creators From Adhoc Studio - Developer Spotlight" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iyHL4QZrMaI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>First released with weekly episodes in October, Dispatch quickly became one of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dispatch-insider-gaming-community-biggest-surprise-hit-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">biggest surprise hits</a> of 2025. The game sold two million copies in its first month, and has since surpassed 3 million copies on PlayStation and PC combined. With the game now coming to Nintendo Switch 2, and possibly more in the future, that number is likely to rise even more. </p>



<p>As far as the future of the franchise is concerned, the team at AdHoc have said repeatedly that they’d like to do and see more from the Z-Team. Whether that ultimately happens, obviously, remains to be seen.</p>



<p>What do you think of Nintendo’s policies to limit the nudity and other vulgar moments in games like Dispatch? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-carmageddon-rogue-shift-game-director-giuseppe-franchi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest episode of the Developer Spotlight</a>&nbsp;with Carmageddon: Rogue Shift Director Giuseppe Franchi. And for even more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-censors-switch-2-version-of-dispatch/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Rubber Ducks In ARC Raiders—How To Find All Rubber Ducks]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/epic-rubber-ducks-in-arc-raiders-how-to-find-all-rubber-ducks/</link>
            <guid>1418830</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>There are plenty of Trinkets to find in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, and looting them can be a great source of money, but there’s always been one that’s held dear amongst the community—the Rubber Duck.</p>



<p>These little guys are only Common loot and don’t sell for much at all, but some fans have enjoyed collecting them. Well, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/studios/embark-studios/" id="96820">Embark Studios</a> has upped the ante with the Headwinds update, as a host of new Rubber Ducks have been added to the game, and they vary in rarity.</p>







<p>If you’re looking to start a brand new Rubber Duck collection in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/solo-vs-squads-matchmaking-arc-raiders-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/solo-vs-squads-matchmaking-arc-raiders-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, then you’re in the right place. This guide will show you all of the new Rubber Duck variants, as well as how you can get your hands on them all.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-new-rubber-ducks-are-there-in-arc-raiders">How Many New Rubber Ducks Are There In ARC Raiders?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>All from one raid. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-release-date-times-confirmed-content/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-release-date-times-confirmed-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Headwinds update</a> has added six new Rubber Ducks to ARC Raiders, bringing the grand total to seven, including the original yellow one.</strong></p>



<p>You’ll know if you’ve found a new Rubber Duck variant not just by its rarity, but by its skin, too. Each new Duck has a unique aesthetic, ranging from a duck with cow markings to a green alien duck! The full list of new Rubber Ducks is listed below:</p>



<ul>
<li>Tropical Duck</li>



<li>Gentle Duck</li>



<li>Alien Duck</li>



<li>Doodly Duck</li>



<li>Flashy Duck</li>



<li>Familiar Duck</li>
</ul>



<p>As fun as they are, they’re not just for show. Depending on the rarity, these Ducks can fetch a pretty penny, with the Familiar Duck selling for 7,000 Coins a pop! They can stack up to 15 times, meaning a full stack of Familiar Ducks is the most valuable group of items in ARC Raiders. If you’re looking to get rich, you’ll need to know where to find them first. </p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-find-the-new-rubber-ducks-in-arc-raiders">How To Find The New Rubber Ducks In ARC Raiders</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Check the chimneys! Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The six new Rubber Ducks can be found on the Buried City map, during the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-bird-city-new-headwinds-map-condition-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-bird-city-new-headwinds-map-condition-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bird City</a> Minor Map Condition.</strong></p>



<p>They can’t be found just anywhere on the map, though, as you’ll need to take to the rooftops. Once you’re up high, search every chimney you come across; birds have made nests inside of them, and they’re prone to storing some valuable Trinkets inside.</p>







<p>As luck would have it, these birds have been stealing a whole variety of Rubber Ducks and stashing them in their nests. Who knows where they migrated from to bring these treasures to the Rust Belt, but your Coin collection should thank them. </p>



<hr>



<p>Have you found any of the new Rubber Ducks in ARC Raiders? Share your haul in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" id="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>. </p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">every stage for the Trophy Display Project</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-epic-augments-in-arc-raiders-headwinds-update-what-are-they-how-to-get-them/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/new-epic-augments-in-arc-raiders-headwinds-update-what-are-they-how-to-get-them/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the two brand-new Augments</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/epic-rubber-ducks-in-arc-raiders-how-to-find-all-rubber-ducks/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Half Sword Have Multiplayer? Co-op & PvP Release Details, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/half-sword-multiplayer-co-op/</link>
            <guid>1418785</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Your life is on the line in Half Sword: Two combatants, two weapons, one winner, and a lot of blood spilled. Half Sword is a combat game designed to unleash the sadistic and barbaric medieval animal in you, and multiplayer or co-op would make it even more of a blood-filled blast.</p>



<p>It may seem hard to believe, but civilization is <em>slightly </em>more civilized than it was a few hundred years ago—even if that is hard to believe. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/half-sword/" id="3509" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Half Sword</a> takes us back in time to a more open age where duels-to-the-death were as common as bread. It requires two people, but does Half Sword require human or AI opponents?</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-half-sword-in-multiplayer-or-co-op">Can You Play Half Sword In Multiplayer or Co-op?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A crushing defeat in more ways than one. Credit to Half Sword Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The white flag needs to be waved on Half Sword co-op or multiplayer for now, with developer Half Sword Games confirming that there is no multiplayer present at the game’s launch.</strong></p>



<p>Insider Gaming will hand it over to the official Half Sword Discord <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1043854763189600337/1272470349245579396" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">FAQ</a> to clear this one up:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We fully understand the appeal of multiplayer and especially PvP. However, we also wish to draw your attention to the fact that physics-based multiplayer on Unreal Engine 5 is as hardcore as it gets as far as development: it is no easy task &amp; Half Sword is our first game. We are focusing on single-player physics right now to build a strong experience aimed at offering hundreds if not thousands of hours of fun.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Developer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/half-sword-games/" id="3510" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Half Sword Games</a> is clearly putting a lot of time and effort into this project, with a view to this being a long-term goal. So, while there’s no multiplayer at launch, it’s not being ruled out.</p>







<h2 id="h-half-sword-multiplayer-release-date">Half Sword Multiplayer Release Date</h2>



<p><strong>According to the developer, a “polished multiplayer experience” is the long-term goal for Half Sword.</strong></p>



<p>The core focus is on single-player. Despite this being a game tailor-made for two real people, the physics and enormity of the gameplay mean a lot more work is needed to ensure a stable base.</p>



<p>The FAQ says: “Are we able to offer multiplayer at release: highly unlikely. Will we do our utmost to provide multiplayer after release: more likely.”</p>



<p>It does seem like Half Sword is destined for multiplayer, doesn’t it? There’s still plenty to enjoy, even if it is only a single-player game for now. Is a lack of multiplayer a dealbreaker? Let us know your thoughts through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Read up on more Half Sword guides, such as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-much-will-half-sword-cost-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how much Half Sword costs</a>, and all <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/half-sword-playstation-xbox-nintendo-all-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Half Sword consoles and platforms</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/half-sword-multiplayer-co-op/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance PS5 Upgrade Revealed by PlayStation Store]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-ps5-upgrade-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1418782</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The PlayStation Store was recently updated with a new production description for Kingdom Come: Deliverance, and it unveils something fans have been curious about for a while. It points to a PS5 upgrade being released <strong>soon </strong>for the sensational medieval RPG, which will include 4K resolutions, a boosted framerate, and high-resolution textures.</p>



<p>This follows <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-upgrade-could-come/">a rumor that surfaced</a> in October 2025 suggesting that such an upgrade would emerge early in 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-kcd-is-getting-the-upgrade-treatment">KCD is Getting the Upgrade Treatment</h2>



<p>Last year, Kingdom Come: Deliverance II was released by Warhorse Studios, several years after the first game spawned off the back of a successful Kickstarter project. The sequel was a mindblowing title, bursting with cinematic storytelling, authentic combat sequences, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-kingdom-comes-tom-mckay-labels-game-success-a-fever-dream/">some of the best acting</a> we’ve seen in a hot minute in the gaming space.</p>



<p>Following in the footsteps of that delivery, the first title, released in 2018, appears to be getting a current-gen upgrade, thanks to the PlayStation Store.</p>



<p>It was recently discovered that <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/227410" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a PS5 upgrade</a> is incoming for the nearly eight-year-old medieval RPG. On the game’s PS Store page, the product description was recently updated to include:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The PS5 version of Kingdom Come: Deliverance now features graphical updates including 4K resolution, improved framerate, high-resolution textures and many more. Medieval Bohemia has never been so beautiful.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>(<em>Thanks to <a href="https://x.com/RinoTheBouncer/status/2016556945323262317" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rino</a> for the spot</em>)</p>



<p>It’s a safe bet it’ll also land on Xbox, of course.</p>



<p>It’s probably a stock-standard upgrade, and it’s not the re-release that some were hoping for, but that doesn’t take anything away from the thing. Kingdom Come: Deliverance is a masterful title that simply must be experienced, as it opens the door to the adventure that is Kingdom Come: Deliverance II, which is worth every one of the <strong>many </strong>hours you’ll sink into it.</p>



<p>That’s what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review/">our full review</a> said about it, anyway.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to exploring a potential PS5 upgrade for Kingdom Come: Deliverance? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/february-free-playstation-plus-games/">February’s free PS Plus games have been announced</a></p>






        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-ps5-upgrade-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>