<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 19:36:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Full PC Specs Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-full-pc-specs-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-full-pc-specs-revealed.1096284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-full-pc-specs-revealed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-87131">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The full PC specifications for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 are now available. The stylized turn-based RPG from the small developer <a href="https://www.sandfall.co/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sandfall Interactive</a> is one of the highlights of Microsoft’s Game Pass titles slated to come out in the first half of 2025.</p>



<p>The release date for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 was revealed at Xbox’s Developer Direct event earlier this month, and now PC players can see what they’ll need to run the game on their system. Here’s the full breakdown of requirements you’ll need before your expedition heads out.</p>



<h2 id="h-clair-obscur-expedition-33-full-pc-specs">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Full PC Specs </h2>



<p>The game requires 55 GB of storage and DirectX Version 12.</p>



<h3 id="h-minimum-specs">Minimum Specs</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Graphics Preset: </strong>Low</li>



<li><strong>Operating System:</strong> Windows 10 64-bit or higher</li>



<li><strong>Processor (CPU):</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i7-8700K or better | AMD Ryzen 5 1600X or better</li>



<li><strong>Graphics Card (GPU)</strong>: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1070 Ti (8 GB) or better | AMD Radeon RX Vega 56 (8 GB) or better | Intel Arc A580 (8GB) or better</li>



<li><strong>Memory (RAM):</strong> 8 GB</li>



<li><strong>Average Performance</strong>: 1080p, 30 FPS</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-recommended-specs">Recommended Specs</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Graphics Preset: </strong>High</li>



<li><strong>Operating System:</strong> Windows 10 64-bit or higher</li>



<li><strong>Processor (CPU):</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i7-11700K or better | AMD Ryzen 5 5600X or better</li>



<li><strong>Graphics Card (GPU)</strong>: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 3070 (16 GB) or better | AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT (16 GB) or better </li>



<li><strong>Memory (RAM):</strong> 16 GB</li>



<li><strong>Average Performance</strong>: 1080p, 60 FPS</li>
</ul>



<p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 will launch on Xbox Series X|S and PC on April 24, 2025. PC players can <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-editions-pre-order-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">purchase and play the game</a> on Steam, the Epic Games Store, or the Xbox app. The game will be available day one on Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>Is your PC equipped to handle Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 on high graphics? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1336/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about Forza Horizon 5 coming to PS5 this spring, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-voices-harry-hawker-sniper-elite-resistance-voice-actors/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-voices-harry-hawker-sniper-elite-resistance-voice-actors/">Who Voices Harry Hawker in Sniper Elite Resistance? All Voice Actors Revealed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>One of the biggest talking points—literally—about Sniper Elite Resistance is Harry Hawker’s voice and actor, but who is he?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-open-genetic-apex-booster-packs-pokemon-tcg-pocket/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-open-genetic-apex-booster-packs-pokemon-tcg-pocket/">How To Open Genetic Apex Booster Packs in Pokémon TCG Pocket</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Genetic Apex Booster Packs arrived first in Pokémon TCG Pocket, but is it possible to open them anymore with newer booster sets releasing?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-complete-the-tomb-main-quest-easter-egg-black-ops-6-zombies/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-complete-the-tomb-main-quest-easter-egg-black-ops-6-zombies/">How to Complete The Tomb Main Quest Easter Egg in Black Ops 6 Zombies Walkthrough</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Tomb Zombies map has a Main Quest Easter Egg to beat in Black Ops 6, and this guide breaks down each step you need to do.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-build-staff-of-ice-wonder-weapon-the-tomb-zombies-black-ops-6/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-build-staff-of-ice-wonder-weapon-the-tomb-zombies-black-ops-6/">How to Build The Staff of Ice Wonder Weapon in The Tomb Zombies in Black Ops 6</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Staff of Ice Wonder Weapon was introduced alongside the rest of the Season 2 content, and the new artifact serves survival key purposes.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 is Coming to The PlayStation 5 This Spring]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-playstation-5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-horizon-5-is-coming-to-the-playstation-5-this-spring.1096245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-playstation-5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Xbox and Playground Games have announced that Forza Horizon 5 is coming to the PlayStation 5 this spring.</p>



<p>Posted to <a href="https://forza.net/news/forza-horizon-5-comes-to-ps5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">forza.net</a>, the announced reads, “With nearly 900 cars available in the game, over 40 thematic game updates, two expansions, and so much more content, our team is excited to announce that this spring, PlayStation 5 players will be able to explore Mexico’s beautiful roads and experience the Horizon Festival for the first time as we are officially launching Forza Horizon 5 on PS5.”</p>



<p>“The PlayStation 5 version of Forza Horizon 5, developed by Panic Button in partnership with Turn 10 Studios and Playground Games, will have the same content as the Xbox and PC releases of the game. Previously released Car Packs, as well as the Hot Wheels and Rally Adventure expansions, will also be available for purchase,” it continues.</p>



<p>Players can now Wishlist Forza Horizon 5 for the PlayStation 5 on the PlayStation store today.</p>



<p>The news confirms a report from eXtas1s, who said the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-was-ready-but-delayed-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announcement was originally delayed</a>.</p>



<p>In addition to the announcement that the game is coming to the PlayStation 5, it was also announced that Playground Games are working on a “special new free content update for all platforms,” named Horizon Realms. </p>



<p>“Realms will give players the chance to explore a curated collection of some of the community’s favourite previously released Evolving Worlds, alongside some other surprises. Stay tuned to&nbsp;<a href="https://linktr.ee/forzahorizonofficial">our channels</a>&nbsp;for more details soon.”</p>



<p>Will you be picking up Forza Horizon 5 on the PlayStation 5? What do you think about Classic Themes leaving PlayStation 5? Let us know in the comments below or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-dlc-leaked-ahead-of-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization 7 DLC leaking ahead of the official reveal</a>,&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League of Legends Will Reportedly Get Its Own Game Changers Circuit in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-will-reportedly-get-its-own-game-changers-circuit-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/league-of-legends-will-reportedly-get-its-own-game-changers-circuit-in-2025.1096194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-will-reportedly-get-its-own-game-changers-circuit-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Riot Games will reportedly establish an official Game Changers circuit in League of Legends this year. The establishment of a Game Changers scene will ideally women and players representing marginalized genders a viable path to the top tier of competitive LoL.</p>



<p>After the success of the endeavor in the VALORANT space, Riot is hoping to see similar results in their flagship title, League of Legends.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-game-changers-lol-seeks-similar-success-as-valorant">Game Changers LoL Seeks Similar Success as VALORANT</h2>



<p>According to reports from both <a href="https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/riot-to-launch-lol-game-changers-tournament-in-2025-for-marginalized-genders" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dot Esports</a> and <a href="https://www.sheepesports.com/articles/sources-riot-to-launch-first-ever-lol-game-changers-initiative-in-emea-starting-in-april/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sheep Esports</a>, Riot will establish a League of Legends Game Changers initiative in the EMEA region this year. The 2025 season will reportedly consist of two splits, with Riot also considering a LAN finals at the end of the second split.</p>



<p>Riot is reportedly looking to invite organizations that field teams in the LEC, the top European league for LoL. Both SK Gaming, G2, and Vitality currently field women’s rosters in LoL. Sheep Esports is reporting that “at least three existing LEC teams – none of which had previously invested in the [GC] scene” have explored roster options “contingent on the launch of a Game Changers initiative.” SK Gaming is also being considered as the host for online qualifiers that could begin in March.</p>



<p>In the VALORANT space, the Game Changers inititiative has been nothing short of a success. Just in the past month, two-time GC champions Shopify Rebellion became the first GC team to qualify for an official Challengers league. This occurred right after the team’s former duelist star, Ava “florescent” Eugene, became the first Game Changers player to compete in the international VCT leagues. The scene as a whole has also provided full-time competition and opportunities to its many players, and has done quite well in regards to viewership.</p>



<p>How exciting is the idea of a Game Changers scene for League of Legends?</p>



<p>Join the discussion down below or in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest esports news</a>, check out or coverage of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/counter-strike-2-premier-season-2-goes-live-with-map-swap-rifle-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the CS2 Premier Season 2 changes</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>