<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 12:33:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Perk & Wildcard in Warzone x Black Ops 6]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/every-perk-wildcard-in-warzone-x-black-ops-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-perk-wildcard-in-warzone-x-black-ops-6.1033404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/every-perk-wildcard-in-warzone-x-black-ops-6/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Perks are a staple of Call of Duty games, and they’re extremely important for a successful loadout in Warzone. With the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 Season 1</a> integration, the battle royale title is getting a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-1-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major overhaul</a>, which includes a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/area-99-revealed-as-new-resurgence-map-in-warzone-at-codnext-event/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new map</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-saug-in-black-ops-6-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guns</a>, Perks, and the introduction of Wildcards.</p>



<p>Speaking of the latter, if you’re wondering how the system will work in Warzone and all the Perks and Wildcards that will be available in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-battle-pass-release-date-season-one-pass-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warzone x Black Ops 6 Season 1</a>, here’s everything you need to know.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-all-perks-in-warzone-amp-how-to-unlock">All Perks in Warzone &amp; how to unlock</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-all-wildcards-in-warzone-amp-unlock-requirements">All Wildcards in Warzone &amp; unlock requirements</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-how-do-perks-and-wildcards-work-in-warzone">How do Perks and Wildcards work in Warzone?</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-can-you-get-specialist-perk-package-in-warzone">Can you get Specialist Perk Package in Warzone?</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-all-perks-in-warzone-amp-how-to-unlock">All Perks in Warzone &amp; how to unlock</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Perk &amp; Slot</th><th>Unlock Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Reflexes</td><td>Season 1 Reloaded Reward</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Veteran</td><td>Season 1 Reward</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Grenadier</td><td>Available Immediately</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Dexterity</td><td>Level 20</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Scavenger</td><td>Level 26</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 1: </strong>Survivor</td><td>Level 47</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Quartermaster</td><td>Available Immediately</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Bomb<strong> </strong>Squad</td><td>Level 8</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Tracker</td><td>Level 29</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Sprinter</td><td>Level 32</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Cold-Blooded</td><td>Level 41</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 2: </strong>Quick<strong> </strong>Fix</td><td>Level 50</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Gung-Ho</td><td>Available Immediately</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Resolute</td><td>Level 5</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Ghost</td><td>Level 17</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Birdseye</td><td>Level 23</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Tempered</td><td>Level 35</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk 3: </strong>Alertness</td><td>Level 44</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk (Loot): </strong>Shrouded</td><td>In-game only</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Perk (Loot): </strong>Irradiated</td><td>In-game only</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>These are all the available Perks in Warzone x Black Ops 6 Season 1 according to the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement#Wildcards" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CoD blog</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-wildcards-in-warzone-amp-unlock-requirements">All Wildcards in Warzone &amp; unlock requirements</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Wildcard</th><th>Unlock Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Overkill</td><td>Player Level 24</td></tr><tr><td>Bandolier</td><td>Player Level 15</td></tr><tr><td>Gunfighter</td><td>Player Level 33</td></tr><tr><td>Battle Ready</td><td>Player Level 38</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-do-perks-and-wildcards-work-in-warzone">How do Perks and Wildcards work in Warzone?</h2>



<p>Warzone has a “Pick 3 System,” which means you can <strong>pick one Perk from each category</strong> (blue, red, and yellow.) You can then pick <strong>one Wildcard</strong> to compliment your loadout. These Perks will drop on the floor so that they can be looted again upon death.</p>



<p>Players will need to choose one Perk for each slot to make a combination of 3. Most of the Perks can be unlocked through leveling up, while the new ones added in Season 1 (Veteran and Reflexes) are unlocked via Season 1 event rewards. There’s no Combat Specialty. Wildcards are also earned through leveling.</p>



<p>There are also lootable Perks in Warzone that players can find to further fortify their loadout. These include four options from the Pick 3 System and two that are exclusive to loot – Shrouded and Irradiated. Lootable Perks will vanish upon death.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-get-specialist-perk-package-in-warzone">Can you get Specialist Perk Package in Warzone?</h2>



<p><strong>Yes</strong>, Specialist Perk Package is back in Warzone x Black Ops 6, and it can be found as a <strong>rare loot drop or via the Care Package Killstreak</strong>. It will give the player all 18 Perks plus the two bootable Perks for a total of 20. Upon death, the Specialist Perk Package will drop and can be looted by anyone.</p>



<hr>



<p>That was everything you need to know about Perks and Wildcards in Warzone. For more, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-ransack-in-black-ops-6-new-game-mode-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guide on the new Ransack mode in BO6 multiplayer</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-assault-rifles-in-black-ops-6-ranked-best-ar-loadout/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the best ARs to use</a>. Be sure to sign up for the <a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming weekly newsletter</a> to stay updated on all things Call of Duty.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Deck OLED: Limited Edition White Releases November 18]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-oled-limited-edition-white-releases-november-18/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-deck-oled-limited-edition-white-releases-november-18.1033269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/steam-deck-oled-limited-edition-white-releases-november-18/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Valve has announced a brand new limited edition white Steam Deck OLED. It will be released on November 18, 2024, at 3 PM PST and will be priced at $670 in all shipping regions for the Steam Deck. The list also includes Japan, South Korea, Taiwan, and Hong Kong via Komodo, as well as new customers in Australia.</p>



<p>The Steam Deck OLED: Limited Edition White features the exact specifications as the 1TB model, the only difference being the handheld console’s new white and grey encasing. The limited edition model will also have an exclusive white carrying case and a white microfibre cloth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Valve has revealed that the Steam Deck OLED: Limited Edition White was manufactured in “limited quantities,” and the stock has been allocated proportionately across the available regions. Hence, the US, CA, UK, EU, AU, and Komodo regions will have individual availability. Moreover, to ensure that more customers can buy this limited edition console, purchases have been restricted to 1 unit per account.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Furthermore, to be eligible for the Steam Deck OLED: Limited Edition White, you will need a Steam account that has made a purchase before November 2024. Lastly, this is a limited edition release, and Valve has explicitly stated, “We will not be making more of this particular design. Once we are sold out, we will be sold out.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Steam’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steams-game-recording-feature-is-now-out-of-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game recording features are now out of beta</a>. Also, Black Ops 6 PlayStation and Steam sales were <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-playstation-steam-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘60% higher’ than Modern Warfare 3</a>. What are your thoughts on the Steam Deck OLED: Limited Edition White?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-class-action-lawsuit-shutting-down-the-crew/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft facing a class-action lawsuit for shutting down The Crew</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft is Facing a Class-Action Lawsuit for Shutting Down The Crew]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-class-action-lawsuit-shutting-down-the-crew/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-is-facing-a-class-action-lawsuit-for-shutting-down-the-crew.1033254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-class-action-lawsuit-shutting-down-the-crew/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft shut down the servers for The Crew in March 2024, and this decision has not been well received by the community. While fans understood the removal of the multiplayer aspect of the game, they were frustrated that the single-player mode was also made inaccessible. Now, fans have filed a lawsuit against the publishers for failing to provide an offline mode.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/476979/ubisoft-the-crew-shut-down-lawsuit-class-action" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Polygon</a>, the <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/790913960/Crew-Lawsuit-via-Polygon" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">court document</a> reveals that plaintiffs Matthew Cassel and Alan Liu have brought this class action against Ubisoft Entertainment S.A. and Ubisoft, Inc. on behalf of themselves and “all others similarly situated” for shutting down The Crew.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plaintiffs have accused Ubisoft of duping them in several ways. Firstly, they stated that Ubisoft “misled consumers by telling them they were buying a game, when in fact, all they were renting was a limited license to access a game.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plaintiffs have also alleged that Ubisoft “omitted material facts from the packaging and marketing” of The Crew. It was stated that Ubisoft didn’t mention that The Crew’s servers could be shut down at any point “without providing, at a minimum, an offline mode for consumers to continue to access the game they paid for”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, they bought physical discs, believing “The Crew itself was encoded onto physical disks consumers could buy or the digital files consumers could pay to download.” Instead, the game was on a remote server, and the physical disc acted as a key to access this server.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plaintiffs stated that when they purchased The Crew’s physical discs, they believed the game would be playable indefinitely without the risk of it being disabled. They also gave examples stating that Ubisoft had shut down online servers for games like Assassin’s Creed 2, Assassin’s Creed 3, and more in the past, but it patched an offline mode later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, in the case of The Crew, even after the community backlash, Ubisoft <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-crew-2-and-the-crew-motorfest-will-feature-offline-modes-for-long-term-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">responded</a>, stating that offline features of other games from the Crew franchise (The Crew 2 and The Crew Motorfest) would be preserved. But the original The Crew was left out of the list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plaintiffs have demanded a trial by jury and “the aggregate claims of all members of the proposed class are in excess of $5,000,000.00, exclusive of interest and cost” as this is a class-action lawsuit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, a group of modders have announced their commitment to resurrect The Crew. Also, Rainbow Six Siege made more money than any other Ubisoft franchise. What are your thoughts on the class-action lawsuit against Ubisoft for shutting down The Crew? Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nadeshot-revenue-leak-earnings-twitch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nadeshot leaking monthly Twitch revenue on Steam</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>