<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 08:49:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Falcons Wins Esports Org of the Year at Saudi-Backed Esports Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/team-falcons-esports-org-of-the-year-saudi-arabia/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-falcons-wins-esports-org-of-the-year-at-saudi-backed-esports-awards.1042587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/team-falcons-esports-org-of-the-year-saudi-arabia/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Esports Awards have ended for another year, and many trophies changed hands on the night. One award that has the esports community up in arms is the title of ‘Esports Organisation of the Year’, which went to Team Falcons.</p>



<p>Team Falcons was founded in 2017 but the brand made almost no waves at all until 2022, when the inaugural ‘Gamers8’ event took place in Riyadh. This Saudi Arabian organisation is backed by the nation’s government, and many have long been sceptical about the legitimacy of the organisation and its funding.</p>



<p>A while ago, The Esports Awards signed a three-year deal with Saudi Arabia’s Esports World Cup Foundation, pledging to host the event in Riyadh for the next three iterations.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-that-s-a-problem">That’s a Problem</h2>



<p>Team Falcons has investment from and ties to the Saudi Arabian government via the PIF and Savvy Games Group. The Esports World Cup, which took place earlier this year, is managed by ESL FACEIT, which is wholly owned by Savvy, and by extension, the Saudi government.</p>



<p>In August, Team Falcons won the grand championship at the Esports World Cup after winning more tournaments and fielding more teams than any other organisation in the world. Before, during, and after the event, Team Falcons was able to buy up some of the best esports players in the world to fill out rosters.</p>



<p>All this was achieved by an organisation founded in 2017, which didn’t really gain any traction until it started to receive sizeable investments from the Saudi government. It was part of what the community refers to as ‘esportswashing’, with the nation’s officials seeking to clean up the country’s image by investing heavily in esports and gaming.</p>



<p>Here are some facts:</p>



<ul>
<li>Team Falcons started winning in Dota 2 this year after picking up some of the world’s best players</li>



<li>Team Falcons’ Counter-Strike exploits have gotten nowhere despite splashing the cash to sign huge players (like s1mple)</li>



<li>Team Falcons did nothing in Apex Legends until the Esports World Cup after signing one of the winningest players in the space</li>



<li>Team Falcons produced little in the way of results in Rocket League until Gamers8 and the Esports World Cup</li>



<li>Team Falcons secured a spot in the COD League (Vegas Falcons) despite having an awful track record in the game’s multiplayer scene</li>



<li>Team Falcons has dominated Warzone tournaments thanks to signing the most capable players in the space</li>
</ul>



<p>Before the Saudi line was tapped into, the only thing Team Falcons was really any good at was Fortnite, and a lot of the team’s earnings in that space had come from Gamers8, the Riyadh-based event that was replaced by the Esports World Cup.</p>



<p>It’s surely becoming clear now how this is a problem with esports fans – it’s a matter of pouring as much money into the space as possible because there are no ‘financial fair play’ rules. </p>



<p>To win the Esports Organisation of the Year trophy at The Esports Awards, Team Falcons had to beat:</p>



<ul>
<li>Natus Vincere</li>



<li>Vitality</li>



<li>Team Liquid</li>



<li>G2 Esports</li>



<li>Gen G</li>



<li>T1 Esports</li>



<li>Fnatic</li>



<li>Team Spirit</li>
</ul>



<p>Team Falcons’ crowning achievement for 2024 is winning an event that it flooded with teams to gain the maximum advantage possible. It also won that event, which is backed by the Saudi government, while being backed by the Saudi government, in Saudi.</p>



<p>But hey, congratulations on the award.</p>



<p>Let us know what you think about this on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-hit-50-million-peak-viewers/">LoL Worlds 2024 final hit 50 million peak viewers</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Score Two of the Best Colony Sim Games for Under $35]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/score-two-of-the-best-colony-sim-games-for-under-35/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/score-two-of-the-best-colony-sim-games-for-under-35.1042425/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/score-two-of-the-best-colony-sim-games-for-under-35/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>For as long as I can remember, I’ve loved strategy games. It started as real-time strategy matches against AI opponents in titles like Age of Empires, Age of Mythology, and Company of Heroes. I quickly found myself drawn to base-building and colony sim titles for the sense of progression and expansion they offer, though, and few compare to RimWorld. But then, there’s also Oxygen Not Included. They’re both exceptional, both offering countless hundreds or, in some cases, thousands of hours of gameplay. Which do you choose? Why not both? You can score two of the best colony sim games for under $35 with the new <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/bundle/46465/Terraform_Titans_Duo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Terraform Titans Duo</a> bundle on Steam!</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-rimworld">What is RimWorld?</h2>



<p>RimWorld is often considered the quintessential colony sim game, following in the footsteps of titles like Dwarf Fortress but offering a unique spin on the story generation mechanics. You’ll take control of a science fiction-fueled colony full of intelligent pawns that must contend with unique enemies, flora, fauna, psychology, climate, interpersonal relationships, and more.</p>



<p>After spending 1,000 hours playing the game, I can tell you that even the base version is worth every penny. But with the expansions and countless mods, you’ll easily score hundreds of hours from RimWorld if it’s your type of game.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-oxygen-not-included">What is Oxygen Not Included?</h2>



<p>Also in the bundle, we have Oxygen Not Included. It’s another sci-fi colony sim game that focuses on the dynamic crew as they overcome obstacles, like alien lifeforms while harnessing the power of the asteroid they’re currently stranded on. For instance, you must consider logistics, like piping water and waste to and from the colony, to ensure no one falls ill. It’s complex and compelling in equal measures.</p>



<p>With ‘Overwhelmingly Positive’ reviews, Oxygen Not Included is a grand time for any colony sim or base-building game fan!</p>



<h2 id="h-score-them-both">Score Them Both!</h2>



<p>With this partnership between Ludeon Studios and Klei Entertainment, you can currently score both colony sim games for less than $35. Oxygen Not Included is on sale, dropping the price of the bundle to its current total. You really cannot pass this one up!</p>



<p>Let us know in the comments below if you grab the bundle! Don’t forget to stop by and share screenshots of your colony in our General Gaming <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Did you know it can cost up to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/it-can-cost-up-to-500000-for-a-spot-on-opening-night-live-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$500,000 for a spot on Opening Night Live 2025</a>? That’s an insane price to pay, and many indie developers can’t afford such extreme advertising costs!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>