<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:23:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei Update 1.100 Patch Notes—New Game Plus, Cosmetics, Bug Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-1-100-patch-notes-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-update-1-100-patch-notes%E2%80%94new-game-plus-cosmetics-bug-fixes.1363303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The newest update for Ghost of Yotei, Version 1.100, as well as patch notes, are available now. With it, New Game Plus has been added, alongside new cosmetics and various bug fixes.</p>







<p>Released in October, Ghost of Yotei serves as a spiritual sequel to 2020’s Ghost of Tsushima. Following mercenary Atsu, she travels across Edo to exact revenge on those who killed her family. The PlayStation 5 exclusive is one of 2025’s best-reviewed titles alongside Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and Death Stranding 2: On The Beach. While it isn’t nominated for Game of the Year at The Game Awards, it did <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-all-award-nominees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">snag some huge nominations</a> like Best Music and Best Performance. Earlier this month, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-new-game-plus-date-revealed-adds-new-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sucker Punch teased Patch 1.100</a>, which would add many new elements. Now, we have a detailed look thanks to the patch notes.</p>



<p>The 1.100 update for Ghost of Yotei isn’t too long, patch notes-wise. However, it finally adds a highly requested mode: New Game Plus. Now, if you completed the game and want more, you can return to the beginning of the story with all your previously unlocked upgrades. Furthermore, new outfits, Photo Mode additions, and fixes to gameplay and UI/UX have been included.</p>



<h2 id="h-ghost-of-yotei-1-100-full-patch-notes">Ghost of Yotei 1.100 Full Patch Notes</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - New Game+ | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vY8MXfksWuw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The full patch notes for Update 1.100 for Ghost of Yotei are available below. To see it in action, check out the video above and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vY8MXfksWuw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">available here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>New Game Plus</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Added ability to replay challenge content after completing them once.
<ul>
<li>All 22 Yotei Six Camps.</li>



<li>26 Replayable Duels.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added a New Game Plus Vendor.
<ul>
<li>Ghost Flowers will be rewarded across the game to be used as currency for the vendor.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Various new cosmetic items and charms.</li>



<li>Two new armor sets.</li>



<li>Two new trophies.</li>



<li>New Photo Mode features.</li>



<li>VRR support.</li>



<li>Added a new “Balanced” graphic mode.
<ul>
<li>Requires a display that supports a refresh rate of 120Hz.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added option to remap touchpad swipe functions to the right directional button on the D-pad.</li>



<li>New option to display a visual indicator when being led by animals.</li>



<li>The player now has the ability to turn off fall damage.
<ul>
<li>Some falls will still be lethal.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added option to automatically loot dead enemies.</li>



<li>Added option to allow for skipping Sumi-e minigames.</li>



<li>Added an additional load-out slot.</li>



<li>Added new alternative controls for mini-games.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Performance and Stability</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Various rare crash fixes.</li>



<li>Various fixes to rare visual bugs.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Various bug fixes across several missions and mission blocker fixes.</li>



<li>Bug fixes and minor adjustments to the autosave feature.</li>



<li>A few adjustments to charm description text to better describe charm perks.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>UI/UX</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Minor photo mode fixes and additional icons.</li>
</ul>







<p>What do you think of Ghost of Yotei Update 1.100’s patch notes? Excited to play New Game Plus? Where does it rank on your Best of 2025 list? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Ghost of Yotei, check out our articles on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-ghost-of-yotei-possible-dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">potential DLC</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-director-love-to-work-more-infamous/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what’s next for Sucker Punch</a>. Make sure to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>&nbsp;for more Insider Gaming!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-1-100-patch-notes-update/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Cheap Gaming Gifts Under $25 For Holiday 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cheap-gaming-gifts-under-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-cheap-gaming-gifts-under-25-for-holiday-2025.1363276/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Finding a good gift for the gamer in your life when you’re working with a tight budget can feel tougher than it probably should. After all, prices keep going up and money feels tighter for many. But not every present needs to cost you a fortune. That’s why Insider Gaming has put together a list of genuinely fun, useful gifts that still feel thoughtful and worth unwrapping. The best part, these gaming gifts are all on the cheap side at less than $25. </p>



<p>Whether you’re shopping for a friend, a family member, or just treating yourself, these picks prove you don’t need to overspend to give something great. When it comes to gifting, sometimes the smaller items end up being the ones people appreciate the most. A clever phone stand, a handy charging dock, or even a retro-themed game or controller can upgrade someone’s setup without hitting your wallet hard. And for those who love gaming culture as much as playing the games, books, card games, and novelty items can be just as meaningful as any big-ticket tech.</p>



<p>Below, you’ll find a mix gifts that stay under that $25 ceiling, making it easier to stick to a budget while still giving something they’ll actually use. Let’s take a look at the best cheap gaming gifts for 2025.</p>







<h2 id="h-best-gaming-gifts-under-25">Best Gaming Gifts Under $25</h2>



<p><strong>1985 Games Mystery Dice</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Want to get a new set of dice for your Dungeons &amp; Dragons campaigns or other table-top nights? This mystery dice set takes the decision of what dice to use out of your hand and gives you a random set of seven. This adds a little extra excitement before your next game night. </p>







<hr>



<p><strong>FYOUNG Nintendo Switch/Switch 2 Controller Charging Dock</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Charging wireless controllers can be frustrating, especially if you forget to plug them in after use. For those with the Nintendo Switch, you can only charge the ones on your console usually, leaving your extras without the juice. This charging dock keeps up to four Joy-Cons charged and works with both Switch 1 <em>and </em>Switch 2 controllers.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>AZURAOKEY Carrying Case</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The ASUS ROG Xbox Ally and Ally X are expensive pieces of equipment. So, why not protect the investment with a carrying cat that also comes with compartments for your chargers, memory cards, and other small accessories?</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>SOUNDANCE Laptop Stand</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Not much you can say about a laptop stand. It opens up room on your desk while bringing the display up higher for your eyes. The stand supports laptops ranging from 12-17.3 inches.</p>











<hr>



<p><strong>Press Reset by Jason Schrier</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>From Jason Schreier himself:</p>



<p><strong>“The business of videogames is both a prestige industry and an opaque one. Based on dozens of first-hand interviews that cover the development of landmark games—Bioshock Infinite, Epic Mickey, Dead Space, and more—on to the shocking closures of the studios that made them,&nbsp;Press Reset&nbsp;tells the stories of how real people are affected by game studio shutdowns, and how they recover, move on, or escape the industry entirely.”</strong></p>







<hr>



<p><strong>8Bitdo M30 Bluetooth Controller</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Want a cheap way to play classic Sega Games, or any game for that matter? This M30 Bluetooth Controller is designed to mimic the classic six-button Sega Genesis controller. It works on your Nintendo Switch or Switch 2, Windows PCs, and even mobile devices.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>8BitDo Wireless USB Adapter 2</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Want to guarantee you can hook up any Bluetooth controller to any device? This wireless USB adapter allows you connect your controllers to your Switch 2, Switch, PC, Steam Deck, and more. </p>







<hr>



<p><strong>8Bitdo Bluetooth Retro Receiver&nbsp;</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>If the person you’re buying for still likes to play on their PlayStation (PS1) or PlayStation 2 (PS2), why not give them the gift of wireless control. The 8Bitdo Bluetooth Retro Receiver allows you to use your Xbox, PS4, PS5, Wii U Pro and Switch Pro controllers wirelessly with the PS1 or PS2. Imagine just sitting on your couch that’s more than 10 feet from your TV?</p>











<hr>



<p><strong>UNO: The Legend of Zelda Card Game&nbsp;</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>UNO? Great game. The Legend of Zelda? Great franchise. So, why not combine them with a special version of UNO that features the artwork of The Legend of Zelda. There’s even a special Triforce Card that forces the next player to draw an addition three cards. Get it? Triforce? Three Cards? </p>







<hr>



<p><strong>JSAUX Docking Station</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The Ally X, Steam Deck, Legion Go, and other handheld gaming PCs are all great devices, but sometimes you don’t want to play on the small screen. This docking station—which is actively in use by Senior Editor Mike Straw—allows you to not only hook your handheld to a larger display with HDMI 2.1, but also connect two USB-A devices, an ethernet cable, and a 100W USB-C charging port for your handheld to stay powered during use.</p>







<hr>



<p><strong>Banjo-Kazooie Mobile Phone &amp; Controller Holder</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>An 8.5″ figure made from PVC, this Banjo-Kazooie holder is the perfect place to set your phone, controller, or other small devices when not in use. </p>







<hr>



<p><strong>The Oregon Trail Card Game</strong></p>



<figure></figure>



<p>If you have a millennial you’re shopping for, why not give them the gift of dysentery and let them relive their youth. Supporting 2-6 players with 8-bit art, The Oregon Trail Card Game has you try to stay alive from Independence, Missouri to the Willamette Valley. </p>







<hr>



<p>Are there any gaming gifts on the cheaper side that you are looking to pick up for the 2025 holiday season? Leave your picks down in the comments and join us over at the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<p><em><strong>NOTE:</strong>&nbsp;Insider Gaming may earn affiliate commission if you purchase items through links on Insider Gaming. Read more about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affiliate commission here</a>.</em></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cheap-gaming-gifts-under-25/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Reveals New Special Edition Crocs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-special-edition-crocs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-reveals-new-special-edition-crocs.1363273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Your shoes are now an Xbox. A new collaboration between Xbox and footwear brand Crocs has been announced, and it’s one for the 2000s kids. </p>







<p>With the 20th anniversary of the Xbox 360, Microsoft has been a bit quiet in terms of celebration. Over the weekend, many outlets, like Insider Gaming, did lists on the console, like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/favorite-xbox-360-games-ever/">the staff’s favorite titles</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-selling-xbox-360-games-all-time/">best-selling</a>. However, it seems the company has had one foot in the door the whole time. Luckily, that foot looks rather stylish with the new designs in its collaboration with Crocs.</p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-crocs-available-november-25th-cost-80">Xbox Crocs Available November 25th, Cost $80</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>Announced today, Crocs and Xbox are collaborating on a <a href="https://houseofheat.co/crocs/xbox-crocs-classic-clog-211439-001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">special edition pair of Crocs shoes</a>. The pair will don the Xbox logo and made to look like an Xbox controller, complete with buttons and joysticks. So, basically, your feet can look like controllers. Who doesn’t want that? The collaboration is starting sales on November 25th and will cost $80. If the controller Crocs are too expensive, you can get limited-edition Xbox Jibbitz, which include designs from Fallout, Halo, and League of Legends, to name a few. Those cost around $20 and also launch on November 25th. You can find the link for purchasing <a href="https://www.crocs.com/p/xbox-classic-clog/211439.html?cgid=standard-exclusion-list&amp;cid=001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<p>In the world of collaborations, it’s not a surprise to see Xbox going outside of the box. A while ago, Xbox made an Xbox Series X Mini Fridge, as the console looked like one. While not connected much, the statement <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/david-jaffe-god-of-war-creator-xbox-grave-joke/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘This is an Xbox’</a> does feel apt for this. The company’s desire to be just about everywhere is certainly working, with exclusives like Halo going to PlayStation and future titles going multiplatform. Soon, you won’t be able to outrun an Xbox; you’ll just wear them on your feet.</p>







<p>What do you think of the Xbox Crocs? Going to get a pair? Just buying the Jibbitz? Any other out-there collaborations Microsoft should do? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more on Xbox, check out our articles for last week’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-partner-preview-november-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Partner Preview</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-xbox-exclusive-has-been-nominated-for-goty-since-2010/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft’s unfortunate Game Awards streak</a>. Make sure to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-special-edition-crocs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Receives 8 New Modes in Season 1]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-multiplayer-receives-8-new-modes-in-season-1/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-multiplayer-receives-8-new-modes-in-season-1.1363246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty fans are getting an early treat in Black Ops 7 Multiplayer with Season 1, as eight new modes are coming to the game—six of which will remain permanently available.</p>



<p>Season 1 in Black Ops 7, kicking off on December 4, brings a host of new additions to the title, including a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-season-1-is-getting-six-new-multiplayer-maps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">variety of maps</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-zombies-gets-new-maps-enemies-more-in-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new maps for Zombies</a>, and players in Multiplayer will be spoiled for choice on the game modes to enjoy.</p>







<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-gets-6-new-modes-2-ltms">Black Ops 7 Gets 6 New Modes, 2 LTMs</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Break your bones. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p>As revealed in the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/uk/en/blog/2025/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-warzone-zombies-season-01#Modes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Call of Duty blog</a>, Black Ops 7 will see the addition of eight new Multiplayer modes, two of which are limited-time only and will form a part of the CODMAS event.</p>



<p>The permanent game modes being added include Prop Hunt, Gun Game, One in the Chamber, and Sticks and Stones, along with a new mode, Takeover, where players fight over three neutral territories and earn points for each zone they control. Once all three zones are captured, a short cooldown takes place before they move to new locations—effectively making it a mix of Domination and Headquarters.</p>



<p>During the season, two limited-time modes are coming as part of CODMAS festivities. Holiday Havoc is a “festive moshpit combiting your favourite modes with holiday cheer,” where players can earn bonuses like Quick Regen, Spring Speed, and Movement Speed for eliminating enemies.</p>



<p>Snowfight is the other LTM featuring in-season, which, as the name suggests, sees players throw snowballs at each other to eliminate them, with no respawns. </p>



<p>Season 1 in Multiplayer also brings additional loadout content in the form of the Deadeye Drone, available as a Weekly Challenge Reward during the season for completing weekly objectives.</p>







<hr>



<p>Which of the game modes coming to Black Ops 7 are you most excited for? Share your thoughts with other players in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-suffers-worst-launch-in-20-year-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">record low of sales in Japan</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-dark-ops-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all of the Dark Ops Challenges in Zombies</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-multiplayer-receives-8-new-modes-in-season-1/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Zombies Gets New Maps, Enemies & More in Season 1]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-zombies-gets-new-maps-enemies-more-in-season-1/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-zombies-gets-new-maps-enemies-more-in-season-1.1363201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Season 1 is on the horizon in Black Ops 7, and the first season in the latest Call of Duty title is bringing a host of new content across all game modes, including Zombies.</p>



<p>Zombies in Black Ops 7 launched with two maps, the larger, story-based Ashes of the Damned map, with a smaller segment of the map, Vandorn Farm, used for the Survival mode, and the tally of maps is set to more than double in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 1</a>—along with the addition of new enemies and the return of content from other Black Ops titles.</p>







<h2 id="h-zombies-receives-new-map-amp-two-survival-maps-in-black-ops-7-season-1">Zombies Receives New Map &amp; Two Survival Maps in Black Ops 7 Season 1</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New map. Image via Activision </figcaption></figure>



<p>As revealed in the latest blog post ahead of Season 1, which kicks off on December 4, Astra Malorum is the next story map in Zombies where players explore “an evil presence festering in the Dark Aether.”</p>



<p>The map features a new enemy, the O.S.C.A.R Elite Robot, a new Wonder Weapon, the LGM-1, and new traps, alongside the story quest and easter eggs to uncover.</p>



<p>For players grinding through Camo challenges and wanting a change of scenery from Vandorm Farm, Season 1 provides exactly that with Exit 115, another location from the larger Ashes of the Damned map, available in Survival from launch, with the Zorya Observatory following in mid-season.</p>



<p>Alongside the new maps, a slew of new and returning Ammo Mods will become available, including Light Mind and Shatter Blast, Field Upgrades, including Tesla Storm and Frost Blast, and the return of the fan-favorite Perk Mule Kick—all of which have their own Research to complete.</p>



<p>Zombies will also support the addition of seven new weapons, with some available at the start and others arriving mid-season, 11 new Weapon Attachments, while Directed Mode for the Ashes of the Damned story quest will also be available, guiding players through the necessary steps for completion.</p>







<hr>



<p>What do you think about the Season 1 additions coming to Black Ops 7 Zombies? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-player-count-black-ops-7-player-count/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s player count compared to Battlefield 6</a>, and check out details of a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-sales-are-down-50-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">huge drop in sales for the franchise in Europe</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-zombies-gets-new-maps-enemies-more-in-season-1/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows x Attack on Titan Crossover Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-x-attack-on-titan-crossover-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-x-attack-on-titan-crossover-announced.1363195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows’ Attack on Titan crossover is live with title update 1.1.6; however, the quest is only available for a limited time, until December 22, 2025. </p>



<p>The details about Assassin’s Creed Shadows have been less lately, with AC Mirage taking up the news in recent days. We recently learned the title <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-mirage-hits-10-million-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossed 10 million players</a> thanks to the arrival of its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-mirage-valley-of-memory-dlc-patch-notes-new-free-content-gameplay-improvements-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Valley of Memory DLC</a>. Now, we are receiving new content for AC Shadows as well, with popular manga and anime series Attack on Titan making its way into the game. </p>







<h2 id="h-assassin-s-creed-shadows-attack-on-titan-crossover-will-add-new-skins-for-yasuke-and-naoe">Assassin’s Creed: Shadows’ Attack on Titan Crossover Will Add New Skins for Yasuke and Naoe</h2>



<p>The Assassin’s Creed Shadows Attack on Titan crossover goes live on November 25 and will run until December 22. During this time, players can take part in a limited-time quest where they face a mysterious, power-hungry faction that has infiltrated feudal Japan and kidnapped a Titan Shifter. There’s a lone survivor with a dark secret who fails to rescue the Shifter and then recruits Naoe and Yasuke to help them out. </p>



<p>To unlock the AOT quest in AC Shadows, players will have to first unlock Yasuke as a playable character and then head to the Yamashiro region, North of Hanazo Tower. While playing the quest, players will unlock new banners and a statue for their hideout and will acquire a crystal katana for Naoe once completed. </p>



<p>Along with the quest, AC Shadows will also receive the Attack on Titan Dual Pack, which is inspired by the series’ universe. This pack includes new outfits, weapons, trinkets, and a new mount. Some of what we saw in the trailer showed Naoe wearing Mikasa Ackerman’s iconic costume, and Yasuke wearing a titan-themed armour. </p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-assassin-s-creed-shadows-third-story-drop-a-puzzlement">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Third Story Drop: A Puzzlement</h2>



<p>Assassin’s Creed: Shadows title update 1.1.6 introduces the game’s third story drop, along with the Attack on Titan crossover. The new quest is called “A Puzzlement”, and it has been described as fun and humorous. It will feature Yasuke and Naoe engaging with two old acquaintances who are having a loud argument about a mysterious door in South Wakasa, and they have tasked the duo with figuring out how to open it. </p>



<p>The quest will have Yasuke and Naoe learning each other’s skills as well. Naoe will learn to perform her own spectacular version of Yasuke’s war-kick ability. Yasuke will learn to stealthily dispatch enemies non-lethally. Players will also finally be able to settle the debate as to who would win in a straight-up duel between our two protagonists. </p>



<h2 id="h-assassin-s-creed-shadows-title-update-1-1-6-patch-notes">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Title Update 1.1.6 Patch Notes</h2>



<p>The new update also features improvements towards Corrupted Castles and a host of bug fixes that you can check out in the patch notes below: </p>



<h3 id="Q29ycnVwdGVkJTIwQ2Fz">Corrupted Castles</h3>



<p>Improvements have also been made to Corrupted Castles. The chances of encountering the same castles from the previous season have been reduced, and the available castles each season will now provide a better distribution of Daisho per castles.</p>



<h3 id="TGlzdCUyMG9mJTIwQnVn">List of Bug Fixes</h3>



<p><em><strong>SPOILER WARNING</strong></em></p>



<h3 id="U3RhYmlsaXR5">Stability</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the game crashed when switching to the ‘Sell Items’ tab in some menus.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="R2FtZXBsYXk=">Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Corrected the two Tanuki Sumi-e rewards so they are no longer swapped.</li>



<li>Sword Hunter’s Prized Odachi Blade can now be obtained from the Sword Hunter.</li>



<li>Loadout slots will no longer reset automatically after completing quests.</li>



<li>Sliding doors will no longer prevent players from summoning allies.&nbsp;<em>You shall now pass!</em></li>



<li>Resolved an issue where the gear vendor in Mibuno Vale kept some engravings for himself.</li>



<li>Addressed a naming issue between the Green Pheasant and the Copper Pheasant, where they sometimes switched personalities.&nbsp;<em>Freaky…</em></li>



<li>Ezio gear engravings now correctly unlock between multiple saves.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the player could purchase the same swords Karuta cards multiple times.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Sword of Fathoms Katana allowed a double transmog exploit, enabling a stack of four engravings.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where certain Bunny, Deer and Doe, Green Pheasant and Flying Squirrel pets were unobtainable.</li>



<li>Players will no longer get stuck when trying to exit Miyataki Warehouse.&nbsp;<em>Get outside and touch some grass!</em></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="Q29tYmF0">Combat</h3>



<ul>
<li>Yasuke can now correctly perform finishers with non-postured attacks.</li>



<li>Addressed an issue where the Bo Staff did not trigger Counterstrike as intended.</li>



<li>Summoned allies will no longer flee combat after only taking only a few hits.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="VUk=">UI</h3>



<ul>
<li>Addressed an issue where the UI indicator for pricing displayed reversed values.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="VmlzdWFscyUyMCUyNiUy">Visuals &amp; Graphics</h3>



<ul>
<li>Addressed an issue where the Dragon Hideout building skin was missing the floor.</li>



<li>The Robe of Ezio outfit no longer glitches while climbing.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Widower’s Solace Saya Katana was a duplicate of Iga’s Flame Saya Katana.</li>



<li>Corrected the knowledge description formatting for Naoe’s&nbsp;<strong>“Damage With Ability”</strong>.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Kimura Kei had texture clipping through his legs during the fight in the quest&nbsp;<strong>“Fighting For The Cause”</strong>.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="TG9jYWxpemF0aW9u">Localization</h3>



<ul>
<li>Corrected some NPC dialogue in Italian that addressed Naoe despite playing as Yasuke.</li>



<li>Corrected the Momochi Sandayu German voice lines during the&nbsp;<strong>“Traditions”</strong>&nbsp;quest.</li>



<li>Addressed an issue where Korean characters (봇 윙 슐 낍) displayed as corrupted square boxes (□).</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="UXVlc3Rz">Quests</h3>



<p><em><strong>MAJOR SPOILERS AHEAD!</strong></em></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>“Fighting For The Cause”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where Kimura Kei could get stuck on a balcony and become invulnerable during the quest.</li>



<li><strong>“Go With The Bo”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where items such as the Long Stick Disciple costume and headband obtained from the quest were missing.</li>



<li><strong>“Ride Into Town”:</strong>&nbsp;Addressed an issue where players were unable to proceed in the quest because Rin wouldn’t move.</li>



<li><strong>“Suika No Bakemono”:</strong>&nbsp;Corrected the quest reward.</li>



<li><strong>“The Pirate Alliance”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where the quest could not be completed because Oni-Yuri glitched when killed.</li>



<li>Players will now correctly receive the Classic Tea Bowl collection after defeating&nbsp;<strong>“The Wise”</strong>.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="Q2xhd3MlMjBvZiUyMEF3">Claws of Awaji</h3>



<ul>
<li>Addressed an issue where Yasuhira’s Secret could not be collected after completing the DLC.</li>



<li>Corrected the description for Yasuhira’s Secret (Spymaster EPZ Fallback Letter).</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where moving a plank at Myoshoji Temple with Yasuke, caused it to no longer be moved by Naoe.</li>



<li>Naoe will no longer get stuck on the big tree in Izanagi Shrine during the quest&nbsp;<strong>“A Snake In The Shrine”</strong>.</li>



<li>Keys collectibles are now correctly present, with a total of 15 collectibles scattered across Awaji island.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="UExBVEZPUk0lMjBTUEVD">PLATFORM SPECIFIC</h3>



<h3 id="WEJPWA==">XBOX</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the audio cuts out, and the game crashes on Xbox after Title Update 1.1.1.</li>
</ul>



<p>The new update details were found on Ubisoft’s <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/24vAMck2BzVz0g5VAQNtDg/ac-shadows-title-update-116-release-notes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website</a>. </p>







<p>In other news, check out Insider Gaming’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-black-flag-remake-set-to-launch-before-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive report</a> which states Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Remake will release before March 31. What are your thoughts on Assassin’s Creed Shadows x Attack on Titan? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/skate-story-will-be-a-day-one-launch-on-playstation-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Skate Story becoming a Day One launch on PlayStation Plus</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-x-attack-on-titan-crossover-announced/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>