<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:47:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat 2 Movie Will Now Release a Week Earlier]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-2-movie-release-date-change/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-2-movie-will-now-release-a-week-earlier.1331197/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s only been a couple of months since it was officially announced that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-mortal-kombat-2-trailer-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mortal Kombat 2</a> movie will be missing its 2025 release date and will be pushed back to May 2026; however, a new tidbit of news has once again changed the movie’s release date.</p>



<p>Moving from its pre-planned May 22nd, 2026 release date, Mortal Kombat 2 is not set to launch one week earlier on May 15, 2026.</p>



<p>Presumably, the date change is intended to give the film breathing room in what appears to be shaping up to be a busy month for movies in May. Notably, it avoids a same-day release as The Mandalorian and Grogu movie, which is set to launch on May 22nd.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-mortal-kombat-2-avoiding-gta-6">Is Mortal Kombat 2 Avoiding GTA 6?</h2>



<p>The movie industry usually doesn’t take note of video game releases, but it could be said that the release date move may also have been made to avoid Grand Theft Auto 6’s release date, which is currently scheduled for May 26th.</p>



<p>In the industry’s eyes, GTA 6 could be a once-in-a-lifetime event for the video game industry, causing millions of gamers to hunker down to play the game. Although movies don’t tend to take notice of video games, I think this is such an unprecedented release, that it was a wise decision if they decided to change because of it.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to watching Mortal Kombat 2 on May 15th? Let me know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>&nbsp;if you’re hoping for a resurgence of Scarface: The World is Yours.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the updated news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-launch-a-week-early/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 7&nbsp;<strong>is not&nbsp;</strong>being released early</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-2-movie-release-date-change/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Many People Can Play RV There Yet? RV There Yet Max Players, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/how-many-people-can-play-rv-there-yet-max-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-many-people-can-play-rv-there-yet-rv-there-yet-max-players-explained.1331194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>You need to know how many people and players can play RV There Yet together if you’ve ever wanted to build haggard-looking contraptions to get an RV over obstacles, negotiate tight mountain roads leading to almost-certain death, and smoke stuff with a moose loose on the RV.</p>



<p>That was quite the opening paragraph, yet it encapsulates everything <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rv-there-yet-playstation-xbox-nintendo-switch-console/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RV There Yet?</a> is about. The Nuggets Entertainment project borrows the odd idea from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/peak-devs-announce-a-new-co-op-title/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PEAK</a>—understandably, given PEAK’s unbelievable success—and adds its own flair.</p>



<p>One familiar gameplay is how many people can play RV There Yet? If you want to know if this is a co-op title with AI, or a fun party co-op game, you’re in the right place.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-players-can-play-rv-there-yet-together">How Many Players Can Play RV There Yet Together?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Nuggets Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>RV There Yet? allows for a maximum of up to four players to work together to get the all-terrain vehicle where it needs to be.</strong></p>



<p>The RV isn’t strictly an all-terrain vehicle, but you certainly need it to be to clear Route 65 in the game. Figuring out how to get past the next inconvenience is all part of the fun in RV There Yet?, and you can do so with at least three other players in your game.</p>



<p>Three of you can kick back and chill in the background, smoking and enjoying your best life, while one of you has the unenviable task of driving the RV and trying not to get it lodged in perilous positions. Exiting Route 65 is tough, but it’s better with friends, although it’s not <em>technically </em>a requirement.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-rv-there-yet-solo">Can You Play RV There Yet? Solo?</h2>



<p><strong>Officially, RV There Yet? can be tackled solo, but it’s not recommended, as the game wasn’t designed this way.</strong></p>



<p>RV There Yet? is easily at its best when there are a few of you coming together. Would Among Us, Lethal Company, Content Warning, or any similar multiplayer game be as fun if you played them by yourself?</p>



<p>Plus, there’s the fact that a dev doesn’t recommend it: “[The] game is 2-4 players (technically can play solo but wasn’t made for that),” says jace on the official RV There Yet? <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1422517981216374818/1427593942232207481/1429856409188700292" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For now, we recommend following these instructions and finding one to three buddies to team up with.</p>



<p>If you do play RV There Yet? on your own, let us know how it goes and if it’s even possible to complete the game. For anything else, head on over to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming Discord</a> to discuss the breakout hit or anything else gaming-related.</p>



<hr>



<p>Also, if you want other indie content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-many-players-can-play-repo-multiplayer-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How Many Players Can Play REPO?</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-many-people-can-play-peak-max-players-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How Many People Can Play Peak?</a> for similar guides and answers.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/how-many-people-can-play-rv-there-yet-max-players/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is RV There Yet? On PlayStation, Xbox Or Nintendo Switch? Console Status Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rv-there-yet-playstation-xbox-nintendo-switch-console/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-rv-there-yet-on-playstation-xbox-or-nintendo-switch-console-status-explained.1331182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The age of climbing games continues with RV There Yet? Another manic title with enough comedic juice to fill a swimming pool. PC players are currently lapping up the bizarre action in it, but as an indie title, it means RV There Yet? on PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch consoles is unclear.</p>



<p>RV There Yet? is just as bonkers as it looks in the trailers. You navigate a classic RV through basic forests and woodland areas to the most perilous of scenarios and impossible-looking climbs. What could go wrong! It follows in the footsteps (and footholds) of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/peak-devs-announce-a-new-co-op-title/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PEAK</a> and other climbing games.</p>



<p>Whether you love the genre or you want to get yourself into some chaotic mishaps, we have information on the game’s console status.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-rv-there-yet-on-playstation-consoles">Can You Play RV There Yet? On PlayStation Consoles?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Sure. Credit to Nuggets Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You currently can’t play RV There Yet? on PlayStation 4 or PlayStation 5 consoles.</strong></p>



<p>That’s two down, unfortunately. RV There Yet can’t be played on current-gen or last-gen PlayStation hardware. It’s not a matter of whether the consoles can support the game—as we know they’re more than powerful enough—but it comes down to coding an indie PC game for a different platform, money, and other factors.</p>



<p>It could be a while until we see it on PlayStation, if ever.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-rv-there-yet-on-xbox-consoles">Can You Play RV There Yet? On Xbox Consoles?</h2>



<p><strong>Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S players also have to miss out on RV There Yet? as it’s also not on Microsoft consoles for now.</strong></p>



<p>It’s not going great. RV There Yet? also can’t make any stops for Xbox users. It’s a similar situation for the Xbox as it is for PlayStation, and until a wider console launch is announced, Xbox owners don’t get to experience RV There Yet either.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-rv-there-yet-on-nintendo-switch">Can You Play RV There Yet? On Nintendo Switch?</h2>



<p><strong>It’s a clean sweep as RV There Yet? isn’t available on either the Nintendo Switch or the Switch 2 successor.</strong></p>



<p>The original Switch had a habit of not incorporating wider third-party AAA titles, but would be home to indie titles—some of which Nintendo got first before PlayStation and Xbox, such as Hades.</p>



<p>However, there’s no such luck with RV There yet? Not even the more powerful and superior Switch 2 has a port lined up yet.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-rv-there-yet-ever-come-to-consoles">Will RV There Yet Ever Come To Consoles?</h2>



<p><strong>The game’s developer “isn’t sure” if RV There Yet will ever see the light of day on consoles.</strong></p>



<p>RV There Yet’s Discord server is quite active, and one user <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1422517981216374818/1427593942232207481/1429855678939398296" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">asked</a>: “Will the game release on console alongside Steam? (If it will have a console release at all?)</p>



<p>jace—a dev and community manager for the game’s Discord—<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1422517981216374818/1427593942232207481/1429856287688102030" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said this</a> concerning a console launch:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“No console release planned at this stage. And unfortunately I’m not great with hardware so I’m not sure.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s not ruled out altogether. As with other breakout indie games, it will likely depend on the game’s long-term profitability, sustainability, and interest in a wider launch. We’ll let you know if the day comes when RV There Yet drives down to PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo demanding a console release.</p>



<p>Have you managed to get on RV There Yet? early, before the game goes viral? How do you think it compares to its contemporaries? Let us know through our own <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out more IG gaming duies, such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders Roadmap latest</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-ninja-gaiden-4-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How long to beat Ninja Gaiden 4</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/rv-there-yet-playstation-xbox-nintendo-switch-console/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Roadmap, Explained—All Future ARC Raiders Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-roadmap/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-roadmap-explained%E2%80%94all-future-arc-raiders-plans.1331167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New extraction shooter ARC Raiders is looking to ‘Embark’ on a long journey. Whether it has the legs remains to be seen, but we’ve extracted some new information about the shooter and the potential ARC Raiders roadmap of future content.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a> is one of the big, new multiplayer dogs in 2025. With Call of Duty unable to crack the DMZ nut, Escape From Tarkov has largely had the genre to itself. Say hello to Embark Studios’ ARC Raiders!</p>



<p>The extraction shooter has had multiple betas—including the late-on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/has-arc-raiders-server-slam-playtest-been-extended-playtest-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Server Slam playtest</a>—and it’s time to look forward instead of back.</p>



<h2 id="h-does-arc-raiders-have-a-roadmap">Does ARC Raiders Have A Roadmap?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We expect to travel and go everywhere. Credit to Embark Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, ARC Raiders doesn’t officially have a roadmap yet, as Embark Studios is unwilling to commit to additional content plans for the time being.</strong></p>



<p>However, it doesn’t mean the developer isn’t thinking about the future, and this is evident with he shocking reveal that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-will-add-10-years-worth-of-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders devs are already planning 10 years worth of content</a>.</p>



<p>Embark Studios design lead Virgil Watkins said: “I think internally, for a very long time, we referred to this [ARC Raiders] as a 10-year game. That is the ambition we are aiming for and that dictates the type and quantity of content we want to put into it.”</p>



<p>We often see multiplayer games and single-player games with season passes announce future content before the current chunk of gameplay is out! <a href="https://arcraiders.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ARC Raiders</a> isn’t going down this path anytime soon, as these plans can “Spiral into promises that can go unfulfilled if things change.”</p>



<h2 id="h-what-new-content-is-coming-to-arc-raiders">What New Content Is Coming To ARC Raiders?</h2>



<p><strong>Virgil Watkins has stated that ARC Raiders is likely to add fresh maps, more quests, and additional common-sense content throughout the game’s lifespan.</strong></p>



<p>Here’s the design lead’s words in full: “Of course, adding things over time like new maps, extending questlines, and introducing new enemies and new weapons, and things like that. We’ll have some stuff lined up post-launch and for a little bit after, but then it will be based on what we see out of the launch and thereafter.”</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It sounds like the typical content you’d come to expect from a post-game launch for an extraction shooter. We respect the fact that the team doesn’t want to put a timeframe on the new content and see how the launch plays out first.</p>



<p>Based on your time in any of the game’s playtests, what do you think ARC Raiders is lacking? It’s time to let us know via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> and the comments section below.</p>



<hr>



<p>We have much more ARC Raiders content, including <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-price-free-to-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its price and whether it’s free to play</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-early-access-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">if there’s Launch Early Access</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-will-have-optional-progression-wipes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders has optional progression wipes</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-roadmap/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legendary GTA Competitor ‘Scarface’ Coming to Steam and Epic with HD Graphics Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/scarface-world-is-yours-coming-to-steam-and-epic/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legendary-gta-competitor-%E2%80%98scarface%E2%80%99-coming-to-steam-and-epic-with-hd-graphics-mode.1331128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In recent hours, eagle-eyed gamers have scoured repositories on Steam and Epic Games on PC to find out everything they can about a reappearance of 2006’s <strong>Scarface: The World is Yours</strong>. The open-world title emerged as a competitor to Grand Theft Auto on the PlayStation 2, but due to complex licensing issues, it was never revisited.</p>



<p>It now <span>appears to be being brought back to life by a new publisher,&nbsp;<strong>and&nbsp;</strong>it is being given a new face with an HD graphics mode added</span> as a DLC. In case you’re unfamiliar, The World is Yours puts players in the shoes of Tony Montana from the 1983 Scarface movie, presenting an alternate universe in which he survives an assassination attempt and must rebuild his drug empire.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-is-scarface-the-world-is-yours-coming-back">Is Scarface: The World is Yours Coming Back?</h2>



<p>Scarface: The World is Yours has always been one of those games that fans have desperately sought a remaster of. It was released in 2006 and offered a large open-world map of Miami, customization options, the ability to rebuild and decorate Tony Montana’s iconic mansion, and the gameplay loop facilitated the construction of an <strong>empire</strong>.</p>



<p>It was buggy as hell in many ways, and the PC port that was released way back when was a shambles, but on PlayStation 2, the game was a certified banger that still sits firmly in my mind twenty years later. It was originally pieced together by Radical Entertainment, the same studio that made The Simpsons Hit &amp; Run and the Prototype games.</p>



<p>Scarface: The World is Yours was a heavily licensed game that featured Al Pacino’s likeness as Tony Montana, dialogue, direct-to-game story elements, a top soundtrack, and branding. This long presented a licensing concern when the discussion came about remastering or re-releasing the game.</p>



<p>Now, Hong Kong-based publisher EC Digital Entertainment appears to be floating the game on digital platforms <strong>for the first time</strong>. The unheard-of publisher seems to be backing a re-release of Scarface: The World is Yours on the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/scarface-the-world-is-yours-7c3e6f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Epic Store</a> and on Valve’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4113570/Scarface_The_World_Is_Yours_2006/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam</a> storefront, but no release date has been given.</p>



<p>It has been suggested by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1ocxf5r/scarface_the_world_is_yours_store_page_shows_up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">some users on social media</a> that the Epic Games store, especially, has been ‘released early’ in what looks like some twisted backend glitch.</p>



<p>Scarface: The World is Yours is a game that all Grand Theft Auto fans should check out. It might have twenty years on it by now, but it’s a phenomenal title that was overshadowed by the earlier launch of GTA: San Andreas in late 2004 and the later launch of GTA: IV in 2008.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’re hoping for a resurgence of Scarface: The World is Yours.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the updated news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-launch-a-week-early/">Black Ops 7 <strong>is not </strong>being released early</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/scarface-world-is-yours-coming-to-steam-and-epic/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 3 Reload Bringing Back Original Singer for New Update]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/persona-3-reload-original-singer-yumi-kawamura-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-3-reload-bringing-back-original-singer-for-new-update.1331053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Persona 3 Reload is bringing back the original’s singer with a new update celebrating the Nintendo Switch 2 release.</p>



<p>Released in 2024, Persona 3 Reload served as the series’ first remake, bringing the 2006 original back to life for newer generations. With the changes, the original vocalist, Yumi Kawamura, did not return. Instead, the music was sung by Azumi Takahashi, as well as returning contributor Lotus Juice. Upon its release, it received tons of praise for its reinvention of the game and dedication to the original. An expansion, titled Project Aigis, came out later that year and acted as an epilogue to the game’s narrative. A port of Persona 3 Reload is launching on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/persona-3-reload-nintendo-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> on October 23rd and, as celebration, a nostalgic voice is making her return.</p>



<h2 id="h-yumi-kawamura-s-original-persona-3-songs-returning-for-persona-3-reload-in-upcoming-update">Yumi Kawamura’s Original Persona 3 Songs Returning for Persona 3 Reload in Upcoming Update</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>An iconic voice returns to Persona 3 Reload… 🎤🎶</p><p>Listen to eight dungeon and battle BGM tracks by the original Persona 3 vocalist – Yumi Kawamura – when the game launches on Nintendo Switch 2! </p><p>Patch will be available on all platforms. <a href="https://t.co/cZKpuVTWyP">pic.twitter.com/cZKpuVTWyP</a></p></div>— Official ATLUS West (@Atlus_West) <a href="https://twitter.com/Atlus_West/status/1980787484729430169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://x.com/Atlus_West/status/1980787484729430169" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Twitter/X</a>, Atlus West revealed that songs from the original Persona 3 and FES will be coming to Reload on October 23rd, when the Nintendo Switch 2 version is released. To celebrate the occasion, vocalist Yumi Kawamura, who performed the songs for the 2006 JRPG, spoke about the addition. In a statement below, she says</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“It’s been a while!” Kawamura states. “I’m truly overjoyed and grateful to be reunited with everyone again. Persona 3 is a treasure to me as well—I can’t help but feel excited. Old friends, will you fight alongside me once more? New friends, how about letting my songs aid you in battle? Let’s celebrate together. Thank you for your continued support!”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The songs being added to Persona 3 Reload from Persona 3 and FES are as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li>“Burn My Dread -Last Battle-“</li>



<li>“Mass Destruction”</li>



<li>“Deep Mentality”</li>



<li>“When The Moon’s&nbsp;Reaching Out Stars”</li>



<li>“Want to Be Close”</li>



<li>“Memories of You”</li>



<li>“Mass Destruction -P3fes Version-“</li>



<li>“Brand New Days”</li>
</ul>



<p>It’s important to note that the songs will only be available during exploration in Tartarus and in battles. The songs, as mentioned before, will come to Persona 3 Reload on October 23rd via a new patch. Luckily, all consoles, like PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S will get to listen to Yumi’s iconic tracks then, too. While Azumi’s versions of Persona 3’s songs were great, Yumi’s rasp and range can’t be beat. As a fan of the series, it’s good to see her renditions return and add some nostalgia to the amazing turn-based gameplay.</p>



<p>Are you excited to see Yumi’s versions come to Persona 3 Reload? Who do you prefer, Yumi or Azumi? Did you play the remake? What did you think of it? Let us know in the comments below and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Persona, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/persona-4-revival-not-releasing-until-at-least-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Persona 4 Revival</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/p-studio-director-already-hinting-at-next-persona-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the series’ future</a>. Don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/persona-3-reload-original-singer-yumi-kawamura-update/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi’s Mansion Coming to Nintendo Switch Online This Halloween]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/luigis-mansion-nintendo-switch-online-halloween-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/luigi%E2%80%99s-mansion-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-this-halloween.1331041/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Luigi’s Mansion is coming to Nintendo Switch 2 via Nintendo Switch Online just in time for Halloween.</p>



<p>As a benefit of Nintendo Switch Online, many nostalgic games from Nintendo’s past are available to play. From NES classics like Donkey Kong to Game Boy hits like Tetris, there’s a lot to enjoy for fans. With the newly released Nintendo Switch 2, an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/switch-2-upgrade-pack-details-revealed-for-nintendo-switch-online-users/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Expansion Pack</a> including GameCube, Nintendo 64, and Game Boy Advance titles was released. As the catalog grows, with recent additions including Forsaken 64 and Chibi-Robo, a spooky hit from the 2000s is coming just in time for Halloween.</p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-switch-online-adding-luigi-s-mansion-releasing-october-30th">Nintendo Switch Online Adding Luigi’s Mansion, Releasing October 30th</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Luigi’s Mansion – Nintendo GameCube – Nintendo Classics" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GvN4hHpfVqQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://youtu.be/GvN4hHpfVqQ?si=YMZmjm1kbZz5gIyG" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a new video</a> from Nintendo, the company announced that Luigi’s Mansion is headed to Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack. Furthermore, you won’t have to wait long to play it, as it releases on October 30th, 2025, the day before Halloween. The iconic 2001 title, released on the Nintendo GameCube, has since gone on to have a 3DS re-release and two other mainline entries.&nbsp;Luigi’s Mansion follows Mario’s brother, Luigi, as he navigates a ghost-infested mansion in search of his brother and friends. With a handy Poltergust 3000 and the kooky Prof. E. Gadd, you’ll take down the many ghosts and specters you’ll encounter.</p>



<p>The most recent title from the Luigi’s Mansion series was a re-release of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-know-about-luigis-mansion-2-hd/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD</a> for the Nintendo Switch in 2024. As for the last mainline entry, that was Luigi’s Mansion 3 in 2019, also for the Nintendo Switch. Its success as a Mario spinoff has made it a household name and one many hope makes a return with a new game. Perhaps the addition to Nintendo Switch Online could be a sign it’s in the works or if interest is there? In any case, Luigi’s Mansion’s addition is a scare we all can enjoy.</p>



<p>Are you going to play Luigi’s Mansion with Nintendo Switch Online? Did you play the original on GameCube? 3DS? What do you think of the game? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Nintendo news, check out our articles on a possible DS patent and the company’s sales hope for the Switch 2. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/luigis-mansion-nintendo-switch-online-halloween-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>