<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:32:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Takes Two & Split Fiction Director Posts BTS Of New Hazelight Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/it-takes-two-split-fiction-director-posts-bts-of-new-hazelight-game/</link>
            <guid>1430878</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The director of It Takes Two and Split Fiction has posted a behind-the-scenes picture of the next Hazelight title. </p>



<p>During the last interview, the director had <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hazelight-is-already-working-on-its-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that a new Hazelight title was already in development; however, it was still in its early stages, with only 130 pages of ideas ready for the upcoming game’s story. Now, he’s given players another teaser that doesn’t offer any concrete information.</p>







<h2 id="h-hazelight-s-next-game-seems-to-be-progressing-well">Hazelight’s Next Game Seems to be Progressing Well</h2>



<p>The new teaser has informed players that the next Hazelight game has progressed in some way. The director of It Takes Two and Split Fiction, Josef Fares, has posted a new image on <a href="https://x.com/josef_fares/status/2021163743036486041" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) that appears to show the game’s cast wearing full-motion capture outfits, with all their faces covered by Fares’ arm.</p>



<p>The director posted the caption “Next game in the making” with this picture, and Hazelight responded, stating the developers are “back in the kitchen, cookin’ up something really delicious”. They also poked fun at the image and Fares’ pose, stating that they now feature “Strategic Arm Placement Tech”. </p>



<p>Talking about Josef Fares, he also recently confirmed that the “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-movies-first-version-of-the-script-has-been-finalized/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first version of the script</a>” for Split Fiction’s movie adaptation had been shown to him. Fares has also spoken with Sydney Sweeney, who is reportedly playing one of the characters in the movie. The director stated, “She seems pretty chill” and “hyped for the movie.”</p>







<p>What are your thoughts on the behind-the-scenes images posted by It Takes Two and Split Fiction’s director for Hazelight’s next game? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhong-kui-is-cooking-with-new-special-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Science literally and figuratively ‘cooking’ with the latest special video for Black Myth: Zhong Kui</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/it-takes-two-split-fiction-director-posts-bts-of-new-hazelight-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Zhong Kui Is ‘Cooking’ With New Special Video]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhong-kui-is-cooking-with-new-special-video/</link>
            <guid>1430833</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New Black Myth: Zhong Kui is an in-engine video where the devs have literally and figuratively cooked. </p>



<p>The next title for the highly popular series by Game Science, Black Myth: Zhong Kui, was revealed during <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhongkui-revealed-at-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamescom 2025’s Opening Night Live</a>. The title is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-sequel-to-black-myth-wukong/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not a direct sequel</a> to the series, but shares &nbsp;“the same foundation of ancient Chinese myth and folklore.” Now, a new in-engine video shows what the game could look like. </p>







<h2 id="h-black-myth-zhong-kui-video-goes-full-masterchef-with-monster-ingredients">Black Myth: Zhong Kui Video Goes Full MasterChef with Monster Ingredients</h2>



<p>The latest video for Black Myth: Zhong Kui is a 6-minute in-engine <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n2tW6ewI5ls" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">special</a> created for the Chinese New Year, specifically celebrating the Year of the Horse. The video begins like a typical cooking show, showcasing the character chopping and preparing various ingredients. It starts with the featured character filleting a fish, setting the tone for the cooking theme.</p>



<p>Everything appears normal at first, but then we begin to notice monsters lurking in the background. These creatures are actually assisting the chef. Some scenes in the video may be unsettling for those with a weak stomach, as we see the chef chopping up meat with eyeballs and plucking chives from a creature that resembles a sleeping baby.</p>



<p>The soup is finally prepared and served to a mysterious figure wearing a hood towards the end of the video. What’s exciting is the level of detail and realism displayed by the engine, particularly in how the character interacts with each ingredient. We already knew that Game Science had raised the bar since “Wukong,” but “Zhong Kui” appears to be advancing the series even further in terms of visuals.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Black Myth: Zhong Kui — 6 Min In-Engine Chinese New Year Special" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n2tW6ewI5ls?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In other news, a recent claim suggests that Black Myth: Wukong will be released<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-will-release-on-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> for the Nintendo Switch 2</a>. What are your thoughts on the new Black Myth: Zhong Kui in-engine video? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-is-getting-a-large-scale-expansion-like-iceborne-and-sunbreak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds getting a large-scale expansion like Iceborne or Sunbreak</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhong-kui-is-cooking-with-new-special-video/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Is Getting a “Large Scale Expansion” Like Iceborne and Sunbreak]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-is-getting-a-large-scale-expansion-like-iceborne-and-sunbreak/</link>
            <guid>1430809</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds producer has revealed that a new large-scale expansion is in development, matching the likes of Iceborne and Sunbreak expansions for previous games. </p>



<p>Since the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-free-title-update-4-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">title update 4</a>, we haven’t received many new details about the game. Last we heard was information through a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-datamine-reveals-graphics-presets-for-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">datamine</a>, which gave us an idea of the graphic preset details for the Switch 2. Now, the developers have arrived with a brand-new update, along with confirmation that a huge expansion is in the works. </p>







<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-new-expansion-confirmed">Monster Hunter Wilds New Expansion Confirmed</h2>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds producer Ryozo Tsujimoto spoke about the “large-scale expansion” at the end of the update 1.041’s reveal <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/2021026692781965533" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">video</a>. Tsujimoto wanted to assure players that they have something big planned next for MHW, a new expansion is in development, matching the likes of MH Worlds’ Iceborne and MH Rise’s Subreak expansion. More details about this update are scheduled to arrive “this summer.”</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MHWilds?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MHWilds</a> Producer Ryozo Tsujimoto shares a look at the update arriving on Feb 18, and what's ahead in the future.</p><p>⛓ Arch-tempered Arkveld<br>⭐ 10-star Arch-tempered monsters<br>🐱 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MHStories3?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MHStories3</a> Special Collaboration<br>🍖 Design Contest Weapon &amp; Pendant<br>🎉 Anniversary Event + Event… <a href="https://t.co/MrqhiS2iAg">pic.twitter.com/MrqhiS2iAg</a></p></div>— Monster Hunter (@monsterhunter) <a href="https://twitter.com/monsterhunter/status/2021026692781965533?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 10, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Iceborne and Sunbreak are some of the biggest expansions in the series. Iceborne almost doubled the content for Monster Hunter World, adding new monsters, story, locales, and so much more. Sunbreak was massive as well, adding a new adventure, enemies, gameplay improvements, and more. So the one for MHW definitely has some work cut out for it, as it has to surpass some huge benchmarks. </p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-update-1-041-goes-live-on-february-18">Monster Hunter Wilds Update 1.041 Goes Live on February 18</h2>



<p>Along with the announcement for the expansion, the Monster Hunter Wilds producer also took us through the upcoming update. The highlights include the arrival of 10-star Arch-tempered Arkveld, quests for grabbing weapon designs that won in a contest, a collab side mission with Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection, extra side missions, and more. Check out the patch notes <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-uk/update/ver_01_4_1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a> and the Monster Hunter Wilds roadmap for February and March events below: </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>What are your thoughts on Monster Hunter Wilds getting a large-scale expansion like Iceborne and Sunbreak? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/detroit-become-human-actor-reacts-to-state-of-play-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Detroit: Become Human actor’s reaction to PlayStation’s State of Play announcement</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-is-getting-a-large-scale-expansion-like-iceborne-and-sunbreak/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>