<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:52:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double Fine Reveals ‘Kiln’ Almost 10 Years After First Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/double-fine-reveal-kiln-10-years-after-announcement/</link>
            <guid>1413505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Double Fine has taken to the (virtual) stage at the Xbox Developer Direct showcase to reveal Kiln, a unique multiplayer, team-based party brawler, <strong>almost a decade </strong>after it was announced. The game first surfaced in 2017, emerging from Double Fine’s ‘Amnesia Fortnight’ event, an annual, two-week game jam that spawns prototype game ideas.</p>



<p>It has remained silent, aside from some prototype images appearing online years ago, until now. During the recent Xbox Dev Direct, Double Fine finally revealed the physics-based, destruction-laden brawler.</p>



<h2 id="h-kiln-ten-years-in-the-making">Kiln – Ten Years in the Making</h2>



<p>If you try to find any information online about Kiln, you’ll find a blurb penned by Double Fine in April 2017:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Kiln is a multiplayer, team-based brawler by Derek Brand with a focus on creating unique player sculpted characters featuring crazy physics-based animation and destruction. In Kiln you play as a Mountain Spirit, supernatural beings forever at war on the summit. You’ll use an ancient pottery wheel to create warrior golems called Vessels, inhabiting them and enabling you to interact with the physical realm to do battle. </p>



<p>Created during the match, extremely diverse character shapes and sizes are possible each exhibiting unique attributes and controls that leverage the possibilities in procedural animation.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was also in 2017 that Double Fine revealed the developers responsible for shaping the early game:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>All of this was <strong>re</strong>shared by Double Fine during today’s announcement.</p>



<p>Today, during the Xbox Developer Direct, we saw how that game has evolved over the last decade. </p>



<p>The trailer opened up with Tim Schafer, the head of the studio at Double Fine, working on some pottery. That’s basically the core concept of Kiln. Players take clay characters and shape them into whatever they can imagine, taking them into destructive environments and smashing each other to pieces.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Kiln | Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/We3DR8w2FNU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>You take your pottery mechanisms, craft ‘pots’, and take those ceramic imaginations into multiplayer battles across entertaining, engaging maps built with the ‘spirit of creativity’.</p>



<p>Double Fine confirmed that Kiln is coming Spring 2026, and a closed beta will come soon.</p>



<p>Do you think Kiln looks like your kind of game? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-was-december-2025s-best-selling-game/">Black Ops 7 was December’s best-selling game</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/double-fine-reveal-kiln-10-years-after-announcement/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beast Of Reincarnation Release Window Announced At Xbox Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/beast-of-reincarnation-release-window-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/</link>
            <guid>1413502</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Beast of Reincarnation’s release window has been confirmed during the latest Xbox Developer Direct 2026, with the game releasing in Summer, 2026.</p>







<p>The upcoming souls-like RPG is being developed by none other than Game Freak, the masters behind the ever-popular <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-is-coming-to-hytale-through-mods/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon series</a>. It’s fair to say it’s a harsh departure from their usual titles, but judging from the gameplay showcased, there’s a lot to be excited about.</p>



<h2 id="h-beast-of-reincarnation-releases-summer-2026">Beast of Reincarnation Releases Summer, 2026</h2>



<p>It’s not just <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-release-date-confirmed-has-4-day-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6</a> that takes place in Japan, as Beast of Reincarnation is also heading there, but with more of a post-apocalyptic twist. The footage showcases a deeper look at the nation, which has been ruined by a strange blight and plagued by monstrous beasts.</p>



<p>The gameplay is described as a ‘one-person, one-dog experience,’ and it’s clear that the protagonist’s wolf companion, Koo, will play a large part in the experience. Together, you’ll explore the ruins of Japan and hunt down Malefacts in an effort to cleanse the blight from the world. </p>



<p>And there’s good news for PlayStation fans out there, as it was confirmed that Beast of Reincarnation will release on Xbox, PC, and PlayStation concurrently—no delay like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-playstation-5-release-window-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>What were your thoughts on the Beast of Reincarnation showcase? Will you be picking it up? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>. </p>



<p>For more details from the Xbox Developer Direct, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-forza-horizon-6-gameplay-footage-revealed-at-xbox-developer-direct-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6 release date</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/beast-of-reincarnation-release-window-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Forza Horizon 6 Gameplay Footage Revealed At Xbox Developer Direct 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/first-forza-horizon-6-gameplay-footage-revealed-at-xbox-developer-direct-2026/</link>
            <guid>1413445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-171396">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Everyone knew Forza Horizon 6 was finally getting its first gameplay reveal at the Xbox Developer Direct 2026. It’s fair to say expectations were high, as should be with such a class series—but Playground Games might have outdone themselves with FH6.</p>



<p>When <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-setting-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6’s location</a> was revealed, it made sense. A ludicrously beautiful country with rich culture and a storied heritage. It’s a match made in heaven. Forza was always going to be the main highlight of the Xbox Developer Direct 2026, but its first gameplay footage went up another gear.</p>







<h2 id="h-xbox-developer-direct-2026-shows-off-forza-horizon-6-gameplay">Xbox Developer Direct 2026 Shows Off Forza Horizon 6 Gameplay</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Mt. Fuji awaits. Credit to Playground Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-release-date-confirmed-has-4-day-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6 Release Date was confirmed</a> hours before the 2026 Xbox Developer Direct. But that quickly became an afterthought once gameplay sped onto the screen.</p>







<p>On one hand, it looks like Forza Horizon, it’s Forza Horizon 5, baby! The visuals are out of this world, and there’s a ton of new modes, cars, and features being added.</p>



<p>You can check out the trailer for yourself.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Forza Horizon 6 | Gameplay Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9wDxHhOaK5c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Were you just as impressed as everyone else with the first Forza Horizon 6 gameplay? Are you hoping it’s like FH5? Does the franchise need to get in touch more with its roots? Let IG know through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news here at IG, check out reports <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdpr-could-spend-up-to-800-million-on-the-witcher-4-its-estimated/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CDPR could spend up to $800 Million on The Witcher 4</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/return-to-silent-hill-bombs-hard-in-early-reviews/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Return to Silent Hill bombing hard in early reviews</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developer-direct-2026-everything-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developer-direct-2026-everything-announced/">
                                Xbox Developer Direct 2026—Everything Announced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft held its Xbox Developer Direct for 2026 on Thursday, showcasing a number of upcoming games to kick off Xbox’s 25th anniversary year.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition-release-date-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2-edition-release-date-announced/">
                                Super Mario Bros. Wonder Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Release Date Announced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Rosalina and Luma join the playable roster in Super Mario Bros. Wonder Nintendo Switch 2 Edition, arriving in March 2026.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-was-december-2025s-best-selling-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-was-december-2025s-best-selling-game/">
                                Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Was December 2025’s Best-Selling Game                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 was the best-selling video game in the US for December 2025, according to sales data.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-tops-ps5-to-lead-hardware-sales-in-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-tops-ps5-to-lead-hardware-sales-in-2025/">
                                Nintendo Switch 2 Tops PS5 to Lead Hardware Sales in 2025                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Data shows Switch 2 topped U.S. hardware sales in December and 2025 overall</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/first-forza-horizon-6-gameplay-footage-revealed-at-xbox-developer-direct-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>