<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:21:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[007: First Light is Taking References from Batman Arkham and Uncharted for Combat]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/007-first-light-is-taking-references-from-batman-arkham-and-uncharted-for-combat/</link>
            <guid>1444771</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>007: First Light’s gameplay director has revealed that the game’s combat will take references from the Batman Arkham and Uncharted series. </p>



<p>IO Interative’s upcoming James Bond-themed adventure is all set to release <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/007-first-light-delay-may-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on May 27, 2026</a>. Ahead of the launch, the developers are revealing small tidbits to build hype, and now we have been given more details about the game’s combat and other gameplay elements.</p>







<h2 id="h-007-first-light-takes-inspiration-from-arkham-games-for-combat">007: First Light Takes Inspiration from Arkham Games for Combat</h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C2MTwTrcGtA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Informer</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/007-first-light-aims-to-channel-batman-arkham-freeflow-combat-with-uncharted-spectacle/1100-6538356/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gamespot</a>), 007: First Light gameplay director Andreas Krogh spoke about drawing inspiration from Arkham Games for combat. Krogh stated that in the approach to close combat sequences, players will see references to Arkham games. But there are also “some modern takes on destructibility in the environment”, which players would not have seen in Arkham, but in games like Uncharted. </p>



<p>Krogh elaborated that IO Interactive has a deeper system as they want to do “more of it”. In terms of shooting, players will also see references from modern games; however, which games exactly were revealed. The developers had to explore this area, since Hitman used combat as a last resort, and the area wasn’t as deeply developed as the stealth experience, so they had to look outside to see how they could improve it. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Exclusive: 007 First Light vs. Hitman – What's Different? | Cover Story Interview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C2MTwTrcGtA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In other news, Lenny Kravitz has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lenny-kravitz-talks-inspiration-for-007-first-light-character/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">commented on the inspiration</a> for his character in 007: First Light. Additionally, here are the PC requirements for the game. What are your thoughts on 007: First Light taking references from the Batman: Arkham and Uncharted series for combat? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-pc-specifications-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation revealing the PC specifications for Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/007-first-light-is-taking-references-from-batman-arkham-and-uncharted-for-combat/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 PC Specifications Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-pc-specifications-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1444726</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A little less than a month ahead of Death Stranding 2: On the Beach’s launch on PC, PlayStation has revealed the game’s system requirements. </p>



<p>During the latest <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-pc-release-date-revealed-at-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">State of Play event</a>, it was announced that Death Stranding 2 will receive a PC port on March 19, 2026, with Nixxes and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/kojima-productions/" id="123">Kojima Productions</a> handling the port. A day later, it was also revealed that this port will come with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-pc-will-launch-with-new-modes-and-features-for-both-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new modes and features</a> for both platforms. Now, Nixxes have revealed the minimum, medium, high (recommended), and very high. </p>







<h2 id="h-death-stranding-2-pc-system-requirements-have-been-revealed">Death Stranding 2 PC System Requirements Have Been Revealed</h2>



<p>A new PlayStation <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2026/02/24/death-stranding-2-pc-specs-detailed-out-march-19/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> details the PC system requirements for Death Stranding 2. The developers have stated that it includes a range of graphic presets, and there’s also a portable preset designed for handheld gaming devices. Players can also access upscaling frame generating tools like NVIDIA DLSS 4, AMD FSR 4, and Intel XESS 2. </p>



<p>Players will also find an option called Pico (Progressive Image Compositor) in the upscale settings, developed by Guerrilla for the Decima engine. This is the same upscaling technology used in Death Stranding 2 on PS5. Dynamic Resolution Scaling and Native AA options are also available. </p>



<p>Additionally, Death Stranding 2 on PC supports ultrawide monitors, including 21:9, 32:9, and 16:9. The 21:9 option will also be available on the PS5 version on PC release day. </p>



<p><strong>Interested readers can check out the minimum, medium, high (recommended), and very high specifications for Death Stranding 2 on PC below: </strong></p>



<h4 id="h-low-spec">Low Spec:</h4>



<ul>
<li>Average Performance: 1080p @ 30 FPS</li>



<li>GPU: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1660/AMD Radeon RX 5500 XT 8GB</li>



<li>CPU: Intel Core i3-10100/AMD Ryzen 3 3100</li>



<li>RAM: 16GB</li>



<li>OS: Windows 10/11 (Version 1909 or newer)</li>



<li>Storage 150GB SSD</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-medium-spec">Medium Spec: </h4>



<ul>
<li>Average Performance: 1080p @ 60 FPS</li>



<li>GPU: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3060 12GB/AMD Radeon RX 6600</li>



<li>CPU: Intel Core i5-11400/AMD Ryzen 5 5600</li>



<li>RAM: 16GB</li>



<li>OS: Windows 10/11 (Version 1909 or newer)</li>



<li>Storage 150GB SSD</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-high-recommended-spec">High (Recommended) Spec: </h4>



<ul>
<li>Average Performance: 1440p @ 60 FPS</li>



<li>GPU: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3070/AMD Radeon RX 6800</li>



<li>CPU: Intel Core i7-11700/AMD Ryzen 7 5700X</li>



<li>RAM: 16GB</li>



<li>OS: Windows 10/11 (Version 1909 or newer)</li>



<li>Storage 150GB SSD</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-very-high-spec">Very High Spec:  </h4>



<ul>
<li>Average Performance: 4K @ 60 FPS</li>



<li>GPU: NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4080/AMD Radeon RX 9070 XT</li>



<li>CPU: Intel Core i7-11700AMD Ryzen 7 5700X</li>



<li>RAM: 16GB</li>



<li>OS: Windows 10/11 (Version 1909 or newer)</li>



<li>Storage 150GB SSD</li>
</ul>







<p>In other news, Hideo Kojima revealed that he <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-person-metal-gear-solid-game-kojima-zampella/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost created a first-person Metal Gear Solid game</a> with the late Vince Zampella. What are your thoughts on the Death Stranding 2 PC requirements? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-on-switch-2-is-not-a-ps4-port-director-reveals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade Switch 2 edition not being a port of the PS4 version</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-pc-specifications-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simpsons Hit & Run and Prototype Studio Radical Entertainment Has Returned]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/simpsons-hit-run-and-prototype-studio-radical-entertainment-have-returned/</link>
            <guid>1444696</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Simpsons Hit &amp; Run and Prototype developer, Radical Entertainment, has relaunched as New Radical Games. </p>



<p>There have been almost no updates on the Simpson Hit &amp; Run and Prototype franchises for a very long time. The last we heard about Prototype was some <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-prototype-remaster-evidence-discovered-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">potential evidence</a> that a remaster could be in the works. We also saw <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/futurama-mod-takes-simpsons-hit-run-to-new-new-york/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a mod</a> that took Simpson Hit &amp; Run. Now, the developer behind both these games has relaunched. </p>







<h2 id="h-simpsons-hit-amp-run-and-prototype-studio-relaunch-as-new-radical-games">Simpsons Hit &amp; Run and Prototype Studio Relaunch as New Radical Games</h2>



<p>Spotted on r/<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1rcqler/radical_entertainment_just_relaunched_their/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamingLeaksAndRumours</a>, Radical Entertainment has relaunched as New Radical Games, a mix of the old company and Hothead. The new development studio will have Ian Wilkinson, the co-founder of Radical Entertainment, as CEO, and Tim Bennison, a former COO at Capcom Game Studio Vancouver, will join as COO of New Radical Games. </p>



<p>Regarding services, New Radical Games will offer work-for-hire for full game development, mobile &amp; console development, co-development, porting, and remastering. They have also listed all their games, including The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run, Hulk: Ultimate Destruction, Scarface: The World is Yours, Crash: Tag Team Racing, Crash: Mind Over Mutant, Crash of the Titans, and Prototype.</p>



<p>Hothead also has a lot of games under its belt, including Kill Shot Bravo, Hero Hunters, Superhit Baseball, Box Office Tycoon, Sid Meier’s Civilization VI mobile, Big Win NHL, Big Win Soccer, Big Win Basketball, Big Win Baseball, and Big Win Football. </p>







<p>In other news, the developer of Styx has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/styx-developer-shade-at-ubisoft-greed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thrown shade</a> at Ubisoft’s stealth brands. Additionally, the Highguard developer, Wildlight Entertainment, has been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-developer-backed-tencent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">funded by the Chinese company Tencent</a>. What are your thoughts on the Simpsons Hit &amp; Run and Prototype studio relaunching as New Radical Games? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-director-now-focusing-on-movie-adaptation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Creative Director shifting focus to movie adaptation</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-developer-teases-more-platform-releases/"></a></p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/simpsons-hit-run-and-prototype-studio-radical-entertainment-have-returned/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>