<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 21:25:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot Scoops Five BAFTA Awards and Dominates The Show]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bafta-games-awards-astro-bot-scoops/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-scoops-five-bafta-awards-and-dominates-the-show.1158834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/bafta-games-awards-astro-bot-scoops/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The BAFTA Games Awards 2025 has wrapped, and all the trophies have been handed out. Sitting at the top of the table is Astro Bot, one of 2024’s most popular titles. It claimed no fewer than <strong>five </strong>BAFTA Awards, securing the winning spot in some of the most competitive categories, including the prestigious ‘Best Game’ slot.</p>



<p>It was joined by games like Helldivers 2 and Still Wakes the Deep, both of which landed multiple awards during the show.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-astro-bot-on-top">Astro Bot on Top</h2>



<p>Astro Bot has claimed the BAFTA Awards for some iconic categories:</p>



<ul>
<li>Best Game</li>



<li>Game Design</li>



<li>Family</li>



<li>Audio Achievement</li>



<li>Animation</li>
</ul>



<p>The results at the <a href="https://www.bafta.org/awards/games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">BAFTA Games Awards</a> in London follow months of similar circumstances for Team Asobi’s wonderful platformer.</p>



<p>Still Wakes the Deep also had a nice spree at the BAFTAs, securing the following wins:</p>



<ul>
<li>New IP</li>



<li>Performer in a Leading Role</li>



<li>Performer in a Supporting Role</li>
</ul>



<p>Still Wakes the Deep was one of my top games of 2024, boasting some intense horror sequences that unfolded during a tense fight for survival aboard a besieged Scottish oil rig. </p>



<p>Helldivers 2 was able to grab the BAFTA Awards for Music and Multiplayer, while Hellblade II landed Technical Achievement. There’s a special nod reserved for Tales of Kenzera: ZAU, which received the BAFTA Award for Game Beyond Entertainment, which given the game’s backstory, is deserved through and through.</p>



<p>To my surprise, Vampire Survivors won Evolving Game, an award that I thought would for sure go to Hello Games and No Man’s Sky. Balatro managed to secure the award for Debut Game, and Thank Goodness You’re Here, the star-studded and bizarre comedy title, won the award for British Game.]</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming, as I was at the BAFTA Games Awards and secured some exclusive interviews with some of the biggest names in gaming.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-next-patch-adds-feature/">next Assassin’s Creed Shadows patch adds something I’ve always wanted</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete Blue Prince Achievements List]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-blue-prince-achievements-list/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/complete-blue-prince-achievements-list.1158678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/complete-blue-prince-achievements-list/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Completing every achievement and unlocking every trophy in Blue Prince, like reaching Room 46, will be difficult, even for grizzled puzzle genre veterans.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-time-does-blue-prince-release-start-date-times-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Blue Prince</a> is far from the traditional puzzle title. Dogubomb’s debut project puts you in the shoes of an heir to Mount Holly Manor and features tabletop card game and roguelike exploration elements. The simple objective is to explore all 45 rooms of the house and discover a secret 46th room, but there is a twist.</p>



<p>Each door opens to one of three rooms, and the choice is yours. The floor plan resets at the end of each in-game day, changing the house layout. It’s up to you to discover tools and permanent upgrades to solve the mystery behind the disappearance of a children’s book author and more secrets along the way. And If there is one thing puzzle fans also love, it’s trophy hunting in games. </p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-every-blue-prince-achievement-amp-trophy">How to Get Every Blue Prince Achievement &amp; Trophy</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Blue Prince has mysteries inside and outside the manor. Image via Dogubomb. </figcaption></figure>



<p>Every room in Mount Holly Manor features some puzzle, tool, or blueprint to discover. Yet, what makes Blue Prince so unique is that players don’t need to complete every challenge. Every player will experience their own journey based on the map layout. However, this list of achievements applies to everyone and can be completed by following the steps below. </p>



<p>In total, there are eight standard achievements and eight secret achievements. While we have this list of achievements, Dogubomb has remained tight-lipped on what trophies will be available. Yet, completing every achievement above should put you on track to acquire every trophy.</p>



<p>Check out their names and how to add them to your collection—credit to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.trueachievements.com/game/Blue-Prince/achievements" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TrueAchievements</a>.</p>



<h3 id="h-main-achievements">Main Achievements </h3>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Blue Prince Achievement Name</th><th>How to Complete</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Full House Trophy </td><td>Draft a room in each open slot of your house</td></tr><tr><td>Bullseye Trophy </td><td>Solve 40 Dartboard Puzzles </td></tr><tr><td>A Logical Trophy </td><td>Win 40 Parlor Games</td></tr><tr><td>Inheritance Trophy </td><td>Reach Room 46</td></tr><tr><td>Complete the Mount Holly Directory </td><td>Explorer’s Trophy </td></tr><tr><td>Reach Room 46 in one day </td><td>Day One Trophy </td></tr><tr><td>Trophy of Speed</td><td>Reach Room 46 in under an hour </td></tr><tr><td>Trophy of Trophies </td><td>Complete the Trophy Case </td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h3 id="h-secret-achievements">Secret Achievements </h3>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Blue Prince Achievement Name</th><th>How to Complete</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Trophy of Invention </td><td>Create all 8 Workshop Contraptions</td></tr><tr><td>Trophy of Drafting </td><td>Win the Drafting Strategy Sweepstakes</td></tr><tr><td>Trophy 8 </td><td>Solve the enigma of Room 8 on Rank 8</td></tr><tr><td>Trophy of Wealth </td><td>Buy out the entire Showroom</td></tr><tr><td>Dare Bird Trophy </td><td>Reach Room 46 in Dare Mode</td></tr><tr><td>Cursed Trophy </td><td>Reach Room 46 in Cursed Mode</td></tr><tr><td>Trophy of Sigils </td><td>Unlock all 8 Realm Sigils</td></tr><tr><td>Diploma Trophy </td><td>Ace the Classroom Final Exam</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more on Blue Prince, check out everything you need to know about whether or not the game will be available on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-blue-prince-on-xbox-game-pass-or-playstation-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass or PlayStation Plus</a>. If you want to know what other highly anticipated games are on the horizon, look at the key details about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-know-about-marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hades-2-launching-as-nintendo-switch-2-console-exclusive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hades 2</a>. </p>



<p>Which Blue Prince achievement are you going to complete first? If you make a discovery and want to share it, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>. </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>