<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:30:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3’s Game Experience is ‘More or Less Complete’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/</link>
            <guid>1376092</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The director of Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 has revealed a few new details about the upcoming title, with the game experience almost complete and the team narrowing down on a name. </p>



<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 is the next big instalment to the series, but the details about this game have been scarce, with players only knowing that the title already has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-already-has-a-lot-of-playable-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“a lot” of playable content</a>. Now, the developers have revealed even more details, including an important keyword to look out for in FF7 Remake Part 3. </p>







<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-director-wants-players-to-play-the-game-as-soon-as-possible">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 Director Wants Players to Play the Game As Soon as Possible</h2>



<p>During a new interview with Julian Chièze on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKxyZ5DsgSs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube</a> (translated via Genki_JPN on <a href="https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1998002580295750126" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a>), Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 director Naoki Hamaguchi revealed some new details about the title. Hamaguchi first stated that the game experience of Part 3 of the FF7 Remake Trilogy is more or less complete!” The team is now in the phase of “thoroughly developing it” and feels “very confident about it.” They are excited about players trying the game, but have to wait until the whole development process is complete. Square Enix is “almost at a point where they can share some more information.” </p>



<p>Naoki Hamaguchi revealed even more details about FF7 Remake Part 3 during the same interview. He first stated that he and Tetsuya Nomura are closing in on the name for the upcoming title, narrowing it down to only two options. The title should be decided within this year. Moreover, the director also stated that “Highwind” is an important keyword for Part 3 and doesn’t want the upcoming title to have the same experience as previous games. He wants to “deliver a new game experience and a new scale with part 3!”</p>







<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 7 Remake developers are <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">considering a “full title”</a> after part 3. Additionally, the size of FF7 Remake Intergrade is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost 100GB on the Switch 2</a>. What are your thoughts on all the new information Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3’s director revealed? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-doesnt-know-if-od-will-work-out/">Hideo Kojima not knowing whether his upcoming title, OD, will work out</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima Doesn’t Know If OD ‘Will Work Out’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-doesnt-know-if-od-will-work-out/</link>
            <guid>1376089</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hideo Kojima recently spoke about his upcoming title, OD, stating that even he can’t say exactly what it is or whether it will work out. </p>



<p>The next Xbox Game Studios title by Hideo Kojima and Kojima Productions, OD, is already in the works, and we received a glimpse of the title earlier this year through its ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/od-gameplay-reveal-kojima/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Knock</a>‘ trailer. We have also heard Kojima say that he wants to scan ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-wishes-to-scan-real-ghosts-for-od/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">real ghosts</a>‘ for his upcoming title. Now, he has revealed more details on the challenges he is facing with OD. </p>







<h2 id="h-hideo-kojima-can-t-say-what-od-exactly-is-but-there-are-hints-in-the-trailer">Hideo Kojima Can’t Say What OD Exactly Is, But There Are Hints in the Trailer</h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://ananweb.jp/categories/entertainment/74735" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ananweb</a> (via <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/hideo-kojima-says-od-is-something-completely-different-from-a-standard-horror-game-we-still-dont-know-if-it-will-work-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton</a>), Hideo Kojima spoke about the challenges he is facing while developing OD. He stated, “I can’t say exactly what it is yet, nor do I know if it will&nbsp;work out.” Kojima added that they have created stealth and delivery games “which were unlike anything before”. However, even those games had systems similar to other titles, which made the process a bit easier. </p>



<p>In the case of OD, Kojima and team are “trying to change the service model from the ground up,” which has proven to be “quite challenging.” At the same time, the recently released trailer is “full of hints,” so the highly passionate players might be able to figure it out if they spend enough time on it. </p>







<p>In other news, Insider Gaming’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eidos-montreal-move-to-japan-kojima/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive report</a> reveals that Eidos Montreal’s employees were working on OD before being asked to move to Japan. Additionally, the popular game director <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-zootopia-2-cameo-cast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">joined Zootopia 2’s cast</a> just days before release. What are your thoughts on even Hideo Kojima not being sure whether his upcoming title, OD, is going to do well? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-michael-coming-back-aged/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 5’s Michael coming back to the game after 12 years</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-doesnt-know-if-od-will-work-out/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>