<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:13:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Planning More Movies Based on Its Franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-movie-franchises-mario-zelda-future/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-planning-more-movies-based-on-its-franchises.1344016/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Nintendo isn’t planning on stopping movie adaptations of its games. Even more so, according to a new sales report, it’s going to be a more common thing.</p>



<p>For the longest time, video game adaptations were a curse on Hollywood. It never seemed to work out, no matter what form it took, from animated (like Final Fantasy) to live-action (like Max Payne). However, the 2020s proved to show it off in style, having massive successes like Sonic the Hedgehog, Fallout, Arcane, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-tv-show-receives-high-praise-from-critics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Last of Us</a>. One of those hits was Illumination’s The Super Mario Bros. Movie, which raked in more than <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-mario-bros-movie-record-breaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one billion dollars</a> at the box office. With a sequel and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-delays-the-legend-of-zelda-live-action-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live-action Zelda film</a>, it’s on one heck of a hot streak. Fortunately, it doesn’t seem like it wants to slow down at all.</p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-involved-in-multiple-movies-based-on-company-ip-in-development">Nintendo Involved in Multiple Movies Based on Company IP in Development</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Universal</figcaption></figure>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/251105e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a sales report from Nintendo Japan</a>, the company talked about its success with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-10-million-sales-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> and its plans for the future. One big part of its strategy is multimedia, with a big push for films. Nintendo states that it’s currently involved in multiple projects on its IP in various stages. No specifics were given as to what franchises those are, but they’ll be releasing after The Legend of Zelda in 2027.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Nintendo plans to be heavily involved in all of the films, from production to financing. Given how well the collaboration worked with Mario, having the creators on the team always leads to a better adaptation. It’ll be interesting to see what the future for Nintendo’s films will look like, whether it be in-house, like it teased with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=75JEwjP_GD8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Close to You</a>, or licensed. Either way, we may see series like Metroid or Animal Crossing make it onto the silver screen soon.</p>



<p>What do you think about Nintendo’s push for IP-based films? Which Nintendo franchise do you want to see as a movie? Metroid? Animal Crossing? F-Zero? Star Fox? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Nintendo news, check out our articles on&nbsp;Animal Crossing’s upcoming <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-free-update-nintendo-switch-2-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2 upgrade</a> and when we may get the trailer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-super-mario-galaxy-movie-trailer-this-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-movie-franchises-mario-zelda-future/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>