<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:16:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Was The Best-Selling Game In September]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-was-the-best-selling-game-in-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-was-the-best-selling-game-in-september.1331518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-153229">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The latest video game sales data for the United States (US) has been announced, and Borderlands 4 was the best-selling game in September 2025.</p>



<p>The new data comes from industry firm <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m3rvmuvpws25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Circana</a>, which posted the data ranging from August 31 to October 4.</p>



<p>Following Borderlands 4 for the month was NBA 2K26, which used back-to-back strong months to become <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the best-selling game of the year</a> so far. Rounding out the top five for September were EA Sports FC 26, Ghost of Yotei, and Madden NFL 26. That means three of the top five games for the month were sports games. </p>



<p>When looking at the full top 20 for the month, nearly half of the games were new releases. Aside from the aforementioned titles above, Silent Hill f, Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds, Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles, NHL 26, Digimon Story: Time Stranger, and Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2 all hit the top 20 for the first time. </p>



<p>You can check out the full list of best-selling games for September below. And be sure to leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-selling-games-for-september-2025">Best-Selling Games For September 2025</h2>



<ol>
<li><strong>Borderlands 4</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>NBA 2K26</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>EA Sports FC 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>Ghost of Yotei</strong> – Sony </li>



<li><strong>Madden NFL 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>Helldivers II</strong> – Sony </li>



<li><strong>Silent Hill: f</strong> – Konami Digital Entertainment</li>



<li><strong>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</strong> – Sega</li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</strong> – Square Enix Inc </li>



<li><strong>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</strong> – Konami Digital Entertainment</li>



<li><strong>EA Sports College Football 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>NHL 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</strong> – Bandai Namco Entertainment</li>



<li><strong>Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2</strong> – Nintendo</li>



<li><strong>Minecraft</strong> – Microsoft</li>



<li><strong>Forza Horizon 5</strong> – Microsoft </li>



<li><strong>Grand Theft Auto V</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>Donkey Kong Bananza</strong> – Nintendo</li>



<li><strong>Kickoff Bundle (2025)</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>Red Dead Redemption II</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>
</ol>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-xp-bot-farming-portal-lobbies-nerfed-by-ea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA nerfing XP farming bot lobbies</a> in Battlefield 6. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-games-7-xbox-game-pass-coming-so/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-games-7-xbox-game-pass-coming-so/">
                                7 New Games Announced as Coming Soon to Xbox Game Pass                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In the next wave hitting Xbox Game Pass, seven great new games are being added. Get the full list here and find out what’s coming.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-ceo-moves-on-from-role-after-nearly-a-decade/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-ceo-moves-on-from-role-after-nearly-a-decade/">
                                Remedy Entertainment CEO Moves On from Role After Nearly a Decade                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Remedy Entertainment’s CEO has resigned effective immediately, and a search for a new CEO is underway. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us/">
                                NBA 2K26 Is The Best-Selling Game Of 2025 In The US                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>NBA 2K26 is the best-selling game in the United States (US) for 2025, surpassing Monster Hunter Wilds within its first month.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-will-be-unveiled-next-month/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-will-be-unveiled-next-month/">
                                Palworld Mobile Will be Unveiled Next Month                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Krafton’s new press release confirmed that Palworld Mobile will be unveiled at G-Star 2025 next month and playable there. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-was-the-best-selling-game-in-september/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 New Games Announced as Coming Soon to Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-games-7-xbox-game-pass-coming-so/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/7-new-games-announced-as-coming-soon-to-xbox-game-pass.1331437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a post on social media and the Xbox Wire, the team at Microsoft has revealed <strong>seven new games </strong>coming to Xbox Game Pass. It’s a mixed list that includes a space-faring RPG, a cleaning simulator, and Football Manager on both PC and consoles. The list is mostly made up of games coming to the service on day one of their respective releases.</p>



<p>Read on to get the full list of games coming to Xbox Game Pass in the coming weeks.</p>



<h2 id="h-next-games-coming-to-game-pass">Next Games Coming to Game Pass</h2>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/10/22/xbox-game-pass-october-2025-wave-2/?ocid=XGP_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_lrn_10.22.1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the Xbox Wire</a>, the next array of titles coming to Xbox Game Pass was revealed.</p>



<h3 id="h-powerwash-simulator-2-october-23">PowerWash Simulator 2 (October 23)</h3>



<p><em>PowerWash Simulator</em>&nbsp;is back, bubbling with fresh locations, soap-erior equipment, and splashy features. Effortlessly transform soiled surroundings into clean, serene scenes, solo or with pals. Satisfaction is a spray away!</p>



<h3 id="h-bounty-star-october-23">Bounty Star (October 23)</h3>



<p><em>Bounty Star</em>&nbsp;is an over-the-shoulder 3D action game that&nbsp;marries mech&nbsp;combat and customization with farming and base building. The player takes on the role of a broken but powerful ex-soldier named Clem, a war veteran, talented fighte,r and expert mech pilot.</p>



<h3 id="h-super-fantasy-kingdom-october-24">Super Fantasy Kingdom (October 24)</h3>



<p>Rebuild your kingdom and explore a vibrant fantasy world in this roguelite city builder. Defeat hordes of monsters with a unique team of defenders as you harvest, build, mine, cook, brew, and grow. But if your&nbsp;defenses should&nbsp;fail, be prepared to watch it all burn!</p>



<h3 id="h-halls-of-torment-october-28">Halls of Torment (October 28)</h3>



<p>Slay hordes of terrifying monsters in this horde survival roguelite. Descend into the Halls of Torment where the Lords of the Underworld await you. Treasures, magical trinkets, and a growing cast of heroes will grant you the power to vanquish these horrors from beyond. How long can you survive?</p>



<h3 id="h-the-outer-worlds-2-october-29">The Outer Worlds 2 (October 29)</h3>



<p><em>The Outer&nbsp;Worlds 2</em>&nbsp;is the eagerly-awaited sequel to the award-winning first-person sci-fi RPG from Obsidian Entertainment (just look at the exciting number of dashes in this sentence!). Time to clear your calendar – get ready for an action-packed adventure with a new crew, new weapons, and new enemies in a new colony!</p>



<h3 id="h-1000xresist-november-4">1000xResist (November 4)</h3>



<p><em>1000xResist</em>&nbsp;is a thrilling sci-fi adventure. The year is unknown, and a disease spread by an alien invasion keeps you underground. You are Watcher. You dutifully fulfil your purpose in serving the Allmother, until the day you discover a shocking secret that changes everything.</p>



<h3 id="h-football-manager-26-november-4">Football Manager 26 (November 4)</h3>



<p>New foundations set the stage for you to define your football destiny. Built on the Unity engine, FM26 is the legacy, redefined, and where storytelling evolves, placing you at the heart of the beautiful game. A reimagined interface and more immersive matchday experience bring you closer to the action and combine to elevate every decision and match-defining moment.</p>



<p>Which game are you most looking forward to coming to Xbox Game Pass? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/scarface-world-is-yours-coming-to-steam-and-epic/">Scarface: The World is Yours is coming to PC again</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-games-7-xbox-game-pass-coming-so/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy Entertainment CEO Moves On from Role After Nearly a Decade]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-ceo-moves-on-from-role-after-nearly-a-decade/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-entertainment-ceo-moves-on-from-role-after-nearly-a-decade.1331434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Remedy Entertainment’s CEO is stepping down with immediate effect, having held the position since August 2016. </p>



<p>Things have not been looking very good for Remedy recently, primarily due to the FBC: Firebreak’s lacklustre launch. Remedy’s now former CEO provided a statement on this topic a little over a week ago, revealing that the game<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fbc-firebreak-still-underperforming-remedy-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> has not met internal sales targets</a>. Now, the latest update from the company shows that the CEO is stepping down. </p>







<p>According to a new <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/releases-and-events/announcements-and-releases/?publicationId=49a7f7db-a1c3-400f-948b-f25b3b7426f8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">press release</a> from Remedy Entertainment, Tero Virtala, the company’s CEO, and the board of directors have mutually decided that Virtala will step down from his position “with immediate effect.” The search process for a new CEO will start immediately, and “Virtala will continue at the service of the company during an agreed transition period to support the handover of CEO duties.”</p>



<p>A new interim CEO has been appointed from Remedy’s Board of Directors. Markus Mäki, one of the founders of the company, a member of the board since 1995, and the Chairman of the Board, will be appointed as the interim CEO, effective as of October 22, 2025. Mäki is also “a member of the company’s core management team responsible for production.” Mäki will step down as Chairman of the Board, and Henri Österlund will take his place. </p>



<p><strong>Here’s what Remedy’s Interim CEO, Markus Mäki, had to say about Tero Virtala: </strong></p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I want to thank Tero Virtala for his substantial contribution to the management of Remedy since 2016. I personally thank Tero for good cooperation and wish him all the best for the future.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In other news, read about Control Ultimate Edition’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/control-ultimate-editions-free-update-adds-outfits-a-mission-and-ps5-pro-support/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free update</a> adding new outfits, a mission, and PS5 Pro Support. Additionally, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-games-working-closely-with-remedy-entertainment-on-max-payne-1-2-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rockstar Games is working closely</a> with Remedy on Max Payne 1 &amp; 2 Remake. What are your thoughts on Remedy Entertainment’s studio stepping down? Let us know through the official&nbsp;Insider Gaming&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/dLOFaEGOMl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/lV5OgMruYQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Palworld Mobile being unveiled next month</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-ceo-moves-on-from-role-after-nearly-a-decade/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NBA 2K26 Is The Best-Selling Game Of 2025 In The US]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us.1331431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-153208">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>NBA 2K26 is the best-selling game in the United States (US) so far in 2025. </p>



<p>According to the latest sales data from <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m3rvmuvpws25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Circana</a>, despite the game not being the top-selling game for September—more on that later—, it has jumped to the top spot for the year.</p>



<p>Its move to the number one position pushes Monster Hunter Wilds down to second after it had been at the top since its February release. Rounding out the top 5 for the year, as of October 4, are Borderlands 4, EA Sports College Football 26, and The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered.</p>



<p>You can check out the rest of the Top 20 best-selling games for 2025 below. In addition to game sales, the latest <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-boosts-hardware-sales-september/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video game hardware sales data</a> for September 2025 was revealed.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-selling-games-of-2025">Best-Selling Games Of 2025</h2>



<ol>
<li><strong>NBA 2K26</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>Monster Hunter: Wilds</strong> – Capcom USA</li>



<li><strong>Borderlands 4</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>EA Sports College Football 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</strong> – Microsoft </li>



<li><strong>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</strong> – Microsoft </li>



<li><strong>Madden NFL 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>MLB: The Show 25</strong> – Sony</li>



<li><strong>Elden Ring: Nightreign</strong> – Bandai Namco Entertainment</li>



<li><strong>WWE 2K25</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</strong> – Plaion</li>



<li><strong>Forza Horizon 5</strong> – Microsoft </li>



<li><strong>Split Fiction</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>Minecraft</strong> – Microsoft</li>



<li><strong>EA Sports FC 26</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>EA Sports MVP Bundle (2025)</strong> – Electronic Arts</li>



<li><strong>NBA 2K25</strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>



<li><strong>Ghost of Yotei</strong> – Sony </li>



<li><strong>Helldivers II</strong> – Sony</li>



<li><strong>Civilization VII </strong> – Take-Two Interactive</li>
</ol>



<p>What do you think of NBA 2K26 being the number one video game so far in 2025? What other games on the list stand out to you? Leave your thoughts in the comments below, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out this <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/futurama-mod-takes-simpsons-hit-run-to-new-new-york/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fan-made The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run mod</a> that transforms Springfield into Futurama’s New New York. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-will-be-unveiled-next-month/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-mobile-will-be-unveiled-next-month/">
                                Palworld Mobile Will be Unveiled Next Month                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Krafton’s new press release confirmed that Palworld Mobile will be unveiled at G-Star 2025 next month and playable there. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-boosts-hardware-sales-september/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-boosts-hardware-sales-september/">
                                Nintendo Switch 2 Boosts Hardware Sales Up 24% In September                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the latest video game hardware sales, the Nintendo Switch 2 has surpassed XX million units sold in the United States.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-2-movie-release-date-change/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-2-movie-release-date-change/">
                                Mortal Kombat 2 Movie Will Now Release a Week Earlier                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Mortal Kombat 2 movie release date has been changed once again and will now release one week prior.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/scarface-world-is-yours-coming-to-steam-and-epic/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/scarface-world-is-yours-coming-to-steam-and-epic/">
                                Legendary GTA Competitor ‘Scarface’ Coming to Steam and Epic with HD Graphics Mode                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been revealed that 2006’s Scarface: The World is Yours could be re-releasing digitally with a HD upgrade, 20 years later.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-is-the-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete Ball X Pit Trophy List—How To Get All Achievements & Trophies]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ball-x-pit-trophy-list-all-achievements-trophies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/complete-ball-x-pit-trophy-list%E2%80%94how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies.1331392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Kenny Sun’s genius Ball X Pit is a fresh take on the roguelike genre with block-busting and ball-bouncing mechanics. Funnily enough, the Ball X Pit trophy list is sure to have you bouncing from wall to wall to clear out its exhausting list of accomplishments.</p>



<p>Each game’s trophy list ranges from story-related trophies to wacky out out-there tasks you’d never even think to do. We’d argue that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ball-x-pit-reaches-a-major-sales-milestone-days-after-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ball X Pit</a>‘s trophy list is a long but simple one—you need to grind more than if you played every Tony Hawk’s game back to back.</p>



<p>It’s to be expected with roguelikes, so let’s take a deeper dive into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ball-x-pit-xbox-game-pass-playstation-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ball X Pit</a>‘s trophy list and achievements.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-ball-x-pit-trophies-amp-achievements">All Ball X Pit Trophies &amp; Achievements</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Balls to the wall action. Credit to Kenny Sun</figcaption></figure>



<p>Adjust your eyes when reading this list, as the onslaught of caps might make your eyes sore. But once you start dissecting the entire Ball X Pit trophy list, you’ll see the achievements and trophies are very attainable.</p>



<p>But completing all areas with different characters and collecting resources for the game’s construction aspect is likely to set you back a lot of hours.</p>



<p>Here’s the <a href="https://www.ballxpit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ball X Pit</a> trophy list in full.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Ball X Pit Trophy &amp; Achievement Name</th><th data-align="center"><strong>How To Unlock</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Legend of New Ballbylon</td><td data-align="center">Obtain all&nbsp;Ball x Pit&nbsp;Trophies.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">BONExYARD</td><td data-align="center">Complete the BONExYARD.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">SNOWYxSHORES</td><td data-align="center">Complete the SNOWYxSHORES.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">LIMINALxDESERT</td><td data-align="center">Complete the LIMINALxDESERT.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GORYxGRASSLANDS</td><td data-align="center">Complete the GORYxGRASSLANDS.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">FUNGALxFOREST</td><td data-align="center">Complete the FUNGALxFOREST.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">SMOLDERINGxDEPTHS</td><td data-align="center">Complete the SMOLDERINGxDEPTHS.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">HEAVENLYxGATES</td><td data-align="center">Complete the HEAVENLYxGATES.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">VASTxVOID</td><td data-align="center">Complete the VASTxVOID.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">BONExYARD Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the BONExYARD with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">SNOWYxSHORES Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the SNOWYxSHORES with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">LIMINALxDESERT Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the LIMINALxDESERT with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GORYxGRASSLANDS Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the GORYxGRASSLANDS with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">FUNGALxFOREST Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the FUNGALxFOREST with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">SMOLDERINGxDEPTHS Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the SMOLDERINGxDEPTHS with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">HEAVENLYxGATES Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the HEAVENLYxGATES with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">VASTxVOID Conquered</td><td data-align="center">Complete the VASTxVOID with 10 different characters.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">True Warrior</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Warrior.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Repentance</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Repentant.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Itch Scratched</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Itchy Finger.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Cogitated</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Cogitator.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Master General</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Tactician.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">All Spent</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Spendthrift.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Embedder</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Embedded.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Radicalized</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Radical.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Golden Years</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Empty Nester.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Long Shadow</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Shade.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Unpacked</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Cohabitants.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Gravity’s Rainbow</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Physicist.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Brick Breaker</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Shieldbearer.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Herculean</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Makeshift Sisyphus.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Masochist</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Flagellant.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Entertainer</td><td data-align="center">Complete every level with The Juggler.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Evolution</td><td data-align="center">Create your first evolution.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Fusion</td><td data-align="center">Fuse two balls for the first time.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Nosferatu</td><td data-align="center">Create Nosferatu.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Nuclear Bomb</td><td data-align="center">Create a Nuclear Bomb.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Satan</td><td data-align="center">Create Satan.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Soul Reaver</td><td data-align="center">Create a Soul Reaver.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Deadeye’s Cross</td><td data-align="center">Create Deadeye’s Cross.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Legion Slayer</td><td data-align="center">Kill 100,000 enemies.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Riches</td><td data-align="center">Collect 5000 gold in total.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Wheat Farmer</td><td data-align="center">Collect 1000 wheat in total.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Woodcutter</td><td data-align="center">Collect 1000 wood in total.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stone Miner</td><td data-align="center">Collect 1000 stone in total.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Gold Miner</td><td data-align="center">Mine 100 gold&nbsp;in a single harvest.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bountiful Harvest</td><td data-align="center">Collect 100 wheat&nbsp;in a single harvest.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Deforestation</td><td data-align="center">Collect 100 wood&nbsp;in a single harvest.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Boulder Breaker</td><td data-align="center">Collect 100 stone&nbsp;in a single harvest.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">City Planner</td><td data-align="center">Collect 50 blueprints.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Trophy</td><td data-align="center">Construct a trophy.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monument</td><td data-align="center">Construct an infinitely upgradeable building.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Worker’s Guild</td><td data-align="center">Construct the Worker’s Guild.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Evolution Chamber</td><td data-align="center">Construct the Evolution Chamber.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Relic Collector</td><td data-align="center">Construct the Relic Collector.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bag Maker</td><td data-align="center">Construct the Bag Maker.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Carpenter</td><td data-align="center">Construct the Carpenter.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Land Grabber</td><td data-align="center">Expand your base 5 times.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Structural Power</td><td data-align="center">Reach +5 bonus in any attribute from a building.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">S Rank</td><td data-align="center">Reach S stat scaling in any attribute</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Neighborhood</td><td data-align="center">Build 15 housing structures.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Fusion Evolution</td><td data-align="center">Fuse two evolved balls.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Scholar</td><td data-align="center">Unlock every base game entry in the Encyclopedia.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ballbylon Has Risen</td><td data-align="center">Complete&nbsp;<em>Ball x Pit</em>.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-many-achievements-amp-trophies-in-ball-x-pit">How Many Achievements &amp; Trophies In Ball X Pit?</h2>



<p><strong>Your Ball X Pit PlayStation and Xbox journey requires you to conquer 64 PlayStation Trophies and 63 Xbox Achievements to complete the game fully and go the extra mile.</strong></p>



<p>The trophy list is heavily in favor of Bronze Trophies—so it’s good news if you like having a large Bronze collection, for some reason!</p>



<p>See how the Ball X Pit is broken up.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Trophy Type</th><th data-align="center">Quantity</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Platinum Trophy</td><td data-align="center">1</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Gold Trophies</td><td data-align="center">1</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Silver Trophies</td><td data-align="center">1</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bronze Trophies</td><td data-align="center">61</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Roguelikes such as this, Balatro, and The Binding of Isaac are always time-sappers. Ball X Pit is worth it, though, so let us know if you intend to get every trophy and achievement via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For even more trophy and achievement lists, check out our other guides here at IG: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-trophy-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden 4</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/powerwash-simulator-2-trophy-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PowerWash Simulator 2</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-trophy-achievement-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Outer Worlds 2</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ball-x-pit-trophy-list-all-achievements-trophies/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>