<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:33:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sniper Elite: Resistance Preview – A Familiar Feeling]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sniper-elite-resistance-preview-%E2%80%93-a-familiar-feeling.1044501/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-preview/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Playing Sniper Elite: Resistance brings a familiar feel to long-time players of the franchise. A game that runs parallel to the events of Sniper Elite 5, Resistance once again puts you in France with the goal of disrupting Nazi plans that could change the course of World War II.</p>



<p>I recently spent over an hour playing Sniper Elite: Resistance where I got to go through the game’s third mission, and experience just a taste of what developer Rebellion has in store for players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I’m not going to lie to you. If you’ve played Sniper Elite 4 or 5, you’ve played Sniper Elite: Resistance. The game uses the same engine with gameplay that’s nearly identical to its 2022 predecessor. Rather than play as Karl Fairburne, however, you’re controlling Harry Hawker, who sounds an awful lot like Jason Statham.</p>



<h6 id="h-help-insider-gaming-nbsp-take-our-2024-reader-survey">HELP INSIDER GAMING:&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/wvT7oBtvjZLVmrEv9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Take Our 2024 Reader Survey</a></h6>



<p>With it being a connected title, the general environment and feeling is similar to what you get with Sniper Elite 5. And although I only played one region of the game, one thing that’s clear with Resistance is that the designers have done enough to make the environment stand on its own. Finding all of the unique ways to take cover and distract the enemies is what lets the Sniper Elite series pull you in as a player, and the level designers did a good job with what I saw.</p>



<p>You can still play at your own pace, something that goes a long way towards getting more players to enjoy the game. Whether I wanted to go in guns blazing or take it as slow as humanly possible, I’m able to do that. It just all depends on what’s happening around me and what I’m trying to accomplish. There are multiple ways to get to, and complete, an objective that you can replay the mission multiple times and it’ll feel fresh for a few playthroughs.</p>



<p>The kill cam that the Sniper Elite series is known for remains as satisfying as ever. Hitting that perfect shot that has you watch a bullet rip through the face of a Nazi is as gruesome as you’d expect. It’s also enjoyable watching the other soldiers scramble and panic after they see a comrade’s head get blown to pieces right next to them.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In the preview build, we couldn’t change the difficulty, meaning we were limited in how we could experience the game from that sense. Luckily, the AI wasn’t too unforgiving, though it did make you work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was nice that when the AI was searching for something (me) after hearing a noise, they wouldn’t play too dumb, so to speak. Plenty of games I’ve played would have the AI stand right on top of you and not notice a thing if you were in cover. In this, there were a couple of times where they would happen to walk right up on me only to spot my cover while I wasn’t moving, leading to me having to fight my way out or die trying.</p>



<p>That said, the AI weren’t savants all of the time. There were times where they would just stand a bit too still or in the same place so long to the point you couldn’t continue without adjusting in a way that didn’t feel natural to what you should or were trying to do.</p>



<p>They can even be too locked in their planned movement. One specific instance involves a Gestapo infantryman always having to sit on a bench, stand up, and then turn and look at the bench before walking around the building to just repeat the sequence. It feels a bit strange in those moments that are more than enough to break immersion.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="INTERVIEW: Sniper Elite Resistance With Lead Level Designer Beck Shaw" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dItx-bQsZ0U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>There was also an instance where it was pretty clear my shot should have hit an enemy in the face only for him to get hit, get up, and just slowly walk away while another bullet just ricochets off his helmet while he <em>continues </em>to walk. Maybe the shot wasn’t as good as I thought it was at the time, but something just felt off with what I believe should’ve happened.</p>



<p>Nevertheless, what I played had me excited about the full story and just how else I’ll be able to take down the Nazi’s in France this time around. However, one thing I kept thinking about after my time with the game was whether there will be enough here with a full game to warrant a purchase by fans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s a full campaign, the returning invasion mode, and new Propaganda Missions that Rebellion hopes keeps players engaged overall. But as I said at the beginning, if you’ve played either of the last two Sniper Elite titles, this will feel quite familiar, especially when the overall setting remains the same from the last game just with new locations. With Resistance coming less than three full years after Sniper Elite 5 – the gap between 4 and 5 was over five years – Rebellion runs the risk of franchise fatigue if the rest of the game’s story doesn’t hold up.</p>



<p>Sniper Elite: Resistance launches January 30 for Xbox, PlayStation, and PC.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our full <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-review-heart-of-chornobyl/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review of STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a>. And don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded: Release date, new guns, CODMAS event & more]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1-reloaded-release-date-new-guns-codmas-event-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-season-1-reloaded-release-date-new-guns-codmas-event-more.1044498/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1-reloaded-release-date-new-guns-codmas-event-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 Season 1</a> has already introduced a load of new content, from the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-krig-c-in-black-ops-6-and-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Krig C</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-saug-in-black-ops-6-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saug SMG</a> to new maps and modes. That said, the devs still have more up their sleeve, as the mid-season Reloaded update is set to bring another wave of content for players.</p>



<p>For those interested in what’s coming in the Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded update, as well as the update’s release date, here are all the details you need to know.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-when-is-black-ops-6-season-1-reloaded-update">When is Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded update?</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-new-weapons-in-season-1-reloaded">New weapons</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-new-maps-amp-modes">New maps &amp; modes</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-codmas-event-in-bo6-season-1-reloaded">CODMAS event in Black Ops 6</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-when-is-black-ops-6-season-1-reloaded-update">When is Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded update?</h2>



<p>BO6 Season 1 Reloaded will arrive on <strong>Thursday, December 5, 2024</strong>, at around <strong>10 AM PT / 1 PM ET / 6 PM GMT</strong>.</p>



<p>Treyarch confirmed this via <a href="https://x.com/Treyarch/status/1860035600344314193" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a>, where they announced the release date for the new Zombie map, Citadelle des Morts, which arrives with the mid-season update.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-weapons-in-season-1-reloaded">New weapons in Season 1 Reloaded</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-maelstorm-in-black-ops-6-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Maelstorm Shotgun</a>, AMR Mod 4 Sniper Rifle, and Cleaver Melee Weapon will all be arriving with the Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded update.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement#Weapons" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CoD blog</a>, these weapons will be available via an “Event Reward.” This likely means that players will need to complete an in-game challenge in order to unlock them, similar to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-sirin-9mm-in-black-ops-6-and-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sirin 9mm</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-power-drill-in-black-ops-6-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Power Drill</a> in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-hit-list-event-release-date-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hit List event</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-maps-amp-modes">New maps &amp; modes</h2>



<p>Black Ops 4’s <strong>Hacienda</strong> arrives as a 6v6 map in BO6 Season 1 Reloaded. Players will also be getting a new, smaller Strike map called <strong>Racket</strong>, while <strong>Nuketown Holiday</strong> brings the Christmas Holiday vibes to the iconic Black Ops map. </p>



<p>The devs also revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-prop-hunt-coming-to-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prop Hunt</a> will be available “in-season,” so we expect that mode to arrive after Season 1 Reloaded. Further, limited-time modes will also be arriving, which seem to be associated with the CODMAS event.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-citadelle-des-morts">Citadelle des Morts</h2>



<p>The brand-new round-based Zombies map, Citadelle des Morts, arrives on December 5th alongside the update, bringing yet another Easter egg for players to complete.</p>



<p>The map is set in an abandoned Castle in Europe, and leaks suggest that the map will feature elemental swords and the iconic Wunderwaffe DG2. For all the details on the new Zombies map, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-new-black-ops-6-zombies-map-coming-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">detailed guide on Citadelle des Morts</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-codmas-event-in-bo6-season-1-reloaded">CODMAS event in BO6 Season 1 Reloaded</h2>



<p>To celebrate the Christmas holidays, Black Ops 6 will host yet another CODMAS event in Call of Duty. This event will bring a variety of rewards for players to earn, all with a holiday theme. </p>



<p>In the past, we’ve seen CODMAS bring a variety of cosmetics to the game as well as map makeovers, which <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-nuketown-manniquin-easter-egg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nuketown</a> Holiday will bring. We’ve also seen limited-time modes like Krampus too, so perhaps players can expect something similar for BO6.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you excited for the Black Ops 6 Season 1 Reloaded update? Let us know what content you’re most looking forward to by leaving a comment in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">forum</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re more into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-1-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warzone</a>, check out our guide on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-level-up-fast-in-warzone-best-mode-weapon-xp-prestige/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to level up your rank and weapons fast</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-perk-wildcard-in-warzone-x-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">every Perk and Wildcard you can use for battle royale</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Christopher Judge Denies God of War Announcement Tease]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-announcement-denied/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/christopher-judge-denies-god-of-war-announcement-tease.1044474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-announcement-denied/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Christopher Judge has taken to X (formerly Twitter) to deny that he was teasing an announcement about God of War.</p>



<p>The God of War actor recently took to TikTok to say that “the next two weeks will be chocked full of announcements and all kinds of good stuff. ” He ended the message by saying “boy,” a phrase that became popular in the recent God of War games. </p>



<p>Whether Judge knew it or not, his tease that there would be announcements “in the next two weeks” coincides perfectly with PlayStation’s 30th anniversary, leading people to believe that an announcement of God of War is on the horizon.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, several rumors circulated that a God of War Trilogy remaster was in the works. Judge’s tease, combined with the rumors, led many fans to conclude that it could be announced during a rumored 30th-anniversary showcase.</p>



<p>However, Judge quickly denied the claims on X. “Absolutely not true! You can’t tease something you know nothing about. I will be making announcements in the near future, I can guarantee none of them will be about OUR beloved God of War. I am awaiting updates just like everyone else,” <a href="https://x.com/iamchrisjudge/status/1860887360931569956" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">he said</a>.</p>



<p>Whether Judge got into trouble with PlayStation because of his original statements remains to be seen, with some people suggesting that the tweet was just to keep the impending announcement a surprise.</p>



<p>As for now though, we’ll have to wait and see. Do you think we’ll get a God of War announcement in the coming weeks? Let us know <span>below, and join the official&nbsp;</span><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/forums/playstation.4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow"><span>Insider Gami</span>ng forums</a> discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-sniper-elites-battle-royale-game-has-been-canceled-as-tencent-pulls-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the cancellation of the Sniper Elite battle royale</a>&nbsp;game. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>