<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 13:25:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Open Beta Poll Reveals Community’s Favorite Map]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-poll-reveals-communitys-favorite-map/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-open-beta-poll-reveals-community%E2%80%99s-favorite-map.1272600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Battlefield 6 Open Beta has ended. For two weekends, hundreds of thousands of players went to war with each other. Now that the dust and rubble have settled, it’s time to see what the community has judged to be the best Battlefield 6 map—and worst.</p>



<p>Battlefield has had its fair share of classic maps over the years. Everyone always wants to see a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-games-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ranking of the best Battlefield games</a>, but we recently went one better. We broke down our favorite <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/9-best-battlefield-maps-of-all-time-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield maps</a>, giving high praise to Wake Island and Caspian Border. It’s time to see which <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-the-battlefield-6-beta-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 beta</a> maps stood out.</p>



<h2 id="h-siege-of-cairo-leads-the-way-in-battlefield-6">Siege of Cairo Leads The Way in Battlefield 6</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A clear winner. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p>Yes, I’ll cut straight to the chase, Siege of Cairo has comfortably been voted as the favorite Battlefield 6 map.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://x.com/BFBulletin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield Bulletin</a>, a poll was launched to find out the answer. It states that only roughly 10,000 votes were cast. Given that the Open Beta recorded well over 500,000 players, we get it’s a tiny percentage of the crowd. Still, it’s fun to analyze this portion of the data.</p>



<p>Out of Siege of Cairo, Liberation Peak, Empire State, and Iberian Offensive, Siege of Cairo came out on top with 47% of the vote. Liberation Peak was a distant second with 27%, Empire State recorded 16%, and Iberian Offensive only managed 11%.</p>



<p>These polls are always subjective, though. Personally, I loved Iberian Offensive. I wouldn’t have had it last (maybe Liberation Peak). </p>



<div><article><p><span>According to a community’s poll with over 10,000 votes via </span><a href="https://twitter.com/Battlefield" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Battlefield</a><span>, Siege of Cairo is the most favourite map from </span><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Battlefield6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#Battlefield6</a><span>‘s Open Beta whereas Iberian Offensive is the less, favourite map.</span></p></article></div>



<p>But this is the time to tell us what you think. Do you agree with Siege of Cairo being number one? Or is it ranked too highly? Head to the comments to let us know. Plus, go to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> to talk all things Battlefield 6.</p>



<hr>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-battlefield-2042-content-appears-following-end-of-battlefield-6-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">New Battlefield 2042 content appearing following the end of the Battlefield 6 Beta</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-annual-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield aiming to become an annual release within 5-6 years</a> are other pieces of hot BF news.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-poll-reveals-communitys-favorite-map/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Petition Calling for Roblox CEO’s Resignation Reaches 110,000 Signatures in 10 Days]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-petition-ceo-resignation-removal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/petition-calling-for-roblox-ceo%E2%80%99s-resignation-reaches-110-000-signatures-in-10-days.1272510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>As the controversial cacophony continues with Roblox, disgruntled gamers worldwide have poured into a petition to demand the removal or resignation of Roblox’s CEO, David Baszucki. In less than ten days, the petition has racked up more than 110,000 signatures, and more are coming in with every passing minute.</p>



<p>This is all in response to the recent (but not the first) complaints regarding Roblox’s handling of child safety protocols and the control of predatory action on the platform.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-roblox-s-ceo-going-to-resign">Is Roblox’s CEO Going to Resign?</h2>



<p>It’s impossible to know what the strategy is for the Roblox team at present, but 110,000 signatures and counting can’t be ignored.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.change.org/p/remove-david-baszucki" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the petition</a>, a clear explanation has been outlined:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Roblox is supposed to be a safe and creative space for children. But under the leadership of CEO David Baszucki, that safety has been repeatedly compromised. Instead of prioritizing the protection of young users, Roblox Corporation continues to allow harmful and exploitative behavior to thrive on its platform — with little accountability or transparency.</p>



<p>Children are being exploited and exposed to dangerous content, all while Roblox’s executive leadership turns a blind eye. If nothing changes, this pattern of negligence will continue — and more children will be hurt. This is not just about poor leadership. This is about child safety.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This is far from being the first time that these criticisms and concerns have surfaced, but this is perhaps the most severe bout we’ve had yet.</p>



<h2 id="h-roblox-is-being-investigated-for-child-safety">Roblox is Being Investigated for Child Safety</h2>



<p>In recent weeks, Louisiana’s attorney general filed a lawsuit against Roblox, demanding that the company do more to protect children on the platform. Most recently, it was announced that Chris ‘To Catch a Predator’ Hansen <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/chris-hansen-confirms-going-after-roblox/">is assembling a documentary</a> diving into the state of play in the world of Roblox, and is working hand-in-hand with the likes of Schlep.</p>



<p>Roblox remains arguably the most popular game in the world by the sheer number of active users within the ecosystem. Could that be set to change with a mass exodus and shunning sitting on the nearby horizon?</p>



<p>Let me know if you’ve had any issues with Roblox on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-descendant-ads-investigation-tiktok/">The First Descendant devs are investigating the recent TikTok AI ads</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-petition-ceo-resignation-removal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is The Gears of War: Reloaded Review Embargo Date?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-gears-of-war-reloaded-review-embargo-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-gears-of-war-reloaded-review-embargo-date.1272507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Gears of War: Reloaded will provide a fresh boost for the franchise in a big push from Microsoft, with another new title also on the cards, and we’ve got all the details on the review embargo.</p>



<p>Set for release on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">August 26</a>, Gears of War: Reloaded is the second big remake for the franchise following Gears of War: Ultimate Edition, and there’s an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-gears-of-war-reloaded-free-upgrade/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upgrade to the new version available</a>, while one of the big additions is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-crossplay-cross-platform-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossplay functionality</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re on the fence on whether to purchase Gears of War: Reloaded, you may want to wait to see how the review scores stack up. There is a review embargo in place, however, and we’ve got all the details on when it lifts.</p>



<h2 id="h-gears-of-war-reloaded-review-embargo-date-explained">Gears of War: Reloaded Review Embargo Date, Explained</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Here we go again. Credit to The Coalition</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The official Gears of War: Reloaded review embargo ends on August 26, though no precise time has been announced.</strong></p>



<p>Confirmation of the review embargo date came from <a href="https://x.com/MrboomstickXL/status/1956428233785672132" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MrboomstickXL on X</a> (formerly Twitter), who told followers they would “be able to give my thoughts on August 26th when the embargo is lifted.”</p>



<p>The embargo comes on the same day as the release, although given the code supplied to the source mentioned is a YouTube channel, there could be a separate review embargo for written content. We’ll update this article with any further details that might emerge.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-gears-of-war-reloaded-scores-can-we-expect">What Gears of War: Reloaded Scores Can we Expect?</h2>



<p><strong>As a remake</strong>, <strong>Gears of War: Reloaded will be marked heavily on the differences compared to the original time at the Ultimate Edition released in 2015, though scores should be high.</strong></p>



<p>The original Gears of War, released in 2006, has an impressive <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/gears-of-war/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metacritic</a> score with 94 from critic reviews, with user scores averaging at 8.2. Those numbers did drop for the Ultimate Edition, however, with a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/gears-of-war-ultimate-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">critic score of 82</a> and a user score of 7.8.</p>



<p>We’d expect scores to be in a similar range for the franchise, which usually lands with an 80-90 average score, including the much-maligned Gears 5, which has an 84 average score and 8.2 user review average.</p>



<p>Anything below the 80 mark would certainly be considered a blow for the title, particularly given that it is making the huge step of leaving Microsoft exclusivity and making a PlayStation debut.</p>



<p>What are you expecting from Gears of War: Reloaded? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Gears of War, check out our ranking of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-gears-of-war-game-ranked-from-worst-to-best/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">every game from worst to best</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-pre-order-bonuses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pre-order bonuses available</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-gears-of-war-reloaded-review-embargo-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Battlefield 2042 Content Appears Following End of Battlefield 6 Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-battlefield-2042-content-appears-following-end-of-battlefield-6-beta/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-battlefield-2042-content-appears-following-end-of-battlefield-6-beta.1272501/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-139923">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>EA is encouraging players to hop back into Battlefield 2042 after a chaotic few weeks in the Battlefield 6 beta. We’re all being tempted back in with new weapons, vehicles, and a rumored new map.</p>



<p>All good things must come to an end. The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-the-battlefield-6-beta-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 beta</a> broke records and has been a big success. Battlefield might finally be back, but the irony of this statement is that it has to go away for another couple of months. But you can hop back into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2042-player-count-steam-charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 2042</a> while you wait as new free goodies await.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-guns-amp-vehicles-added-to-battlefield-2042">New Guns &amp; Vehicles Added to Battlefield 2042</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’ll be back, don’t worry. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p>We recently reported that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2042-update-surprisingly-big-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 2042 could be getting a ‘Surprisingly Big’ update soon</a>. BF 2042 has largely abandoned the seasonal content schedule as it’s full steam ahead for Battlefield 6.</p>



<p>This hasn’t stopped <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-2042" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield 2042</a> from receiving the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lynx (Weapon)</li>



<li>F2000 (Weapon)</li>



<li>Warthog (Vehicle)</li>



<li>Frogfoot (Vehicle)</li>
</ul>



<p>As of writing, there are still items missing from the update that were initially rumored: The Prototype (another weapon) and the Iwo Jima map. This doesn’t mean they won’t be happening. We’ll keep an eye on things to see if they’re added to Battlefield 2042.</p>



<p>Are you returning to Battlefield 2042 before Battlefield 6’s full launch? Or are you interested in checking out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-5-player-count-steam-charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 5</a> again, for example? Share your thoughts and more via the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>We have more Battlefield content waiting to be read: Check out the report that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-annual-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield is aiming to become an annual release within 5-6 years</a>, and a dev saying <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-and-call-of-duty-complement-each-other-says-developer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield and Call of Duty complement each other</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-voice-actor-david-hayter-has-forgiven-mgs5-after-refusing-to-play-it-because-of-humiliation/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-voice-actor-david-hayter-has-forgiven-mgs5-after-refusing-to-play-it-because-of-humiliation/">
                                Metal Gear Solid Voice Actor David Hayter Has “Forgiven” MGS5 After Refusing to Play it Because of “Humiliation”                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>David Hayter is the most iconic MGS voice actor, and he recently revealed that he had only just played Metal Gear Solid 5: The Phantom Pain.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-to-debut-mega-evolution-later-this-year/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-to-debut-mega-evolution-later-this-year/">
                                Pokémon TCG Pocket to Debut Mega Evolution Later This Year                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokémon TCG Pocket is introducing Mega Evolution this Fall as part of a new season, with the first cards already revealed.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-feature-ranked-battles-four-player-pvp-mode/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-feature-ranked-battles-four-player-pvp-mode/">
                                Pokémon Legends: Z-A Will Feature Ranked Battles &amp; Four-Player PvP Mode                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A has made a big shift from Pokémon Legends: Arceus with the introduction of online features.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-annual-releases/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-annual-releases/">
                                Battlefield is Aiming to Become an Annual Release Within 5-6 Years, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim has said that EA wants the Battlefield franchise to become an annual release, just like Call of Duty.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-battlefield-2042-content-appears-following-end-of-battlefield-6-beta/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Voice Actor David Hayter Has “Forgiven” MGS5 After Refusing to Play it Because of “Humiliation”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-voice-actor-david-hayter-has-forgiven-mgs5-after-refusing-to-play-it-because-of-humiliation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-voice-actor-david-hayter-has-%E2%80%9Cforgiven%E2%80%9D-mgs5-after-refusing-to-play-it-because-of-%E2%80%9Chumiliation%E2%80%9D.1272480/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>While you might not recognize David Hayter if you walked past him on the street, you’d certainly become wide-eyed if you heard his Snake voice. The legendary voice actor, who commanded the role of Snake for many years in MGS, recently revealed that he has finally played Metal Gear Solid 5—a tough ask, given he was replaced as Snake’s voice actor.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kojima-working-on-physint-all-by-himself/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hideo Kojima</a> is the creative visionary behind Metal Gear Solid. There’s no denying MGS wouldn’t be what it is without him. But the gruff, roughness of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/david-hayter-mgs-konami/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">David Hayter</a>‘s Solid Snake voice added to the character’s aura of the years. However, Hideo Kojima replaced Hayter with Kiefer Sutherland for Metal Gear Solid 5: Ground Zeroes and The Phantom Pain. This hurt Hayter a lot.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Time is the ultimate healer. Credit to Konami</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hayter told <a href="https://gameinformer.com/b/news/archive/2016/03/25/david-hayter-playing-metal-gear-solid-v-would-have-been-60-hours-of-humiliation.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Informer</a> in 2016 that playing Metal Gear Solid V would have been “60 hours of humiliation.” He also added that Kojima had been trying to replace Hayter before The Phantom Pain, before ultimately doing so with Kiefer Sutherland—best known for the TV show 24.</p>



<p>As a result, Hayter didn’t play The Phantom Pain or Ground Zeroes: “Yeah. That’ll be 60 hours of humiliation that I can’t get to. I haven’t played the latest two iterations, because it’s just too painful.”</p>



<p><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/all-is-forgiven-after-being-dropped-for-metal-gear-solid-5-david-hayter-now-says-its-my-favourite-gameplay-of-the-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VGC</a> reports that David Hayter has finally played Metal Gear Solid 5: The Phantom Pain: “And then I played it and I’m like, I think this is my favourite gameplay of the series. The fact that you can go into the same scenario each time, and the [enemy] soldier’s gonna be doing the same thing, but you can take on different routes or different strategies of attack, makes it feel like time travel.”</p>



<p>He added that the gameplay is “badass” and “all is forgiven.”</p>



<p>David Hayter was returned to the role of Snake in the upcoming <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-a-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>. The voice actor has new lines as the remake looks to provide new content for all fans. Are you happy to hear the OG voice actor is back for the Snake Eater Remake? What’s your favorite Snake line? Let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more MGS content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-remake-original-mgs-snake-eater-3-differences-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Remake &amp; original MGS Snake Eater 3 differences</a>, and the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-trophy-list-all-achievement-trophy-differences-in-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trophy list</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-voice-actor-david-hayter-has-forgiven-mgs5-after-refusing-to-play-it-because-of-humiliation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>