<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 20:21:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where is Cache in Counter-Strike 2? (Answered)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered.1102278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The fluctuating map pool of Counter-Strike keeps the iconic first-person shooter from getting stagnant, but CS2 players have not gotten to (officially) experience Cache yet. In fact, Cache has not been in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-adds-train-to-map-pool/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the “active duty map pool”</a> for years, and the last time it was played at a Major was before the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>So where is Cache?</p>



<p><em>Before you jump below, consider&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trying your luck on Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;– you could turn your unwanted skins into something much more valuable (18+ only)</em></p>



<h2 id="h-why-is-cache-not-in-counter-strike-2">Why Is Cache Not in Counter-Strike 2?</h2>



<p>Cache is not in CS2 yet because the the original map creator, Shawn “FMPONE” Snelling, is still remaking it. According to the creator’s Discord, a portion of the map areas are complete, but this update was last made in July 2024. The areas that are supposedly complete are the A site, A Main, A Long, B Halls, B Checkers, B Site, Garage, Middle, and the T Spawn. This leaves areas like CT Spawn, A Truck, Highway, Z, Heaven, and Tree as potentially still being worked on.</p>



<p>FMPONE is one of the three original creators of Cache for CS:GO, along with Sal “Volcano” Garozzo and Lenz “penE” Monath. While the other two have gone on to other projects, FMPONE has created other maps such as Santorini and Thera. However, those maps never reached the active duty map pool, and fans continued to clamor for a remade Cache.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Back in late 2023, after CS2 was originally announced, FMPONE <a href="https://x.com/FMPONE/status/1645147213205520385" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">did confirm</a> that he would remake Cache. However, he opted to focus on creating his new maps first. Still, throughout 2024, FMPONE released a series of images teasing the return of Cache and showing progress on the remake. Every update that’s been posted has been met with a wave of excitement from long-time players who are eagerly awaiting the debut of a new look Cache.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-cache-coming-to-cs2">When is Cache Coming to CS2?</h2>



<p>The last public update fans saw of Cache though came back in October, with a collection of screenshots showing T spawn, the CT truck angle of A site, and other areas. Prior to this update, fans were treated to new screenshots every month. But as of February 2025, it’s been more than three months since the last Cache update. Is FMPONE focused on other things at this time? Or is the radio silence building to a soon-to-be-revealed surprise launch?</p>



<p>Do you want to see Cache officially return to CS2? Let us know in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p><em>If you want to unlock free daily cases and rewards in CS2,&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;(18+ only)</em></p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>