<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 20:19:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Developers Detail Season And Half-Season Ranks]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks.1105161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>With the first half of Season 1 drawing to a close, Marvel Rivals developer NetEase has published a new update regarding ranks. This update helps players understand what to expect at the end of the half and in the second half of the inaugural season and beyond.</p>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/devdiaries/20250210/40954_1210988.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s website</a>, the studio said that the first half of the season will end on February 21. At that time, all rankings will be locked and players ranked Gold and higher will get a costume reward. Those Grandmaster and higher as well as the Top 500 will receive the “Crest of Honor”.</p>



<p>“In the second half of the season, we will be rolling out new costume rewards for Gold rank players, along with brand new Crests of Honor,” NetEase said. “These Crests will recognize players at Grandmaster, Celestial, Eternity, and One Above All (the top 500), each with its own unique design to celebrate your skill!”</p>



<p>After the first-half ranks are settled, they will all be reason when the second half of Season 1 starts that day. When it starts, NetEase says  that players will see their rank drop by four divisions. In future seasons, that drop will be six divisions at the beginning and then a drop of four at the start of the second half of each season.</p>



<p>Lastly, the studio says that in order to make sure only players who actually play during the current season can earn rewards, players will need to play at least 10 matches in competitive mode along with meeting required ranking conditions.</p>



<p>What do you think of how Marvel Rivals is handling in-season ranks? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony turning down the Resistance 4&nbsp;pitch</a> and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phasmophobia-reveals-2025-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2025 roadmap for Phasmophobia</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>