<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:54:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Call of Duty Players to Watch in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/top-call-of-duty-players-to-watch-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/top-call-of-duty-players-to-watch-in-2025.1066065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/top-call-of-duty-players-to-watch-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Call of Duty League’s 2025 season is in full flow, and there are plenty of players on the board eager to prove themselves this year. It has been a mixed bag of matches to kickstart the competitive season, and some shockers have been handed out. In the opening weeks of the CDL 2025 season, Atlanta FaZe plummeted to the bottom of the table, sending shockwaves through COD’s community.</p>



<p>In this guide, I’m going to break down the top Call of Duty players to watch in 2025. From the upcoming rookie talent to the future world champions, this list covers everyone worth watching this season.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-mixed-bag">Mixed Bag</h2>



<p>Here are the players you should keep an eye on as the competitive season unfolds.</p>



<h3 id="h-isaiah-gwinn-gwinn">Isaiah ‘Gwinn’ Gwinn</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Gwinn hit the ground running this year with the Carolina Royal Ravens. He served an instrumental role in the team being propelled to the top of the table, securing a perfect record in the opening weeks against some capable squads, including Atlanta FaZe. He was pivotal in handing FaZe the first 0 – 3 loss the team has secured in almost two years.</p>



<p>By mid-December, Gwinn was sitting on a KD of 1.34, leading the pack and standing atop some of the best Call of Duty players in the world.</p>



<h3 id="h-thomas-scrap-ernst">Thomas ‘Scrap’ Ernst</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Scrap’s ascension has been a glorious thing to watch. He started as a loud-mouthed rookie on Toronto Ultra, beefing with anyone who would look in his direction. He eventually mellowed and became much more rounded out as a player, but the Call of Duty League Championship has remained out of reach for him two years in a row.</p>



<p>With a second-place finish in 2023 and a third-place finish in 2024, it’s only a matter of time before this world-class player secures his trophy, and this year, he’s backed by a killer team on LA Thieves.</p>



<h3 id="h-anthony-shotzzy-cuevas-castro">Anthony ‘Shotzzy’ Cuevas-Castro</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s impossible to jot down the most electrifying competitors in COD esports and <strong>not </strong>include Shotzzy. For years, this young pro player has been a superstar of the game, securing two world championships and dominating from every angle. He’s one of the most entertaining players to watch, and many consider him to be godlike on the sticks.</p>



<p>Last year, he secured the world championship with OpTic Texas, and he’s already started strong this season. In Black Ops 6, Shotzzy can make the most of Omnimovement, flying around the map with reckless abandon, and even if he doesn’t go back-to-back at CDL Champs, he’s one of the most hilarious players to watch, period.</p>



<h3 id="h-khalid-khhx-almadhi">Khalid ‘Khhx’ Almadhi</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Khhx is one of the newest players in the Call of Duty League, entering the fray with the Vegas Falcons, an all-new squad backed by a Saudi Arabian investment. Fans wrote off the Vegas Falcons ahead of the competitive season, and a donut hasn’t helped the squad gain much traction, but a standout member of the team is Khalid ‘Khhx’ Almadhi.</p>



<p>At the time of publishing, the Vegas Falcons boasted a 0 – 4 win record and a 14% map win percentage, which is woeful, but Khhx has been working like gangbusters to escape the bottom of the leaderboard.</p>



<p>His debut match against the Royal Ravens was a loss, but it saw him secure a solid opening KD, and per the stats, he went on to hit a 1.28 KD in his second spin, becoming the first player to kickstart his tenure in the CDL with two matches above a 1.2 KD. To open the season, he sat above the likes of Dashy and Pred in terms of overall KD.</p>



<h3 id="h-paco-hydra-rusiewiez">Paco ‘HyDra’ Rusiewiez</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>HyDra has been a phenomenal player year in, year out since debuting with the New York Subliners in 2021. In the Modern Warfare II season, he skyrocketed to success with the squad, securing two Major wins and a world championship victory, along with a smattering of MVP awards.</p>



<p>Last season, he snatched a second-place finish at COD Champs, securing some of the most exhilarating plays in the wider tournament and cementing himself as one to watch for years to come. This year, he’s flying the LA Thieves banner alongside Envoy, Scrap, and Ghosty, which many consider to be one of the greatest potential-filled rosters <strong>ever</strong>.</p>



<p>He has opened the season with a 1.18 overall KD and a perfect record of 4 – 0, at the time of publishing. Few players are more worthy of your time or attention than HyDra.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think about this list? Are there other players you’d like to see on this page? Let us know in the comments and stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports coverage</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naoe Will Be ‘The Fastest Assassin We Ever Made’, Ubisoft Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/naoe-fastest-assassin-ever/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naoe-will-be-%E2%80%98the-fastest-assassin-we-ever-made%E2%80%99-ubisoft-says.1066056/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/naoe-fastest-assassin-ever/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows will be released early next year, and already the game has started splitting the community down the middle. Since the title was revealed by Ubisoft earlier this year, it has proven to be a divisive game, and nobody truly knows how to feel about it. It was given a significant pushback by Ubisoft already, as it was supposed to be released in October 2024.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with Entertainment Weekly, Ubisoft’s Jonathan Dumont took a deep dive into Naoe, one of the game’s lead characters who fights alongside Yasuke, the first assassin in the series based on someone who <strong>actually existed</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-super-speedy">Super Speedy</h2>



<p>In the interview with Entertainment Weekly, the creative director of Assassin’s Creed Shadows, Jonathan Dumont, explained the advantages of Naoe, a ‘shinobi’-style character with insane agility levels:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Naoe’s the fastest Assassin we ever made. She runs super fast, she has a lot of gadgets to keep her stealth so that she doesn’t have to fight often. We wanted to satisfy that for players that come in for that ninja-Assassin game.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Assassin’s Creed fans spent years begging for a title to surface set in Japan, but when it was finally revealed, it left many feeling disappointed. Given that Ubisoft was beaten to the punch by the likes of Ghost of Tsushima, a high bar has been set that the current Ubisoft formula might not be able to reach.</p>



<p>The proof will be in the pudding, though.</p>



<p>In 2023, Ubisoft released Assassin’s Creed Mirage, and it was taken in remarkably well by fans because it was a small-form game that was seen as a return to the more classic AC experience. In AC Shadows, it’s back to the gargantuan open-world RPG model.</p>



<p>In Shadows, Naoe’s story is all about self-discovery and the betterment of her character and those close to her. Dumont explored that in the interview with <a href="https://ew.com/assassins-creed-shadows-naoe-backstory-fastest-assassin-we-ever-made-exclusive-8762696" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Entertainment Weekly</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>She will start a bit of a path of vengeance or fulfilling a promise that she made to her family. As she discovers a world in need, she begins to really value the community values her father taught. Can she make a better world?</p>



<p>The Hidden Blade is given by her father, and we’re going to learn a little bit more what that means.</p>



<p>She does feel like a panther looking at her prey.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows will launch amidst a packed release window on February 14 – are you looking forward to the game? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-confirmed-for-2027/">Sonic the Hedgehog 4 is coming in 2027</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indie Game Awards 2024 – Every Winner Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/indie-game-awards-2024-every-winner-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indie-game-awards-2024-%E2%80%93-every-winner-announced.1066005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/indie-game-awards-2024-every-winner-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-75158">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The inaugural Indie Game Awards presented by Six One Indie took place on Thursday night (December 19), and with it came 20 awards and honors given out to some of the best indie games and studios of 2024. </p>



<p>You can see all of the Indie Game Awards winners below along with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inaugural-indie-game-awards-announce-full-list-of-nominees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">various nominees</a> if relevant. In addition to listing the winners, you can watch each specific segment as well. If you want to watch the full show, you can do so below or on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WeYNL_wSntE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official Six One Indie channel</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Indie Game Awards 2024: December 19th at 4PM PT / 7PM ET" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WeYNL_wSntE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-indie-game-awards-2024-winners">The Indie Game Awards 2024 Winners</h2>



<h3 id="h-game-of-the-year">Game of the Year</h3>



<ul>
<li>1000xRESIST</li>



<li>Animal Well</li>



<li>ARCO</li>



<li><strong>Balatro – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Crypt Custodian</li>



<li>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</li>



<li>Mouthwashing</li>



<li>Neva</li>



<li>Nine Sols</li>



<li>UFO 50</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-the-mohammad-fahmi-storyteller-award">The Mohammad Fahmi Storyteller Award</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Toge Productions Presents the Mohammad Fahmi Storyteller Award at The Indie Game Awards" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E-puGaS9B7s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3 id="h-industry-impact-four-winners">Industry Impact – Four Winners</h3>



<ul>
<li>Outersloth</li>



<li>New Blood</li>



<li>Day of the Devs</li>



<li>Strange Scaffold</li>
</ul>



<h3>Debut Game</h3>



<ul>
<li>Arranger</li>



<li>Lil’ Guardsman</li>



<li><strong>Little Kitty, Big City – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Loddlenaut</li>



<li>MULLET MADJACK</li>



<li>Worldless</li>
</ul>



<h3>Notable Achievement in Accessibility</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Another Crab’s Treasure – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Elsie</li>



<li>Periphery Synthetic</li>



<li>Pine Hearts</li>



<li>SteamWorld Heist II</li>



<li>Surmount: A Mountain Climbing Adventure</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-able-to-play-introduction">Able To Play Introduction</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Arman Nobari Introduces Able To Play During The Indie Game Awards" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-QaZOQxjeHE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3>Music</h3>



<ul>
<li>Core Keeper</li>



<li>Flock</li>



<li><strong>Pacific Drive – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>The Cub</li>



<li>Thrasher</li>



<li>Wild Bastards</li>
</ul>



<h3>Visual Design</h3>



<ul>
<li>Bo: Path of the Teal Lotus</li>



<li>Crow Country</li>



<li><strong>Harold Halibut – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Hauntii</li>



<li>The Plucky Squire</li>



<li>Ultros</li>
</ul>



<h3>Bite-Sized Game</h3>



<ul>
<li>Buckshot Roulette</li>



<li>Clickholding</li>



<li>Duck Detective: The Secret Salami</li>



<li>Minami Lane</li>



<li>Please Touch the Artwork 2</li>



<li><strong>Thank Goodness You’re Here – WINNER</strong></li>
</ul>



<h3>Innovation</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cryptmaster – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>KarmaZoo</li>



<li>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</li>



<li>ODDADA</li>



<li>Rusty’s Retirement</li>



<li>UFO 50</li>
</ul>



<h3>Emotional Impact</h3>



<ul>
<li>In Stars and Time</li>



<li>Kind Words 2</li>



<li><strong>Neva – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Selfloss</li>



<li>Thirsty Suitors</li>



<li>Until Then</li>
</ul>



<h3>Gameplay Design</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Balatro – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Grunn</li>



<li>Minishoot Adventures</li>



<li>Nine Sols</li>



<li>Tiny Glade</li>



<li>Victory Heat Rally</li>
</ul>



<h3>Community Management</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Aggro Crab – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Black Tabby Games</li>



<li>LocalThunk</li>



<li>Massive Monster</li>



<li>NPC Studio</li>



<li>Pounce Light</li>
</ul>



<h3>Narrative</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>1000xRESIST – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>ARCO</li>



<li>Caravan SandWitch</li>



<li>Fear The Spotlight</li>



<li>Last Time I Saw You</li>



<li>Mouthwashing</li>
</ul>



<h3>Women-Led Game</h3>



<ul>
<li>Gourdlets</li>



<li>Keylocker</li>



<li>Love, Ghostie</li>



<li><strong>Mexico, 1921. A Deep Slumber. – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Nightmare Kart</li>



<li>The Crimson Diamond</li>
</ul>



<h3>Solo Development</h3>



<ul>
<li>Aerial_Knight’s We Never Yield</li>



<li><strong>Animal Well – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Children of the Sun</li>



<li>Crypt Custodian</li>



<li>Knuckle Sandwich</li>



<li>Magical Delicacy</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>Do you agree with the choices at The Indie Game Awards 2024? Let us know in the discussion over on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-confirmed-for-2027/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-confirmed-for-2027/">Sonic The Hedgehog 4 Confirmed For 2027</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Paramount Pictures has confirmed that Sonic the Hedgehog 4 is coming, and it will release in theaters in 2027.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/11-bit-studios-cancels-project-8-lays-off-employees/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/11-bit-studios-cancels-project-8-lays-off-employees/">11 Bit Studios Cancels Project 8, Lays Off Employees</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Frostpunk developer 11 Bit Studios has announced layoffs along with the cancellation of its Project 8 game.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/second-wave-helldivers-2-killzone-2-crossover-content-will-be-free/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/second-wave-helldivers-2-killzone-2-crossover-content-will-be-free/">Second Wave Of Helldivers 2 X Killzone 2 Crossover Content Will Be Free</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Arrowhead Game Studios and Guerrilla Games have announced that the next wave of Helldivers 2 x Killzone 2 crossover content will be free.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-confirms-it-recast-black-ops-6-zombies-actors/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-confirms-it-recast-black-ops-6-zombies-actors/">Activision Seemingly Confirms It Recast Black Ops 6 Zombies Actors</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has confirmed that it recast actors in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Zombies, referencing the SAG-AFTRA strike as a reason.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>