<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:32:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Voice Actor Found Out About Game Cancelation Through Media]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/voice-actor-game-cancelation-through-media/</link>
            <guid>1416169</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s what she calls “the most devastating moment” of her career: the moment Eman Ayaz found out about a video game’s cancelation through the media. </p>



<p>In a new video on her <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gY0hv4QFIak" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube channel</a>, the voice actor spoke about booking a “life-changing role on a life-changing project”. She said that she’s spent the last three years working on the project, watching it grow through various stages of development. She also says she “waited and waited” until she could finally talk about it.</p>







<p>Unfortunately, however, that never happened. </p>



<p><strong>“And this week I found out through the internet that the project has been cancelled,”</strong> she said.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-she-found-out-about-the-cancelation">How She Found Out About The Cancelation</h2>



<p>Ayaz revealed that she found out when her brother reached out to ask if everything was ok. Confused, Ayaz replied “Yeah, I’m okay. Why wouldn’t it be okay?” Her brother then sent her a link to an article that reported the project was canceled.</p>



<p><strong>“I was just in total shock,”</strong> she said. <strong>“Just last month or two months ago, I had filmed marketing for this project. Everything had been running smoothly and that was the last that I had heard. And we were all really looking forward to it being released this year.”</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Most Devastating Moment Of My Acting Career" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gY0hv4QFIak?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>While she didn’t directly mention the game, the implication here is that Ayaz is talking about the canceled <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake</a> at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/publishers/ubisoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft</a>. Insider Gaming had previously reported that marketing documents reviewed by staff included plans to being marketing in December with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-release-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release in January</a>. </p>



<p>That clearly didn’t happen, with Insider Gaming’s Tom Henderson then learning that the release had been pushed to, at least, March before it was canceled.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ayaz finding out her project was canceled through the media? Do you think the publisher had an obligation to tell her about the game cancelation beforehand? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For the latest gaming news, read about when you could be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-state-of-play-arriving-in-february-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">seeing the next PlayStation State of Play</a>. And for even more Insider Gaming delivered directly to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/voice-actor-game-cancelation-through-media/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomodachi Life Nintendo Direct Arriving This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tomodachi-life-nintendo-direct-arriving-this-week/</link>
            <guid>1416109</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new Nintendo Direct event has been confirmed for January 29, 2026, and it will focus on Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream. </p>



<p>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream was announced <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-september-2025-everything-announced/">back in the September 2025 Nintendo Direct</a>, with the developers announcing an Autumn 2026 release window. The announcement also came with a 2-minute trailer that briefly discussed the game’s features, systems, and more. It seems that we might receive a release date at the upcoming Nintendo Direct, along with new gameplay. </p>







<h2 id="h-tomodachi-life-nintendo-direct-scheduled-for-january-29">Tomodachi Life Nintendo Direct Scheduled for January 29</h2>



<p>As announced on the official Nintendo of America <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/2015787236264915199" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> post (formerly Twitter), the Tomodachi Life Nintendo Direct will be hosted on January 29 at 6 AM PT. The event will last about 20 minutes and share more details on the upcoming Switch title; a release date will also be announced. Interested readers can tune in to the YouTube livestream or watch it on their smart device through the Nintendo Today application. The YouTube livestream has been embedded below: </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream Direct 1.29.2026" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_0kl1WiSPg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream, players will be in charge of an island where Mii characters live carefree lives. Players will be able to create Mii characters with extensive customisation options, including changing their appearance, personality, voice, and more. Players are also responsible for taking care of them, by seeing what’s on their minds, solving their problems, and watching them interact with others. </p>







<p>In other news, Kensuke Tanabe recently announced that Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will be his <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-will-be-kensuke-tanabes-final-nintendo-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">final game at Nintendo</a>. Additionally, the Super Mario Galaxy trailer has revealed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-mario-galaxy-trailer-reveals-yoshi-and-birdo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Yoshi and Birdo</a>. Will you be tuning in for the Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream Nintendo Direct? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-stick-to-unreal-engine-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 devs finalizing a title and sticking to Unreal Engine 4.</a> Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tomodachi-life-nintendo-direct-arriving-this-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 Will Bring Back the Snowboarding Mini-Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-bring-back-the-snowboarding-mini-game/</link>
            <guid>1416070</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fans can rejoice as their beloved Snowboarding min-game is returning in a more meaningful way in Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3. </p>



<p>We keep learning more and more information on Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 as the days go on. It was recently revealed that the game’s title has been finalized, and they will be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-stick-to-unreal-engine-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sticking with Unreal Engine 4</a> for the upcoming instalment. Now, discussions about the upcoming title’s mini-games have surfaced online. </p>







<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-director-mentions-queen-s-blood-and-snowboarding-mini-games">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 Director Mentions Queen’s Blood and Snowboarding Mini-Games</h2>



<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake series director Naoki Hamaguchi mentioned part 3’s snowboarding and Queen’s Blood mini-games in a new interview with <a href="https://www.polygon.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-queens-blood-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Polygon</a>. Talking about Queen’s Blood, the director reveals that he wants to expand and enhance the min-game, to provide players “a more powered-up version” in Part 3. </p>



<p>Regarding Snowboarding, the director informed players that he can’t reveal too many details about these mini-games, but he knows how much they mean to fans’ hearts. Hamaguchi did confirm that it will not be a simple snowboarding mini-game, instead they will incorporate it into the story “to have that sort of connection with the theming of it.”</p>



<p>Additionally, the director also discussed the development progress of FF7 Remake Part 3. Hamaguchi stated that it is coming along “smoothly” and the team has been “tracking on time” for the milestones they have set for themselves. At this moment, “the game is playable, technically.” However, further polishing is required to bring it to the level where they can release it. </p>







<p>In other news, FF7 Remake series director has stated that he wants <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-should-be-led-by-someone-else-says-ff7-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">someone else to lead</a> the Final Fantasy 6 Remake. Additionally, the developers are considering a “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full title</a>” after Part 3. What are your thoughts on snowboarding returning to the series with Final Fantasy 7 Remake part 3? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-2-0-could-be-real-after-all/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new mention of Starfield 2.0 surfacing online</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-bring-back-the-snowboarding-mini-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>