<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:32:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Devs Are ‘Rolling Out a Fix’ for Bullets Not Registering]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-devs-are-rolling-out-a-fix-for-bullets-not-registering/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-devs-are-%E2%80%98rolling-out-a-fix%E2%80%99-for-bullets-not-registering.1325137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6’s principal game designer has stated that a fix for bullets not registering is on the way. </p>



<p>The developers of Battlefield 6 have done a spectacular job with the game, and the sales reflect that: the game has sold <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-has-reportedly-sold-over-6-5-million-copies-in-first-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than 6.5 million copies</a> within a few days. However, there is still some work to do, as several <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-glitches-exploits-ea-working-overtime/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bugs and glitches</a> continue to plague BF6. Fortunately, the next patch will address the ghost bullets issue in Battlefield 6.</p>



<h2 id="h-battlefield-6-hits-not-registering-will-be-fixed-in-next-patch">Battlefield 6 Hits Not Registering Will be Fixed in Next Patch</h2>



<p>A new post by Battlefield 6’s principal game designer, Florian Le Bihan, on <a href="https://x.com/DRUNKKZ3/status/1978405809814987229" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) discusses ‘rolling out a fix’ for bullets not registering. The developers have observed an issue “where bullets hit an enemy and where blood splatters are visible but don’t cause damage.” Le Bihan explained that this issue was caused “intermittently with certain weapons and attachments combinations and should now be resolved.” </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>We are rolling out a fix to address the issue seen where bullets hit an enemy and where blood splatters are visible but don't cause damage.</p><p>The issue happened intermittently with certain weapons and attachments combinations and should now be resolved. <a href="https://t.co/rf4L04PpLR">https://t.co/rf4L04PpLR</a></p></div>— Florian – DRUNKKZ3 (@DRUNKKZ3) <a href="https://twitter.com/DRUNKKZ3/status/1978405809814987229?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 15, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In a reply to the thread, Le Bihan clarified that some hit registration issues can be caused by poor internet or game server performance; however, players will be informed of this through performance icons at the top left. The principal game designer also confirmed that this Battlefield 6 fix will not address bloom, as that’s “a different issue”. </p>



<p>In other news, Battlefield 6’s campaign tells you to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6s-campaign-tells-you-to-uninstall-when-youre-done/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">uninstall once you have completed it</a>. Additionally, the game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-beats-call-of-dutys-all-time-concurrent-player-count-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">beat Call of Duty’s all-time concurrent player count</a> on Steam with nearly 750k players. What are your thoughts on Battlefield 6 receiving a fix for bullets not registering? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-and-silent-hill-2-are-coming-to-playstation-plus-in-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Until Dawn and Silent Hill 2 coming to PlayStation Plus in October 2025</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-devs-are-rolling-out-a-fix-for-bullets-not-registering/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn and Silent Hill 2 Are Coming to PlayStation Plus in October]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-and-silent-hill-2-are-coming-to-playstation-plus-in-october/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-and-silent-hill-2-are-coming-to-playstation-plus-in-october.1325110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new leak reveals that Until Dawn, Tekken 3, and more will join Silent Hill 2 on PlayStation Plus in October 2025. </p>



<p>With Halloween set to arrive at the end of this month, it seems PlayStation is gearing up to provide players with some of the best horror titles in October through PS Plus. The subscription service has already provided players with Alan Wake 2, a recent leak says <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-remake-coming-to-playstation-plus-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silent Hill 2 is coming this month</a> as well, and now Until Dawn has been added to the mix. </p>



<h2 id="h-playstation-plus-celebrates-halloween-with-silent-hill-2-and-until-dawn">PlayStation Plus Celebrates Halloween with Silent Hill 2 and Until Dawn </h2>



<p>According to a new report by <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/ps-plus-dautres-titres-dont-une-exclu-ps5-viennent-etoffer-le-catalogue-de-jeux-doctobre-2025-60636" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dealabs</a>, Until Dawn is the next big game set to be available to PlayStation Plus players in October 2025. It is the 2024 version of the title, which is developed by Ballistic Moon and released for PlayStation 5 and PC. The other two games that will be joining PS Plus Extra this month are As Dusk Falls, an original interactive drama from studio Interior/Night, and V Rising, an open-world survival game by Stunlock Studios where you play as a vampire. </p>



<p>That’s not all; the report also tells us there are some big additions to PlayStation Plus Premium in October. Tekken 3 and Tomb Raider Anniversary will also be playable this month. Lastly, the report states that the official announcement for these games should arrive today, October 15. </p>



<p>In other news, Cocoon and Goat Simulator 3 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-october-2025-alan-wake-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">were added to PS Plus</a>, along with Alan Wake 2, in October. Additionally, Battlefield 6 players on PlayStation <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-october-2025-alan-wake-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">earn more XP than those on Xbox or PC</a>. What are your thoughts on Until Dawn joining Silent Hill 2 on PlayStation Plus in October? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-has-reportedly-sold-over-6-5-million-copies-in-first-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 reportedly selling over 6.5 million copies in the first week</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-and-silent-hill-2-are-coming-to-playstation-plus-in-october/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League of Legends 2025 World Championship—LoL Worlds Schedule, Teams, and Predictions]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2025-schedule-predictions-teams/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/league-of-legends-2025-world-championship%E2%80%94lol-worlds-schedule-teams-and-predictions.1325071/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The League of Legends 2025 World Championship is upon us, with the Swiss Stage having kicked off on October 15. This stellar tournament will take players from Chengdu to Shanghai to Beijing, representing the most powerful, popular, and valuable esports event in the business.</p>



<p>This guide breaks down everything you need to know about LoL Worlds 2025, whether you’re a casual viewer or a diehard League of Legends enthusiast. It’s a $5 million tournament that features the talents of the most prolific esports pro players in the world, so you <strong>won’t want to miss a second.</strong></p>



<p>Read on to learn everything you need to know.</p>



<h2 id="h-lol-worlds-2025-schedule">LoL Worlds 2025 Schedule</h2>



<p>This year’s League of Legends World Championship tournament is broken down across four stages:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Play-In Stage: </strong>October 14</li>



<li><strong>Swiss Stage</strong>: October 15–25</li>



<li><strong>Knockout Stage</strong>: October 28–November 2</li>



<li><strong>Grand Final</strong>: November 9</li>
</ul>



<p>The tournament’s Grand Final will take place in the Dong’an Lake Sports Park Multifunctional Gymnasium (that’s one heck of a name) in Chengdu, China. It’s one of the biggest venues for an esports tournament to occupy, featuring a whopping 18,000-seat capacity.</p>



<h2 id="h-teams-playing-at-lol-worlds-2025">Teams Playing at LoL Worlds 2025</h2>



<p>There are 17 teams competing at the League of Legends World Championship in 2025. The first team to be eliminated on October 14 was Invictus Gaming, whittling the teams in the Swiss Stage down to 16.</p>



<p>Here’s the full list of teams competing at the League of Legends World Championship in 2025:</p>



<ul>
<li>Gen.G</li>



<li>Hanwha Life</li>



<li>KT Rolster</li>



<li>Bilibili Gaming</li>



<li>Anyone’s Legend</li>



<li>Top Esports</li>



<li>FlyQuest</li>



<li>Keyd Stars</li>



<li>100 Thieves</li>



<li>G2 Esports</li>



<li>KOI</li>



<li>Fnatic</li>



<li>CTBC Flying Oyster</li>



<li>Secret Whales</li>



<li>PSG Talon</li>



<li>T1</li>



<li>Invictus Gaming (<strong>eliminated</strong>)</li>
</ul>







<p>Everyone comes into the League of Legends World Championship with keen eyes on T1 Gaming, the defending champions and the home of Faker, arguably the GOAT of the esports world. Last year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-winner/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Faker made history</a> while flying his traditional T1 banner, and the team has every opportunity to win <strong>yet another </strong>LoL Worlds this time around.</p>



<p>Behind T1 sits Gen.G, the top seed coming out of Korea and heading into LoL Worlds after a <strong>dominant </strong>run through the summer and regional qualifiers. Faker’s nemesis in Chovy is ready to bring it all to the table in China.</p>



<p>For the European League of Legends fans, the pick remains G2 Esports, Europe’s best hope for a League of Legends World Championship trophy.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> who you think will win LoL Worlds 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-watch-lol-worlds-2025">How to Watch LoL Worlds 2025</h2>



<p>The easiest way to watch the League of Legends World Championship 2025 event for free is via the official channels:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@lolesports" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">LoL Esports YouTube</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/riotgames" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Riot Games Twitch</a></li>
</ul>



<p>You’ll also get regional broadcasts (LCK, LPL, LCS, etc) that are localized and translated, plus there will be the regular line-up of content creators, pro players, and streamers broadcasting the League of Legends World Championship via watch parties.</p>



<p>Last year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-hit-50-million-peak-viewers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">50 million peak viewers</a> watched the LoL Worlds Grand Final, will you be one of them this year?</p>



<h2 id="h-top-tips-for-new-lol-worlds-viewers">Top Tips For New LoL Worlds Viewers</h2>



<p>If this is your first League of Legends World Championship event, you’ll want to take these top tips into your viewing experience:</p>



<ul>
<li>Learn the basics and read a wiki or two regarding the Champions, roles, objectives, and strategies in League of Legends</li>



<li>Watch the tournaments with audio and commentary to hear the commentators break down plays and tactics</li>



<li>Follow team and player social channels to get behind-the-scenes content</li>



<li>Play the game as LoL Worlds unfolds and take inspiration from the awesome gameplay!</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>For more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming esports</a> coverage, stay tuned</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2025-schedule-predictions-teams/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Center Cancelling Some Legends: Z-A Pre-Orders]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-center-cancelling-some-legends-z-a-pre-orders/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-center-cancelling-some-legends-z-a-pre-orders.1325032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Some Pokémon fans have been hit with disappointment ahead of the long-awaited launch of Pokémon Legends: Z-A, after their Pokémon Center pre-orders were cancelled.</p>



<p>The title, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-release-date-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launching October 16</a> on the Nintendo Switch family of consoles, features the return to Kalos’ Lumiose City and makes a big change to battle mechanics with a move to real-time combat.</p>



<p>Two days before the big release, however, some fans who pre-ordered through the Pokémon Center have seen their pre-orders cancelled, with the majority reporting that they have received no reason.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Bad news. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>An initial post on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LegendsZA/comments/1o6icr4/pokemon_center_preorder_was_just_canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reddit</a> stated two pre-orders from the Pokémon Center were cancelled without reasoning, even showing the plushie they had been granted as a pre-order bonus.</p>



<p>Many more users then commented that they had seen their pre-orders cancelled, with some reportedly being told the site was unable to reauthorize a payment method, despite a charge having been taken, and others stating they had been informed the product had been oversold.</p>



<p>Adding to the confusion, some of the tracking for the cancelled Pokémon Legends: Z-A pre-orders is said to be showing a status of received, which indicates the pre-order is still in the system.</p>



<p>At this stage, it appears the issues are only with Pokémon Center pre-orders for the game, and the specific reason for the cancellations is unknown. However, with the game due to launch in just a matter of hours, it serves as a major disappointment for those who were hoping to jump in immediately.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Pokémon for comment and we will update this article accordingly if we receive a response.</p>



<hr>



<p>Have you successfully pre-order Pokémon Legends: Z-A? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon Legends: Z-A, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-season-1-ranked-release-date-times-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">schedule for Season 1 of Ranked play</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-pokedex/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s full Pokédex</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-center-cancelling-some-legends-z-a-pre-orders/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Glitches Have Players Flying Around The Map]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-glitches-exploits-ea-working-overtime/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-glitches-have-players-flying-around-the-map.1325020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6 has been in the open for almost a week, and it has been met with a solid response from players worldwide, except for the lacklustre campaign offering. The multiplayer platform is enjoyable, stable, and receiving constant tweaks by the Electronic Arts studios that fed energy into the creation of the first-person shooter.</p>



<p>In recent days, it has seemed as though the studios under the EA banner are working overtime to keep up with the number of movement exploits and glitches that are being uncovered by players, promising to patch them out as they crop up.</p>



<h2 id="h-hammers-ladders-and-drones">Hammers, Ladders, and Drones</h2>



<p>In the last few days, various clips have surfaced on social media of Battlefield 6 glitches that are being manipulated to give players an edge in-game.</p>



<p>One of the easiest to replicate is the ‘ladder glitch’ that allows players to launch themselves off ladders if they’re positioned and approached <strong>in a certain way</strong>. The resulting glitch catapults players at high speeds far across the map, which means users can gain access to an objective behind enemy lines in a matter of seconds.</p>



<p>This is actively being addressed by DICE, but as far as we know, a patch hasn’t been released to address the glitch:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Another entertaining bug that’s giving players a serious advantage is the ‘hammer and drone’ glitch. In clips on social media, we’ve seen players stand on their teammate’s drone and repeatedly slam it with a sledgehammer melee weapon. Each hit propels the drone higher and higher, pushing towards the skybox ad infinitum.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Hammer + Drone = INSANE SNIPES 🤣 #battlefield6" width="422" height="750" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NuFEl31l8Yw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Once at the highest point, players can simply whip out their weapons and start firing shots across the map, confusing everyone trying to spot where the incoming fire is originating from.</p>



<p>Again, this is being addressed by Electronic Arts’ association of studios.</p>



<p>Have you noticed any hilarious glitches in Battlefield 6 that are giving you an advantage? Let me know about them on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-co-creator-gregg-mayles-resigning-rare/">Gregg Mayles has left Rare after 36 years</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-glitches-exploits-ea-working-overtime/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>