<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:45:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Was the Most Downloaded PS5 Game in November 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-was-the-most-downloaded-ps5-game-in-november-2025/</link>
            <guid>1372963</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 has been revealed as the most downloaded PS5 game in the month of November 2025. </p>



<p>Black Ops 7, the latest Call of Duty title released on November 14, 2025, wasn’t able to make the same impact as previous instalments in the franchise. The game suffered the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-suffers-worst-launch-in-20-year-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">worst launch in Japan in its 20-year history</a>, sales were down by 50% in Europe, and it hit a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-metacritic-user-rating/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">series low Metacritic user rating</a>. However, things don’t seem too bad, as it dominated the PS5 store last month. </p>







<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-dominates-ps5-charts-in-november-2025">Black Ops 7 Dominates PS5 Charts in November 2025</h2>



<p>Sony PlayStation is back again with its <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/04/playstation-store-november-2025s-top-downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">monthly charts</a>, revealing the top downloads across PS5, PS4, PS VR2, and free-to-play games in the month of November 2025, and we already know where Black Ops 7 shone. In PS4, Red Dead Redemption 2 was the top dog, PSVR 2 had Alien: Rogue Incursion VR in the lead, and the free-to-play section was split between Where Winds Meet and Battlefield REDSEC. Check out the top 5 most downloaded games across all categories below: </p>



<h3 id="h-ps5">PS5</h3>



<p><strong>US/Canada</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</li>



<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Dispatch </li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>NBA 2K26</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>EU</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</li>



<li>EA Sports FC 26</li>



<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-ps4">PS4</h3>



<p><strong>US/Canada</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Red Dead Redemption 2</li>



<li>Batman: Arkham Knight</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</li>



<li>A Way Out</li>



<li>Grand Theft Auto 5</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>EU</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Red Dead Redemption 2</li>



<li>EA Sports FC 26</li>



<li>A Way Out</li>



<li>Unravel Two</li>



<li>The Forest</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-psvr2">PSVR2</h3>



<p><strong>US/Canada </strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Alien: Rogue Incursion VR</li>



<li>Beat Saber</li>



<li>Arizona Sunshine Remake </li>



<li>Metro Awakening </li>



<li>Job Simulator </li>
</ul>



<p><strong>EU</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Alien: Rogue Incursion VR</li>



<li>Metro Awakening</li>



<li>Horizon Call of the Mountain</li>



<li>Beat Saber</li>



<li>Arizona Sunshine Remake</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-free-to-play-ps5-ps4">Free to Play (PS5 + PS4)</h3>



<p><strong>US/Canada</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Where Winds Meet</li>



<li>Battlefield REDSEC</li>



<li>Fortnite </li>



<li>Roblox</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Warzone</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>EU</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Battlefield REDSEC</li>



<li>Where Winds Meet</li>



<li>Fortnite </li>



<li>Roblox</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Warzone</li>
</ul>







<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/treyarch-pushing-sbmm-in-black-ops-7-due-to-increased-engagement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Treyarch is pushing SBMM</a> in Black Ops 7 due to “increased engagement”. Additionally, here are the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-season-1-patch-notes-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 1 patch notes</a> for the new title. What are your thoughts on Black Ops 7 being the most downloaded PS5 game in November 2025? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-players-can-get-free-500000-through-discord/">GTA Online players getting free $500,000 through Discord</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-was-the-most-downloaded-ps5-game-in-november-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online Players Can Get Free $500,000 Through Discord]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-players-can-get-free-500000-through-discord/</link>
            <guid>1372915</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>GTA Online players can get a free $500,000 bonus in-game, without GTA+; all they need to do is link their Discord account. </p>



<p>Rockstar’s Grand Theft Auto 5 has been out for 12 years now, and the game is still going strong, all thanks to its online multiplayer mode. The game’s popularity remains high enough that it’s up for a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-auto-5-is-up-for-a-goty-award-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game of the Year award in 2025</a>. As Rockstar keeps on bringing new content to the title, players are now eligible to claim some free GTA Online money. </p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-link-discord-and-rockstar-account-to-claim-500-000-in-gta-online">How to Link Discord and Rockstar Account to Claim $500,000 in GTA Online?</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://gamerant.com/gta-online-promotion-discord-free-money-december-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gamerant</a>, GTA Online players can grab free $500,000 by linking their Rockstar and Discord accounts, no GTA+ subscription required. All you need to do is visit the linked accounts section on the Rockstar Games <a href="https://socialclub.rockstargames.com/settings/linkedaccounts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website</a> after signing in to your account. Here, you can link your Discord and Rockstar accounts. Once that is done, players will need to <a href="https://discord.com/invite/rockstargames" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">join</a> the Rockstar Games Discord and claim the reward from the designated channel. The reward can then be redeemed when playing GTA Online next. </p>



<p>Before GTA+ came about, Rockstar would provide $500,000 each month for GTA Online through PlayStation Plus, and all you needed to do was go and claim the reward. Since the arrival of GTA+, that bonus is only reserved for subscribed members. Moreover, being a member of Rockstar’s subscription service also provides GTA Online to players for free, so you don’t even need to buy the base game. </p>







<p>In other news, GTA Online <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-fivem-mods-can-now-be-converted-for-enhanced-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FiveM modes can be converted</a> for the Enhanced Edition through a new tool. Additionally, a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-video-in-development-grand-theft-auto-rockstar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">short in-development video</a> of GTA 6 recently surfaced online. Will you be claiming the free $500,000 in GTA Online by linking your Discord account? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-tomb-raider-set-to-reinvent-the-franchise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amazon’s Tomb Raider, reinventing the franchise</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-players-can-get-free-500000-through-discord/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PIONER Open Beta Launches Again as New Trailer Drops]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pioner-open-beta-launches-again-new-trailer/</link>
            <guid>1372912</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PIONER, an upcoming post-apocalyptic MMO, is back in open beta until December 9, giving GFA Games the chance to optimize it before the game’s ultimate release (in early access) on December 16. This new open beta phase coincides with the release of an all-new trailer showcasing the game’s setting, the ruined island of Tartarus.</p>



<p>PIONER comes from GFA Games, a Serbian studio, and it promises intense, end-of-the-world action in a Soviet-era setting that’s deeply reminiscent of games like STALKER and Fallout.</p>



<h2 id="h-pioner-launching-december-16-but-you-can-play-it-now">PIONER Launching December 16, But You Can Play It Now</h2>



<p>GFA Games’ PIONER is set to drop in just a couple of weeks, but if you want to play it now (exclusively on Steam), then you can simply install the open beta and give it a try.</p>



<p>PIONER is a little rough around the edges, but it’s launching in early access, so that can mostly be excused. It’s a very ambitious title that boasts an MMO, live-service operating model, a branching campaign, a PvPvE ecosystem, and sumptuous visuals.</p>



<p>The newest trailer offers a great look at the environments players will need to contend with when the game comes out on December 16:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="PIONER - Mist" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G2nUqz-p1_4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Fans of STALKER will notice the similarities between the two games. In PIONER, which was developed by some former STALKER devs, players must contend with anomalies that are made detectable by a scanner, and to defeat them, they can throw pieces of scrap metal into them to trigger them.</p>



<p>Sound familiar?</p>



<p>It’s a bit of a copy and paste, but there’s enough meat on the bones of PIONER for it to feel unique, and the game’s combat, customization, and freedom mechanics are all top-notch.</p>



<p>Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’re looking forward to PIONER being released.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bad-robot-games-sony-four-player-shooter-left-4-dead/">Bad Robot Games is making a new four-player shooter</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pioner-open-beta-launches-again-new-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s Tomb Raider Set to “Reinvent the Franchise”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-tomb-raider-set-to-reinvent-the-franchise/</link>
            <guid>1372909</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Amazon’s Tomb Raider series will apparently reinvent the franchise, interconnecting the live-action series and video games into a unified storytelling universe. </p>



<p>Quite a few details about Amazon’s live-action Tomb Raider series emerged earlier this year, with the biggest of them being <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prime-video-tomb-raider-sophie-turner-lara-croft-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sophie Turner</a> taking on the role of the highly popular character, Lara Croft. Moreover, we were also informed that shooting for this show will begin in January 2026. The latest development reveals how Amazon is treating this live-action series. </p>







<h2 id="h-tomb-raider-series-will-interconnect-the-live-action-show-and-video-games">Tomb Raider Series Will Interconnect the Live-Action Show and Video Games</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-live-action-tomb-raider-adaptation-will-reinvent-the-franchise-and-interconnect-with-the-games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Story Kitchen’s <a href="https://www.story-kitchen.com/projects/tombraider" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">website</a> has been updated to provide new details about Amazon’s Tomb Raider series. The updated listing reveals that the new deal between Story Kitchen, Crystal Dynamics, and Amazon MGM Studios will “reinvent the franchise on a massive scale.” Moreover, the Tomb Raider show will interconnect the “live-action television series and video games into a unified storytelling universe.”</p>



<p>The Amazon Tomb Raider series is being led by Phoebe Waller-Bridge, an Emmy winner, known for their work on Fleabag. They will be “spearheading the next chapter of Tomb Raider, launching an ambitious reimagining of the Lara Croft universe. Moreover, Shogun’s Jonathan Van Tulleken will be a director and executive producer on the project. Lastly, Chad Hodge will serve as an executive producer and co-showrunner on the series. </p>







<p>In other news, Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-definitive-edition-shadow-dropped-for-switch-and-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shadow-dropped for Switch and Switch 2</a> last month. Additionally, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-legend-lara-croft-final-season-december/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">final season</a> of Tomb Raider: The Legend of Lara Croft will release this month. What are your thoughts on Amazon’s Tomb Raider reinventing the franchise? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bad-robot-games-sony-four-player-shooter-left-4-dead/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bad Robot Games joining Sony for a new four-player shooter from Left 4 Dead creator</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-tomb-raider-set-to-reinvent-the-franchise/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad Robot Games Joins With Sony For New Four-Player Shooter From Left 4 Dead Creator]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bad-robot-games-sony-four-player-shooter-left-4-dead/</link>
            <guid>1372864</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Sony Interactive Entertainment has revealed the imminent arrival of a new four-player, cooperative shooter from Bad Robot Games, the gaming division of JJ Abrams’ Bad Robot. The title is being directed by Mike Booth, best known for leading the charge on Left 4 Dead, one of the best games in the genre and a cult classic.</p>



<p>The game was revealed as being in development for PlayStation 5 and PC, and while details are scarce at present, more will be revealed soon.</p>







<h2 id="h-mike-booth-is-back-in-the-studio-and-cooking">Mike Booth is Back in the Studio and Cooking</h2>



<p>In September, we covered the news that Mike Booth, the creator and designer of Left 4 Dead, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/left-4-dead-coded-shooter-coming-from-game-creator/">was developing a new shooter</a> ‘built on the foundations of what made L4D special.’</p>



<p>Fast forward to today, and Sony Interactive Entertainment has revealed a partnership with Bad Robot Games that will serve as the creative pathway for that game to come to life.</p>



<p>On Reddit, Booth wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I’m Mike Booth (creator of Left 4 Dead), and I’m excited to share that I’m working on a brand new project —a 4-player co-op shooter built on the foundations of what made L4D special.</p>



<p>If you enjoyed the teamwork, tension, and replayability of my past games, you’ll probably find this one interesting. It expands on the co-op formula in ways I’ve wanted to explore for a long time.</p>



<p>We’re still in the early stages of development, but we’re opening up playtests to a limited number of players. If you’re interested in joining us on this next adventure and helping shape the game early on, we’d love to have you involved.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In a <a href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/press-releases/2025/sie-partners-with-bad-robot-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">new press release</a> on the Sony Interactive site, it was explained by Anna Sweet, CEO of Bad Robot Games:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Partnering with Sony Interactive Entertainment allows us to bring our new IP to life, with an expansive vision for this new universe.</p>



<p>With the support of PlayStation, we hope to deliver a bold, innovative experience that is truly special for players. I could not be more excited that Mike Booth is at the creative helm, crafting a cooperative adventure that will lead to unforgettable moments with friends.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Left 4 Dead and Left 4 Dead 2 remain two of the most beloved zombie shooters ever released. They’re still popular today and are being kept alive by an extensive modding community that never ceases to innovate and optimise the game.</p>







<p>Are you excited to see what Mike Booth and Bad Robot Games can produce in the four-player shooter space? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/russia-blocks-access-to-roblox-because-of-extremist-materials/">Russia has blocked access to Roblox</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/bad-robot-games-sony-four-player-shooter-left-4-dead/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Banjo-Kazooie: Mumbomania Is A New PlayStation-Only Game Playable In Dreams]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-mumbomania-is-a-playstation-only-game-playable-in-dreams/</link>
            <guid>1372861</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Moon Studios’ William Butkevicius has used their free time productively to create a whole new Banjo-Kazooie game for PlayStation owners on PS4 and PS5. It comes with a couple of minor caveats: It’s not an official Banjo-Kazooie game, and you need to own a copy of Dreams.</p>



<p>It boggles the mind that there hasn’t been a new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-co-creator-gregg-mayles-resigning-rare/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Banjo-Kazooie</a> game in nearly 20 years. 2008’s Nuts &amp; Bolts remains the final BK game to see the light of day, and if you’ve got a hankering for a new release, a talented developer might have you jumping around the room.</p>







<h2 id="h-a-new-banjo-kazooie-game-on-playstation-sort-of">A New Banjo-Kazooie Game On PlayStation, Sort Of</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It looks like the real thing. Credit to Eupholace</figcaption></figure>



<p>William Butkevicius is a level designer at Moon Studios. They’ve been working on No Rest for the Wicked, but their spare time has involved a lot of ‘Dreams,’ it seems.</p>







<p>The PlayStation-exclusive title is considered one of the most sophisticated content generation games in the world, and the freedom and control you have to create your own levels and games in Dreams is nearly endless.</p>



<p>Butkevicius posted to X on December 3 with a fun message: “Banjo-Kazooie: Mumbomania is out NOW on Dreams for PS4/PS5!”</p>



<p>If you need convincing, there’s even a 1-minute and 43-second trailer showing off the game. It does indeed look like a deep Banjo-Kazooie game, and it looks terrific by every metric!</p>



<p>The way Banjo looks, the movement and mechanics, all the way down to the music—performed by <a href="https://x.com/thegamebrass" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">@thegamebrass</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Again, this is only for PlayStation owners, and you need to have a working copy of Dreams to play it. If you meet this criteria, this might be the closest you’ll ever get to a new Banjo-Kazooie title.</p>



<p>Is it about time the series makes a triumphant comeback? Would it be amazing to see Rare back at the helm? Share all your thoughts through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>IG has many more news stories to check out: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/russia-blocks-access-to-roblox-because-of-extremist-materials/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Russia Blocks Access To Roblox Because of ‘Extremist Materials’</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/treyarch-pushing-sbmm-in-black-ops-7-due-to-increased-engagement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Treyarch Pushing SBMM In Black Ops 7 Due To “Increased Engagement”</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-locks-basic-feature-behind-30-amiibo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Locking A Basic Feature Behind $30 Amiibo</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-mumbomania-is-a-playstation-only-game-playable-in-dreams/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia Blocks Access To Roblox Because of ‘Extremist Materials’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/russia-blocks-access-to-roblox-because-of-extremist-materials/</link>
            <guid>1372858</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Roblox is now banned in Russia as it has been accused of distributing extremist materials and “LGBT propaganda”. </p>



<p>The popular gaming platform, Roblox, has been in the news recently for its age-estimation features, with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-age-estimation-feature-users-concerned/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some users concerned</a> about the requirement for children to upload photos of themselves to its AI tool. Now, Roblox is in the news again, for being banned in a country, accused of distributing extremist materials. </p>







<h2 id="h-roblox-negatively-impacts-the-spiritual-and-moral-development-of-children">Roblox Negatively Impacts the “Spiritual and Moral Development of Children”</h2>



<p>According to a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/russia-blocks-access-us-childrens-gaming-platform-roblox-2025-12-03/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reuters</a> report (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-banned-russia-lgbtq-propaganda-child-safety-measures" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>), access to Roblox has been blocked in Russia, with the country’s communications watchdog, Roskomnadzor, stating that the platform was “rife with inappropriate content that can negatively impact the spiritual and moral development of children.” Russia is not the only country to block access to Roblox; Turkey also banned the title earlier last year over <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-gets-banned-in-turkey-over-concerns-of-child-exploitation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concerns of child exploitation</a>. </p>



<p>A Roblox spokesperson’s response is also included in the report. The spokesperson states that they “respect the local laws and regulations in countries” where Roblox operates, and they believe the platform provides “a positive space for learning, creation, and meaningful connection for everyone.” They added that the platform has “a deep commitment to safety, and we have a robust set of proactive and preventative safety measures designed to catch and prevent harmful content on our platform.”</p>







<p>In other news, there was a ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-roblox-shutting-down-roblox-ban-2025-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hoax campaign</a>‘ on social media and content platforms earlier this year claiming that Roblox would shut down in 2025. What are your thoughts on Roblox being banned in Russia and being accused of distributing extremist materials? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-high-on-life-2-campaign-gameplay-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first campaign gameplay for High on Life 2.</a> Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/russia-blocks-access-to-roblox-because-of-extremist-materials/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>