<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:58:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: New Horizons Getting Free Update And Nintendo Switch 2 Edition]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-free-update-nintendo-switch-2-edition/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/animal-crossing-new-horizons-getting-free-update-and-nintendo-switch-2-edition.1339207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s time to revisit the island. Nintendo has announced that Animal Crossing: New Horizons is the latest first-party game from the company to get a Nintendo Switch 2 Edition for players on the new system. In addition to the Switch 2 Edition, it was also revealed that a free content update is coming for all players.</p>



<p>Releasing on January 15, 2026, the Switch 2 Edition will be available for $64.99. If you already own the game, you can upgrade for just $4.99.</p>



<p>Included in the Switch 2 Edition of Animal Crossing: New Horizons are 4K visuals in TV mode, mouse controls with the right Joy-Con 2, an in-game megaphone that allows you to call for residents on the island, 12-player online sessions for other Switch 2 Edition players, and CameraPlay to see your friends as you play online. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Animal Crossing: New Horizons | Nintendo Switch 2 Edition &amp; Free Update | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_JuSQT3kvSY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-a-free-update-is-coming-for-everyone">A Free Update Is Coming For Everyone</h2>



<p>As mentioned, there’s also a free update for all Animal Crossing: New Horizons players launching on the same day. The update, the game’s first major update since November 2021, includes a new resort hotel, a new reset feature, a multiplayer island, and more. You can check out the new additions for players below, courtesy of Nintendo.</p>



<h3 id="h-animal-crossing-new-horizons-update-details"><strong>Animal Crossing: New Horizons Update Details:</strong></h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Resort Hotel’s Grand Opening:</strong>&nbsp;A resort hotel is opening on the pier, and it’s run by Kapp’n’s family. To bring in guests from off the island, you’ll help out by decorating guest rooms and more. Plus, find new furniture and clothing at the souvenir shop and dress up mannequins with outfits that guests can wear.</li>



<li><strong>Making Island Life More Convenient</strong>: Want a fresh start? Resetti is on hand with a convenient Reset Service to help tidy up your island. Additionally, you can now upgrade your home storage to hold up to 9,000 items, and store trees, shrubs and flowers there, too.</li>



<li><strong>Slumber Island:&nbsp;</strong>Players with a&nbsp;<a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fus%2Fonline%2F&amp;esheet=54348006&amp;newsitemid=20251030590749&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=Nintendo+Switch+Online&amp;index=6&amp;md5=c0218baab6aaf58593b6a14f136216fa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch Online</a>&nbsp;membershipcan design and save up to three islands and play with friends online. Select the size and layout of the island, build and design it collaboratively, access your inventory and decorate, plus invite residents from your home island.</li>



<li><strong>Collaborations</strong>: Collect Nintendo items like the Ultra Hand and Nintendo consoles in-game to add some classic flair to your island. Nintendo Switch Online members can play select classic Nintendo titles in-game when interacting with specific Nintendo console items, too! LEGO<sup>®</sup>&nbsp;items will also make their debut with this update. And use select The Legend of Zeldaand Splatoonseries amiibo<sup>8</sup>&nbsp;to invite certain characters — and unlock various items inspired by those series.</li>
</ul>



<p>What do you think of the updates—both free and paid—coming to Animal Crossing: New Horizons? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ai-cant-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says/">had to say about AI and the future of Grand Theft Auto</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-free-update-nintendo-switch-2-edition/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>