<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:45:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent Agrees to Pause Light of Motiram Promotion While Horizon Clone Lawsuit Continues]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-agrees-to-pause-light-of-motiram-promotion-while-horizon-clone-lawsuit-continues/</link>
            <guid>1370842</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Tencent and Sony have agreed to a later hearing date for the Horizon clone lawsuit if Light of Motiram pauses its promotion and public testing. </p>



<p>Sony has been fighting Tencent in court for allegedly ripping off elements from PlayStation’s Horizon series for their upcoming title, Light of Motiram. Tencent has filed a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-claps-back-at-sony-playstations-horizon-clone-lawsuit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">motion to dismiss</a> this case, whereas Sony has filed for an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-files-injunction-to-bar-tencent-from-using-any-resemblance-to-horizons-aloy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">injunction</a>. Both entities have now agreed on delaying these hearings, however, with some conditions. </p>











<p>According to a new order filed yesterday by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/tencent-promote-light-of-motiram-run-public-tests-sony-horizon-lawsuit-2026-hearing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>, there are some new developments in Sony and Tencent’s Horizon clone lawsuit. It seems that both entities have &nbsp;“engaged in discussions in order to resolve the current dispute.” These discussions have led to Sony Interactive Entertainment and Tencent Entities agreeing to extend the briefing schedule and to a later requested hearing date; however, these come with some conditions. </p>



<p>Sony and Tencent have agreed on four conditions to extend the hearing: </p>



<ul>
<li>Firstly, the extension “will not be used to argue that SIE delayed in seeking a preliminary injunction.” </li>



<li>Secondly, there can be “no new promotion or public testing of Light of Motiram during the pendency of the Motion for Preliminary Injunction.” </li>



<li>Thirdly, the release date of Light of Motiram cannot be “moved up to before Q4 2027.”</li>



<li>Lastly, Tencent Entities “will not seek expedited discovery in connection with the Motion for Preliminary Injunction.”</li>
</ul>







<p>Due to the new extension, Tencent’s deadline to file its response to Sony’s preliminary injunction is now December 17, 2025, instead of December 3. Sony must file its Reply in Support by January 2, 2026. Both entities will also request that Judge Jacqueline Corley hear the injunction and the motion to dismiss simultaneously on January 29, 2026, rather than on January 15. </p>



<p>In other news, Tencent’s last response to the lawsuit was “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-responds-to-sony-horizon-clone-lawsuit-fame-does-not-create-a-trademark/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fame does not create a trademark</a>.” What are your thoughts on Tencent pausing Light of Motiram’s promotion? For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-pc-file-size-reduced-by-85-slim-version-now-available-in-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Helldivers 2’s file size being reduced by 85%</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-agrees-to-pause-light-of-motiram-promotion-while-horizon-clone-lawsuit-continues/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>