<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:09:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS6 Won’t Use Full RDNA 5 GPU Architecture, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-wont-use-full-rdna-5-gpu-architecture-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1436731</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New information concerning the internal hardware expectations of the next Sony PlayStation has surfaced.</p>



<p>Do not expect the next Sony PlayStation console to use only AMD’s upcoming RDNA 5 GPU. During a recent discussion on the <a href="https://www.neogaf.com/threads/mlid-xbox-magnus-rdna-5-finalized.1693408/page-9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NeoGAF forum</a>, reliable tech leaker KeplerL2 noted that the PS5’s internals are a hybrid of RDNA1 and ray tracing, and that the “PS6 isn’t full RDNA 5 either.”</p>







<h2 id="h-further-hardware-expectations-for-the-next-gen-sony-ps6">Further Hardware Expectations for the Next-Gen Sony PS6</h2>



<p>In another recent post, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-specs-playstation-handheld-impressive-memory/">Kepler claimed</a> that the PlayStation 6 could have up to 30 GB of GDDR7 memory. The often-discussed next-gen Sony handheld could also feature up to 24 GB of LPDDR5X memory. If that is the case, it would be on par with the recently released ROG Xbox Ally X.</p>



<p>The rumored handheld is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-handheld-console-will-be-dockable-its-claimed/">expected to be dockable. </a>It’s also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-portable-can-definitely-run-ps5-games-leaker-clarifies/">expected to run PS5 titles</a>. Still, it’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/portable-ps6-wont-be-as-powerful-as-ps5-its-claimed/">not expected to be as powerful</a> as the current PlayStation 5 console.</p>



<p>However, don’t expect to see the next set of PlayStation consoles on the market <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-to-release-in-2027-its-claimed/">until at least 2027.</a></p>







<p>Speaking of next-generation hardware expectations, AMD recently said that it was preparing to support a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amd-says-next-xbox-console-may-launch-next-year/" id="173908">2027 launch for the next Xbox console.</a> However, Microsoft has since said it is not committing to a hard launch date for its next hardware lineup. Learn more about that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-not-committed-to-hard-2027-launch-for-next-xbox-its-claimed/" id="175153">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>What are you looking for from the next generation of consoles? Would you prefer a return to dedicated handhelds with their own separate lineup of games, or do you prefer hybrid consoles like the Nintendo Switch? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-wont-use-full-rdna-5-gpu-architecture-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Year 11 Roadmap Revealed—Everything You Need to Know]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-year-11-roadmap-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1436707</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ubisoft has unveiled the full Rainbow Six Year 11 roadmap during the Six Invitational in Paris. On one of the grandest stages in the esports landscape, Ubisoft uncovered the next year of Rainbow Six Siege content, and things are looking great.</p>



<p>The breakdown started with a new trailer that revealed the death of Phobos. From there, the team talked about Ranked 3.0, balancing changes that will update how players enjoy the game (looking first at entry and roaming, and the new cadence with seasonal updates.</p>



<p>Check out everything you need to know below.</p>







<h2 id="h-rainbow-six-siege-year-11-roadmap-is-more-siege-more-often">Rainbow Six Siege Year 11 Roadmap is ‘More Siege, More Often’</h2>



<p>The running theme of Rainbow Six Siege’s Year 11 roadmap is, according to Ubisoft, ‘more Siege, more often’.</p>



<p>That all begins with a hefty array of new seasons coming to the game over the next 12 months. For some reason, the team started by detailing <strong>season four</strong>, dropping at the end of the year.</p>



<p>This update will be all about <strong>teamplay</strong>, and to accommodate better collaboration, a new <strong>social hub </strong>will be implemented. A new ‘testing grounds’ playlist will also drop in season four, with Ubisoft monitoring feedback and seeing what needs to change before Year 12 kicks off.</p>



<p>Towards the end of Year 11, a new strategic option is coming to the test area in the form of <strong>half reinforcements</strong>:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>In Y11S4, the Hostage mechanic is also going to get a major rework. Additionally, The Grand Larceny, a limited-time event not seen for almost <strong>six years</strong>, is coming back.</p>



<p>Players will be able to prove their expertise with specific Operators in Y11S4, too, leaning on Operator Mastery tiers. As the team said, this gives your time with these characters ‘more meaning’.</p>



<p>Y11S3, which will drop <strong>before season four</strong> (obviously), introduces a new Defender with a brilliant counter for shield users, codename: <strong>Firework</strong>. The small teaser we got for the unnamed character revealed a gadget that can punch clean through shields.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In Y11S2, the in-game esports tab is getting a huge update, allowing fans of the competitive scene to better connect with and follow their favourite competitors.</p>



<p>This season will also welcome a new Rainbow Six Siege map, pulled straight from Rainbow Six Vegas – <strong>Calypso Casino</strong>. It’s a ‘tribute to the amazing Vegas games from Rainbow’s past,’ said Alex Kaparzis, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-creative-director-stepping-down/" id="173856">former Creative Director of the game</a>.</p>



<p>Y11S2 will also yield a remaster for Dokkaebi, giving her a ‘more personal and targeted approach’ as well as a new primary weapon to broaden her arsenal. It was stressed that the weapon won’t be locked behind a battle pass but will be available to all users when it drops.</p>



<p>But what about what comes in the first season of Year 11?</p>



<h2 id="h-year-11-season-1-welcomes-a-recognisable-face">Year 11 Season 1 Welcomes a Recognisable Face</h2>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/solid-snake-rainbow-six-siege-revealed/">Y11S1 welcomes Solid Snake</a>, the protagonist of the <strong>older </strong>Metal Gear Solid games. He’ll be joining Zero as a new Operator, and he’s coming on board with a standalone story to set him up nicely in the universe.</p>



<p>The first season of Year 11 is themed almost entirely around Metal Gear. There’s a new event named [REDACTED] that brings MGS-themed skins and a limited-time 4v4 mode, a string of cosmetics coming in the battle pass, and, of course, Solid Snake himself.</p>



<p>He’s coming in as a one-health, three-speed Operator with unique voice lines, a new gadget, and a sweet loadout.</p>



<p>The first season, Operation Silent Hunt, launches on March 3rd. It’s set to welcome modernized maps, a 1v1 arcade mode, and a huge balancing overhaul, amongst other things.</p>



<p>For your information and perusal, here’s the full Rainbow Six Siege Year 11 roadmap:</p>



<figure></figure>











<p>What are you most excited about from the Rainbow Six Year 11 roadmap? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-the-new-west-reveal-trailer-published/">new trailer for Fallout: The New West</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-year-11-roadmap-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solid Snake Unveiled for Rainbow Six Siege, Coming in Y11S1 ‘Operation Silent Hunt’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/solid-snake-rainbow-six-siege-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1436701</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ubisoft has revealed that Solid Snake is coming to Rainbow Six Siege in Y11S1, a season dubbed ‘Operation Silent Hunt’. He’s coming into the game as a <strong>permanent Operator </strong>and has unique, new voice lines recorded by the iconic David Hayter. He’s coming to the Rainbow Six world with unique gadgets, weapons, and an immense aura.</p>



<p>During the Six Invitational in Paris, France, Ubisoft debuted a short trailer that saw Solid Snake welcomed to the franchise by none other than Sam Fisher. The team went on to reveal that Konami has provided iconic sounds from the Metal Gear series for his arrival in Rainbow Six.</p>







<h2 id="h-solid-snake-is-rainbow-six-siege-s-new-operator">Solid Snake is Rainbow Six Siege’s New Operator</h2>



<p>The short trailer that was revealed to unveil Solid Snake went down like a storm at the Six Invitational in Paris. Towards the end of January, it was revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-rainbow-six-siege/">Solid Snake would be coming</a> to the game as a new Operator by dataminers, which prompted many to fully expect a full reveal at the Six Invitational.</p>



<p>And here it is:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Solid Snake will be a one-health, three-speed Operator, which means he can’t take a hell of a lot of damage, but he’s fast, which is what you’d expect from one of the stealthiest heroes from the gaming world.</p>



<p>His loadout is already iconic and features the F2 assault rifle, the PMR90A2 battle rifle, and the TACIT .45, a powerful and suppressed handgun. His OSP Pouch gadget provides a unique radar and early warning system, which is where the sounds iconic from the Metal Gear series come from.</p>



<p>To welcome Solid Snake to the game, a new event has been set up for Y11S1, now one of the most highly anticipated seasons in recent years. It’s called [REDACTED], and it sees some of the most recognizable characters from the Metal Gear franchise surface as skins in an exclusive 4v4 mode.</p>



<p>And of course, a stack of battle pass cosmetics is coming too:</p>



<figure></figure>











<p>Are you eager to assume control of Solid Snake in Rainbow Six Siege? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bishop-rainbow-six-returning-year-11-siege/">Bishop is coming back to Rainbow Six this year</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/solid-snake-rainbow-six-siege-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bishop is Returning to Rainbow Six with Year 11 of Siege]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bishop-rainbow-six-returning-year-11-siege/</link>
            <guid>1436680</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>During the unveiling of the Rainbow Six Year 11 roadmap at the Six Invitational in Paris, Ubisoft’s game leadership team revealed what’s coming next for the game.</p>



<p>In one of the most exciting revelations, fans learned that Bishop is making a return to the Rainbow Six universe. This is a fan-favourite character who hasn’t been seen in the series since Rainbow Six Vegas 2 was released in 2008. As he said in the teaser that unveiled his return, ‘Things must be bad if you’re calling me.’</p>







<h2 id="h-bishop-s-rainbow-return-is-imminent">Bishop’s Rainbow Return is Imminent</h2>



<p>In 2008, Bishop was last seen in Rainbow Six Vegas 2, serving the all-important role as protagonist. While Bishop could have been either male or female <strong>back then</strong>, Ubisoft has confirmed that the character’s return will be solely focused on the male variant.</p>



<p>When the events of Rainbow Six Vegas 2 had wrapped up, Bishop was sent to be the Deputy Director of Rainbow, but then the character faded out of the universe.</p>



<p>This year, Bishop is coming back, resurfacing after almost twenty years away from the franchise. Rainbow Six Vegas 2 is often considered one of the gems of the franchise, having launched way back in 2008.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Bishop has changed a little since 2008, that’s for sure.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Over the years, fans of the series have wondered <strong>why </strong>Ubisoft doesn’t bring back Bishop as an Operator or some kind of starring character, and now those questions have been answered.</p>







<p>Are you excited to see Bishop returning to Rainbow Six with Year 11 of Siege? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-the-new-west-reveal-trailer-published/">Fallout: The New West has received a reveal trailer</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/bishop-rainbow-six-returning-year-11-siege/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#981)—Answers for Monday, February 16]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-16-981/</link>
            <guid>1436659</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s time for a whole new week, and that means seven fresh NYT Connections challenges are waiting to be dominated. Hopefully, you can start as you mean to go on with a big win from today’s NYT Connections puzzle. That’s why I’m here, actually! I’m here to bring you the best NYT Connections hints and solutions for this challenge.</p>



<p>If you want the fastest and clearest tips for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, just read on.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-play-nyt-connections">How to Play NYT Connections</h2>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words can have double meanings, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty, from least to most.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-february-16">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (February 16)</h2>



<p>Here are the words from today’s NYT Connections puzzle:</p>



<ul>
<li>BUCK</li>



<li>SCREAM</li>



<li>DO</li>



<li>LAUGH</li>



<li>FAWN</li>



<li>DOE</li>



<li>FLIGHT</li>



<li>SQUAWK</li>



<li>HOOT</li>



<li>FIGHT</li>



<li>RIOT</li>



<li>DOUGH</li>



<li>FREEZE</li>



<li>CACKLE</li>



<li>DOH</li>



<li>CLUCK</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– Ways to describe something hilarious</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – Sounds the same but spelled differently</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> –<em> </em>What noises a chicken might make</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – How you respond to stress</li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, February 16:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-february-16-981">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, February 16 (#981)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– HOOT, LAUGH, RIOT, SCREAM</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – DO, DOE, DOH, DOUGH</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BUCK, CACKLE, CLUCK, SQUAWK</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – FAWN, FIGHT, FLIGHT, FREEZE</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-16-981/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Strands #714 Hints and Answers for February 15, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-714-hints-and-answers-for-february-15-2026/</link>
            <guid>1436635</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/strands/" id="3586">Strands </a>is a daily word search puzzle game from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/new-york-times/" id="2981">The New York Times</a>. It is a relatively new game, launched in 2024, in which players seek a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid.</p>



<p>Whether it’s your first time playing or you’re a Strands veteran, today’s tips and strategies can help you find words faster. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Strands, don’t worry, below you’ll find some&nbsp;<strong>helpful hints and even the answers for Strands Game #714</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for Sunday, February 15, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-672014a9-ce75-4ea0-b98d-12b9214dbb53">To play today’s Strands,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/strands" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">head to the game’s website.</a></p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of Strands. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure id="block-5f20defe-2f05-4eb9-b880-6af2f94b324d"></figure>







<h2 id="block-e2995432-719e-4ed6-8fad-a1db37670203">How To Play Strands</h2>



<p id="block-da980997-0420-4527-946e-b66c49bf3d07">Strands is a daily word search that challenges you to find words with a common theme. There’s also a Spanagram that reveals the deeper theme behind the words.</p>



<ul id="block-d0bea02d-4b9f-4991-b9db-3b35778ff3bf">
<li>Words that are three letters and under do not count.</li>



<li>Words that reveal the correct theme appear in blue.</li>



<li>The Spanagram turns yellow when found.</li>



<li>Finding three words that don’t fit the theme will reveal a hint to help you find the proper words.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-5e597b53-af1c-4c06-a00c-6c5a4694e9e0">The goal is to string together as many words as possible. Every letter on the grid gets used! Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p id="block-cd7aaa7f-9491-4ad0-b994-72d0102c5bed">Strands can only be played on the New York Times website. You can also play on the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/crosswords/apps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NYT Games app.</a></p>



<h2 id="block-c6d4979d-f8eb-4473-a011-33019cb8da2c">Strands Hints For Today, February 15, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-23b6a5a9-2c25-47c2-a0ea-e23a99c87abd">The Strands’ answers for Game #714 are all aboutenlightenment. When you realize the theme is, “Now I get it!” You’ll have a good idea of what words to look for immediately. I was fortunate enough that I didn’t need any in-game hints. But if you need some hints,, just keep reading.</p>



<h3 id="block-6777813b-1426-4c21-b507-3024542b4683">General Strands Hints For February 15</h3>



<p id="block-b36e160d-6e5e-4dc8-aae9-5352ee681266">Without giving today’s Strands answers completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul id="block-5c9f7d28-537c-424b-92c3-2a9906b57178">
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;Get out of the dark.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong>&nbsp;You are Patrick Star, telling Squidward how to hold an item.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;When something finally clicks for you, you can say that you fully [this].</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-7fb794eb-0d89-4f8d-a7cf-082d0148b796">Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving&nbsp;<strong>Strands #714</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for February 15, 2026.</strong></p>







<h3 id="block-73a1d2f5-fc2b-49b7-9c10-539e38a2b946">Words to Help You Find Strand Hints for February 15, 2026</h3>



<p id="block-0853e28e-417e-4720-9526-9f2808a268be">If you want help getting started without having today’s Strands answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you unlock some in-game hints. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul id="block-2ca8fb79-d1a4-43e4-8764-e4d238a3cc97">
<li>HOME</li>



<li>SEETHE</li>



<li>FLIGHT</li>



<li>FIGHT</li>



<li>PLIGHT</li>



<li>LIGHT</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-strands-answer-for-game-714-on-february-15-2026">Today’s Strands Answer For Game #714 On February 15, 2026</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p id="block-4ee7c8b7-21fe-4613-8d40-bdf10f8881d0">If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answers to today’s Strands below. Check out yesterday’s answers <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-713-hints-and-answers-for-february-14-2026/" id="176679">here</a>.</p>



<ul>
<li>GRASP</li>



<li>REALIZE</li>



<li>UNDERSTAND</li>



<li>FATHOM</li>



<li>APPREHEND</li>



<li><strong>SPANAGRAM</strong>: SEETHELIGHT</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-0e0094cc-40a6-49a3-a98c-ee90172006ac">If you solved today’s Strands without our answers, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="block-44882c9d-d6a6-4e4f-9b1a-8312ae0b3036">When Is The Next Strands Game After #714?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6">All New York Times games are&nbsp;<strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before, giving players a heads-up. The game on&nbsp;<strong>February 16</strong>&nbsp;will be&nbsp;<strong>Strands Game #715.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-96ac6df0-5b63-4788-9eff-98ceece739ee">What Is Strands?</h2>



<p id="block-cde2c274-bfd9-4d27-a0d9-3ebe6f1ff7f2">Strands is a daily word search puzzle game created by The New York Times. Launched in 2024, Strands challenges players to discover a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid. The game’s original concept was developed by Juliette Seive, a research director on The New York Times Games team, with the aim of replicating Wordle’s success. Tracy Bennett serves as the puzzle editor for Strands, overseeing the creation and curation of daily puzzles since its launch.</p>



<hr>



<p id="block-9d1c4fad-eba9-422a-a628-5cb7b00aea3b">For even more Insider Gaming delivered straight to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-714-hints-and-answers-for-february-15-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>