<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:19:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Union Workers At Bethesda Have Gone On Strike]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike.1034676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Union employees at Bethesda have gone on strike across multiple locations in the United States.</p>



<p>According to a new report from <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/bethesda-strike-zenimax-xbox-microsoft" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Inverse</a>, “hundreds” of employees have walked off the job in both Maryland and Texas. It’s claimed that the strike is due to the company not addressing remote work concerns as well as the recent outsourcing of quality assurance. The latter being something the union never agreed to.</p>



<p>The report claims that the union is “looking to limit the percentage of quality assurance testers the company outsources in comparison to the number of full-time workers present in its bargaining unit”.</p>



<p>The union, which is the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bethesda-game-studios-union-microsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">largest video games union</a> in the United States, is also looking for a more flexible remote work policy after employees are being denied remote work requests.</p>



<p>“They have continually given us their first proposal again and again, and it’s become obvious that our different mobilization tactics have not worked,” Bethesda Quality Assurance Test Lead Rhyanna Eichner told Inverse regarding the company’s negotiations with the union.</p>



<h6 id="h-related-raven-software-union-files-complaint-against-microsoft-and-activision">RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/raven-software-union-files-complaint-against-microsoft-and-activision/">Raven Software Union Files Complaint Against Microsoft And Activision</a></h6>



<p>“Striking isn’t fun or ideal, but there’s a satisfaction in having a concrete physical action we can do to fight for better work conditions,” Senior Quality Assurance Tester Juniper Dowell told the outlet. “Hopefully, we can convince them to stop dragging their feet and meet us at the table.”</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Microsoft and Bethesda for comment on the strike. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>What do you think of the Bethesda strike? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read what Xbox boss Phil Spencer said <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-handheld-confirmed-phil-spencer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">about a future Xbox handheld console</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam No Longer Supports Windows 7 or 8]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/steam-no-longer-supports-windows-7-or-8/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-no-longer-supports-windows-7-or-8.1034673/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/steam-no-longer-supports-windows-7-or-8/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Valve has released an update for Steam that officially ends support for Windows 7 and 8 operating systems. </p>



<p>The update, <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/4472730495692571025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">released on November 5</a> that includes the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steams-game-recording-feature-is-now-out-of-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ability to record games</a> within Steam, forces those who wish to continue to use Steam to either upgrade to Windows 10 or 11. Or, if you don’t want Windows at all, you can move to MacOS or Linux.</p>







<p>“This version of the Steam client will no longer run on Windows 7 or Windows 8,” the update reads. “Users on these OS versions will not automatically update to this new version of the Steam Client.”</p>



<p>In it’s FAQ page on the support ending, Valve says moving on from the old operating systems has to do with the security of its users.</p>



<p>“This change is required as core features in Steam rely on an embedded version of Google Chrome, which no longer functions on older versions of Windows,” Valve said. “In addition, future versions of Steam will require Windows feature and security updates only present in Windows 10 and above.”</p>



<p>They continued: “Computers running these operating systems, when connected to the internet, are susceptible to new malware and other exploits which will not be patched. That malware can cause your PC, Steam and games to perform poorly or crash. That malware can also be used to steal the credentials for your Steam account or other services.”</p>



<p>It’s also worth noting that Steam will also no longer work on MacOS 10.13 or 10.14.</p>



<p>Are you one of the holdouts still using Windows 7 or 8? Will this finally get you to upgrade? Let us know down below.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Tech news, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intel-battlemage-gpu-to-be-announced-next-month-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest claims surrounding Intel’s</a> next-generation GPU. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Leak Reveals All Nike and Jordan Kicks Cosmetics]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-reveals-all-nike-and-jordan-kicks-cosmetics/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-leak-reveals-all-nike-and-jordan-kicks-cosmetics.1034523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-reveals-all-nike-and-jordan-kicks-cosmetics/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-68366">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Prominent Fortnite Leaker HYPEX has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0sqCnqFHE7g" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed</a> the game’s upcoming Nike and Jordan cosmetics. Check out the complete list below.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-kicks-cosmetic-nike-jordan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epic announced</a> that Fortnite will officially introduce Kicks as the new cosmetic item, which will be available across 500 of the most popular skins in the game. The blog post also revealed the initial lineup for Fortnite Kicks, featuring Nike and Jordan brands, with some originals from Fortnite. The latest leak reveals which Nike and Jordan sneakers are making it to the game.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s the complete list of Fortnite Nike and Jordan Kicks revealed by HYPEX:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Air Jordan 1 High OG’ Black Toe Reimagined’</li>



<li>Air Jordan 11 ‘Retro Bred’</li>



<li>Air Jordan 3 ‘Black Cement-Gray’&nbsp;</li>



<li>Air Jordan 3 ‘Retro Palomino’&nbsp;</li>



<li>Air Jordan 4 ‘Retro Manila’&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fortnite Shark Slippers&nbsp;</li>



<li>Nike Air ‘Galaxy Foamposite’&nbsp;</li>



<li>Nike Cortez OG</li>



<li>Nike Shox</li>
</ul>



<p>In the game, these Nike and Air Jordan Kicks cosmetics will be usable on skins like <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1856636159578734806" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Miles Morales</a>, <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1856640005982081340" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Cell</a>, <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1856647771803054304" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">John Wick</a>, and <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1856649273846206648" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">many more</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Fortnite has confirmed that the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/original-fortnite-map-returning-permanently-in-december/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OG map will return permanently on December 6</a>. Also, the game’s<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-first-person-mode-arrives-on-december-11/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> first-person mode will launch on December 11</a>.&nbsp;What are your thoughts on the leaked Fortnite Nike and Air Jordan Kicks?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-handheld-confirmed-phil-spencer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phil Spencer confirming an Xbox handheld console that is years away</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-handheld-confirmed-phil-spencer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-handheld-confirmed-phil-spencer/">Phil Spencer Confirms Xbox is Planning an Xbox Handheld, But It’s a Few Years Away</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer has confirmed that Xbox is planning an Xbox handheld console, but it’s a few years away from release.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-first-person-mode-arrives-on-december-11/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-first-person-mode-arrives-on-december-11/">Fortnite’s First-Person Mode Arrives on December 11</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to an announcement by the Fortnite Creative account, the game’s first-person mode will launch on December 11, 2024. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-outlanders-officially-announced-for-mobile/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-outlanders-officially-announced-for-mobile/">Monster Hunter Outlanders Officially Announced for Mobile&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>TiMi Studio Group and Capcom have released an announcement trailer for Monster Hunter Outlanders. Here are more details on the mobile game. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-ceo-andrew-wilson-ceo-of-disney/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-ceo-andrew-wilson-ceo-of-disney/">EA’s CEO Could Be The Next Top Boss at Disney</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Andrew Wilson could be the next in line to take over the CEO position at Disney, it has been revealed. Get the full report here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>