<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 10:08:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inzoi Modders Have Already Added Infamous Inappropriate The Sims Mod to Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-modders-have-already-added-infamous-inappropriate-the-sims-mod-to-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inzoi-modders-have-already-added-infamous-inappropriate-the-sims-mod-to-game.1151784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-modders-have-already-added-infamous-inappropriate-the-sims-mod-to-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Inzoi has barely been out, and it’s already got the famous WickedWhims mod seen in The Sims. The user-created content is designed to let you experience Inzoi in a more unrestricted and uncensored fashion, and it was only a matter of time.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-25th-birthday-bundle-all-included-dlc-for-the-sims-1-and-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Sims</a> has always taken a lighthearted approach to intimate human activity. The action is usually pixelated and presented in a comedic yet casual fashion. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-most-wanted-wishlist-game-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Inzoi</a> is 2025’s realistic take on everyday life and features the usual hustle and bustle of existence: Jobs, Taxes, Death, and the creation of life.</p>



<p>It also keeps any intimate moments well hidden. But if you install the WickedWhims mod, you might want to play privately. </p>



<h2 id="h-controversial-the-sims-wickedwhims-mod-arrives-in-inzoi">Controversial The Sims WickedWhims Mod Arrives in Inzoi</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The mod gives you action more intense than this. Credit to Inzoi Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>X user <a href="https://x.com/WickedWhims" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TURBODRIVER</a> is back at it again with mods. They are the creator of the WickedWhims mods—as seen in The Sims. In Inzoi, it allows you to “Undress anything you want at any moment without censorship getting in the way.”</p>



<p>Furthermore, you can: “Get on a bed, or on a sofa, or the floor, or anywhere you want to get freaky with anybody you want.” The mod promises fully interactive animations and realistic interactions between Zois. This is only possible because the game doesn’t support <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-inzoi-have-denuvo-denuvo-status-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deunvo</a>.</p>



<p>The official mod’s site has four simple instructions required to install the mod. Once you’ve done this, your copy of Inzoi becomes steamier and hotter in a matter of seconds! Don’t say we didn’t warn you.</p>



<p>Inzoi has already been in the headlines of late as it was discovered you could <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-lets-you-run-over-children/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">run over children</a>. This was later addressed by the developer who claimed the action to be a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-developers-say-ability-to-run-over-children-was-a-bug/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bug, and it was patched</a>.</p>



<p>Let us know your thoughts on Inzoi over in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a>. Plus, we also have a few guides to aid your experience with the game: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-a-job-in-inzoi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to get a job</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-move-your-home-in-inzoi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to move your home</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-the-inzoi-money-cheat/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to use the money cheat</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remake Could Be Released Tomorrow, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/oblivion-remake-release-tomorrow-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remake-could-be-released-tomorrow-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1151745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/oblivion-remake-release-tomorrow-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It has been claimed by an insider that the Oblivion remake that has been the talk of the town for a while could suddenly be released <strong>tomorrow</strong>. Recently, it was suggested by <strong>another </strong>rumour that the Oblivion remake would be released ‘sooner than expected’, and April was touted as being the month when the reveal would take place.</p>



<p>However, this all-new claim suggests that the game will just be dropped without warning. It’s time to take out the salt bowl and grab a pinch, folks.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-in-our-dreams">In Our Dreams</h2>



<p>The slew of rumours that have emerged regarding the Oblivion remake haven’t been all that wild, but we’re yet to see <strong>anything </strong>about the project. Per the claims, it’s in development at Virtuous Games and will be a full-blown rebuild of the 2006 title in Unreal Engine 5. It has been suggested that considerable upgrades have also been made to the game’s mechanics and combat systems.</p>



<p>It sounds great, but we don’t know a thing about it, including which platforms it’ll be released on, how much it’ll cost, and <strong>what it will look like</strong>.</p>



<p>On March 13, Nate The Hate posted on social media that he was expecting ‘news’ on the Oblivion remake <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elder-scrolls-oblivion-remake-coming-sooner-than-expected-its-claimed/">to surface in April</a> and that the release date for the game could be earlier than ‘the original June target’.</p>



<p>April is earlier than June, right?</p>



<p>Now, Detective Seeds has posted on Twitter with an all-new claim:</p>



<div><article><p><span>I believe the Oblivion remake is going to release end of next week, likely Thursday April 3rd.  Then 13 days later Indiana jones on the 16th on PS5, and then 13 days later forza horizon 5 on 29th on PS5.</span></p></article></div>







<p>He expanded in the comments, covering his tracks slightly by placing the responsibility of the rumour on an undisclosed source, explaining:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>It is a little iffy if it is going to be this week or next. They were confident in it coming though.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>With that being said, we’re not <strong>really </strong>any closer to getting the truth. It could be tomorrow, it could be next week, or it could be June. Strangely, nothing has been revealed just yet, but a UE5 Elder Scrolls game, even a remake, would be a <strong>very welcome arrival </strong>right now.</p>



<p>Do you think the Oblivion remake rumours are real? Let me know in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-next-major-change-bosses/">next Escape from Tarkov update could change the game in a major way</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The International 2025 Schedule, Format, and Structure]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-international-2025-schedule-format-and-structure/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-international-2025-schedule-format-and-structure.1151736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-international-2025-schedule-format-and-structure/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The International is one of the most prestigious esports events in history. It has boasted some of the largest prize pools in competitive gaming, and it draws in millions of viewers every year. It’s considered the pinnacle of the industry by many, and it’s set to surface again in 2025.</p>



<p>Valve has outlined the schedule and format for The International 2025, but more granular details are yet to be revealed. This page will be updated as the information is released by Valve, but for now, you can read on to learn about The International 2025 schedule and format.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-road-to-the-international-2025">The Road to The International 2025</h2>



<p>Valve has highlighted that The Road to The International will start on Thursday, September 4 and will run until September 7. It’ll include two Swiss rounds and their successive elimination roads, and it’ll lead to eight teams out of the sixteen invited being eliminated.</p>



<p>The remaining eight teams will advance to the arena environment for The International proper.</p>



<p>Here’s how The Road to The International <a href="https://www.dota2.com/newsentry/536597286667419796" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">will work in 2025</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>This year, The Road to The International starts with a five-round Swiss bracket: Over the first three days, sixteen teams will play best-of-three matches against other teams with the same series record (a 2:0 team will face another 2:0 team, a 1:3 team will face another 1:3 team, etc.). A fourth series win will cause that team to automatically advance to The International; a fourth loss will cause that team to be eliminated.</p>



<p>After five rounds of Swiss, the three teams with four wins will have secured their spot in The International and the three teams with four losses will have been eliminated. The ten remaining teams will face-off in a special elimination round (strongest against weakest) with the five winners advancing to the International and the five losers being eliminated.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 id="h-the-international-2025-schedule">The International 2025 Schedule</h2>



<p>This year’s The International will start on Thursday, September 11. It’ll unravel in the arena over a four-day window, with the Grand Finasl taking place on Sunday, September 14.</p>



<p>The eight teams that make it to The International will compete in front of a grand crowd in Barclays Arena, with the winner claiming an undisclosed prize pool and lifting the Aegis.</p>



<h2 id="h-faqs">FAQs</h2>



<h3 id="h-where-is-the-international-2025">Where is The International 2025?</h3>



<p>The International 2025 will take place in the Barclays Arena in Hamburg, Germany. It’s a top venue with a capacity of 15,000, and it’ll likely sell out very fast as The International 2025 approaches.</p>



<h3 id="h-what-is-the-international-2025-prize-pool">What is The International 2025 Prize Pool?</h3>



<p>The prize pool is yet to be determined for The International 2025. Last year’s tournament had a pool of $2.7 million, but in 2021, the record was set when the prize pool reached $40 million. Since then, the pool has decreased rapidly, but the expectation is that it’ll be <strong>at least </strong>$2.5 million this year.</p>



<h3 id="h-how-many-teams-are-at-the-international-2025">How Many Teams Are at The International 2025?</h3>



<p>The Road to The International starts with sixteen invited teams, but the elimination brackets will remove eight of them. There will be eight teams that make it to The International 2025.</p>



<h3 id="h-which-team-is-the-favourite-to-win-the-international-2025">Which Team is the Favourite to Win The International 2025?</h3>



<p>It’s tough to gauge the competition this early on. The most recent winner of The Invitational was Team Liquid, but for the last two tournaments, Gaimin Gladiators have claimed a second-place spot. Could this be the year for the European organisation to finally win?</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">Insider Gaming esports</a> coverage</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameCube Coming To Nintendo Switch Online A Matter Of “When, Not If”, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-when-not-if-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-%E2%80%9Cwhen-not-if%E2%80%9D-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1151667/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gamecube-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-a-matter-of-when-not-if-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-107323">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Nintendo GameCube games could be coming to Nintendo Switch Online sooner rather that later. During <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fuxJOnR2awY&amp;t=667s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">his latest podcast</a>, known leaker Nate The Hate touched on what could be shown during the Nintendo Switch 2 direct on April 2. One area he focused on was Nintendo Switch online and whether GameCube games could be part of the event.</p>



<p>“I think it’s also going to be a good venue for them to go over Nintendo Switch Online enhancements and new platforms that will come to the Switch 2 and, likely, even the Switch itself in the future—maybe within that first launch year,” Nate The Hate said. “And I think GameCube is very likely. </p>







<p>“I’ve heard GameCube will be coming to NSO [Nintendo Switch Online]. It’s just a question of when, not if. And maybe you give a nice little roadmap of some of the titles that would come to the GameCube NSO app.”</p>



<p>As always, until this information is confirmed independently by Insider Gaming or announced by Nintendo itself, please take any rumors with a grain of salt. Luckily, it won’t be long until fans find out if GameCube games will be added as part of the Nintendo Switch 2 launch or not.</p>



<p>Do you think Nintendo GameCube games will come to Nintendo Switch Online? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read what Take-Two Interactive’s CEO had to say about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-says-lack-of-gta-6-news-is-to-create-enormous-anticipation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lack of updates surrounding Grand Theft Auto 6</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-watch-nintendo-switch-2-direct-event/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-watch-nintendo-switch-2-direct-event/">
                                How To Watch The Nintendo Switch 2 Direct Event                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Nintendo Switch 2 full reveal is here, and this is how you can watch the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct when it airs at 9am ET/6am PT.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-will-the-nintendo-switch-2-direct-last/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-will-the-nintendo-switch-2-direct-last/">
                                How Long Will The Nintendo Switch 2 Direct Last?                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Nintendo is holding its Nintendo Switch 2 Direct event on Wednesday, April 2, and one question people are wondering is how long will it be?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-rumors-heat-up-with-new-ff9-website-launch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-rumors-heat-up-with-new-ff9-website-launch/">
                                Final Fantasy 9 Remake Rumors Heat Up With New FF9 Website Launch                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The 25th anniversary celebration of Final Fantasy 9 has resulted in a new website for the game, and remake rumors have intensified again.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/developers-say-nintendo-switch-2-dev-kits-dont-have-4k-output/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/developers-say-nintendo-switch-2-dev-kits-dont-have-4k-output/">
                                Developers Say Nintendo Switch 2 Dev Kits Don’t Have 4K Output                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Despite rumors that the Nintendo Switch 2 will support 4K, developers have told Insider Gaming that the dev kit doesn’t include 4K output.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pred Signs With Vegas Falcons Following OpTic Departure]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure.1151604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pred-signs-with-vegas-falcons-following-optic-departure/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fresh off his release from OpTic Texas, reigning Call of Duty League champion Amer “Pred” Zulbeari has signed with Vegas Falcons. While OpTic may be joking about roster moves on April Fool’s Day, Falcons aren’t screwing around after a tough start to their time in the CDL.</p>



<h2 id="h-pred-joins-a-falcons-roster-still-looking-for-its-first-win-in-call-of-duty-league">Pred Joins a Falcons Roster Still Looking For Its First Win in Call of Duty League</h2>



<p>Pred was removed from the OpTic starting roster at the end of March, after a turbulent 2025 that followed a superb 2024 season. The product of Australian CoD joined OpTic before the start of the 2024 campaign, and a promising start cascaded into a CDL championship, the first for the OpTic brand since the League’s inception.</p>



<p>But months after OpTic lifted the elusive CDL world championship, Pred moved to the inactive roster, needing a break to “handle personal issues” and work on his mental health. In his stead, Cuyler “Huke” Garland returned to the starting roster for 2025, but Pred came back in February, though OpTic’s results continued to worsen. A struggling Kenneth “Kenny” Williams chose to step down before the Stage Two Major, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-texas-repeats-history-drops-pred-for-huke-again/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OpTic chose to swap Huke in for Pred again</a>, but this time permanently.</p>



<div><article><p><span>A World Champion has arrived in Vegas. It’s time to make a statement.

Welcome, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/Pred" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Pred</a><span> 🦅💚 </span></p></article></div>



<p>Pred now joins a Vegas Falcons team that is in desperate need of some positive momentum. The Vegas franchise was sold to Saudi Arabian organization Team Falcons after the 2024 season ended, and the organization chose to stick with a Saudi roster going into 2025, with former champion James “Clayster” Eubanks joining as coach. But the roster just has been unable to keep up with the talent in the league, and went completely winless throughout all of Stage 1 and Stage 2.</p>



<p>With the signing of Pred, the Vegas Falcons are making their first big splash on a non-Saudi player. Will it be enough to secure the team’s first win in CDL, or are more moves on the horizon? Let us know which one is your favorite in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/faker-biggest-esports-star-50-million-won-donation/">Faker made a 50 million Won donation to charity</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>