<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:03:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: New Horizons 3.0 Update—All New Content, Villagers & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-update-new-content/</link>
            <guid>1398322</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>After years of waiting, Animal Crossing: New Horizons is receiving a slew of new content in the 3.0 update, releasing alongside the Nintendo Switch 2 upgrade of the game.</p>



<p>Six years after it was first released, and four years on from the 2.0 update, Animal Crossing: New Horizons receives the 3<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-switch-2-edition-exact-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">.0 update on January 15</a>, bringing new content, new villagers, and more to the game.</p>



<p>For a complete rundown on everything being added in the update, Insider Gaming has you covered.</p>







<h2 id="h-all-new-content-in-animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-update">All New Content in Animal Crossing: New Horizons 3.0 Update</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New tasks. Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<h3 id="h-new-amp-returning-villagers">New &amp; Returning Villagers</h3>



<p>Four additional villagers will become available in Animal Crossing: New Horizons with the 3.0 update, although the process to add them to your island requires using an Amiibo, and they cannot be invited to your island without them.</p>



<p>Mineru and Tulin are the two new additions, from the Legends of Zelda Amiibos, while Cece and Viche are returning villagers, available by scanning Splatoon Amiibos.</p>



<p>Without the use of Amiibos, none of the four additional villagers coming to New Horizons in the 3.0 update can be invited to your island.</p>



<h3 id="h-quality-of-life-improvements">Quality-of-Life Improvements</h3>



<p>Several quality-of-life improvements are introduced in the 3.0 update, increasing the maximum amount of available storage to 9,000, along with the ability to place trees, bushes, andd flowers inside storage.</p>



<p>When crafting, you are able to select the number of items in total you want to craft, rather than having to do one at a time, and crafting now pulls materials from storage, meaning you will no longer have to have all the materials required in your pockets.</p>



<p>Finally, when terraforming, movement changes make it easier to build or remove fences, paths, cliffs, and rivers on a single axis, with quick steps in a single direction.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Design time. Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<h3 id="h-resort-hotel">Resort Hotel</h3>



<p>The biggest gameplay addition in the New Horizons 3.0 update is the Resort Hotel, where players are tasked to design rooms for guests matching a specified theme.  Tourists will visit the island and can be found wandering around, with the ability to invite specific villagers using Amiibo. </p>



<p>Completing requests earns Hotel Tickets, used to claim goods at the souvenir shop run by Grams, and Hotel Tickets are also earned by fulfilling requests for DIY goods, which also increases the hotel’s international brand recognition.</p>



<p>Additionally, the hotel lobby has two mannequins that can be dressed with custom outfits, which both animal and human visitors can borrow to wear.</p>



<h3 id="h-reset-service">Reset Service</h3>



<p>Mr. Resetti’s island Reset Service is added in the 3.0 update, allowing players to easily clear specific areas of the island. When doing so, you can choose for items to be disposed of, or placed into storage.</p>



<p>The Reset Service can also be used to clear planted flowers and custom designs, making it much easier to give your island a new makeover.</p>



<h3 id="h-slumber-islands">Slumber Islands</h3>



<p>Slumber Islands are available in a new dream world, with each player able to create up to three. There is a selection of random layouts, and three varying sizes.</p>



<p>Islands can be fully terraformed and decorated with items from a player’s catalog, while the time of day and weather can also be set. Lloid is available to construct bridges and inclines on demand.</p>



<p>You can also invite other players to join your Slumber Island via multiplayer and work together crafting the island.</p>



<h3 id="h-collaborations">Collaborations</h3>



<p>Several collaborations are added in the New Horizons 3.0 update, bringing a host of new items, decorations, and rare furniture items into the game.</p>



<p>Grams’ souvenir shop stocks rare furniture items as the Hotel’s brand recognition increases, themed on classic Nintendo consoles and retro toys. With an active Nintendo Switch Online subscription, players can select and play games on the consoles, with Clu Clu Land, ice Climber, Dr. Mario, Panel de Pon, and F-Zero available.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, LEGO-themed furniture is added to Nook Shopping, and can be purchased when it becomes available. There are also themed items from The Legend of Zelda and Splatoon available when compatible Amiibos are scanned.</p>







<hr>



<p>What are you most excited for in the Animal Crossing: New Horizons 3.0 update? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date details for Highguard</a>, and take a look at all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-platforms-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platform information for Hytale</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-update-new-content/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Wave Of Xbox Game Pass Games Announced For January]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-wave-xbox-game-pass-games-january/</link>
            <guid>1398262</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Microsoft has announced a new wave of games are coming to Xbox Game Pass in January. Joining the ever-expanding catalog as early as today (January 6) are 11 games, including some being made available to Xbox Game Pass Premium members for the first time. </p>



<p>Of the 11 games, only one is a “day one” release for players, MIO: Memories in Orbit. Games that were previously available exclusive for Game Pass Ultimate members <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/06/xbox-game-pass-january-2026-wave-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">but are now available</a> for Game Pass Premium subscribers include Rematch, Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine – Master Crafted Edition, Atomfall, and Lost in Random: The Eternal Die.</p>







<p>You can check out the full list of new additions to the service below. And be sure to leave your thoughts on the new games down in the comments and over in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-xbox-game-pass-games-january-2026-wave-1">Xbox Game Pass Games – January 2026 Wave 1</h2>



<p><strong>Brews &amp; Bastards (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – Available Today</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition (Cloud, Handheld, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – Available Today</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>Atomfall (Cloud, Console, Handheld, PC) – January 7</strong><br>Game Pass Premium</p>



<p><strong>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die (Cloud, Xbox Series X|S, Handheld, PC) – January 7</strong><br>Game Pass Premium</p>



<p><strong>Rematch (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – January 7</strong><br>Game Pass Premium</p>



<p><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine – Master Crafted Edition (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – January 7</strong><br>Game Pass Premium</p>



<p><strong>Final Fantasy (Cloud, Xbox Series X|S, PC) – January 8</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>Star Wars Outlaws (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – January 13</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>My Little Pony: A Zephyr Heights Mystery (Cloud, Console, Handheld, PC) – January 15</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>Resident Evil Village (Cloud, Console, PC) – January 20</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Premium, PC Game Pass</p>



<p><strong>MIO: Memories in Orbit (Cloud, Handheld, PC, Xbox Series X|S) – January 20</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</p>







<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about Sony <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-patents-ai-technology-that-can-play-the-game-for-you/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">patenting AI technology that can play games</a> for you. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-wave-xbox-game-pass-games-january/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem NVIDIA Video Showcases Raccoon City]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-nvidia-video-showcases-raccoon-city/</link>
            <guid>1398208</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>NVIDIA has released a brand-new tech showcase for Resident Evil Requiem, offering players a glimpse of Raccoon City in action.</p>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem is set to release next month on February 27, 2026, and the developers have been slowly revealing more information about the game as launch approaches. Recently, the director stated that the upcoming title will be ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-is-almost-like-having-two-games-says-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost like having two games</a>‘. Now, Raccoon City’s environment has been teased in a new NVIDIA showcase. </p>







<h2 id="h-resident-evil-requiem-s-raccoon-city-looks-and-feels-amazing">Resident Evil Requiem’s Raccoon City Looks and Feels Amazing</h2>



<p>The tease for Resident Evil Requiem’s Raccoon City comes through a new 4K Path Tracing &amp; NVIDIA DLSS 4 <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0mgOPbpagc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">trailer</a> uploaded by NVIDIA. The video showcases short clips of a cityscape that captures a dark, gritty vibe, perfectly aligning with Raccoon City’s aesthetic. In the footage, we see Grace walking through the city, and from the few seconds shown, it looks incredible. Interested readers can check out the video below: </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem | 4K Path Tracing &amp; NVIDIA DLSS 4 Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u0mgOPbpagc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Coming to the tech talk, Resident Evil Requiem has been optimised for a wide range of PCs ahead of its release, featuring path-traced effects, DLSS 4, accelerated performance, and enhanced image quality. Thanks to path tracing, the game will be able to render multiple shadows from multiple light sources, along with complex lighting effects such as reflections and refractions through glass.</p>



<p>Additionally, the game will also be available on GeForce Now at launch, allowing players to access the power of a GeForce RTX 5080 with DLSS 4 enabled. </p>







<p>In other news, a new claim stated that Resident Evil Code Veronica and Zero remakes <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-code-veronica-and-zero-remakes-scheduled-for-2027-2028-respectively-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">are scheduled for 2027 and 2028, respectively</a>. Additionally, Leon Kennedy <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-kennedy-the-game-awards-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">finally received his official reveal</a> for Requiem at The Game Awards last month. What are your thoughts on Resident Evil Requiem’s NVIDIA showcase teasing Raccoon City? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-patents-ai-technology-that-can-play-the-game-for-you/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony patenting new Ghost Player AI tech, which can play the game for you</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-nvidia-video-showcases-raccoon-city/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>