<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 01:33:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smite 2: Full List Of First 50 Gods Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/smite-2-full-list-of-first-50-gods/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/smite-2-full-list-of-first-50-gods-revealed.1031484/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/smite-2-full-list-of-first-50-gods/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-67736">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Hi-Rez Studios has released the full list of the first 50 playable Gods available in Smite 2 when the game heads to free-to-play in early 2025. </p>



<p>Smite 2 launches free-to-play in January 2025 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. The game features a new gameplay engine, improved graphics, a new item system, and more. Smite 2 will offer five game modes for players: Conquest, Arena, Joust, Assault, and Slash.</p>



<p>Those who want access to the game early can do so by either registering for a closed Alpha or purchasing a Smite 2 <a href="https://www.smite2.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Founders Pack</a>.</p>



<p>Currently, those with access to the game have 31 Gods available to them. From publishing through the first month of full launch in January, there will be 19 more added. You can check out the full list of the first 50 Gods, minus a yet-to-be-revealed God, below. </p>



<h2 id="h-smite-2-first-50-gods">Smite 2: First 50 Gods</h2>



<p><strong>May 2 – Alpha Weekend 1 (14 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Anhur</li>



<li>Anubis</li>



<li>Bacchus</li>



<li>Bellona</li>



<li>Cernunnos</li>



<li>Chaac</li>



<li>Loki</li>



<li>Neith</li>



<li>Ymir</li>



<li>Zeus</li>



<li>Athena</li>



<li>Fenrir</li>



<li>Kukulkan</li>



<li>Sol</li>



<li>Hades</li>



<li>The Morrigan</li>



<li>Thanatos</li>



<li>Hecate</li>



<li>Ares</li>



<li>Susano</li>



<li>Mordred</li>



<li>Jing Wei</li>



<li>Amaterasu</li>



<li>Nu Wa</li>



<li>Baron Samedi</li>



<li>Yemoja</li>



<li>Hercules</li>



<li>Danzaburou</li>



<li>Ra</li>



<li>Sobek</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>November 12 (34 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Nemesis</li>



<li>Izanami</li>



<li>Khepri</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>November 26 (37 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Thor</li>



<li>Poseidon</li>



<li>Cupid</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>December 10 (40 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Aphrodite</li>



<li>Pele</li>



<li>Medusa</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>January Wave 1 (45 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>All-New SMITE 2 God  (TBA)</li>



<li>Ullr</li>



<li>Agni</li>



<li>Mulan</li>



<li>Geb</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>January Wave 2 (50 gods)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rama</li>



<li>Hun Batz</li>



<li>Achilles</li>



<li>Cabrakan</li>



<li>Vulcan</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/news/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">News Hub</a>. You can also join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>. </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-rocket-league-ranks/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-rocket-league-ranks/">All Rocket League Ranks | Get the Edge in Rocket League</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>First time playing Rocket League ranked? Here is a list of all the ranks in the popular game.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/giantx-wins-vct-spotlight-series/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/giantx-wins-vct-spotlight-series/">GIANTX Wins VCT Spotlight Series</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The VCT Spotlight Series has officially ended with GIANTX winning the event.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guides-hub/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guides-hub/">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battles Guides Hub</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Check out the Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Episode Battle Guides Hub, for explanations on all 21 sagas of this game mode. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-counter-strike-pro-s1mple-breaks-silence-on-his-return-to-competing/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-counter-strike-pro-s1mple-breaks-silence-on-his-return-to-competing/">Former Counter-Strike Pro, S1mple, Breaks Silence On His Return To Competing</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Former Counter-Strike pro breaks his silence on whether or not he plans to return to the game competitively.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earn More Money in Planet Coaster 2 and Expand Your Horizons]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/earn-more-money-in-planet-coaster-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/earn-more-money-in-planet-coaster-2-and-expand-your-horizons.1031481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/earn-more-money-in-planet-coaster-2/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>You need money. We all need money, but we’ll have to settle for virtual cash in a game like Planet Coaster 2. At least in that world, you have total control and can plop down an entire roller coaster in your backyard. I tried that once, and the city sent a zoning expert to shut everything down. Anyway, you can earn more money in Planet Coaster 2, and I’d like to help your amusement park flourish with a few tips!</p>



<h2 id="h-best-ways-to-make-more-money-in-planet-coaster-2">Best Ways to Make More Money in Planet Coaster 2</h2>



<p>Without a constant and ever-growing source of income, you can’t reinvest in your park to open additional rides, like rollercoasters and carousels, or expand your offerings to the new waterpark mechanics. But earning more money in Planet Coaster 2 is easier said than done, right? Nope, here are a few tips:</p>



<h3 id="h-lower-the-entry-fee-to-free">Lower the Entry Fee to Free</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Screenshot by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>First and foremost, open up your Park Management screen. It’s the top-most icon on the top left-hand side of the screen. Here, you can alter your Park Options, including the price of admission for the various ticket and pass types in the game.</p>



<p>Here, I recommend lowering your entry tickets to $0.00. That’s right; allow everyone free entry to your for-profit amusement park. Doing so will entice more visitors to check out your park, where you stand to make money. With the ticket prices free, people can spend more on drinks, food, merchandise, and the rides themselves. Jack up those prices, baby!</p>



<h3 id="h-add-scenery-to-rides">Add Scenery to Rides</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Screenshot by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Don’t forget about the scenery as you expand your park, plopping down a new ride or two along your most recent expansion. It’s easy to ignore scenery, as everything little bit costs money. It’ll feel as if you’re hemorrhaging money initially. But trust me when I tell you it’s an investment with long-term gains.</p>



<p>The scenery in Planet Coaster 2 directly increases ride and park appeal, which increases the Prestige of your attractions. As appeal and Prestige increase, so does guest happiness. They’ll spend more time at your park, riding the rides and buying merchandise, making you money.</p>



<h3 id="h-relax">Relax!</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Screenshot by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>I like to watch whatever show I’m binging while playing a game like Planet Coaster 2. Inevitably, you still encounter slow periods of gameplay where it’s often best to sit back and relax. For instance, once you’re profitable, with a handful of rides and attractions bringing in customers, speed up the game and chill.</p>



<p>Now’s a good time to catch up on Reddit, read a chapter in your book, or catch a few moments of your favorite show while your park works in the background, constantly ticking up those dollar signs with every passing second.</p>



<p>Would you like to share a few Planet Coaster 2 tips and tricks with us? Comment below, or visit <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forum</a> to discuss Frontier Developments and its games!</p>



<hr>



<p>If you’ve yet to try the game, there’s a good chance it’s because you’re waiting to hear about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/planet-coaster-2-on-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Planet Coaster 2 on Game Pass</a>, right?</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Announces ‘The Dramatic Showdown’ Tournament]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-announces-the-dramatic-showdown-tournament/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-announces-%E2%80%98the-dramatic-showdown%E2%80%99-tournament.1031370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-announces-the-dramatic-showdown-tournament/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero has just announced a non-traditional esports tournament called ‘The Dramatic Showdown’. The competition begins in November 2024 and will conclude during the Dragon Ball: Games Battle Hour 2025 event in Los Angeles, CA, January 18-19, 2025.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-sparking-zero-the-dramatic-showdown-schedule-nbsp">Sparking Zero: The Dramatic Showdown Schedule&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero The Dramatic Showdown’s online qualifiers will begin on November 16 and end on December 8, 2024. In that time, 9 champions will be decided through a series of tournaments across 9 regions: Mexico, Germany, United Kingdom, France, Japan, Spain, Italy, USA East and USA West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, seven extra players will qualify for the Grand Finals through a tournament taking place at Battle Hour on January 18, 2025. With this addition, the total number of fighters participating in the Grand Finals is 16.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-the-dramatic-showdown-format-rules-and-more">The Dramatic Showdown Format, Rules and More</h2>



<h3 id="h-qualifiers-nbsp">Qualifiers&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The rules for Sparking Zero: The Dramatic Showdown’s online and Battle Hour qualifiers are the same. The platform of choice is PlayStation 5, and the tournament format will be best-of-three games (first to two wins), single elimination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The decided game mode is DP battle, where players can pick a team of characters with a limit of 15 DP. Winners must stay with the same characters for the next consecutive game, whereas losers can change. Items will not be allowed, there are no restrictions on stage and time limit is set for 600 Seconds.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-grand-finals">Grand Finals</h3>



<p>For Sparking Zero: The Dramatic Showdown’s Grand Finals, qualified players from the region-specific tournaments and Battle Hour qualifiers must use preset characters. These characters were decided through a draw during the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g8NuUOeZkrE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">producer message video</a>. Players can choose whichever form they want to use of their designated character to start their battles. Check out which champion has been allotted to which region below.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>France – Goku (Super) Ultra Instinct&nbsp;</li>



<li>Mexico – Golden Frieza&nbsp;</li>



<li>Germany – Super Baby 2 (GT)</li>



<li>Italy – Broly (Super), Super Saiyan (Full Power)</li>



<li>Spain – Future Trunks, Super Saiyan&nbsp;</li>



<li>USA West –&nbsp; Gogeta (GT), Super Saiyan 4</li>



<li>USA East – Ultimate Gohan/Gohan Teen Super Saiyan 2</li>



<li>United Kingdom – Gogeta (Super), Super Saiyan God Super Saiyan</li>



<li>Japan – Gotenks, Super Saiyan 3</li>



<li>Battle Hour 1 – Kedla Super Saiyan 2</li>



<li>Battle Hour 2 – Vegeta (Super), Super Saiyan God Super Saiyan</li>



<li>Battle Hour 3 – Jiren, Full Power&nbsp;</li>



<li>Battle Hour 4 – Goku Black, Super Saiyan Rosé</li>



<li>Battle Hour 5 – Super Janemba</li>



<li>Battle Hour 6 – Vegito (Super) Super Saiyan God Super Saiyan</li>



<li>Battle Hour 7 – Perfect Cell</li>
</ul>



<p>Additionally, players in the Grand Finals will have the option to add a second character to their team from a pool of 40 characters. However, this pool includes characters with an in-game level of less than 4 DP. Lastly, some items will be allowed depending on the in-game DP of each of the 16 characters. More details will be revealed later. Check out Bandai Namco’s <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/dragon-ball/news/announcing-the-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-the-dramatic-showdown-tournament?utm_source=SM_Official&amp;utm_medium=official_post&amp;utm_campaign=DBSZ_Dramatic_Showdown" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> about the event for registration details and rules.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In other news, Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s 90% of sales <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-90-of-sales-came-from-europe-and-na/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came from Europe and NA</a>.&nbsp;Also, If you are new to the game, check out the&nbsp;Attack,&nbsp;Movement&nbsp;and&nbsp;Defense&nbsp;guides. What are your thoughts on Dragon Ball Sparking Zero: The Dramatic Showdown? Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-isnt-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Take-Two not being worried about GTA 6’s performance on the Xbox Series S</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>