<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 16:22:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LoL Worlds 2024 Final Hit 50 Million Peak Viewers]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-hit-50-million-peak-viewers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lol-worlds-2024-final-hit-50-million-peak-viewers.1041855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-hit-50-million-peak-viewers/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It was recently revealed by Riot Games that the League of Legends Worlds final, which took place on November 2 in London, secured a whopping 50 million peak viewers worldwide. This number was driven mostly by esports fans in China.</p>



<p>That figure includes an all-time high for esports viewers outside of China, the company revealed. </p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-into-perspective">Into Perspective</h2>



<p>To put that figure into perspective, this year’s NBA Finals pulled in a peak viewer count of around 12.3 million users across the United States. The Super Bowl, which was held in February 2024, racked up a total unique viewer count of 120.2 million people, averaging a peak of 38.5 million.</p>



<p>The data was <a href="https://x.com/lolesports/status/1859295721956024521" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">provided by Riot Games on social media</a> via Stream Hatchet.</p>



<p>This year’s League of Legends World Championship final is widely considered one of the best events in <strong>many years</strong>. It was a spectacle to behold, with live performances taking centre stage at the O2 Arena in London before T1 and Bilibili descended upon their stations to compete in front of a sold-out stadium.</p>



<p>The closing moments of the match were nothing short of legendary, and it marked a <strong>fifth </strong>Worlds win for both T1 and Faker.</p>



<p>In terms of numbers and buzz on social and streaming platforms, the grand final fixture was one of the most popular (if not <strong>the most</strong>) esports matches in the industry’s history. Nothing before has topped the grandiose profile of the full series, and it’s unlikely anything will again – for a long time, at least.</p>



<p>The League of Legends World Championship continues to grow. It’s the number-one esports event of the year, and it’s a perfect example of the ever-developing power of the esports market.</p>



<p>Did you watch LoL Worlds this year? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/off-the-grid-600k-tournament-ended/">the recent Off The Grid tournament</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker Developer Heart Machine Suffers Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hyper-light-breaker-developer-heart-machine-suffers-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-developer-heart-machine-suffers-layoffs.1041849/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hyper-light-breaker-developer-heart-machine-suffers-layoffs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Another games studio is letting go of staff. Heart Machine, the developers behind Hyper Light Breaker and its predecessor Hyper Light Drifter, have confirmed that its holding layoffs.</p>



<p>First reported and confirmed by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hyper-light-breaker-developer-heart-machine-confirms-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Developer</a>, the Los Angeles-based studio didn’t give a specific reason for the layoffs, nor did they confirm how many people are being let go. However, it will be providing severance and healthcare to those being let go. </p>



<p>It was also affirmed that the upcoming launch of Hyper Light Breaker won’t be impacted by the layoffs.</p>



<p>“Hyper Light Breaker’s&nbsp;upcoming launch will not be impeded by this sad news–in fact, a strong and timely launch will rekindle opportunities for those affected as we look to evolve and grow the game throughout Early Access. Our other projects, including&nbsp;Possessor(s), will also remain unaffected,” studio community and PR manager Yiyi Zhang told Game Developer.</p>







<p>Zhang continued: “We really appreciate our communities who have rallied in support of our studio and others in similar positions, and are hopeful for what’s on the horizon for our upcoming games, our colleagues, and the industry as a whole.”</p>



<p>Though an exact date hasn’t been announced, Heart Machine is planning to launch Hyper Light Breaker in early access sometime in 2025. The game was originally scheduled to release in late 2024 before being delayed in August.</p>



<p>The games industry has seen more that 14,100 known jobs lost due to layoffs in 2024. The real number, according to some sources, could be as high as 16,000 to even 17,000.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-not-getting-ps5-pro-upgrade/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">won’t be getting a PS5 Pro update</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Ranked Play loadout in Black Ops 6]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-ranked-play-loadout-in-black-ops-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-ranked-play-loadout-in-black-ops-6.1041753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-ranked-play-loadout-in-black-ops-6/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play-everything/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 Ranked Play</a> allows players to test their might against similarly skilled players for rewards and bragging rights. To even out the playing field, only certain weapons, attachments, Equipment, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-perk-wildcard-in-warzone-x-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Perks</a> are available.</p>



<p>You can only pick from a pool of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-assault-rifles-in-black-ops-6-ranked-best-ar-loadout/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assault Rifles</a>, SMGs, and Sniper Rifles, so many are wondering what the best loadout is for each category. To help you dominate every <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-black-ops-6-game-modes-maps-equipment-field-upgrades/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">map and mode</a> in BO6 Ranked Play, here are the best loadouts to build.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-best-assault-rifle-loadout-for-bo6-ranked-play">Best Assault Rifle</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-smg-loadout-for-black-ops-6-ranked-play">Best SMG</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-sniper-loadout-for-ranked-play-in-bo6">Best Sniper Rifle</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-assault-rifle-loadout-for-bo6-ranked-play">Best Assault Rifle loadout for BO6 Ranked Play</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The best Assault Rifle loadout for BO6 Ranked Play.</figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Primary: </strong>Model L
<ul>
<li><strong>Optic</strong>: Merlin Mini</li>



<li><strong>Muzzle</strong>: Ported Compensator</li>



<li><strong>Barrel</strong>: Reinforced Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Rear Grip</strong>: Commando Grip</li>



<li><strong>Stock</strong>: Balanced Stock</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Secondary: </strong>Stryder .22</li>



<li><strong>Tactical:</strong> Concussion</li>



<li><strong>Lethal:</strong> Frag</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade:</strong> Trophy System</li>



<li><strong>Perk 1:</strong> Tac Mask</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2:</strong> Fast Hands</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3:</strong> Double Time</li>



<li><strong>Perk 4: </strong>Ninja</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard: </strong>Perk Greed</li>
</ul>



<p>The <strong>Model L</strong> is a top performer in <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/uk/en/playnow/blackops6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Black Ops 6</a>, mainly thanks to its low recoil and high damage. This makes it our pick for the best Assault Rifle in Ranked Play, especially with the attachments that aim to increase the handling and damage profile.</p>



<p>We’ve gone with Perks that protect you against enemy Tactical Equipment and give you more mobility, while also utilizing the Perk Greed Wildcard for Ninja. You’ll find this same Wildcard and Perk 4 combination throughout our best Ranked Play loadouts, as being able to move around the map freely without worrying about your footsteps is extremely strong.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-smg-loadout-for-black-ops-6-ranked-play">Best SMG loadout for Black Ops 6 Ranked Play</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Everything you need for the best SMG loadout in Ranked Play.</figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Primary: </strong>PP-919
<ul>
<li><strong>Muzzle</strong>: Ported Compensator</li>



<li><strong>Barrel</strong>: Short Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Magazine</strong>: Fast Mag II</li>



<li><strong>Rear Grip</strong>: CQB Grip</li>



<li><strong>Stock</strong>: Balanced Stock</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Secondary: </strong>Stryder .22</li>



<li><strong>Tactical:</strong> Concussion</li>



<li><strong>Lethal:</strong> Semtex</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade:</strong> Trophy System</li>



<li><strong>Perk 1:</strong> Flak Jacket</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2:</strong> Fast Hands</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3:</strong> Double Time</li>



<li><strong>Perk 4: </strong>Ninja</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard: </strong>Perk Greed</li>
</ul>



<p>If you’re looking for something more close-range, this <strong>PP-919</strong> BO6 Ranked Play loadout is the one for you. With a fast fire rate, high magazine count, and attachments that aid recoil control, handling, and mobility, you’ll be shredding enemies both up close and at medium range.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-sniper-loadout-for-ranked-play-in-bo6">Best Sniper loadout for Ranked Play in BO6</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The LR 7.62 is the best Sniper in BO6 Ranked Play.</figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Primary: </strong>LR 7.62</li>



<li><strong>Secondary: </strong>Stryder .22</li>



<li><strong>Tactical:</strong> Smoke</li>



<li><strong>Lethal:</strong> Frag</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade:</strong> Trophy System</li>



<li><strong>Perk 1:</strong> Tac Mask</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2:</strong> Fast Hands</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3:</strong> Double Time</li>



<li><strong>Perk 4: </strong>Ninja</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard: </strong>Perk Greed</li>
</ul>



<p>For those who prefer a more precise playstyle, the <strong>LR 7.62</strong> is the Sniper Rifle to use in Black Ops 6 Ranked Play thanks to its consistent one-shot capabilities.</p>



<p>We’ve then gone for Smokes in the Tactical slot to block off angles and prevent enemies from clocking your position from other lanes. </p>



<hr>



<p>Which weapons have you been using in Black Ops 6’s Ranked Play? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>If you want more BO6 guides be sure to check out how to unlock the new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 1</a> weapons – the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-saug-in-black-ops-6-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saug SMG</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-krig-c-in-black-ops-6-and-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kric C Assault Rifle</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>