<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:29:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tarkov’s Snow Disappears as Spring Arrives and Ducks Take Flight]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-update-spring-ducks-patch-notes/</link>
            <guid>1430959</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov’s latest update, 1.0.2, has been deployed and is available to download in full. This patch brings a collaboration with Escape from Duckov, a new spring weather system, and various quality-of-life upgrades, amongst other things.</p>



<p>In the full Escape from Tarkov patch notes, Battlestate Games detailed dozens of fixes and changes, as well as new customization elements for both BEAR and USEC PMCs, and a string of weapon adjustments.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-s-new-in-escape-from-tarkov-patch-notes-explained">What’s New in Escape from Tarkov? Patch Notes Explained</h2>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/escape-from-tarkov/" id="232">Escape from Tarkov</a>‘s latest update adds the Escape from Duckov crossover that has been teased for the last few weeks. Per the <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/news/id/378" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">patch notes</a>:</p>



<ul>
<li>Temporary collaboration event with Escape from Duckov:<br>Players can take part in an in-game duck hunting task in Escape from Tarkov. After completing the task, players will receive a set of exclusive rewards in both PvP and PvE modes</li>
</ul>



<p>Improvements have been added as major changes to Escape from Tarkov in this patch, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>Added Steam Rich Presence support for Steam players, displaying current in-game activity</li>



<li>Improved the game room startup algorithm to reduce game server launch time. We will continue working to speed up and improve matchmaking in future updates</li>



<li>Added a visual effect to optical sight lenses</li>



<li>Improved the grenade throw synchronization to reduce cases of grenade position desync during throws</li>



<li>Improved the AI behavior during looting</li>



<li>Added a new container for posters</li>



<li>Added a chapter switching sound effect in the Story Tasks interface</li>
</ul>



<p>And of course, it’s no longer <strong>winter </strong>in Escape from Tarkov, which means the snow has thawed.</p>



<p>USEC PMCs can be equipped with the Fahrenheit outfit, and BEAR PMCs with the Arktika outfits, both winter-themed clothing items, after purchasing them from either escapefromtarkov.com or via Steam.</p>



<p>Here’s the full breakdown of the balancing changes added with 1.0.2:</p>



<ul>
<li>Reduced the character level requirement for Prestige from 55 to 47</li>



<li>Increased the experience modifier when finishing a raid with the Killed in Action and Missing in Action status from 0.4 to 0.75</li>



<li>Replaced the Pineapple juice craft at Nutrition Unit level 2 with Can of beef stew (Large)</li>



<li>Added the ability to insure night vision goggles</li>



<li>Removed the Found in Raid sledgehammer requirement for dismantling the Defective Wall in the Hideout</li>



<li>Added the ability to store money in the Keycard holder case</li>



<li>Reduced the experience gain for killing bots and bosses in The Labyrinth</li>



<li>Added new loot points at the school building, Rus Post office, Klimov mall, and Cardinal apartment complex on Streets of Tarkov</li>



<li>Added new ammo spawn points on Streets of Tarkov and Reserve</li>



<li>Increased the max ammo stack size for the following calibers: 7.62х25 TT, 9х18 PM, 9х19, 9х21, 4.6х30, 5.7х28, .45 ACP, .357, .50 AE, 5.45х39, 5.56х45, 9х39, .300 BLK, .366 ТКМ, 6.8х51, 7.62х51, .308 ME, .50 BMG, 20/70, 12/70</li>
</ul>



<p>And here are the general fixes added with this patch:</p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed the cases where armor zones on Tagilla’s welding masks and Atomic Defense CQCM mask were ignored, allowing players to receive fatal damage to the “Head, Nape” hitbox</li>



<li>Fixed several visual, culling, and shadow/lighting issues in all locations</li>



<li>Fixed the secure container display and certain inventory operations during raids when the player inspected their character inventory while loading into a local PvE game</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing the game client to freeze after pressing ESC during a raid when automatic memory cleanup was enabled</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where achievement progress could reset after being obtained in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed the cases where the Minotaur’s guards appeared directly in the player’s field of view</li>



<li>Fixed the cause of weapon soft-locks after weapon interactions in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed the inability to list ammo packs on the Flea Market</li>



<li>Fixed the starting task items being granted only after restarting the client in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could encounter a soft-lock after listening to a previously crafted audio tape during a raid</li>



<li>Fixed the incorrect mannequin display after changing the lower clothing in the Gear Rack Hideout zone in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed the construction timer display for the Gear Rack Hideout zone<br>Improved the folding system for built-in iron sights when using reflex and optical sights</li>



<li>Fixed the incorrect display of armbands when using the USEC Day Off and BEAR Vacation customization sets</li>



<li>Fixed the incorrect behavior of the low-frequency filter for certain ambient sounds related to occlusion</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where music was not muted while previewing and selecting character voices in the game settings</li>



<li>Fixed the glass display when viewing through transparent geometry</li>



<li>Fixed the ability to claim rewards for BTR Driver tasks as a Scav</li>



<li>Fixed the known causes of Sniper Scavs teleporting in local PvE raids on Customs in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed the aggressive behavior of RUAF bots on Terminal toward players previously marked as enemies by the Rogues on Lighthouse</li>



<li>Fixed the cases where the BTR gunner could appear outside the BTR</li>



<li>Fixed the missing player preview display on the Overall tab in certain cases</li>



<li>Fixed the incorrect weapon display on the USEC character during character creation</li>



<li>Fixed the ability to interact with signal flare extracts when playing as a Scav<br>Improved and balanced the logic of fog density influence on AI detection systems</li>



<li>Fixed the situations with bots not re-equipping their weapons after looting another weapon</li>



<li>Fixed the issue with Partisan getting stuck in the underbarrel grenade launcher reload animation.</li>
</ul>







<p>Are you excited to get stuck in and uncover everything from the latest Escape from Tarkov update? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/leslie-benzies-leave-ceo-build-a-rocket-boy-mindseye/">Leslie Benzies is ‘on leave’ from BARB</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-update-spring-ducks-patch-notes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Machinery of Oppression Update Details Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-machinery-of-oppression-update-details-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1430920</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Helldivers 2’s Machinery of Oppression update brings the Cyborg Legion back to the game today. </p>



<p>Through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-cyborg-legion-return/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previous trailer</a>, we were informed that the Cyberog Legion will be returning to the game sometime soon. Now, the update details revealed how their return will be and what measures Helldivers can take to avoid casualties. Learn more about the Machinery of Oppression update below: </p>







<h2 id="h-helldivers-2-machinery-of-oppression-update-takes-players-to-cyberstan">Helldivers 2 Machinery of Oppression Update Takes Players to Cyberstan</h2>



<p>As the Automatons have seized the schematics for the Star of Peace, Helldivers have to take the fight to the streets of Cyberstan in the Machinery of Oppression <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2026/02/10/new-helldivers-2-update-out-today/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">update</a>. Players will have to step foot in this bot-infested world and breach their massive factory cities. The Factory Cities feature huge industrial complexes riddled with danger at every turn. </p>



<p>The update introduces a brand-new primary mission: halting the production of additional Cyborgs and compromising the Automaton Defenses. The way to do this is to destroy the factory buildings by building and tearing down statues of war criminals and terrorists. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Helldivers 2 - Machinery of Oppression | PS5 &amp; PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xzxwfxpPPS8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-helldivers-2-update-introduces-3-new-enemy-types">Helldivers 2 Update Introduces 3 New Enemy Types</h2>



<p>The latest Machinery of Oppression Update for Helldivers 2 will bring back an old, familiar threat, the Cyborgs. There are three new enemy types: Agitators who command the Automaton legion in the field and are heavily armoured; Cyborg Radicals that will rush you and fight up close and personal. The last one is the Vox Engine: the Voice of the Cyborg Legion, a war machine armed with dual laser cannons, rockets, laser gatlings, and more. </p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-deaths-will-be-counted-in-the-battle-against-cyberstan">Deaths Will be Counted in the Battle Against Cyberstan </h2>



<p>What’s more, players have to stay alive for as long as possible after this update drops; you can’t go willy-nilly dying each second. A Galactic Reinforcement Counter will be used to count every death in the Battle for Cyberstan. There is a finite number of Helldivers that can be deployed, and if the counter hits zero, then the Helldivers have lost the battle. </p>







<p>In other news, Helldivers 2 has reportedly <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-surpassed-20-million-copies-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold over 20 million copies</a>. What are your thoughts on Helldivers 2 Machinery of Oppression Update? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-update-1-15-0-patch-notes-shared-watch-cold-snap-return-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the ARC Raiders update 1.15.0, adding Shared Watch, Cold Snap return, and more</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-machinery-of-oppression-update-details-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG Mobile Competitive Roadmap Unveiled for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-mobile-competitive-roadmap-2026/</link>
            <guid>1430917</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>KRAFTON and PUBG Mobile Esports have lifted the lid on the 2026 competitive roadmap, uncovering a year of high-stakes tournaments and huge prize pools. As one of the top-tier handheld esports titles, PUBG Mobile enjoys a prestigious roadmap every year, and 2026 promises to be no different.</p>



<p>It all begins with the inaugural season of the PUBG Mobile Global Open. Registration for this event starts this month, and by June, we’ll have the grand finals for this all-new global event. But there’s so much more on the way.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-pubg-mobile-esports-events-revealed-for-2026">All PUBG Mobile Esports Events Revealed for 2026</h2>



<p>In a new press release, the team at KRAFTON unveiled what’s coming to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/pubg-mobile/" id="1716">PUBG Mobile’s</a> esports ecosystem this year.</p>



<p>The PUBG Mobile Global Open kicks off first, with the main event of that tournament circuit taking place in Indonesia. The second season of that circuit will culminate in a major LAN event in Pakistan, and <strong>both </strong>seasons will boast a monumental prize pool worth $500,000.</p>



<p>KRAFTON anticipates more than 200 countries will participate in the ‘Road to PMGO’, attempting to qualify for the new events.</p>



<p>Beyond that, the PUBG Mobile World Cup will land at the Esports World Cup in Riyadh, just as it did last year. This event will feature 32 of the world’s best PUBG Mobile teams, all competing for an enormous prize pool worth $3 million.</p>



<p>That’s not all, as towards the end of the year, the PUBG Mobile Global Championship will unfold, featuring 38 teams and <strong>another </strong>$3 million prize pool. These events and their combined prize pots make PUBG Mobile one of the most lucrative esports games in 2026. It’s a testament to the <strong>value </strong>of mobile esports.</p>



<p>Which PUBG Mobile esports event are you most looking forward to this year? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-vitality-wins-iem-krakow-beat-furia/">Team Vitality won IEM Krakow</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-mobile-competitive-roadmap-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete ARC Raiders Update 1.15.0 Patch Notes—Shared Watch, Cold Snap Return & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-update-1-15-0-patch-notes-shared-watch-cold-snap-return-more/</link>
            <guid>1430914</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A brand new patch for ARC Raiders has arrived, introducing new features like Shared Watch along with content and bug fixes. </p>



<p>We have been hearing a lot about ARC Raiders leading up to the recent update, with the developers confirming that there will be no ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-wont-have-fortnite-skins-protect-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite Skins</a>‘ to protect the game’s vision, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/embark-studios/" id="1161">Embark</a> CEO has also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embark-responds-to-arc-raiders-players-unsatisfied-with-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">responded</a> to the players who are unsatisfied with the roadmap. Now, the latest update is live, and here’s what’s new about it. </p>







<h2 id="h-everything-new-in-arc-raiders-update-1-15-0">Everything New in ARC Raiders Update 1.15.0? </h2>



<p>Starting with all the new additions in ARC Raiders Update 1.15.0, which include Shared Watch, Cold Snap return, and new cosmetics. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-shared-watch-event-launches-tomorrow/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shared Watch</a> is a new event designed for players to team up against machines. The event begins today and runs live until February 24. Players will be rewarded for destroying, assisting, and damaging ARC, while no merits will be earned through PvP encounters. </p>



<p>The Cold Snap map condition is back in rotation of outdoor maps, arriving with Frostbite Damage and the ability to collect Candleberries and throw Snowballs. There are two new cosmetic sets to look forward to with RC Raiders Update 1.15.0: The Vulpine Set and The Slugger Set. Check out all the bug fixes in the patch notes below: </p>



<h2 id="h-all-arc-raiders-update-1-15-0-patch-notes">All ARC Raiders Update 1.15.0 Patch Notes</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Shared Watch</strong>
<ul>
<li>This is an opportunity to team up in the fight against the machines.&nbsp;</li>



<li>The Shared Watch Event starts today and ends on February 24. Players will earn merits from destroying, assisting and damaging ARC and earn rewards. No merits will be earned from PvP encounters. Bring a friend or bring a stranger, but above all, bring enough ammo to make sure the machines notice you first.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Cold Snap Map Condition</strong>
<ul>
<li>Winter is not quite done with the Rust Belt – We are bringing back Cold Snap!</li>



<li>The map condition is back in rotation on outdoor maps with the same mix of risk and reward. Frostbite damage will make your trip topside a short one if you don’t seek shelter, but for those who do brave the tundra – there’s increased loot value at stake!&nbsp;</li>



<li>You can still collect Candleberries, but they are no longer tied to any event. You can also collect, and throw, snowballs! Use them wisely, or don’t.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Cosmetics</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Vulpine set</li>



<li>The Slugger set</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-content-and-bug-fixes-nbsp">Content and Bug Fixes&nbsp;</h3>



<h4>Miscellaneous</h4>



<ul>
<li>Improved instances where players sometimes could not reconnect after disconnecting from a game.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the match start tunnel scene sometimes wasn’t being shown.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where trials’ objective rewards could fail to grant at the end of a round due to a timeout, ensuring partial rewards are awarded when earned.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the end of round screen would sometimes show incorrect merits, XP, and Live Event points.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players’ platform icons would sometimes show incorrectly.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where crafting would sometimes get cancelled.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Utility</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Trailblazer Grenade</strong>
<ul>
<li>The explosions no longer deal damage through walls.</li>



<li>Deals more damage to small enemies but less damage to bigger enemies such as the Leaper and Bastion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<h4>Weapons&nbsp;</h4>



<ul>
<li>Fixed inconsistent weapon cycling when bound to keys other than the mouse wheel; keybinds now swap weapons reliably.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Known Issues</h4>



<ul>
<li>One of the Marco set helmet variants may appear incorrectly in preview and in the menu but will appear correctly in game.</li>



<li>Players may occasionally not receive a skill point as indicated in the result screen. A reboot/playing another round fixes the issue.</li>



<li>‘Purchase Raider Tokens’ page may appear in front of the inbox and profile page when switching between them.</li>



<li>Player animations may appear broken when interrupting a search of the Baron Husk.</li>



<li>Certain containers may be unavailable to be interacted with.</li>



<li>Ziplines placed onto destroyed ARC parts will not appear correctly.</li>



<li>Scrappy “Batting Helmet” and the “Slugger” outfit might not appear correctly in the event preview.</li>



<li>The “Blindsided” achievement may not trigger as intended on the first attempt.</li>
</ul>



<p>The <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/patch-notes-1-15-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">patch notes</a> for the latest update were found on the ARC Raiders website. </p>







<p>What are your thoughts on all the new additions of ARC Raiders Update 1.15.0? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatchs-anran-set-for-redesign-after-community-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Overwatch redesigning ‘Anran’ after community backlash</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-update-1-15-0-patch-notes-shared-watch-cold-snap-return-more/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Takes Two & Split Fiction Director Posts BTS Of New Hazelight Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/it-takes-two-split-fiction-director-posts-bts-of-new-hazelight-game/</link>
            <guid>1430878</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The director of It Takes Two and Split Fiction has posted a behind-the-scenes picture of the next Hazelight title. </p>



<p>During the last interview, the director had <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hazelight-is-already-working-on-its-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that a new Hazelight title was already in development; however, it was still in its early stages, with only 130 pages of ideas ready for the upcoming game’s story. Now, he’s given players another teaser that doesn’t offer any concrete information.</p>







<h2 id="h-hazelight-s-next-game-seems-to-be-progressing-well">Hazelight’s Next Game Seems to be Progressing Well</h2>



<p>The new teaser has informed players that the next Hazelight game has progressed in some way. The director of It Takes Two and Split Fiction, Josef Fares, has posted a new image on <a href="https://x.com/josef_fares/status/2021163743036486041" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) that appears to show the game’s cast wearing full-motion capture outfits, with all their faces covered by Fares’ arm.</p>



<p>The director posted the caption “Next game in the making” with this picture, and Hazelight responded, stating the developers are “back in the kitchen, cookin’ up something really delicious”. They also poked fun at the image and Fares’ pose, stating that they now feature “Strategic Arm Placement Tech”. </p>



<p>Talking about Josef Fares, he also recently confirmed that the “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-movies-first-version-of-the-script-has-been-finalized/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first version of the script</a>” for Split Fiction’s movie adaptation had been shown to him. Fares has also spoken with Sydney Sweeney, who is reportedly playing one of the characters in the movie. The director stated, “She seems pretty chill” and “hyped for the movie.”</p>







<p>What are your thoughts on the behind-the-scenes images posted by It Takes Two and Split Fiction’s director for Hazelight’s next game? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhong-kui-is-cooking-with-new-special-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Science literally and figuratively ‘cooking’ with the latest special video for Black Myth: Zhong Kui</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/it-takes-two-split-fiction-director-posts-bts-of-new-hazelight-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>