<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:55:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Director Talks About Their Involvement With the Upcoming Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-director-talks-about-their-involvement-with-the-upcoming-movie/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-director-talks-about-their-involvement-with-the-upcoming-movie.1080627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-director-talks-about-their-involvement-with-the-upcoming-movie/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Helldivers 2’s creative director has revealed how involved Arrowhead Game Studios will be with the upcoming movie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.vg247.com/helldivers-2-movie-arrowhead-wont-have-final-say" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VG247</a>, Johan Pilestedt recently posted a photo of the Helldivers 2 team having a meal together on <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1877764599409221678" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter). In the comment section of this post, the creative director was asked whether Arrowhead would be involved in the upcoming Helldivers movie’s production. Pilestedt responded, “The short answer is yes. The long answer is that we’ll see.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pilestedt added that Arrowhead Studios are game developers and not “Hollywood people,” so they are unaware of “what it takes to make a movie.” The director concluded by stating, “Therefore, we don’t, and shouldn’t, have the final say” in the production of the upcoming Helldivers movie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For those wondering about the Helldivers movie, the announcement arrived from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-horizon-zero-dawn-and-helldivers-movies-at-ces-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony at CES 2025</a>. During the same event, they announced other adaptations too, such as a live-action movie for Horizon Zero Dawn and an anime adaptation of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-ghost-of-tsushima-anime/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Tsushima: Legends</a>, the online multiplayer experience of Sucker Punch’s 2020 action-adventure game.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Helldivers 2 developers have already begun fleshing out the ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-dev-next-game-concept/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">high concept’ for the team’s next game</a>. Also, the title was Insider Gaming Community’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-is-the-insider-gaming-communitys-best-multiplayer-game-of-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“Best Multiplayer Game” of 2024</a>. How involved do you think Arrowhead should be with the upcoming Helldivers movie?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/titan-quest-2-build-gets-leaked-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new leak revealing Titan Quest 2’s development build</a>,&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titan Quest 2 Build Gets Leaked Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/titan-quest-2-build-gets-leaked-online/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/titan-quest-2-build-gets-leaked-online.1080363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/titan-quest-2-build-gets-leaked-online/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A development build for Titan Quest 2 has been leaked online. </p>



<p>First spotted by <a href="https://en.gamegpu.com/game/v-set-utekla-sborka-titan-quest-2-beta-3-1-for-developers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GameGPU</a>, the build is a beta version of the game from early November. This build, dupped Beta 3.1, doesn’t feature any multiplayer aspects. Rather, it’s deployment was for internal testing of various gameplay features. You can watch some of the leaked gameplay <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVIDMQ_DNYQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">if you’d like</a> should it not be taken offline.</p>



<p>Obviously, it’s not a final build of the game and players should expect changes between what they see and what they’ll get.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to THQ Nordic and developer Grimlore Games for comment on the reported leak. As of publishing, however, no response has been received.</p>



<p>A sequel to 2006’s Titan Quest, fans have been waiting nearly 20 years for the next game in the series. The mythology-themed action RPG <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-titan-quest-2-will-not-feature-pay-to-win-or-loot-box-mechanics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">won’t feature any</a> pay-to-win or loot boxes, according to its developers.</p>



<p>“We do despise this with a passion,” Grimlore Games said. “There will never ever be any monetization mechanic in the game, urging you to spend money on any gameplay-related item to give anybody an advantage.”</p>



<p>Regarding its planned early access release, they added that they want players involved from the start, and for the game to “stand its own ground”.</p>



<p>“We want Titan Quest 2 to stand its own ground within the ARPG genre and we are convinced that there is only one way to pull it off: swarm intelligence,” they said.</p>



<p>Titan Quest 2 is scheduled to launch in sometime in 2025, and will be available for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. An exact release date has yet to be announced. </p>



<p>What do you think of a development build of Titan Quest 2  being leaked? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-appoints-advisors-to-explore-all-company-options/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest developments at Ubisoft</a>&nbsp;and a possible sale and our official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">preview of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2.</a>&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>