<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:00:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Responds To Black Ops 7 AI Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-responds-black-ops-7-ai-claims/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-responds-to-black-ops-7-ai-claims.1354132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-157940">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Activision has responded to claims regarding the use of generative AI to create calling cards in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>



<p>The response comes in the form of an email statement sent to Insider Gaming by an Activision spokesperson. In the statement, which you can read below, the company says that it uses a “variety” of tools, “including AI tools” for their development.</p>







<p><strong>“Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players,”</strong> the statement reads, which was first given to <a href="https://xboxera.com/2025/11/14/activision-responds-on-genai-use-in-black-ops-7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Era</a> before the rep responded to Insider Gaming’s request. <strong>“Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios.”</strong></p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out for more specific clarification as to what assets were generated by AI. Should that get a response, it will be published on Insider-Gaming.com and in the new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gaming-mobile-app-membership-tiers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming App</a>.</p>







<p>What are your thoughts on Activision’s statement regarding the use of AI in Black Ops 7? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-delays-earnings-report-halts-share-trading/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft delaying their earnings report</a>&nbsp;and suspending stock trading just minutes be for it was scheduled to release. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/">
                                Activision Accused of Using Generative AI Art For Black Ops 7 Calling Cards                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has been accused of using generative AI art for assets like calling cards in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-hellrunners-zombie-game-never-made-it/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-hellrunners-zombie-game-never-made-it/">
                                EXCLUSIVE: Dying Light: Hellrunners—The Zombie Game That Never Made It                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Dying Light: Hellrunners would have represented a sudden genre pivot for Techland, but the game never saw the light of day.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-isnt-the-only-horizon-multiplayer-game-coming/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-isnt-the-only-horizon-multiplayer-game-coming/">
                                Horizon Steel Frontiers Isn’t the Only Horizon Multiplayer Game Coming                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Horizon Steel Frontiers isn’t the only multiplayer game coming for the franchise; Guerrilla Games has something in the works as well. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-version-is-still-coming-insider-reveals/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-version-is-still-coming-insider-reveals/">
                                Red Dead Redemption 2 Enhanced Version is Still Coming, Insider Reveals                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The release of Red Dead Redemption’s current-gen port doesn’t ‘negate’ the development of Red Dead Redemption 2’s Enhanced Version. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-responds-black-ops-7-ai-claims/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Accused of Using Generative AI Art For Black Ops 7 Calling Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards.1354081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><strong>Update: </strong>Activision has issued the following statement to Insider Gaming.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em>Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams to create the best gaming experiences possible for our players. Our creative process continues to be led by the talented individuals in our studios.</em></p>
</blockquote>







<hr>



<p><strong>Original: </strong>Activision has been known to use generative AI in Call of Duty in the past, but now there are accusations of it being used in a new way within Call of Duty: Black Ops 7.</p>



<p>Many have taken to social media to show examples of what looks to be generative AI art in Black Ops 7 calling cards.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-possibly-ai-in-black-ops-7">What Is Possibly AI In Black Ops 7?</h2>



<p>First shared by <a href="https://x.com/Kumesicles/status/1988982194916999619" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kume on Twitter</a>, the ones being called out specifically come from challenges like “Over Here Buddy”, “Peekaboo”, “Reeled In”, and more. The cards in question use Studio Ghibli art style, which has been easy to generate in most AI art programs. </p>



<p>The use of AI is disclosed on the game’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3606480/Call_of_Duty_Black_Ops_7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam store page</a>. However, it doesn’t say what was done. Instead, it simply reads, “Our team uses generative AI tools to help develop some in game assets.” So, seeing things like calling cards be, possibly, the work of AI shouldn’t come as <a href="https://x.com/MikeStrawMedia/status/1865107470751834402" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">much of a surprise</a>. That said, it still might not sit well with players. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Activision for comment on the claims. As of publishing, no response has been received, but should one come, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>If that doesn’t bother you, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/black-ops-7-loaded-xbox-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">is available now</a> for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/black-ops-7-amazon-us-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5</a>, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC.  </p>



<p>What do you think of the possibility of generative AI being used for things like calling cards in Black Ops 7? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/after-pivot-ai-first-krafton-voluntary-resignations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Krafton offering employees voluntary resignations</a> just weeks after announcing its pivot to being an “AI first” company. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>



<p><em><strong>NOTE:</strong> Insider Gaming may earn affiliate commission if you purchase items through links on Insider Gaming. Read more about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/privacy-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">affiliate commission here</a>.</em></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-accused-of-using-generative-ai-art-for-black-ops-7-calling-cards/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>