<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:17:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yakuza Kiwami Line Ends With Third Game, New Series Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/yakuza-kiwami-line-ends-with-third-game-new-series-planned/</link>
            <guid>1431601</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-175588">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/studios/ryu-ga-gotoku-studio/" id="96159">RGG</a>‘s Masayoshi Yokoyama has stated that Sega’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/yakuza-kiwami/" id="154859">Yakuza Kiwami</a> series will conclude with the third installment, setting the stage for a new series.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/yakuza-kiwami-3/" id="2971">Yakuza Kiwami 3</a> is set to release on February 12. It is the latest in the line of Kiwami remakes for the Yakuza series. Unfortunately for those looking for more of this style of game, Masayoshi Yokoyama revealed during a recent livestream that the forthcoming game will be the series’ final installment, making way for new games with a different title. The spin-off will not be comparable to the Like A Dragon series either.</p>



<p>“I don’t think it will continue as the ‘Kiwami’ series anymore. I think a different series will begin, and not something like ‘Like A Dragon 9, ‘ but rather a new series on a different line, with a different meaning. This might be something you’ll understand once you play Yakuza Kiwami 3.”</p>



<figure></figure>







<h2 id="h-yakuza-kawami-3-also-comes-bundled-with-dark-ties">Yakuza Kawami 3 Also Comes Bundled With Dark Ties</h2>



<p>In addition to the remake of 2009’s Yakuza 3, this new game also comes with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties/" id="173294">Dark Ties DLC</a>. In this expansion, you will play as the antagonist of Yakuza 3, Yoshitaka Mine. This is a prequel story following Mine as he joins the Yakuza Tojo Clan. </p>



<p>This version is comparable to Sonic x Shadow Generations in that it gives players a choice of which mode to launch first.</p>







<hr>



<p>Are you excited for a new Yakuza line of games? Are you upset that other Yakuza games won’t get the Kiwami treatment? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-matches-and-details-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-matches-and-details-revealed/">
                                WWE 2K26 CM Punk Showcase Matches and Details Revealed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Get ready to take over the career of the “Best in the World” CM Punk in WWE 2K26.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-2-launches-next-week/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-2-launches-next-week/">
                                Battlefield 6 Season 2 Launches Next Week                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlefield 6’s second season officially launches on February 17, and the action is headed to Germany.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvels-spider-man-2-headlining-playstation-plus-game-catalog-in-february-2026/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvels-spider-man-2-headlining-playstation-plus-game-catalog-in-february-2026/">
                                Marvel’s Spider-Man 2 Headlining PlayStation Plus Game Catalog in February 2026                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new report has revealed that Marvel’s Spider-Man 2 is the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog headliner for February 2026. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/directive-8020-release-date-revealed-pre-orders-now-live/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/directive-8020-release-date-revealed-pre-orders-now-live/">
                                Directive 8020 Release Date Revealed, Pre-Orders Now Live                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The first game in the next season of Supermassive Games’ Dark Pictures anthology is now available for pre-order.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/yakuza-kiwami-line-ends-with-third-game-new-series-planned/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K26 CM Punk Showcase Matches and Details Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-matches-and-details-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1431511</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Get ready to take over the career of the “Best in the World” CM Punk in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/wwe-2k26-2/" id="174969">WWE 2K26.</a></p>



<p>Insider Gaming reported several weeks ago that CM Punk, the WWE 2K26 cover star, was planned to be the focal point of this year’s WWE 2K Showcase. Now, 2K has confirmed the news and is giving fans a deep dive into what to expect this year and the different paths to unlock all Showcase content.</p>







<h2 id="h-get-punked-in-wwe-2k26-showcase">Get Punked in WWE 2K26 Showcase</h2>



<p>WWE 2K not only released a written <a href="https://wwe.2k.com/2k26/ringside-report/showcase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ringside Report</a> on the forthcoming mode, but also a new trailer narrated by the current WWE World Heavyweight Champion, who breaks down how players can relive his history in some matches and rewrite it in others.</p>



<p>The mode, taking a page from last year’s Showcase, kicks off with a match from this year’s WrestleMania, putting players in the middle of the action between Seth Rollins, Roman Reigns, and CM Punk. Other historical bouts include John Cena, Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson, The Undertaker, Brock Lesnar, and more. Check out the full list of historical matches below:</p>



<ul>
<li>CM Punk vs. JBL, SummerSlam 2008</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Rey Mysterio, Armageddon 2008</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Randy Orton, WrestleMania 27</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Undertaker, WrestleMania 29</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. John Cena, RAW Feb. 2013</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. The Rock, Elimination Chamber 2013</li>



<li>CM Punk vs Brock Lesnar, SummerSlam 2013</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Drew McIntyre, Bad Blood 2024</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Seth Freakin’ Rollins, RAW Jan. 2025</li>



<li>CM Punk vs. Seth Freakin’ Rollins vs. Roman Reigns, WrestleMania 41</li>
</ul>



<p>There are also three announced “Fantasy Warfare” scenarios. One match sees CM Punk take on Steve Austin. Another sees CM Punk facing off against Eddie Guerrero. The last sees CM Punk teaming up with his wife, AJ Lee, to do battle with The Miz and Maryse. These all take place in a fantasy arena called the “CM Punkvillion.”</p>



<p>Lastly, there are the what-if scenarios. These include matches that ask questions such as “What if CM Punk never left WWE in 2014?” and “What if certain rivalries went differently?”</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ringside Report #2 - Showcase | WWE 2K26" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AXPQL3Gg4OQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<h2>Players Can Choose to Run the Gauntlet Instead</h2>



<p>For anyone who wants to unlock all the content associated with WWE 2K26’s Showcase mode, players can simply run the Gauntlet instead. In this mode, you can choose either CM Punk or AJ Lee and try to beat 20 consecutive opponents. In any case, there is a wealth of content to be unlocked.</p>



<p>Speaking of unlockables, this year’s game introduces a new Ringside Pass system. Learn more about that at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-dev-confident-fans-will-like-new-ringside-pass/" id="175166">this link.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>Are you excited to play through the career of CM Punk in WWE 2K26? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-matches-and-details-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>