<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:48:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Extends Beta Test Due to PlayStation Network Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-extends-beta-test-due-to-playstation-network-outage/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-extends-beta-test-due-to-playstation-network-outage.1104969/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-extends-beta-test-due-to-playstation-network-outage/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds players could not enjoy the recent open beta test 2 over the weekend due to the recent PlayStation Network outage. As compensation, the developers will extend the second week of OBT 2. </p>



<p>The developers had planned to conduct two Open Beta Test 2 sessions, the first between February 6 and 9 and the second between February 13 and 16. However, after the PSN issue hampered the experience during the first week, they decided to extend the second session across all platforms (PlayStation 5, Xbox, and Steam). The extended period for the Monster Hunter Wilds open beta test 2 is “Feb. 13, 7 pm PT / Feb. 14, 3 am GMT – Feb. 17, 6:59 pm PT / Feb. 18, 2:59 am GMT.”&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The developers have <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1888907223285256244" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a> that players will still be eligible for “participation bonuses” during the extended Monster Hunter Wilds beta test. These bonuses will also be available in the full version of the game. The beta test features a new training mode, crossplay, Gypceros, Arkveld, the previously available content, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds’s open beta test 2 was not the only game affected during the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-network-down-worldwide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Network outage</a>. All online games on the platform were rendered unplayable, and players could only access their single-player physical titles. Sony stated that an “operational issue” caused the 20-hour outage, and as compensation, it has provided players with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-gives-reason-for-psn-outage-offers-amends/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">5 days of free PlayStation Plus</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guide</a> on all Monster Hunter Wilds, including the release time, editions, prices, etc. Also, here’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-beta-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how the previous</a> open beta test went. What are your thoughts on Monster Hunter Wilds extending their open beta test 2 due to the PlayStation Network outage?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-section-disney-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Rivals having it’s own section on Disney Plus</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two CEO Talks GTA 6 Not Coming To PC At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch.1104942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Grand Theft Auto (GTA 6) is likely coming to PC, it’s just a matter of when. In a new interview with IGN, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick was asked about the game coming to the platform and the decision to not launch on what he calls an “important part” of the business.</p>



<p>In the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025?utm_source=threads,twitter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">interview</a>, Zelnick says, usually, Take-Two’s strategy has not been to release on all platforms at once. Instead, he says, it would start with a console or two before branching out. With GTA 6, that plan appears to be no different as there is a focus on moving more PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series systems with the game’s release.</p>



<p>“When you have a big title in the market and we have many of them coming, historically that has sold consoles,” Zelnick said while also mentioning that it’s not always the case to not release on all platforms at once. He pointed to Civilization 7 as an example of a full multi-platform release that includes PC and Nintendo Switch.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 Still On Track For 2025: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>Regarding PC launches, specifically, Zelnick says that the company knows how big the market it. According to the Take-Two boss, PC versions of a game can result in up to 40% of a game’s total sales.  It’s not something that’s lost on him.</p>



<p>“We have seen PC become a much more and more important part of what used to be a console business, and I wouldn’t be surprised to see that trend continue,” he said. </p>



<p>GTA 6 is currently scheduled to launch this fall on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. The latest update on the game still being on track  sent Take-Two <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-stock-hits-all-time-high-after-gta-6-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stock to an all-time high</a>.</p>



<p>When do you think GTA 6 will come to PC? Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony turning down the Resistance 4&nbsp;pitch</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is Steam Next Fest 2025 and When Does The Next Fest Sale Start?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-details/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-and-when-does-the-next-fest-sale-start.1104888/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-details/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Steam Next Fest is one of the most exciting events for PC players. It’s an event that lasts more than a week, with developers worldwide (both big and small) bringing their upcoming games to an eager audience. It happens three times a year, and the next Steam Next Fest is set to take place between February and March 2025.</p>



<p>At the Steam Next Fest event, you’ll get your hands on exclusive demos, check out developer livestreams, and offer critical feedback on developing titles, all within Steam.</p>



<p>So, when is Steam Next Fest 2025 and when does the killer sale that accompanies Next Fest kick-off?</p>



<p>Read on to find out.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-steam-next-fest-2025-dates">Steam Next Fest 2025 Dates</h2>



<p><strong>The first Steam Next Fest of 2025 will take place between February 24 and March 3. This is known as the Steam Next Fest: February Edition.</strong> Following that, the second Steam Next Fest 2025 event will land between June 9 – 16. These events will be accompanied by regular sales and other themed, limited-time events.</p>



<p>The third and final Steam Next Fest 2025 event is yet to be revealed, but 2024’s ‘winter edition’ landed in October, so perhaps we’ll see the same thing unravel this year.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-steam-next-fest">What is Steam Next Fest?</h2>



<p>Steam Next Fest is a legendary showcase of some of the most highly anticipated – or unheard of – games on PC. It’s a one-stop-shop for PC gamers worldwide who want to connect with indie developers to find out which hidden gems are being released soon on PC.</p>



<p>Developers both solo and major will prepare exclusive demos and trial products for Steam Next Fest, and many will offer special promotions for those wishlisting or pre-ordering their game during the event.</p>



<p>It’s also a good time to buy games on PC – <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-steam-sale-steam-sale-dates/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Steam Next Fest sale</a> runs parallel to the demo showcase.</p>



<p>From February 24 at 10 AM PST to March 3, you’ll be able to explore hundreds of games, connecting with developers on Steam like never before and offering key feedback on their emerging titles. </p>



<p>The most popular <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-next-fest-june-2024-10-games-you-need-to-check-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Next Fest 2024 games</a> and demos included:</p>



<ul>
<li>Delta Force</li>



<li>Supervive</li>



<li>The Precinct</li>



<li>Sand</li>



<li>Permafrost</li>



<li>Commandos: Origins</li>



<li>Incantation</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-games-at-steam-next-fest-2025">Best Games at Steam Next Fest 2025</h2>



<p>The full suite of games being showcased at the Steam Next Fest 2025 is yet to be revealed. Stop back here when the showcase is live to get the full scope of what’s worth playing at Steam Next Fest: February Edition.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>