<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:44:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Sparking Zero’s 90% of Sales Came From Europe and NA]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-90-of-sales-came-from-europe-and-na/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero%E2%80%99s-90-of-sales-came-from-europe-and-na.1030842/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zeros-90-of-sales-came-from-europe-and-na/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>During the QA Section of Bandai Namco’s latest earnings call, it was revealed that most of the sales for Dragon Ball Sparking Zero came from Europe and North America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fighting/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-saw-outstanding-sales-and-bandai-namco-says-roughly-90-percent-of-that-was-from-european-and-north-american-fans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Games Radar</a>, Bandai Namco <a href="https://www.bandainamco.co.jp/files/ir/financialstatements/pdf/20241106_qa.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">revealed</a> that Dragon Ball Sparking Zero “has been a hit mainly overseas, with sales in Europe and the US accounting for about 90% of the game’s sales” (as translated by Google). The publishers changed their global marketing structure for Japan and North America at the start of this fiscal year. They formed different strategies for approach according to the region they were targeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bandai Namco explained that Sparking Zero’s marketing primarily focused on social media for most regions. However, for specific areas, they also hosted on-ground events.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero is a direct instalment to the iconic Budokai Tenkaichi series, which was dormant for over a decade. The developers have put real thought into the title’s gameplay, and combining that with its spectacular visuals and varying game modes; it has become a recipe for success.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While in early access, the game beat the concurrent numbers of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sparking-zero-tops-all-dragon-ball-games-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Dragon Ball titles and other fighting games on Steam</a>. It also sold over 3 million copies within the first 24 hours. The overall popularity of the title has also <a href="https://www.bandainamco.co.jp/files/ir/financialstatements/pdf/en_20241106_Presentation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">significantly impacted</a> their “Toys and Hobby” businesses, helping them beat “previous forecasts.”&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dfbu3CJS0uY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>If you are new to Sparking Zero, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-attack-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Attack</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-movement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Movement</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-defense-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Defense</a>&nbsp;guides. Also, here are the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-episode-battles-guides-hub/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Episode Battles</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-bonus-battles-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bonus Battles</a> guide hubs. What are your thoughts on Sparking Zero becoming a major hit in Europe and NA? Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-isnt-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Take-Two not being worried about GTA 6’s performance on the Xbox Series S</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp; </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two Isn’t Worried About GTA 6 Series S Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-isnt-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-isn%E2%80%99t-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance.1030818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-isnt-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-67629">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick has stated that he is “not really worried” about GTA 6 running on the Xbox Series S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the latest Take-Two <a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2024/11/06/take-two-interactive-software-ttwo-q2-2025-earning/?irclickid=wQIV77RNJxyKWsB3AWwmhXdXUkCTkgySWUGN2E0&amp;utm_campaign=mpid&amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;irgwc=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">earnings call</a>, Zelnick was asked whether the team was concerned about GTA 6 facing problems on the Xbox Series S, as the title could potentially be one of the most advanced games to date. Zelnick replied that they would continue supporting platforms as long as consumers were on them. “Despite different levels of tech”, the team will “find a way to support platforms”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zelnick said he’s not worried about hardware advancements and doesn’t worry about things he has zero control over. He believes in the audience, and if the audience shows up for their properties, they “have to make sure to be on an array of platforms.” From the looks of it, GTA 6 should be fine on the Xbox Series S. </p>



<p>Zelnick also discussed PCs and how open formats will continue to grow. Take-Two believes the PC platform is “a more and more important part of the console business going forward,” which isn’t a problem to support. Zelnick concluded, “We make the tech work when we can make it work as long as the audience is big enough to make that worthwhile.” GTA 6 does not yet have a release window for PCs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Take-Two has confirmed that GTA 6 and Borderlands 4 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-and-borderlands-4-will-not-release-close-to-each-other/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will not release close to each other</a>. Also, Rockstar once thought ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-age-of-trump-gta-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the age of Trump</a>’ would mess with GTA 6. What are your thoughts on GTA 6 running on the Xbox Series S?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-19-million-players-since-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kojima confirming Death Stranding had 19 million players</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/displate-black-friday-deal/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/displate-black-friday-deal/">Displate Offers Gamers a Sweet Black Friday Deal</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Displate is offering gamers a solid Black Friday deal three weeks early! Get a massive discount when you buy multiple Displates now.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-19-million-players-since-launch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-19-million-players-since-launch/">Hideo Kojima Announces Death Stranding has had 19 Million Players</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hideo Kojima announced that Death Stranding has had 19 million players worldwide, even before the game’s Xbox port was announced.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tests-avoid-concord/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tests-avoid-concord/">PlayStation Will Hold More Tests to Avoid Another Concord Disaster</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>PlayStation intends to conduct more tests to avoid a new Concord disaster. Read our story to learn the company’s next steps.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-65-million-units/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-65-million-units/">PlayStation Has Now Sold 65 Million PlayStation 5 Units</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced that PlayStation has sold 65 Million Units of the PlayStation 5.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Displate Offers Gamers a Sweet Black Friday Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/displate-black-friday-deal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/displate-offers-gamers-a-sweet-black-friday-deal.1030812/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/displate-black-friday-deal/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Displate is known far and wide for printing and providing some of the best gaming collectables in the business. The firm focuses on ‘metal posters’, sheets of durable stainless steel with resilient prints finished in a range of effects, from shimmering colours to 3D textures.</p>



<p>To celebrate Black Friday early, Display is running an exclusive promotion, offering sizeable discounts across the full range of <strong>1.5 million designs</strong>. If you’re a gamer – or you’re buying a Christmas gift for one – you can’t go wrong with a Displate (or several).</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-get-a-displate-discount">Get a Displate Discount</h2>



<p>Displates are well worth the money, but getting them at a discount feels even better.</p>



<p>From today to November 10, you can get 27% off when you buy <strong>two </strong>Displates or 35% off three or more posters. That’s a sizeable saving that’ll accommodate you redesigning your gaming room or setup, or helping to pad out a gamer’s gift pile under the tree this coming holiday season.</p>



<p>Displate offers designs that cover almost every major game franchise on the market. It doesn’t matter if you’re a Fallout fan or a Call of Duty player, or if you’re a Cyberpunk 2077 addict or an Elden Ring nut, there’s something for everyone on Displate. Even the niche titles and genres are accounted for on the site.</p>



<p>It couldn’t be easier to install a Displate, either. They’re attached to surfaces using an innovative magnetic bond that doesn’t damage walls, so they’re perfect for bedrooms, living rooms, offices – wherever you want to put them. </p>



<p>If you’re interested in taking part in the sale, simply <a href="https://displate.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">go to Displate.com</a>, assemble your basket, and use the discount code <strong>BLACK</strong> when prompted.</p>



<p>It’s worth hanging around Displate after you’ve purchased, too – the company often runs limited edition prints and designs that can sometimes boast an exclusive attribute. For instance, when Cyberpunk 2077 partnered with Displate, a range of tech-focused OLED posters were produced on a limited basis.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is Warzone Season 1? Black Ops 6 integration & everything you need to know]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-1-black-ops-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-warzone-season-1-black-ops-6-integration-everything-you-need-to-know.1030767/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-season-1-black-ops-6/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Warzone is set to get a huge overhaul with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 Season 1</a>, as the battle royale takes on Omnimovement, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/area-99-revealed-as-new-resurgence-map-in-warzone-at-codnext-event/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Area 99</a>, and a fresh set of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-black-ops-6-weapons-every-gun-and-how-to-unlock/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guns</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re wondering when the Warzone x <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6</a> Season 1 update is arriving, here are all the details you need.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-warzone-black-ops-6-season-1-release-date">Warzone Black Ops 6 Season 1 release date</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-new-area-99-map-arrives">New Area 99 map arrives</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-black-ops-6-omnimovement-amp-guns-in-warzone">Black Ops 6 Omnimovement &amp; guns in Warzone</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-warzone-ranked-play-arrives-in-season">Warzone Ranked Play arrives in-season</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-looting-changes">Looting changes</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-black-ops-6-progression-carries-over-to-warzone">Black Ops 6 progression carries over to Warzone</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-warzone-black-ops-6-season-1-release-date">Warzone Black Ops 6 Season 1 release date</h2>



<p>Warzone’s first season under Black Ops 6 will begin on <strong>November 14 at around 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET / 6 PM GMT</strong>.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement#Prestige" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">downloadable update</a> brings a plethora of new content to the battle royale as well as Black Ops 6. Warzone Season 1 will include some huge gameplay, UI, and weapon changes too, as the devs aim to bring the battle royale more in line with BO6.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that it will also bring the brand-new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-battle-pass-release-date-season-one-pass-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 Season 1 Battle Pass</a>, which is filled with new weapons, Operators, and other rewards.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-area-99-map-arrives">New Area 99 map arrives</h2>



<p>A <strong>brand-new Resurgence map called Area 99</strong> arrives in Warzone Season 1. Set in the same classified facility as the multiplayer maps <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-nuketown-manniquin-easter-egg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nuketown</a> and Warhead, Area 99 is an ode to the iconic map that first arrived in the original Black Ops.</p>



<p>As well as Area 99, both Urzikstan and Rebirth Island will be returning. That said, it will be a slightly older version of Urzikstan, the version without Superstore.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-omnimovement-amp-guns-in-warzone">Black Ops 6 Omnimovement &amp; guns in Warzone</h2>



<p>Both <strong>Omnimovement and Black Ops 6’s arsenal of weapons</strong> will be brought to Warzone in Season 1. This means players will experience the all-new movement system that allows you to sprint, slide, and dive in every direction, as well as a new set of weapons.</p>



<p>The guns, Perks, and Equipment from Black Ops 6 will be implemented into the battle royale too. This brings the grand total of weaponry in Warzone to 177. This includes the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-weapons-black-ops-6-coming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 new weapons arriving in Black Ops 6 Season 1</a>, such as the Krig C and Saug.</p>



<p>Most of the weapons from previous titles will be unusable since Black Ops 6 weapons will be so dominant, so it’s not like players will be using guns from MW2 or MW3.</p>



<h2 id="h-warzone-ranked-play-arrives-in-season">Warzone Ranked Play arrives in-season</h2>



<p>The devs also announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-ranked-play-coming-to-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ranked Play</a> for Warzone will be <strong>arriving in-season</strong>, which likely means the mid-season update.</p>



<p>It will likely follow a similar format to what has previously been seen in the battle royale and Call of Duty Multiplayer, where players climb Skill Divisions and earn Rank Points by performing well.</p>



<h2 id="h-looting-changes">Looting changes</h2>



<p>Warzone is getting some huge looting changes with the Black Ops 6 integration, as <strong>Backpacks are being removed and the inventory is reverting back to a more classic system</strong>, where there are set slots for your Equipment.</p>



<p><strong>Satchels are also returning</strong>, there will be an Armor Satchel that increases the amount of Armor Plates you can carry, and a Munitions Satchel, which allows you to carry more ammo.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-progression-carries-over-to-warzone">Black Ops 6 progression carries over to Warzone</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-progression-and-prestige-system-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prestige</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-black-ops-6-mastery-camo-in-multiplayer-zombies-warzone-all-camos-listed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mastery Camos system</a> will also make their way into Warzone. Battle royale players will have their <strong>rank reset to their Black Ops 6 level </strong>and will be able to unlock a <strong>new set of Mastery Camos through Warzone</strong>.</p>



<p>Playing and earning XP in Warzone will contribute to your overall level and Prestige progression, allowing you to continue <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-prestige-rewards-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unlocking rewards</a> just like in Multiplayer and Zombies.</p>



<hr>



<p>For all the latest on Warzone and Black Ops 6, sign up for the <a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a> for all the news weekly. If you’re eager for more guides, make sure you also check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-assault-rifles-in-black-ops-6-ranked-best-ar-loadout/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best Assault Rifles to use in BO6</a>, which will likely also be strong in Warzone.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima Announces Death Stranding has had 19 Million Players]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-19-million-players-since-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hideo-kojima-announces-death-stranding-has-had-19-million-players.1030764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-19-million-players-since-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hideo Kojima announced that Death Stranding has had 19 million players worldwide, even before the game’s Xbox port was announced.</p>



<p>The news came from Hideo Kojima’s X account (formerly Twitter), where Kojima said that November 8th marks the fifth anniversary of Death Stranding’s release. During the thank you video, Kojima revealed that the game had sold 19 million units to date.</p>



<p>“We have expanded to various platforms, and currently, the number of porters has reached over 19 million worldwide, for which I am very grateful,” <a href="https://x.com/Kojima_Hideo/status/1854779891046400213">Kojima said</a>.</p>



<p>Kojima’s announcement follows a surprise <span>shadow drop yester</span>day, in which the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-xbox-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Death Stranding Director’s Cut was announced for Xbox</a> and released at a 50% discount. Death Stranding on the Xbox will be published by 505 Games.</p>



<p>Kojima Productions also announced that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-ip/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">company now wholly owns the Death Stranding IP</a>, implying that Death Stranding 2 will also be coming to the Xbox platform in the future. Death Stranding 2 is scheduled to release in 2025 on the PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>That’s not all for the Death Stranding IP, either. Earlier this year, Kojima announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-adaptations-kojima-confirm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Death Stranding has several adaptions in production</a>. </p>



<p>During&nbsp;<a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/hideo-kojima-death-stranding-movie-hollywood-wme-1236157008/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">his interview</a>, Kojima spoke about what the team is building with the Death Stranding IP:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>There are several “Death Stranding” adaptation projects currently underway, but there is a different story I’ve written that’s intended for a movie. But I don’t have the time to direct it, so I won’t.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>What do you think of the success of Death Stranding and the sale of 19 million copies? Join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-in-production-at-warner-bros-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest on the Hogwarts Legacy sequel</a>&nbsp;from Warner Bros. Games. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Has Now Sold 65 Million PlayStation 5 Units]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-65-million-units/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-has-now-sold-65-million-playstation-5-units.1030746/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-65-million-units/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-67573">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Sony has announced that PlayStation has sold 65 Million Units of the PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>The news came via the company’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/er/pdf/24q2_supplement.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Q2 earnings results</a>, which revealed&nbsp;that the company had sold 3.8 million units in its last quarter, bringing the total number of PlayStation 5s sold to 65.5 million. The company reported that the last quarter saw a 29% reduction in PlayStation 5 sales compared to the same quarter the previous year.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, the PlayStation 5 total sales are just behind that of the PlayStation 4, which sold around 67.5 million units, a 2 million unit difference. Earlier this year, PlayStation announced that it expects a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-sales-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">continued decline in its PlayStation 5 sales</a> as the console enters its latter half in the market.</p>



<p>It’s not all doom and gloom, though (if you could argue that anyway), as the company saw its biggest amount of Monthly Active Users for Q2 in its history at 116 million. The company saw 107 million Monthly Active Users during the same period last year.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>During the same earnings call, Sony also announced that PlayStation 5 exclusive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Bot sold 1.5 million units in its first 2 months</a>.</p>



<p>What do you think of the PlayStation 5 sales? Join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-in-production-at-warner-bros-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest on the Hogwarts Legacy sequel</a>&nbsp;from Warner Bros. Games. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-million-units/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-million-units/">Astro Bot Sells 1.5 Million Units 2 Months After Launch</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced that the PlayStation-exclusive Astro Bot has sold 1.5 million units in its first two months.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/macaulay-culkin-joins-cast-fallout-season-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/macaulay-culkin-joins-cast-fallout-season-2/">Macaulay Culkin Joins Cast of Fallout Season 2 As a ‘Crazy Genius’</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>As hype quickly grows for the upcoming Fallout Season 2, new cast members join the fray. Now, it’s time for Macaulay Culkin to step into the wasteland!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-makes-changes-to-how-players-unlock-fighters/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-makes-changes-to-how-players-unlock-fighters/">MultiVersus Makes Changes To How Players Unlock Fighters</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Player First Games has announced a new way for players to unlock fighters in MultiVersus, removing the Fighter Currency system.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/full-details-on-new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-maps-released/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/full-details-on-new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-maps-released/">Full Details on New Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Maps Released</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has released full details on the first batch of new maps coming to Call of  Duty: Black Ops 6 in Season 1.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>