<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 22:44:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Battlefield Portal’ is Returning to The Next Battlefield With Classic Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-portal-return/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98battlefield-portal%E2%80%99-is-returning-to-the-next-battlefield-with-classic-maps.1099155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-portal-return/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Battlefield Portal, which was first introduced into Battlefield 2042 will be returning to the next title, DICE has confirmed.</p>



<p>The news came via the YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KOih6h3VeTE&amp;ab_channel=Flakfire" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Flakfire</a>, who had an early online presentation of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-confirms-battlefield-labs-community-testing-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Labs</a> reveal last week. In Flakfire’s latest video, he said that the developers confirmed the return of Portal, a gamemode which introduces classic maps, weapons, and more into the latest game.</p>



<p>“We had surprising confirming in the briefing that Portal will be making a return with the next Battlefield title,” he said. </p>



<p>“Portal could be one of those slices tested under the Battlefield Labs program,” he theorised. </p>



<p>Battlefield Labs is essentially a Community Test Environment, where players can give feedback of specific features in the next Battlefield game and presumably, future DLC, too.</p>



<p>Flakfire pointed out earlier in the video that those who sign up to the Battlefield Labs program will be under an NDA, whcih presumably will still not stop people from sharing footage and information.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Battlefield Labs: Everything You Need To Know (Plus - Portal Returns?)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KOih6h3VeTE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>While we currently don’t have the name for the next Battlefield title (unless it’s just Battlefield), it has been confirmed that the game will be for current-generation consoles only, meaning it will release on the PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and PC. According to EA, the game will release later this year.</p>



<p>What remains to be seen is the announcement of a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-battle-royale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Battle Royale</a>, which has been in development at Ripple Effect for the past couple of years and was exclusively reported on by Insider Gaming in early 2024.</p>



<p>What do you think of Battlefield Portal making its return in the next Battlefield game? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a> </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review/">our review of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> or <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-learned-from-the-new-battlefield-game-footage/">Everything We Learned From The New Battlefield Game Footage</a><br></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HBO’S The Last of Us Season 2 Will ‘Mess Around’ With The Timeline From The Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-season-2-timeline/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hbo%E2%80%99s-the-last-of-us-season-2-will-%E2%80%98mess-around%E2%80%99-with-the-timeline-from-the-game.1099014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-season-2-timeline/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a new interview with HBO’s The Last Of Us Season 2 showrunners Craig Mazin and Neil Druckmann, it’s been revealed that the timeline will be slightly different from the games source material.</p>



<p>Speaking to <a href="https://ew.com/the-last-of-us-creators-set-stage-dense-episodes-season-2-exclusive-8783868" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Entertainment Weekly</a>, Druckmann said that there’s from “deviations of where we place things” in terms of the shows timeline compared to that of the game because of how a show has its own challenges.</p>



<p>We certainly are going to mess around with time the way it was in the source material, but as Neil said, we messed around in ways that we felt were appropriate for the show,” Mazin continued. </p>



<p>Of course, it’s impossible to know exactly what Mazin and Druckmann are referring to here, but fans familiar with the second game will know that a considerable character death does occur. In theory, it would make sense to keep said character alive for as long as possible, especially because the showrunners want it to continue well past season 3.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Last Of Us Season 2 | April 2025 | Max" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylovT43x3yo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“I think it’s pretty likely that our story will extend past a season 3,” Mazin says. “How far past? I can’t say. And that’s not to say that there are not other stories that could be told, but this story is the one that Neil and I are telling.”</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-last-of-us-season-2-coming-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Last of Us Season 2</a> will have seven episodes, with the showrunners promising “high-calorie, dense episodes.” Mazin went on to say that “each one of these episodes packs quite a wallop. You will not be bored.”</p>



<p>The Last of Us Season 2 is scheduled to release sometime in April 2025, but no exact release date has yet been given.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to the show? What do you think the showrunners did to mess around with the The Last of Us Season 2 timeline?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review/">our review of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>