<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:18:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Mini Crossword Hints Today—Answers For Tuesday, February 24]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-24-hints/</link>
            <guid>1444498</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The NYT Mini Crossword is a popular, quick-to-complete word game to test yourself daily, but some of the puzzles can be difficult to complete.</p>



<p>If you’ve found yourself stuck on today’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nyt-mini/">NYT Mini</a>, Insider Gaming has some helpful hints and all the answers for the NYT Mini Crossword on Monday, 24 February, 2026.</p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of the NYT Mini Crossword. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-play-nyt-mini-crossword">How to Play NYT Mini Crossword</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Daily challenge. Image via NYT</figcaption></figure>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword is available to play on the New York Times Games app or website, but, as of September 2025, a New York Times Game subscription is required.</p>



<p>The NYT Games Subscription is priced at $6.95 per month, but there are introductory offers available for other NYT subscriptions that include games access, which might be worth considering.</p>



<p>Without a Games subscription, access to the NYT Mini Crossword is blocked.</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-mini-crossword-clues-feb-23">NYT Mini Crossword Clues (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are all the clues provided for the NYT Mini Crossword for February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across">Across</h3>



<p>1 – Goosebumps-inducing</p>



<p>6 – Buddy, informally</p>



<p>7 – Rub off, as pencil markings</p>



<p>8 – Enjoys a quiet weekend morning, perhaps</p>



<p>9 – David Szalay novel that won the 2025 Booker Prize</p>



<h3 id="h-down">Down</h3>



<p>1 – Section of a bookcase</p>



<p>2 – Color similar to salmon that’s also named for a sea creature</p>



<p>3 – Leave speechless</p>



<p>4 – Gets out of bed</p>



<p>5 – “Uff-da!”</p>



<h2 id="h-additional-clues-for-nyt-mini-feb-23">Additional Clues For NYT Mini (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are some additional clues to help you solve the NYT Mini Crossword on February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across-0">Across</h3>



<p>1 – 2000’s comedy series, ___ Movie</p>



<p>6 – Marge Simpson’s nickname for her husband</p>



<p>7 – Use the end of a pencil</p>



<p>8 – Lounging about</p>



<p>9 – Meaty part of human body</p>



<h3 id="h-down-0">Down</h3>



<p>1 – Storage platform</p>



<p>2 – Great Barrier Reef builders</p>



<p>3 – Blow away</p>



<p>4 – Batman movie, The Dark Knight ___</p>



<p>5 – Sounds terrible</p>



<h2 id="h-all-nyt-mini-crossword-answers-feb-23">All NYT Mini Crossword Answers (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are all the answers for the NYT Mini Crossword on February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across-1">Across</h3>



<p>1 – SCARY</p>



<p>6 – HOMIE</p>



<p>7 – ERASE</p>



<p>8 – LAZES</p>



<p>9 – FLESH</p>



<h3 id="h-down-1">Down</h3>



<p>1 – SHELF</p>



<p>2 – CORAL</p>



<p>3 – AMAZE</p>



<p>4 – RISES</p>



<p>5 – YEESH</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-game">When is The Next Game?</h2>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword refreshes daily at 10 PM ET on weekdays and Saturdays, and at 6 PM ET on Sundays.</p>



<p>As such, the next NYT Mini Crossword will be available at 7 PM PT/9 PM CT/10 PM ET/3 AM GMT/2 PM AET.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-nyt-mini-crossword">What is The NYT Mini Crossword?</h2>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword was introduced in 2014 as a shorter and quicker-to-complete game to accompany the main New York Times Crossword, which was initially released in 1942.</p>



<p>Until September 2025, the NYT Mini Crossword was free, but it has now been consolidated into a monthly NYT Games Subscription alongside several other popular games.</p>







<hr>



<p>Did you struggle with the NYT Mini Crossword today? Share your thoughts in the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more word games, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hints and answers for today’s Wordle</a>, and find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">clues for today’s Contexto</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-24-hints/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Contexto #1255: Hints & Answer For February 24, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/</link>
            <guid>1444486</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Contexto is a word association game that gives you a new word to guess every single day. With every attempt, the AI algorithm determines how close your guess is to the daily answer based on thematic and contextual similarity.</p>







<p>Sometimes, though, no matter how experienced you are, the word you’re looking for can be incredibly vague and hard to deduce. Luckily for you, this guide is full of hints to give you a helping hand, but make sure you give today’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwipr4zrptGSAxWdREEAHYkSF0kQFnoECAwQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcontexto.me%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw21MfS02qcTAe3-U9GeyYlh&amp;opi=89978449" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Contexto</a>&nbsp;a go if you haven’t already!</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-play-contexto">How To Play Contexto</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Time to guess. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Contexto is incredibly simple to play, but difficult to master. All you have to do is type words into the search bar, and the AI algorithm will tell you how close your word is to the answer.</strong></p>



<p>You’ll know how close your guess is based on the colour of the bar and the number next to it.</p>



<ul>
<li>Red includes guesses with the number 1,501 and above, meaning you’re way off from the secret word.</li>



<li>Orange includes guesses between 301 and 1,500, meaning you’re getting closer, but still some ways off.</li>



<li>Green includes guesses between 1 and 300, meaning you’re on the right track.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-contexto-tips-amp-tricks">Best Contexto Tips &amp; Tricks</h2>



<ul>
<li>Start off using broad terms, then narrow down once you’ve got under the 1,000 mark.</li>



<li>Try using Nouns first, and dip into verbs or adjectives once you’ve discovered the context.</li>



<li>Experiment with random words at times, especially as different forms of a root word can rank differently, such as work and worker.</li>



<li>Guess away, as unlike other word games like Wordle, you aren’t limited to a strict number of attempts.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-starting-words-for-contexto">Best Starting Words For Contexto</h2>



<p><strong>Here are some great starting words to get you going with Contexto:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Thing</li>



<li>Person</li>



<li>Place</li>



<li>Animal</li>



<li>Work</li>



<li>Nature</li>



<li>Game</li>



<li>Concept</li>



<li>Idea</li>



<li>Food</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-contexto-hints-for-today-february-24-2026">Contexto Hints For Today, February 24, 2026</h2>



<p>Without giving away today’s Contexto answer, here are a few helpful hints to get you thinking in the right direction:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;It’s a job or a hobby</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong>&nbsp;Needs a body of water</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;Involves catching fish</li>
</ul>



<p>If they don’t help, then here are the nine closest words, going from tenth to second:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hunter</li>



<li>Bait</li>



<li>Trout</li>



<li>Fishery</li>



<li>Sailor</li>



<li>Boat</li>



<li>Boater</li>



<li>Fish</li>



<li>Angler</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-contexto-answer-for-game-1255-on-february-24-2026">Today’s Contexto Answer For Game #1255 On February 24, 2026</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, and still can’t figure out today’s Contexto answer, then you can find it down below:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> Fisherman</p>



<p>A Fisherman is a person who catches fish for a living or for sport.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-contexto-game-after-1255">When Is The Next Contexto Game After #1255?</h2>



<p><strong>Contexto is updated daily at 12 AM or Midnight in your respective time zone, meaning the next game will start on February 25</strong></p>



<p>The Contexto schedule is very consistent, with a new game releasing at the same time every day.</p>



<hr>



<p>How did you find today’s Contexto? Share your thoughts in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<p>For more daily guides, check out IG’s other word game guides:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-24-989/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-24-989/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NYT Connections</a></li>
</ul>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MOUSE: P.I. For Hire Release Delayed Until April]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mouse-p-i-for-hire-release-delayed-until-april/</link>
            <guid>1444312</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-179213">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>An unfortunate but important update has been shared from the team behind MOUSE: P.I. For Hire.</p>



<p>MOUSE: P.I. For Hire is an upcoming narrative-driven first-person shooter. One of the game’s main elements is its black-and-white art style, inspired by the rubber-hose animation style. MOUSE is one of many projects that entered development once the Steamboat Willie version of Mickey Mouse entered the public domain.</p>



<p>A mini behind-the-scenes documentary was released in October 2025, covering the development of MOUSE. It was shared during the ID@Xbox Fall showcase.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Mouse: P.I. For Hire - Official Deep Dive Documentary | ID@Xbox Fall 2025 Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/163eHZOMbDA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<h2 id="h-mouse-p-i-for-hire-release-date-pushed-back">MOUSE: P.I. For Hire Release Date Pushed Back</h2>



<p>The game was slated for a March 19 release date. However, developer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/fumi-games/" id="3438">Fumi Games</a> and publisher PlaySide have issued a joint statement saying that the game will now be released on April 16. The reason given for the delay is simply a request for extra time to ensure the game’s quality.</p>



<p>“As we approached the final stages of development, we want to ensure that we are taking the extra time and care needed to make MOUSE: P.I. For Hire an experience to remember,” the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2416450?emclan=103582791473604212&amp;emgid=490465653219656390" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">statement read. </a>“We remain unwavering in our goal to deliver you the best game we can, and that will just take an extra few weeks.”</p>







<p>Insider Gaming will continue to provide the latest information on MOUSE: P.I. For Hire as its release date approaches. For more first-person shooters being released in 2026, click <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/big-shooters-releasing-2026-best-fps/">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>How disappointed are you in the delay of MOUSE? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-shuts-down-rumor-of-standalone-zombies-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-shuts-down-rumor-of-standalone-zombies-game/">
                                Call of Duty Shuts Down Rumor of Standalone Zombies Game                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Call of Duty dismisses claims of a separate Zombies release, shutting down the rumor online.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-king-of-meat-shutting-down-just-6-months-after-launch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-king-of-meat-shutting-down-just-6-months-after-launch/">
                                Amazon’s King of Meat Shutting Down Just 6 Months After Launch                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Amazon Games title King of Meat will shut down on April 9, 2026, less than six months after its rough October launch.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-co-creator-thinks-new-ceo-is-there-to-sunset-xbox-brand/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-co-creator-thinks-new-ceo-is-there-to-sunset-xbox-brand/">
                                Xbox Co-Creator Thinks New CEO Is There To Sunset Xbox Brand                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Seamus Blackley, Xbox co-creator, believes the recent changes at Microsoft Gaming are intended to sunset the Xbox brand.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-expands-the-island-with-new-multiplayer-options/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-expands-the-island-with-new-multiplayer-options/">
                                WWE 2K26 Expands The Island With New Multiplayer Options                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>WWE 2K26 upgrades The Island with Triple Threats, Fatal 4-Way matches, MyTAG teams, and more.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/mouse-p-i-for-hire-release-delayed-until-april/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Shuts Down Rumor of Standalone Zombies Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-shuts-down-rumor-of-standalone-zombies-game/</link>
            <guid>1444309</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/games/call-of-duty/" id="3373">Call of Duty</a> team recently shut down a rumor regarding an upcoming game project.</p>



<p>Recently, a “leak” from TheGhostofHope on Twitter claimed that the Call of Duty team was planning to release a standalone Zombies title alongside the standard Call of Duty release. The post also noted that Microsoft hoped Activision would be less attached to annual releases going forward.</p>



<p>However, it appears none of that is true.</p>







<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-team-denies-rumor">Call of Duty Team Denies Rumor</h2>



<p>The Call of Duty Twitter account actively shut down the rumor. Replying to a Dexerto post, they would say that the “rumor factory is working overtime” and that “this ain’t it.”</p>



<div><article><p><span>EXCLUSIVE: Sources indicate to me that the delay on the next Xbox has “hurt” a lot of CODs marketing plans as they wanted Modern Warfare 4 to be a launch title and draw a lot of hype to compete with peoples attention alongside GTA VI.

Because of this delay, the idea of two Call</span></p></article></div>



<p>There you have it. If you were looking forward to a standalone Zombies Call of Duty game, you may have to wait a little longer. This ain’t it, chief.</p>











<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-is-selling-very-well">Call of Duty Black Ops 7 Is Selling Very Well</h2>



<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 was recently listed as the best-selling game of January 2026. That was the second month in a row, as it also claimed the same spot in December 2025. Therefore, things are looking alright for the CoD brand.</p>



<p>They did recently shut down one of their mobile games, however. It was noted that Warzone Mobile will shut down in April. Learn more about that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-to-go-offline-in-two-months/" id="177181">here</a>.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will continue to report the latest gaming news as it breaks.</p>



<hr>



<p>Were you looking forward to the possibility of a standalone Zombies game? Do you wish the franchise would release more than one game per year or perhaps take a year off? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-shuts-down-rumor-of-standalone-zombies-game/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>