<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:46:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our Favorite Xbox 360 Games Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/favorite-xbox-360-games-ever/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/our-favorite-xbox-360-games-ever.1360903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-159474">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The Xbox 360 turns 20 on November 22, and it had many at Insider Gaming thinking about the time spent with Microsoft’s most popular console. From experiencing titles like Grand Theft Auto 5 for the first time to the peak of the Halo franchise, there were no shortage of great games released on the Xbox 360 that went on to become lifelong favorites.</p>



<p>So, some of the staff at Insider Gaming decided to have a little fun and put together lists of their favorite Xbox 360 games. Now, no one is saying these are the best games on the system. These are just the ones everyone had the most fun playing when they came out.</p>







<p>It’s always fun to look back at what was loved. And who knows, maybe there’s a game you might have forgot about that you want to revisit or play for the first time. Check out the staff’s favorites and leave your thoughts in the comments and over in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord.</a></p>



<p>For more Xbox 360 anniversary coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-selling-xbox-360-games-all-time/">best-selling games on the platform.</a></p>



<h2 id="h-insider-gaming-s-favorite-xbox-360-games">Insider Gaming’s Favorite Xbox 360 Games</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Mike</th><th>Grant</th><th>Albert</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Halo 3</td><td>Fallout 3</td><td>Halo 3</td></tr><tr><td>Fable II</td><td>Dead Island</td><td>Perfect Dark Zero</td></tr><tr><td>Gears of War</td><td>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2</td><td>Burnout Paradise</td></tr><tr><td>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2</td><td>Battlefield 3</td><td>Gears of War</td></tr><tr><td>Uno</td><td>Assassin’s Creed II</td><td>Portal 2</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Michael</th><th>Josh</th><th>Erick</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Halo Reach</td><td>Halo Reach</td><td>Red Dead Redemption</td></tr><tr><td>Bioshock</td><td>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2</td><td>Bioshock Infinite</td></tr><tr><td>Mass Effect 2</td><td>Left 4 Dead 2</td><td>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</td></tr><tr><td>Call of Duty: Black Ops 2</td><td>Read Dead Redemption</td><td>Call of Duty: Black Ops</td></tr><tr><td>Red Dead Redemption</td><td>Portal 2</td><td>Forza Horizon</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>Want more Insider Gaming delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today for the free <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-selling-xbox-360-games-all-time/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-selling-xbox-360-games-all-time/">
                                The Best-Selling Xbox 360 Games of All Time                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Xbox 360 is now 20 years old and has seen its share of classics, but what are the best-selling Xbox 360 games of all time?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/love-or-hate-extraction-shooters-wild/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/love-or-hate-extraction-shooters-wild/">
                                Love Them or Hate Them, Extraction Shooters Are Running Wild Right Now                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With the arrival of ARC Raiders, the success of Duckov, and the imminent release of Tarkov, extraction shooters are going nuts right now.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-perfect-extraction-shooter/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-perfect-extraction-shooter/">
                                ARC Raiders is the Perfect Extraction Shooter for Gamers Who Don’t Play Extraction Shooters                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>ARC Raiders is, without any doubt, the best extraction shooter for those totally new to or afraid of the genre. Find out why here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-feature-i-want-back/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-feature-i-want-back/">
                                Battlefield 6 is Great, But There’s Still One Feature I Want Back                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlefield 6 is proving to be the best thing to happen to the series in a decade, but there’s one feature I’m still hurting for.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/favorite-xbox-360-games-ever/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Controversial Kirby Air Riders Bikini Skin Has Already Been Removed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/controversial-kirby-air-riders-bikini-skin-has-already-been-removed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/controversial-kirby-air-riders-bikini-skin-has-already-been-removed.1360834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Kirby Air Riders allows you to customize special skins and sell them for in-game currency. One skin has taken it too far, and the already-infamous bikini skin has been rendered unavailable on the Kirby Air Riders Machine Market.</p>



<p>Sometimes you need to take a step back and realise what you’re saying and typing. But it’s all true: A controversial customizable bikini skin is no longer obtainable in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kirby-air-riders-switch-1-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kirby Air Riders</a>. The humorous but risqué&nbsp;outfit can no longer be bought, and it’s probably a warning to all players that you need to tread carefully with any sus designs.</p>







<h2 id="h-kirby-air-riders-bikini-skin-is-now-unavailable">Kirby Air Riders Bikini Skin Is Now Unavailable</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Family-friendly entertainment, right? Credit to Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>Within 24 hours of the game coming out, users were making eye-opening skins and selling them on the game’s Machine Market. Everything is bought and traded using the game’s currency.</p>



<p>One particular skin went viral very quickly: A design showing Chef Kawasaki wearing a micro-bikini. If you didn’t know, Chef Kawasaki is a regular character in the Kirby universe, and their default getup is usually just some kind of cooking apron.</p>







<p>According to <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chef-kawasaki-micro-bikini-ride-deleted-from-kirby-air-riders-machine-market-immediately-replaced-by-succubus-chef-kawasaki/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton</a>: “Chef Kawasaki&nbsp;wearing a micro&nbsp;bikini has been a running&nbsp;joke&nbsp;among&nbsp;a&nbsp;portion&nbsp;of&nbsp;Japanese Kirby fans for quite a few years.&nbsp;The&nbsp;headcanon&nbsp;seems to have resulted from fans looking at Chef Kawasaki’s standard attire –&nbsp;naked&nbsp;save for a single&nbsp;apron&nbsp;– and thinking, ‘Isn’t that kind of lewd?'”</p>



<p>So, once you give players the appropriate tools, they are sure to create inappropriate outfits. Kirby Air Riders’ technology finally allowed the Chef Kawasaki&nbsp;bikini look to happen.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Have you rinsed your eyes yet? Well, it only took hours for the design to be removed.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It was fun while it lasted, but this dual-wields as both an action and a warning to Kirby Air Riders players: Think twice before putting Chef Kawasaki—or anyone, for that matter—in a micro-bikini and selling it on the Machine Market.</p>



<p>Have you seen any other bizarre or hilarious outfits in the Kirby Air Riders Machine Market? Feel free to share them through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-price-revealed-ahead-of-early-access-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale Price Being Revealed Ahead of Early Access Release</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-new-map-has-secret-breaking-bad-easter-egg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s New Map Having A Secret Breaking Bad Easter Egg</a> for more fun news and content.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/controversial-kirby-air-riders-bikini-skin-has-already-been-removed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>