<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:38:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Devs Tease New Update for 5th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-devs-tease-new-update-for-5th-anniversary/</link>
            <guid>1369477</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Cyberpunk 2077 developers have made a very cryptic post that teases a new update for December 2025, which also falls during the game’s fifth anniversary. </p>



<p>Recently, CD Projekt Red provided us with some information on how they are laying the foundation for Cyberpunk 2, with plans to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cd-projekt-red-adds-50-new-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increase the dev team</a> for the game by a tremendous amount by 2027. However, right now we are looking at the original title, Cyberpunk 2077, which seems to be getting more content 5 years after release. </p>



<h2 id="h-could-cyberpunk-2077-get-update-2-4-in-december-2025">Could Cyberpunk 2077 Get Update 2.4 in December 2025?</h2>



<p>No concrete details were revealed about Cyberpunk 2077’s new update in their latest post on <a href="https://x.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1995500633277755416" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter); however, they did mention some dates in cryptic messages for players to look out for. The new post includes the words “SECURE COMMS CHANNEL ESTABLISHED. STANDBY FOR INCOMING PRIORITY TRANSMISSION…” The post also includes an image of a calendar that lists Cyberpunk 2077 for December 10, Solomon Reed for December 12, and Songbird for December 29. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>SECURE COMMS CHANNEL ESTABLISHED. <br>STANDBY FOR INCOMING PRIORITY TRANSMISSION…</p><p>CYBERPUNK 2077 — 10.12</p><p>REED, SOLOMON — 12.12</p><p>SONG, SO MI — 29.12</p><p>END OF TRANSMISSION. <a href="https://t.co/3PcagdOjlt">pic.twitter.com/3PcagdOjlt</a></p></div>— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1995500633277755416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>There are no other details in the post, and all players can do right now is wait for these dates to find out for sure what the Cyberpunk 2077 devs are cooking up. The game’s fifth anniversary arrives on December 10, 2025, so there’s a chance we’ll learn more on or before that date. Many players have been anticipating the announcement of update 2.4 for Cyberpunk 2077, which might introduce new features and content, and there’s a chance this is it. </p>



<p>In other news, Cyberpunk 2077 recently reached a huge new sales milestone, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-hits-new-sales-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">surpassing 35 million copies sold</a>. Additionally, Cyberpunk 2 could feature <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2-could-feature-online-multiplayer-new-job-listing-suggests/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online multiplayer</a> according to a new job listing. What are your thoughts on Cyberpunk 2077 devs teasing a new update for the game’s fifth anniversary? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-terminal-map-entered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how Escape from Tarkov’s Terminal map has been entered</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-devs-tease-new-update-for-5th-anniversary/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption Remastered PS5, Xbox Series X|S & Nintendo Switch 2 Upgrade Release Date & How To Play]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-remastered-ps5-nintendo-switch-2-xbox-series-xs-upgrade/</link>
            <guid>1369426</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Rockstar Games promised everyone a definitive Red Dead Redemption Remastered upgrade for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch 2 consoles, and the release date is a defining day.</p>



<p>Recency bias would cause most people to pick Red Dead Redemption 2 as their favorite game. But many underestimate the impact and power of the original RDR story and gameplay. Yes, RDR 2 provided substantial upgrades, but the first game still has a certain charm that makes it worth replaying even now.</p>







<p>If RDR is something you want to play or you’ve never tried, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-owners-on-last-gen-consoles-are-eligible-for-free-upgrades/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Red Dead Redemption Remastered upgrade</a> release date for all modern hardware should interest you.</p>



<h2 id="h-red-dead-redemption-remastered-upgrade-release-date">Red Dead Redemption Remastered Upgrade Release Date</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Everything’s here. Credit to Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Red Dead Redemption Remastered Upgrade for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2, and even Netflix, iOS, and Android launches on December 2.</strong></p>



<p>It’s an early Christmas present for all Red Dead Redemption fans. Rockstar Games might be busy with GTA 6, but the team is big enough to handle extra goodies—such as the remastered upgrade.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-play-red-dead-redemption-remastered-upgrade">How To Play Red Dead Redemption Remastered Upgrade</h2>



<p><strong>You need to own a copy of Red Dead Redemption Remastered to experience the free revamp for modern-day consoles and platforms, a <strong>GTA+ subscription,</strong>&nbsp;or download it via PlayStation Plus on December 2.</strong></p>



<p>On the one hand, the upgrade is free. Conversely, it’s only free if you already own Red Dead Redemption Remastered through one of the stated means.</p>



<p>Here’s what Rockstar says about the upgrade:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Current owners on PS4, Nintendo Switch, or the digital backward compatible version on Xbox One will be able to upgrade digitally for free. Anyone who owns the PS4 version can utilize previous PS4 save data to pick up where they left off, and Switch 2 players can continue with their previous save data from the previous Nintendo Switch console.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If you are looking forward to playing the RDR upgrade, it includes the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>60 FPS.</li>



<li>Enhanced image quality.</li>



<li>HDR support enabled.</li>



<li>4K capabilities.</li>



<li>Nintendo Switch 2 owners get DLSS, HDR, mouse controls, and 60 FPS at high resolution.</li>



<li>Undead Nightmare DLC.</li>
</ul>



<p>Have you ever played the original Red Dead Redemption before? Or is this your first time taking a wild walk into the wild west? Discuss all things RDR, GTA 6, and anything else you fancy through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should also check out the latest update on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-version-is-still-coming-insider-reveals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Red Dead Redemption 2 Enhanced Version</a>. Furthermore, if you’re interested in Grand Theft Auto news, you should check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-video-in-development-grand-theft-auto-rockstar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">A Short In-Development Video of GTA 6 Surfacing Online</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-remastered-ps5-nintendo-switch-2-xbox-series-xs-upgrade/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>