<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 15:36:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket Triumphant Light Officially Announced & Ranked Battles Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-triumphant-light-officially-announced-ranked-battles-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-triumphant-light-officially-announced-ranked-battles-confirmed.1120458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-triumphant-light-officially-announced-ranked-battles-confirmed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After being initally leaked, both the new Triumphant Light A2A Set and Ranked Battles have been confirmed to arrive in Pokémon TCG Pocket—and their debut is very soon.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-leak-triumphant-light/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Triumphant Light</a> A2A aptly came to light on Febraury 27 when a leak revealed the new set. The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-presents-february-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February 28 Pokémon Presents</a> presentation confirmed that it’s a brand-new mini-set—like Mythical Island—and features an array of news cards and ex beasts.</p>



<p>If this wasn’t enough, the also-leaked <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-reportedly-adding-ranked-battles-very-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ranked Battle</a> system is also official. It is expected to be a way for Pocket players to flex their best decks in a competitive environment.</p>



<h2 id="h-triumphant-light-amp-ranked-battles-coming-to-pokemon-tcg-pocket">Triumphant Light &amp; Ranked Battles Coming to Pokémon TCG Pocket</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New possibilities await. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>The February 205 Pokémon Presents showcase unveiled a ton of cool content across the company’s vast selection of mobile and console titles. But <a href="https://tcgpocket.pokemon.com/en-us/?pubDate=20250225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a> fans have been hearing murmurs about game-chaning features and content updates for a while now.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-set-a2a-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Set A2A</a> was leaked a while back, and now we’ve seen it all for ourselves. The debut trailer is the usual eye-candy of shiny new cards and special Pokémon that will be hard to get. There’s likely to be new Events, Drops, and more Solo Battles to contend with too.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Ranked Battles will be added to test decks, skill, and as we all know—a bit of luck here and there too! </p>



<p>The showcase didn’t go too deep into the system’s details, but I’d expect a league-based system based on skill ratings like most Ranked Modes. The more matches you win, the higher you ascend up the ranks, the better your rewards are, and the sterner the opposition.</p>



<p>You can check out the full Triumphant Light trailer for yourself right here.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Pokémon TCG Pocket: Triumphant Light | Coming February 28!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/urmBeWH0bxw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>