<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:49:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MachineGames Hints At New Game In Anniversary Post]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/machinegames-new-game-anniversary-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/machinegames-hints-at-new-game-in-anniversary-post.1322149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>MachineGames posted a new 15th anniversary picture and, in it, showcases a new yet-to-be-announced game.</p>



<p>For 15 years, MachineGames has been crafting some of the best action FPS on the market. From the Nazi-killing bloodbath of Wolfenstein to the historic adventures of Indiana Jones, the team are masters of the craft. With last year’s release of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-hands-on-previews/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, fans have been waiting to see what’s next from the studio. Fortunately, we now know it is working on something new, thanks to a new celebratory post.</p>



<h2 id="h-machinegames-15th-anniversary-poster-shows-mysterious-next-game">MachineGames’ 15th Anniversary Poster Shows Mysterious Next Game</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://x.com/machinegames/status/1976685867235164308?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a Twitter/X post</a>, MachineGames revealed a poster celebrating the studio’s 15th anniversary. All of the newest titles, like Wolfenstein: The New Order and Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, are there. However, next to Indy is a blocked off box with a question mark. Seeing as Great Circle was the most recent, it seems MachinesGames is hinting it’s currently working on the studio’s next new title. Furthermore, as it’s on the 15th anniversary poster, we could find out what it is before the end of the year.</p>



<p>As for what the next game could be, it’s likely it’ll be either a new Wolfenstein or Indiana Jones. For Wolfenstein, the team <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/machinegames-new-wolfenstein-tease/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">expressed interest</a> in returning to the series in a recent documentary. With Indiana Jones, the massive success and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">push from Disney</a> may have the team invigorated to pick up his whip sooner than later. Still, it could be an entirely new project or IP, seeing as MachineGames has been doing franchise titles for a bit. Either way, it’s clear the studio is almost ready to share it’s next title and, if it’s anything like the others, it’s one to watch out for.</p>



<p>Are you excited to see what MachineGames’ new title is? What do you hope the new game will be? Wolfenstein? Indiana Jones? Something new for its anniversary? Let us know in the comments, forums, and <a href="https://discord.com/invite/5f4cvU6G" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more on MachineGames, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/harrison-ford-troy-baker-indy-brilliant-job/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harrison Ford’s reaction</a> to Troy Baker’s Indiana Jones and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/quake-tease-machine-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">possible Quake revival</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/machinegames-new-game-anniversary-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>