<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 23:56:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Science Confirms Black Myth: Wukong Journey ‘Won’t End Here’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/game-science-confirms-black-myth-wukong-journey-wont-end-here/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-science-confirms-black-myth-wukong-journey-%E2%80%98won%E2%80%99t-end-here%E2%80%99.1274985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Game Science has dropped a tease at an expansion to the story of Black Myth: Wukong, confirming the Journey to the West is not over.</p>



<p>The title, which was released last year and is finally joining Xbox on August 20, was a breakout success for the studio, with many expecting DLC would be announced at Gamescom.</p>



<p>Instead, the finale of Gamescom Opening Night Live was a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-zhongkui-revealed-at-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal trailer for Black Myth: Zhong Kui</a>, a brand-new title from Game Science that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-black-myth-zhong-kui-a-sequel-to-black-myth-wukong/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">isn’t a sequel to Black Myth: Wukong</a>—but more could be on the horizon.</p>



<h2 id="h-black-myth-wukong-journey-will-continue">Black Myth: Wukong Journey Will Continue</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Time to wait. Image via Game Science</figcaption></figure>



<p>On the <a href="https://www.gamesci.cn/zhongkui" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official website</a> for Black Myth: Zhong Kui, a series of questions and answers were shared about the development of the new title, with one stand-out entry concerning the decision to develop a brand-new game and not create a sequel for Black Myth: Wukong.</p>



<p>Explaining the decision, Game Science stated the aspiration to “take a tentative first step” to “build more game experiences,” “challenge ourselves with bolder features,” and “bring fresh ideas to our world and narrative design.”</p>



<p>The key detail concerning Wukong, however, came right at the end with a message that said: “And to all friends who love Black Myth: Wukong, the westward journey won’t end here.”</p>



<p>It’s not clear whether the story from Wukong will continue in a new title as a direct sequel, or whether DLC is planned for the original title.</p>



<p>If the plan is for a direct sequel, that would likely come after the release of Black Myth: Zhong Kui, which itself is a long way off, considering development is in very early stages and “even Yocar himself has absolutely no idea” when a release will be.</p>



<p>Do you want to see DLC released for Black Myth: Wukong, or are you happy to wait for a direct sequel? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/3347/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Gamescom news, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-gets-gameplay-trailer-at-opening-night-live/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gameplay trailer for Resident Evil Requiem</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/world-of-tanks-2-0-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal for World of Tanks 2.0.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/game-science-confirms-black-myth-wukong-journey-wont-end-here/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>