<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:44:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake 2 has Sold Over 2 Million Copies and is Finally Profitable]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/alan-wake-2-has-sold-over-2-million-copies-and-is-finally-profitable/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-2-has-sold-over-2-million-copies-and-is-finally-profitable.1106628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/alan-wake-2-has-sold-over-2-million-copies-and-is-finally-profitable/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Remedy Entertainment, the creator of Alan Wake 2, released its financial results today, revealing that the game has sold over 2 million units.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remedy revealed what actions it took in the second half of 2024 to help Alan Wake 2 reach the milestone of 2 million copies sold. The developers first released The Lake House expansion in October, which received a positive reception. In addition, players received a physical retail release for Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A few months later, the developers provided a PlayStation 5 Pro update for the game, alongside other updates to improve the game’s quality across all platforms. Lastly, they released a physical Collectors Edition for enthusiasts in partnership with Limited Run Games. Thanks to these actions, Alan Wake 2 enjoyed long-term sales and recouped the costs incurred. Remedy “has started to accrue royalties” from the game’s sales towards the end of 2024.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remedy also outlined <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/releases-and-events/announcements-and-releases/?publicationId=de036915-53b0-4bfc-8564-7ce4872914e5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">its plans</a> for Alan Wake and Control, which are linked through the Remedy Connected Universe. The upcoming games in these franchises will be self-published, and growing and expanding them is the key focus for their future. The developers aim to “be a highly regarded creative studio with sustainable, significant commercial success” by the end of 2030.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, read about Remedy Entertainment’s first multiplayer game, “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainments-first-multiplayer-game-fbc-firebreak-coming-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FBC Firebreak</a>”. Also, the developer took out a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-entertainment-gets-e15-million-loan-from-tencent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">€15 million loan from Tencent</a> last year. What are your thoughts on Alan Wake 2 selling 2 million units?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hunt-showdown-1896-developer-is-laying-off-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hunt: Showdown 1896 developer letting go of 15% of its workforce</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunt: Showdown 1896 Developer is Laying Off 15% of Its Work Force]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hunt-showdown-1896-developer-is-laying-off-employees/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunt-showdown-1896-developer-is-laying-off-15-of-its-work-force.1106607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hunt-showdown-1896-developer-is-laying-off-employees/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hunt: Showdown 1896 developer Crytek announced today that the company will be laying off around 15% of its 400 employees.</p>



<p>Crytek revealed in a post on <a href="https://x.com/Crytek/status/1889623029723885913/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> that it is the latest studio in the industry to lay off employees due to “unfavourable market dynamics.” The developer will lay off around 60 employees across the “development teams and shared services.” The developer also revealed that since the next Crysis game was put on hold in Q3 2024, they are trying to move its workforce to Hunt: Showdown 1896.</p>



<p>Crytek stated that layoffs would be “inevitable” if the company had to move forward. They had already tried reducing costs and “cutting operating expenses,” but to no avail. To help the affected employees, the Hunt: Showdown developer will provide them with “severance packages and career assistance services”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Crytek believes that Hunt Showdown: 1896 offers a “very strong gaming service.” Therefore, they are “fully committed to its operation” and will continue to “expand and evolve” the game with new content. The focus on their engine, Cryengine, will also continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Crytek is the latest studio to lose employees in 2025. We have already seen <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rocksteady</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-holds-more-layoffs-across-multiple-departments/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/unity-cuts-entire-behavior-development-team-as-part-of-new-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Unity</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-layoffs-memo-to-staff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft</a>, and others lay off employees this year, and it seems this trend isn’t going to stop soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What do you think about Crytek’s decision to lay off 15% of its employees?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-ii-black-update-new-game-photo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden II Black receiving photo mode and new game+ in its latest update</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Xbox Exclusive Games Coming to PlayStation & Rumored Releases]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-xbox-exclusive-games-coming-to-playstation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-xbox-exclusive-games-coming-to-playstation-rumored-releases.1106571/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-xbox-exclusive-games-coming-to-playstation/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Xbox and PlayStation’s partnership continues to strengthen. To celebrate this, we’ve compiled a list of every confirmed Xbox game coming to PlayStation and every rumored release potentially in the works.</p>



<p>I didn’t know anything else other than console wars throughout high school. I was (and still kind of am) a PlayStation fan, and there was always a primal urge to defend the brand. As I’ve grown, I’ve seen the error of my ways and learned to appreciate all aspects of gaming. But so have Microsoft and Sony it seems. PlayStation is releasing exclusives on PC, whereas Xbox is bringing its library to everything.</p>



<p>2025 is set to be one of the most unimaginable years yet. A few Xbox-exclusive launches are penciled in for Sony’s PlayStation consoles, and many others are rumored. </p>



<h2 id="h-every-confirmed-xbox-exclusive-coming-to-playstation">Every Confirmed Xbox Exclusive Coming to PlayStation</h2>



<p><strong>These Xbox games are 100% confirmed for PlayStation.</strong> If you own a PlayStation, you can buy and own one of these titles once they finally release. Some you might not have thought possible, but never say never.</p>



<p>Certain titles like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-releases-on-may-15-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DOOM The Dark Ages</a> don’t make this list because they’re not released as Microsoft exclusives. It’s a third-party game from day one, although it is tied to Bethesda and Microsoft. Every game on this list isn’t currently available on PlayStation and is already out on <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB?msockid=18c366288f2166303b0f72118e066724" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox</a>.</p>



<p>We’ll continue to update this list as more shocking announcements are unveiled.</p>



<h3 id="h-forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon 5</h3>



<figure><figcaption>PlayStation inherits a classic arcade-racing series. Credit to Playground Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-period-release-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 5</a> was rumored to be in the pipeline for PlayStation for a while. A Holiday 2024 announcement was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-was-ready-but-delayed-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed</a>, but January 2025 saw a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-5-playstation-5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spring 2025 release</a> confirmed. Racers feel like a dying breed at the moment, and Gran Turismo 7 is coming up to its third birthday.</p>



<p>Forza has always been one of Microsoft’s biggest brands providing authentic simulated racing through Forza Motorsport, and Horizon being the arcade relief. Forza Horizon 5 smashed it when it first came out, so this is a big coupe for the blue brand.</p>



<h3 id="h-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle</h3>



<figure><figcaption>A playable Indiana Jones film. Credit to Bethesda</figcaption></figure>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/will-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-be-on-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PS5 Indiana Jones and The Great Circle</a> launch isn’t exactly a well-kept secret. Since day one of Microsoft’s Bethesda purchase, the gaming community has often wondered which titles are coming to PlayStation. After initially seeming like Xbox would get a ton of exclusives, many are coming to PlayStation after all—and Indiana Jones and The Great Circle is one.</p>



<p>Initially, The Great Circle is a timed exclusive. It came out on Dec. 9, 2024, for Xbox Series X|S and PC. But its PlayStation status was quickly confirmed too. It’s set to be an epic PS5 release in 2025, and the more hands on The Great Circle the better.</p>



<h2 id="h-rumored-xbox-games-coming-to-playstation">Rumored Xbox Games Coming to PlayStation</h2>



<p>More exciting than the confirmed Xbox-exclusive games coming to PlayStation are the ones <strong><em>potentially </em>releasing on PS4 or PS5</strong>. The rumors pipeline is hectic and chaotic, and it makes for exciting reading. As someone who’s missed out on many Xbox exclusives over the years, it might be an amazing time to be a PlayStation fan in 2025 and beyond.</p>



<h3 id="h-age-of-mythology">Age of Mythology</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Not a myth anymore? Credit to Ensemble Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>Jez Corden is one of the gaming industry’s leading insiders. He’s one of the frontrunners when it comes to leaks and rumors, and he’s claimed Age of Mythology is coming to PlayStation at some point in 2025.</p>



<p>The strategy title first came out in 2002, and <em>Age of Mythology: Retold</em> came out 22 years later as a suped-up rerelease with all the expansion packs and it remasters the original from the ground up. It would be a great addition to the PS5 catalog and give real-time strategy fans a new universe to explore.</p>



<h3 id="h-gears-of-war-e-day">Gears of War E-Day</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Make it happen. Credit to The Coalition</figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-coming-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gears of War E-Day coming to PS5 could be surreal</a>. Gears of War was a franchise I was jealous of growing up—not owning an Xbox. It looked cool and brutal, and my Xbox friends all played and basked in its glorious goryness. Using a chainsaw gun to carve up an enemy is the perfect adolescent-enhancing rush anyone could ask for.</p>



<p>E-Day is an upcoming prequel set 14 years before the first mainline entry. It brings beloved characters back together, and I can’t think of a better way to start a Gears of War journey than with a narrative chronicling the pre-origins of Gears of War. With <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-possibly-considering-gears-of-war-playstation-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft considering a Gears of War PlayStation release</a>, I think many would be on board.</p>



<h3 id="h-gears-of-war-collection">Gears of War Collection</h3>



<figure><figcaption>What age are we living in? Credit to The Coalition</figcaption></figure>



<p>Carrying on the Gears of War narrative is a rumored <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-collection-coalition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gears of War Collection</a>. It would be a whole collection featuring remasters of any of Gears of War 1, 2, 3, 4, and Judgement. It would understandably be a big project —presumably from developer The Coalition—and the PS5 would be a likely destination.</p>



<p>As with many entries on this list, it’s speculation and pinches of salt here and there. But don’t be shocked to see at least one older Gears of War title come to PS5.</p>



<h3 id="h-halo-the-master-chief-collection">Halo The Master Chief Collection</h3>



<figure><figcaption>I never thought we’d see the day. Credit to 343 Industries</figcaption></figure>



<p>Leaker NateTheHate claims several <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/at-least-two-xbox-exclusives-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox exclusives are on the way to PlayStation</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a>. Microsoft is spreading the love to everyone at this point. Amongst these rumors is news of the Halo Master Chief Collection heading to PlayStation. Again, the teenage version of myself (and the adult version) can’t wrap my head around this possibility.</p>



<p>Halo was Xbox’s premier franchise for years. Halo 3’s launch was historic and all over the news at the time. Granted, its popularity has waned in recent years (Halo Infinite being a perfect example) and a PlayStation launch could give the series a much-needed shot in the Spartan Armor.</p>



<h3 id="h-senua-s-saga-hellblade-2">Senua’s Saga Hellblade 2</h3>



<figure><figcaption>It would follow in the footsteps of its predecessor. Credit to Ninja Theory</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hellblade 2 carried on Senua’s battle with psychosis in the 9th century. The able-bodied warrior originally debuted as a timed-exclusive on PlayStation and PC, before eventually getting an Xbox port later down the line. The tables most certainly turned with Senua’s Saga Hellblade 2 as it was released on Xbox and PC—not PlayStation.</p>



<p>Now, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hellblade-2-and-gears-of-war-are-also-reportedly-coming-to-playstation-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hellblade 2 is reportedly coming to PlayStation in 2025</a>. Hellblade 2 cost a lot more to develop, and deserves more praise and recognition. A PS5 launch could go a long way to doing this.</p>



<h3 id="h-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</h3>



<figure><figcaption>A casual stroll in the sky. Credit to Microsoft</figcaption></figure>



<p>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 had the hard task of trying to better the outstanding Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. It arrived with a ton of new features and missions, and it was also a Microsoft exclusive. However, PlayStation owners might need to clean off and ready their own cropdusters if gossip is to be believed.</p>



<p>The same Jez Corden report about Age of Mythology and Hellblade 2 also mentions Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Again, there’s no substance regarding a release date or announcement, but a 2025 release of the Xbox game on PS5 a real possibility.</p>



<h3 id="h-starfield">Starfield</h3>



<figure><figcaption>A big occasion. Credit to Bethesda</figcaption></figure>



<p>No, you’re not spacing out, Starfield coming to PS5 might not be a rumor anymore. If you don’t believe us, take it from the mouth of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-ps5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phil Spencer who suggests Starfield is flying to PlayStation 5</a>. Initial suggestions indicated a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-starfield-coming-to-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Starfield PS5</a> release was never going to happen under any circumstances.</p>



<p>When asked about Starfield staying on Xbox, Spencer has an interesting response: “There’s no specific game that I would…This goes back to my redline answer, there’s no reason for me to put a ring fence around any game and say this game will not go to a place that it will find players where we would have business success for us.”</p>



<p>It’s not difficult to read between the lines and get our hopes up for Starfield and PlayStation star-hopping together.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you also finding it hard to accept a world where PlayStation and Xbox finally join forces? If this is only the beginning, which other Xbox exclusives from years gone by do you want to see arrive on PlayStation?</p>



<p>PlayStation exclusives could be making the jump too with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-xbox-release-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy 16 move to Xbox</a> being a major example.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>