<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:52:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fable Release Window Announced at Xbox Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fable-release-window-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/</link>
            <guid>1413547</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fable fans can finally count down to the long-awaited release of the next game in the franchise after the release window was announced during the Xbox Developer Direct on January 22.</p>



<p>Developed by Playground Games, the new Fable is a reboot for the franchise, releasing a whopping 16 years after Fable III, and, after previous delays, a new release window has finally been announced.</p>







<h2 id="h-fable-release-window-announced">Fable Release Window Announced</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fable | Gameplay Teaser | PS5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bpaF1zf8baE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>During Xbox’s January 2026 Developer Direct, Playground Games announced that Fable will be released on Xbox Series X|S and PC in Autumn 2026. As previously announced, Fable will be available day one with an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription.</p>



<p>Additionally, it was confirmed that Fable will be available on PlayStation 5, and the release window will be the same as on other platforms, meaning that PlayStation players won’t have to wait longer for a release, unlike another Playground Games title, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-playstation-5-release-window-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6</a>.</p>



<p>Fable was previously slated for release in 2025, but was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fable-delayed-into-2026-by-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pushed back to a 2026 window in February</a> last year, when Xbox Studios head Craig Duncan said the title was “definitely worth the wait” and is the “most beautifully realized version of Albion” that players have ever seen.</p>



<p>The Fable reboot was officially announced in 2020, though gamers had to wait until 2023 to see the first proper trailer, and it’s been somewhat of a rollercoaster ride since then due to the hefty delay. Finally, though, the end is now in sight.</p>







<hr>



<p>Is Fable one of your most anticipated games in 2026? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out the confirmed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forza-horizon-6-release-date-confirmed-has-4-day-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date and early access details for Forza Horizon 6</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-shares-crash-by-30-after-restructure-news/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft’s share price crashing after restructure news</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fable-release-window-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double Fine Reveals ‘Kiln’ Almost 10 Years After First Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/double-fine-reveal-kiln-10-years-after-announcement/</link>
            <guid>1413505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Double Fine has taken to the (virtual) stage at the Xbox Developer Direct showcase to reveal Kiln, a unique multiplayer, team-based party brawler, <strong>almost a decade </strong>after it was announced. The game first surfaced in 2017, emerging from Double Fine’s ‘Amnesia Fortnight’ event, an annual, two-week game jam that spawns prototype game ideas.</p>



<p>It has remained silent, aside from some prototype images appearing online years ago, until now. During the recent Xbox Dev Direct, Double Fine finally revealed the physics-based, destruction-laden brawler.</p>



<h2 id="h-kiln-ten-years-in-the-making">Kiln – Ten Years in the Making</h2>



<p>If you try to find any information online about Kiln, you’ll find a blurb penned by Double Fine in April 2017:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Kiln is a multiplayer, team-based brawler by Derek Brand with a focus on creating unique player sculpted characters featuring crazy physics-based animation and destruction. In Kiln you play as a Mountain Spirit, supernatural beings forever at war on the summit. You’ll use an ancient pottery wheel to create warrior golems called Vessels, inhabiting them and enabling you to interact with the physical realm to do battle. </p>



<p>Created during the match, extremely diverse character shapes and sizes are possible each exhibiting unique attributes and controls that leverage the possibilities in procedural animation.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was also in 2017 that Double Fine revealed the developers responsible for shaping the early game:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>All of this was <strong>re</strong>shared by Double Fine during today’s announcement.</p>



<p>Today, during the Xbox Developer Direct, we saw how that game has evolved over the last decade. </p>



<p>The trailer opened up with Tim Schafer, the head of the studio at Double Fine, working on some pottery. That’s basically the core concept of Kiln. Players take clay characters and shape them into whatever they can imagine, taking them into destructive environments and smashing each other to pieces.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Kiln | Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/We3DR8w2FNU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>You take your pottery mechanisms, craft ‘pots’, and take those ceramic imaginations into multiplayer battles across entertaining, engaging maps built with the ‘spirit of creativity’.</p>



<p>Double Fine confirmed that Kiln is coming Spring 2026, and a closed beta will come soon.</p>



<p>Do you think Kiln looks like your kind of game? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-was-december-2025s-best-selling-game/">Black Ops 7 was December’s best-selling game</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/double-fine-reveal-kiln-10-years-after-announcement/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>