<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:11:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Monster Hunter Wilds Pre-Order Bonuses & How to Pre-Order]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-monster-hunter-wilds-pre-order-bonuses-how-to-pre-order/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-monster-hunter-wilds-pre-order-bonuses-how-to-pre-order.1108152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-monster-hunter-wilds-pre-order-bonuses-how-to-pre-order/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Having any extra gear in Monster Hunter Wilds can help. Pre-Order Bonuses can help you here, as can your Pre-Order method, and your history with Monster Hunter. Let’s investigate everything we know about Wilds’ Pre-Order Bonuses and how to secure your copy early.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> has already attracted much interest through its open beta. Not like the series needs extra attention given it’s sold millions. Nevertheless, Capcom has drummed up big hype for Monster Hunter Wilds. The extra attention it received to kickstart the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February 2025 Sony State of Play Event</a> was the cherry on the top.</p>



<p>No matter your interest level, you need to know about the game’s Pre-Order content, how to obtain it, and how to get some additional items on top of this.</p>



<h2 id="h-every-monster-hunter-wilds-pre-order-bonus">Every Monster Hunter Wilds Pre-Order Bonus</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Free is good. Credit to Capcom</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You can get the Guild Knight Set Layered Armor and Hope Charm Talisman as Monster Hunter Wilds Pre-Order Bonuses. Also, a Digital Mini Art Book is a PlayStation-exclusive goodie, and there are bonuses for having previous Monster Hunter save files.</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-pre-order-bonus">Pre-Order Bonus</h3>



<p>Securing any Monster Hunter Wilds <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-editions-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">edition</a> through a Pre-Order guarantees you content. The <strong>Guild Knight Set Layered Armor and Hope Charm Talisman</strong> are Pre-Order incentives. The armor speaks for itself, whereas the Hope Charm guarantees you a Talisman to equip.</p>



<h3 id="h-playstation-bonus">PlayStation Bonus</h3>



<p>If you Pre-Order Monster Hunter Wilds through the PlayStation Store, you get a <strong>Digital Mini Art Book</strong>. It becomes available as a standalone piece of software content once active. It has drawings, rough sketches, and all sorts of preliminary concept designs inside.</p>



<h3 id="h-save-files">Save Files</h3>



<p>Having a Monster Hunter World and/or Monster Hunter World Iceborne save file rewards you. Take a look at these specific bonuses below.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Save File</th><th data-align="center">Type of Reward</th><th data-align="center">Bonus</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Armor Set</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Leather</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Weapon</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Acorn Spade</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World</td><td data-align="center">Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">Extra Frame — World</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World Iceborne</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Armor Set</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Duffel</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World Iceborne</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Weapon</td><td data-align="center">Felyne Trekker Peckaxe</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Monster Hunter World Iceborne</td><td data-align="center">Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">Extra Frame — Iceborne</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-to-pre-order-monster-hunter-wilds">How to Pre-Order Monster Hunter Wilds</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Are you keen? Credit to PlayStation</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You can either head to the Monster Hunter Wilds Product information page to choose your Pre-Order, or you can Pre-Order Wilds independently from any applicable retailer.</strong></p>



<p>Pre-Ordering from a retailer comes with several benefits: It can be cheaper, you might have loyalty points with them to redeem against the cost, and you have a physical edition which can eventually be traded in.</p>



<p>But, if you want a digital Pre-Order, learn how to do this here:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to the <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/product/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Wilds Product Page</a>.</li>



<li>Scroll down to the <strong>Select a Platform</strong> section.</li>



<li>Choose <strong>PS5, Xbox Series X|S, or Steam</strong>.</li>



<li>Select your edition.</li>



<li>Press on the store icon for the edition.</li>



<li>Click to Pre-Order Monster Hunter Wilds.</li>



<li>Complete the purchase, and you’ve secured both the game and Pre-Order bonuses!</li>
</ol>



<hr>



<p>I hope this guide was informative and helped you out. Are you looking forward to Monster Hunter Wilds? Is this your first foray into Capcom’s fantastical world of creature slaying?</p>



<p>Keep up to date with the latest Monster Hunter Wilds guides including its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-file-size-how-many-gb-is-it/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">file size</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">requirements</a>, and if it has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-denuvo-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Denuvo</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Has Sold Over 75 Million Units]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-has-sold-over-75-million-units/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-has-sold-over-75-million-units.1108083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-has-sold-over-75-million-units/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>During today’s earnings call, Sony revealed that the PS5 has sold over 75 units in its lifetime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During Sony’s <a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/er/pdf/24q3_supplement.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">earnings call</a> today, the gaming and network services segment was the highlight of the show. PS5 crossed the 75 million milestone by selling 9.5 million units in Q4. PlayStation Networks’ monthly active users were up, too, increasing from 118 million in FY23 Q3 to 129 million in FY24 Q3.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s not all; PS5 and PS4 topped 95.9 million units sold in software, gaining a 6.2 million increase from last year’s 89.7 million. During this time, 11.6 million units of first-party games were sold, which decreased from 12.3 million last year. Moreover, out of the 95.9 million, 74% were full-game digital software downloads, down from last year’s 77%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to PlayStation 5’s growing sales, the current-generation console is just 1.5 million units behind the PS4 in outselling it during the same period. The console manufacturer believes that this number will only increase with the release of first-party games like Ghost of Yotei and third-party games like GTA 6.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/days-gone-remastered-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Days Gone Remastered</a> is coming to PlayStation 5 with Pro and VRR support on April 25. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here’s everything that was announced</a> during PlayStation’s State of Play event yesterday. What are your thoughts on the PS5 selling over 75 million units?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-3-snake-eater-release-date-confirmed-during-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Konami confirming Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater’s release date at State of Play</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>