<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:53:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clive Barker’s Hellraiser Revival HANDS-ON Preview: The Most Disturbing Game I Have Ever Played]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/clive-barkers-hellraiser-revival-hands-on-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clive-barker%E2%80%99s-hellraiser-revival-hands-on-preview-the-most-disturbing-game-i-have-ever-played.1280505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>As visually shocking as the Hellraiser reveal trailer was, I don’t think it could’ve prepared me for the hour-long theater of violence and sadism my poor eyes were going to be subjected to at Gamescom 2025. My Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival preview is not for the faint of heart, but if you can stomach it, there could be a special horror game here.</p>



<p>Let’s start with the most important detail first: I have never consumed one second of Hellraiser media. Never watched a movie, know nothing about the lore, and my only exposure is basic horror knowledge of the Hellraiser character. I think we can label me a Hellraiser noob in this case.</p>



<p>I was very excited to be invited to an exclusive hands-on preview with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-think-saber-interactive-are-teasing-new-hellraiser-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival</a> at Gamescom 2025. This preview will not hold back, folks. If you’re squeamish, get a sick bag on standby.</p>



<h2 id="h-hellraiser-will-raise-blood-pressure-and-anxiety">Hellraiser Will Raise Blood Pressure and Anxiety</h2>



<figure><figcaption>If only you’d seen the things my eyes have. Credit to Saber Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>The first five minutes of the <a href="https://hellraisergame.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival</a> preview demo features graphic nudity, the male and female genitalia, BDSM, extreme mutilation, and images the human mind should only dream of—not see. It’s a continuation of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hellraiser-revival-trailer-revealed-saber-interactive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hellraiser reveal trailer</a>, which shocked audiences on July 22.</p>



<p>It’s not long before I take control of Aidan in this brand-new Hellraiser story (considered canon). Associate game directors Srđan Nedić and Aleksandra Pelivanović made it clear to me that this is the perfect starting point for newcomers. The Genesis Configuration is a legendary device mysteriously activated by Aidan and his girlfriend, Sunny. Hellraiser and his cultist cronies want to know how you activated it and want to harness its power. </p>



<p>Aidan needs to suffer until this happens. You must wrench a hook out of your body, cut away at your stitched-up torso, and pull nails out of your hands. It’s just a casual Saturday night for some. There’s an impressively broad spectrum of horror on display throughout the demo: PT-esque hallways, clever environmental puzzles requiring lateral thinking, chase sequences, jump scares, and the constant dread of psychological torture and mental anxiety.</p>



<p>Oh, I nearly forgot the visual horror—only joking, the shocking images are burned into my retinas. My journey through the Labyrinth is a supreme gut check, which is apt as I lost count of how many entrails I saw. The cultists who inhabit the area are obsessed with art and making people suffer. You venture from room to room, and it becomes a swift game of one-upsmanship.</p>



<p>Each new ‘piece’ features new layers of evisceration, dismemberment, and testing the limits of the human body. It’s even more disturbing when you encounter people who are clearly <em>still alive</em> and are suffering through this. A distinct moment of the demo features a dancing ‘doctor’ cutting up a naked woman strapped helplessly to a vertical surgery table. Her jaw is missing, causing her tongue to flail around like an angry cat’s tail. I eventually have to sneak past the scene—getting close to the massacre in the process—and watch in horror as a pair of hands suddenly fly past me—hers, and she’s still alive.</p>



<h2 id="h-if-you-love-resident-evil-you-ll-love-hellraiser">If You Love Resident Evil, You’ll Love Hellraiser</h2>



<figure><figcaption>This isn’t a Wendy’s, is it? Credit to Saber Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hellraiser turned out to be my most surprising game of Gamescom 2025. I went in with no expectations, and it’s now immediately on my perpetual wanted list. If I had to describe my time with it, I’d liken it to Resident Evil 7 and 8—a proper first-person horror game with puzzles, finding key items, and even in its combat.</p>



<p>This isn’t an Outlast-type of horror journey. You get weapons early on, and you must be cognizant of their types. Certain tools won’t be effective against armored enemies, for instance. Each tool has a degradation meter, so you could easily destroy your weapon without really inflicting any damage. I also got a gun towards the end of my playtime. </p>



<p>The enemy AI was quite smart and was quick to go into cover if I had a gun. They would utilize the surroundings to try and flank me. However, there was nothing I could do against The Chatterer. Some basic research allows me to understand it’s not a new enemy in the Hellraiser universe, but for me, it’s one of the most horrifying figures I’ve come across. Think of Nemesis, but with unnerving chattering teeth, with every coming together of those canines ringing in my ear like hypnotic torture.</p>



<p>Do not sleep on Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival, there’s something horribly cool here. If this Hellraiser preview hasn’t made it clear, you probably won’t want to sleep anyway.</p>



<hr>



<p>I hope you get to see what I saw for yourself. Its palette of violence and vivid imagery is so rare in gaming. You can expect Terrifier levels of gratuitous gore in Clive Barker’s Hellraiser: Revival. If Saber’s new horror game can maintain its consistency throughout the whole runtime, this might not be our first visit to hell.</p>



<hr>



<p>Let me know what you’re most excited for about the game via the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>. What do non-Hellraiser fans need to know or do to prepare themself?</p>



<p>Also, check out even more IG previews coming straight out of Gamescom 2025: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phantom-blade-zero-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phantom Blade Zero</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-voyagers-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LEGO Voyagers</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valor-mortis-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Valor Mortis</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-meat-boy-3d-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Super Meat Boy 3D</a>,&nbsp;and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/clive-barkers-hellraiser-revival-hands-on-preview/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Battlefield 6 Camos Have Leaked, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/first-battlefield-6-camos-have-leaked-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-battlefield-6-camos-have-leaked-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1280436/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>FPS weapon skins is always a divisive topic. Call of Duty’s reputation as a serious military shooter has been increasingly questioned in recent years due to its outlandish camos and Operator skins. Battlefield 6 appears to be curbing this zaniness, and the new BF6 weapon skin leaks suggest this.</p>



<p>Adding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-adding-beavis-butt-head-operators/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Beavis and Butt-Head to Black Ops 6</a> jumped the shark for many CoD fans. The franchise has incorporated anime characters and larger-than-life Kaiju characters such as Godzilla in recent years. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-cod-next-2025-schedule-where-to-watch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Call of Duty</a> fans are becoming disillusioned with the series’ lack of seriousness and self-awareness, and this seems to be something <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/this-made-me-pre-order-battlefield-6-fans-react-to-black-ops-7-gameplay-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6</a> is trying to steer away from.</p>



<h2 id="h-here-s-a-look-at-battlefield-6-weapon-skins">Here’s a Look at Battlefield 6 Weapon Skins</h2>



<figure><figcaption>No floating dragons here, yet. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p>Battlefield 6 devs have already hinted that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-dev-hints-that-game-wont-have-unrealistic-skins-cosmetics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BF6 won’t have unrealistic skins and cosmetics</a>. EA and Battlefield Studios <em>seem </em>to know what the people want.</p>



<p>A new leak from <a href="https://x.com/TheBFWire" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield Wire</a> reveals many Battlefield 6 weapon camos. Honestly, they’re quite normal, and it’s refreshing!</p>



<p>We’ve seen hundreds of camos from FPS games over the years. You’ve likely seen or equipped these skins if you play FPS games like CoD regularly. The Battlefield 6 camo leak shows an assortment of leafy woodland camos, minimalistic makeovers, more artistic and complex designs, and some that resemble classic Call of Duty Digital and Blue Tiger colors.</p>



<div><article><p><span>LEAK: Here are some of the Weapon Camos coming to Battlefield 6

W or L?</span></p></article></div>



<p>This is a leak at the end of the day. Don’t be surprised if some of these don’t make it to the final game. They could be subject to change, as we don’t know at which stage of development these leaked designs come from. So keep this in mind before you start dreaming about your favorite camo.</p>



<p>Are you hoping and praying that Battlefield 6 keeps it on the straight and narrow and doesn’t start throwing in lucrative tie-ins left, right, and center? Let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>There are many hot IG stories here for you. Check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-movement-mechanics-nerfed-by-ea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 movement mechanics being nerfed</a> ahead of the full launch, and the incredible <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-record-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 Open Beta and its record stats.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/first-battlefield-6-camos-have-leaked-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost Soul Aside Team Warns of Spoilers After Physical Copies Release Early]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lost-soul-aside-team-warns-of-spoilers-after-physical-copies-release-early/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-soul-aside-team-warns-of-spoilers-after-physical-copies-release-early.1280427/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It doesn’t seem to happen as often as it used to, but physical copies of games can still occasionally be sent out too early, and players get games several days ahead of launch. This is exactly what’s happened with Lost Soul Aside, and you should be on alert for spoilers, according to the game’s social media team.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lost-soul-aside-release-date-platforms-editions-and-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lost Soul Aside</a> continues the recent trend of pure action games instead of the relentless march toward Soulslike supremacy. The new ARPG is in the same vein as a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phantom-blade-zero-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phantom Blade Zero</a>, and if you’re excited for it, you might want to watch out for spoilers.</p>



<h2 id="h-lost-soul-aside-spoilers-could-be-out-there">Lost Soul Aside Spoilers Could be Out There</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Sworn to secrecy. Credit to Ultizero Games.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Lost Soul Aside doesn’t officially release until August 29. This applies to digital editions and physical launches. However, unlike digital copies, it’s harder to keep a lid on physical pre-orders. Retailers can send out orders early, for example.</p>



<p>The official <a href="https://x.com/Lost_Soul_Aside" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X account</a> for Lost Soul Aside has become aware of this very act happening: “It has been brought to our attention that some people may have gotten their hands on physical copies of Lost Soul Aside. Please do not spoil the game online, out of respect for each other!”</p>



<p>People are always keen to be first to everything. You can bet that YouTube is probably already filled with Lost Soul Aside videos and walkthroughs for content that’s not supposed to be seen by the public eye yet. I won’t check, as I also don’t want the game to be spoiled for me!</p>



<p>I advise you to block and avoid all mentions of ‘Lost Soul Aide’ on social media until the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonys-lost-soul-aside-release-date-delayed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date</a>.</p>



<div><article><p><span>It has been brought to our attention that some people may have gotten their hands on physical copies of Lost Soul Aside.
Please do not spoil the game online, out of respect for each other!</span></p></article></div>



<p>How do you avoid spoilers for upcoming games? Or are you not bothered and are quite happy to get the early leaks before launch? Let me know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tokyo-game-show-2025-lineup/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation announcing its Tokyo Game Show 2025 lineup</a> and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-leak-teases-deadpool-daredevil/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Rivals leak teasing Deadpool and Daredevil</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lost-soul-aside-team-warns-of-spoilers-after-physical-copies-release-early/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>