<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:32:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Set To Buy Warner Bros In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/netflix-set-to-buy-warner-bros-in-2026/</link>
            <guid>1374187</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>After weeks of accepting bids from potential suiters, it’s been announced that Netflix is set to buy Warner Bros. in 2026. The deal is expected to close after Warner Bros. Discovery completes its split into two separate companies.</p>



<p>In a joint <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-to-acquire-warner-bros" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">press release</a> on Friday, it was revealed that Netflix <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netflix-looking-at-buying-warner-bros-discovery/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will be acquiring</a> only the Streaming &amp; Studios side of the split. That means, based on the <a href="https://www.wbd.com/news/warner-bros-discovery-separate-two-leading-media-companies" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">previously announced</a> details, Netflix will own Warner Bros. Games. That means studios like NetherRealm, Rocksteady, TT Games, and Avalanche will likely all soon fall under the Netflix Games umbrella.</p>



<p><strong>“Today’s announcement combines two of the greatest storytelling companies in the world to bring to even more people the entertainment they love to watch the most,”</strong> Warner Bros. Discovery president and CEO David Zaslav said.</p>



<p>Netflix co-CEO Greg Peters added, <strong>“This acquisition will improve our offering and accelerate our business for decades to come. </strong></p>



<p><strong>“With our global reach and proven business model, we can introduce a broader audience to the worlds they create—giving our members more options, attracting more fans to our best-in-class streaming service, strengthening the entire entertainment industry and creating more value for shareholders.”</strong></p>



<p>It’s worth mentioning that, while the deal mentions a full acquisition of Warner Bros., which is set to be the name of the streaming and studios side of the company, there was no mention of the games division in the press release.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Warner Bros. and Netflix for clarification on what the plans are for the gaming division. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story. </p>



<p>What do you think of Netflix owning Warner Bros, including Warner Bros. Games? Leave your thoughts down below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out everything that was announced during <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-show-most-wanted-everything-announced/">Thursday’s PC Gaming Show: Most Wanted</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/netflix-set-to-buy-warner-bros-in-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 is Relaunching Later This Month as ‘SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-arena-reloaded/</link>
            <guid>1374169</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Splitgate developer 1047 Games has announced that Splitgate 2 will be relaunching later this month under the new name SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded. The latest trailer shows that the game isn’t just relaunching with a new name, though, and that 1047 Games has been hard at work listening to community feedback and improving the game in as many areas as possible.</p>



<p>As said in the game’s latest YouTube trailer (see below), the game has seen a significant graphic overhaul, a pullback on the game’s heroes and abilities, and a rebuild of the game from the ground up, taking the best of Splitgate 1 and Splitgate 2 and removing what didn’t work.</p>







<figure><p>
<iframe title="SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded | December 17" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hrcUZ_F7vX8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<div><p>In addition to those changes, SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded now also has player stats, leaderboards, a career system, and a new competitive experience.</p><p>SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded, Josh Watson, also revealed that the game will launch with five new maps, four new weapons, new modes, and more, with “A lot more to share in the coming weeks”.</p></div>



<h2 id="h-splitgate-s-redemption-arc">Splitgate’s Redemption Arc?</h2>



<p>After a horrible launch earlier this year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-developers-say-its-going-back-to-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Splitgate 2 was taken offline back to BETA</a> after the game failed to make a good impression on players and see significant player retention. Splitgate 2’s failed launch was hindered by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-ceo-apologizes-for-sgf-controversy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">controversial comments</a> from 1047 Games CEO Ian Proulx at Summer Games Fest and since then, the game struggled to find any kind of interest from the wider community.</p>



<p>Now, though, 1047 Games seems like it’s started a redemption arc by listening to the community and seemingly keeping Proulx away from the game’s marketing. The YouTube community on the trailer seem to suggest that players are once again interested, which would be a huge turnaround for the developers if they can pull it off.</p>







<p>The game is set to launch as a free-to-play title on December 17th on PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S|X, and PC, with the latest game trailer </p>



<p>Will you be giving SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded a go on December 17th? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more fun news, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-finals-has-a-new-weapon-skin-that-literally-makes-your-gun-cook-toast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The FINALS Adding A New Weapon Skin That Literally Makes Toast</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todd-howard-revealed-what-makes-fallout-special/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Todd Howard Revealing What Makes Fallout Special To Him</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-arena-reloaded/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cast Outs Reveal Trailer Drops, Features Developers From Closed Sony London Studio Team]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cast-outs-reveal-trailer-drops-features-developers-from-closed-sony-london-studio-team/</link>
            <guid>1374166</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Sony’s London Studio is back with fewer staff members and has been rebranded as Twisted Works. The team has revealed Cast Outs, which bears a striking resemblance to London Studio’s canceled game it was working on.</p>



<p>Last May, the unfortunate news broke that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstations-london-studio-has-closed-after-20-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation’s London Studio closed after 20 years</a>. The team primarily focused on games designed around gadgets, such as the EyeToy and PlayStation VR. But Twisted Works is comprised of several London Studio members, and they are working on Cast Outs.</p>







<h2 id="h-london-studio-developers-return-to-finish-what-they-started">London Studio Developers Return To Finish What They Started</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Back, sort of. Credit to Sony</figcaption></figure>



<p>In the wake of London Studio’s 2024 closure, everyone learned of a canceled PS5 game the developer was working on.</p>







<p>An online co-op game, Cast Outs uses fantasy elements in its London setting. You’ll need to embrace the fantastical arts, such as magic and spells. Here’s how Twisted Works described the game:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Cast Outs&nbsp;brings you the pure spectacle of magic where spellcasting hits with the physical impact of a brawler and the immediate kick of a&nbsp;shooter. Dive into the ultimate magical urban battleground where you and your friends can truly cooperate, regardless of skill level. It’s the perfect balance of quick-fix fun and high-octane action, built to be played together.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Much of the footage and elements sound like the studio’s original canceled project. Development must be moving along well, as the studio is already talking about a beta: “We are entering production soon and plan to release an early access beta in early 2027.”</p>



<p>You can see the reveal trailer for yourself.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Cast Outs - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/edd1DvyBB9g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Does it look like something you’d play? Share your thoughts on Cast Outs through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>, and share any fond memories you have of the defunct developer’s previous work.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more fun news, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-finals-has-a-new-weapon-skin-that-literally-makes-your-gun-cook-toast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The FINALS Adding A New Weapon Skin That Literally Makes Toast</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todd-howard-revealed-what-makes-fallout-special/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Todd Howard Revealing What Makes Fallout Special To Him</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cast-outs-reveal-trailer-drops-features-developers-from-closed-sony-london-studio-team/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The FINALS Has A New Weapon Skin That Literally Makes Toast]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-finals-has-a-new-weapon-skin-that-literally-makes-your-gun-cook-toast/</link>
            <guid>1374109</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Everyone, raise your glass and let’s make a toast to The FINALS, as it’s quite literally introduced a weapon skin that makes toast as you’re playing a match.</p>



<p>Just when you think you’ve seen every kind of wacky cosmetic in a live-service shooter, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-finals-current-player-count/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The FINALS</a> comes along and boots all expectations out of the window and into the kitchen—next to your toaster. If the thrill of killing and scoring points doesn’t satiate your appetite, then a new toast-making skin might.</p>







<h2 id="h-the-finals-players-are-toast-thanks-to-new-skin">The FINALS Players Are Toast, Thanks To New Skin</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A real breadwinner. Credit to Embark Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you’ve fallen out of love with the P90 or need a new exercise to use it, Embark might interest you with the new Toast &amp; Roast Skin.</p>



<p>When you want to reload, simply insert bread. Hilariously, the longer you fire the gun and the more you burn through your ammo clip, the more the bread will cook—Ergo, the more it will toast.</p>







<p>Should you suddenly be overcome by full, unadulterated, and unfilmed bullet-spewing menace, barreling through a full clip will completely incinerate your toast: Taking it from a well-toasted snack to a charred mess.</p>



<p>It’s a genius skin, and fits in with the arcadey and kooky nature of The FINALS.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It would look out of place in Call of Duty or Battlefield, that’s for sure. Is it your new favorite skin in The FINALS? If you still play The FINALS, what keeps drawing you in compared to all the other new shooters released in 2025?</p>



<p>As always, please head to the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> to express your thoughts, whether about The FINALS or anything else!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news in the gaming and shooter space, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-most-searched-game-2025-drop-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders Being The Most-Searched Game of 2025, Despite Dropping in October</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/treyarch-pushing-sbmm-in-black-ops-7-due-to-increased-engagement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Treyarch Pushing SBMM In Black Ops 7 Due To “Increased Engagement.”</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-finals-has-a-new-weapon-skin-that-literally-makes-your-gun-cook-toast/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 PS5 Price, Explained—How Much Does It Cost On PlayStation 5?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-ps5-price/</link>
            <guid>1374076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you’re wondering whether a year-old Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 on PS5 still has a high price, you might be in for some turbulence. This guide has details on the game’s full price and the different editions you can pick up.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-release-date-early-access-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 on PS5</a> isn’t a free in-flight meal, far from it. Originally an Xbox and PC title, MSFS 2024 arrives on PS5 with all the updates and content additions that have landed over the last 12-plus months. But don’t think Xbox Game Studios and Microsoft will go easy on you, PlayStation owners.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-much-does-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-ps5-cost">How Much Does Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 PS5 Cost?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Xbox Game Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Standard Edition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 on PS5 has a fairly routine $69.99 or £69.99 price.</strong></p>



<p>No discount, no price reduction, it’s a full-priced port on PlayStation. It is a premium property with a ton of content, though, so it’s worth the price of admission. When you also consider that this is the first entry in the series’ 40-year history to arrive on PlayStation, it’s quite a significant milestone.</p>



<p>Many will see $69.99 as a fair deal. This is only for the Standard Edition, so is the damage much worse for more expensive packages?</p>







<h2 id="h-all-microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-ps5-editions-amp-prices">All Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 PS5 Editions &amp; Prices</h2>



<p><strong>There are four Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 editions for PS5: Standard, Deluxe, Premium Deluxe, and Aviator.</strong></p>



<p>Here’s a quick breakdown of each edition and what it costs. Warning: The later editions get sky-high with their pricing.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">MSFS 2024 Edition</th><th data-align="center">Price</th><th data-align="center">Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Standard Edition</td><td data-align="center">$69.99 or £69.99</td><td data-align="center">-Base game<br>-70 Aircraft<br>-150 Airports</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Deluxe Edition</td><td data-align="center">$99.99 or £99.99</td><td data-align="center">-Base game<br>-Early Access<br>-80 Aircraft<br>-155 Airports</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Premium Deluxe Edition</td><td data-align="center">$129.99 or £129.99</td><td data-align="center">-Base game<br>-Early Access<br>-95 Aircraft<br>-160 Airports</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Aviator Edition</td><td data-align="center">$199.99 or £199.99</td><td data-align="center">-Base game<br>-Early Access<br>-125 Aircraft<br>-160 Airports</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>It’s up to you if you can justify as much as $200 for the PS5 launch of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. What do you think of its pricing? Should it be more reasonable? Is $200 too much for simply adding more vehicles and airports? Feel free to discuss this via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>Also, if you’ve still not got around to playing MSFS 2024 yet, check if you <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Can Play Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 on Xbox Game Pass</a>. Plus, you should also read the fun story about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/euro-truck-simulator-2-new-peak-player-record/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Euro Truck Simulator 2 Hitting A New Player Record 13 Years After Release</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-ps5-price/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Showcase Announced for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-showcase-announced-for-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1374073</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new Monster Hunter Showcase is scheduled for December 8, 2025, featuring the title update 4 for MH Wilds and the latest information on MH Stories 3. </p>



<p>Monster Hunter Wilds was one of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-is-still-2025s-best-selling-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top launches of 2025</a>, but some PC performance issues and content complaints have brought criticism from the community. The developers already confirmed they are working on those issues and have now announced a new showcase that will provide players with details on another free content update for Monster Hunter Wilds and the latest information on their upcoming title, MH Stories 3: Twisted Reflection. </p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-watch-monster-hunter-showcase-on-december-8-2025">How to Watch Monster Hunter Showcase on December 8, 2025?</h2>



<p>Announced through the Monster Hunter <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1996867143057445119" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter), the Monster Hunter Showcase will begin on Monday, December 8, 2025, at 2:00 PM PST. Interested readers can tune in to the live stream on the official <a href="https://t.co/WbntyFTmOM" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Twitch</a> and <a href="https://t.co/KNEebgyzzy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube</a> accounts. The developers have also explicitly stated that “For Monster Hunter Wilds, the event will focus solely on Free Title Update 4.” For Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection, we might get to see new story details or maybe a gameplay deep dive. Players will have to wait to know for sure. </p>



<p>Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection is set to arrive in March 2026 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2. The title is the latest instalment of the RPG series set in Monster Hunter World. Players get to become a rider who can raise and bond with their favourite monsters while exploring a brand new story that involves two countries on a path of destruction and a set of twin Rathalos, a species that was thought to be extinct. Pre-orders for the game went live in October.  </p>







<p>Will you be tuning in for the Monster Hunter Showcase next week? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-most-searched-game-2025-drop-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders becoming the most-searched game of 2024 despite releasing in October</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-showcase-announced-for-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>