<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:36:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite x Cyberpunk Crossover Confirmed by Epic Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-cyberpunk-collaboration/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-x-cyberpunk-crossover-confirmed-by-epic-games.1067913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-cyberpunk-collaboration/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It has been confirmed: Johnny Silverhand and ‘V’ from Cyberpunk 2077 are heading to Fortnite soon. It seems bizarre that a character who was iconic for rebelling against corporations and consumerism would appear in a game like this, but here we are. It hasn’t been confirmed when the characters will arrive in Fortnite, but it should be soon.</p>



<p>In a short teaser uploaded on social media, Epic Games revealed the characters – the female variant of V, and the standard model of Johnny Silverhand, who Keanu Reeves famously played in the 2020 open-world RPG.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-night-city-meet-fortnite">Night City, Meet Fortnite</h2>



<p>This will be the second time that Keanu Reeves has appeared in Fortnite. In 2019, the actor was introduced to the Fortnite universe as John Wick, arguably one of his most famous roles to date, beyond playing Neo in The Matrix franchise.</p>



<p>He’ll surface in Fortnite as Johnny Silverhand, one of the most major characters in Cyberpunk 2077 and the catalyst for the events that unfold throughout the game. Also being added is ‘V’, the game’s protagonist. While neither gender is canonical, Epic Games has opted to include the female variant in the upcoming crossover.</p>



<div><article><p><span>We’re expecting some guests from Night City 🌆 </span></p></article></div>







<p>It’s not yet confirmed what’s coming in the bundle, but we’ve seen snippets online showing Cyberpunk 2077’s ‘Mantis Blade’ weapons as a pickaxe replacement.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/cyberpunkgame/comments/1hjz19e/cyberpunk_x_fortnite_collab_skins_leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a leak on other social media platforms</a>, the character models were reportedly revealed, along with the blades, a back bling, and weapon wraps.</p>



<p>Will you be securing something from the Cyberpunk x Fortnite crossover? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-double-xp-week-event/">a Black Ops 6 Double XP event is inbound</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld’s Feybreak Update Introduces a New Weapon For their  Terraria Collab]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-feybreak-update-introduces-meowmeow-from-terraria/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld%E2%80%99s-feybreak-update-introduces-a-new-weapon-for-their-terraria-collab.1067910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-feybreak-update-introduces-meowmeow-from-terraria/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Palworld’s Feybreak update has arrived with v0.4.11, and it introduces a new weapon called Meowmeow as the first instalment of their Terraria collab. The update also introduces a new island, fresh features, areas, pals, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-palworld-s-meowmeow-is-a-bullet-firing-melee-weapon-nbsp">Palworld’s Meowmeow is a “Bullet Firing Melee Weapon”&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Through the Feybreak update, players can now try out Meowmeow from Terraria in Palworld. This is a “small tease of the collab,” with more to come in 2025. For those wondering, this “Bullet Firing Melee Weapon” is actually a sword that makes cat sounds when you attack. When the player swings the blade, a cat projectile with a rainbow trajectory is thrown at the enemy.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-feybreak-island-new-mechanics-and-more">Feybreak Island, New Mechanics and More</h2>



<p>The next big part of the Palworld update is the Feybreak Island itself, a land filled with new mysteries, challenges and goals. Additionally, there’s a new faction that you need to look for on this island, the Feybreak Warriors. These pesky individuals have taken over the island with the power of their missile battery camp.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The update has also added new mechanics such as Expeditions, Research, Predator Pals, and Bounty NPCs. Players also receive a new raid called Xenolord, where they must defeat a mechanical dragon controlling the Xeno army. There’s also a Random Pal mode that randomises Pal Spawns. You can filter it by region or keep it entirely random for some chaos.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Palworld Feybreak update adds much more content, such as the ability to create new weapons, the addition of new strongholds and stronghold bosses, items, unique skills, player changes, increased cap level, bug fixes, and so on. Check out the full patch notes <a href="https://x.com/Palworld_EN/status/1871017118654923212" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a> to learn about everything new in this update.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Palworld | FEYBREAK Gameplay Trailer | Palnews | Pocketpair" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WS2yS9rO-lI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, Palworld has recently changed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-has-changed-how-pal-spheres-work-in-the-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how Pal Spheres work in the game</a>. Also, here are more details about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-lawsuit-palworld-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo’s Lawsuit against Pocket Pair</a>. What are your thoughts on Palworld’s Feybreak update?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-double-xp-week-event/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 receiving a Double XP event for Christmas</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Double XP Coming For The Holiday Period]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-double-xp-week-event/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-double-xp-coming-for-the-holiday-period.1067892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-double-xp-week-event/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Black Ops 6 is getting a Double XP sweep starting tomorrow, December 24. Although it hasn’t been announced by Treyarch (or any Activision studio), there’s a listing for a Double XP event on the Black Ops 6 menu, and it says it’s starting tomorrow. This will be the latest in a long line of such events that have run since the game dropped in October.</p>



<p>Some could argue that Treyarch has put on <strong>too many </strong>Double XP events, reducing the efficacy of the ‘special period’ that allows players to get more out of their grind. Others have argued that the Double XP events are ‘fixed’ and that they don’t offer the full boost of experience points you’d expect.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-more-xp-incoming">More XP Incoming</h2>



<p>The next Black Ops 6 Double XP event is set to start tomorrow, December 24. That’s per a placeholder on the Black Ops 6 menu – it’s yet to be announced by Activision.</p>



<p>Black Ops 6 has started struggling in recent weeks, ebbing away from the claims that it’s the ‘best Call of Duty game in years’, and that’s mostly because the title is <strong>plagued </strong>with cheaters. It was admitted by the Call of Duty team that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-anti-cheat-not-good-enough/">they ‘missed the mark’</a> with the game’s anti-cheat mechanic, which means it’s hard for anyone to have any faith in the product right now.</p>



<p>To that end, some pro players and streamers have started abandoning Black Ops 6 in favour of other games. Most recently, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-nadeshot/">Nadeshot gave up on streaming</a> Black Ops 6 and relocated to Marvel Rivals.</p>



<p>In any case, Black Ops 6 is getting a new Double XP event from tomorrow, December 24. It comes at a time when many new players – the age-old ‘Christmas noobs’ – will be joining the ecosystem. However, thanks to SBMM – which definitely <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-black-ops-6-have-sbmm-answered/">exists in Black Ops 6</a> – you won’t bump into them unless you’re pretty awful at the game.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sega-subscription-service-claim/">Sega is reportedly sizing up a subscription service</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Could Create a New Game Subscription Service, Report Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sega-subscription-service-claim/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-could-create-a-new-game-subscription-service-report-says.1067889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sega-subscription-service-claim/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A recent report suggested that Sega, the Japanese gaming giant, could produce a standalone game subscription service based on the extensive library it has built up over the years. This would likely see its games withdrawn from similar subscription schemes live today, capitalising on the growth of the operating model.</p>



<p>The gaming world is no stranger to such service. Today, Ubisoft, Electronic Arts, Rockstar Games, PlayStation, and Xbox all offer gaming-based subscription programs.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-undisclosed">Undisclosed</h2>



<p>In a recent interview <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/ckgnj7e8028o" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">with the BBC</a>, Sega’s president, Shuji Utsumi, explained:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We’re thinking something – and discussing something – we cannot disclose right now.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He was talking about subscription-based products, and reportedly mentioned that they’re ‘very interesting’ and that Sega is ‘evaluating some opportunities’.</p>



<p>These days, the average gamer is surrounded by subscription-based schemes, and the rise of the live-service game has meant that we’re all putting money into a pot every few weeks over a long period, rather than paying for something once and then never again.</p>



<p>It’s one of the most common operating models in the gaming world right now.</p>



<p>Between Xbox Game Pass and PlayStation Plus, some 80 million gamers worldwide are subscribed to a service that delivers free games every month and gives them access to repositories filled with games both old and new. </p>



<p>Ubisoft has a service that operates in much the same way, as does Electronic Arts with EA Play.</p>



<p>Sega entering the subscription market might not be the move everyone had on their cards, but why shouldn’t it? It’s free game and the market is wide open for such schemes right now.</p>



<p>Sega has been running since the 1960s, and in the 1990s, it really dominated the gaming industry. There are <strong>a lot </strong>of classic franchises sitting in that Sega library that would flesh out a subscription service quite nicely.</p>



<p>What do you think? Would you pay for a Sega subscription service? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/">more Indiana Jones games could be in development</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Indiana Jones Games Are Reportedly in Development]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-indiana-jones-games-are-reportedly-in-development.1067886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-75583">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>A reputable movie insider has said that more Indiana Jones games are in development.</p>



<p>That’s according to DanielRPK, who <a href="https://x.com/DanielRPK/status/1870926309842473117?t=nxgc-3ez5wVn75-3JoS6Hg&amp;s=09" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">tweeted</a>, “Looks like we’re getting more Indy games.”</p>



<p>While there isn’t much to go on at face value, DanielRPK has had a knack for getting some tidbits from movies and games over the years, so his comment should suggest that some projects could have been greenlit behind the scenes.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, it’s only been two weeks since the Indiana Jones and The Great Circle released, so whether or not the game’s positive reception and/or sales led to more games being approved remains to be seen.</p>



<p>One thing is for sure, though – if the games were approved recently, we’re likely several years away from seeing another released.</p>



<p>The game description for Indiana Jones and The Great Circle reads, “Uncover one of history’s greatest mysteries in Indiana Jones and the Great Circle™, a first-person, single-player adventure set between the events of Raiders of the Lost Ark™ and The Last Crusade™. Get ready to don your fedora and whip as you step into the shoes of the legendary archaeologist — Indiana Jones™. Embark on an epic globetrotting adventure in a race against enemy forces to uncover the secrets of the mysterious Great Circle.”</p>



<p>Are you excited for more Indiana Jones games? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/glen-schofield-dead-space-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Glen Schofield Says EA Turned Down Dead Space 4 Earlier This Year<br></a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-major-fallout-4-faction-ranked/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-major-fallout-4-faction-ranked/">Every Major Fallout 4 Faction, Ranked</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fallout 4 is timeless, as are its factions. In this list, we’re seeing every major Fallout 4 faction, ranked. Where does your favourite group sit?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-easiest-platinum-trophies-of-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-easiest-platinum-trophies-of-2024/">The Easiest Platinum Trophies of 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Find out which are the easiest games to platinum this year</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-far-cry-games-ranked/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-far-cry-games-ranked/">All Far Cry Games, Ranked Worst to Best</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In this list, we’ve ranked all the Far Cry games from worst to best. Where does your favourite game sit in the list? Find out now.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/10-best-dlcs-ever-released/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/10-best-dlcs-ever-released/">10 Best DLCs Ever Released</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Check out our list of the best DLCs ever in gaming history. Does your favourite expansion make the cut? Find out here and now.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Major Fallout 4 Faction, Ranked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/every-major-fallout-4-faction-ranked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-major-fallout-4-faction-ranked.1067862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/every-major-fallout-4-faction-ranked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fallout 4 has some fantastic factions that make up the backbone of the game itself – without them, there would essentially be no story for the player to experience. However, there’s a point of contention within the community as to which Fallout 4 faction is ‘the best’. It’s mostly a subjective debate, but in this list, we’re seeing every major Fallout 4 faction ranked from worst to best. </p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-ranking-fallout-4-s-factions">Ranking Fallout 4’s Factions</h2>



<p>Out of all the Fallout 4 factions, we’ve zeroed in on the ‘main’ groups that contribute the most to the story, so don’t be disappointed if your all-time favourite fringe faction doesn’t make the cut. Leave a comment stressing who you think should make the list and we’ll consider adding it!</p>



<p>Here we go – every major Fallout 4 faction, ranked <strong>from worst to best</strong>.</p>



<h3 id="h-4-the-railroad-worst">4. The Railroad (Worst)</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>The Railroad might have some admirable goals in mind, but this basement-dwelling, secretive organisation that distrusts the player from the word ‘go’ is typically left standing in the nuclear dust in Fallout 4. They only care about helping synths, and that’s a huge sticking point for much of the Commonwealth. </p>



<p>There’s a sweet bonus in the ‘Ballistic Fiber’ mod you can unlock for siding with The Railroad, but it’s enough to save the faction.</p>







<h3 id="h-3-the-institute">3. The Institute</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>The Institute – arguably the most important Fallout 4 faction because of where it fits into the story, but it’s called ‘The Boogeyman of the Commonwealth’ for a reason. It terrifies people, and some of the experiments it carries out are nothing short of abhorrent. With that being said, the whole ‘preservation of science and rebuilding the world’ bit is positive and a huge redeemer for the faction.</p>



<p>There’s a huge amount of work needed in The Institute’s PR department, but the upkeep of a hyper-clean, flawless scientific facility some 200 years after the nuclear apocalypse is something that can’t be discredited.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Honourable Mention: Gunners</em></strong></h3>



<p><em>In Fallout 4, the Gunners are akin to the Raiders, but they’re more military-based in their appearance and how they operate, and they facilitate the backstory of one of the game’s best companions, MacCready. They often pair up with the likes of Assaultrons and bring the force of a well-trained unit to any fight.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-2-brotherhood-of-steel">2. Brotherhood of Steel</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>The Brotherhood of Steel is easily the most recognisable Fallout 4 faction – it’s probably the most iconic faction from the franchise, period. In Fallout 4, the Brotherhood of Steel ‘chapter’ that arrives to shape up Boston is unfortunately quite bigoted and fascist-like in how it goes about its mission, but there’s something valiant about wanting to rid an entire region of mutated, cannibalistic, and intensely violent creatures, right?</p>



<p>As a special mention, it’s worth stressing that their arrival in the Commonwealth Wasteland is one of the most epic moments in Fallout history.</p>



<h6 id="h-related-10-most-iconic-brands-from-fallout"><strong>Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/10-most-iconic-brands-from-fallout/">10 Most Iconic Brands From Fallout</a></strong></h6>



<h3 id="h-honourable-mention-atom-cats"><em>Honourable Mention: Atom Cats</em></h3>



<p><em>No Fallout 4 faction is cooler than the Atom Cats. They’re a real live bunch, you dig? With their customised suits of power armour and their ‘Greased Lightning’ vibe, they’re instantly likeable and probably way more chilled out than they should be, given their surroundings.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-1-minutemen-best">1. Minutemen (Best)</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>As we see every major Fallout 4 faction ranked, we can’t help but list the Minutemen at the top of the pile. This selfless faction exists to unite settlements across the Wasteland, pulling together with community spirit and ensuring that everyone has a voice – and a home. There’s no sinister sub-plot, no underlying regime – it’s just regular folks trying to get by and share what they have with those that need it.</p>



<p>Out of every major Fallout 4 faction, the Minutemen are deserving of the top spot. They might not boast vertibirds or next-generation scientific technology, but they’re decent people, and they’re triers, and that’s all that matters. </p>



<h6 id="h-read-next-we-know-who-fired-first-in-fallout"><strong>Read Next: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-first-nukes/">We Know Who Fired First in Fallout</a></strong></h6>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Glen Schofield Says EA Turned Down Dead Space 4 Earlier This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/glen-schofield-dead-space-4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/glen-schofield-says-ea-turned-down-dead-space-4-earlier-this-year.1067847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/glen-schofield-dead-space-4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dead Space creator Glen Schofield has said that the team tried to pitch Dead Space 4 earlier this year, but the publisher was not interested.</p>



<p>The news came from a live stream by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cU5PrEr1HjM&amp;t=5476s&amp;ab_channel=DanAllenGaming" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dan Allen Gaming</a> a few weeks ago, where he sat down with Dead Space creators Glen Schofield, Bret Robbins, and Cristopher Stone.</p>



<p>“We tried actually, the three of us, to [pitch] Dead Space 4, said Schofield. “I mean, we’re talking this year [that they pitched Dead Space 4]”, he continued. In response, Allen replied, “And what they didn’t budge?”</p>



<p>“Well, we didn’t go too deep; they just said we’re not interested right now, we appreciate it, blah blah blah, and we respected their opinion,” replied Schofield. He finished on the topic with “We have some ideas,” with the trio all saying they would return for a Dead Space 4. </p>



<p>The last game in the Dead Space series to be released was Dead Space 3 in 2013, with the original Dead Space receiving a remake by Motive Studio in 2022. </p>



<p>Since the Dead Space IP stopped with its game in 2023, Schofield released The Callisto Protocol in 2022 with his new studio Striking Distance Studios, which was considered a spiritual successor to the Dead Space series. The game failed to meet Krafton’s sales expectations of five million units, lowering their expectations to two million.</p>



<p>As for if we’ll ever see another Dead Space, it remains to be seen, but for now, it looks like its creators are all on board with jumping ship to EA if the project gets greenlit.</p>



<p>Would you like to see another Dead Space game? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-4-romance-options-meaningful/">The Witcher 4’s romance options will be much more meaningful</a></p>








    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>