<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:16:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shroud Predicts ARC Raiders Will Be ‘Bigger Than Fortnite’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-arc-raiders-fortnite-hot-take/</link>
            <guid>1395358</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a statement that some have dubbed a hot take, popular streamer and former esports pro, Shroud, has suggested that ARC Raiders is <strong>bigger </strong>than Fortnite. He suggested that, going forward, Embark Studios’ extraction shooter will be <strong>bigger than </strong>the likes of Fortnite, VALORANT, and Apex Legends, prompting many to doubt his knowledge of ball.</p>



<p>Shroud has found plenty of success streaming ARC Raiders since the game dropped on October 30, but this latest comment is a tricky one, and it has fans debating how serious the content creator was.</p>







<h2 id="h-will-arc-raiders-be-bigger-than-fortnite">Will ARC Raiders Be Bigger Than Fortnite?</h2>



<p>During <a href="https://x.com/JakeSucky/status/2006425120722792795" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a recent stream</a>, Shroud plainly stated:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>This game is definitely the biggest game since Fortnite for sure. The only other game I can think of along the way is maybe like VALORANT and Apex. But I think this game is bigger than both those games and will be bigger as time goes on.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was a hot take, and it has since been met with some ridicule, even from fans of ARC Raiders.</p>



<p>The extraction adventure title, which was released by Embark Studios on October 30, has proven to be one of the biggest hits of 2025. It’s one of the most popular extraction games ever made, and two months after release, it is effortlessly retaining enormous player counts across all platforms where other, similar games have faltered and fallen.</p>



<p>To say it’s bigger than Fortnite is a stretch, though. It’s no big secret that Fortnite is the most successful live-service shooter of all time, and the most popular battle royale title ever created. It has peaked at more than 40 million concurrent players, while ARC Raiders has managed a peak concurrent user count of 481,000 on Steam. </p>



<p>Embark Studios remains committed to expanding and evolving ARC Raiders and has already pushed out some engaging events and updates since the game dropped. Before ARC Raiders dropped, Embark Studios pledged <strong>years </strong>of support, and it’s easy to see that happening given what we already know about the game.</p>







<p>Do you think ARC Raiders will be ‘bigger than Fortnite’? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/harada-tekken-dead-veteran-dev-final-message/">Katsuhiro Harada has officially left Tekken</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-arc-raiders-fortnite-hot-take/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Harada TEKKEN is Completely Dead’: Veteran Bandai Dev Shares Final Message with Fans]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/harada-tekken-dead-veteran-dev-final-message/</link>
            <guid>1395349</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Katsuhiro Harada has bid farewell to more than thirty years of working under the Bandai Namco banner, moving on from Tekken after decades of developing the series. In a new social media post, Harada ushered in 2026 by stressing that he’s ‘no longer a developer/creator of the TEKKEN series’.</p>



<p>At the start of December 2025, Harada and the Bandai Namco team shared the news that the legendary developer would be parting ways with the firm after 31 years.</p>







<h2 id="h-katsuhiro-harada-has-moved-on">Katsuhiro Harada Has Moved On</h2>



<p>In a new post on social media, Katsuhiro Harada shared the following message:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I’m no longer a developer / creator of the TEKKEN series.</p><p>Harada_TEKKEN is completely dead.</p></div>— Katsuhiro Harada (@Harada_TEKKEN) <a href="https://twitter.com/Harada_TEKKEN/status/2006390358859809229?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 31, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>The iconic developer was quick to update his bio, writing, ‘Former Game Director and Chief Producer of action and fighting games.’</p>



<p>On December 8, Harada shared the revelation with fans worldwide that he would be stepping down from his tenured spot at Bandai Namco:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I’d like to share that I’ll be leaving Bandai Namco at the end of 2025. With the TEKKEN series reaching its 30th anniversary—an important milestone for a project I’ve devoted much of my life to—I felt this was the most fitting moment to bring one chapter to a close.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Fans shared their sentiments in the comments under Harada’s post. One drew comparisons to the series that Harada was pivotal in creating, saying, ‘Heihachi ‘died’ like 4 times. Kazuya came back from a volcano. We know how this works in the Tekken universe. See you in the next patch notes, boss.’</p>



<p>Others offered more simple, heartfelt messages: ‘We will always think of you, Harada-san, thank you for everything.’</p>



<p>Harada worked in production and direction roles on the Tekken series since Tekken 3 debuted in 1997, and was a driving force in the space ever since. He’s set to appear one last time in the Tekken space at some upcoming esports events, but then the world afterwards is his oyster.</p>







<p>Are you sad to see the back of Katsuhiro Harada? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-rtx-5090-prices-to-5000-in-2026/">NVIDIA RTX 5090 GPUs could hit $5000 in 2026</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/harada-tekken-dead-veteran-dev-final-message/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#935)—Clues and Answers for Thursday, January 1]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-1-935/</link>
            <guid>1395343</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>I haven’t seen you since last year! It’s 2026, and it’s time to keep moving forward with stacks of NYT Connections hints, solutions, and tips. If you’ve burst into 2026 with a desire to keep your NYT Connections streak running, I’m here to help you achieve that resolution. Below, you’ll find the solutions for today’s puzzle.</p>



<p>Let us know in the comments below what your resolutions are for 2026 and how you plan to hold yourself to them!</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-january-1">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (January 1)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #935:</p>



<ul>
<li>SHUCK</li>



<li>SCOTCH</li>



<li>HEAD</li>



<li>RAT</li>



<li>CURSE</li>



<li>SKIN</li>



<li>NUT</li>



<li>FLY</li>



<li>HOUND</li>



<li>FINGERS</li>



<li>SPELL</li>



<li>SHELL</li>



<li>CHARM</li>



<li>BUFF</li>



<li>PEEL</li>



<li>HEX</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think about the small, concentrated forms of supernatural influence — the kind of mystical actions that show up in fairy tales, fantasy novels, or folklore.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Imagine you’re prepping food in a kitchen — or working with anything that has a natural outer layer</em>.</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>These are the words you attach to someone who is REALLY into a topic — the kind of person who knows every detail, every fact, every obscure bit of trivia.</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Picture the word “butter” followed by another word to form a familiar phrase or compound.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, January 1:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-january-1-935">NYT Connections Answers for Today, January 1 (#935)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– CHARM, CURSE, HEX, SPELL</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – PEEL, SHELL, SHUCK, SKIN</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BUFF, HEAD, HOUND, RAT</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – FINGERS, FLY, NUT, SCOTCH</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">r</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-1-935/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Insider Gaming’s Game of the Year 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gaming-game-of-the-year-2025/</link>
            <guid>1395064</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Awards for individual genres are amazing, and recognition for one game conquering a whole field of gameplay. However, this is the big one. There have been so many elite contenders for the 2025 Game of the Year accolades, and Insider Gaming has selected the one deemed the best.</p>



<p>12 months of video game releases have led to this big moment. Top-level developers have worked hard, and publishers have put their faith in games in the hope of being acknowledged as the best. 2025 has emptied wallets and consumed hours with amazing Roguelikes, RPGs, Action-Adventure games, and more.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming</a> has crowned a winner.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-game-of-2025-winner-hollow-knight-silksong">Best Game Of 2025 Winner—Hollow Knight: Silksong</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>It’s a testament to numerous games that a few releases could be in this spot. If you can overlook the dastardly difficulty of Hollow Knight: Silksong and ignore the elitist conversation of a AAA game needing to be GOTY, then Silksong is a worthy winner, and the Insider Gaming team has spoken!</p>



<p>This year has seen Silksong go from being barely a figure in the shadows to receiving a launch date soon after it reemerged at Gamescom 2025 in August. It’s rare for an indie game to have the levels of hype it did, but that’s exactly what happened. It single-handedly took the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-xbox-eshop-offline-downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam, Xbox, and eShop stores offline once downloads went live</a>, due to demand, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-beat-hollow-knight-all-time-peak-player-count-in-15-minutes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decimated the original’s all-time peak player count in minutes</a>.</p>



<p>It’s one of the highest-rated games of 2025, and it’s a breathtaking adventure from start to finish. You’ll struggle to find indie games this beautiful and carefully manicured—there are no ugly edges to be found. The gameplay and depth of quests and things to do have been greatly expanded, and every locale feels unique. Combat is a steep learning curve, but there’s nothing wrong with that, and owners will receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-sea-of-sorrow-dlc-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sea of Sorrow DLC</a> for free.</p>



<p>Silksong suddenly ended up being one of the year’s most anticipated games, and in Insider Gaming’s opinion, the best, without question.</p>



<h2 id="h-insider-gaming-game-of-the-year-2025-runner-up-clair-obscur-expedition-33">Insider Gaming Game of the Year 2025 Runner-Up—Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Another accolade. Image via Sandfall Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>So many turn-based RPGs successfully execute one or more aspects of a game: Gameplay, Story, Performances, Music, and Art. Very few dare to tackle them all head-on and nail it! Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 wasn’t as hyped as Silksong was, but it emerged as one of the most must-play RPGs of the modern era.</p>



<p>Yes, Sandfall Interactive’s first game was created by world-class developers with years of AAA experience. It didn’t mean Clair Obscur would work by any means. The odd design choice here and there could maybe have used some more work, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indie-game-awards-disqualifies-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gen-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI controversy</a> does leave the slightest of sour tastes in the mouth.</p>



<p>Nevertheless, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is an easy runner-up. With other games like Hades 2, Blue Prince, and Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 all delivering their own serving of excellence, respect needs to be put on Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s name.</p>



<p>This is one of the best games in years.</p>



<p>It’s likely many of you would swap our winner and runner-up around—or omit Hollow Knight: Silksong altogether! If you have thoughts or your own winner, head to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> to discuss them.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out more fun Insider Gaming content, including the thought that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/year-in-review-fortnite-has-to-be-considered-the-best-free-to-play-game-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite has to be considered the best free-to-play game ever</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-games-added-to-playstation-plus-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all games added to PlayStation Plus in 2025</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gaming-game-of-the-year-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>