<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:23:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Doesn’t Want You To Ban Jetpack Cat in Overwatch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/blizzard-doesnt-want-you-to-ban-jetpack-cat-in-overwatch/</link>
            <guid>1433659</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Overwatch developers are asking players not to ban Jetpack Cat, as players get tired of the overpowered character’s abilities. </p>



<p>Overwatch came in guns blazing for their latest <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-new-content-in-overwatch-season-1-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 1 update</a>, introducing 5 new Heroes to the title, including Domina, Emre, Mizuki, Anran, and Jetpack Cat. Along with that, new sub-roles for the core roles and a bunch of other content were revealed. Today, we are talking about one of the newly released characters. </p>







<h2 id="h-overwatch-s-jetpack-cat-seems-to-be-too-overpowered">Overwatch’s Jetpack Cat Seems to be Too Overpowered</h2>



<p>Overwatch has just posted on their official <a href="https://x.com/PlayOverwatch/status/2021774745243726021" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter), “NO BAN JETPACK CAT PLZ” with a very innocent image of the character. Many players in the comments section don’t agree with the developers, stating they will continue to ban the character, while others request a balance in the character’s skills. Some players seem to agree, chiming in with the ‘don’t ban Jetpack Cat’ chants. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>There is a full-fledged Reddit post on r/<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Competitiveoverwatch/comments/1r1iuj4/jetpack_cat_has_a_massive_issue/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Competitiveoverwatch</a>, discussing how the character can be a big problem in competitive games. It seems that Jetpack Cat excels at close and midrange duels and can disengage easily. What’s more, their ultimate attack is considered a guaranteed tank killer, and the Tether ability can be a game-changer as well. Many players have said they want the character permanently banned until changes are made. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>In other news, Overwatch’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatchs-anran-set-for-redesign-after-community-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Anran is getting a redesign</a> after receiving community backlash. Additionally, Fortnite’s Overwatch crossover is bringing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-overwatch-crossover-brings-genji-tracer-d-va/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Genji, Mercy, Tracer, and D.Va as new skins</a>. What are your thoughts on Overwatch devs requesting players not to ban Jetpack Cat? Do you agree or disagree? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-has-a-kingdom-hearts-collab-in-development-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite actively developing a Kingdom Hearts collaboration</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/blizzard-doesnt-want-you-to-ban-jetpack-cat-in-overwatch/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>