<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 06:21:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Console Players Can Finally Switch Off Crossplay]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-console-players-switch-off-crossplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-console-players-can-finally-switch-off-crossplay.1150617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-console-players-switch-off-crossplay/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>One of the most asked-for changes to Call of Duty Warzone arrives with Season 03, which drops tomorrow, April 2. In this long-awaited update, console-based Warzone players will <strong>finally </strong>be able to switch off crossplay functionality in regular multiplayer matchmaking.</p>



<p>That means that they can remove any chance of connecting with PC players, which eradicates a fair portion of the user base that engages in nefarious practices like <strong>cheating</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-long-time-coming">Long Time Coming</h2>



<p>In a recent <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2025/03/call-of-duty-bo6-warzone-season-03-patch-notes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> breaking down the Season 03 patch notes, it was confirmed:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>In Season 03, we’re giving console players more granular options by separating the MP Ranked Play and Call of Duty: Warzone Ranked Play settings and adding a new Multiplayer-only setting for Quickplay, Featured, and Party Games matches.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This means that console players will be able to <strong>switch off crossplay in Warzone </strong>for regular multiplayer matches.</p>



<h3 id="h-how-to-turn-off-crossplay-in-warzone">How to Turn Off Crossplay in Warzone</h3>



<p>To switch off crossplay in Warzone on console, you’ll need to navigate to the network settings menu and select ‘Cross-Play Off’. This will lock your selection unless the following happens:</p>



<ul>
<li>If you play with a mixed-platform party, your settings will be temporarily adjusted to ‘Cross-Play On’</li>



<li>If you play with at least <strong>one </strong>PC player, your settings will be temporarily adjusted to ‘Cross-Play On’</li>
</ul>



<p>Once your party returns to a single platform, your settings will automatically update to reflect your original choice.</p>



<p>Activision has warned that locking your matchmaking mechanics to a single platform might negatively impact your queue times, but that’s a small price to pay for feeling a little safer while playing Warzone on console.</p>



<h3 id="h-when-does-the-new-warzone-map-come-out">When Does The New Warzone Map Come Out?</h3>



<p>If you’re eager to switch off crossplay and dive into Verdansk, the new Warzone map, you don’t have long to wait. It’ll drop in Call of Duty: Warzone on April 3 at 9 am PST / 5 pm BST.</p>



<p>It has been several years since Verdansk was last in Warzone, and it’s expected to be a resurgence of sorts (no pun intended) for the popular battle royale map.</p>



<p>Let me know in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a> how much of a W this crossplay decision is.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everyone-favourite-warzone-emote-coming-back/">everyone’s favourite Warzone emote is coming back</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everyone’s Favourite Warzone Emote is Coming Back]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/everyone-favourite-warzone-emote-coming-back/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everyone%E2%80%99s-favourite-warzone-emote-is-coming-back.1150602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/everyone-favourite-warzone-emote-coming-back/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It was recently discovered that one of the most popular Warzone emotes is returning with the Season 03 update. It’ll be tucked into the battle pass, so you’re guaranteed to unlock it if you play enough. If you were around during the peak of Warzone when Verdansk first existed, you’ll recognise how humorous this emote can be.</p>



<p>That’s right – <strong>the middle finger emote is coming back to Warzone</strong>.</p>



<p>But there’s a catch.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-crank-job">Crank Job</h2>



<p>The ‘Crank Job’ middle finger emote was a fan-favourite when it first emerged in Warzone. It allowed players to rebel against their opponents one last time as they lay bleeding out on the floor. It was great fun when fused with killcams, which is why it rapidly became one of the most popular emotes in the game.</p>



<p>It was recently revealed that the middle finger emote will return to Warzone in the Season 03 battle pass.</p>



<p>There’s a catch, unfortunately. </p>



<p>It has been mentioned that it’s a third-person variant of the Crank Job emote, which might eradicate any sense of whimsy attached to popping it once you’ve downed an enemy. I’m willing to hold out hope that it’ll be as funny as ever, but the third-person aspect might have ruined it a bit.</p>



<p>Here’s what everyone’s favourite Warzone emote used to look like:</p>



<div><article><p><span>A 3rd Person Version of the ‘Middle Finger’ Emote is RETURNING in the </span><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#BlackOps6</a><span> Warzone Season 3 Battlepass 😭 </span></p></article></div>







<p>There will be plenty more to unlock in the Season 03 battle pass in Black Ops 6 and Warzone, including <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/r0-z3-skin-call-of-duty-controversial-paywall/">a new Roze skin</a>, the AMAX, and the HDR sniper rifle.</p>



<p>Are you prepared for Verdansk’s return? Let me know what you’re most excited about in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-verdansk-is-back-calling-card/">you can unlock an exclusive Verdansk calling card</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Counter-Strike 2 3/31 Update: New Armory, Weekly Care Package Skins, and a Bigger Banana]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/counter-strike-2-3-31-update-new-armory-weekly-care-package-skins-and-a-bigger-banana/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/counter-strike-2-3-31-update-new-armory-weekly-care-package-skins-and-a-bigger-banana.1150470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/counter-strike-2-3-31-update-new-armory-weekly-care-package-skins-and-a-bigger-banana/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It’s no April Fool’s Day joke: Valve has dropped their latest Counter-Strike 2 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/730/view/529842339955343453" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">update</a> on March 31st, featuring a handful of new weapon skins and a “clean up” Inferno and Train. It’s no brand new operation, but it’s a pretty sizable update to CS2 compared to others.</p>



<h2 id="h-counter-strike-2-march-31st-update-new-changes">Counter-Strike 2 March 31st Update – New Changes</h2>



<p>The CS2 weekly care package feature now includes three new weapon collections added to the drop list: Ascent, Boreal, and Radiant. The new collections have added “over 70 new [weapon] finishes,” featuring a wide variety of styles. It doesn’t appear that players will get to choose which weapon collection their weekly care package skin comes from, but it does increase the variety of skins that appear.</p>



<p>New skins aren’t exclusive to just the weekly care package for this update. A new case and a new weapon skin collection have been added to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-the-armory-update-charms-battle-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Armory</a>. Players can acquire the Fever case from the Armory page for two credits. By purchasing a Fever case key, players can open their case for a chance at the AWP Printstream or get extremely lucky and open one of several Shattered Web knives in Chroma finishes. Players can also spend four Armory credits to get one random skin from the new Train collection. The “limited edition” item has also been swapped out, and players can save 15 credits for one of the XM1014 Solitude variants. This items will be removed from the Armory on Sunday, July 13.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>As for gameplay changes, Inferno and Train and have been hit with some “spring cleaning.” Both maps now feature some “cleaner surfaces, less clutter,” and a noticeably wider Banana section (B Main area) on Inferno specifically.</p>



<p>Any new skins in particular catch your eye? Let us know which one is your favorite in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out our coverage of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/asus-seemingly-teases-project-kennan-xbox-handheld-ahead-of-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Kennan Xbox Handheld device</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered PC System Requirements—Minimum, Recommended & Best Specs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ail-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-pc-system-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-pc-system-requirements%E2%80%94minimum-recommended-best-specs.1150326/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ail-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-pc-system-requirements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered makes its bow on PC, broadening the game’s availability. The survival title already looked unbelievable on consoles, so let’s tell you its PC specs and system requirements to have you clacking at Clickers in no time.</p>



<p>The Last of Us Part 1 Remastered came to PC, so it makes sense for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-2-remastered-announces-free-no-return-content-for-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered</a> to follow suit. Naughty Dog’s award-winning sequel is here in all its remastered and revitalized glory. It features the complete dual-narrative of The Last of Us Part 2 but comes with lots of new features.</p>



<p>Not everyone’s PC setup is the same. This is why system requirements are important before a game’s release. Naughty Dog has unveiled the entire list of PC specs and requirements here, and you should look to see which tier you are compatible with.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-minimum-requirements-on-pc">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Minimum Requirements on PC</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The game is breathtaking. Credit to Naughty Dog</figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.naughtydog.com/blog/the_last_of_us_part_ii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Last of Us Part 2</a> Remastered’s requirements are split into four categories: <strong>Minimum, Recommended, High, and Very High</strong> settings. Minimum is what you need to run Part 2 at all. We need to hit these requirements to ensure the game works and we don’t run into any problems.</p>



<p>The game runs better the closer you get to “Very High.” This is reserved for the most elite gaming configurations though, so don’t be disheartened if you fall short of the requirements.</p>



<p>Without further ado, here’s every set of system requirements for The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered on PC.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Minimum PC Spec</th><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Minimum Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Operating Software</td><td data-align="center">Windows 10 / 11 (Version 1909 or newer)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Ryzen 3 1300X / Intel i3-8100</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Radeon RX 5500 XT / NVIDIA RTX 1650</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Memory</td><td data-align="center">16 GB RAM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">DirectX</td><td data-align="center">Version 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Storage</td><td data-align="center">At least 150 GB SSD</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-recommended-requirements-on-pc">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Recommended Requirements on PC</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Recommended PC Spec</th><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Recommended Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Operating Software</td><td data-align="center">Windows 10 / 11 (Version 1909 or newer)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Ryzen 5 3600 / Intel i5-8600</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Radeon RX 5700 / NVIDIA RTX 3060</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Memory</td><td data-align="center">16 GB RAM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">DirectX</td><td data-align="center">Version 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Storage</td><td data-align="center">At least 150 GB SSD</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-high-requirements-on-pc-0">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered High Requirements on PC</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered High PC Spec</th><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered High Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Operating Software</td><td data-align="center">Windows 10 / 11 (Version 1909 or newer)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Ryzen 7 3700X / Intel i7-9700K</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Radeon RX 6800 / NVIDIA RTX 3070</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Memory</td><td data-align="center">16 GB RAM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">DirectX</td><td data-align="center">Version 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Storage</td><td data-align="center">At least 150 GB SSD</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-very-high-requirements-on-pc-0">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Very High Requirements on PC</h2>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Very High PC Spec</th><th data-align="center">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Very High Requirement</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Operating Software</td><td data-align="center">Windows 10 / 11 (Version 1909 or newer)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Ryzen 7 5700X / Intel i7-11700</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GPU</td><td data-align="center">AMD Radeon RX 7900XT / NVIDIA RTX 4080</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Memory</td><td data-align="center">32 GB RAM</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">DirectX</td><td data-align="center">Version 12</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Storage</td><td data-align="center">At least 150 GB SSD</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>Head over to our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> to check out new conversations each day. You can also let the world know your thoughts on The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered and if you’re excited to play it on PC.</p>



<p>For more The Last of Us news, check out the latest on the TV show’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-season-2-release-date-and-episode-count-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 2 release date and episodes</a>. Also, check out reports that Season 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-season-2-timeline/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will ‘mess around’ with the timeline from the game</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>