<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:39:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next The Sims 4 Expansion Pack Has Been Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-the-sims-4-expansion-pack-has-been-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-the-sims-4-expansion-pack-has-been-leaked.1095063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-the-sims-4-expansion-pack-has-been-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-86829">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The next expansion pack for The Sims 4 has been leaked ahead of its reveal. Known Sims leaker <a href="https://x.com/anadius/status/1884512026455638345" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">anadius</a> has found that the next expansion pack for the game will be a “Businesses &amp; Hobbies” pack.</p>



<p>The announcement is expected to come within the next week as part of The Sims 25th Anniversary roadmap. The exact date is expected between February 4-6.</p>



<div><article><p><span>Just names this time:
Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack + Set Up Shop (bonus content if you buy early)
Got that info 8h ago but wanted more details. There’s still nothing.</span></p></article></div>



<p>Details of the 18th expansion pack are still scarce as anadius said he didn’t have all the information just yet. He did add there will be bonus content should you buy the expansion early.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-nbsp-xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST:&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Developers Direct Us: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>The leak of the next expansion pack isn’t the only news for The Sims to make the rounds. A <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-sims-re-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent report claims</a> that both The Sims 1 and The Sims 2—along with all of their expansions—will be getting a re-release this week. The latest update suggests Friday, January 31 as the launch.</p>



<p>EA hasn’t commented on the rumors of the re-release. The company is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-eas-next-earnings-report-date-time-and-what-to-expect/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scheduled to announce</a> its Q3 FY2025 earnings on Tuesday, February 4 where it’s possible the series’ recent performance and future plans will be discussed.</p>



<p>What are you hoping for with The Sims 4 Business &amp; Hobbies expansion pack? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the free games coming to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Plus members in February</a> and and check out the details for the latest&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major update to No Man’s Sky</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/">Next God of War Game Is Reportedly Centered Around Egyptian Mythology</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new report claims that God of War is making the moving to Egyptian mythology, and Sony is looking for actors.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-fake-leaks/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-fake-leaks/">Marvel Rivals Developers Are Allegedly Hiding Fake Heroes in Game Files to Catch Leakers</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>New claims have hit the internet that the Marvel Rivals developers are adding fake heroes within its game files to confuse and catch leakers, or are they?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-launch-to-be-worst-when-it-comes-to-availability/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-rtx-5090-and-rtx-5080-launch-to-be-worst-when-it-comes-to-availability/">Nvidia RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 Launch To Be “Worst When It Comes To Availability”</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to multiple claims, the launch of the Nvidia RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 are expected to be the “worst” in terms of availability.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-sees-20-performance-increase-over-last-gen-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-sees-20-performance-increase-over-last-gen-its-claimed/">Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 Sees 20% Performance Increase Over Last Gen, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim suggests that the Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 will see performance improvements of up to 20% over the last generation.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Monthly Games for February 2025 Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-announced.1095024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Sony has announced the PlayStation Plus monthly games for February 2025 will be Payday 3, High on Life, and Pac-Man World Re-Pac.</p>



<p>All <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-payday-3-high-on-life-pac-man-world-re-pac/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">three of the games</a> will be available for PlayStation Plus members starting February 4. Like always, once you add the games to your library, they will be available to download as long as you have an active subscription.</p>



<h2 id="h-february-2025-s-free-playstation-plus-games">February 2025’s Free PlayStation Plus Games</h2>



<p>Of the three games coming on February 4, Payday 3 is the biggest name. First released in September 2023, the latest game from Starbreeze has seen its share of ups and downs over the last year-plus. High on Life was released in December 2022 while Pac-Man World Re-Pac launched in August 2022.</p>



<p>Payday 3 will be available for PS5 while High on Life and Pac-Man World Re-Pac will be available on both PS4 and PS5.</p>



<p>Speaking of PS4, Sony <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-announces-focus-on-ps5-games-for-future-ps-plus-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced that it’s shifting away</a> from adding PS4 games to the free monthly games and PlayStation Game Catalog starting in January 2026. Instead, the focus will be on PS5 titles.</p>



<p>“As we shift to PS5, PS4 games will no longer be a key benefit and will only be occasionally offered for PlayStation Plus Monthly Games and Game Catalog starting January 2026,” Sony said.</p>



<p>Until February 3, PlayStation Plus Members can still add January’s games to their library. Those games include Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, Need for Speed: Hot Pursuit Remastered, and The Stanley Parable: Ultra Deluxe.</p>



<p>What do you think of the PlayStation Plus monthly games coming in February? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about why the planned story DLC for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-2s-next-dlc-has-been-delayed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Division 2 has been delayed</a> and what NASCAR series is&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nascar-25-to-feature-four-official-series-including-arca/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">making its console game debut</a>.&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Will Incentive Users With PSN Accounts On PC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-will-incentive-users-with-psn-accounts-on-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-will-incentive-users-with-psn-accounts-on-pc.1094973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-will-incentive-users-with-psn-accounts-on-pc/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-86821">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>PlayStation wants you to have a PlayStation Network (PSN) Account when you play their games on PC. And it’s willing to give players freebies for doing just that.</p>



<p>In a post on the PlayStation Blog, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/new-in-game-content-incentives-coming-to-playstation-games-on-pc/">the company announced</a> a number of new incentives for players on PC who also have a PSN account. Games like Marvel’s Spider-Man 2, God of War Ragnarök, Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered, and The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered will be given in-game content if they create and link their account.</p>



<p>“An account for PlayStation Network will become optional for these titles on PC,” PlayStation said. “Players who still opt to sign into a PlayStation Network account will also enjoy added benefits like trophies and friend management.”</p>



<p>When you login to your PSN account, you will get the following depending on the game:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Marvel’s Spider-Man 2:</strong> Early unlock suits: the Spider-Man 2099 Black Suit and the Miles Morales 2099 Suit</li>



<li><strong>God of War Ragnarök:</strong> Gain access to the Armor of the Black Bear set for Kratos at the first Lost Items chest in the Realm Between Realms (previously only accessible in a New Game+ run) and a resource bundle (500 Hacksilver&nbsp;and 250 XP)&nbsp;<em>&nbsp;</em></li>



<li><strong>The Last of Us Part II Remastered:</strong> +50 points to activate bonus features and unlock extras and Jordan’s Jacket from Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet as a skin for Ellie&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered:</strong> Gain access to Nora Valiant outfit</li>
</ul>



<p>Sony added that more games from PlayStation Studios will get benefits in the future.</p>



<p>What do you think of Sony giving away free in-game content to those who create and link their PSN account on PC? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about why the new story&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-2s-next-dlc-has-been-delayed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DLC for The Division 2 was delayed</a>&nbsp;and check out the details for the latest&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major update to No Man’s Sky</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/age-of-empires-3-definitive-edition-dlc-cancelled/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/age-of-empires-3-definitive-edition-dlc-cancelled/">Age of Empires 3: Definitive Edition DLC Cancelled</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developer World’s Edge has announced that the planned Age of Empires 3: Definitive Edition DLC has been cancelled.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-update/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-update/">No Man’s Sky Worlds Part 2 Update Adds Countless New Stars, Planets, and More</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hello Games has released its latest major update for No Man’s Sky—Worlds Part 2—that brings new planets, stories, stories, and more. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-new-publisher/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-snap-new-publisher/">Marvel Snap Developers Have Found a New Publisher After US Ban Fiasco</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Marvel Snap developer Second Dinner have announced that its found a new publisher following the US ban fiasco that saw TikTok and its game banned in the US.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dino-crisis-1-and-2-modern-release/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dino-crisis-1-and-2-modern-release/">Dino Crisis and Dino Crisis 2 Are Now Playable on Modern PCs</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>GOG has announced that both Dino Crisis and Dino Crisis 2 are now fully playable on modern PCs.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>