<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 18:56:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show 25 Gameplay Trailer Reveals New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mlb-the-show-25-gameplay-trailer-reveals-new-features/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mlb-the-show-25-gameplay-trailer-reveals-new-features.1100031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/mlb-the-show-25-gameplay-trailer-reveals-new-features/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Sony San Diego has released the first gameplay trailer for MLB The Show 25, and with it came reveals of new features coming to this year’s game.</p>



<p>MLB The Show 25 features a number of updates coming to each of the game’s core modes. With Road to the Show, players will be able to now play in high school and college before making it to the big leagues. Colleges confirmed in the game so far—based on the trailer—include UCLA, LSU, TCU, Cal-State Fullerton, Vanderbilt, Texas, South Carolina, and Tennessee.  There are also metal bats in the game, replicating the play and sound from lower-levels of baseball.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="MLB The Show 25 | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DdbcF6TCAXM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Moving on to Franchise Mode, Sony San Diego is touting a new “Front Office Experience”. According to the studio, “choices matter, consequences are real, and time is precious as a revitalized Free Agency system adds risk/reward elements, strategy, and excitement to the pursuit of the top free agents each offseason”.</p>



<p>For Diamond Dynasty, the game’s card-collecting mode, there will be two new game modes within. The first is called  Diamond Quest, a rogue-like offline mode. The second is an online league-style mode called Weekend Classic. </p>



<p>Other new features revealed include the addition of more quick-time events, first-person cameras, and more. More details and deep dives into the modes will come as part of Sony San Diego’s pre-launch roadmap that you can see below.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>MLB The Show 25 launches March 18 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch. For the first time in years, the game won’t be available day one on Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>What do you think of the new MLB The Show 25 gameplay trailer along with the new features announced? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read our full&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a>&nbsp;and read what EA had to say about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/need-for-speed-isnt-dead-ea-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">future of Need for Speed</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 2025—Release Period, Battlefield Labs Testing & First Battlefield 6 Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-2025%E2%80%94release-period-battlefield-labs-testing-first-battlefield-6-gameplay.1100028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-release/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It feels like we’ve not had an amazing Battlefield game for a long time. This is why EA is giving its all to make Battlefield 2025’s release as good as it can be and bring the franchise back to the forefront of FPS gaming with a bang in Battlefield 6.</p>



<p>Battlefield 2025 is exactly what I’m looking for right now. Call of Duty is still great but can be arcadey, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel Rivals</a> and Overwatch are compelling Hero shooters, and The Finals is lacking something, but adds the delicious destruction I seek. Battlefield has always provided something a bit different, and (in my opinion) we haven’t had a memorable entry since 2016’s Battlefield 1.</p>



<p>Early indicators are EA is inventing a lot of time, resources, and manpower into Battlefield 2025, so let’s check out what we know about the next <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-will-the-next-battlefield-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield release</a> and more.</p>



<h2 id="h-battlefield-2025-release-period">Battlefield 2025 Release Period</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Boom. Credit to Battlefield Studios – Official Battlefield Labs Reveal Teaser video on YouTube</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>It’s unconfirmed, but Battlefield 2025 is being eyed up for a potential 2025 release, and multiple reports seem to verify this.</strong></p>



<p>We’ve reported previously <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-battle-royale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA’s next Battlefield game was aiming for 2025</a>. A few months later Vince Zempella—heading the new Battlefield title—hinted Battlefield was returning to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-modern-era/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">modern-day combat, also in 2025</a>.</p>



<p>EA hasn’t come out and said a 2025 date is happening, but it seems extremely likely. I highly doubt it’s going to stay as “Battlefield 2025” either, and we could finally be getting the long-awaited <strong>Battlefield 6</strong> many have been asking for.</p>



<h2 id="h-battlefield-2025-battlefield-labs-testing-explained">Battlefield 2025 Battlefield Labs Testing Explained</h2>



<p><strong>Battlefield Labs is described as the “The most ambitious community collaboration in franchise history” and is a full-on cohesive alliance of multiple developers and players to create the ultimate Battlefield 2025 game.</strong></p>



<p>February 3 saw the first mention of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-confirms-battlefield-labs-community-testing-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Labs</a> project. It’s a series of tests throughout the pre-alpha phase (and probably beta testing) to continually ascertain the quality of the product. Consistent player feedback is looking to help the four studios working on Battlefield 2025: <strong>DICE, Ripple Effect, Motive, </strong>and <strong>Criterion</strong>.</p>



<p>We don’t how long <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/news/announcing-battlefield-labs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield Labs</a> will last, but you can try to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-sign-up-for-battlefield-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for Battlefield Labs</a> and test the potential Battlefield 6 entry—providing feedback of your own.</p>



<h2 id="h-first-battlefield-6-gameplay-revealed">First Battlefield 6 Gameplay Revealed</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Let’s hope for a good one. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The first-ever footage of Battlefield 2025 AKA Battlefield 6 was shown off during the Battlefield Labs demonstration. It showed explosive gameplay, destructible environments, vehicles, high-octane weapons, and much more.</strong></p>



<p>It looks spectacular for pre-alpha footage, but we’ve been fooled by Battlefield before. Nevertheless, you can check out the reveal for yourself below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Introducing Battlefield Labs | Battlefield Studios" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_fGteYuaNxA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>What does Battlefield 2025 need to do differently from Battlefield 2024—and even Battlefield 5—to make itself relevant again and bring the player base back? Is this the last chance saloon for EA and Battlefield as a whole? Get involved with a comment below.</p>



<p>We’ve also learned <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-portal-return/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Portal</a> makes a return for Battlefield 6, and we’ve gone through and dissected everything we’ve seen and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-learned-from-the-new-battlefield-game-footage/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">learned from the first gameplay footage</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bayonetta 3’s Developer Has Lost 5 More Game Directors]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bayonetta-3s-developer-has-lost-5-more-game-directors/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bayonetta-3%E2%80%99s-developer-has-lost-5-more-game-directors.1099947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/bayonetta-3s-developer-has-lost-5-more-game-directors/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>PlatinumGames has now lost the game directors for Bayonetta 3, Astral Chain, Metal Gear Rising, and other titles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f5iRwbkbVQQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube video</a> by former PlatinumGames vice president Hideki Kamiya revealed that the development studio will lose five prominent staff members. The departed employees include the game directors of some of the studio’s most popular titles: Yusuke Miyata from Bayonetta 3, Adebe Tinari from Bayonetta Origins, who has left for HouseMarque, Takahisa Taura from Astral Chain, Kenji Saito from Metal Gear Rising, and Masaki Yamanaka, the character designer for Resident Evil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hideki Kamiya revealed the developers’ exit from PlatinumGames in the last section of his video, where the development studio’s employees were seen having a party. Kamiya also asked the audience to support the newly departed developers, stating that people create games and that creativity will follow wherever they go.</p>



<p>On the other hand, Hideki Kamiya, the former vice president of PlatinumGames, created his own studio, Clovers, which Capcom backs. Kamiya’s first work for the new studio will feature Okami 2. The video didn’t reveal what the other game directors will do next.  </p>



<p>In other news, Bioware Employees are <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-bioware-employees-worried-about-more-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">worried about more layoffs</a>. Also, Ubisoft’s recent reason for layoffs was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-layoffs-memo-to-staff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“more efficient operating models.”</a> What are your thoughts on PlatinumGames losing 5 game directors? Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/just-cause-movie-adaptation-will-be-written-by-jack-ryans-writer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">&nbsp;the Just Cause movie being written by Jack Ryan’s writer</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>