<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:09:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda Movie Has Seemingly Started Filming]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-legend-of-zelda-movie-filming-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-movie-has-seemingly-started-filming.1344811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to an updated listing, The Legend of Zelda live-action film has started production. Previously, the Nintendo/Sony movie, based on the iconic franchise, was in pre-production and set to release in 2027.</p>



<p>The success of Nintendo’s film projects has only gained speed thanks to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/super-mario-bros-movie-record-breaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Super Mario Bros</a>. Movie in 2023. Its blockbuster sales at the Box Office proved that bringing iconic IPs to the screen can work if done well. Interestingly, the next project announced was a highly ambitious live-action adaptation of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-legend-of-zelda-is-finally-getting-a-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Legend of Zelda</a>. Helmed by The Maze Runner’s Wes Ball, the film plans to release on May 7th, 2027. Casting has been done for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/link-and-zelda-actors-confirmed-nintendo-legend-of-zelda/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Link and Zelda</a>, but not much else is known. Well, now we may be getting some more information soon, if the listing is correct.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-live-action-legend-of-zelda-film-is-in-production-listing-claims">The Live-Action Legend of Zelda Film Is In Production, Listing Claims</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://productionlist.com/production/the-legend-of-zelda/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a listing from ProductionList</a>, it says that Sony’s The Legend of Zelda is now in production. If true, this means that casting and crew have been assigned and filming has begun. The filming dates are from November 4th, 2025, to April 7th, 2026. As for where it’s set to film, the site lists Wellington, New Zealand. Wellington is a major hub for movies like Avatar, The Lord of the Rings, and King Kong, so it makes sense for The Legend of Zelda to be there.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that Nintendo has not confirmed that filming has started, so take the news with a grain of salt until then. However, seeing as the world of Hyrule will likely spend some time in post-production for CGI and such, filming now makes sense. The film had already been delayed from March 2027 to May 2027. Coincidentally, the movie is being filmed during the 40th anniversary of The Legend of Zelda franchise. Perhaps we could see some set photos and maybe even a teaser in early 2026? We’ll have to wait and see for now!</p>



<p>What do you think of The Legend of Zelda starting filming? Do you think the series can work in live-action? Who’s your dream Ganondorf casting? Any game you hope it adapts? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Zelda news, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-new-trailer-nintendo-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-movie-franchises-mario-zelda-future/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo’s plans to adapt other IPs</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-legend-of-zelda-movie-filming-rumor/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Wordle #1601: Hints And Answer For November 6, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1601-hints-answer-november-6-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/today%E2%80%99s-wordle-1601-hints-and-answer-for-november-6-2025.1344736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Wordle challenges players to guess a fresh five-letter word each day in six tries or fewer. Whether you’re a beginner or a daily player, today’s tips and strategies can help you solve it faster and maintain your streak—if you’re open to a little extra help. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Wordle, don’t worry, below you’ll find some <strong>helpful hints and even the answer for Wordle Game #1601 for November 6, 2025</strong>.</p>



<p>To play today’s Wordle, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to the game’s website.</a> If you want to go right to today’s answer without any tips or tricks, you <strong><a href="#h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1601-on-november-6-2025">can click right here</a>.</strong> If you’ve missed any days, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle Answer Archive</a> for every past answer.</p>



<p><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> The following information includes spoilers on today’s</em> and yesterday’s editions<em> of Wordle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure></figure>



<h2>How To Play Wordle</h2>



<p>Wordle is a simple but addictive word puzzle. Each day, players have to <strong>guess a five-letter word answer</strong> in no more than six attempts. After each guess:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Green letters</strong> are correct and in the right position.</li>



<li><strong>Yellow letters</strong> are correct, but in the wrong position.</li>



<li><strong>Gray letters</strong> are not in the word at all.</li>
</ul>



<p>The goal is to guess the word in as few tries as possible. Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p>Wordle can only be played on the New York Times website. There is currently no app for you to download the official game.</p>



<h2 id="h-wordle-hints-for-today-november-6-2025">Wordle Hints For Today, November 6, 2025</h2>



<p>The Wordle answer for game #1601 is going to be easier to solve than the past few puzzles. According to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/05/crosswords/wordle-review-1601.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NY Times Wordle</a> review, today’s answer takes an average of 3.8 of 6 guesses. That makes it lower than the 3.8 guess average on November 5.</p>



<h3 id="h-general-wordle-hints-for-november-6">General Wordle Hints For November 6</h3>



<p>Without giving today’s Wordle answer completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul>
<li>SIEGE</li>



<li>GUEST</li>



<li>GUIDE</li>
</ul>



<p>Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving <strong>Wordle #1601 for November 6, 2025</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-starter-words-for-november-6-2025">Starter Words For November 6, 2025</h3>



<p>If you want help getting started without having today’s Wordle answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you figure out some included letters. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> Think misdirection or presentation, but in a non-physical sense.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> Often used when someone hides their true intentions.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong> It’s a 5-letter noun borrowed from French.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 4:</strong> A word you might hear in mystery stories or social deception.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1601-on-november-6-2025">Today’s Wordle Answer For Game #1601 On November 6, 2025</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answer to today’s Wordle below.</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> GUISE</p>



<p>If you solved today’s Wordle without our answer, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-yesterday-s-wordle-answer">Yesterday’s Wordle Answer</h2>



<p>If you missed the previous game, here’s yesterday’s Wordle answer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1600-hints-answer-november-5-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game #1600 on November 5, 2025</a>:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> SHORT</p>



<p>While not always the case, looking at previous words can sometimes give you insight into common patterns or letter usage in Wordle puzzles. Reminder, you can check out every past Wordle answer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our official archive</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-wordle-game-after-1601">When Is The Next Wordle Game After #1601?</h2>



<p>Wordle games are <strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before to give players a heads up. The game on <strong>November 7 </strong>will be <strong>Wordle Game #1602</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-wordle">What Is Wordle?</h2>



<p>Wordle is a daily word puzzle created by Josh Wardle. Initially developed as a prototype in 2013, it wasn’t fully released until 2021. The game challenges players to guess a five-letter word in six tries or fewer, using hints from each attempt to narrow down the answer. Its straightforward concept, accessibility, and the thrill of solving a new puzzle each day helped it surge in popularity by late 2021. The success of Wordle inspired numerous spin-offs and social media challenges, leading to its acquisition by The New York Times in early 2022.</p>



<hr>



<p>Need more help with other daily games? Let us know what games you’d like tips and clues for in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1601-hints-answer-november-6-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>