<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:55:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Counter-Strike 2 Makes Surprise Premier Season 2 Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/counter-strike-2-makes-surprise-premier-season-2-announcement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/counter-strike-2-makes-surprise-premier-season-2-announcement.1091646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/counter-strike-2-makes-surprise-premier-season-2-announcement/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Premier Season 2 of Counter-Strike 2 has been officially <a href="https://www.counter-strike.net/newsentry/520829437562848128" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> by Valve, bringing to an end what’s felt like the longest first season of the game’s main competitive mode. When Season 2 begins, a couple new changes to the game’s rifles might shake up the meta.</p>



<p>Full details for Season 2 below.</p>



<h2 id="h-welcome-to-cs2-season-2">Welcome to CS2 Season 2</h2>



<p>With Season 1 coming to an end, active Premier players that earned a rating will “receive a commemorative Premier Season One Medal.” This medal will feature various stats from across the season, including their map distribution, rating history, overall K/D, total multi-kills, and their win/loss record.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The major changes coming to Counter-Strike 2 in Season 2 are <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-adds-train-to-map-pool/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Train-Vertigo substitution in the map pool</a>, and changes to the M4A4 and FAMAS. The M4A4 will get a price reduction down to $2900, which matches its silenced counterpart, the M4A1-S. The FAMAS is getting buffs to its standing and crouching accuracy values, as well as a price cut, which should make it an extremely more viable option during half-buy rounds.</p>



<p>When Season 2 begins, player will need to win 10 matches in Premier in order to refresh their rating. Players will also be able to earn a Premier Season Two Medal, which will have custom colors and bars to represent peak rating and total wins. To be eligible to receive a Premier Season Two Medal, players will have to win 25 matches and have an active rating when the season ends. Season two will end after the BLAST Austin Major, which concludes on June 22.</p>



<p>The only thing missing from the CS2 Premier Season 2 announcement is a start date. Considering how long Season 1 lasted, and given that Season 2 supposedly will end in just 3 months, it has to start sooner rather than later.</p>



<hr>



<p>What’s the highest your CS2 rating reached during Season 1? Tell us what you think below and on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>, stay tuned to Insider Gaming, and our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shopify-rebellion-becomes-first-game-changers-team-to-reach-challengers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coverage of Shopify Rebellion’s history-making VALORANT moment</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CDL Major IV Heads to DreamHack Dallas in May]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cdl-major-iv-dreamhack-first-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cdl-major-iv-heads-to-dreamhack-dallas-in-may.1091523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cdl-major-iv-dreamhack-first-time/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Activision has just revealed that DreamHack Dallas will serve as the staging ground for the Call of Duty League Major IV tournament. This grand event will unravel between May 23 – 25 at the Kay Bailey Hutchinson Convention Center in Dallas, Texas.</p>



<p>Not only that, but the team has confirmed that DH Dallas will play host to a Challengers Open. This is great news for those competing in the tier <strong>below </strong>the Call of Duty League, as the Challengers circuit has felt a little overlooked in recent months.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-major-first">Major First</h2>



<p>In a statement posted on the Call of Duty blog, Daniel Tsay, the GM of COD Esports at Activision, explained:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We’re excited to bring Major IV to DreamHack for the first time in Call of Duty League history.</p>



<p>An event at DreamHack will allow our fans to enjoy this iconic celebration of gaming and esports, and also provide new fans the experience of competitive Call of Duty live.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Fans are excited to see the return of Challengers Opens through 2025. Presently, three have been lined up for the year ahead, with the first one taking place at Major II in Texas. The only CDL Major this year to <strong>not </strong>have any Challengers events will be the upcoming Major I, set to take place next week in Madrid.</p>



<p>Every <a href="https://callofdutyleague.com/en-us/news/2025-season-update" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Challengers Open event</a> will go hand-in-hand with a $100,000 prize pool, with $40,000 being reserved for the first-place team.</p>



<p>This season is one of many firsts in the CDL. Not only do we have the first EU Major in Call of Duty League history, but we now have the first CDL Major to take place at a DreamHack event.</p>



<p>If you’re not in the know, DreamHack represents one of the most well-known and prolific gaming and esports ecosystems in the world. This historic event dates back to 1994, and in the last 30 years, it has travelled the world and played host to many top-tier tournaments.</p>



<p>Last year, the Overwatch Champions Series World Finals event was held at DreamHack Stockholm.</p>



<p>Are you going to attend DreamHack Dallas to catch Major IV? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-star-yay-says-his-new-ceiling-goes-beyond-chamber/">recent interview with VALORANT’s yay</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: Is Yay Back? The VALORANT Star Says ‘Not Yet’, But His New Ceiling Goes Beyond Chamber]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-star-yay-says-his-new-ceiling-goes-beyond-chamber/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-is-yay-back-the-valorant-star-says-%E2%80%98not-yet%E2%80%99-but-his-new-ceiling-goes-beyond-chamber.1091499/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-star-yay-says-his-new-ceiling-goes-beyond-chamber/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>At the end of 2022, VALORANT’s biggest star and hottest free agent was Jaccob “yay” Whiteaker. Arguably the best player during pro VALORANT’s Chamber meta, yay converted his electric season with OpTic Gaming, which included a trophy at Masters Reykjavík, into <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/valorant/cloud9-set-to-sign-valorant-star-yay-from-optic-gaming-report-says-1943658/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a major deal with Cloud9</a> at the start of the partnership era.</p>



<p>What followed yay’s terrific tenure with OpTic was a two year odyssey of setbacks and losing. Yay was dropped from Cloud9 after two matches, with the organization citing “role issues.” Yay played seven matches with Disguised, a tier two NA VALORANT team owned by streamer Disguised Toast, losing all seven matches. He then went across the world to BLEED Esports in the VCT Pacific league, winning just one match in eight matches played.</p>



<p>Yay now finds himself on Evil Geniuses, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eg-coach-potter-says-yay-has-to-prove-hes-not-a-chamber-main/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“a place where every player ends up not by choice,” according to the team’s world champion coach Christine “potter” Chi</a>. After EG defeated FURIA at the VCT 2025 Americas Kickoff, yay’s first win in the Americas league ever, the reborn VALORANT star spoke to Insider Gaming about his new agent pool, his “back” status, and how he’s grown during his tumultuous journey.</p>



<hr>



<p>The following interview has been edited slightly for clarity and length.</p>



<p><strong>IG: Astra isn’t really an agent that utilizes the Operator very much, but you couldn’t tell by watching your performance today. Do you feel like the best version of yourself is the one that has the Op in your hands?</strong></p>



<p>I would say…yes and no? That’s tough to be honest. I would say my rifle is almost equally as good as my Op. That’s one of my strengths as a player throughout my whole career: I’m able to do both very well. I feel like I can pick up anything to be honest with you.</p>



<p>The Operator is really strong on Abyss in general, and [using it with Astra] is something that potter recommended. Since I’m able to place smokes from anywhere on the map, it’s good to have it in my hands so we can let Icy entry, and then I can just hold anything.</p>



<p><strong>IG: This is the question that everyone has been asking: is yay back?</strong></p>



<p>[Laughs] I would say not yet, but I think as we continue to progress as a team and I continue to work on certain things, I will fully regrow that confidence. This was a big step; getting another win on the board.</p>



<p><strong>IG: What’s the highest level of “back” you think you can reach? Are we talking OpTic yay?</strong></p>



<p>That was a very unique situation in which I was on Chamber for an extended period. I like to believe I [still] have a very high ceiling that extends well beyond Chamber and that whole meta, but I think I need to build more confidence with that. You won’t see the same yay, but you’ll hopefully see something similar [with] a new style. And hopefully some championships as well.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Derrek and yay celebrate on stage. Photo by Colin Young-Wolf/Riot Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>IG: What do you want to accomplish this year?</strong></p>



<p>I would really like to make another international event, at bare minimum. And rebuild a lot of the self confidence I used to have. I think I’m pretty much there, but now it’s about proving it to myself at this point.</p>



<p><strong>IG: You’ve mentioned getting your confidence back a few times now. How badly did those two years away mess with you, personally and on the server?</strong></p>



<p>It was a pretty rough period. It’s a very hard feeling to describe to someone, because you go from the very peak [of VALORANT] to not being able to flat out win anything. It’s something that throughout my entire pro career, even extending back to other games, I’ve never experienced before in my life. To go from such high highs to low lows in such a short time frame, it takes a toll on you, and I’m not gonna pretend that it didn’t.</p>



<p>But I think I’ve done a pretty good job of figuring out and working through that, and I’m excited for the future.</p>



<p><strong>IG: Is that experience something you’re trying to learn from, or one that rather just forget about entirely?</strong></p>



<p>You take what you can from that situation. There’s some things I learned in terms of just being a better human being. Like not relying so much on the results of what’s going on around. For a long period, what defined me was VALORANT, and when results aren’t going well, you feel very bad about yourself.</p>



<p><strong>IG: What’s the most important thing you’ve learned on this big journey?</strong></p>



<p>I’ve learned how to deal with expectations. I put a lot of stock into what the community or what other people thought of me. I’ve learned to realize that what the outside world thinks of you doesn’t really reflect who you are. It’s [more] important to realize what’s important to you and what you stand for. And if I do need to fix something or change I have people I can rely on for that.</p>



<hr>



<p>Is yay back? Tell us what you think below and on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>, stay tuned to Insider Gaming, and our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shopify-rebellion-becomes-first-game-changers-team-to-reach-challengers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coverage of Shopify Rebellion’s history-making VALORANT moment</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League of Legends Was the Most Watched Esports Game of 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-was-the-most-watched-esports-game-of-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/league-of-legends-was-the-most-watched-esports-game-of-2024.1091466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-was-the-most-watched-esports-game-of-2024/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Despite the continued rise of VALORANT and the post-release energy surrounding Counter-Strike 2, the most watched esport in the world is still League of Legends, and it’s not really that close. The MOBA that serves as Riot Games’ foundation nearly doubled the amount of total hours watched from the second most watched title of 2024.</p>



<hr>







<p>According to <a href="https://escharts.com/news/top-esports-games-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data</a> from Esports Charts, fans watched 749.6 million hours of League of Legends esports events in 2024, up 27% from the year before. The 2024 World Championships, known commonly as Worlds 2024, unsurprisingly was the biggest event of the year. Worlds 2024 accumulated over 190 million hours watched, accounting for over a quarter of League esports hours watched all year. The event peaked during its grand finals, with a record 6,856,769 viewers tuning in to watch <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lol-worlds-2024-winner/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">T1 and the legendary Lee “Faker” Sang-hyeok win their fifth Worlds event</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Trailing behind League of Legends is the mobile-based MOBA, Mobile Legends: Bang Bang, which is wildly popular in Southeast Asia. In third place is Counter-Strike 2, followed by VALORANT, and then Dota 2 in fifth place. 2024 represents the first time that VALORANT has surpassed Dota 2 in total hours watched. While the Dota 2 scene suffered due to the discontinuing of the Dota Pro Circuit, VALORANT continued to grow internationally.</p>



<p>Esports Charts’ data doesn’t track viewership from Chinese livestreaming platforms though, due to “the unreliability of the reported statistics and lack of transparency in regards to how they are calculated.” But it’s clear that China is a massive priority for the top performing games. VALORANT expanded with the VCT China League in 2024, and also saw the first Chinese team, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/edward-gaming-wins-valorant-champions-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EDward Gaming, win its world championship</a>. For the first time in Counter-Strike’s illustrious history, a Major was held in Shanghai, where <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-spirit-win-shanghai-cs-major/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Team Spirit lifted the trophy</a>.</p>



<p>Will any game ever catch up to League of Legends? Tell us what you think below and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-playtests/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out the exclusive report on what’s coming to Xbox Game Pass in February</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>