<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:06:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 16’s Xbox Release Announcement is Imminent, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-xbox-release-announcement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-16%E2%80%99s-xbox-release-announcement-is-imminent-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1101846/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-xbox-release-announcement/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>An insider has claimed that Final Fantasy 16’s Xbox release announcement will arrive soon. The game’s release seemingly is planned for the “first half of 2025.” The leaker also revealed details about Final Fantasy 7 Remake and Rebirth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by IdleSlothVGT on <a href="https://x.com/IdleSlothVGT/status/1887250040491745562" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a>, NateTheHate recently spoke about Final Fantasy 16’s release plans for Xbox on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-studios-bethesda-abk-ot34-reseteora.1090722/page-103#post-135340638" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ResetEra</a>. According to Nate, the announcement should come shortly, but “not in the near future” if the developers aren’t implementing any “late changes”. Also, Final Fantasy 16 is scheduled to release for Xbox in the first half of 2025, “spring basically”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nate also spoke about Final Fantasy 7 Remake and Rebirth’s release plans on Xbox. The first instalment from Square Enix’s Remake Project is scheduled to arrive for Xbox “later this year,” and Rebirth is planned for 2026. Nate is unsure about the time but speculates that Final Fantasy Remake, Rebirth and FFXVI for Xbox “will be announced at the same time for maximum impact”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NateTheHate also mentioned Final Fantasy’s plans for Nintendo’s highly anticipated console, the Switch 2. It seems that the developers have decided to prioritise Final Fantasy 7 Remake and Rebirth for the Switch 2 over Final Fantasy 16. Regardless, it is exciting to see Final Fantasy embrace a multi-platform future for the franchise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth broke the franchise’s<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-single-player-record-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> single-player record on Steam</a>. Also, the third part of the Remake Project will be released on a ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-release-on-a-wide-range-of-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wide range of platforms</a>’. What are your thoughts on Final Fantasy 16’s Xbox release announcement arriving shortly?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-2-reveal-si-2025-rumour/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new rumour that claims Rainbow Six Siege 2 will be revealed this month</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feast for the Poor Quest Guide – How To Complete This KCD2 Side Quest]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/feast-for-the-poor-quest-guide-how-to-complete/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/feast-for-the-poor-quest-guide-%E2%80%93-how-to-complete-this-kcd2-side-quest.1101807/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/feast-for-the-poor-quest-guide-how-to-complete/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In Kingdom Come Deliverance 2, you’ll eventually be offered a side quest with an interesting premise. You’ll need to break into a military encampment and steal King Sigismund’s prized sausages reserved exclusively for royalty. However, the camp is heavily guarded and you’ll be challenged whenever you walk towards the gates.</p>



<p>Let’s talk about the solution for Feast for the Poor and figure out how to get the sausages from the camp in the easiest way possible.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-how-to-solve-feast-for-the-poor">How to Solve Feast for the Poor</h2>



<p>Feast for the Poor seems like a simple enough quest at first blush, but it’s tricky. Even going into the camp at night spells trouble, as you’re almost guaranteed to be seen by the many guards patrolling the area.</p>



<p>If you want to accept a challenge, you can dress in dark, light clothing and sneak into the camp after distracting a gate guard with a rock. Around the back of the camp (in the blue circle in the image below), you’ll find a barn with a window at the side of it – it’s quite visible.</p>



<p>If you climb up into that window, you’ll find yourself in the loft of a hay barn, and from here, you can get the best access to the camp without being challenged by a guard:</p>



<figure><figcaption>Blue = Entry, Green = Sausage</figcaption></figure>



<p>Instead of picking around the camp looking for the sausages, you can just head to the green circle on my map above. It’s here that you’ll find a painted chest in a circular tent – that’s the box containing the sausages.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, it’s a ‘very hard’ lock, so unless you have a high lockpicking skill, you’ll need to kill and loot a guard <strong>or </strong>pickpocket them for a set of keys. Once you’ve got the keys, you can get the sausages.</p>



<p><em>Remember that the bonus objective is to leave a head of cabbage in the box, but it doesn’t have much of an impact on the outcome if you forget</em>.</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>Spoiler Note:</strong></p>



<p>If you wait until you complete the main campaign, the camp will no longer be off-limits, allowing you to walk in unchallenged and find the sausages. You’ll still need to get the keys or pick the lock, but at no point will guards demand you or attack you.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Now that you’ve got the sausages, you can leave and pick up the next part of this quest. You’ll need to head into Kuttenberg and find people begging in the streets, giving them sausages and choosing who you want to name as the responsible donor. </p>



<p>That’s how to complete Feast for the Poor in Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 in a nutshell.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 guides, check out my <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tips-for-stealth-kingdom-come-deliverance-2/">top stealth tips</a> and learn about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-achievements-guide/">all the game’s achievements</a> </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Siege 2 Reveal Coming at SI 2025, Rumour Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-2-reveal-si-2025-rumour/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rainbow-six-siege-2-reveal-coming-at-si-2025-rumour-claims.1101804/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-2-reveal-si-2025-rumour/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A new claim states that Rainbow Six Siege 2 will be revealed at the Six Invitational 2025 (SI 2025), which is scheduled for February 14-16, 2025.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to a report by <a href="https://thegamepost.com/rainbow-six-siege-2-in-the-works/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>, an X user called <a href="https://x.com/fraxiswinning/status/1887257947043975667" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">fraxiswinning</a> recently posted about Rainbow Six Siege 2 being allegedly revealed this month at the SI 2025 event. The post also claims that the game is internally referred to as Siege X and will feature a complete “engine overhaul” along with a “graphical upgrade in textures and models.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaker has alleged that it is “likely” that Rainbow Six Siege 2 will be released around the Year 10 Season 2 update, which is scheduled to arrive in a few months. It is also rumoured that Siege X will not see any old events return but will only host new ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rainbow Six Siege 2 is a sequel that players have long waited for. The original game was released in 2015 and has been going strong since then. The title still attracts thousands of players daily, with its latest 24-hour peak at <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/359550/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">over 67,000 players</a> on Steam. The developers also frequently provide new content, and recent updates have added<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-y9s4-patch-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> new operations</a> and features like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-is-finally-getting-full-crossplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full cross-play</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, players are hoping for a change, and it will be exciting to see what sort of graphical and engine improvements Ubisoft can make to an already successful franchise like Tom Clancy’s Rainbow Six Siege.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-rules-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft is taking strict action</a> against Rainbow Six Siege cheaters, introducing more stringent anti-cheat measures. Also, an internal memo stated that recent layoffs were due to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-layoffs-memo-to-staff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“more efficient operating models.</a>” What are your thoughts on Rainbow Six Siege 2 being revealed at SI 2025?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-3-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metal Gear Solid 3 launching on August 28, 2025</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>