<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:47:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Movie Reportedly on the Cards Already After Successful Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-split-fiction-movie-is-reportedly-on-the-cards-already-after-successful-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-movie-reportedly-on-the-cards-already-after-successful-launch.1141101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/a-split-fiction-movie-is-reportedly-on-the-cards-already-after-successful-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After a hugely successful release, it seems several studios are already set to battle it out to claim the rights to a full-length Split Fiction movie—bringing the dramatic journey of Mio and Zoe to life.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-trophy-and-achievement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Split Fiction</a> had the tough job of following up <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-co-op-games-like-it-takes-two-split-fiction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">It Takes Two</a>—2021’s Game of the Year. I’d argue that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-reaches-major-sales-milestone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">milestone of two million copies sold in just one week</a> has put this doubt to rest. Josef Fares and his team have done it again, and it looks like another triumphant statement that cooperative multiplayer sells.</p>



<p>Now, it’s time to see if the medium is as effective on the big screen. A Split Fiction movie is heavily rumored—barely two weeks removed from its debut—and it looks promising.</p>



<h2 id="h-split-fiction-movie-could-make-a-great-co-op-caper">Split Fiction Movie Could Make A Great Co-op Caper</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Imagine what the power of modern cinema could do. Credit to Hazelight Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>According to <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/split-fiction-movie-video-game-adaptation-1236344367/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Variety</a>, the 2025 Game Developers Conference has birthed Split Fiction movie talk. Story Kitchen is the company potentially “<strong>Putting together the film’s cast, writers and director into a package as offers for the rights keep coming in from multiple top Hollywood studios.</strong>“</p>



<p>Again, the rumor and chatter come directly from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gdc-awards-balatro-game-of-the-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GDC 2025</a>, so it remains to be seen if the talk will continue once the event has concluded. Hopefully, a Split Fiction movie has better luck than the It Takes Two one. A movie for the previous co-op title was given the go-ahead, but it apparently remains on hold for now.</p>



<p>If we do get a Split Fiction movie, will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-split-fiction-voice-actors-revealed-who-voices-zoe-mio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Zoe and Mio’s voice actors</a> get to reprise their roles? Only time will tell. For now, we’ll continue to lap up every second of Split Fiction. After all, new secrets keep being discovered such as the now-infamous <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-split-fiction-laser-hell-secret-level/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Laser Hell Secret Hell</a> featuring a guest appearance from director Josef Fares himself!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>