<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:45:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New World: Aeternum To Be Taken Offline Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-aeternum-to-be-taken-offline-next-year/</link>
            <guid>1407466</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The time of New World: Aeternum is coming to an end. </p>



<p>After it was announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-development-cancelled-amazon-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no new content was coming</a> to the game and that it would be taken offline after 2026, Amazon Games has given an update as to when New World: Aeternum will go dark.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-will-new-world-come-down">When Will New World Come Down?</h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> on Thursday, Amazon Games announced that New World: Aeternum will be taken offline on January 31, 2027. From that point on, no one will be able to continue playing the game.</p>



<p>With this announcement also comes the news that as of today, January 15, the game will be delisted and no longer available for purchase. If you already own the game, you can still play it and reinstall it as much as you want until the January 31, 2027 date arrives. </p>



<p><strong>“We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion,” </strong>they said. <strong>“We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community.”</strong></p>



<p>The end of New World comes after its development team was hit with layoffs back in October. At the time, the layoffs spanned across all of Amazon, including its game studios and Twitch.</p>







<p>It has been our pleasure to work on&nbsp;<em>New World: Aeternum</em>&nbsp;and evolve this unforgettable adventure with you all. We look forward to one more year together and giving this fantastic adventure a sendoff worthy of a legendary hero. From the bottom of all our hearts, thank you for sharing this world with us.</p>



<p>Are you going to jump back into New World: Aeternum before it goes offline? Leave your thoughts on the game’s legacy down in the comments, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read the exclusive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details surrounding WWE 2K26’s Showcase Mode</a> and its feature star CM Punk. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-aeternum-to-be-taken-offline-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subway Surfers Is Getting a Sequel Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/subway-surfers-is-getting-a-sequel-next-month/</link>
            <guid>1407370</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The sequel to Subway Surfers, Subway Surfer City, releases on February 26, 2026; interested players can pre-register now. </p>



<p>Subway Surfers is undoubtedly not only one of the most popular endless runners out there, but also one of the most-played mobile games. I know I have spent hours on end trying achieve the highest score and beat all my friends. Fans of this game can now look forward to a brand new sequel, which introduces a lot of new stuff. </p>







<h2 id="h-subway-surfers-city-release-date-revealed">Subway Surfers City Release Date Revealed </h2>



<p>Revealed through a new post on <a href="https://x.com/subwaysurfers/status/2011831031184138243" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), Subway Surfers City arrives next month with new gameplay mechanics, game modes, challenges, and improved visuals. A new press release on <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20260115285583/en/SYBO-Announces-Subway-Surfers-City-The-Long-Awaited-Next-Chapter-to-Subway-Surfers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Business Wire</a> by the developer SYBO reveals some of the new mechanics players will be able to try out. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Time to gear up. 🏙️</p><p>Join the crew. Be part of the movement.</p><p>Subway Surfers City expands the journey into Subway City with new gameplay mechanics and modes, handcrafted challenges, and stunning visuals.</p><p>🎮 Pre-register now: <a href="https://t.co/xCJUIT1hcF">https://t.co/xCJUIT1hcF</a><br>📅 Launching Feb 26… <a href="https://t.co/BhCN8XFZg2">pic.twitter.com/BhCN8XFZg2</a></p></div>— Subway Surfers (@subwaysurfers) <a href="https://twitter.com/subwaysurfers/status/2011831031184138243?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>The game will introduce a “<strong>stomp move</strong>” that can be used to reveal hidden advantages, a “<strong>bouncy bubblegum shield</strong>” that can enhance your jump abilities, and more. </p>



<p>Additionally, there are three new modes to look forward to once Subway Surfers City is released. <strong>Classic Endless</strong>, the endless runner experience where players chase new high scores. The <strong>City Tour</strong>, which is a finite game mode where players will progress through levels, complete goals and explore districts while completing missions and finding hidden stars. Lastly, there is the <strong>Events</strong> mode, which will feature a rotation of finite runs and trials. </p>



<p>The original Subway Surfers game crossed 4.5 billion lifetime downloads in 2025, making it the most downloaded mobile game of all time, so the sequel has some pretty big shoes to fill. </p>



<p>Interested readers can pre-register for Subway Surfers City prior to its release on the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sybogames.subway.surfers.game&amp;hl=en_IN" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://apps.apple.com/ph/app/subway-surfers-city/id6504188939" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">iOS App Store</a>. </p>







<p>In other news, a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-life-is-strange-game-reveal-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new Life is Strange game</a> is scheduled to be revealed next week. Additionally, PlayStation recently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-has-delisted-over-1000-shovelware-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delisted over 1,000 shovelware games</a> from its store. Will you be playing Subway Surfers City once it releases next month? Leave your thoughts on all this and more down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more tech news from Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the exclusive report on CM Punk headlining WWE 2K26’s Showcase Mode</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/subway-surfers-is-getting-a-sequel-next-month/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>