<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:21:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Animus Hub Reveals Season Pass Content For Shadows and More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-animus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-animus-hub-reveals-season-pass-content-for-shadows-and-more.1036212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-animus/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A new datamine leak of the Assassin’s Creed Animus Hub, which will launch alongside Assassin’s Creed Shadows has revealed Season Pass content and more.</p>



<p>As <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-infinty-news/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">initially reported by Insider Gaming</a>, the Assassin”s Creed Infinity Hub, called the Animus will launch alongside Assassin’s Creed Shadows and be the launcher for Assassin’s Creed games moving forward. In the Animus, it will contain things like a Season Pass, and cosmetics and tell the ‘modern-day story’ of the Assassin’s Creed games moving forward.</p>



<p>Datamined and leaked by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Thorites/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reddit user /u/Thorites</a>, the first Battle Pass will be called “Eye in the Dark,” containing 20 different cosmetic tiers. Insider Gaming had also heard of three other Battle Passes previously named “The Hidden Network,” “@The Last Ronin,” and “In The Shadows,” all of which had 20 different tiers, too, but it’s unclear when or if, they’ll release.</p>



<p>The data mine leak also reveals that the Animus Hub will have an in-game store where players can buy cosmetic items for their characters, environments, and even pets. You can look at all the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1grbg48/information_and_assets_of_the_upcoming_animus_hub/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">leaked images here</a>.</p>



<p>In September 2024, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-to-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft announced that it would delay Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> from its scheduled November release date to February 2025 to improve the game’s polish. </p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows is scheduled to release on February 14, 2024.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to Assassin’s Creed Shadows and the Animus Hub? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read our exclusive on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/aew-strongly-considering-new-partner-for-future-video-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AEW considering a new partner</a>&nbsp;for its future video games. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thunderful Announces Second Wave Of Mass Layoffs This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/thunderful-announces-second-wave-of-mass-layoffs-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/thunderful-announces-second-wave-of-mass-layoffs-this-year.1036077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/thunderful-announces-second-wave-of-mass-layoffs-this-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Thunderful has announced its second restructuring in less than a year’s time. This time, it could see up to 100 people lose their jobs within the company.</p>



<p>The announcement came on Thursday via the <a href="https://thunderfulgroup.com/news-room/press-releases/2024-11-14-thunderful-group-implements-strategic-restructuring-program-doubling-down-on-third-party-game-publishing-and-scaling-back-internal-development-resulting-in-write-downs-of-220-240-msek" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">company’s website</a>.</p>



<p>“This newly announced program follows the cost-saving measures introduced earlier this year, as well as the divestment of the Group’s distribution business to manage previously incurred net debt,” Thunderful said. “Whilst significant reductions in cost levels were achieved this year, revenue targets have not been met and the Group is still struggling with negative cash flow.”</p>



<p>This restructuring will see the company move focus to external publishing with third-party games. Thunderful says it will “reduce the Group´s fixed costs and allow for greater flexibility, enabling faster, diverse game releases by leveraging external talent and resources in a balanced manner, while still retaining some internal development capacity.”</p>



<p>“It is regrettable to announce a second restructuring of Thunderful in less than a year, but we unfortunately see no other alternatives in order to ensure the Group’s long-term sustainability and resilience,” Thunderful CEO Martin Walfisz said.</p>



<p>As part of the moves, somewhere between 80-100 people in and outside of Sweden will lose their jobs. Those in management and administration will also be impacted by the layoffs.</p>



<p>Thunderful expects to have one-time costs of $22.8M – $27.4M as part of separation costs after negotiating with unions. In total, however, they anticipate the job  cuts to improve the overall cash flow by $73M – $82.2M.</p>



<p>In 2024, there have been nearly 14,000 known jobs lost due to layoffs across more than 160 companies.</p>



<p>What do you think of the restructuring and layoffs at Thunderful? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what Xbox’s Phil Spencer had to say about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-delay-wasnt-due-to-game-quality-phil-spencer-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the decision to delay Avowed</a> into February 2025. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is Trading coming to Pokémon TCG Pocket Trading? Release Date Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-trading-coming-to-pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-release-date-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-trading-coming-to-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-trading-release-date-explained.1036074/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-trading-coming-to-pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-release-date-explained/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Trading has been part of the Pokémon fabric and DNA since day one. It’s no surprise Trading is a huge topic of discussion in Pocket, and I’ve gathered the latest news and announcements to tell you everything we know about Pokémon TCG Pocket’s Trading mechanic.</p>



<p>Once you’ve opened many Pokémon TCG Pocket <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-pack-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-to-open-right-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">packs</a> and reeled off <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-wonder-pick-exploit-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wonder Picks</a>, your collection should look very full; but you’re also bound to have tons of duplicates. Getting extras of the same card is crucial when it comes to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-flair-in-pokemon-pocket-tcg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flair</a> in Pokémon TCG Pocket, but it can become an annoyance too. There are so many Pokémon I love when I first pull but become irritated by when I see them for the 10th time—or twice in one pack!</p>



<p>You can swap duplicates in real life—one area where the physical edition of the Pokémon TCG differs from the virtual format. We know Trading is in Pokémon TCG Pocket, but questions are being asked about it daily, and I’ll answer them now.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-trade-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">Can you Trade in Pokémon TCG Pocket?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Let me Trade, please! Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You cannot Trade in Pokémon TCG Pocket at present</strong> as the feature is currently locked behind a notice saying “<strong>Coming soon.</strong>” I think this part of the equation is quite self-explanatory. You can’t Trade, but The Pokémon Company has addressed the future of the mechanic.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-trading-coming-to-pokemon-tcg-pocket">When is Trading Coming to Pokémon TCG Pocket?</h2>



<p>As announced by the <a href="https://x.com/PokemonTCGP_JP/status/1856864629009363249" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Pokémon TCG Pocket X social media page</a>, “<strong>January 2025</strong>” is the official start period for Trading.</p>



<p>The post has been <a href="https://x.com/PokemonDealsTCG/status/1856820750529040857" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">translated</a>, and says, “We are aiming to add a feature that allows certain cards to be Traded started in January 2025. We are gradually planning to expand the selection of cards that are able to be Traded.”</p>



<p>So, <strong>not all cards can be Traded on day one</strong>. Using my best judgment, I’d say all cards ranging between <strong>one and three diamonds</strong> are going to be eligible to Trade. It does mean EX cards and other mega-rare pulls—such as Full Arts—need to wait a bit longer. </p>



<p>Unfortunately, like many players, I find myself in the situation where I have completed most of the main Genetic Apex set, and I’m mainly missing the odd EX card, as well as Full Arts. The Pokémon Company likely doesn’t want so many people having every card already, and it encourages players to spend more money and open more packs in a bid to pull the rarest cards.</p>



<p>Also, don’t be surprised if <strong>Gold Crown cards are never made Tradeable in Pokémon TCG Pocket.</strong> We’ll update this as we learn more about the card criteria for Trading.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-trade-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">How to Trade in Pokémon TCG Pocket</h2>



<p>The actual Trading process hasn’t been outlined yet, but we wager a similar system to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/pokemon-go/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon GO</a> is likely to be employed: Direct, one-to-one Trading between connected players, and you need to have a certain amount of currency to do so.</p>



<p>Pokémon GO requires Stardust to Trade—with certain cards made untradable altogether—and I expect you probably need a certain amount of Shinedust to Trade in Pokémon Pocket. The amount likely depends on the rarity of the creature, and Trading may be limited to a certain amount per day. This is all conjecture for now, but I can’t imagine the system will drastically deviate from this theory.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you looking forward to Trading in Pokémon TCG Pocket? Do you think it will be heavily restricted when it finally drops? Let us know in the comments, and be sure to check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-pokemon-tcg-pocket-electric-deck/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best Electric Deck</a> in Pocket, along with a guide on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-mew-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get Mew</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>