<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 01:25:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#885)—Clues and Answers for Wednesday, November 12]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-12-885/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-885-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-wednesday-november-12.1350634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>We’re at the midway point of the week and raring to go with another NYT Connections puzzle. Below, I’ve provided the top NYT Connections hints and solutions you’ll need to smash today’s challenge. How’s your week going? Let me know in the comments if you’ve been playing any other puzzling games and what you might like to see more hints for!</p>



<p>Read on to get the NYT Connections answers you’re looking for. Today’s puzzle is a little bizarre as it features <strong>exclusively </strong>four-letter words. You’ll see what I mean below.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-november-12">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (November 12)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #885:</p>



<ul>
<li>YOLO</li>



<li>POLO</li>



<li>LOCO</li>



<li>DODO</li>



<li>COMO</li>



<li>FOMO</li>



<li>JUDO</li>



<li>BOGO</li>



<li>BOZO</li>



<li>ROJO</li>



<li>YO-YO</li>



<li>SUMO</li>



<li>POCO</li>



<li>DOPE</li>



<li>GOLF</li>



<li>GOAT</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em><em>These all involve physical competition, but not your everyday gym workout.</em></em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em><em>Terms for someone who’s not exactly the sharpest tool in the shed.</em></em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em><em>Internet-born abbreviations that pack a punch.</em></em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em><em>You might hear these in Madrid or Mexico City.</em></em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, November 12.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-november-12-885">NYT Connections Answers for Today, November 12 (#885)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– GOLF, JUDO, POLO, SUMO</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BOZO, DODO, DOPE, YO-YO</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BOGO, FOMO, GOAT, YOLO</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – COMO, LOCO, POCO, ROJO</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a>r</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-12-885/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign’s First Expansion Revealed, Releasing December 4th]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-expansion-dlc-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-nightreign%E2%80%99s-first-expansion-revealed-releasing-december-4th.1350502/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Elden Ring Nightreign is getting a new expansion, titled The Forsaken Hollows, and it’s coming in less than a month. The reveal, as well as a new trailer, premiered at the State of Play Japan.</p>







<p>In 2022, Elden Ring seemingly took over the world, becoming one of the most popular games that year. It’s intense Soulsborne combat and great graphics made it many outlets’ Game of the Year winner. Even it’s DLC, Shadow of the Erdtree, was up for some year-end awards. Fortunately, a new multiplayer entry, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-everdark-sovereign-roadmap-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring: Nightreign</a>, came out earlier in 2025 and crafted a more focused yet fun experience. Now, we have a look at some new content coming to the game.</p>



<h2 id="h-elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-revealed-during-state-of-play-japan">Elden Ring Nightreign: The Forsaken Hollows Revealed During State of Play Japan</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d7GO1FjenwI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In the trailer, shown above, we see some fearsome bosses and Nightfarers. Via <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/11/elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-launches-dec-4-on-ps5-ps4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the PlayStation Blog</a>, the new characters are the Scholar and Undertaker, with two new formidable bosses to take down. Furthermore, a new section, called The Great Hollow, will be added to the game, allowing players to explore a deadly new area. The Forsaken Hollows marks the first new expansion for Elden Ring: Nightreign. Furthermore, we already have a release date: December 4th, 2025. No pricing was announced, however.</p>



<p>While Nightreign hasn’t hit as big as Elden Ring, constant updates and content is sure to keep fans coming. As it seems, there will be quite a lot of stuff for returning and new players to enjoy. We’re sure to hear more soon as it’s December 4th release date approaches.</p>







<p>What do you think about Elden Ring: Nightreign’s new content? Did you play the game? What did you think of it? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more FromSoftware, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fromsoftware-boss-does-not-mind-a-bloodborne-pc-port/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bloodborne PC</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-details-on-the-duskbloods-revealed-in-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Duskbloods</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-expansion-dlc-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>