<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 13:44:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Releases as a Global Top Seller on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-releases-as-a-global-top-seller-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-releases-as-a-global-top-seller-on-steam.1113081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-releases-as-a-global-top-seller-on-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Avowed has climbed the charts to become Steam’s number-one-selling game globally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Avowed reached Steam’s Top Seller list <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-tops-steams-best-sellers-chart-days-before-full-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">four days before its full release</a>, becoming America’s number-one-selling game on Steam. Now, spotted by <a href="https://gameranx.com/updates/id/529298/article/avowed-launches-as-steams-1top-seller-in-the-us-and-worldwide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gameranx</a>, an <a href="https://x.com/aarongreenberg/status/1891957370902728762" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> post by Aaron Greenberg, VP of Games Marketing at Microsoft, reveals Obsidian has clinched the top spot in the UK, France, Germany, Italy, Sweden, Finland, and more, making the game the number one selling game globally on the platform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Avowed’s becoming a global top seller on Steam is an exciting achievement for Obsidian, considering the game is available for free through Game Pass. If players head over to <a href="https://steamdb.info/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, they will see that Obsidian’s new action RPG is topping the charts for ‘Trending Games’ and ‘Popular Releases’, too. Avowed peaked at 17,171 players on Steam on its launch day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For those wondering, Avowed is Obsidian’s latest fantasy action RPG, which takes players to Eora’s mysterious world, first seen in the Pillars of Eternity franchise. You enter the Living Lands, an island filled with ancient magic and many mysterious secrets.&nbsp;Your decisions here will shape the fates of the inhabitants of this world. You will also face off against some nasty foes, but don’t worry; your arsenal is filled with swords, spells, guns, and shields, and your trusty grimoire will get you out of any sticky situations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Avowed isn’t open-world because “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-not-open-world-because-zones-tough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the pacing is really tough</a>” without zones. Also, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-game-director-reveals-new-details-about-companions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how companions work</a> in the game. What are your thoughts on Avowed becoming a global top seller on Steam?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-thps-remasters-will-shadow-drop-at-xbox-summer-showcase-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">THPS 3+4 remasters releasing at Xbox Summer Showcase</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next THPS Remasters Will Shadow Drop at Xbox Summer Showcase, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-thps-remasters-will-shadow-drop-at-xbox-summer-showcase-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-thps-remasters-will-shadow-drop-at-xbox-summer-showcase-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1113048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-thps-remasters-will-shadow-drop-at-xbox-summer-showcase-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-91569">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>According to an industry insider, Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3+4 Remaster will be released after the Xbox Summer Showcase in June 2025.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Recently, we learned through the pro skateboarder <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-new-tony-hawks-pro-skater-remaster-is-coming-skater-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tyshawn Jones</a> that a new remaster for Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater series is in the works and that he is in conversation with Activision again, which is “insanely exciting.” Industry insider eXtas1s has confirmed that the upcoming game is none other than Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3+4 Remaster, and it might be released sooner than we think.&nbsp;</p>



<p>eXtas1s posted a new video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnCqKCNNJFs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube</a> (via r/<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1iswtxn/extas1s_tony_hawk_34_will_be_shadow_dropped_at/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamingLeaksAndRumours</a>) in which he confirmed that Jones’s information is accurate and that a THPS 3+4 remaster is in the works. Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3+4 Remaster is internally referred to as Project Chicago at Microsoft and will be ready to be released by June 2025. The insider has stated that the THPS 3+4 remaster will be shadow-dropped after the Xbox Summer Showcase presentation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, THPS 3+4 Remaster will seemingly arrive as a Day One title for Xbox Game Pass and will also be available separately on Steam and PlayStation 5. eXtas1s couldn’t confirm whether the THPS 3+4 remaster will be released for the Switch 2, but he is pretty confident about his claim on the game’s release window.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, February Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 titles include <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-wave-2-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed, Watch Dogs: Legion, F1 24</a>, and more games. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-titles-will-remove-9-games-this-february/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nine games will be removed</a> from the service this month. What are your thoughts on THPS 3+4 Remaster shadow dropping at the Xbox Summer Showcase in June 2025?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NetEase’s statement on recent Marvel Rivals layoffs</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs/">NetEase Releases Statement On Marvel Rivals Layoffs</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>NetEase’s statement reveals that the recent Marvel Rivals layoffs occurred due to organisational reasons and development optimisation. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-go-developer-niantic-close-to-selling-games-business/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-go-developer-niantic-close-to-selling-games-business/">Pokemon Go Developer Niantic Close To Selling Games Business</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokemon Go developer Niantic is close to a deal to sell its video game business, including all games, to Saudi Arabia-backed Scopely.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-laid-off-as-netease-guts-entire-team/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-laid-off-as-netease-guts-entire-team/">Marvel Rivals Developers Laid Off As NetEase Guts An Entire Team</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the game’s director, publisher NetEase has laid off multiple developers on Marvel Rivals, including an entire US-based team.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens/">Marvel Rivals Players Can Finally Exchange Their Battle Pass Chrono Tokens</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Excess Chrono Tokens will no longer go to waste for Marvel Rivals fans that redeem all their battle pass rewards.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[17 Best Co-op Games Like It Takes Two & Split Fiction in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-co-op-games-like-it-takes-two-split-fiction/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/17-best-co-op-games-like-it-takes-two-split-fiction-in-2025.1113027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-co-op-games-like-it-takes-two-split-fiction/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Co-op gaming brings us all closer together—for better or for worse. While single-player gaming and online multiplayer continue to thrive, so does co-op. Certain studios and game makers are ensuring the art doesn’t die, and we’re here to recognize this with the best co-op games you need to be playing in 2025—especially if you want something akin to It Takes Two and Split Fiction.</p>



<p>Hazelight Studios inspired this list, and I take great pleasure in declaring this. I grew up playing local co-op games with my friends whenever possible. A Crash Team Racing tournament, a backstage scrap in WWF Smackdown, or an intense 1v1 in Point Blank. Multiplayer gaming has veered off toward online for the most part. But you’ve got the likes of Hazelight Studios developing games intended as a co-op-only title.</p>



<p>The developer is responsible for the Game of the Year-winning <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-hazelight-studios-next-game-it-takes-two-sequel-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">It Takes Two</a> and the upcoming <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Split Fiction</a>. If you need more local co-op fixes, here’s a list of contenders to consider in 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-co-op-games-you-need-to-play-in-2025">Best Co-op Games You Need to Play in 2025</h2>



<h3 id="h-a-way-out">A Way Out</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Where it all began. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Game director Josef Fares’ first project heading up the newly-formed <a href="https://www.hazelight.se/games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hazelight Studios</a> was A Way Out. Two human players have to choose their character—Vincent or Leo. The action plays out in split-screen fashion across a dramatic story with gameplay fueled by teamwork. It’s not as polished as It Takes Two, but it’s a breath of fresh air, and I’d recommend you try it out.</p>



<h3 id="h-baldur-s-gate-3">Baldur’s Gate 3</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Get ready to lose hours. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Yes, 2023’s outstanding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-devs-have-moved-their-full-attention-to-the-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> can be enjoyed locally with another player. There are no cutbacks or restrictions either as you can create your characters and unravel BG3’s world together like normal. <strong>The RPG is about as refined and revered as they come</strong>, and it has enough content to keep you going until a probable Baldur’s Gate 4.</p>



<h3 id="h-borderlands">Borderlands</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Take your pick. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>I’ve stood by Borderlands since its 2009 debut and will continue to do so. From its first iteration to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-know-about-borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands 4</a>, I don’t think it matters much which title you opt to play in co-op. <strong>Borderlands 2 is my favorite</strong> as it captures the soul of Pandora perfectly with its story, characters, and quests. But a stroll through Tiny Tina’s Wonderlands or enjoying a blast from the past with the Pre-Sequel won’t do any harm either in the epic looter shooter saga.</p>



<h3 id="h-brothers-a-tale-of-two-sons">Brothers A Tale of Two Sons</h3>



<figure><figcaption>True kinship. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Brothers A Tale of Two Sons was Fares’ directorial debut in video games. He worked under the banner of Starbreeze Studios to bring the story of two brothers to life before he founded Hazelight Studios. The game didn’t have co-op at launch, but the remake addressed this overlooked issue. This narrative-heavy adventure is a must, and you can once again see the <strong>groundwork being laid down for It Takes Two and Split Fiction</strong>.</p>



<h3 id="h-chained-together">Chained Together</h3>



<figure><figcaption>The only way up is down. Credit to Steam</figcaption></figure>



<p>I watched internet darlings Kai Cenat and IShowSpeed almost destroy each other playing Chained Together. Its concept is simple: You and a partner are chained together, and you must work together to escape hell. Every step, jump, and action you take affects your cohort. One false move, and you’re sent spiraling back down to the bottom—potentially startling Satan in his slumber.</p>



<h3 id="h-cuphead">Cuphead</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Good day for a swell battle! Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Cuphead is one of my favorite games of the last 10 years. Its presentation is incredibly niche and nuanced and Cuphead is essentially a boss rush—with a handful of platforming levels for good measure. It’s more fun with a partner but also frustrating as the enemy’s health scales accordingly. You can spend a good hour or two beating a boss, but <strong>the feeling of satisfaction is unbridled and unbeatable</strong>. It has a delicious last course through its DLC if you’re not satiated—called The Delicious Last Course!</p>



<h3 id="h-diablo-4">Diablo 4</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Everyone’s heard of Diablo. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Blizzard’s multimedia empire includes the iconic Diablo franchise. 2023 saw the release of Diablo 4, and the ARPG title not only offers more looting, dungeon crawling, bosses, and run-ins with demons and angels but also local co-op. You can buddy up with someone next to you, pick a class, and explore the plagued grounds of Sanctuary as you try to carefully tip-toe around the ongoing conflict between the High Heavens and the Burning Hells.</p>



<h3 id="h-don-t-starve-together">Don’t Starve Together</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Friendly. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Whereas something like Cuphead is overtly difficult, Don’t Starve doesn’t give this impression. Don’t let it fool you though as Don’t Starve demands you survive at all costs. You need food, hydration, sleep, warm surroundings, and a means of defending yourself. You don’t need to channel your inner Bear Grylls on your own though as the free Don’t Starve Together update introduces local co-op.</p>



<h3 id="h-lara-croft-and-the-guardian-of-light">Lara Croft And The Guardian of Light</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Niche but needed. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Lara Croft and the Guardian of Light—and its Temple of Osiris follow-up—feels derided. I question how many people (and even Tomb Raider fans) remember this 2010 gem. Unlike other entries on our best co-op games you need to play in 2025 list, this benefits from an in-person friend helping you out. It has Lara, her trademark pistols, outfit, and classic Tomb Raider exploration—<strong>what more do you want?</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-moving-out">Moving Out</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Frustration aplenty. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Anyone who’s ever <em>literally </em>moved out in real life automatically understands this game. It’s a nuisance in so many ways. So what better way to exemplify the rigors of moving out than by taking this nightmare, cranking up the hyperbole, and inciting chaos in relationships and friendships? Moving Out is a wonderful display of co-op and calamity, and it has a sequel if you want more punishment.</p>



<h3 id="h-overcooked">Overcooked</h3>



<figure><figcaption>It doesn’t start like this, I promise. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Substitute “moving out” with “cooking” and I can be done with this entry. Alas, this wouldn’t be informative of me and lacks integrity. I will say that if I was ranking the games on this list, <strong>Overcooked 1 and 2 would be near the top</strong>. Ghost Town Games created something hilarious, hellacious, and heartwarming with this series. Your ability to coalesce with individuals into a unified force is tested with every meal. Unfortunately, I don’t think there will be any more Overcooked, but there’s a good reason why—more on this later.</p>



<h3 id="h-portal-2">Portal 2</h3>



<figure><figcaption>A classic. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Remember when Valve used to make award-winning single-player games? No? I wouldn’t blame you as it’s incredibly slim picking nowadays. <strong>2011’s Portal 2 is a compulsory play </strong>for anyone with a penchant for immaculate storytelling, puzzles, physics, and co-op capers. Separate from the main story is an independent and original adventure only intended for two players. The quality is just as good and requires you both to don thinking caps playing this one.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Eye sense danger here. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>Speaking of highly successful IPs being abandoned, Rayman Legends is an excellent 2D platformer bubbling with life and personality. It has the grace of a galloping gazelle and might be <strong>the best Rayman title ever</strong>. It has a ton of fun-to-find collectibles, one ingenious level design after another (don’t get me started on the music levels), and best of all? Local co-op.</p>



<h3 id="h-sackboy-a-big-adventure">Sackboy: A Big Adventure</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Slowly does it. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>PlayStation and PC owners can sample a piece of this succulent Sackboy snack. It doesn’t do anything revolutionary or push the boundaries of 3D platforming in a way contemporaries and historical releases have, but it’s fun! Youngsters will get a kick out of it, and it’s mindless fun for older folks. You can get stuck into the bubble bursting with local users in co-op.</p>



<h3 id="h-stage-fright">Stage Fright</h3>



<figure><figcaption>A lot of promise. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>We’re back with Overcooked’s Ghost Town Games and its newest IP Stage Fright. I’m jumping the gun on this one as it’s not out yet. But its hilarious debut trailer could already be a sign of things to come. It’s also co-op focused, looks outstandingly creative, and could be one of the most-talked-about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-major-co-op-games-coming-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">co-op games in 2025</a> after Split Fiction.</p>



<h3 id="h-the-binding-of-isaac-rebirth">The Binding of Isaac Rebirth</h3>



<figure><figcaption>The tears crash around me. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Binding of Isaac Rebirth appeared as a PlayStation Plus Monthly game in November 2014. I barely batted an eyelid. However, one day, I needed something to play and decided to give it a crack. Even though I didn’t know what any items did, why my main weapon was a small child’s tears, or why I was trying to kill Isaac’s mother, I was engrossed forever. The Binding of Isaac kickstarted my <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/10-best-roguelike-games-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">roguelike/roguelite</a> journey, and if you haven’t, I implore you to do the same as it has added co-op since release.</p>



<h3 id="h-unravel-two">Unravel Two</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Threading the eye of a needle. Credit to IDGB</figcaption></figure>



<p>The first Unravel was a blast, but the sequel supersedes it by allowing two players to intertwine. Your relationship with your co-op partner is unlikely to unravel as the title is straightforward and shouldn’t trouble you. But its tamer nature is a more welcome and pleasant one. Once you’re done, you’ll both yarn for more.</p>



<hr>



<p>Let me know your favorite co-op games and experiences ever. Are you rooted in childhood with multiplayer classics like Goldeneye? Or are there fun story-based co-op adventures I’ve missed? </p>



<p>If you love co-op games, Split Fiction will fix the itch. Keep up to date with our latest content including if it has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-split-fiction-cross-platform-crossplay-status-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossplay or cross-platform play</a>, as well as its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-split-fiction-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-or-ea-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a> status.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NetEase Releases Statement On Marvel Rivals Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs.1112952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/netease-releases-statement-on-marvel-rivals-layoffs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>NetEase has just released a statement regarding the recent layoffs of the Marvel Rivals team in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Marvel Rivals game director Thaddeus Sasser revealed yesterday that his entire team in the United States was<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-laid-off-as-netease-guts-entire-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> suddenly gutted</a>. Sasser added that the layoffs took place even after their team was able to “deliver an incredibly successful new franchise in Marvel Rivals for NetEase Games”. It was unclear why the layoffs occurred, but NetEase’s latest statement clarifies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NetEase’s statement on Marvel Rivals layoffs was first spotted on an <a href="https://x.com/stephentotilo/status/1892090498803696046/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> post by Stephen Totilo. It revealed that the layoffs were part of a “difficult decision” required for “organisational reasons and to optimise development efficiency”. The decision led to cutting down their Seattle design team, which comprised six people. The developers stated that the affected will receive confidential and respectful treatment “with recognition for their individual contributions”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, they assure players that the core development team for Marvel Rivals, which resides in Guangzhou, China, and is led by Weicong Wu, is “fully committed” to providing the best experience for the players. The developers are investing more in the game’s growth and are looking forward to delivering new characters, maps, features, and engaging live-service content for their community.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Here’s NetEase’s statement on the Marvel Rivals layoffs in Seattle:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We recently made the difficult decision to adjust Marvel Rivals’ development team structure for organizational reasons and to optimize development efficiency for the game. This resulted in a reduction of a design team based in Seattle that is part of a larger global design function in support of Marvel Rivals. We appreciate the hard work and dedication of those affected and will be treating them confidentially and respectfully with recognition for their individual contributions.</p>



<p>We want to reassure our fanbase that the core development team for Marvel Rivals, which continues to be led by Lead Producer Weicong Wu and Game Creative Director Guangyun Chen in Guangzhou, China, remains fully committed to delivering an exceptional experience. We are investing more, not less, into the evolution and growth of this game. We’re excited to deliver new super hero characters, maps, features, and content to ensure an engaging live service experience for our worldwide player base.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In other news, Marvel Rivals players can exchange their <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battle Pass Chrono Tokens</a> after the Season 1.5 update. Also, the new update will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-is-nerfing-the-new-triple-strategist-meta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nerf the triple strategist meta</a>. What are your thoughts on Netease’s statement on the recent Marvel Rivals layoffs?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-go-developer-niantic-close-to-selling-games-business/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokemon GO developer planning to sell its gaming division</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>