<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 14:31:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSoft’s Horizon MMO Has Also Reportedly Been Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ncsofts-horizon-mmo-has-also-reportedly-been-canceled/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft%E2%80%99s-horizon-mmo-has-also-reportedly-been-canceled.1087557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ncsofts-horizon-mmo-has-also-reportedly-been-canceled/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>NCSoft’s Horizon MMO, codenamed Project H, has reportedly been canceled.</p>



<p>That’s according to the South Korean website <a href="https://news.mtn.co.kr/news-detail/2025011314314667267" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MTN</a> (via <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-horizon-mmo-developed-by-ncsoft-has-reportedly-been-cancelled.1087482/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ResetEra</a>), who say that at least three projects at NCSoft had been canceled, including Project Pantera, Project H, and Project J. According to widespread rumors, Project H was the codename of the Horizon MMO, which would be later called Skyline.</p>



<p>According to the report, both Project J and Project H were canceled at the beginning of the year, with its developers being notified that they’d been moving to different teams across the company.</p>



<p>In late 2023, NCSoft announced a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-and-ncsoft-global-business-partnership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">global business partnership with Sony</a>, spearheaded by SIE’s Jim Ryan and NCSOFT’s Taekjin Kim. </p>



<p>The Horizon MMO shouldn’t be confused with Horizon Online, another Horizon project in development at Guerrilla Games, which is forecasting up to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/guerrilla-games-1-million-players-horizon-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one million players on the title</a>. The Horizon Online Multiplayer title was&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a>&nbsp;in 2022 as a “online project set in the Horizon universe.” A recent job listing suggests that the title <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-online-multiplayer-game-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">could launch in 2025</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Project H’s cancellation marks the third project this month reportedly canceled. Last week, Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier reported that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-live-service-games-cancelled-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">two live-service games were canceled</a>, one at Bend Studio and the other at Bluepoint. According to the report, Bluepoint’s game was a live-service God of War game.</p>



<p>As of 9 May 2023, the&nbsp;Horizon&nbsp;series has sold over 32 million copies worldwide, over 8.4 million of which are for Horizon Forbidden West.</p>



<p>What do you think of canceling a Horizon MMO? Do you think it was the right move? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-organisation/">Shroud might start a Marvel Rivals team</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-goes-gold-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization 7 Goes Gold Ahead Of Release</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>