<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:57:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Scarlet/Violet DLC Cost as Much to Make as Legends: Arceus, Leaks Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-cost-as-much-to-make-as-legends-arceus-leaks-reveal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-scarlet-violet-dlc-cost-as-much-to-make-as-legends-arceus-leaks-reveal.1324393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New leaks have revealed that Pokémon Scarlet/Violet’s cost went way over budget, matching the likes of Pokémon Legends: Arceus’ entire development. </p>



<p>A massive number of leaks have surfaced online about the Pokémon franchise since yesterday, revealing details about past, present, and future games. We have already been informed about the Gen 10 title, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-gen-10-wind-and-waves-story-setting-new-mechanics-leak-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wind and Wave</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-games-and-dlc-roadmap-allegedly-revealed-in-new-datamine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a roadmap</a> for future Pokémon games. Now, new details about Scarlet and Violet’s DLC have also surfaced online. </p>



<h2 id="h-pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-s-expansion-brought-in-6-15-million-downloads">Pokémon Scarlet and Violet’s Expansion Brought In 6.15 Million Downloads</h2>



<p>As revealed by the reliable CentroLeaks on <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1978000011733664139" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), the cost for Pokémon Scarlet and Violet’s DLC development surpassed their estimated budgets enormously, reaching “as much as the entire Legends: Arceus development”. After that, the development team decided that DLCs would be kept “at an appropriate scale commensurate with the revenue, and focus on achieving low costs”. In the first 10 months, the DLC sold 6.15 million downloads, which is 25% of the players that own the game. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Pokémon Scarlet/Violet DLC development ended up going way over budget, costing as much as the entire Legends: Arceus development.</p><p>"Going forward, we will keep the DLC at an appropriate scale commensurate with the revenue, and focus on achieving low costs". <a href="https://t.co/gIkuf3FwIV">pic.twitter.com/gIkuf3FwIV</a></p></div>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/1978000011733664139?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<h2 id="h-dlcs-became-a-mandate-after-pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-s-expansion-0">DLCs Became a Mandate After Pokémon Scarlet and Violet’s Expansion</h2>



<p>A previous post from Centro also talks about troubles during the development of the Pokémon Scarlet and Violet DLC, which led to a decision that many fans will be happy about. It seems that the DLC was not planned from the beginning, which led to a bug that affected development. After this issue, “Game Freak mandated that all future games will be programmed assuming DLC will be made.” Which means all future Pokémon games will be made with an expansion in mind. </p>



<p>In other news, read more about Pokémon Gen 10’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-gen-10-leak-reveals-boss-fight-and-mmo-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">boss fight and MMO features</a>. Additionally, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-year-one-anniversary-update-includes-huge-wonder-pick-buff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TCG Pocket’s Year One Anniversary update</a>. What are your thoughts on Pokémon Scarlet and Violet’s DLC costing as much as Legends: Arceus’ entire development?&nbsp;Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-exists-because-ea-were-ds-says-vince-zampella/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vince Zampella stating that Call of Duty only exists because “EA were d***s”</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>. </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-cost-as-much-to-make-as-legends-arceus-leaks-reveal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A Season 1 Ranked—Release Date, Start Time & Rewards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-season-1-ranked-release-date-times-rewards/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-season-1-ranked%E2%80%94release-date-start-time-rewards.1324390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you can’t wait to get stuck into Pokémon Legends: Z-A Season 1’s Ranked mode, you need to hear about its official start date, what time it’s expected to go live, and potential rewards waiting for you if you can be the very best like no one ever was.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-release-date-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> has a different feel to Arceus. From its location to its gameplay mechanics, there are differences across the board. But we’ve not had to wait for the game’s launch to find out everything about the RPG. We already know the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-pokedex/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">complete Pokémon Legends: Z-A Pokédex</a> and its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-preload-guide-file-size-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">file size</a>.</p>



<p>The developer is also keen to keep you all up to date with Season 1 Ranked—and so are we!</p>







<figure><figcaption>A lot to look forward to. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You can write down October 16 in your diary as the start date for Z-A Season 1’s Ranked mode.</strong></p>



<p>Funnily enough, it coincides with the game’s release day! Many new releases wait until some time after launch before going full board with any Season 1 content. If you’re looking forward to <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Pokémon</a> Legends: Z-A’s Ranked content, you won’t have to wait long to get stuck in.</p>







<p><strong>Pokémon has revealed that 6:00 UTC is the official start time for Season 1 Ranked.</strong></p>



<p>Here’s a quick time breakdown of what this looks like for different regions if you’re having trouble converting UTC to your time zone.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Pokémon Legends: Z-A Season 1 Ranked Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">11:00 PM—October 15</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">1:00 AM—October 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">2:00 AM—October 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">British Summer Time (BST)</td><td data-align="center">7:00 AM—October 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">5:00 PM—October 16</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<p><strong>So far, we know you can earn a Greninjite for ranking up in Season 1.</strong></p>



<p>Obviously, there will be a lot more to earn, which we’ll learn about once Season 1 is live. The more battling you do, and the more you win, the better your loot at the end of it!</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Are you already looking to get your competitive edge on in Season 1? Which other Pokémon games have you vigorously taken part in their online modes? Let us know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a>, and also tell us which Pokémon you’re looking to use the most.</p>



<hr>



<p>Also, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-switch-1-vs-switch-2-performance-which-version-should-you-buy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A Switch 1 Vs Switch 2 Performance Guide</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-pokemon-legends-z-a-starters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Pokémon Legends: Z-A Starters And Which Pokémon Can You Choose</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-season-1-ranked-release-date-times-rewards/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Exists Because “EA Were D***s”, Says Vince Zampella]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-exists-because-ea-were-ds-says-vince-zampella/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-exists-because-%E2%80%9Cea-were-d-s%E2%80%9D-says-vince-zampella.1324366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The current lead for the Battlefield franchise has stated that the only reason Call of Duty exists is because EA had a fallout with him. </p>



<p>The Battlefield franchise is back to its victory days with the release of BF6, finally giving the likes of Call of Duty some serious competition. Their last title, Battlefield 2042, didn’t perform well with fans, but the developers have pulled off a complete turnaround, with BF6 reaching <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-beats-call-of-dutys-all-time-concurrent-player-count-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost 750k concurrent players</a> on launch day. </p>



<h2 id="h-vince-zampella-reveals-call-of-duty-is-only-here-because-ea-were-d-s">Vince Zampella Reveals Call of Duty is Only Here Because ‘EA Were D***s’</h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/article/battlefield-6-vince-zampella" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GQ</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/battlefield/call-of-duty-creator-and-current-battlefield-6-head-vince-zampella-says-the-only-reason-that-cod-exists-is-because-ea-were-d-ks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+</a>), Vince Zampella spoke about Call of Duty’s existence. The executive vice president at Electronic Arts stated, “The only reason that&nbsp;Call of Duty&nbsp;exists is because EA were dicks”. For those unaware about Zampella’s past, he left EA after a dispute, only to make Infinity Ward in 2002, which led to the creation of the Call of Duty franchise. He later returned to EA to oversee games such as Titanfall, Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order,&nbsp;and Apex Legends.</p>



<p>Vince Zampella is a true veteran of the shooter genre, delivering players with some of the biggest hits in this space. He started with Medal of Honor: Allied Assault, where we worked closely with Steven Spielberg. After the dispute, Activision tasked him with creating a franchise that would kill Medal of Honor, and that was Call of Duty. However, after that, he returned to EA and is now overseeing the latest big thing in the FPS space, Battlefield. </p>



<p>In other news, Battlefield 6’s campaign offers players <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6s-campaign-tells-you-to-uninstall-when-youre-done/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an uninstall button</a> after completion. Additionally, Black Ops 7 beta matches were nearly 99% cheater-free. What are your thoughts on Call of Duty not existing if Zampella didn’t have a fallout with EA? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-switch-2-release-date-leaks-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Assassin’s Creed Shadows Switch 2 release date leaking online</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-exists-because-ea-were-ds-says-vince-zampella/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sucker Punch Could Make A New Sly Cooper Or inFamous Game After Ghost of Yotei]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-could-make-new-sly-cooper-infamous-game-after-ghost-of-yotei/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sucker-punch-could-make-a-new-sly-cooper-or-infamous-game-after-ghost-of-yotei.1324336/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PlayStation has benefited from the mammoth exclusive launch of Ghost of Yotei—the follow-up to Ghost of Tsushima. Now, Sucker Punch is already looking ahead to a potential Sly Cooper or Infamous game as the next project.</p>



<p>Aside from 1999’s forgotten Rocket: Robot On Wheels, the American-based team known as Sucker Punch Studios got its career firmly on track with 2001’s Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus. This led to a further two Sly games (the fourth being handled by Sanzaru Games), before moving onto the inFamous franchise. 2009 to 2014 saw five separate inFamous experiences, and then it was time for Ghost of Tsushima. </p>



<p>Once <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-best-games-like-ghost-of-yotei/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei</a>‘s Legends multiplayer update has been added, Sucker Punch is weighing up what to do next.</p>



<h2 id="h-going-back-to-sly-a-serious-possibility-for-sucker-punch-studios">“Going Back To Sly” A Serious Possibility For Sucker Punch Studios</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The next samurai story might have to wait. Credit to Sucker Punch</figcaption></figure>



<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.videogamer.com/news/ghost-of-yotei-sucker-punch-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VideoGamer</a>, Sucker Punch studio head and co-founder Brian Fleming said: “Whatever we do next, whether it’s continuing Ghost or going back to Sly, the decision is really more limited by, again, our cherishing of focus and time to iterate, which means that we really can only do one thing at a time”.</p>



<p>Fleming indicates that despite the studio’s size, it can’t do more than one project at a time.</p>



<p>This follows an interview with <a href="https://gameinformer.com/interview/2025/07/17/ghost-of-yotei-directors-share-philosophy-on-balancing-freedom-with-story" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GameInformer</a>, where Ghost of Yotei co-creative director Nate Fox said he “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-director-love-to-work-more-infamous/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Would love Sucker Punch to work on more InFamous</a>.” Again, whatever the company decides, it will likely be the only piece of media the studio develops for a few years.</p>



<p>Sucker Punch Productions has steadily become one of the most prolific and premium game studios in the world. You never hear bad words or controversy about it, and the company goes about its business creating one incredible game after another. With the main bulk of Ghost of Yotei’s development complete—aside from post-launch content—the future could be interesting.</p>



<p>What do you think? Will Sucker Punch listen to the old-school fans crying out for a new Sly or inFamous game? Is a new ‘Ghost’ game to make a trilogy a given? More importantly, what do you want to see from the incredible studio? Share all your thoughts and more through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-year-one-anniversary-update-includes-huge-wonder-pick-buff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon TCG Pocket’s Year One Anniversary Update</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-switch-2-release-date-leaks-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Switch 2 Release Date Leaking Online.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/sucker-punch-could-make-new-sly-cooper-infamous-game-after-ghost-of-yotei/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>