<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:34:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Are the 20 Highest Rated Video Games of 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/these-are-the-20-highest-rated-video-games-of-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/these-are-the-20-highest-rated-video-games-of-2024.1068915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/these-are-the-20-highest-rated-video-games-of-2024/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-74848">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>How many games did you play in 2024? With so many new and hit releases, many of which took us by surprise, it was tough to keep up with the slew of new games launching month after month. We tried, though. Thankfully, it’s a bit easier to pick and choose what to play if you sort by the highest-rated titles of the year, according to <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/browse/game/all/all/current-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metacritic</a>. There are a few titles in here that you’d expect, and a few I’m even surprised by, like UFO 50 and Thank Goodness You’re Here!</p>



<h2 id="h-what-are-the-highest-rated-games-of-the-year">What Are the Highest Rated Games of the Year?</h2>



<p>You’d expect to find plenty of titles here, including The Game Awards’s Game of the Year, Astro Bot, and plenty of top games, like Elden Ring, Metaphor, and Final Fantasy VII Rebirth. </p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Astro Bot (94)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree (94)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Metaphor: ReFantazio (94)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth (92)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Slay the Princess – The Pristine Cut (92)</strong></li>



<li><strong>UFO 50 (91)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Animal Well (91)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Satisfactory (91)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Balatro (90)</strong></li>



<li><strong>The Last of Us Part II Remastered (90)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Thank Goodness You’re Here! (90)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Tekken 8 (90)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Destiny 2: The Final Shape (89)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Tsukihime: A Piece of Blue Glass Moon (89)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Horizon Forbidden West (89)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth (89)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Castlevania Dominus Collection (89)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes (88)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Tactical Breach Wizards (88)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Kill Knight (88)</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Did you manage to play any of the top 20 titles of 2024? Let us know in the comments below!</p>







<h2 id="h-honorable-mention-titles-we-recommend">Honorable Mention Titles We Recommend</h2>



<p>Of course, the top 20 is all well and good, but it’s not a comprehensive list of the best games of the year. That list extends far beyond what most people are willing to read online, so let us offer a few runner-up suggestions that still deserve your attention:</p>



<ul>
<li>Warhammer 40,000: Rogue Trader – Void Shadows</li>



<li>Unicorn Overlord</li>



<li>Silent Hill 2</li>



<li>Mouthwashing</li>



<li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li>



<li>Sons of the Forest</li>



<li>Dragon’s Dogma 2</li>



<li>Frostpunk 2</li>



<li>1000xResist</li>



<li>Crow Country</li>



<li>Forgive Me Father 2</li>



<li>Fear the Spotlight</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>We’d love to hear about your favorite games of 2024! Visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official community forum</a> to discuss the year’s hottest releases and your recommendations with the team!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025/">The Biggest Video Game Releases of January 2025</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>There are numerous big video game releases in January 2025 to look forward to, including Dynasty Warriors, Sniper Elite, and more!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-2024-video-games-you-should-replay/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-2024-video-games-you-should-replay/">The 5 Best 2024 Video Games You Should Replay During Your Holiday Break</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>For many, the holiday season is the only time of the year they get off from work. It’s a chance to sit back on the couch, relax between chores around the house, and play a video game or two. You might even have time to beat one. If you’re on the fence about what to […]</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/5-best-custom-content-for-the-sims-4-holiday-season/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/5-best-custom-content-for-the-sims-4-holiday-season/">5 Best Custom Content for the Sims 4 Holiday Season</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Spice up your holiday season with the best custom content for The Sims 4 holiday season!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-black-master-chief-fortnite-skin/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-black-master-chief-fortnite-skin/">How to Get Black Master Chief Fortnite Skin</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fortnite’s Black Matte Master Chief Skin has been popular for the longest time, and we have the latest on the cosmetic’s status.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Indie Game of 2024—Best New Indie Games This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-indie-game-of-2024-best-new-indie-games-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-indie-game-of-2024%E2%80%94best-new-indie-games-this-year.1068891/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-indie-game-of-2024-best-new-indie-games-this-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Move aside AAA games, it’s time to recognize the lesser-known, not-as-well-funded titles this year. The best 2024 indie titles have delivered immeasurably, with one, in particular, achieving GOTY talk—so let’s go through the contenders and our winner.</p>



<p>Indie games can’t die. While the big-time developers and publishers push big-budget, large-scale-production blockbusters, the lifeblood of indies mustn’t dry up. For every copy-and-paste open-world game, someone has the vision to turn a crab into a soulslike superstar, or have you complete odd jobs in a bizarre English town.</p>



<p>The best indie games of 2024 have all shown ingenuity, and proven they can hang with the big boys, and every nomination on this list deserves to be played.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-indie-title-of-2024-winner-balatro">Best Indie Title of 2024 Winner — Balatro</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You might have guessed it. Credit to LocalThunk</figcaption></figure>



<p>Poker has been around since the 1800s, but I’m sure its creator didn’t think to combine the card game with intricate roguelike mechanics to create an infinitely replayable breakout hit that would go toe-to-toe with multi-million projects for the GOTY crown. This is what LocalThunk have been able to achieve with Balatro.</p>



<p>Balatro starts you off with a traditional deck of 52 cards comprised of four suits going from Ace to King. The format of the game revolves around you beating increasingly tougher decks requiring higher point totals achieved with high-scoring poker hands. Balatro is a basic poker game at its atomic level, but if we break down its complexities, it’s so much more than this.</p>



<p>You can buy Jokers to add devious and cunning modifiers to your deck—increasing the points earned—allowing us to overcome harder “Blinds.” The roguelike loop means failing is encouraged because you learn the intricacies of the mechanics and understand hands and scoring better. Plus, who can resist one “final” run?</p>



<p>Balatro’s impact in 2024 is tangible. It’s a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2024-all-nominees-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game of the Year nominee</a>, already won the Indie Game of the Year award at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/golden-joystick-awards-2024-all-award-winners/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Golden Joystick Awards</a>, and sold well over <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-hits-2-million-units-sold-major-gameplay-update-coming-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">two million copies</a>. Balatro is a simple idea executed flawlessly, and it’s a worthy recipient of our Best Indie Title of 2024 award.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-indie-games-of-2024-nominations">Best Indie Games of 2024 Nominations</h2>



<p>Balatro has us all in, yes, but we haven’t revealed our full hand yet. If you’re tired of the monotony of mainstream gaming, 2024 has produced some whoppers in the indie game category.</p>



<h3 id="h-animal-well">Animal Well</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Unnerving. Credit to Shared Memory</figcaption></figure>



<p>Animal Well makes me uncomfortable from start to finish: The sound design, the enemies, the edgy and retro-inspired visuals—and I love it. It’s a basic, 2D Metroidvania adventure relying on backtracking and memorization to progress, but its array of items and delicate world-building make the journey seamless.</p>



<p>The mini-boss encounters are low-key terrifying, the puzzles are logical and lucid, and the sense of progression is satisfying. I took umbrage with the map which becomes intensely layered and obfuscated the greater it unravels, and the platforming can be a bit floaty. Animal Well was developed by a single person, and this fact alone turns my mind to mush. If you have a weekend to spare, I implore you to check this out as it pushed Balatro close.</p>



<h3 id="h-hades-2">Hades 2</h3>



<figure><figcaption>I can’t wait until this is finished. Credit to Supergiant Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hades is on my Mt. Rushmore of roguelike entries—and it could be all four heads, honestly. Saying goodbye to Zagreus and making merry with Melinoë is tough, but within the first hour, I was saying Zagreus who? The Princess of the Underworld is just as engaging as her brother, and Supergiant Games has pretty much reinvented the Hades universe. New weapons, abilities, and a curious underground and surface mechanic are some of the new additions to the roguelike formula as you battle through brand-new, enemy-filled biomes.</p>



<p>Predictably, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-are-the-hades-2-voice-actors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hades 2</a> misses out because it’s not finished yet. 2024 is only the beginning of the Hades 2 adventure, testing the soul-filled waters of the Underworld with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hades-ii-early-access-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Early Access</a>. Its full release is looking likely for 2025, and there’s every chance this sequel can go one better than a nomination next year.</p>



<h3 id="h-little-kitty-big-city">Little Kitty, Big City</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Honestly, the cat alone could’ve won this. Credit to Double Dagger Studio</figcaption></figure>



<p>Let me preface, I’m a cat person. I’ve owned cats before, and I own cats now. They are the greatest creatures walking the Earth, and I care for them more than most humans. Little Kitty, Big City appeals to the cat connoisseur in me, and everything our purring protagonist does causes me to unconsciously let slip a squeak. Little Kitty, Big City’s charming appeal is letting you be a cat: You nom bread, carelessly walk into people to knock them over, use random objects as scratching posts, and there’s a dedicated meow button—à la Stray.</p>



<p>Its cutesy nature aside, Little Kitty, Big City is a self-contained open-world platformer. The world itself isn’t gigantic, but has lots of depth and verticality. You’re encouraged to explore, find fun side missions, and claim collectibles. It’s not genre-defining, it’s fairly predictable and can be completed in one sitting. Nevertheless, it’s a lot of fun and whiskers away from being a-meowzing.</p>



<h3 id="h-palworld">Palworld</h3>



<figure><figcaption>What a visual. Credit to Pocket Pair</figcaption></figure>



<p>“Pokémon with guns” there, I said it, I said <em>the </em>line. Palworld has been associated with Pokémon since day one, although it’s not hard to understand the comparison. Pocket Pair’s creature-collecting, monster-battling open-world title has a deep Paldeck full of weird and wonderful specimens to fight and befriend. Once you do this, you assign them to various work jobs: Kindling, Lumbering, Transporting, and other labor-intensive tasks—there might be an RSPCA issue here.</p>



<p>The big headline grabbers are the ability to shoot Pals, have them shoot other people, butcher Pals, and even capture humans. Blatant murder and human trafficking aside, Palworld is an extremely diverse RPG. Hopefully, it comes through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-lawsuit-palworld-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo-Palworld lawsuits</a> unscathed and adds to its Early Access build—as this is still a game very much in progress and lacking a bit of depth.</p>



<hr>



<p>So, Balatro scoops the crown for our Best Indie Game of 2024 award. What do you think? Do you agree with our decisions? Or have we missed any out? Let us know, and check out our Best Shooter of 2024, and the biggest games coming in 2025.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Biggest Video Game Releases of January 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025.1068807/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-biggest-video-game-releases-of-january-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Let’s be honest: 2024 was an exceptional year for video games. We had titles such as Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree, Balatro, Astro Bot, The Outlast Trials, UFO 50, Animal Well, and many others to consider. It’s a bit much, honestly. Well, it appears 2025 is keeping up the momentum, as straight off the bat, the video game releases in January 2025 aim to come out swinging!</p>



<h2 id="h-the-hottest-game-releases-of-january-2025">The Hottest Game Releases of January 2025</h2>



<p>When all is said and done, January is still a quiet month regarding video game releases for 2025. We have a few big-name titles returning to the fray, such as Ys Memoire, Turnip Boy, and Dynasty Warriors, but for the most part, it’s a quiet month with more than a few indie titles. For now, let’s focus on the big releases:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Ys Memoire: The Oath in Felghana</strong> – PlayStation 5/PlayStation 4/Nintendo Switch – January 7, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Turnip Boy Robs a Bank</strong> – iOS/Android – January 14, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</strong> – Nintendo Switch – January 16, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</strong> – PC/PlayStation 5/Xbox Series X|S – January 17, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Tales of Graces f Remastered</strong> – PC/PlayStation 4/PlayStation 5/Xbox Series X|S/Nintendo Switch – January 17, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</strong> – PC – January 23, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Tails of Iron II: Whiskers of Winter</strong> – PC/PlayStation 4/PlayStation 5/Xbox Series X|S/Nintendo Switch – January 28, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Sniper Elite: Resistance</strong> – PC/PlayStation 4/PlayStation 5/Xbox One/Xbox Series X|S – January 30, 2025</li>



<li><strong>Spider-Man 2</strong> – PC – January 30, 2025</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-looking-forward-to-february-2025">Looking Forward to February 2025</h2>



<p>While January 2025 is full of some genuinely interesting video game releases, especially for those who love RPGs, it looks like February is going to take the cake. You get to look forward to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Civilization VII</li>



<li>Assassin’s Creed: Shadows</li>



<li>Avowed</li>



<li>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</li>
</ul>



<p>The list for February goes on for seemingly miles, so prepare your wallet and free time!</p>



<hr>



<p>What titles are you most looking forward to in 2025? Let us know down in the comments, or visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a> to talk gaming with the team and our community!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 5 Best 2024 Video Games You Should Replay During Your Holiday Break]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-2024-video-games-you-should-replay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-5-best-2024-video-games-you-should-replay-during-your-holiday-break.1068768/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-2024-video-games-you-should-replay/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>For many, the holiday season is the only time of the year they get off from work. It’s a chance to sit back on the couch, relax between chores around the house, and play a video game or two. You might even have time to beat one. If you’re on the fence about what to play, however, we can help. Here are the five best video game releases from 2024 worth replaying this holiday season!</p>



<h2 id="h-top-5-game-releases-worth-replaying-in-2024">Top 5 Game Releases Worth Replaying in 2024</h2>



<p>It was a big year in gaming, with too many new releases to count, and more than a handful of standout releases. If you were unable to keep up with all the new launches, or have a handful of favorites that you’d like to return to, this holiday season is a good time!</p>



<h3 id="h-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Following the announcement of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-announced-at-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>, which features <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-solo-or-trio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">solo or three-player co-op</a> play, many of us fully intend to return to the world of The Lands Between this holiday season. But more importantly, it’s an excellent time to dive into the expansion, which is absolutely massive and, in some cases, more challenging than the vanilla game.</p>



<h3 id="h-slay-the-princess-the-pristine-cut">Slay the Princess – The Pristine Cut</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>It’s like Groundhog Day but more twisted. Slay the Princess is an existential horror game in which your dialogue choices change the course of the story across various timelines. Each world varies in some way, from a different setting to a different princess altogether, and your choices can either set off a chain of events that end the world or save everyone at a significant cost.</p>



<h3 id="h-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Screenshot by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>While it didn’t fully stick its landing, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is still an exceptional RPG with so much depth and potential. There’s a lot to explore, from countless quests to mini-games to collectibles. It’ll eat up most of your vacation time, and you might finish it if you’re lucky, but now’s a good time to try before the third entry releases.</p>



<h3 id="h-like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth">Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>If you only want to play one game this holiday season, Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth will eat up every second of your free time. It’s a massive, lengthy RPG featuring Ichiban Kasuga, the loveable underdog, and Kazuma Kiryu, the broken fighter, exploring a huge landscape with countless turn-based battles and memorable minigames to play.</p>



<h3 id="h-balatro">Balatro</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to LocalThunk</figcaption></figure>



<p>What’s left to say about Balatro? It’s one of the more unique releases of the past year, focusing on roguelike deck-building and out-there poker mechanics that make for an enthralling experience. It’s one many were hoping would win Game of the Year, though Astro Bot beat it, as expected, but that shouldn’t stop anyone from sitting down for a hand or two or fourteen this holiday season!</p>



<hr>



<p>Don’t forget to visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forum</a> to discuss your favorite titles of 2024!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biggest Games Coming in 2025—Best New Games on PlayStation, Xbox, Switch & PC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-games-coming-in-2025-best-new-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/biggest-games-coming-in-2025%E2%80%94best-new-games-on-playstation-xbox-switch-pc.1068651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-games-coming-in-2025-best-new-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After an epic 2024, it’s already time to look ahead to the biggest games coming out in 2025 across all the major platforms: PlayStation, Xbox, Nintendo Switch, and PC—and it’s good news, many amazing-looking titles are looking to bankrupt us all.</p>



<p>I would argue 2024 didn’t reach the sky-high heights of 2023’s barnstorming 12 months. However, this isn’t to say it was a bad year by any means. RPGs have smashed it with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-success/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-games-coming-in-2025-best-new-games/ReFantazio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Bot</a> brought a new lease of life to 3D platformers, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-has-generated-approximately-4-4-million-on-mobile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Balatro</a>—an underdog indie title—justifiably achieved Game of the Year recognition.</p>



<p>There’s been plenty to enjoy in 2024, but now, we look ahead to the next year. 2025’s biggest projected games are seriously seismic, and my bank account is already worried. Providing we don’t get any delays, here is our projected list of the nine best new games releasing in 2025 across PlayStation, Xbox, Nintendo Switch, and PC.</p>



<h2 id="h-9-best-new-games-releasing-in-2025">9 Best New Games Releasing in 2025</h2>



<p>You can never tell what the gaming industry has up its sleeve. For now, this is our list of top titles expected to come out in 2025, but expect to be blindsided by shadow drops and shock announcements during Summer Game Fest, Gamescom, and the Tokyo Game Show, amongst others.</p>



<h2 id="h-grand-theft-auto-6">Grand Theft Auto 6</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Expect GTA 6 to mirror real life more than ever. Credit to Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>Let’s be honest, if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-gta-6-coming-out-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> does release in 2025, it’s game over for everyone else. Every subsequent launch for about a month  (and beyond) has to contend with millions of players getting stuck into GTA 6. It’s probably already got Game of the Year in the bag, and it’s the<strong> biggest video game ever</strong>. </p>



<p>Rockstar’s track record is about as good as any, and while we’ve seen very little of GTA 6—we don’t need to—what we have seen looks like the meatiest and most engaging GTA project to date. Fingers crossed GTA 6 comes out in 2025, and if it does, we’re already in for one of the best gaming years in recent memory.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for 2025.</p>







<figure><figcaption>SNAAAAAKE. Credit to Konami</figcaption></figure>



<p>The initial Metal Gear Solid Delta Snake trailers show Konami is faithfully recreating the original story and fleshing it out with refined gameplay mechanics. The lifelike graphics are what we come to expect from a Konami production, and the fact a new generation gets to experience the thrill of where the series chronologically began, gives me a beaming smile on my face.</p>



<p>Metal Gear Solid is one of my two favorite franchises ever (God of War being the other) and I’m not making it up when I say <strong>MGS3 is my pick of the bunch</strong>. The fact it’s the first one to get the fully-fledged, next-gen remake treatment warms my soul more than any fire-roasted Kenyan Mangrove Crab could. Welcome back, Big Boss.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for 2025.</p>







<figure><figcaption>Z-A has big shoes to fill. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>In Pokémon Legends: Z-A, we’re in Lumiose City—set in the Kalos region. Again, not much is known about what the new adventure entails. It is another isolated journey in a fixed location, and the debut trailer suggests the game world might be slightly more crowded compared to the quieter nature of Arceus.</p>



<p>Pokémon Legends Arceus deviated from what is considered the norm for a Pokémon game. Its large, open-world design is still relatively new, it moves away from the familiar locales of cities, gyms, and the hustle and bustle of an active Pokémon title, and it features the game-changing attribute of having wild Mon attacking you! Between the flexible catching mechanics, epic Raid-style boss battles, and unique story, Legends Arceus was a bold and beautiful new direction for the franchise. </p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-assassin-s-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Can Ubisoft finally get it right? Credit to Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>2024 was not a good year for Ubisoft</strong>, and its stock might metaphorically and literally might be as low as it’s ever been. Skull &amp; Bones’ hellish development cycle costing hundreds of millions of dollars flopped, Star Wars Outlaws is more low-level rookie than it is heroic wookie, and XDefiant—Ubisoft’s much-hyped Call of Duty killer—is already <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-xdefiant-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shutting down</a> in 2025. Several other Ubisoft games have been canceled, the company is facing countless layoffs, and the public perception of the once-legendary studio isn’t great.</p>



<p>No pressure on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-assassins-creed-red-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> then. The cut-and-dried Ubisoft open-world formula is a big concern heading into the latest AC game. Players are tired of the same routine, collect-a-thons with barebones stories, and a lack of innovation. Shadows can write these wrongs, its 16th-century Japanese setting intrigues, and gameplay footage shows you can be a true assassin once again. Ubisoft needs a big win here, and it could be a true Valentine’s love story if Assassin’s Creed Shadows captures the hearts and minds of its fan base on launch day.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Feb. 14, 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Don’t toy with our emotions, Nintendo. Credit to Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond didn’t have the “Beyond” name for a while, nor did it have any identity, or fill fans with confidence it would ever see the light of day. Metroid Prime 4 was announced at E3 2017 and went through development hell after having its progress restarted. Finally, the June 18, 2024, Nintendo Direct showed us the first-ever gameplay footage of Prime 4.</p>



<p>Two minutes of Morph Ball mayhem, Space Pirate scallywags, and Samus being Samus later, and Metroid Prime fans everywhere are crying—me included. <strong>I fail to see a universe where Metroid Prime 4: Beyond isn’t a GOTY contender</strong>, and even if it’s not, everyone is primed and ready for what’s coming—and Beyond.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-judas">Judas</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Years in the making. Credit to Ghost Story Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>Oh, Ken Levine, where have you been in my life for the last 11 years? The Bioshock trilogy is as consistent as three games get, and Judas is the natural successor to Levine’s masterful trifecta of first-person shooters. <strong>Judas’ core mechanics are akin to System Shock and Bioshock</strong>, and short of having the word “shock” somewhere in the game title, I’m pleased to say the shooter appears to share a lot in common with those who painfully paved the way through Rapture and Columbia.</p>



<p>Your left hand is used for magical powers and elemental enchantments, whereas your right hand is mainly used to fire weapons. I expect another deeply woven story with an assortment of narrative strands taking us in every direction, allowing us to dictate our ending. The enemies manage to look equal parts cutesy, terrifying, and horrifying, and Judas’ biomes are sure to give Levine’s previous work a run for its money.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for March 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-2025">Call of Duty 2025</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We’ve got another job to do. Credit to Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p>CoD titles leaking years in advance is a common occurrence. We already know the 2025 edition of Activision’s multi-billion shooter bonanza is a “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-2-call-of-duty-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">semi-futuristic Black Ops 2 sequel.</a>” It’s under the codename of “Saturn,” and <strong>Call of Duty 2025 is set well in the future</strong>. It remains to be seen if your boots remain on the ground—I hope so—but what is going to be seen is an assortment of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cod-2024-black-ops/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops map remakes</a>.</p>



<p>BLOPS campaigns are always a blast, so it should be fun to see where the franchise goes next. Call of Duty 2025 should have no connection to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6</a>, and we expect more leaks to come out of thin air like a ramp-propelled RC-XD. Stay tuned for further developments throughout 2025.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Rumored for October / November 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-donkey-kong-country-returns-hd">Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A beloved classic is back. Credit to Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>Oddly, we haven’t had an original Donkey Kong game in a while, but Donkey Kong Country Returns HD should suffice. In the same way, 2018’s Donkey Kong Country: Tropical Freeze was a port of the OG 2014 release, Donkey Kong Country Returns HD is a sprucing up of 2010’s Donkey Kong Country Returns—first debuting on the Nintendo Wii.</p>



<p>You know what to expect with Donkey Kong Country Returns HD, and even if you’ve played it before, it might be worth swinging into the jungle one more time—you’d be bananas if you didn’t, so stop monkeying around.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Jan. 16, 2025.</p>



<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Monster Hunter be wild. Credit to Capcom</figcaption></figure>



<p>It can be argued that 2018’s Monster Hunter: World catapulted the long-running series into the marquee: Finally achieving worldwide superstardom. A metaphorical sleeping beast is now very much awake. The attention Monster Hunter: Wilds has gotten already—thanks to exposure from PlayStation Showcases and similar presentations—shows Capcom’s monster-maiming franchise is escalating at a monstrous (pun intended) rate.</p>



<p><strong>Monster Hunter: Wilds incorporates more naturalism and realism</strong>, it’s catering to fans both old and new, and features a slew of new monsters waiting to be slain or saved. The first open beta alone attracted half a million players on Steam, and you can tell Capcom is chomping at the bit to make Wilds larger than life.</p>



<p><strong>Release Date: </strong>Feb. 28, 2025.</p>



<hr>



<p>Please let us know your most anticipated games of 2025 down below. It’s sure to be a great year, and also be sure to check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/our-favorite-playstation-games-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">favorite PlayStation games ever</a> and see if you agree with any.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to WIN PRIZES this Xmas and receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>