<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:25:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 ‘Connection Lost’ Steam Error Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-connection-lost-steam-error-fix/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-%E2%80%98connection-lost%E2%80%99-steam-error-explained.1337842/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Following the deployment of the 1.1.1.0 update in Battlefield 6, Steam players worldwide have been met with a ‘Connection Lost’ error message when trying to access the Battlefield 6 campaign. This has been addressed by Electronic Arts as a known issue, but the team has yet to provide further updates regarding a resolution.</p>



<p>In this snapshot guide, we’ll help you understand the Steam ‘Connection Lost’ error in Battlefield 6, and provide information on how to get around it.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-fix-connection-lost-error">How to Fix Connection Lost Error</h2>



<p>If you’re booting Battlefield 6 through Steam and getting a ‘Connection Lost’ error in the campaign, there are a few things you can try to workaround the issue.</p>



<p>First, <strong>restart the game and quit the Steam launcher entirely, rebooting both after a few seconds</strong>. This will clear your sessions and refresh your login to both Steam and Battlefield 6.</p>



<p>Second, you can try to <strong>power cycle your router and modem</strong>, refreshing your networking connection and resetting your WAN IP to hopefully fix routing issues, if that’s the problem.</p>



<p>If you can, <strong>switch from Wi-Fi to Ethernet </strong>to eliminate any residual issues with internet speed or capabilities. As a rule, gaming is best done with an Ethernet connection, as this offers uninterrupted, unbroken links.</p>



<p>Finally, <strong>disable any VPN or proxy services </strong>that you might be using, as this can cause a direct conflict with EA’s systems and servers.</p>



<p>If you want to go <strong>even deeper </strong>with network-related fixes, you can try to change your DNS settings, flush your DNS cache, or even fully reinstall Battlefield 6.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>We’re aware some Steam players are encountering a “Connection Lost” message when launching the Battlefield 6 campaign. Stay tuned for further updates as the team investigates this issue.</p><p>Thank you for your patience.</p></div>— Battlefield Comms (@BattlefieldComm) <a href="https://twitter.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1983405982584844292?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 29, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<h3 id="h-steam-specific-fixes">Steam-Specific Fixes</h3>



<p>Some users have had luck fixing the Connection Lost Battlefield 6 error by enabling Steam’s Beta Client.</p>



<p>Here’s how you do this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Open Steam</li>



<li>Click Steam &gt; Settings &gt; Interface</li>



<li>Under ‘Client Beta Participation’, select ‘Steam Beta Update’</li>



<li>Then restart Steam</li>
</ul>



<p>In the meantime, it’s worth staying connected to the <a href="https://help.ea.com/en/server-status/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA server status page</a> and following the <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield Comms page</a> on social media to stay up to date with all the issues ongoing in Battlefield 6.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’ve had any luck fixing the Connection Lost error in Battlefield 6.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-review-br-warzone-coded/">Battlefield REDSEC review</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-connection-lost-steam-error-fix/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield REDSEC Review—A Solid BR But Very Warzone Coded]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-review-br-warzone-coded/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-redsec-review%E2%80%94a-solid-br-but-very-warzone-coded.1337836/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6’s REDSEC platform is now open for all to access, and as a free-to-play Battle Royale game, it’s doing exactly what you’d expect. There’s a large, open map, a couple of battle passes to choose from, a bunch of missions to resolve in-game, and an ever-shrinking circle of death that eventually strangles the entire lobby.</p>



<p>It’s Warzone-coded, and in many ways, that makes sense, because the leadership team piecing REDSEC together has that in their blood. Ultimately, REDSEC doesn’t offer anything in the way of any huge innovations on the Battle Royale genre, but it <strong>is </strong>a decent entry into the space that should at least be tried.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-battlefield-redsec-any-good">Is Battlefield REDSEC Any Good?</h2>



<p>As a Battle Royale title, Battlefield REDSEC is everything you could hope for. Players parachute into a map from helicopters, picking their landing zone from a series of POIs, looting crates, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-battle-royale-missions/">kick-starting missions</a>, and fighting other players. As the game clock ticks over, the playable zone shrinks, surrounded by a ring of deadly fire.</p>



<p>It’s the same concept as Firestorm, the Battlefield 5 BR mode introduced almost seven years ago, which more or less fell flat on its face.</p>



<p>REDSEC offers all the trappings of Battlefield 6. The weapons, characters, equipment, vehicles, and movement mechanics are all pulled from the central experience, which is itself a fantastic offering. On the surface, REDSEC feels great to play; the movement is smooth and fluid, and the core elements of a Battlefield game, such as intense destruction, are&nbsp;present.</p>



<p>As you explore Fort Lyndon, the map in REDSEC, you’ll find ‘killstreaks’, challenges <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-tanks-in-battlefield-redsec-battle-royale/">to unlock tanks</a> and other powerful vehicles, custom weapon drops, and kits that you can use to upgrade weapons on the fly.</p>



<p>This is where the innovations that <strong>do exist </strong>start to leech into the game, and it’s also where we see some cross-collaborative innovations coming over from games like Apex Legends, also published by Electronic Arts.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Even the Double XP token system is pulled clean from Call of Duty</figcaption></figure>







<p>It’s good, but I couldn’t help but feel I was playing Warzone at times, which isn’t what you want from <strong>a direct competitor</strong>. Everything from the double XP token structure to the battle pass mechanics, and from the nature of side missions to the loadout features, REDSEC simply smacks of Call of Duty: Warzone.</p>







<h2 id="h-redsec-proves-battle-royale-is-still-going-strong">REDSEC Proves Battle Royale is Still Going Strong</h2>



<p>The Battle Royale genre is an ebb-and-flow kind of thing that never seems consistent. It has been populated over the years with multiple games, and once upon a time, developers in fringe titles threw their hat in the ring to see what they could do.</p>



<p>With that, I mean that even games like Forza Horizon and Fallout 76 once had Battle Royale modes.</p>



<p>The hype surrounding REDSEC was palpable, and going into the game at launch, players were met with sizeable queues. There was a spike in traffic on streaming and content platforms, and player counts had a nice injection of energy, with Battlefield and Call of Duty fans alike eager to explore this free-to-play BR platform.</p>



<p>Even after more than a decade, the concept of the Battle Royale remains a winning one, and REDSEC takes the ball and runs with it, producing something laden with potential that might just be stable enough to challenge the likes of Warzone. </p>



<p>There’s a learning curve for sure, especially concerning the destruction capabilities of the game and some of the movement and weapon handling mechanics, but I feel that this is as accessible a Battle Royale as you could hope for.</p>



<figure><figcaption>The Battlefield REDSEC map is deeply Californian</figcaption></figure>







<p>The map is great, too. It’s the kind of environment I love, fusing urban biomes with natural regions and a touch of mountainous, desert areas. It’s diverse, large enough to accommodate the player count without feeling enormous, and has plenty of nooks to explore.</p>



<h6><strong>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-review-multiplayer-campaign/">Full Battlefield 6 Review</a></strong></h6>



<h2 id="h-but-it-s-not-perfect">But It’s Not Perfect</h2>



<p>REDSEC has had issues at launch. When I played, I experienced more than my fair share of bugs and glitches:</p>



<ul>
<li>Network instability causing packet loss and rubber banding</li>



<li>Dynamic elements like custom weapon drops floating in midair</li>



<li>Weapon crates duplicating on interaction and falling into each other</li>



<li>Players falling under the map (and staying there)</li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-battle-royale-redeploy-teammates/">Redeploy towers</a> throwing teammates into the fire</li>
</ul>



<p>Teething issues are commonplace these days, and it’s hardly fair to take points away from the game, but you’d imagine that REDSEC would launch in a better state given the consistency of the multiplayer platform and how much stock Electronic Arts (and associated studios) have poured into the Battle Royale platform.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Being so close to Warzone, can REDSEC ultimately escape the competition?</figcaption></figure>







<p>If you’re going to give REDSEC a try, I’d recommend picking up a battle pass (ideally the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-bf-pro-battle-pass-worth-it-battlefield-6-rewards/">BF Pro battle pass</a>) if you think you’re going to sink a few hours into it. It adds another layer of meat to the bones of the game, and you’ll have a bit more to aim for. The core gameplay loop is fulfilling enough, but BRs have a tendency to get dull quite quickly under the strain of repetition.</p>



<p>Time will tell how Electronic Arts treats Battlefield REDSEC. For now, it’s a great Battle Royale title that has everything you’d expect from a Battlefield bolt-on, and I’m certainly going to invest more than a few hours into it.</p>



<h2 id="h-verdict-4-5-great">Verdict: 4/5 – ‘Great’</h2>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> what you think of Battlefield REDSEC.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the recent <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-update-1-1-1-0-patch-notes-full/">patch notes for Battlefield 6’s 1.1.1.0 update</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-review-br-warzone-coded/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embark Studios is Developing Two More Games, One of Which is ‘Edgy’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/embark-studios-developing-two-more-games-edgy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embark-studios-is-developing-two-more-games-one-of-which-is-%E2%80%98edgy%E2%80%99.1337830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders is about to hit the market, introducing to the world one of the most popular extraction shooters around. For Embark Studios, it follows the earlier launch of The Finals, an arena-based, destructive first-person shooter that served as the studio’s debut title.</p>



<p>Embark Studios isn’t done when ARC Raiders is out, though. In a recent interview, the studio’s CEO, Patrick Soderlund, confirmed that the team is working on <strong>two new games</strong>, one of which has ‘a lot more edge to it’ than ARC Raiders or The Finals.</p>



<h2 id="h-but-the-other-is-more-conventional">But The Other is More Conventional</h2>



<p>In a recent interview with The Game Business, Embark’s CEO sat down to talk about the studio, its evolution, the release of ARC Raiders, and where things go from here. In one segment, the CEO, Patrick Soderlund, was asked about what other games are in development at the studio.</p>



<p>These projects are in the earlier, more conceptual stages, but there are <strong>two </strong>being pieced together. When asked if they’re all online games, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ONLWtl85bjU&amp;t=2141s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Soderlund explained</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>That I think is just ingrained in our DNA. That doesn’t mean that they’re online games the same way as The Finals or ARC Raiders. One of the concepts we have, I would say, has a lot more <strong>edge </strong>to it than The Finals or ARC Raiders does.</p>



<p>The other one maybe is a little bit more conventional.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Embark Studios has gone from strength to strength in the last few years, and the imminent arrival of ARC Raiders is a testament to the work the studio has put in. This is arguably going to be the most exciting and anticipated extraction shooter ever made, if the numbers are anything to go by.</p>



<p>In recent weeks, the extraction genre has skyrocketed, particularly with the arrival of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-sells-1-million-copies/">Escape from Duckov</a>, a parody title that has sold millions of copies in just a couple of weeks.</p>



<p>What kind of game do you think Embark Studios should make next? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bully-online-announced-huge-catch/">Bully Online has been announced… Kind of</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/embark-studios-developing-two-more-games-edgy/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#871)—Clues and Answers for Wednesday, October 29]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-29-871/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-871-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-wednesday-october-29.1337824/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s the middle of the week, and regardless of what your plans are for the day ahead, I’ve got the latest NYT Connections hints that you need to dominate today’s puzzle. It’s a tricky one today, and there are some very clever answers, but if you’re stumped, just read on to get the answers you need.</p>



<p>The top NYT Connections hints await.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-october-29">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (October 29)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #871:</p>



<ul>
<li>BACKBONE</li>



<li>MEDIUM</li>



<li>VENUE</li>



<li>SCRABBLE</li>



<li>SPIRIT</li>



<li>COMPUTER KEYBOARD</li>



<li>SACRUM</li>



<li>COURAGE</li>



<li>PLATFORM</li>



<li>SEYCHELLES</li>



<li>HEART</li>



<li>OUIJA BOARD</li>



<li>SEITAN</li>



<li>OUTLET</li>



<li>SÉANCE</li>



<li>ABECEDARIUM</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>These words all relate to qualities that represent someone’s core or emotional resilience</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Each term is a way to deliver content or host experiences</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>Each word is fun to ‘say’</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each term covers the full A to Z</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, October 29.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-october-29-871">NYT Connections Answers for Today, October 29 (#871)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– BACKBONE, COURAGE, HEART, SPIRIT</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – MEDIUM, OUTLET, PLATFORM, VENUE</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – SACRUM, SEITAN, SEYCHELLES, SÉANCE</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – ABECEDARIUM, COMPUTER KEYBOARD, OUIJA BOARD, SCRABBLE</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-29-871/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Playable Prototype of Pokémon Pokopia Has Leaked Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-playable-prototype-leak-teraleak-nintendo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-playable-prototype-of-pok%C3%A9mon-pokopia-has-leaked-online.1337740/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>An early prototype of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-announced-for-2026-nintendo-switch-2-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Pokopia</a>, Nintendo’s upcoming farming sim, has leaked online. Furthermore, it is fully playable in Unity and verified by the recent Teraleak.</p>



<p>Revealed earlier this year, Pokémon Pokopia is a joint collaboration between Koei Tecmo and Nintendo. The life-sim lets you play as a humanoid Ditto, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-dev-responds-to-pokopia-and-palfarm-comparisons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">befriending different Pokémon</a> and building a life for themselves. With crafting and farming, the title is one of 2026’s most anticipated games. However, it seems an early playable prototype of the title has been leaked, as well as information regarding its development.</p>



<h2 id="h-pokemon-pokopia-prototype-leaks-online-features-pixel-art-style">Pokémon Pokopia Prototype Leaks Online, Features Pixel-Art Style</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Teraleak: A complete unreleased prototype of Pokopia has been found, and we have the full Unity source code.</p><p>Pokopia originally looked a lot more like Stardew Valley than Minecraft. You would assign your Pokémon to build and harvest resources.</p><p> <a href="https://t.co/oNryTNkZNP">pic.twitter.com/oNryTNkZNP</a></p></div>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/1983243634729165265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 28, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>The leak first came from RyDawgE, who was then verified by the infamous Centro Leaks, who previously revealed much of Pokémon’s future with the Teraleak, like Gen 10. In a Twitter/X post, RyDawgE <a href="https://x.com/RyDawgE_/status/1983010050663751705" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">captured in-game screenshots</a> and footage of an early prototype of Pokémon Pokopia. Centro Leaks then posted <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1983243634729165265">video footage of an early prototype</a>, seen above, and linked the apparent source code of the prototype, allowing anyone to play it on Unity.&nbsp;The leaker also claims that the project was originally all Game Freak before being outsourced to Koei Tecmo.</p>



<p>As you can see from the leak, Pokémon Pokopia looks quite different than what was revealed this year. Instead of the 3D style we know, it’s entirely pixel-art, similar to Stardew Valley. Early reports mention that the game was originally <a href="https://nintendoeverything.com/pokemon-pokopia-nintendo-switch-1-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a Nintendo Switch 1 title</a> and a successor to Pokémon: Let’s Go from the Teraleak. Fans online have expressed enthusiasm over the art style and visuals, as it feels reminiscent of older titles. While knowing this is what the game could’ve been, it does seem like, if this is what the final product will play like, it’ll be a great one.</p>



<p>What do you think about Pokémon Pokopia’s early prototype? Do you wish the game kept the pixel art style? Has it made you more or less excited for the full release in 2026? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Pokémon, check out our guides for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trading-stone-special-evolutions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-first-week-sales-nintendo-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its impressive sales</a>. Don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a> for more Insider Gaming!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-playable-prototype-leak-teraleak-nintendo/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft CEO Wants Games ‘To Be On Every Platform’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-xbox-games-every-platform-playstation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-ceo-wants-games-%E2%80%98to-be-on-every-platform%E2%80%99.1337617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, the company <strong>wants to put its games “on every platform”</strong>. Just recently, Halo: Campaign Evolved, a remake of Combat Evolved, is now <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-campaign-evolved-remake-playstation-announcement-xbox-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">heading to PlayStation consoles</a> at launch, a first for the series.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-possibly-considering-gears-of-war-playstation-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gears of War: Reloaded</a> made the jump to PlayStation 5, as will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-ps5-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Flight Simulator 2025</a>. Many Xbox exclusives have slowly been heading to different consoles. Now, it seems this is the start of many, maybe even ending the exclusivity fans have come to respect forever.</p>



<h2 id="h-microsoft-wants-its-games-to-be-everywhere-says-ceo-satya-nadella">Microsoft Wants Its Games To Be Everywhere, Says CEO Satya Nadella</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The consoles wars are now over. What does that mean for Microsoft's gaming business model?</p><p>"We just want to make sure the games are being enjoyed by gamers everywhere; consoles, PC, mobile, cloud, or TV." – <a href="https://twitter.com/satyanadella?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@satyanadella</a> <a href="https://t.co/AOGf3mj0Kf">pic.twitter.com/AOGf3mj0Kf</a></p></div>— TBPN (@tbpn) <a href="https://twitter.com/tbpn/status/1983248873335468142?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 28, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>The news comes from <a href="https://x.com/tbpn/status/1983248873335468142" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TBPN</a>, as the group chatted with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella about the company’s new partnership with OpenAI. The CEO talks a bit about Xbox and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/white-house-uses-ai-donald-trump-master-chief/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘end’ of the console wars</a>. In the clip, <a href="https://x.com/stephentotilo/status/1983255817785597980" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">transcribed by GameFile’s Stephen Totilo</a>, Nadella states,</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Remember, the biggest gaming business is the Windows business,” says Nadella to TBPN. “To us, gaming on Windows, and of course Steam – has built a massive marketplace on top of it and done a very successful job of it.&nbsp;So to us, the way we are thinking about gaming is; let’s first of all, now we are the largest publisher, after the Activision [deal] so therefore we want to be a fantastic publisher, similar approach to what we did with Office. <strong>We’re going to be everywhere, in every platform</strong>. We want to make sure, whether it’s consoles, whether it’s the PC, whether it’s mobile, whether it’s cloud gaming – or the TV; <strong>we just want to make sure the games are being enjoyed by gamers everywhere</strong>.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s not too surprising to see Microsoft and Xbox shed the exclusivity factor. Many games, like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-sales-drop-about-90-in-japan/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a>, sold less than stellar due to sticking to one console. While it’s franchises, especially Halo, never seemed to have that problem, it may lead to more sales. Still, the recent shift, plus <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-is-outpacing-ps4-while-xbox-series-trails-xbox-one-in-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lackluster sales of Xbox Series X|S</a>, do ring out a touch off for the once-influential company. Whether it’s next console, rumored for a 2027 release, is going to include big changes is unclear.</p>



<p>What do you think of Satya Nadella’s comment on bringing Xbox games everywhere? Is it too ambitious? Too risky? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Xbox, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-insomniacs-spider-man-will-be-playable-on-next-xbox-console/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">possible PlayStation games</a> on next-gen Xbox and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-will-not-mandate-the-use-of-ai-confirms-phil-spencer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its AI stance</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-xbox-games-every-platform-playstation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New World Ends Development Following Amazon Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-development-cancelled-amazon-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-world-ends-development-following-amazon-layoffs.1337599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Following <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-games-twitch-hit-by-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Amazon layoffs</a>, <strong>New World is stopping development</strong> and ending with Season 10 and the recent Nighthaven update. The news comes after more than 14,000 were let go from Amazon and its affiliates like Twitch. </p>



<p>Released in 2021 on PC and in 2024 for consoles, New World, also known as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-aeternum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">New World Aeternum</a>, is an MMORPG from Amazon Games. It was revealed as one of three titles announced to be in development for Amazon. New World was the only one to succeed, despite abandoning its original free-to-play entry. Unfortunately, the game’s journey will stop here, unfortunately ending development and future updates.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-world-ending-with-season-10-after-amazon-layoffs-servers-shutting-down-after-2026">New World Ending with Season 10 After Amazon Layoffs, Servers Shutting Down After 2026</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In a statement from <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/update-on-new-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the New World team</a> on the official website, development on the game has ended. According to the team, <strong>further support is no longer sustainable</strong> and have pulled the cord. The recent Season 10 and Nighthaven update, which launched earlier this month, are the final updates. <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/update-on-new-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">In the blog</a>, the team states,</p>



<blockquote>
<p>After four years of steady content updates and a major new console release, <strong>we’ve reached a point where it is no longer sustainable to continue supporting the game with new content updates</strong>. The recently launched Season 10 and Nighthaven update will serve as the final content release for&nbsp;<em>New World</em>&nbsp;on PC and consoles. It is only after much consideration that we’ve reached this decision.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Both the Nighthaven and Rise of the Angry Earth updates are now free for fans on PC and Aeternum will remain on PS+ Premium and Extra for the time being. <strong>Servers for New World will remain open through 2026</strong>, with more information regarding the game’s future to be revealed at a later date. </p>



<p>While not stated in the blog, the team was hit with multiple firings due to today’s massive-scale Amazon layoff. A report from Bloomberg, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazon-games-twitch-hit-by-layoffs/">which we wrote on</a>, said that Amazon’s game studios were hit hard. Specifically, the layoffs were felt hardest for teams developing MMOs, like Amazon Game Studios. Sadly, this will likely be the first of many bad news stories surrounding the topic, as the studios were working on multiple new titles that are now in jeopardy.</p>



<p>What do you think about New World’s sudden cancellation? What’s your opinion on the Amazon layoffs? Let us know in the comments and on the official Insider Gaming Discord!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Amazon news, check out our articles on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/emiru-statement-after-twitch-assault-twitchcon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TwitchCon Emiru incident</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-tv-amazon-casting-call-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked God of War casting call</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a> to keep up to date on everything gaming.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-development-cancelled-amazon-layoffs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>