<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:32:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Reportedly Cutting RTX 50 Series Production In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-cutting-rtx-50-series-production-2026/</link>
            <guid>1387210</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-166751">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The memory shortage is hitting the GPU market. A new report suggest Nvidia is preparing to cut down on production of its GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards.</p>



<p>According to Chinese outlet <a href="http://www.boardchannels.com.cn/thread-130069-1-1.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">BoBantang</a> via <a href="https://benchlife.info/nvidia-will-adjust-geforce-rtx-50-suppy-due-gddr7-shortage/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Benchlife</a>, Nvidia is looking to reduce supply of the latest series of cards by as much as 30-40% compared to the first half of 2025. The report adds that this is being done due to the memory shortage for GDDR6 and GDDR7 RAM. Across the industry, this shortage has seen <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-ram-costs-more-than-new-graphics-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">consumer prices skyrocket</a> as AI companies buy up all of the available supply.</p>







<p>In addition to the original report, Benchlife adds that various AIC partners and suppliers have told the outlet that the first cards to likely be cut back are the GeForce RTX 5070 Ti and GeForce RTX 5060Ti 16GB.</p>



<p>As of publishing, Nvidia hasn’t confirmed or denied the report. Insider Gaming has made attempts to contact Nvidia for an official statement on the matter, but, so far, all requests have gone unanswered. Should one come, it will be added to this story. </p>



<p>What do you think of other areas of consumer PC components being impacted by the over-expansion of AI centers? Leave your thoughts in the comments down below and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>. </p>







<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Tech news, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/micron-shutting-down-its-consumer-crucial-ram-and-ssd-brand/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Micron shutting down its consumer</a> SSD and RAM brand, Crucial. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-cutting-rtx-50-series-production-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light 2’s New Winter Update Includes Beastly ‘Evolving’ Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-2-winter-update-evolving-bundle/</link>
            <guid>1387156</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Techland is pushing out the first major update for Dying Light 2: Stay Human for some time. Now that Dying Light: The Beast is in the open and doing well, the team has reverted to focus more on the live-service Dying Light 2, which was released back in 2022. The new winter update is dubbed ‘Winter Tales: Gifts from Above 2025’, and it comes with some neat content.</p>



<p>This fresh update also boasts a new bundle called <strong>The Evolving Bundle</strong>. It’s an interactive set that gets better once you’ve bought it, with the various items in the set <em>evolving </em>and taking on new forms.</p>







<h2 id="h-winter-has-come-to-villedor">Winter Has Come to Villedor</h2>



<p>The festive theme lands in Villedor once a year, blanketing the map in challenges, exclusive rewards, and seasonal activities.</p>



<p>In a new press release published by Techland, the return of <strong>Baka </strong>was highlighted:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>Baka is back in the Villedor</strong>&nbsp;with a set of new bounties for players to complete, progressing with him will unlock items in his shop based on the level players are at. These items can be bought with Candies collected from killing seasonal zombie enemies – including Naughty Biters, Naughty Bolters, Naughty Virals, Uncle Snow, and Ice Spitters.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If you complete enough challenges, you’ll get your ‘Letter to Santa’ from Baka, which triggers a special airdrop guarded by fearsome enemies.</p>



<p>From today, December 18, community goals are being kick-started to allow players access to even more gear. Here’s the spread of challenges coming up:</p>



<ul>
<li>December 18 – December 23 – Week 1: Kill Naughty Biters – rewards include the Glacier Shank Knife and Snow Season Ornament Charm</li>



<li>December 23 – December 30 – Week 2: Kill Naughty Virals – rewards include The Guiding Star Mace and Gift Season Ornament Charm.&nbsp;</li>



<li>December 30 – January 8 – Week 3: Kill Uncle Snow – rewards include the Fractal Frost Axe&nbsp;and New Year’s Ornament Charm.</li>
</ul>



<p>One of the more unique elements of the Winter Update in Dying Light 2: Stay Human is the new <strong>Evolving Bundle</strong>. This has been dubbed ‘the first of its kind’, suggesting that more are coming, and this is why it’s so important for fans of the franchise:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The first bundle of that kind is the&nbsp;<strong>Night Wolf Evolving Bundle</strong>&nbsp;which evolves into the Crimson Werewolf set as players progress through a four-part questline. This way players can acquire two versions of a powerful rifle, an outfit, six gear pieces, and a paraglider skin. The bundle also contains the Wolf’s Claws melee weapon and an exclusive grappling hook variant.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As you play the new questline, you’ll see your weapons and equipment evolving before your eyes, which is a super neat touch.</p>



<p>This announcement was made in addition to the team at Techland highlighting big discounts across the Dying Light franchise, which includes Dying Light: The Beast being up to 20% off right now.</p>







<p>Are you going back to Villedor to check out the Winter Update? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/world-war-z-is-getting-a-the-walking-dead-crossover-in-january/">World War Z is getting a Walking Dead crossover</a></p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/dying-light-2-winter-update-evolving-bundle/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>