<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 20:11:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Backyard Baseball Launches July 9]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-backyard-baseball-launches-july-9/</link>
            <guid>1447612</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Get ready to head back to the backyard for an all-new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/backyard-baseball/" id="2001">Backyard Baseball</a> title. Appropriately enough, it should make everyone’s summer vacation a little more lively as the game launches on July 9, 2026.</p>



<p>The release date for the upcoming title was announced on social media. The game is being developed by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/mega-cat-studios/" id="3592">Mega Cat Studios</a>, and they’ve ported several classic <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/backyard-sports/" id="1860">Backyard Sports</a> titles to PC via Steam. This forthcoming release will be playable on PC and Mac and will get console releases.</p>



<figure></figure>







<h2>History of Backyard Sports</h2>



<p>The first Backyard Baseball was released in 1997. The games were minimalistic PC titles featuring a diverse roster of children playing many sports, the first of which was Backyard Baseball. Games eventually made it to platforms such as the original Sony PlayStation, the PlayStation 2, the Nintendo GameCube, and the Nintendo Game Boy Advance. Still, they were always available on home computers through 2009.</p>



<p>The football version of Backyard Sports even spun off an animated special in 2002.</p>



<p>Now, a new generation of children, not to mention adults looking for the nostalgic hit of that silly sports game that they might have picked up at a Scholastic Book Fair, will get the chance to play an all-new Backyard Baseball this summer.</p>







<h2>PC Specs for Backyard Baseball 2026</h2>



<p>The 4th coming game will feature six different game modes with three ways to play. There will also be achievements, unlockables, and collectibles. However, the developers are boasting that this game won’t have microtransactions.</p>



<p>The minimum required PC specs have been made available. Check them out below:</p>



<h4 id="h-minimum-os-windows-10-64-bit-latest-update-processor-intel-core-i3-6100-3-7ghz-or-amd-athlon-x4-88k-4ghz-memory-8-gb-ram-graphics-nvidia-gtx-660-2gb-or-amd-radeon-hd-7850-2gb-directx-version-12-network-broadband-internet-connection-storage-13-gb-available-space-recommended-os-windows-10-or-newer-processor-intel-i76700k-amd-ryzen-7-3700x-memory-16-gb-ram-graphics-radeon-rx5600-xt-nvidia-gtx-1070-directx-version-12-network-broadband-internet-connection-storage-13-gb-available-space">Minimum:<br>OS: Windows 10 – 64-Bit (Latest Update)<br>Processor: Intel Core i3-6100 @3.7GHz or AMD Athlon X4 88K @4GHz<br>Memory: 8 GB RAM<br>Graphics: NVIDIA GTX 660 2GB or AMD Radeon HD 7850 2GB<br>DirectX: Version 12<br>Network: Broadband Internet connection<br>Storage: 13 GB available space<br>Recommended:<br>OS: Windows 10 or newer<br>Processor: Intel i76700K/AMD Ryzen 7 3700X<br>Memory: 16 GB RAM<br>Graphics: Radeon RX5600 XT/ Nvidia GTX 1070<br>DirectX: Version 12<br>Network: Broadband Internet connection<br>Storage: 13 GB available space</h4>



<hr>



<p>Will you be picking up the new backyard baseball release? Did you play the Backyard Sports games frequently as a child? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-backyard-baseball-launches-july-9/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent Pulled Funding After Highguard’s Rough Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-pulled-funding-after-highguards-rough-launch/</link>
            <guid>1447540</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New details have emerged regarding Highguard’s downfall. A new report notes that Tencent pulled <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-developer-backed-tencent/" id="177492">its funding</a> for the game, leading to the mass layoffs at Wildlight Entertainment. While not confirmed, it is believed that financing was contingent upon the game hitting certain metrics, such as a strong retention rate.</p>



<p>This new report <span>from<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2026-02-26/the-story-behind-the-failure-of-highguard?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc3MjEyNjY2MSwiZXhwIjoxNzcyNzMxNDYxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUQjJURlpLR0lGVDEwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.ty0kXKqfEl28WgD25I4hsgwQZcpJq_K3n3AVsJXMoWc&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" target="_blank">&nbsp;Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier</a></span> notes that fewer than 20 people remain at Wildlight Entertainment. The organization had announced a major restructuring in the wake of Highguard’s rough launch. News of the lack of funding came in a meeting on February 11, only two weeks after the game was launched.</p>







<h2 id="h-highguard-devs-suggest-that-leadership-s-pride-came-before-the-fall">Highguard Devs Suggest That Leadership’s Pride Came Before the Fall</h2>



<p>The report notes that several team members used the word “hubris” when asked what went wrong with the launch. There was a belief that the company’s leadership felt they could recapture the success of Apex Legends, a title they’d worked on previously, without recognizing the changing landscape of gaming. </p>



<p>As of this writing, the game has 362 concurrent players. The peak in the last 24 hours was just over 600.</p>



<p>The downsized development team remains committed to improving Highguard. You can read the full statement following the restructuring <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-developer-wildlight-entertainment-has-mass-layoffs/" id="175994">at this link</a>. Also, check out what one of the former artists who worked on the project <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/laid-off-highguard-tech-artist-reflects-on-games-launch/" id="176282">had to say about its difficult launch.</a></p>







<p>For more news concerning the fate of games with rough launches, learn more about the plans to shut down the servers of Amazon’s King of Meat video game. Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>



<hr>



<p>How do you feel about what ultimately became of Highguard? Did you play the game? Do you have hopes that it will continue on and find its audience? Sound off in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Discord server.</a> </p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tencent-pulled-funding-after-highguards-rough-launch/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>