<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:54:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Owners Can Play One of the Best RPGs Ever Made For Free This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-owners-best-rpg-ever-made-free-this-weekend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-owners-can-play-one-of-the-best-rpgs-ever-made-for-free-this-weekend.1346605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Warhorse Studios, the creator of the Kingdom Come franchise, has revealed that the second game in the critically-acclaimed series is <strong>free to play </strong>this weekend, exclusively on Xbox. Earlier this year, Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 was released to an overwhelmingly positive reception, and many believe it’s lining up for several Game of the Year awards.</p>



<p>It’s the twilight period for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2, with the game’s final DLC dropping soon, bringing an end to years of development and evolution. If you’ve never played the ambitious open-world epic, now is the time.</p>



<h2 id="h-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-is-free-this-weekend">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 is Free This Weekend</h2>



<p>If you own an Xbox Series X or an Xbox Series S console, you can play Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 for free this weekend. It’s a no-strings-attached kind of deal, and it’s set to run hand-in-hand with one of the biggest discounts ever applied to the game.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we published our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review/">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 review</a>, dubbing the game a ‘monumental medieval masterpiece’. It was years in the making, borne of a Kickstarter campaign that began more than a decade ago.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The free play window for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 is set to run from November 6 (yesterday) to November 10, giving you plenty of time to soak up all that the stellar title has to offer.</p>



<p>It won’t be enough, though. That’s why the massive discount has been arranged, so if you want to keep up your adventures with Henry of Skalitz, you can do so by purchasing the game at the lowest price it has ever boasted.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’ll be playing Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 this weekend.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that Escape from Tarkov’s developers <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-devs-tricks-up-sleeve-cheaters/">are trying harder to combat cheaters</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-owners-best-rpg-ever-made-free-this-weekend/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Devs Have ‘Tricks Up Their Sleeve’ to Combat Cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-devs-tricks-up-sleeve-cheaters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-devs-have-%E2%80%98tricks-up-their-sleeve%E2%80%99-to-combat-cheaters.1346602/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a recent interview, the head of the studio at Battlestate Games, Nikita Buyanov, revealed that extra effort is being applied to take care of cheaters when 1.0 is released later this month. As one of the biggest concerns around, fans are worried that cheaters will negatively impact the game’s launch, which has been building for <strong>a decade</strong>.</p>



<p>Buyanov has explained that years of ‘hatred’ haven’t prevented a ‘huge department’ from working ‘day and night’ to produce new methods to combat cheaters in the spearhead extraction shooter game.</p>



<h2 id="h-cheaters-be-damned-in-escape-from-tarkov">Cheaters Be Damned in Escape from Tarkov</h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/escape-from-tarkov/1-0-steam-cheating-measures-battlestate-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent interview</a>, Nikita Buyanov, the prolific leader of Battlestate Games, explained how the company has ‘a few tricks up our sleeve for the release’ of Escape from Tarkov. This is in reference to combating the cheaters that have plagued the game for years, causing one of the most consistent issues around.</p>



<p>It’s one of the reasons why so many players have turned to PvE over the last year and a half, removing other players from their experience and eradicating the concern of cheating.</p>



<p>Buyanov explained how the studio has remained stalwart despite years of criticism:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>It is truly unfortunate and somewhat upsetting to read all kinds of comments over the years and navigate through waves of hatred, as if we are not doing anything.</p>



<p>We have a huge department working on this, banning players day and night and coming up with new methods. But it’s impossible to change the players’ opinions. And that can be depressing at times. To be honest, to some extent, this emotional background is very discouraging and frustrating. But we’re used to it. It’s a never-ending race, and we’ve never given up and don’t intend to give up.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Recently, the studio <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-rewards-revealed-pre-order/">revealed the rewards</a> coming to all Escape from Tarkov owners when the game goes live on November 15. There’s a pack incoming, including exclusive outfits, dogtag models, hideout customization elements, and more.</p>



<p>Also on November 15, Escape from Tarkov will be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/do-i-need-to-buy-escape-from-tarkov-steam-again/">released on Steam</a>, marking the first time that the game has been available outside Battlestate Games’ proprietary launcher.</p>



<p>Do you believe that cheaters will be taken care of when Escape from Tarkov’s 1.0 release is here? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-sales-results-softer-than-expected/">Borderlands 4’s sales results</a> weren’t what Take-Two was expecting</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-devs-tricks-up-sleeve-cheaters/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fired Rockstar Dev Makes Counter-Claims About ‘Leaking’ Dismissal Case]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fired-rockstar-dev-counter-claims-leaking/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fired-rockstar-dev-makes-counter-claims-about-%E2%80%98leaking%E2%80%99-dismissal-case.1346590/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a post on GTA Forums that was later verified by the site’s admins, a former Rockstar Games employee divulged information about the recent controversy that saw more than 30 employees suddenly dismissed from the company. In the words of Rockstar, they were fired for leaking game information in a Discord server, but that might not be the case.</p>



<p>As the user posted, nobody was leaking anything in the private Discord server that contained only Rockstar Games employees, but instead, they were using it to discuss unionization in a bid to encourage change at Rockstar Games for the better.</p>



<p>It has been alleged that Rockstar Games fired these employees for taking part in this activity.</p>



<h2 id="h-former-rockstar-employees-are-lashing-out">Former Rockstar Employees Are Lashing Out</h2>



<p>The lengthy post on <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1004182-rockstar-games-alleged-union-busting/#comment-1072605777" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the GTA Forums</a> reveals a tale of heartbreak and disappointment at the sudden dismissal of more than 30 Rockstar Games employees in the United Kingdom and Canada.</p>



<p>In the post, the user named ‘Organize’, who joined the forums in June, revealed that Rockstar Games broke several UK employment laws when dismissing staff on grounds of gross misconduct. Many have claimed this was a thinly veiled attempt to bust unionization efforts.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Last week, my colleagues who were in the studio were each individually messaged by HR for a short friendly meeting, under the friendly guise of “Hey, are you free for a quick chat?”</p>



<p>Upon attending this meeting they were handed an envelope with a short letter stating that their employment had been terminated for “gross misconduct” regarding posts made in Discord.</p>



<p>They failed to provide any evidence when asked, nor was any stated in the letter. And did not divulge any other information or reasoning – “and no other reason”</p>



<p>They refused their right to Union representation in the disciplinary meeting (which is against UK employment law) and were frogmarched out of the studio with the meeting lasting less than 5 minutes.</p>



<p>For colleagues who were not in the Studio that day, they received a phone call from HR that lasted less than 2 minutes telling them they were fired and that they’d receive the same letter as above. I am aware of one employee who had a panic attack at this moment, and HR hung up on them during this panic attack not caring at all about their wellbeing.</p>



<p>These colleagues of mine were hard workers who have spent many many years at R* in critical roles. With colleagues who have been at R* for more that 18 years and none of them have ever had a disciplinary in that time. They are not easily replaced and will certainly affect us in making our project deadlines.</p>



<p>These are very senior artists, animators, QA testers, designers, programmers and producers. Including Leads. All super talented people who were proud of their work over multiple R* titles, and all they wanted was the best for R* and their fellow colleagues.</p>



<p>Some of these members were off sick, recovering from surgery or on paternity leave. Fired without pay, losing their careers and putting them into hardship in the lead up to Christmas, and even potentially losing their VISAs to work in the UK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me make this clear! I never saw any discussion/leaking of Rockstar projects in the Union Discord. The only ever discussion was around unionisation efforts and the working conditions at R*. The Discord wasn’t public. It was a private Discord group that only contained R* employees and the IWGB Union officials.</p>



<p>This was Union Busting and nothing else! Everyone fired was a Union Member, they were also predominantly from those who were on the Union Organising Committees of each UK studio.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The user revealed that almost enough members had been reached to ‘seek recognition and begin engaging in collective bargaining.’</p>



<blockquote>
<p>They have fired over 34 of us now. There were over 250 of us in that Union/Employee Discord group. There is the fear that if they get away with this, they’ll have nothing stopping them from doing this again and again.</p>



<p>Those of us who are lucky and remain for now work in fear! Fearful when talking to each other at the tea prep, fearful that we’re next in line and are easily got rid of, too scared to go outside the studio and talk to (or even acknowledge) our colleagues outside protesting in fear of reprisals. Morale in the studio is at rock bottom. When we should be excited about what’s to come over the next year we are now totally deflated and our trust and confidence in others is totally shot.</p>



<p>Which is the truly heartbreaking part, as for us in the Union, all of our ambition was to make R* a happier, fairer, safer and more equitable place. That’s all. What has happened clearly shows that we care more about the wellbeing of our colleagues at Rockstar than the Company does.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This would have allowed the employees to address key issues in the company: ‘worsening crunch, inadequate pay, and inflexible working arrangements.’ To protest the firing of these Rockstar Games employees, the IWGB union and former employees <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fired-rockstar-workers-protest-take-two/">marched on Take-Two’s London office</a> yesterday.</p>



<p>In recent Rockstar Games news, Grand Theft Auto 6 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delay-november-2026/">was delayed by several months</a> and will now be released on November 19, 2026, rather than May 26, 2026.</p>



<p>Let me know what you think about these claims on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that fresh art of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-ad-rogue-gambit/">Rogue and Gambit in Marvel Rivals</a> has been revealed</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fired-rockstar-dev-counter-claims-leaking/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Ad Reveals Images of Rogue and Gambit]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-ad-rogue-gambit/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-ad-reveals-images-of-rogue-and-gambit.1346587/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a new TikTok ad, it was once again teased that Rogue and Gambit are coming to Marvel Rivals. Fans were quick to spot and screenshot the images, but it became tough to replicate it until a Marvel Rivals leaks page uncovered the ad and confirmed it was real.</p>



<p>Rogue and Gambit would join a roster of more than 40 playable heroes from across the Marvel Universe, and they’re expected to arrive on November 14 when the game’s fifth season goes live.</p>



<h2 id="h-are-rogue-and-gambit-coming-to-marvel-rivals">Are Rogue and Gambit Coming to Marvel Rivals?</h2>



<p>The imminent arrival of Rogue and Gambit has been teased in recent patch notes, with eagle-eyed players spotting the characters in the background of an image posted by NetEase.</p>



<p>On November 14, the game’s fifth season will drop, and many believe that’s when Rogue and Gambit will surface as the latest new characters.</p>



<p>In a recent TikTok ad, art of the two characters was revealed. It was picked up by Marvel Rivals pages on social media and shared around before <a href="https://xcancel.com/X0X_LEAK/status/1986491569122299996" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XOX LEAK confirmed</a> the content’s validity.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Fans are wondering why NetEase hasn’t dropped the trailer for season five yet, which would undoubtedly reveal the presence of Rogue and Gambit as new playable heroes.</p>



<p>There are rumors that the trailer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-marvel-rivals-season-5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">season five</a> will be released on November 11, revealing everything coming in the supersized update.</p>



<p>In recent news related to the game, one of the most prominent esports organisations in the business <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sentinels-announce-marvel-rivals-esports-exit/">left Marvel Rivals</a> and made quips about how NetEase isn’t effectively supporting the ecosystem.</p>



<p>Do you think Rogue and Gambit are coming with season five of Marvel Rivals? Let me know what your expectations are on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-sales-results-softer-than-expected/">Borderlands 4’s sales results were ‘softer’ than Take-Two wanted</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-ad-rogue-gambit/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4’s Sales Results Were ‘Softer’ Than Expected, Take-Two Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-sales-results-softer-than-expected/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4%E2%80%99s-sales-results-were-%E2%80%98softer%E2%80%99-than-expected-take-two-says.1346581/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Take-Two has been in a sticky spot of late. The company faced a protest yesterday in London as former Rockstar employees unfairly dismissed were joined by union members outside Take-Two’s office in the heart of the United Kingdom. Then, an announcement of another GTA 6 delay caused the company’s stock value to plummet by 10%.</p>



<p>In a recent interview, the CEO of Take-Two Interactive, Strauss Zelnick, confirmed that Borderlands 4 also failed to meet expectations, adding another layer of woe to the Take-Two story this year.</p>



<h2 id="h-borderlands-4-didn-t-do-as-well-as-everyone-thought">Borderlands 4 Didn’t Do as Well as Everyone Thought</h2>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/grand-theft-auto-vi-delayed-again?r=52dp8y&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;triedRedirect=true" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Business</a>, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick confirmed that, while Borderlands 4 had a great launch, it failed to wow with sales figures, and the numbers were ultimately ‘softer’ than the company would have liked.</p>



<p>Here’s the quote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The critical acclaim for Borderlands 4 was superb, and we’re really happy with the release.</p>



<p>Equally, as you know, there were some challenges with the Steam release. Gearbox has been addressing those challenges and will continue to do so. In terms of units sold out of the gate, the numbers were <strong>a little softer than we would have liked</strong>. In the fullness of time, we think it’s going to do great.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That means that Zelnick expects Borderlands 4 to keep selling as time goes on, even if the game is already slipping far down the charts in favor of other, more recent titles.</p>



<p>In recent Take-Two news, the publisher found itself in hot water over the delay of Grand Theft Auto 6. While many thought it would be the case, it caused Take-Two’s stock value to drop by around 10%, representative of the shaken faith of investors.</p>



<p>Are you surprised that Borderlands 4 didn’t sell as well as expected? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-bots-are-returning-to-verified-experiences/">bots are coming back to Battlefield 6</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-sales-results-softer-than-expected/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#880)—Clues and Answers for Friday, November 7]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-5-878-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-880-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-friday-november-7.1346578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s the end of the week – congratulations on making it this far! I hope your NYT Connections streak is still looking clean and consistent. I’m here today to support that goal, bringing you today’s NYT Connections hints and solutions, allowing you to solve today’s puzzle in the quickest way possible.</p>



<p>Read on to get the NYT Connections hints and answers you need for today.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-november-7">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (November 7)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #880:</p>



<ul>
<li>HULA HOOP</li>



<li>EGGPLANT</li>



<li>SALSA VERDE</li>



<li>BAGEL</li>



<li>SWING STATE</li>



<li>RELISH</li>



<li>ANIMAL PRINT</li>



<li>POLKA DOT</li>



<li>WASHER</li>



<li>BARNEY THE DINOSAUR</li>



<li>PESTO</li>



<li>HOUNDSTOOTH</li>



<li>INNER TUBE</li>



<li>CHIMICHURRI</li>



<li>HERRINGBONE</li>



<li>PEOPLE EATER</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think of what you might see on a fashionable coat or a retro couch</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Zesty, herby, and often spooned over grilled meats or sandwiches</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>Round and hollow — some edible, some inflatable</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>These words are feeling kind of purple</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, November 7.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-november-7-880">NYT Connections Answers for Today, November 7 (#880)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– ANIMAL PRINT, HERRINGBONE, HOUNDSTOOTH, POLKA DOT</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – CHIMICHURRI, PESTO, RELISH, SALSA VERDE</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BAGEL, HULA HOOP, INNER TUBE, WASHER</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BARNEY THE DINOSAUR, EGGPLANT, PEOPLE EATER, SWING STATE</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-5-878-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>