<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:17:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Romeo Is A Dead Man On Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/is-romeo-is-a-dead-man-on-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>1422931</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Console boundaries are constantly shifting, especially concerning Xbox. It seems like most of their titles are playable on other platforms, and plenty of them are available as part of the Game Pass service.</p>







<p>When it comes to third-party titles like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/romeo-is-a-dead-man/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/romeo-is-a-dead-man/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Romeo Is A Dead Man</a>, though, it’s not always a guarantee that they’ll appear on Xbox, let alone on Game Pass. If you were hoping to pick up Suda51’s latest title on Game Pass, then allow Insider Gaming to let you know if you stand a chance.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-romeo-is-a-dead-man-available-on-xbox">Is Romeo Is A Dead Man Available On Xbox?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Green like Xbox. Image by Grasshopper Manufacture.<br></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yes, Romeo Is A Dead Man will be available to play on both Xbox Series X|S.</strong></p>



<p>Suda51’s titles have appeared on Xbox platforms in the past, so it’s not surprising that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-romeo-is-a-dead-man-have-early-access/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/does-romeo-is-a-dead-man-have-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Romeo Is A Dead Man</a> will be available on the Series X|S. With the latest and greatest consoles available, expect to see bloody and gory brilliance like Grasshopper Manufacture has never displayed before.</p>







<p>However, while it may be available on the console, that doesn’t mean it will necessarily appear on Xbox Game Pass. </p>



<h2 id="h-is-romeo-is-a-dead-man-coming-to-game-pass">Is Romeo Is A Dead Man Coming To Game Pass?</h2>



<p><strong>Whilst Romeo Is A Dead Man will be playable on Xbox consoles, it won’t be available as part of the Xbox Game Pass service. </strong></p>



<p>Whilst it may not launch on the service, that’s not to say that it will never be available there in the future. Xbox often pick up third-party titles after they’ve released and includes them as part of the deal—maybe Romeo Is A Dead Man could feature down the line?</p>



<p>If it ever does, Insider Gaming will be the first to let you know, so keep your eyes peeled on the site and the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" id="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> for Xbox Game Pass updates. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/8-best-games-to-play-if-you-like-hytale/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/8-best-games-to-play-if-you-like-hytale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 8 best games to play if you like Hytale</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/is-romeo-is-a-dead-man-on-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Romeo Is A Dead Man Have Early Access?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-romeo-is-a-dead-man-have-early-access/</link>
            <guid>1422892</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s been over five years since Goichi “Suda51” Suda and his studio, Grasshopper Manufacture, developed a brand new concept, but <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/romeo-is-a-dead-man/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/romeo-is-a-dead-man/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Romeo Is A Dead Man</a> is set to break that spell. </p>







<p>The upcoming bloody action-adventure title is on the horizon, and plenty of fans are dying to get their hands on it. If you’re struggling to wait for its release date, you might be wondering if Romeo Is A Dead Man has Early Access, and Insider Gaming has all the answers for you.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-there-romeo-is-a-dead-man-early-access">Is There Romeo Is A Dead Man Early Access?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Expect a bloody mess. Image by Grasshopper Manufacture.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Unfortunately, Grasshopper Manufacture is not offering any form of Early Access to Romeo Is A Dead Man.</strong></p>



<p>If you were hoping to get your hands on Romeo Is A Dead Man a little bit earlier than the rest of the crowd, then you’re out of luck. There will be no forms of Early Access for Suda51’s next title, meaning you’ll have to wait for its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/romeo-is-a-dead-man-release-date-countdown-exact-start-times/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/romeo-is-a-dead-man-release-date-countdown-exact-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date</a> like everyone else. </p>



<p>That’s not necessarily a bad thing, though. Paying more just to get a single-player title early seems to miss the point of Early Access—if there is one to begin with. </p>



<h2 id="h-does-romeo-is-a-dead-man-have-a-demo">Does Romeo Is A Dead Man Have A Demo?</h2>



<p><strong>Adding to the misery, Romeo Is A Dead Man does not have a playable demo, but that’s not to say there won’t be one in the future.</strong></p>



<p>PlayStation often offer two-hour-long demos for titles once they’re released as part of the PlayStation+ Premium service. Whilst there isn’t a pre-game demo to get a taste for Romeo Is A Dead Man, there’s a chance one could still come in the future, perhaps to that service in particular. </p>







<p>As things stand, though, the only chance you’ll have to play Romeo Is A Dead Man is by purchasing the game when it releases—standard procedure, all things considered.</p>



<p>Are you excited to play Romeo Is A Dead Man? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" id="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-open-world-rpg-games-releasing-2026/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/best-open-world-rpg-games-releasing-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">9 upcoming open-world RPGs releasing in 2026</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/does-romeo-is-a-dead-man-have-early-access/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#968)—Clues and Answers for Tuesday, February 3]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-3-968/</link>
            <guid>1422886</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>How’s your week going? It has only just started, but let me know in the comments if anything amazing has happened. In the meantime, I know why you’re here. It’s because you want the best and fastest NYT Connections hints and solutions you can find anywhere online! Well, I’m more than happy to help you with that.</p>



<p>Read on to get today’s NYT Connections answers in a matter of seconds!</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-february-3">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (February 3)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #968:</p>



<ul>
<li>CARD</li>



<li>WOOD</li>



<li>FOAM</li>



<li>DICE</li>



<li>BOARD</li>



<li>CUBE</li>



<li>QUARTER</li>



<li>HOLE</li>



<li>HASH</li>



<li>HOUSE</li>



<li>IRON</li>



<li>MINCE</li>



<li>WEDGE</li>



<li>LANE</li>



<li>LODGE</li>



<li>PUTTER</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– Ways to chop food finely</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – Give someone a roof and a bed</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> –<em> </em>You’ll find them in a golfer’s bag</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – Words that can follow “memory”</li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, February 3:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-february-3-968">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, February 3 (#968)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– CUBE, DICE, HASH, MINCE</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BOARD, HOUSE, LODGE, QUARTER</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – IRON, PUTTER, WEDGE, WOOD</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – CARD, FOAM, HOLE, LANE</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-3-968/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Nioh 3 On Xbox? Nioh 3 Xbox Game Pass Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-xbox-game-pass-status/</link>
            <guid>1422883</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Nioh franchise and Xbox don’t have the most solid of relationships, in all honesty. That said, let’s see if Nioh 3 is coming to Xbox, and if it will be a day-one Xbox Game Pass addition.</p>



<p>The first Nioh wasn’t on Xbox at any point, nor was Nioh 2. Things are so crazy in the gaming world that you almost expect to see any game appear on another platform. With new boundaries being crossed every day, let’s see if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Nioh3.jpg" id="147929" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nioh 3</a> is finally <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/xbox/" id="131" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox</a>-bound, and if you, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/game-pass/" id="316" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Pass</a> subscribers, are getting a nice bonus.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-nioh-3-on-xbox">Can You Play Nioh 3 On Xbox?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A losing battle. Credit to Team Ninja</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There is no Xbox port for Nioh 3 on the Xbox One or Xbox Series X|S at launch, but one could be arriving later down the line.</strong></p>



<p>As it stands, you can’t play Nioh 3 on Xbox. The trend from the last two games repeats itself here. There’s no agreement between Team Ninja and Microsoft for an Xbox port. The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-upcoming-soulslike-games-2026/" id="172993" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Soulslike</a> will be making its debut on PlayStation 5 and PC for now, but there’s room for an Xbox port in the future.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More IG: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nioh 3 Release Date Countdown &amp; Exact Start Times</a></li>
</ul>



<p>It was revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-has-a-timed-console-exclusivity-deal-with-playstation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nioh 3 has a timed console exclusivity deal with PlayStation</a>. The first six months of Nioh 3’s lifecycle will restrict it to the PlayStation as a console exclusive. However, after this, all bets are off.</p>



<p>This doesn’t mean an Xbox port is happening, but this is definitely the closest Xbox owners will ever come to potentially playing a Nioh game on Xbox One or Xbox Series X|S.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-nioh-3-coming-to-xbox-game-pass">Is Nioh 3 Coming To Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Game over. Credit to Team Ninja</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Just like its official Xbox status, there will be no way to play Nioh 3 for free using Xbox Game Pass.</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More IG:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-review-embargo-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">When Is The Nioh 3 Review Embargo Date? Nioh 3 Review Countdown</a></li>
</ul>



<p>This again comes down to the game’s future. If Nioh 3 gets an Xbox console port later down the line, there’s every chance it could coincide with an Xbox Game Pass announcement,too. With the ever-increasing costs of Game Pass, Microsoft is surely on the lookout for ways to make the subscription service more appealing—offering Nioh 3 could be a big help!</p>



<p>Keep checking back for more Nioh 3 Xbox updates here at Insider Gaming. You can keep up to date with the latest news and guides, and you should also check out the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> for daily gaming conversations.</p>



<hr>



<p>Read about potential <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nioh 3 early access and its potential demo status</a> for more answers.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nioh-3-xbox-game-pass-status/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>