<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 04:43:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales 30th Anniversary Illustration Hints at Next Remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tales-30th-anniversary-illustration-abyss-remaster/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-30th-anniversary-illustration-hints-at-next-remaster.1360345/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A celebratory illustration for the Tales series’ 30th anniversary may have spoiled the next remaster. Even more so, it’s a title many fans have been vocal about since the Remaster project was announced.</p>







<p>Since 1995, the Tales series (also known as Tales of Series) has been charming players with vibrant adventures and grand action RPG combat. While not as mainstream as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy</a> or Persona, the Bandai Namco franchise has had a few successes in the West with Tales of Symphonia and Vesperia. Since 2021, with Tales of Arise, the series has been remastering past games like Xillia and, announced this week, Berseria. The full lineup hasn’t been revealed, but a new illustration from Ufotable may have let the cat out of the bag early.</p>



<h2 id="h-tales-of-the-abyss-remastered-possibly-in-development-hints-anniversary-illustration">Tales of the Abyss Remastered Possibly in Development, Hints Anniversary Illustration</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">◤ Step back into the story ◢<br>The 30th Anniversary Key Visual by ufotable is now revealed ✨<br>Characters from titles celebrating their anniversaries in 2025–2026, along with characters from remastered titles, invite you into the heart of the story. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tales30thAnniversary?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Tales30thAnniversary</a> <a href="https://t.co/BNcY6IfIJI">pic.twitter.com/BNcY6IfIJI</a></p>— Tales of Series (@TalesofSeries) <a href="https://twitter.com/TalesofSeries/status/1991703111467958370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In the post, <a href="https://x.com/TalesofSeries/status/1991703111467958370?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">seen above</a>, the Tales series commemorates its 30th anniversary. The illustration, done by Ufotable (Demon Slayer), showcases all the recent Tales titles like Arise, Xillia Remastered, Graces f Remastered, and Berseria Remastered. However, one character there is from a game that isn’t a remaster, let alone announced: Luke from Tales of the Abyss. Given that the game came out in 2005, it being there is a bit interesting.</p>



<p>Tales of the Abyss was a PlayStation 2 exclusive and the eighth main title in the series. Following Luke fon Fabre, he’ll venture into the unknown to figure out his birth and escape a dangerous prophecy. Fans have been asking to see the game brought back to life for a while. It wouldn’t be too surprising if the next remaster after Berseria is Abyss, though Xillia 2 was confirmed earlier this year. Still, while it isn’t confirmation, it does give a small glimmer of hope that the PS2 title may be reborn.</p>







<p>What do you think of the illustration for Tales’ 30th anniversary? Do you think Tales of the Abyss is getting the remaster treatment? Any other titles you want to see redone? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more RPGs, check out our articles on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-5-most-influential-rpgs-of-all-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the most influential</a>&nbsp;and Clair Obscur’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-nominations-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">record-breaking Game Awards nominations</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tales-30th-anniversary-illustration-abyss-remaster/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[xQc Thinks League of Legends is an ‘Unwatchable’ Esports Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xqc-league-of-legends-unwatchable-esports/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xqc-thinks-league-of-legends-is-an-%E2%80%98unwatchable%E2%80%99-esports-game.1360330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>During a recent stream, Felix ‘xQc’ Lengyel, one of the biggest streamers in the world, bagged on League of Legends esports. He stressed that the game is fine to play, but branded the esports side of things ‘f***ing unwatchable’. Instead, he backed Counter-Strike 2, suggesting that Valve’s shooter ‘clears it by a margin of like 10x or 20x’.</p>



<p>Once upon a time, xQc was an esports competitor himself, but those days are long gone. Do you think xQc is right about League of Legends esports?</p>



<h2 id="h-that-will-probably-never-change">‘That Will Probably Never Change’</h2>



<p>In a recent stream clip, xQc was captured telling his viewers that League of Legends is, in his opinion, an awful esports game.</p>



<p>This was during the Esports Awards, where League of Legends secured the award for Game of the Year, beating games like Counter-Strike 2 and VALORANT to the punch. It has been a stunning year for League of Legends, with records being broken at the League of Legends World Championship event, hosted this season in China.</p>



<p>That’s not enough for xQc, though.</p>



<p>In a slight rant, xQc said on stream:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>CS2 will always win: It’s a game that offers good storytelling, the spectator POV is unmatched, and it’s easy to make a story. Anyone can just jump in, and they know exactly what’s going on, and that will probably never change. It’s why it’s still so successful as a title. League of Legends? </p>



<p>It’s god f**king unwatchable… It’s great to play, but it’s not a great esports game… I love League, don’t get me wrong, but Jesus, as an esports game, Counter-Strike clears it by a margin of like 10x or 20x.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://escorenews.com/en/csgo/news/73655-xqc-i-love-league-but-as-an-esports-game-cs2-clears-it-by-a-margin-of-10x-or-20x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">EScoreNews</a> for the quote)</em></p>



<p>Counter-Strike hasn’t made the cut at the Esports Awards in almost a decade. The last time it clinched Game of the Year was in 2017, and since then, League of Legends, Overwatch, and VALORANT have all had their time in the limelight.</p>



<p>Do you think League of Legends is a bad esports game? Let the community know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-elite-series-announced-with-1-million-prize-pot/">Battlefield REDSEC is getting a $1 million tournament</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xqc-league-of-legends-unwatchable-esports/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#894)—Clues and Answers for Friday, November 21]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-21-894/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-894-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-friday-november-21.1360309/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s Friday, and that means that the weekend is <strong>finally here</strong>. Before you can enjoy it, you simply must complete today’s NYT Connections puzzle! Fortunately, I’ve got the hints and solutions you need to get things wrapped up as quickly as possible. If you’re stumped by today’s puzzle, simply read on for the top NYT Connections hints.</p>











<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-november-21">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (November 21)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #894:</p>



<ul>
<li>RACECAR</li>



<li>LAPEL PIN</li>



<li>SCREWDRIVER</li>



<li>WOLF EEL</li>



<li>BOLT CUTTER</li>



<li>GREYHOUND</li>



<li>SCARF RING</li>



<li>GRUMPY OLD MAN</li>



<li>COSMOPOLITAN</li>



<li>LAVALIER</li>



<li>CLOWNFISH</li>



<li>AWARENESS RIBBON</li>



<li>TALKING DOLL</li>



<li>CHOW MEIN</li>



<li>BOUTONNIÈRE</li>



<li>SEA BREEZE</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think of what politicians, prom dates, or awareness campaigns might wear.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em><em>Names evoke breezes, colors, or canine companions.</em></em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>They’re the heart of beloved family films</em>.</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each begins with a word that means to devour.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, November 21:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-november-21-894">NYT Connections Answers for Today, November 21 (#894)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– AWARENESS RIBBON, BOUTONNIÈRE, LAPEL PIN, LAVALIER</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – COSMOPOLITAN, GREYHOUND, SCREWDRIVER, SEA BREEZE</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – CLOWNFISH, GRUMPY OLD MAN, RACECAR, TALKING DOLL</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BOLT CUTTER, CHOW MEIN, SCARF RING, WOLF EEL</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">r</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-november-21-894/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Black Friday Xbox Deals 2025: Consoles, Games & Accessories]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-friday-xbox-deals-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-black-friday-xbox-deals-2025-consoles-games-accessories.1360207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The 2025 holiday shopping season has already started for many, and Xbox is rolling out a wide range of discounts to help players grab some last-minute gifts. Whether you’re hunting for a new Xbox Series X or S console, fresh accessories, or deals on Game Pass subscriptions and the biggest games of the year, Microsoft has lined up plenty of savings for Black Friday and beyond.</p>



<p>So, what do you need to be on the lookout for, and what deals are actually worth jumping on directly from Xbox? Below, you’ll find the best Xbox Black Friday deals for 2025. If something catches your eye, leave your thoughts in the comments and join the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Gaming Discord</a> to talk about what you’re picking up this year.</p>







<h2>When Do the Xbox Black Friday Deals Start?</h2>



<p>Xbox’s Black Friday deals began on <strong>November 20th</strong> and will run through <strong>December 3rd</strong> for most hardware and game discounts. </p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-best-xbox-deals-for-black-friday-and-the-2025-holidays">Best Xbox Deals for Black Friday and the 2025 Holidays</h2>



<h3 id="h-xbox-series-x-s-console-deals">Xbox Series X|S Console Deals</h3>



<p>Unfortunately, if you are looking to pick up an Xbox Series X or S console this holiday season, you won’t find any luck getting a traditional discount from the official Microsoft store. All available systems are still their full retail price if you want one. The only way to save on a new console is by trading in an eligible system for up to $130 off the purchase of a new Xbox console. </p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-xbox-game-pass-deals">Xbox Game Pass Deals</h3>



<p>If you’re looking to finally join Xbox Game Pass, there really isn’t a discount on a long-term subscription, either. Instead, Xbox is offering 14 days for $1 either Xbox Game Pass Essential or Xbox Game Pass Premium. After that period ends, however, it will go up to $9.99 and $14.99 per month, respectively.</p>







<hr>



<figure></figure>



<h3 id="h-xbox-accessories">Xbox Accessories</h3>



<p>Where Microsoft really starts pushing its sales this year are with accessories like controllers and headsets. This year, Microsoft is offering up to nearly 40% off on a variety of Xbox controllers and up to 20% on headsets. You can check out some of the better deals available, below.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Accessory</th><th data-align="center">Holiday Deal</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/xbox-wireless-controller#white" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller- Robot White</a></td><td data-align="center">38% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/xbox-wireless-controller" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller- Carbon Black</a></td><td data-align="center">38% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/pulse-cipher-special-edition" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller – Pulse Cipher Special Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">31% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/breaker-series-special-edition#heart-breaker" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller – Heart Breaker Special Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">26% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/breaker-series-special-edition#ice-breaker" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Breaker Series Special Edition Xbox Controllers</a></td><td data-align="center">25% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/xbox-elite-wireless-controller-series-2-core" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Elite Wireless Controller Series 2 – Core White</a></td><td data-align="center">13% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/headsets/xbox-stereo-headset" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Stereo Headset</a></td><td data-align="center">8% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/headsets/xbox-wireless-headset" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless H</a><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/headsets/xbox-wireless-headset">eadset</a></td><td data-align="center">17% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/elite-wireless-controller-series-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Elite Wireless Controller Series 2</a></td><td data-align="center">21% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/accessories/controllers/arctic-camo-special-edition" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wireless Controller – Arctic Camo Special Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">29% off</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-xbox-games">Xbox Games</h3>



<p>When it comes to games, Microsoft is advertising up to 75% off a number of games in the library. While you <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/browse/black-friday-sale" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">can comb through the thousands</a> of Xbox games being put on sale as part the Black Friday holiday deals, below you’ll find some of the biggest discounts as well as deals on some of the latest games.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Game</th><th data-align="center">Holiday Deal</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/nba-2k26-standard-edition/9PJ2RVRC0L1X" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NBA 2K26 Standard Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">55% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/the-outer-worlds-2/9P8RMKXRML7D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Outer Worlds 2</a></td><td data-align="center">20% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/assassins-creed-shadows/9P42LWGMC7K4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a></td><td data-align="center">40% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-6---cross-gen-bundle/9PF528M6CRHQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 – Cross-Gen Bundle</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/fallout-76/BS6WJ2L56B10" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fallout 76</a></td><td data-align="center">75% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/battlefield-6/9P2FF14JZLL3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield 6</a></td><td data-align="center">15% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/dragon-ball-sparking-zero/9N7XMJJHNFC3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DRAGON BALL Sparking! ZERO</a></td><td data-align="center">40% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/ea-sports-fc-26-standard-edition-xbox-one--xbox-series-xs/9MXZBTLG26VX">EA SPORTS FC 26 Standard Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/borderlands4/9MX6HKF5647G/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Borderlands 4</a></td><td data-align="center">20% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2/9N9PCZWHVP2L/0010">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/forza-horizon-5-standard-edition/9NKX70BBCDRN/0010">Forza Horizon 5 Standard Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-pc/9NXFX68ZNKK0/0010">Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced (PC)</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/doom-the-dark-ages/9PH9X0760B0T/0010">DOOM: The Dark Ages</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-cross-gen-edition/9N926481VT1Z/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 – Cross-Gen Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">40% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/ea-sports-madden-nfl-26/9NVD16NP4J8T/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Madden NFL 26</a></td><td data-align="center">50% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business/9NNNFB5F54C9/0010">RoboCop: Rogue City – Unfinished Business</a></td><td data-align="center">35% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/age-of-empires-iv-anniversary-edition/9N94NCGM1Q2N/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Age of Empires IV: Anniversary Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">65% off</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><a href="http://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/alan-wake-2-deluxe-edition/9NP42RG7LBGL/0010">Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition</a></td><td data-align="center">70% off</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, be sure to sign up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-friday-xbox-deals-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Return to Silent Hill Gets New Trailer And It’s Confusing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/return-to-silent-hill-2-new-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/return-to-silent-hill-gets-new-trailer-and-it%E2%80%99s-confusing.1360177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Return to Silent Hill has a new trailer ahead of its January 23rd release in theaters. While an adaptation of Silent Hill 2, it certainly looks to be a loose and confusing one.</p>







<p>Director Christophe Gans, who did the original Silent Hill film in 2006, is back at the helm to do Return to Silent Hill. A teaser for the film <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/return-to-silent-hill-teaser-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came out in August</a>, and it was certainly a first look. Lots of shots compiled into one trailer, and it was confusing to figure out just what was going on. While the new official trailer does clear things up, it does make fans of the original Silent Hill 2 quite confused.</p>



<h2 id="h-return-to-silent-hill-official-trailer-released-features-iconic-characters">Return to Silent Hill Official Trailer Released, Features Iconic Characters </h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="RETURN TO SILENT HILL | Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_oNLLln8aE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The new trailer, <a href="https://youtu.be/z_oNLLln8aE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">seen above</a>, shows off a lot more footage of Return to Silent Hill than we’ve seen so far. In it, the film brings several characters from Silent Hill 2, like Angela, Eddie, and Laura. Their scenes look fairly similar to those in the game, but the rest is a bit confusing. It seems to be a loose adaptation, as some scenes look new, like the burning hospital and pre-Silent Hill 2 town scenes. It doesn’t scream Silent Hill 2 as it does a typical horror flick.</p>



<p>For many fans, the Return to Silent Hill trailer isn’t the Silent Hill 2 news they wanted to see today. Silent Hill 2 Remake was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-remake-switch-2-xbox-rumor-website/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">supposedly being announced today</a> at the Xbox Partner Preview, but it was a no-show. Unfortunately, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-remake-xbox-achievements-go-live-full-announcement-imminent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">achievements</a> and even <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Australia’s Xbox Store listing</a> have been found, meaning an announcement is imminent. In any case, at least the remake can act as a palate cleanser before the film arrives on January 23rd, 2026.</p>







<p>What do you think of Return to Silent Hill’s new trailer? Do you think it looks good? Bad? Any Easter Eggs around? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Silent Hill, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-f-has-already-sold-over-1-million-copies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silent Hill f’s sales numbers</a> and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-townfall-release-date-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">possible future reveal of Townfall</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/return-to-silent-hill-2-new-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>