<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:43:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Budget Was $75 Million, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-budget-was-75-million-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1422574</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>An analyst has claimed that Embark Studios had set a budget of $75 million for ARC Raiders, which included marketing. </p>



<p>ARC Raiders is easily one of the most popular titles from 2025, with Embark Studios hitting it out of the park with their new extraction adventure. The title also received a massive update recently, which <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-significantly-impacts-looting-speed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">broke some systems</a> but <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-update-1-13-0-patch-notes-solo-vs-squads-bird-city-open-parties-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">added a lot of new content</a>. However, today we aren’t talking about that; instead, we are talking about how much it costs to make the game. </p>







<h2 id="h-arc-raiders-budget-reportedly-revealed">ARC Raiders Budget Reportedly Revealed</h2>



<p>In the latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=58P5sZJ3Vho" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SIFTD Games</a> video, industry analyst Michael Pachter revealed the budget for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/arc-raiders/" id="790">ARC Raiders</a>. The new video explores whether Ubisoft will survive after the recent restructuring announcement, with Patcher sharing his insights on several topics. Towards the end of the video, Patcher discusses different game budgets and timelines, where the cost of making ARC Raiders was revealed. </p>



<p>Patcher states that Ubisoft taking 5 years to develop a game and selling only 5 million units is not sustainable; “3 years is plenty.” He then talks about people bringing Rockstar into comparison, which might be $1.5-2 billion on GTA 6, but don’t understand that “they are going to make that $2 billion back in the first week.” </p>



<p>The analyst adds that everybody shouldn’t be comparing themselves to “GTA, FIFA, or the former glory of Call of Duty,” instead, they should compare themselves to ARC Raiders. Patcher then drops a secret, stating, “ARC Raiders cost $75 million to make.” It was developed over 3 years, had a team of 70 developers, and included marketing in the budget. Patcher added that the game has already made $500 million from 12 million-plus units sold and will “probably” make close to a billion. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Is Ubisoft going to survive? - Pachter Factor Live Episode 63" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/58P5sZJ3Vho?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In other news, Embark Studios revealed that ARC Raiders faced “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-devs-confirm-server-issues-are-due-to-ddos-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extensive, coordinated DDoS attacks</a>” recently. Additionally, here’s a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-easily-complete-all-arc-raiders-trials-this-week-february-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guide to completing all the trials for this week</a> (February 2). What are your thoughts on the ARC Raiders’ budget being $75 million? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-anti-cheat-community-playsafe-id/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Escape from Tarkov anti-cheat plea gaining community traction</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>. </p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-budget-was-75-million-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#967)—Clues and Answers for Monday, February 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-2-967/</link>
            <guid>1422430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s Monday, and while it’s time for a new week in your world, it’s also time for a new NYT Connections puzzle. I know you love them! But I also know you sometimes want to get the best NYT Connections hints squared away as soon as possible to start your day. That’s why I’ve outlined the answers and solutions below, just for you!</p>



<p>Read on to quickly resolve today’s NYT Connections puzzle.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-february-2">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (February 2)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #967:</p>



<ul>
<li>POPULAR</li>



<li>PERIOD</li>



<li>CROSS</li>



<li>STAMP</li>



<li>SPAN</li>



<li>PSALM</li>



<li>PASS</li>



<li>RYAN</li>



<li>LANYARD</li>



<li>STRETCH</li>



<li>REACHER</li>



<li>MARPLE</li>



<li>FAIR</li>



<li>INTERVAL</li>



<li>WRISTBAND</li>



<li>BOSCH</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Words you’d use to describe how long something lasts.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Items that let you <em>prove you belong</em> somewhere — concerts, events, secure areas.</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> –<em> Last names of lead characters from popular thriller/crime novels and TV adaptations.</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each word becomes a type of tree when you add or remove a single letter.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, February 2:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-february-2-967">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, February 2 (#967)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– INTERVAL, PERIOD, SPAN, STRETCH</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – LANYARD, PASS, STAMP, WRISTBAND</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BOSCH, CROSS, REACHER, RYAN</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – FAIR, MARPLE, POPULAR, PSALM</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-2-967/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Anti-Cheat Plea Gaining Community Traction]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-anti-cheat-community-playsafe-id/</link>
            <guid>1422418</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov has long had an issue with cheaters, and the developer in Battlestate Games has always professed how much of a full-time job it is to constantly combat them. For every head you eviscerate, two more pop up – it’s that adage linked to the concept of the hydra, but in this case, the mythical monster is very real, and it concerns <strong>malicious gamers</strong>.</p>



<p>Recently, a new community-backed initiative (or plea) has started gaining traction within the Escape from Tarkov space. Long-term fans of the hardcore extraction title are requesting that Battlestate Games implement <strong>PlaySafe ID</strong> verification, echoing a successful move made recently by SCUM’s developer.</p>







<h2 id="h-could-playsafe-id-change-the-game-in-escape-from-tarkov">Could PlaySafe ID Change the Game in Escape from Tarkov?</h2>



<p><a href="https://playsafeid.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlaySafe ID</a> is all about anti-cheat mechanics and player protection, encouraging the facilitation of verified matchmaking features that link <strong>legitimate players </strong>with <strong>other </strong>legitimate players. The technical infrastructure behind it is much more complex than that, but the long and short of it is that it <strong>works </strong>as an anti-cheat solution and is <strong>not </strong>disruptive.</p>



<p>In a trending suggestion on the Tarkov Community site, which regularly hosts player-backed initiatives ranked by user votes, it has been requested that Battlestate Games ‘finally beat cheaters with PlaySafe ID’.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, <a href="https://tarkov.community/posts/10017/finally-beat-cheaters-with-playsafeid-just-like-scum-did" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the suggestion had pulled in</a> 153 total votes, of which 93% are in favor of the recommendation. In the comments, users spoke positively of PlaySafe ID and the potential protection gains the company could provide if it were to join forces with Battlestate Games.</p>



<p>The suggestion reads:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>This isn’t about punishing legit players — it’s about finally protecting them. At this point, a system like PlaySafe ID feels like the only solution that can actually work long-term.</p>



<p>So, after the successful rollout of PlaySafeID in SCUM, it’s time to seriously talk about bringing it to Escape from Tarkov.</p>



<p>Let’s finally get rid of cheaters, that have plagued us since the alpha of this game</p>
</blockquote>



<p>PlaySafe ID started probing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/anti-cheat-firm-plans-rid-tarkov-hackers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Escape from Tarkov space</a> back in June 2025, revealing an interest in working with the developers to improve the state of play in the world’s biggest extraction shooter title.</p>



<p>In August 2025, the company backed an investigative report and survey that revealed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/report-gamers-encounter-cheaters-online-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">more than 80% of gamers</a> had encountered cheating in an online game. It’s no big secret that Escape from Tarkov is one of the most troubled games in that respect.</p>







<p>Do you think you’d participate in what PlaySafe ID could offer in Escape from Tarkov? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-changes-harder-higher/">Black Ops 7 Ranked Play changes are coming soon</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-anti-cheat-community-playsafe-id/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Ranked Play Changes Make Things Harder As You Go Higher]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-changes-harder-higher/</link>
            <guid>1422385</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>During the Call of Duty League Major I finals in Dallas, Treyarch took to the stage to present the future of Ranked Play in Black Ops 7. Next week, the more competitive ecosystem will be introduced to Black Ops 7, allowing players to flex their skills, unlock exclusive rewards, and climb the ranks.</p>



<p>However, in a brief interview, Treyarch explained that changes coming to Black Ops 7’s Ranked Play platform mean that the higher the rank you are, the <strong>harder time you will have</strong>, for multiple reasons.</p>







<h2 id="h-ranked-play-restrictions-on-higher-levels">Ranked Play Restrictions on Higher Levels</h2>



<p>Treyarch appeared in Dallas, Texas, during the CDL Major I grand final to dish the dirt on Black Ops 7’s season two update, scheduled to drop next week. The conversation turned to the imminent arrival of Ranked Play and the <strong>changes </strong>that have been made to the competitive ecosystem.</p>



<p>First, it was confirmed that placement matches are being overhauled. The system will start calculating your opening rank from your first placement match, and after you’ve won <strong>three matches</strong>, you’ll be assigned an amount of SR and a starting rank that <strong>doesn’t </strong>put you at the lowest level out of the gate.</p>



<p>It was then explained that, as you climb the ranks, things get harder. If you make it into the top 250, the most prestigious annals of the Ranked Play platform, you’ll face immense losses when you fail to win your matches. You’ll drop harsher in terms of SR than you would at lower levels, keeping things much more competitive.</p>



<p>Also, you <strong>will not </strong>be able to queue with more than <strong>two </strong>Crimson-or-above-ranked players in one party. This is another limitation imposed to keep things more balanced.</p>



<p>Treyarch also confirmed that new ‘Ranked Play Series’ circuits will start up as season two unfolds. This fresh system will stand at the <strong>end </strong>of the season, allowing users to directly compete against those who finished ‘close to them’ in the Ranked Play space for more rewards and ‘the ultimate bragging rights.’</p>







<p>Do you think these changes are good, or are they putting you off playing Ranked? Let us know your <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cor3-first-trailer-revealed-shooter-tarkov/">COR3’s first trailer has been released</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-ranked-play-changes-harder-higher/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AdHoc Working With Nintendo After Dispatch Censorship Controversy]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/adhoc-working-with-nintendo-after-dispatch-censorship-controversy/</link>
            <guid>1422310</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/adhoc-studio/" id="2968">AdHoc </a>says they’re working closely with Nintendo to find a pathway forward after a censored version of Dispatch was released on the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<p>Dispatch is a superhero interactive fiction video game in which your choices determine how the story unfolds. The game was released in the latter half of 2025 on PlayStation, Xbox, and PC. The game was instantly met with critical acclaim and fanfare.</p>



<p>Dispatch eventually made its way to Nintendo Switch 2, but instead of allowing some adult language and content to be censored, the decision was made for you, and the game is permanently censored on the Nintendo Switch.</p>







<h2 id="h-nintendo-s-response-and-adhoc-s-current-stance">Nintendo’s Response and AdHoc’s Current Stance</h2>



<p>AdHoc initially responded to the backlash by explaining that different platforms have different submission criteria. They also stated that they worked with Nintendo to ensure the content met release criteria and assured players that the core narrative of the gameplay experience remained unchanged.</p>



<p>Nintendo then released a statement confirming that while they inform Partners when a submitted game does not meet their platform’s guidelines, they do not make changes to partners’ content.</p>







<p>AdHoc most recently stated in a <a href="https://discord.com/invite/adhocstudio">Discord </a>message that, like most players, they assumed they could access uncensored mature content on Nintendo Switch because games like The Witcher 3 and Cyberpunk 2077 are also available on the platform. </p>



<p>However, they’re continuing to work with Nintendo on a path forward. Still, they advise players to expect and update their addresses; at least some of the censored content will take weeks due to development time and the console submission process.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“People have a right to be pissed. Lots of lessons learned here. Thanks for sticking with us. More soon.”</p>
</blockquote>



<hr>



<p>Are you waiting for these changes to be addressed to play Dispatch on the Nintendo Switch, or are you more content playing on another platform? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/adhoc-working-with-nintendo-after-dispatch-censorship-controversy/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>