<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:04:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[QPAD Flux 65 Keyboard & Obsidian Glass Superglide Mouse Mat]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/qpad-flux-65-keyboard-obsidian-glass-superglide-mouse-mat-review/</link>
            <guid>1397554</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>After over a decade in the shadows, QPAD is back with a range of new products to sift through, including the new Loop TKL Model 3 Keyboard and Glass Superglide Mouse Mat.</p>



<p>Gamers have an embarrassment of riches when it comes to choosing accessories and peripherals to accompany their PC, and it’s easy to overlook keyboards and mouse mats to complete their build.</p>







<p>With controllers, headsets, microphones, cameras, and more to think about, it’s tempting not to put too much focus on a keyboard and mouse mat when gearing up your PC, and that’s exactly what I did. However, QPAD has made me change my ways, particularly with the Flux 65 Keyboard.</p>



<h2 id="h-change-i-never-knew-i-needed">Change I Never Knew I Needed</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>Having grown up as a predominantly console player, for years my PC and accessories were bread and butter, and, when I finally got a gaming PC, my focus was on components, screens, and the bigger parts of the build. In fact, I couldn’t even tell you what the basic keyboard I had was. </p>



<p>I didn’t see the need to change my keyboard unless it broke, and it was doing me fine. However, after swapping it out for the QPAD Flux 65 Keyboard, it’s safe to say I am never going back.</p>



<p>The biggest change I’ve had to adjust to is the smaller size, which, as a writer, was daunting at first, as I was worried it would mess up my typing. While there was small teething issues initially, they were soon put to rest, and now I can enjoy even more space on my desk to work with.</p>







<p>The keys are not silent, but they’re also not extremely loud, and it’s a much better experience than before.</p>



<p>As for the Edge Mouse Mat, it was another expense I initially thought was unnecessary. The main mat I have on my desk is a Pokémon TCG playmat, which I have for aesthistics rather than use. This lives under my keyboard and, until the Superglide Mouse Mat, my mouse was straight on the desk.</p>



<p>Unsurprisingly, this has resulted in many scuffs and marks on my aging desk, along with frustrating moments where the most didn’t quite track to where I wanted it to. Now, though, I don’t have that problem at all.</p>



<p>It comes with a hefty price-tag though, with a current sale price at Currys of £59.99. While I don’t feel comfortable enough saying it’s definitely worth that outlay, it’s certainly been a benefit to my set-up.</p>



<p>All in all, both devices have changed my PC set-up significantly and will be staying put for my day-to-day usage, and I’ve certainly learned the benefit of putting extra attention into these sorts of accessories.</p>



<hr>



<p>What does your current PC set-up consist of? Share your builds and accessories in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/qpad-flux-65-keyboard-obsidian-glass-superglide-mouse-mat-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard Release Date—New Game From Apex Legends & Titanfall Devs, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-release-date/</link>
            <guid>1397551</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>You’ll do well to find a more intriguing shooter than Highguard in 2026. The game’s skeleton features work from former Respawn Entertainment and Apex Legends devs, and Highguard’s release date serves as one of 2026’s curtain openers.</p>



<p>Needless to say, everyone was shocked when <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-dead-on-arrival-gamers-fear-a-flop/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Highguard</a> was given the honor of closing out The Game Awards 2025, where game announcements and trailers were concerned. However, when you take a step back and assess, it’s a new IP, and the team behind it has some experienced heads, it would be fair to say.</p>



<p>If you’re keen to give Highguard a chance, read on for launch details.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-highguard-coming-out">When Is Highguard Coming Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>There’s no denying how good it looks. Credit to Wildlight Entertainment, Inc.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Wildlight Entertainment’s Highguard has an official release date of January 26, making it one of 2026’s first huge AAA titles.</strong></p>



<p>This means it’s barely a one-month turnaround from Highguard being revealed to the world at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TGA 2025</a> for the first time and launching globally! Logically, Wildlight Entertainment has to be confident in the game and believe it’s more than ready to go.</p>



<p>It’s been in development for over <em>four </em>years, and its reveal trailer boasts some incredible-looking gameplay.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-highguard-from-former-respawn-entertainment-amp-apex-devs">What Is Highguard From Former Respawn Entertainment &amp; Apex Devs?</h2>



<p><strong>Highguard is a high-intensity PvP shooter featuring the signature Apex Legends and Titanfall brands of fast-paced action, an emphasis on mobility, powers and abilities, and the curveball of horseback combat.</strong></p>



<p>The FPS title is literally a mix of Apex and Titanfall, with new ideas thrown into the melting pot. Highguard is a delicate hybrid, factoring in ability-based gameplay, precision shooting mechanics, and the idea of traversing the environment efficiently.</p>



<p>Highguard literally embraces its heritage, even on the official website: “From the creators of Apex Legends and Titanfall, comes Highguard.”</p>



<p>Wildlight Entertainment’s main leaders include the following, with a look at what they did previously:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Chad Grenier:</strong> 12 years at Respawn, including as a game director.</li>



<li><strong>Dusty Welch:</strong> COO of Respawn Entertainment &amp; GM of the Apex Legends dev team. </li>



<li><strong>Jason McCord:</strong> Design director on Apex Legends and former level designer for Call of Duty.</li>
</ul>



<p>If you have doubts, there are years of senior-level experience behind Highguard. The game might not be everyone’s cup of tea, but it would be foolish to write off its hype until you’ve had a chance to play. The jury is out for now.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Highguard | Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_6tjMvckZ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>What have you made of Highguard so far? Does it look decent and different enough to stand out from a heated selection of shooters in 2026? Head to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>There are many other guides here at Insider Gaming. Check out if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-platforms-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale will be on PlayStation 5 &amp; Xbox Series X|S</a>, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-switch-2-edition-exact-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date, and start times for Animal Crossing: New Horizons 3.0 &amp; Switch 2 Edition</a>, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/top-10-lowest-rated-games-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top 10 lowest-rated games of 2025</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Siege Bans Return, Inspired by Viral ’67’ Meme]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-bans-return-inspired-by-viral-67-meme/</link>
            <guid>1397488</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It seems Rainbow Six Siege players are being banned again; what’s more, the ban is for 67 days, inspired by the viral ’67’ meme. </p>



<p>For those unaware, Rainbow Six Siege servers shut down <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-hack-servers-shut-down-ubisoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">after a massive hack</a> late last month, which led to multiple developer-only skins, billions of credits, and bans. Siege and the Marketplace were intentionally shut down while the team resolved the issue; however, it appears Ubisoft hasn’t yet reached a solution. </p>







<h2 id="h-rainbow-six-siege-hands-out-67-day-bans-inspired-by-viral-67-meme">Rainbow Six Siege Hands Out 67-Day Bans, Inspired by Viral “67” Meme</h2>



<p>If you haven’t heard about the viral ‘6-7’ trend, then you are better off not knowing about it; however, it has somehow made its way into Rainbow Six Siege in the most surprising way possible, with several players reportedly receiving 67-day bans. The cause for these bans is unclear; however, a screenshot posted by vxunderground on <a href="https://x.com/vxunderground/status/2007891913425531290" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) via <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/rainbow-six/rainbow-six-siege-hacked-again-as-breach-triggers-67-day-bans-3300391/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dexerto</a> reveals that these 67-day bans are being handed out “due to harassment”. Additionally, if players head to the Rainbow Six Siege <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/rainbow-six/siege/status" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">status</a> page, they will see “4 unplanned issues” across every platform the game is available on. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ubisoft's Rainbow Six Siege has been compromised (again). Social media is filled with players complaining about being banned for "67 days", a reference to the "Six Seven" meme. <a href="https://t.co/1gYvvoU3WT">pic.twitter.com/1gYvvoU3WT</a></p>— vx-underground (@vxunderground) <a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/2007891913425531290?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 4, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Due to the appearance of the viral meme number 67, players believe Rainbow Six Siege has been hacked again. However, Ubisoft has yet to confirm that it has been hacked again. To fix the earlier issue, Ubisoft had begun a “rollback of all transactions” that occurred after the hack, followed by extensive quality control tests “to ensure the integrity of accounts and effectiveness of changes.”</p>







<p>In other news, Rainbow Six Mobile will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-mobile-releasing-february/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release globally in February 2026</a>. Players in Canada, France, Poland, and LATAM can download and play the test version of the game now. What are your thoughts on Rainbow Six Siege players receiving viral ’67’ meme-inspired bans? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-datamine-reveals-graphics-presets-for-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds datamine revealing graphics preset details for Switch 2</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/rainbow-six-siege-bans-return-inspired-by-viral-67-meme/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Isn’t Announcing A New GPU At CES 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-isnt-announcing-a-new-gpu-at-ces-2026/</link>
            <guid>1397485</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-168066">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>CES 2026 is here and that means another keynote speech from Nvidia. While, usually, CEO Jensen Huant takes the stag and reveals a brand new graphics card for players, that won’t be the case this year.</p>



<p>Shortly before the company’s scheduled keynote on Monday, Nvidia confirmed that no new GPUs will be announced during the event. There also won’t be any sort of GPU announcement during Nvidia’s <a href="https://twitter.com/NVIDIAGeForce/status/2008176911747371438?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2008176911747371438%7Ctwgr%5E4123a5ccd62e9a05d4cd884725a5b1bd7c63d3e5%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fvideocardz.com%2Fnewz%2Fnvidia-confirms-no-rtx-50-super-gpus-at-ces-2026-but-promises-updates-for-gamers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GeForce On community update</a> broadcast on Monday night.</p>







<p>That means that the rumored RTX 50 Super graphics card isn’t coming just yet. As far as what is coming, Nvidia is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-reveal-dlss-4-5-at-ces-2026/">expected to unveil DLSS 4.5</a> during the annual event. The major update to the technology will include newer Super Resolution paths as well as the ability for RTX 50 series cards to generate up to six times the number of frames. </p>



<p>While no new graphics cards might be disappointing to some, it doesn’t feel like much of a surprise. The consumer electronics industry, specifically PCs, is going through a tumultuous time. The continued rise of AI and Data Centers have made components like storage, memory, and others in scarce supply. That’s led to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-ram-costs-more-than-new-graphics-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extreme price increases</a>, leaving regular enthusiasts out in the cold. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NVIDIA Live with CEO Jensen Huang" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0NBILspM4c4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>What do you think of no new GPU announcement from Nvidia at CES 2026? Leave your thoughts down below, and join the discussion in the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Tech, read about Nvidia reportedly being set to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">re-release the RTX 3060</a>&nbsp;in 2026. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/">
                                NVIDIA to Re-Release GeForce RTX 3060 in Q1 2026, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that NVIDIA will bring back GeForce RtX 3060 GPUs in Q1 2026 to battle the ongoing memory shortage. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/top-fortnite-players-can-now-get-a-free-gpu-for-playing-fortnite/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/top-fortnite-players-can-now-get-a-free-gpu-for-playing-fortnite/">
                                Top Fortnite Players Can Now Get a Free GPU for Playing Fortnite                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Amid the rising cost of computer components, NVIDIA is distributing a free GPU in an upcoming Fortnite tournament.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-cutting-rtx-50-series-production-2026/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-cutting-rtx-50-series-production-2026/">
                                Nvidia Reportedly Cutting RTX 50 Series Production In 2026                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new report, Nvidia is preparing to cut production of its current-gen GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards in early 2026.</p>
                    </div>

                            </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-isnt-announcing-a-new-gpu-at-ces-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Datamine Reveals Graphics Preset Details for Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-datamine-reveals-graphics-presets-for-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>1397455</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new datamine has revealed Monster Hunters Wilds Switch 2 port details, and it seems the game could run at 30FPS with DLSS enabled on Nintendo’s latest console. </p>



<p>Rumours about a Monster Hunter Wilds Switch 2 port have been circulating for a while now, with dataminers constantly providing new details through the latest update. One of the recent posts on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1pyv6pp/more_info_on_mh_wilds_for_switch_2_including/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reddit</a> discusses Monster Hunter: Wilds Switch 2 data on local multiplayer, DLSS, NPC Culling, and more. Now, details on the graphics preset have also surfaced online. </p>







<h2 id="h-monster-hunter-wilds-switch-2-preset-seemingly-runs-better-than-the-very-low-preset-on-pc">Monster Hunter Wilds Switch 2 Preset Seemingly Runs Better than the ‘Very Low’ Preset on PC</h2>



<p>Spotted by Necrolipe on <a href="https://x.com/necrolipe/status/2007523103845253447" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/evidence-grows-for-a-nintendo-switch-2-port-of-monster-hunter-wilds-including-a-glimpse-at-how-it-could-run/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VGC</a>, the Chinese group responsible for the recent Monster Hunter Wilds datamines has revealed graphics details for the Switch 2 port. The details revealed that the game will run at 30 FPS with DLSS enabled and at 1080p when docked. It is said to have “better fidelity” than the ‘very low’ graphics preset for the PC version of the game. Necrolipe’s post also provides a video based on the datamining preset; however, it doesn’t represent the final version of the port. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="pt" dir="ltr"><p>(Monster Hunter Wilds) </p><p>Grupo chinês 老金群, responsáveis pelo datmining do jogo, divulgaram um vídeo simulando como seria o gameplay no modo portátil do Nintendo Switch 2:</p><p>*Obs.: O vídeo tem como base o preset do datamining, não representa o possível produto final <a href="https://t.co/F07eo4T4P7">pic.twitter.com/F07eo4T4P7</a></p></div>— 'Necro' Felipe #UnivNintendo (@necrolipe) <a href="https://twitter.com/necrolipe/status/2007523103845253447?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 3, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>It doesn’t seem too far-fetched for Capcom to create a Switch 2 port for Monster Hunter Wilds, considering they have already planned Day One releases for their next flagship title, Resident Evil Requiem, as well as Pragmata, Monster Hunter Stories 3, and Mega Man. Additionally, the developers have also revealed that Resident Evil Village and Resident Evil 7 Biohazard will also be released on the platform alongside Requiem. </p>







<p>In other news, Monster Hunter Wilds received its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-free-title-update-4-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free Title Update 4</a> last month, along with a roadmap for the following updates. Additionally, Monster Hunter Wilds was the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-showcase-announced-for-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best-selling game of 2025&nbsp;</a>earlier in the year. What are your thoughts on the datamine graphics presets for Monster Hunter Wilds on Switch 2? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-sales-estimate-hits-12-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders hitting a new sales milestone, and with a peak player record looming</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/monster-hunter-wilds-datamine-reveals-graphics-presets-for-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>