<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:23:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Ascended Heroes Release Date—All Cards & Products]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date-products/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-ascended-heroes-release-date%E2%80%94all-cards-products.1359424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Pokémon TCG sets continue to come thick and fast, and, while Phantasmal Flames has only just hit the shelves, the countdown has begun until the next big set, Ascended Heroes, releases.</p>



<p>Ascended Heroes is the next holiday set in the Pokémon TCG, following on from fan favourites like Prismastic Evolutions and 151, which have set a high bar to meet. However, with the return of Mega Evolution having caught the eye, expectations are high.</p>



<p>If you want to make sure you don’t miss out on the drop of any Pokémon TCG Ascended Heroes products, Insider Gaming has all the crucial details.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-the-pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date">When is The Pokémon Ascended Heroes Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Coming soon. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Ascended Heroes Pokémon</strong> <strong>TCG set releases on January 30, 2026, as confirmed by The Pokémon</strong> <strong>Company, and will be the first set of the new year.</strong></p>



<p>Ascended Heroes will be the third set in the Mega Evolution line, following on from Phantasmal Flames and the base set, featuring the TCG debut of many Mega Pokémon introduced in Pokémon Legends: Z-A, including Mega Dragonite, Mega Hawlucha, and Mega Eelektross.</p>



<p>Not all products are released at once, however, and they are staggered throughout the year. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-pokemon-ascended-heroes-products">All Pokémon Ascended Heroes Products</h2>



<p><strong>Ascended Heroes Pokémon</strong> <strong>TCG products have various release dates, with the first in the line releasing on January 30. </strong></p>



<p>However, many of the most popular products, like Elite Trainer Boxes and Booster Bundles, don’t release on the same date. Additionally, as the set is classed as a holiday set, there is no Booster Box of 36 packs available—similar to Black Bolt, White Flare, and Prismatic Evolutions in 2025.</p>



<p>The table below highlights all the announced products so far for Ascended Heroes and the release dates.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Product</th><th data-align="center">Contents</th><th data-align="center">Release Date</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 2x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Coin<br>– 1x Promo Card</td><td data-align="center">Jan. 30, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Tech Sticker Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 3x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– 1x Sticker Sheet</td><td data-align="center">Jan. 30, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Elite Trainer Box</td><td data-align="center">– 9x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– Gameplay Accessories</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Pokémon Center Elite Trainer Box</td><td data-align="center">– 11x Booster Packs<br>– 2x Promo Cards<br>– Gameplay Accessories</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Mini Tin</td><td data-align="center">– 2x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Art Card<br>– 1x Sticker Card</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Premium Poster Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 10x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– 1x Two-Sided Poster</td><td data-align="center">March 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Booster Bundle</td><td data-align="center">– 6x Booster Packs</td><td data-align="center">– April 24, 2026</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-pokemon-ascended-heroes-cards">All Pokémon Ascended Heroes Cards</h2>



<p><strong>The Ascended Heroes set will feature cards initially printed in the Japanese Mega Dream ex set and Start Deck 100s, though the set lists won’t be identical,</strong> as some cards will be saved for future sets<strong> or pulled to feature as promos.</strong></p>



<p>Only a handful of English cards have been officially revealed so far; Mega Charizard Y ex, a special illustration rare Mega Gengar ex, and basic cards for N’s Vanilluxe and Entei.</p>



<p>Other cards have been revealed in Japanese, however, including a Psyduck art rare, new Team Rocket cards, Mega Froslass ex. With the set releasing on November 28, the majority of cards featuring in Ascended Heroes will be revealed then.</p>



<p>However, the Start Deck 100 in Japan doesn’t release until early December. Not every card printed in the Start Deck will feature in Ascended Heroes, with many set to be reprints of cards released in previous sets this year.</p>



<hr>



<p>What are your thoughts on the Ascended Heroes Pokémon TCG set so far? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-next-pokemon-tcg-set-is-a-master-set-nightmare/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how Mega Dream ex is going to be a nightmare for master set collectors</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-trailer-reveals-new-pikachu-snorlax-variants/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal of Peakychu and Mosslax</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date-products/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Already for Sale on Australian Xbox Store]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store.1359418/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-159088">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The Xbox Partner Showcase is at 1pm ET/10 am PT on Thursday, but it appears one of the bigger announcements has been spoiled ahead of time. Silent Hill 2, which has long been rumored to be coming to Xbox Series X|S this month, has appeared on the Australian Xbox Store. But here’s the kicker, it’s <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-AU/games/store/SILENT-HILL-2/9PNVDQKPJRQV">already for sale</a> for 50% off.</p>



<p>The store listing also confirms that the game will be an Xbox Play Anywhere title. That means if you buy it on your console or PC, you can play on both systems.</p>







<p>This isn’t the first time that the Xbox store has leaked plans for Silent Hill 2. Earlier this month, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-store-leaks-silent-hill-2-xbox-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">store revealed</a> a release date of November 21, though it was quickly removed. </p>



<p>As of publishing, Silent Hill 2 has a “generally favorable” rating of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/silent-hill-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">86 on Metacritic</a>&nbsp;from 105 reviews while the user score is even higher at 9.1 from 3,998 user ratings.</p>



<p>Are you going to pick up Silent Hill 2 for Xbox when it officially releases worldwide? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about Battlefield 6 already <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">setting franchise sales records</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/">
                                Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Be Close to 100GB on Switch 2                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade’s storage requirements for the Switch 2 have been changed, now closer to 100GB. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/">
                                Reanimal Release Date Confirmed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Reanimal’s release date has been confirmed, and pre-orders for the title are now live. Here’s what you need to know. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/">
                                Battlefield 6 Breaks Franchise Sales Record                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the latest data, Battlefield 6 has broken its franchise sales record in just its first month.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-was-the-uss-best-selling-game-of-october-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-was-the-uss-best-selling-game-of-october-2025/">
                                Battlefield 6 Was the US’s Best-Selling Game of October 2025                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the latest sales data, Battlefield 6 was the best-selling game for October 2025 with five other new games in the top 20.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is The Next Black Ops 7 Double XP Weekend?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-next-black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend.1359415/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Black Ops 7 is now firmly set as the latest Call of Duty experience, with players naturally wondering when exactly the double XP events will kick off, and Insider Gaming has everything there is to know.</p>



<p>Although Black Ops 7 may not be everyone’s cup of tea, and has split opinions since its release, Call of Duty remains as one of the industry’s heavy hitters, and special events attract thousands of players into the game.</p>



<p>Whether you have a gun you’re looking to max out or want to get through Prestige as quickly as possible, this guide has all the details about double XP events.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-black-ops-7-s-next-double-xp-weekend">When is Black Ops 7’s Next Double XP Weekend?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Bonuses. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No official dates have been set for the first double XP weekend in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, but leakers have shared some crucial information.</strong></p>



<p>According to reliable data miner <a href="https://x.com/realityuk/status/1989775184182611976" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reality</a>, the first event in Black Ops 7 is right around the corner and will last longer than the usual event.</p>



<p>It’s stated that the first double XP event will kick off on November 25 and will run until December 1, giving players six full days to grind through Prestiges much quicker. However, this event is yet to be confirmed, and will remain as speculation until Activision lifts the lid.</p>



<p>If the dates are correct, though, expect news about the first double XP event in Black Ops 7 to be shared imminently. From there, the events may be more regular, with the launch of Season 1 on the horizon, and major events like Christmas and New Year’s.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-frequent-are-double-xp-weekends">How Frequent Are Double XP Weekends?</h2>



<p><strong>It’s not yet known how frequent double XP weekends will be in Black Ops 7, but the format from Black Ops 6 gives hints of what players can expect.</strong></p>



<p>After the first double XP event in Black Ops 6, Activision settled into a routine that saw double XP events happen at least once a month, with the majority of months having two.</p>



<p>November, December, February, April, May, and July in Black Ops 6 all had at least two double XP events in the month, so expect to see them appear regularly in the latest title </p>



<hr>



<p>How often should double XP events appear in Black Ops 7? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-endgame-available-campaign-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full unlock of the endgame mode for all players this week</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-black-ops-7-warzone-coming-out-black-ops-7-warzone-integration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when Warzone integration is expected</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Be Close to 100GB on Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2.1359376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade’s storage requirements have been changed for the Nintendo Switch 2, now coming in close to 100GB. </p>



<p>We have been hearing a lot about Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 recently, with devs stating they are considering a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whole new game</a> after the release of the final part. However, in the meantime, development on FF7 Remake Intergrade continues for Switch 2, and it seems the game will take up almost half of Switch 2’s base storage space. </p>



<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-remake-will-take-up-almost-half-of-switch-2-s-storage-space">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Take Up Almost Half of Switch 2’s Storage Space</h2>



<p>The announcement about changes towards Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade 2’s storage size on the Switch 2 was revealed through a new official post on <a href="https://x.com/finalfantasyvii/status/1991431395873530291" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter). The standard edition of the title will now range from 90GB to 95GB, up from the previously announced 87.8GB. The Limited Early Purchase Edition and the Limited Early Purchase Digital Deluxe Edition will be priced between 93.8GB and 99GB. These changes will reflect on the Nintendo Store pages soon. </p>



<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade will release for the Switch 2 on January 22, 2026, where players adventure with Avalanche, a ragtag group of idealists who aim to protect the planet. The game follows the story of Cloud Strife, a former soldier turned mercenary who has joined Avalanche to blow up Reactor 1. This edition also includes FF7R EPISODE INTERmission, where players get to play as Yuffie Kisaragi, a young ninja from Wutai, as she infiltrates Midgar on a mission to steal the ultimate materia from the Shinra Electric Power Company.</p>



<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 9 Remake might be ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-might-be-on-ice-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on ice</a>‘ according to information shared by a reliable insider. Additionally, FF7 Remake Trilogy has been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-trilogy-officially-confirmed-for-xbox-and-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially confirmed for Xbox and Switch 2.</a> What are your thoughts on the new storage requirements for Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade on Switch 2? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reanimal’s release date</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>