<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:45:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romeo is a Dead Man Release Date Leaked Ahead of Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/romeo-is-a-dead-man-release-date-leaked-playstation/</link>
            <guid>1373518</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PlayStation may have leaked the official release date of Romeo is a Dead Man. The leak comes only a day before the game’s dedicated presentation by the developer.</p>



<p>Revealed during June 2025’s State of Play, the action-packed Romeo is a Dead Man is the next title from Grasshopper Manufacture. Led by No More Heroes creator Suda51, it looks like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/romeo-is-a-deadman-avoiding-firm-release-date-because-of-gta-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a wild thrill ride</a>, fitting for the creator and his resume. The bloody action title was met with positive reactions from fans and critics after an initial preview. A presentation regarding the game is set for December 5th, but it seems PlayStation might have leaked one of the big announcements: its release date.</p>







<h2 id="h-romeo-is-a-dead-man-releasing-in-february-playstation-leak-states">Romeo is a Dead Man Releasing in February, PlayStation Leak States</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>The Romeo is a Dead Man release date leak comes from <strong>PlayStation itself and the PlayStation app</strong>. It was first spotted by <a href="https://x.com/HazzadorGamin/status/1996636997373644861" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HazzadorGaming on Twitter/X</a>. When you click on the game on the app, instead of the 2026 or ‘Just Announced’ filler used for the icon, it says <strong>February 11th, 2026</strong>. Furthermore, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10016000" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official PlayStation store</a> <strong>mentions the date as well</strong>, giving more leeway to it. However, it’s important to note that is is not official yet, so take it with a grain of salt.</p>



<p>It’s likely PlayStation jumped the gun on the reveal, which would’ve likely been revealed at the presentation. The ‘Grasshopper Direct’ is only five minutes and solely focused on Romeo is a Dead Man. Regardless, fans will still see new gameplay and such, so not all has been spoiled. With <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-all-award-nominees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards</a> slowly approaching, hopefully, no other games will get release date leaks. Even still, this does mean that, if true, players can add Romeo is a Dead Man to their 2026 must-plays.</p>







<p>What do you think of the Romeo is a Dead Man release date being leaked? Think February is a good date? Excited to see more of the game? What’s your favorite Suda51 game? Leave a comment below and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more leaks and rumors, check out coverage on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-shown-exclusively-in-japan-reveals-new-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem gameplay</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-dead-rising-hollywood-possible-capcom-report/">Dead Rising</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/romeo-is-a-dead-man-release-date-leaked-playstation/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carmageddon Is Back With Carmageddon: Rogue Shift]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/carmageddon-is-back-with-carmageddon-rogue-shift/</link>
            <guid>1373515</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>For the first time since 2015, there’s a brand new Carmageddon game. Developer 34BigThings has officially announced Carmageddon: Rogue Shift, the fifth game in the 28-year-old franchise.</p>



<p>The announcement came as part of Thursday’s PC Gaming Show.</p>







<p>According to the developer, Carmageddon: Rogue Shift “blends the signature metal-on-metal carnage of the classic series with modern roguelite depth and silky arcade handling.”</p>



<p><strong>“We are bringing something fresh to the franchise and the racing genre,” </strong>game director Giuseppe Enrico Franchi said. <strong>“Carmageddon means explore, experiment, paint the streets red and crumple up opponents. We want our players to adapt, upgrade, and unleash destruction on zombie hordes with glee behind the wheel of a killing machine.</strong></p>



<p><strong>“Rogue Shift will hit with those who fondly remember the legendary series, and those who are discovering it for the first time – reignited, reinvented and more thrilling than ever.”</strong></p>



<p>While no release date has been announced yet, it was confirmed that the game is coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2, and PC. It’ll also be available for GeForce NOW subscribers.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Carmageddon: Rogue Shift | Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6erdzhnhUEs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<h2 id="h-carmageddon-goes-rogue-lite">Carmageddon Goes Rogue…lite.</h2>



<p>In Carmageddon: Rogue Shift, players go through a roguelite campaign with branching event maps, dynamic challenges and permanent progression between runs. There are 15 upgradeable vehicles that range from tanks to hot rods with 13 weapon classes and over 80 perks to equip.</p>



<p>Other features include a dynamic weather and day-night cycle that impacts which enemies appear and how battles play out, boss fights, and more.</p>



<p>More information on the game, including the release date, will be announced at a later time and can be found on the <a href="https://playcarmageddon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">game’s website.</a> </p>



<p>What do you think of the first information for Carmageddon: Rogue Shift? Leave your thoughts down below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out everything coming in the next Path of Exile 2 update, Last of the Druids. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/carmageddon-is-back-with-carmageddon-rogue-shift/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Druid Class Headlines Path of Exile 2’s Huge 0.4.0 Update]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-druid-class-headlines-path-of-exile-2s-huge-0-4-0-update/</link>
            <guid>1373395</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Grinding Gear Games pulled back the curtain on what’s coming next for Path of Exile 2 in update 0.4.0, and it’s one of the game’s largest updates yet. Also known as Last of the Druids, update 0.4.0 releases on December 12 and introduces the long-awaited Druid class, complete with three shapeshift forms, alongside an entirely new league, major crafting systems, performance upgrades, and sweeping balance changes across the board.</p>



<p>The reveal opened with Game Director Jonathan Rogers introducing The Druid, a hybrid Strength/Intelligence class the team says has been “one of the hardest classes for us to design.” The class blends traditional spellcasting with fluid shapeshifting between Bear, Wolf, and Wyvern forms, each built around completely different playstyles. Rogers emphasized that form-swapping is designed to be “seamless and immediate,” letting players weave in and out of forms mid-combat without friction.</p>







<p>Each form offers its own mechanics: Bear specializes in heavy, rage-powered melee; Wolf leans on mobility and cold damage to build a pack of summoned companions; and Wyvern unleashes long-range elemental breath attacks while consuming corpses to gain power charges. Human-form spells like Volcano, Entangling Vines, and Thunderstorm stack on top of that, creating setups that fuel form-based combos. The class also introduces a new weapon type—Animal Talismans—which determine which form is active and provide the form’s basic attack.</p>



<p>The Druid is also launching with two ascendancy classes: the Shaman, which channels rage into spell damage and enhances elemental chaos around the player, and the Oracle, which uses Foresight to predict incoming skill opportunities and unlocks more than 130 additional passives through alternate-timeline “future selves.”</p>



<p>A third Druid ascendancy will come later, but for now, players can look forward to several new support gems, over 20 Druid skills, and a standout unique item called Fury of the King, which transforms Bear form into a fire demon using the Molten Crash slam.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Path of Exile 2: Last of the Druids Update 0.4.0 | Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EsmeY8npe4c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-introducing-the-fate-of-the-vaal-league"><strong>Introducing the Fate of the Vaal League</strong></h2>



<p>Alongside the Druid comes Path of Exile 2’s newest league, Fate of the Vaal, which dives deep into the lore surrounding Atziri and the ancient Vaal civilization. Game Director Mark Roberts walked through the new league structure, which revolves around uncovering arcane Vaal remnants across Wraeclast. Fully activating them opens a portal into a lost underground temple once belonging to Atziri herself.</p>



<p>The twist is that players essentially build the dungeon themselves. Every run offers six rooms that can be placed to shape the temple layout, link pathways, and position reward rooms. Room interactions matter as much as placement—Garrisons strengthen next to a Commander, Golemworks can power a Smithy, and generators can energize the entire system. Once a layout is set, players enter the temple, clear each room, and begin preparing for the next rebuild.</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<p>Things escalate when the player gains access to a prototype time-portal device. Roberts explains that it takes players back to “right before Atziri triggered the cataclysm,” unlocking an entire suite of past-only rooms with some of the update’s most powerful crafting opportunities. These include multi-stage corruption chambers, new Soul Cores, and the league’s wildest mechanic: limb replacement at the hands of a Vaal Flesh Surgeon, complete with random upgrades that disappear when the player dies.</p>



<p>Defeating the league’s Architect boss unlocks special reward rooms and a path to finally confront the Queen of the Vaal in a reimagined boss fight during her moment of transformation. One of the highlight drops is <strong>Atziri’s Rule</strong>, a staff that increases levels of all corrupted gems and causes projectiles to split into novas when fired at spawning mirrors around the arena.</p>







<h2 id="h-rise-of-the-abyssal-becomes-core-in-path-of-exile-2"><strong>Rise of the Abyssal Becomes Core In Path of Exile 2</strong></h2>



<p>Rise of the Abyssal is officially moving into the core endgame, though players won’t see Abysses in every area. Instead, a new Abyss Tablet allows players to force Abysses into maps and craft Abyss-specific modifiers. Grinding Gear has also built a full Atlas tree around the mechanic, letting players specialize in bosses, factions, or internal league interactions.</p>



<p>At the same time, GGG is addressing one of the biggest complaints about the endgame: monster density. Instead of scaling monster counts up by Tier 15, the team is now keeping density consistent and scaling rewards instead. According to the reveal, monsters will “drop 40% more items, grant 40% more experience, and have 40% more life” as tiers rise—without ballooning horde sizes.</p>



<p>The team is also toning down delirium fog visuals, removing Instilling from waystones, and shifting similar power to Tablets, which last ten maps and reduce micromanagement.</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<h2 id="h-performance-upgrades-and-huge-balance-pass"><strong>Performance Upgrades and Huge Balance Pass</strong></h2>



<p>Performance is another focus in Path of Exile 2’s update 0.4.0, with Rogers noting players “should see frame rates at least 25% higher” thanks to significant CPU-side optimizations. This includes better multithreading and fewer frame spikes, particularly on consoles.</p>



<p>The update also includes broad balance adjustments:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>11 new Unique items</strong></li>



<li><strong>21 rebalanced Lineage Supports + 9 new ones</strong></li>



<li><strong>Major ascendancy updates across nearly all classes</strong></li>



<li><strong>Rebalancing of 90 active skills</strong></li>



<li><strong>Over 250 new passive skills added</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Roberts confirmed that additional endgame content originally planned for 0.4.0 has been pushed to 0.5.0, but emphasized that a “significant overhaul to the atlas passive tree” and new pinnacle bosses are already in development.</p>



<p>Which part of Path of Exile 2’s update 0.4.0 are you most excited to check out on December 12? &nbsp;Leave your thoughts down below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/legacy-of-kain-reboot-eidos-montreal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game Eidos-Montreal had been working on</a>&nbsp;before the Embracer buyout. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-druid-class-headlines-path-of-exile-2s-huge-0-4-0-update/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>