<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:58:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Player Count – How Many People Play Fortnite?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-player-count-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-player-count-%E2%80%93-how-many-people-play-fortnite.1077147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-player-count-confirmed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fortnite is nothing short of sensational. It’s the world’s most popular battle royale game, and since 2024, it has become a titanic title of epic proportions, featuring many ‘smaller’ games within its ecosystem. There’s a racing game, a Guitar Hero-style game, and an infinite suite of UGC for players to enjoy.</p>



<p>On the subject of ‘players’, how many people play Fortnite? Is the Fortnite player count as strong as it was a couple of years ago? In this short guide, I’m diving into that very topic and answering the question.</p>



<p>Read on to find out how many people are playing Fortnite.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-player-count-confirmed">Fortnite Player Count Confirmed</h2>



<p><strong>At the time of writing, a whopping 1.81 million people were playing Fortnite</strong>, with a 24-hour peak of 2.45 million users. That number is typical for Fortnite, which remains one of the most-played games in the world, even almost a decade after it first hit the market. </p>



<p>On <a href="https://fortnite.gg/player-count" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fortnite.gg</a>, users can see exactly how many people play Fortnite and find out statistics such as gain percentage and average rates, plus player peaks – it’s very interesting stuff.</p>



<p>The site also lists various other stats, which I’ll cover now.</p>



<h3 id="h-what-is-the-most-played-fortnite-map">What is the Most Played Fortnite Map?</h3>



<p><strong>‘Battle Royale’ is the most-played Fortnite map</strong>, boasting an all-time peak of 6.53 million players.</p>



<h3 id="h-who-is-the-top-fortnite-creator">Who is the Top Fortnite Creator?</h3>



<p><strong>Epic is the top Fortnite creator</strong>, boasting control of some of the most popular maps ever made in the Fortnite world. Epic has accrued 959 billion minutes played. Behind Epic sits ‘bullseye’, with 25.6 billion minutes played.</p>



<h3 id="h-what-is-the-most-played-fortnite-genre">What is the Most Played Fortnite Genre?</h3>



<p><strong>Most players prefer PvP</strong> – there are 65,787 PvP maps in the Fortnite universe, and at the time of writing, 410,000 players were dedicating their time to PvP. </p>



<h3 id="h-what-is-the-all-time-highest-fortnite-player-count">What is the All-Time Highest Fortnite Player Count?</h3>



<p><strong>The most players ever in Fortnite at the same time was 14,343,880</strong>, and that number was recorded in December 2024.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-fortnite-dying">Is Fortnite Dying?</h2>



<p>It seems bizarre to suggest that Fortnite is dying when you look at how many people play the game, but here we are. There are always those who will oppose the game and suggest it’s ‘dead’ or ‘dying’, regardless of how many people play Fortnite. That’s just a fact of life.</p>



<p>The reality is, Fortnite is only becoming more powerful over time. It’s still the world’s most popular game, and it drives competitive and creative ecosystems like no other game ever made.</p>



<p>It’s not dying, and it probably won’t for many years to come.</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/news/">latest gaming news</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Player Count – How Many People Play Marvel Rivals?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-player-count-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-player-count-%E2%80%93-how-many-people-play-marvel-rivals.1077144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-player-count-confirmed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Marvel Rivals is a showstopper of a game. It was released by NetEase on December 6, 2024, skyrocketing up the charts and becoming known as a powerhouse title that quickly pulled in more than 20 million players – in just a few weeks. As we all know, time impacts the popularity of a game like nothing else, so what does the Marvel Rivals player count look like now?</p>



<p>I’ve taken a look at how many people play Marvel Rivals, breaking down the player data that we can see to determine the health of the game.</p>



<p>Is Marvel Rivals already dying, or is the player count soaring? Let’s find out.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-player-count-confirmed">Marvel Rivals Player Count Confirmed</h2>



<p>It’s not possible to get accurate Marvel Rivals player count data from all the platforms it’s available on, but we can get a representative figure from Steam and simply extrapolate from there.</p>



<p><strong>At the time of writing, 231,346 people were playing Marvel Rivals on PC</strong>, and the 24-hour peak sat at 437,541 users. Amazingly, more users flooded Marvel Rivals in January than in December, with the game gaining momentum as 2025 kicked off.</p>



<p>This might only be data for PC gamers, but it’s a solid indication that the game is performing very strongly on all platforms, given that it’s free to play and highly accessible.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-marvel-rivals-already-dead">Is Marvel Rivals Already Dead?</h2>



<p>Marvel Rivals has suffered slightly with some teething issues, particularly some concerns regarding network stability, unbalanced heroes, and of course, cheaters. However, none of these topics have been powerful enough to prevent the game from growing, such is proven by the Marvel Rivals player count.</p>



<p>This is a solid and substantial alternative to hero shooters like Overwatch, and it’s already proving to be a thorn in the side of those supporting Valve’s Deadlock, which is yet to be released. As there’s a fantastic roster of characters that gamers love and find familiar, the fanbase for the title was ready and waiting on the day the game was released.</p>



<p>If you haven’t played Marvel Rivals, you’re missing out. As the player count proves, it’s a success with gamers worldwide.</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/news/">latest gaming news</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Pokemon Presents Date Seemingly Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-pokemon-presents-date-seemingly-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-pokemon-presents-date-seemingly-leaked.1077072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-pokemon-presents-date-seemingly-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-82389">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The next Pokemon Presents date has seemingly been leaked, and it comes from an unexpected source. </p>



<p>A keen-eyed <a href="https://x.com/mattyoukhana_/status/1876988464878567879" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">user on Twitter</a> spotted metadata from Niantic that hints at the next Pokemon Presents taking place on February 27, 2025. In the data it shows a title of “Pokemon Presents 2025 x GO Tour: Unova Timed Research”. </p>



<p>The leaked date shouldn’t come as a surprise. Since 2021, there has been a Pokemon Presents on February 27 every year to coincide with Pokemon Day. If we are looking at when each of the last four events were announced, they usually didn’t come until just days prior. That means fans shouldn’t expect an official announcement on the next Pokemon Presents until around February 20 or so. </p>







<p>As far as what to expect during the showcase, it’s clear based on the title that a new timed research event for Pokemon Go will be shown. Also, with Pokemon Legends Z-A scheduled to launch this year, it could be assumed that the game will be shown in some way.  Elsewhere, Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket is likely to see a solid presence after it’s successful launch late last year. There’s also a good chance The Pokemon Company has a surprise or two up its sleeve in honor of the 29th Anniversary of Pokemon’s 1996 launch.</p>



<p>Whatever The Pokemon Company has in store for fans, Insider Gaming will have full coverage of the broadcast.</p>



<p>What do you think we see during the Pokemon Presents on Pokemon Day 2025? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what PlayStation franchises are getting&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-horizon-zero-dawn-and-helldivers-movies-at-ces-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live-action movie adaptations</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lenovo-legion-go-s-is-the-first-third-party-steamos-handheld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first third-party handheld PC</a> to come with SteamOS. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developer-direct-announcement-imminent/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developer-direct-announcement-imminent/">Xbox Developer Direct Announcement Imminent?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new tease online, a new Xbox Developer Direct for 2025 could be announced in the near future.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-next-gen-xbox-prime/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-next-gen-xbox-prime/">New Rumor Says Xbox’s Next-Gen Console is a 2026 Release And Called ‘Xbox Prime’</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new rumor has circulated online that the next-gen Xbox called ‘Xbox Prime’ is targeting a 2026 release date.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-1-is-coming-to-pc-game-pass-in-january-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-1-is-coming-to-pc-game-pass-in-january-its-claimed/">Diablo 1 is Coming to PC Game Pass in January, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been claimed that Diablo 1, in addition to a few other games, will make its way to PC Game Pass in January.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elder-scrolls-oblivion-remake-could-be-revealed-next-month-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elder-scrolls-oblivion-remake-could-be-revealed-next-month-its-claimed/">Elder Scrolls Oblivion Remake Could Be Revealed Next Month, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new rumor hints that The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion remake may not only be revealed next month, but could launch sometime in 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Devs Reveal New Parkour Details]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-devs-reveal-new-parkour-details/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-devs-reveal-new-parkour-details.1076979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-devs-reveal-new-parkour-details/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft has just released a new blog post detailing the parkour systems for Assassin’s Creed Shadows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parkour has always been an integral system for every Assassin’s Creed title, and it seems to be a handy tool in Shadows. Parkour will be an excellent feature for exploration and a key tool for stealth and combat. Naoe is the parkour master, and she can quickly scale castles, leap across rooftops and surf the crowds in the streets of Kyoto thanks to her speed and agility. Check out how parkour works in Assassin’s Creed Shadows below.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-new-parkour-inputs-for-assassin-s-creed-shadows-nbsp">New Parkour Inputs for Assassin’s Creed Shadows&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The upcoming game has changed specific inputs to add more mechanics. The crouch and dodge buttons have switched places to add the ability to go prone and let dodge mechanics lead directly to parkour.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Assassin’s Creed Shadows, players will see that dodge and parkour down mechanics have merged thanks to the new input mapping. The new mapping will also disable the stance switch so that you can use any stance when going down from a rooftop. Players will also see new moves with the dodge button, such as acrobatic dodges over railings, jumping out of windows, or new silent drop-downs.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-assassin-s-creed-shadows-parkour-moves-nbsp">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Parkour Moves&nbsp;</h2>



<h3 id="h-parkour-up">Parkour Up</h3>



<p>Players who have played previous Assassin’s Creed games will know that this mechanic lets players hold a button to scale any building or structure they want, and the same parkour system will make its way to Shadows, too. The mechanic works while running up walls, jumping across gaps and leaping into the void. Naoe is better at jumping further and reaching higher than Yasuke.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-recovery-roll-nbsp">Recovery Roll&nbsp;</h3>



<p>When jumping from a distance, players can use the Igan Recovery Roll by pressing the dodge/parkour down button, considerably softening the blow and reducing the noise.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Parkour Deep Dive: Parkour Up &amp; Recovery Roll" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/33Yq6RcLE8Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3 id="h-parkour-down">Parkour Down</h3>



<p>Here’s where the new Assassin’s Creed Shadows parkour system comes into play. As dodge and parkour mechanics have blended, players can press dodge near a ledge to transition into a parkour down traversal. Naoe will have acrobatic descents, while Yasuke will have heavy drops. Parkour down will let you access the safest lowest point below your character and avoid the player needlessly jumping into the void.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Parkour Deep Dive: Dodge to Drop Down" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iZMKe8NZBTI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-sprint-mechanics-nbsp">Sprint Mechanics&nbsp;</h2>



<p>A new system unique to Naoe, the fastest assassin in the franchise, has been introduced. This mechanic allows players to trigger an extended dive roll over smaller objects such as fences, crates, rails, etc.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows also includes two more systems: automated passovers and shoulder tackles. Automated Passovers allow the characters to jump over smaller objects acrobatically. On the other hand, automated shoulder tackle is exclusive to Yasuke, allowing him to bash through enemies or destructive objects while sprinting. If there are non-destructible objects, Yasuke will use automated passover, but it won’t be as clean as Naoe.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Parkour Deep Dive: Sprint Dodge to Escape" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fm0OssNa4eI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-grappling-mechanics">Grappling Mechanics</h2>



<p>Apart from sprinting and parkour, Assassin’s Creed Shadows players can also access a grappling hook. With this tool, players can perform vertical ascents and hook swings. Naoe can also scale unclimbable walls by wall running and using the grappling hook on a ledge.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Parkour Deep Dive: Wall Run to Grappling Hook" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/obO-PMO1Tfw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-advanced-parkour-in-assassin-s-creed-shadows">Advanced Parkour in Assassin’s Creed Shadows</h2>



<h3 id="h-stance-dodges">Stance dodges</h3>



<p>There are three types of stances: standing, crouching, and prone, and each stance has its own way of dodging for Naoe. Yasuke can dodge directionally while standing and crouching; however, only Naoe can dodge directionally while prone. This prone dodge will allow her to move side-to-side, roll forward, or slide backwards.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Stealth Deep Dive: Prone Assassination" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uTuL0Ob2EnU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3 id="h-wall-run-eject">Wall Run Eject</h3>



<p>Thanks to her acrobatic skills, Naoe can run up any wall. The Wall Eject tool allows her to perform an incredible jump off the wall by pressing the parkour button at the top of the run. If her hands and feet are connected to a surface, Naoe can also use this move while climbing.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-parkour-down-backward-dodge-and-high-structure-safety-nbsp">Parkour Down Backward Dodge and High Structure Safety&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Parkour Down Backward Dodge is a new move that allows the character to move while their back is facing the edge. In this position, the player can tap the parkour down button without directional input to cause their character to perform a backward dodge, rolling over the edge and down on the ground with a “muffled landing.”&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Assassin's Creed Shadows - Parkour Deep Dive: Backward Drop Assassination" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WXehGq8UkuM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Parkour Down High Structure Safety is a new system that provides safety for the character at heights where fall damage could occur. In this situation, using parkour-down transitions would cause the character to hold on to the edge and hang there. You must press an additional button to make the character drop-down or climb up.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-unclimbable-surfaces">Unclimbable Surfaces</h2>



<p>Lastly, Assassin’s Creed Shadows will have surfaces that Yasuke and Naoe <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/assassins-creed/news/4TA6gKaTvtOC1mOjZIxCZd/assassins-creed-shadows-parkour-system-overview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">cannot climb</a> with the help of parkour, as they do not have any physical handholds to grab on. The associate game director, Simon, shared that this move is a big deal for them as they must be “more thoughtful about creating interesting parkour highways.” Additionally, this allows them to have “more control about where Naoe can go and where Yasuke can’t,” adding more contrast to the play style.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the developers have assured that most Assassin’s Creed Shadows areas are “very much climbable,” and even more so with the grappling hook. Players must look for “valid entry points from time to time.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-combat/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">combat system overview</a> for Assassin’s Creed Shadows. Also, half of the devs working on this game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/half-of-assassins-creed-shadows-devs-have-never-built-a-game-before/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have never built a game before</a>. What are your thoughts on Assassin’s Creed Shadows’ parkour mechanics?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonys-immersive-concept-showcases-new-ways-to-experience-the-last-of-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony’s new future immersive The Last of Us concept project</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>