<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:36:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#940)—Clues and Answers for Tuesday, January 6]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-6-940/</link>
            <guid>1398016</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>We’re getting our heads into January, and by association, into 2026. What’s ahead are hundreds of NYT Connections puzzles for you to solve before we get into <strong>the next year</strong>, but that’s far too long into the distance to be concerning right now. All that matters today is that you decimate the NYT Connections puzzle presented <strong>right now</strong>.</p>



<p>With that being said, I’ve got the NYT Connections hints and solutions you need below. Have fun!</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-january-6">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (January 6)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #940:</p>



<ul>
<li>DIGS</li>



<li>CLEAR</li>



<li>FLAT</li>



<li>DEEP</li>



<li>PAD</li>



<li>FULL</li>



<li>RICH</li>



<li>QUARTERS</li>



<li>BOAT</li>



<li>BALLOON</li>



<li>FLUSH</li>



<li>PACK</li>



<li>QUADS</li>



<li>PARTY</li>



<li>STUFFED</li>



<li>STRAIGHT</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Slang or casual terms for where you live.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Think about how something might sound.</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>THands you might make at a card table.</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Add “animal” after each</em> <em>word</em>.</li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, January 6:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-january-6-940">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, January 6 (#940)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– DIGS, FLAT, PAD, QUARTERS</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – CLEAR, DEEP, FULL, RICH</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BOAT, FLUSH, QUADS, STRAIGHT</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BALLOON, PACK, PARTY, STUFFED</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">r</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-6-940/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov’s Ending Was ‘Changed’, But Not How Players Were Expecting]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-change-unexpected/</link>
            <guid>1398010</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlestate Games pulled a bit of a sneaky on players looking for an easier ending in Escape from Tarkov following the arrival of the 1.0 release midway through November. In the closing chapter of the game, players must navigate the Terminal map, slaying hundreds of AI enemies, to make it to a boat that marks their ultimate escape from Tarkov.</p>



<p>However, a trickery in the design meant that, in a group, not <strong>everyone </strong>could get a seat on the boat. In a post on social media, one streamer asked to alter the number of seats available on the boat to get out of Tarkov, to which Battlestate said, ‘It’s changed already.’</p>



<p>But the nature of that change has players perplexed.</p>







<h2 id="h-solo-or-no-go">Solo or No Go</h2>



<p>Under <a href="https://x.com/Velion/status/2007488455002206273" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Velion’s post</a> asking for ‘everyone’ to be able to escape together, Battlestate Games’ Nikita Buyanov wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Its changed already</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This prompted many to believe that, as a group, all comers could escape from Tarkov together, no longer needing to sacrifice themselves or kill their friends at the ultimate exfiltration point.</p>



<p>However, the change that Battlestate Games implemented was something pretty drastic and <strong>not </strong>what fans were anticipating. Instead of allowing a group to escape from Tarkov, Battlestate has ensured that just <strong>one seat </strong>is available on the ZUBR boat, regardless of squad size.</p>



<p>That means if you make it through Terminal as a five-man squad, you’ll be left choosing which solo player gets to complete the game at the final post.</p>



<p>This was <a href="https://x.com/Pestily/status/2008264876163228137" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">detailed by Pestily</a>, arguably the most recognizable Escape from Tarkov streamer, in a post on social media:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Hey I watched multiple runs of Terminal yesterday and even with 5 people getting to the end it’s always 1 seat now? I understand “changed” can mean multiple things but only 1? Bruh…</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Fans were quick to comment on the change, and as always, feedback was dramatically mixed and divisive. One user wrote, ‘If this isn’t fixed soon, I’m done with this game.’ Another wrote, “I like the 1-seat change – it forces an actual decision instead of defaulting to the 5-man safety net.”</p>



<p>One Tarkov player suggested a dynamic seating structure that changes according to the ending the players have. The ‘nicer’ their ending, the more seats are available on their boat.</p>







<p>Have you managed to escape from Tarkov yet? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you were forced to run solo.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cloudhead-games-layoffs-staff-impossible-position/">Cloudhead Games has laid off 70% of staff</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-change-unexpected/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cloudhead Games Lays Off 70% of Staff After Landing in an ‘Impossible Position’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cloudhead-games-layoffs-staff-impossible-position/</link>
            <guid>1398007</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a recent <span>social media release, VR-first developer Cloudhead Games announced a massive restructuring that will result in the&nbsp;<strong>layoff of 70% of its employee base,</strong>&nbsp;effective</span> January 7th. The post, penned by the company’s CEO, Denny Unger, revealed a series of issues that had landed the studio in an <strong>impossible position</strong>.</p>



<p>These included a lack of platform funding in the VR space, ‘still nascent challenges’ preventing the widespread success of VR, and the ‘general downturn of the gaming industry.’</p>







<h2 id="h-cloudhead-still-wants-to-transform-humanity">Cloudhead Still Wants to ‘Transform Humanity’</h2>



<p>The post on <a href="https://x.com/CloudheadGames/status/2008316673774715195" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">social media</a> from Cloudhead’s CEO was an emotional one:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The team leaving us are consummate professionals and wonderful people in general. We took great collective pride in creating a culture that was as caring about VR content as they were working to support each other.</p>



<p>Each and every one of them shared a true sense of ‘give a damn’ as we worked through still unseen projects, and they will be deeply missed at our studio. And although we have done our best to pad the landing with supports, if you have room on your team, please see the link below to our ‘Reverse Recruiting’ spreadsheet and contact them directly.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The release went on to explain that the studio can’t achieve immense things alone, and referenced a drop in investment in VR technology and software as a leading contributor to mass redundancies.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Cloudhead has weathered many storms in our 14 years in Virtual Reality. Our belief remains in the power of VR as a medium, as a shared dream machine that will one day <strong>transform humanity</strong>. We have no doubt VR’s mainstream relevance is predestined, with future devices that do ‘everything’, but it will take studios like ours to be there when that time comes.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Cloudhead is working on an unannounced game, but previously produced Pistol Whip, Aperture Hand Lab (in collaboration with Valve), and The Gallery series.</p>



<p>Cloudhead Games is one of the earliest studios to announce a wave of mass layoffs in 2026. As the studio points out, there’s still a general downturn and a global restructuring across the gaming industry, so it likely won’t be the last.</p>



<p>What’s your stance on VR gaming? Have you invested in a headset? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hyperx-headset-reads-brainwaves-make-you-faster/">HyperX has revealed a brain-reading headset</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cloudhead-games-layoffs-staff-impossible-position/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HyperX Reveals Headset That Uses AI to Read Your Brain and Make You Faster]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hyperx-headset-reads-brainwaves-make-you-faster/</link>
            <guid>1397998</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>That isn’t some fictional, dystopian headline; this is where we’re at right now in gaming peripheral technology. At CES 2026, HyperX and Neurable revealed a collaboration that has given way to an AI-powered, sensor-fitted <strong>neurotechnological gaming headset.</strong> It uses ‘non-invasive sensors’ to read brainwaves and encourage gamers to boost their performance.</p>



<p>The combination of HyperX’s peripheral technology and Neurable’s cognitive monitoring solutions endeavours to give players insights into their real-time brain performance and reduce their reaction times.</p>







<h2 id="h-would-you-let-a-headset-monitor-your-brain">Would You Let a Headset Monitor Your Brain?</h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20260105973259/en/Neurable-Introduces-Neurotechnology-Powered-Gaming-Wearable-Headset-With-HyperX?utm_source=neurable&amp;utm_medium=newsroom" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">press release</a> detailing everything you’d want to know about the HyperX x Neurable gaming headset, some telling tidbits of data were handed out. It was claimed that testing participants resulted in an ‘improved reaction time’ of around 43 milliseconds on average, a number that was made ‘even more pronounced’ by testing the headset with pro esports players.</p>



<p>The CEO of Neurable, Ramses Alcaide, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>HyperX allows us to bring neurotechnology to gamers at a scale we’ve never been able to reach before.</p>



<p>We look forward to the excitement of this strategic relationship, which represents a promising future of gaming, one where understanding your mind becomes as natural as understanding your mechanics. By making brain-computer interfaces (BCI) intuitive and invisible inside the tools players already use, we’re proving that neuroscience can meaningfully elevate performance and transform the way people play.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>HP’s Josephine Tan echoed the sentiment:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We’ve always been about empowering power players with the best technology to play, and now with our strategic collaboration with Neurable, we look forward to giving more insight into how one’s cognitive skills and focus impacts their gameplay to ultimately make them as competitive as possible.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s not clear when the HyperX x Neurable headset will make it to market, and it hasn’t been suggested how much such a device would cost.</p>







<p>Do you think you’d invest in a headset that can monitor your brainwaves? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-dead-on-arrival-gamers-fear-a-flop/">Highguard could be dead on arrival</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hyperx-headset-reads-brainwaves-make-you-faster/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>