<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:43:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 4 Preload Guide & File Size Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-preload-guide-file-size-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ninja-gaiden-4-preload-guide-file-size-explained.1321330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Ninja Gaiden 4 release is quickly approaching, allowing players to download the game ahead of launch, and the preload and file size are available now.</p>



<p>If you have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-ninja-gaiden-4-pre-order-bonuses-amp-editions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pre-ordered the game</a>, you are just about ready to go, but to make sure you can play <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the moment that it’s available</a>, you should get the download out of the way now.</p>



<p>Here is a preload guide for Ninja Gaiden 4 and the pre-launch file size on each platform.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-can-you-preload-ninja-gaiden-4">When Can You Preload Ninja Gaiden 4?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The wait is almost over. Image by Team Ninja</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Preloads for Ninja Gaiden 4 are currently available on PC via the Windows Store and Xbox Series X|S. As of this writing, PlayStation 5 and Steam players will have to wait just a little longer before they can start downloading the game.</strong></p>



<p>Unfortunately, we do not have a confirmed date or time that Steam and PlayStation will allow players to start the <a href="https://teamninja-studio.com/ng4/us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ninja Gaiden 4</a> preload. The release date is set for October 21, so you should expect it to be available any day now.</p>



<h2 id="h-ninja-gaiden-4-file-size-explained">Ninja Gaiden 4 File Size Explained</h2>



<p><strong>As of pre-launch, the Ninja Gaiden 4 file size sits at 54.9 GB on PC through the Windows Store, 36.82 GB on Xbox Series X, and 23.55 GB on PlayStation 5. Steam players can probably expect a similar file size to the Windows Store version.</strong></p>



<p>As is pretty usual, the file size on PC is larger because the game has to account for a larger variety of hardware that will be running the game, a lot of which is stronger than you see in the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X. With that said, the PlayStation 5 version being less than half of the PC version is definitely a testament to the compression work in that version.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that these file sizes are for the game ahead of launch. If there is a day-one patch or update, who knows how much the file sizes could jump up.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-preload-ninja-gaiden-4">How to Preload Ninja Gaiden 4</h2>



<p><strong>To preload Ninja Gaiden 4, you will have to pre-order the game digitally through any of the supported platforms. Anyone looking to get the game physically will have to wait until release, when they have the disc in hand.</strong></p>



<p>If you <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-ninja-gaiden-4-have-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pre-order the game now</a>, there should be an option at checkout to start downloading the game immediately. If you have preordered previously, look in your owned games library for the option to start downloading. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers</a> can go to the Game Pass app and search for the game to find the pre-install option.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you anxiously awaiting the release of Ninja Gaiden 4? Let us know your hype meter in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>Check out some of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-ninja-gaiden-4-gameplay-trailer-shows-off-disgusting-levels-of-difficulty/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">difficult combat you have coming your way</a> when Ninja Gaiden 4 releases.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-preload-guide-file-size-explained/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Minecraft Movie Sequel Confirmed For 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-confirmed-2027/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-confirmed-for-2027.1321246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A sequel to A Minecraft Movie is officially in the works, complete with a June 2027 release.</p>



<p>The worldwide sensation Minecraft has kept players occupied with its world-building fun since 2011. Millions of fans have purchased the game, and it has become a household name since. This year, Warner Bros. released a movie adaptation of the game, called A Minecraft Movie. Needless to say, it is currently the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-movie-301-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">third-highest-grossing film of 2025</a>. Now, after months of speculation, it seems we’ll be returning to the mines real soon.</p>



<h2 id="h-a-minecraft-movie-sequel-releasing-on-june-27th-2027-director-returning">A Minecraft Movie Sequel Releasing on June 27th, 2027, Director Returning</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/AMinecraftMovie/status/1976341544266498142" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Twitter/X</a> post, it was announced that A Minecraft Movie sequel is officially in the works. It’s unknown what the sequel will be named. Furthermore, the original director, Jared Hess, will return to do the second one. With a poster showing two shiny pickaxes, we also have a release date: June 27th, 2027. The date does place it with to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-simpsons-movie-coming-after-almost-20-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Simpsons Movie 2</a>, so it’s sure to be a big day for the box office.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, it’s unknown if any of the original cast will return for the sequel. Even more so, we don’t know about the plot, as it’s being kept under wraps for now. Despite that, the movie is sure to be just as popular, especially since it knows what worked. Countless memes like “Chicken Jockey” and “I am Steve” flooded the internet even before its release and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-minecraft-movie-has-added-a-disclaimer-warning-viewers-not-to-throw-popcorn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even caused uproars</a> in theaters. Warner Bros. is aware of it and honed in on it for marketing, which likely caused its box-office soar. It’ll be interesting to see how it fares out and if it’ll keep the charm many fans enjoyed.</p>



<p>Are you excited for A Minecraft Movie sequel? Did you watch the first one? What did you think of it? Let us know in the comments, forums, and on&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/5f4cvU6G" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Minecraft, check out our coverage on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-superman-skin-pack-released-to-celebrate-new-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the recent Superman DLC pack</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/jack-black-has-logged-more-than-100-hours-on-minecraft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jack Black’s commitment to Steve</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-sequel-confirmed-2027/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tron-Inspired Synth Riders: Overdrive Coming to Nintendo Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/synth-riders-overdrive-nintendo-switch-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tron-inspired-synth-riders-overdrive-coming-to-nintendo-switch.1321192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>One of VR’s biggest music games is launching an all-new entry, Synth Riders: Overdrive, on the Nintendo Switch later this year.</p>



<p>The music action genre is one not explored as much as it should be. Games like Rhythm Heaven, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hi-fi-rush-aaron-greenberg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hi-Fi Rush</a>, and the upcoming Unbeatable bring the beats and fun, but the genre still unexplored. However, the VR space, led by Beat Saber, has been a beacon of groovy gameplay and entertainment. One such game was 2019’s Synth Riders, which has launched on multiple VR platforms like Oculus Rift and PSVR. The game mixes Tron-like cyberpunk visuals with music-based gameplay featuring today’s biggest songs. Its success with fans and critics left its mark on them and, now, the acclaimed series is returning, this time for the Nintendo Switch.</p>



<h2 id="h-synth-riders-overdrive-brings-the-beats-to-nintendo-switch">Synth Riders: Overdrive Brings The Beats To Nintendo Switch </h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Synth Riders: Overdrive - Official Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LfeXfq44AiM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Announced today with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LfeXfq44AiM" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a new trailer</a>, developer Kluge Interactive revealed that Synth Riders: Overdrive, a new game in the series, is coming to the Nintendo Switch. Made from the ground up, the title brings the music-filled gameplay to newer audiences, along with the addition of multiplayer and story mode. With three difficulty modes, you can play through dozens of pop songs from artists like Charli XCX, Jack Harlow, Starcadian, and more. In a statement from Kluge, founder and CEO Arturo Perez said the following:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“As experts in music rhythm games who’ve created a successful VR immersive experience, we’re excited to bring our expertise and passion for music to Nintendo Switch gamers with Synth Riders: Overdrive,” states Perez. “The Switch’s portability and local multiplayer capabilities make it the perfect platform for friends and families to experience this fast-paced musical adventure together.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Synth Riders: Overdrive plans to release before the end of 2025, with DLC already in the works featuring Gorillaz and Monster Cat. More information can be found on <a href="http://synthriders.gg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s official website</a>, as well as on social media.</p>



<p>Are you excited for Synth Riders: Overdrive? Did you play the original Synth Riders on VR? Let us know in the comments, forums, and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/5f4cvU6G" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more rhythm games, check out our coverage on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/redoctane-games-launches-to-revive-rhythm-game-genre-with-guitar-hero-devs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Guitar Hero</a> and our picks for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/5-rhythm-games-you-need-to-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the best in the genre</a>. Don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!<br></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/synth-riders-overdrive-nintendo-switch-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Adds Two Classic Heroes of Might & Magic Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-adds-two-classic-heroes-of-might-magic-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-adds-two-classic-heroes-of-might-magic-games.1321156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-151219">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Ubisoft has announced that it’s adding two classic Heroes of Might &amp; Magic games to the Xbox Game Pass library. </p>



<p>Starting today, October 9, both Heroes of Might and Magic II: Gold and Heroes of Might and Magic III: Complete are available for all members on the platform. The games will be available on PC for PC Game Pass and Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers.</p>



<p>“I can think of no better way to teach a new generation the meaning of key words like throng, necromancy, and logistics,” Ubisoft’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YB2kNoEMd70" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chris Watters said</a>.</p>



<p>In addition to the games being added to the service, it was also revealed that Heroes of Might &amp; Magic: Olden Era’s Early Access release <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heroes-of-might-magic-olden-era-early-access-demo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was being pushed to 2026</a>. To fill in the gap between now and the launch, however, developers Unfrozen have released a demo on PC via Steam.</p>



<p>Are you going to check out the Heroes of Might &amp; Magic II or III now that they’re on Game Pass? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hyper-light-breaker-developers-ending-development-and-laying-off-staff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developer Heart Machine stopping work</a> on Hyper Light Breaker. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heroes-of-might-magic-olden-era-early-access-demo/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heroes-of-might-magic-olden-era-early-access-demo/">
                                Heroes of Might &amp; Magic: Olden Era Early Access Pushed To 2026, Demo Released                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>As part of the franchise’s 30th anniversary celebration, the release date for Heroes of Might &amp; Magic: Olden Era has finally been announced.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-founder-describes-game-pass-price-hikes-as-greed-over-gaming/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-founder-describes-game-pass-price-hikes-as-greed-over-gaming/">
                                Xbox Founder Describes Game Pass Price Hikes as ‘Greed Over Gaming’                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Xbox founder has provided their views on the recent Game Pass price hike, calling it a betrayal. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-players-on-playstation-earn-more-xp-than-xbox-pc/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-players-on-playstation-earn-more-xp-than-xbox-pc/">
                                Battlefield 6 Players on PlayStation Earn More XP Than Xbox &amp; PC                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>If you’re on PlayStation, you can earn more multiplayer XP than users on either Xbox or PC, offering a big advantage.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-launch-patch-notes-movement-nerfs-weapon-handling-rebalanced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-launch-patch-notes-movement-nerfs-weapon-handling-rebalanced/">
                                All Battlefield 6 Launch Patch Notes—Movement Nerfs &amp; Weapon Handling Rebalanced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlefield 6 is poised to launch to the world and a flood of patch notes have been shared, making significant tweaks across many aspects.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-adds-two-classic-heroes-of-might-magic-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>