<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 19:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New DOOM: The Dark Ages Gameplay Revealed, Game Releases on May 15, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-releases-on-may-15-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-revealed-game-releases-on-may-15-2025.1090275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-releases-on-may-15-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-85496">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>DOOM: The Dark Ages has been confirmed to release on May 15, 2024, as a part of the Xbox Developer Direct.</p>



<p>New DOOM: The Dark Ages gameplay footage has been revealed at this year’s January Xbox Developer Direct, where it was also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-may/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed following leaks</a> that the game will launch May 15, 2025, on the Xbox Series S|X (day one on Game Pass), PC (day one on Game Pass), and the PlayStation 5. You can watch the gameplay trailer below:</p>



<p><strong>TRAILER NOT YET UPLOADED </strong></p>



<p>The game description reads, “DOOM: The Dark Ages is the single-player, action FPS prequel to the critically acclaimed DOOM (2016) and DOOM Eternal. You are the DOOM Slayer, the legendary demon-killing warrior fighting endlessly against Hell. Experience the epic cinematic origin story of the DOOM Slayer’s rage in 2025.”</p>



<p>For those out of the loop, a bit <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-gameplay-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more DOOM: The Dark Ages gameplay</a> was revealed yesterday via a behind-the-scenes technical demo. </p>



<p>DOOM: The Dark Ages launches May 15, 2025.</p>



<p>Will you be playing the game? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-organisation/">Shroud might start a Marvel Rivals team</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/civilization-7-goes-gold-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization 7 Goes Gold Ahead Of Release</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-release-date-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-release-date-announced/">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Release Date Announced</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Kepler Interactive announced the release date for Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 during the Xbox Developer Direct event on January 23.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-rules-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-rules-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters/">Ubisoft is Cracking Down on Rainbow Six Siege Cheaters with New Rules</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ubisoft is clamping down hard on Rainbow Six Siege cheaters. Check out the latest changes the team has made to the game’s anti-cheat measures</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-release-on-a-wide-range-of-platforms/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-release-on-a-wide-range-of-platforms/">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 Will Release on a ‘Wide Range of Platforms’&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 might not be exclusive to PS6, according to Square Enix’s recent statement. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced/">South of Midnight Release Date Announced</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Xbox has finally revealed the release date for the upcoming South of Midnight from developer Compulsion Games.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft is Cracking Down on Rainbow Six Siege Cheaters with New Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-rules-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-is-cracking-down-on-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters-with-new-rules.1090269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-rules-rainbow-six-siege-cheaters/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft has released an update on the state of play with Rainbow Six Siege’s anti-cheat mechanics. In a release published on social media, the team revealed that things are getting tougher for the cheaters and malicious operators who want to spoil everyone else’s fun in the tactical FPS.</p>



<p>Most of the changes are live now and are being witnessed first-hand by streamers and pro players.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-getting-stricter">Getting Stricter</h2>



<p>In the recent update from Ubisoft, it was explained that three major changes are being made to Rainbow Six Siege’s anti-cheat mechanics:</p>



<p><strong>Botting: Permanent Ban on First Offence</strong></p>



<p>‘We’ve heard your feedback and are updating our sanctioning systems for players detected for botting. Players will now be permanently banned on their first botting offense, rather than an initial 15-day ban followed by a permanent ban on the second offense. This stricter and more aggressive sanctioning has been made possible by an improved detection system that drastically reduces false positives.’</p>



<p><strong>Cheater Match Cancellation and Live Kick</strong></p>



<p>‘As of now, cheaters sanctioned by our systems will be kicked from their ongoing match and the match will be automatically cancelled.’</p>



<p>This was captured first-hand by a popular streamer:</p>



<div><article><p><span>So it turns out </span><a href="https://twitter.com/Rainbow6Game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Rainbow6Game</a><span> is not messing around. It kicks the cheater and instantly cancels the match. No elo is taken from anyone and rollback commences for all who queued with the cheater that season. 

This is an unbelievable development and I am SO hype.</span></p></article></div>







<p><strong>Encryption: Binary Hardening and Security</strong></p>



<p>‘Along with Y9S4.2, we are shipping a new round of hardening and security updates, as we did in each patch (4.0, 4.1, 4.1.1) with major disruption and impact on the most prevalent cheat providers.’</p>



<p>Do you think these changes are a win, or are they likely to backfire on honest, legitimate players? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-whats-next/">Gray Zone Warfare has a stacked year ahead</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South of Midnight Release Date Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced.1090263/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>South of Midnight finally has a release date. During its 2025 Xbox Developer Direct on Thursday, developer Compulsion Games revealed that the game will launch on April 8.</p>



<p>When it launches, South of Midnight will be available on Xbox Series X|S, PC, and via Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>South of Midnight comes from the developers of We Happy Few, and takes players to the deep south of the United States. The game sees you play Hazel who becomes a Weaver after a storm hits her home of Prospero. According to Compulsion Games, a Weaver is a “magical mender of broken bonds and spirits”.</p>



<p>“Imbued with these new abilities, Hazel will confront and subdue dangerous creatures, untangle the webs of her own family’s shared past and -if she’s lucky – find her way to a place that feels like home,” the game’s description reads.</p>



<p>South of Midnight is Compulsion Games’ first release under the Xbox Game Studios umbrella. The studio had been independent before it was purchased by Xbox in 2018. The game itself was first announced in June 2023 before getting its first gameplay trailer in June 2024. That’s when the 2025 release window was also confirmed before getting a firm release date during the Developer Direct.</p>



<p>“At Compulsion Games, we love to craft around central themes,” game director Jasmin Roy said. “We’re lucky to have talent across all our disciplines that collaborate to give South of Midnight such a unique personality.”</p>



<p>In addition to a release date, Compulsion Games released the story trailer, giving players a deeper look at what they can expected when loading into South of Midnight.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="South of Midnight - Story Trailer | Developer_Direct 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/klgw-To1rqc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Are you excited to finally know the release date for South of Midnight? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what game was the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-was-the-best-selling-game-of-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best-selling game for 2024</a>. &nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 2 Remastered Drops Today on Xbox – ‘Ninja Gaiden 2 Black’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-2-black-remastered-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ninja-gaiden-2-remastered-drops-today-on-xbox-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98ninja-gaiden-2-black%E2%80%99.1090176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-2-black-remastered-xbox-game-pass/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It was just revealed at the Xbox Developer Direct showcase that Ninja Gaiden 2 Remake – known as ‘Ninja Gaiden 2 Black’ – drops <strong>today </strong>on Xbox Game Pass. This shadowdrop comes courtesy of Team Ninja, who revealed Ninja Gaiden 4 just moments before announcing the sudden and unexpected arrival of the rebuilt Ninja Gaiden 2.</p>



<p>You can play Ninja Gaiden 2 Black <strong>now</strong>, and it’s guaranteed to keep you busy until Ninja Gaiden 4 is released in Fall 2025.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-back-in-black">Back in Black</h2>



<p>Ninja Gaiden 2 Black has been fully built in UE5 by Team Ninja, honouring the ‘original style of the game’ with lush visuals. There will be a string of playable characters, including Ayane, Momiji, Rachel, and of course, Ryu Hayabusa.</p>



<p>Here’s the trailer for Ninja Gaiden 2 Black:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NINJA GAIDEN 2 Black Official Launch Trailer | Developer_Direct 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFjWCZIVZDw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Ninja Gaiden 2 Black is available now on Xbox and PC, and it has been added to the Game Pass subscription service.</p>



<p>During the Xbox Developer Direct showcase, Team Ninja said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We are happy to deliver this to the fans that have been dedicated to Ninja Gaiden over the years, as well as to newcomers of the series. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Ninja Gaiden 2 was originally released on the Xbox 360 way back in 2008, so this certainly is a blast from the past. Are you excited about the legendary game resurfacing? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/south-of-midnight-release-date-announced/">South of Midnight releases April 8th</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 4 Announced At Xbox Developer Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ninja-gaiden-4-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct.1090173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-announced-at-xbox-developer-direct/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A new Ninja Gaiden game is on its away. From developers Team Ninja and PlatinumGames, Ninja Gaiden 4 was announced during the Xbox Developer Direct on Thursday.</p>



<p>The game’s announcement confirms the rumors that a “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-to-get-a-new-game-from-legendary-japanese-franchise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">legendary Japanese IP</a>” was going to see a game announced during the annual event.</p>



<p>“To all the ‘Master Ninja’ around the world, after more than 10 years, the wait is finally over,” Team Ninja’s Fumihiko Yasuda said. “We’re excited to announce Ninja Gaiden 4, a new mainline entry in this high-speed action series, where you become the ultimate ninja and take on relentless enemies in fierce combat.”</p>



<p>Ninja Gaiden will release in Fall 2025 on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC. The game will also be available day one on Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>In addition to the announcement of Ninja Gaiden 4, Koei Tecmo <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-2-black-remastered-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced Ninja Gaiden 2 Black</a>. Built in Unreal Engine 5, Ninja Gaiden 2 Black is a remake of the game from 2008. To bridge the gap between now and the release of Ninja Gaiden 4, the remake is available starting today on PC, console, and Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>“I want to thank fans who have patiently waited for the return of the series. Their passion was the driving force behind the development of&nbsp;Ninja Gaiden 4&nbsp;and our collaboration with PlatinumGames. I’m thrilled that we were finally able to make this announcement and hope it brings joy to our fans. We’ll continue working hard to meet your expectations.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NINJA GAIDEN 4 Official Announce Trailer | Developer_Direct 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08vbgX9lpWY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>What do you think of a new Ninja Gaiden game coming to Xbox? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/unknown-9-awakening-developer-reflector-hit-with-layoffs-after-games-failure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details on the layoffs</a> that took place at Unknown 9: Awakening developer Reflector Entertainment. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>