<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:03:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Limited Edition Marathon DualSense Controller and Headset Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/limited-edition-marathon-dualsense-and-headset-revealed/</link>
            <guid>1410172</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>From January 29, prospective fans of Marathon, Bungie’s all-new extraction shooter, can pre-order the limited edition DualSense and Pulse Elite wireless headset. The exclusive range is being manufactured to welcome Marathon to the market, and the announcement comes at the same time as the game’s release date was confirmed.</p>



<p>The full game will be released on March 5, but for now, you can stoke your excitement by <strong>preparing </strong>to preorder the limited edition controller and headset.</p>







<h2 id="h-marathon-s-marketing-march-starts-now">Marathon’s Marketing March Starts Now</h2>



<p>Bungie dropped a new trailer earlier today, revealing the full release date for Marathon, the upcoming extraction title. It came hours after the full trailer was leaked online, uncovering the game’s launch date before Bungie could drop the announcement.</p>



<p>What wasn’t revealed ahead of time was the new DualSense controller and Pulse Elite wireless headset, produced in honor of the new game.</p>



<p>It has been a rocky road for Marathon and Bungie over the last year or so, but by all accounts, things are starting to straighten up ahead of the game’s ultimate release.</p>



<p>Here’s a look at the new controller:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>And a nice glimpse at the new Pulse Elite wireless headset:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>While you can pre-order the peripherals from January 29, you won’t get your hands on them until the game launches in March. Also, you can <strong>only </strong>pre-order the Pulse Elite wireless headset from PlayStation Direct.</p>



<p>Here are your pricing points:</p>



<p><strong>DualSense –</strong> $84.99</p>



<p><strong>Pulse Elite</strong> <strong>– </strong>$169.99</p>



<p>Marathon could turn around all expectations and smash into the extraction space with a mighty roar in just a few weeks. People are approaching the game with bated breath, but recent playtests have suggested that it’s potentially shaping up to be something enjoyable, at the very least.</p>







<p>Are you going to be investing in a Marathon DualSense or Pulse Elite headset? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-2-location-post-apocalyptic-china/">Stellar Blade 2 might head to China</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/limited-edition-marathon-dualsense-and-headset-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Heartopia on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Or Switch? All Console Platforms, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/heartopia-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-switch-all-platforms/</link>
            <guid>1410169</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Heartopia will likely end 2026 as one of the most lovingly titled games, and the life-sim title established itself early on as a game to keep an eye on. Its popularity boomed very quickly, and if you PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo owners want in on the action, there are answers for you all.</p>



<p>You’d think you can only have so many <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/year-in-review-forget-gta-6-2026-is-all-about-the-life-sim-genre/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">life-sim</a> games like Heartopia. Yet, the game from developer XD is proving once again that humanity can’t get enough of building houses and completing menial tasks that would be more productive if done in the real world—but we’re all gamers here, it would be hypocritical to suggest you go touch grass.</p>



<p>If you have a Heartopia-shaped box on your mind, its console status should be of interest.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-heartopia-on-playstation-5">Can You Play Heartopia On PlayStation 5?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Pretty bubbles in the air. Credit to XD</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>It’s an arrow through the heart for PS5 users as Heartopia isn’t available to play on PlayStation consoles at launch.</strong></p>



<p>Heartopia’s launch day player numbers on PC were fantastic, as were the ones after it! Before it came to Steam, Heartopia actually launched on the Google Play Store and the App Store. It garnered a reputation very first, making its Steam release a popular one. Tens of thousands of people got straight to work on creating homes and virtual lives.</p>



<p>For now, PlayStation 5 owners must miss out and play the waiting game. </p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-heartopia-on-xbox-series-x-s">Can You Play Heartopia On Xbox Series X|S?</h2>



<p><strong>Heartopia is bypassing Xbox consoles, leaving Xbox Series X|S users to have their hearts skip a beat.</strong></p>



<p>Everyone is striking out with Heartopia. The life-sim title doesn’t have any love in its heart for Microsoft and Xbox owners right now. It follows the same sorrowful fate as PlayStation players, but let’s hope there’s a future where this can change.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-heartopia-on-nintendo-switch-or-switch-2">Can You Play Heartopia On Nintendo Switch or Switch 2?</h2>



<p><strong>Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 owners can also get in the same loveless boat, as Heartopia isn’t on a Nintendo console either.</strong></p>



<p>Per the Heartopia Discord Server, one of its main moderators (sweetkayla_xo) <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1128257488375005215/1420319877507579988/1458417800250134569" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“No – Heartopia isn’t launching on consoles yet.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s unclear how much official information they have on the game. If they do know the inner-workings of the game’s development and reach, then this is a surefire sign that Heartopia is coming to consoles; we just don’t know when.</p>



<p>Are you playing Heartopia on mobile or PC? Do you have anything to say about the poor console players who are missing out? You can share your thoughts via the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more guides, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-the-residents-request-office-in-heartopia/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where the Resident’s Request Office is in Heartopia</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/heartopia-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-switch-all-platforms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade 2 Location Tease Points To Post-Apocalyptic China]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-2-location-post-apocalyptic-china/</link>
            <guid>1410166</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Shift Up recently posted an image on social media revealing a ‘location scout’ for their ‘next title’, which is almost certainly Stellar Blade 2. The follow-up to the 2024 post-apocalyptic sultry slasher was confirmed a while back, and by now, it should be full steam ahead for Shift Up in terms of piecing it together.</p>



<p>The apocalyptic landscape shared by the team on social media is a snippet taken from Chongqing, China. This is a gargantuan, dense cityscape with a population of <span>over 32 million people, but in Stellar Blade 2, it appears&nbsp;<strong>as</strong></span><strong> a ghost city</strong>. </p>







<h2 id="h-stellar-blade-2-promises-to-turn-heads">Stellar Blade 2 Promises to Turn Heads</h2>



<p>Stellar Blade dropped on PlayStation 5 in 2024, emerging as a game that intrigued players because, while it was marketed almost as a ‘gooner game’, it turned out to have some immensely satisfying combat mechanics and a decent story.</p>



<p>The game’s lead, Eve, wastes no time in showing as much flesh as possible, and that’s why the game perhaps didn’t get as serious a stamp of approval as it should have from some critics.</p>



<p>Regardless, it was a commercial success that was compounded by a hugely successful launch on PC a year later, and recently, the team at Shift Up revealed that <strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-sequel-in-development-now/">another game in the series</a> is coming</strong>.</p>



<p>The recent post <a href="https://x.com/StellarBlade/status/2012973553562321375">on social media</a> shows a crumbling, abandoned landscape, which eagle-eyed fans immediately identified as being a rendition of Chongqing, China. This was confirmed by Shift Up shortly after, giving fans the impression that, whenever Stellar Blade 2 arrives, it might take inspiration from or be directly set in and around the Chinese city.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It’s no big secret that Chinese fans were hugely approving of the game. It was estimated that 58% of PC-related sales of Stellar Blade were <strong>from </strong>China.</p>







<p>We know nothing about Stellar Blade 2, outside of these tiny tidbits from Shift Up. The nature of the game is yet to be revealed, but it might not be too long before <strong>it is</strong>. Fans expect something to be uncovered <strong>in the coming months</strong>.</p>







<p>What are you expecting to see from Stellar Blade 2? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-official-bungie/">Marathon’s release date has been confirmed</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-2-location-post-apocalyptic-china/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riot MMO Secures World of Warcraft Lead Producer]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/riot-mmo-secures-world-of-warcraft-lead-producer/</link>
            <guid>1410130</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>World of Warcraft’s former lead producer has confirmed that they are jumping ship to work on Riot’s upcoming MMO. </p>



<p>Not much is known about the upcoming Riot League of Legends MMO, other than the fact that it is set in the Runeterra universe. League of Legends itself is reportedly scheduled to receive a major overhaul by 2027, which will seemingly be dubbed as ‘League Next’. However, today we aren’t talking about that title. </p>







<h2 id="h-riot-mmo-brings-in-world-of-warcraft-s-raymond-bartos">Riot MMO Brings in World of Warcraft’s Raymond Bartos </h2>



<p>The World of Warcraft’s lead producer, Raymond Bartos, announced his departure from Blizzard last month, after working for 3 years at the company. During that time, Bartos helped push content like Plunderstorm, multiple Remixes, Gear update, Dungeon Followers, Dastardly Duos and more. However, now he is ready to kick-start a new chapter in his game development journey. </p>



<p>Bartos took to <a href="https://x.com/RaymondBartos/status/2011629347803734299" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) to reveal that he will be moving to Riot Games to work on their upcoming MMO and taking on the role of Senior Game Producer. After working on one of the biggest MMORPGs on the planet, his expertise will be crucial to developing this project. The values of Riot Games were influential in securing Bartos, with the former WoW lead producer revealing that “kindness, respect, and care aren’t just words” at Riot, and it is something the “team truly lives by”. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I’m incredibly excited to be joining <a href="https://twitter.com/riotgames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@riotgames</a> on the MMO team!!!</p><p>From my very first conversation with Riot, I immediately gravitated toward their values—and I was genuinely impressed by how clearly those values showed up throughout the interview process. It made it obvious… <a href="https://t.co/Sap1O7CQeo">pic.twitter.com/Sap1O7CQeo</a></p></div>— GoodGuyRay 💙 (@RaymondBartos) <a href="https://twitter.com/RaymondBartos/status/2011629347803734299?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Regarding Riot’s MMO, the last major update was <a href="https://x.com/MarcMerrill/status/1770479141600874553" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">back in 2024</a>, when the company’s co-founder spoke about future plans. At the time, they had decided to reset the direction of the project. Resetting also meant that they would be “going dark” for “several years,” and that seems to be the case. The company doesn’t want to create an MMO that players have played before with a Runeterra coat of paint. Instead, they want to do something “that truly feels like a significant evolution of the genre.” </p>







<p>In other news, Riot Games has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/riot-congratulates-hytale-six-months-after-canceling/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">congratulated Hytale’s early access launch</a>, six months after cancelling the game. What are your thoughts on Riot MMO securing World of Warcraft’s lead producer? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-official-bungie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bungie officially revealing Marathon’s release date</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/riot-mmo-secures-world-of-warcraft-lead-producer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Wordle #1676: Hints and Answer for January 20, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1676-hints-answer-january-20-2026/</link>
            <guid>1410127</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p id="block-82589153-ecc8-4fc6-9372-9d8a78357ece">Wordle challenges players to guess a fresh five-letter word each day in six tries or fewer. Whether you’re a beginner or a daily player, today’s tips and strategies can help you solve it faster and maintain your streak—if you’re open to a little extra help. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Wordle, don’t worry, below you’ll find some <strong>helpful hints and even the answer for Wordle Game #1676</strong> <strong>for January 20, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-672014a9-ce75-4ea0-b98d-12b9214dbb53">To play today’s Wordle, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to the game’s website.</a> If you want to go right to today’s answer without any tips or tricks, you <strong><a href="#h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1676-on-january-20-2026">can click right here</a>.</strong></p>







<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> The following information includes spoilers on today’s and yesterday’s editions of Wordle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure id="block-5f20defe-2f05-4eb9-b880-6af2f94b324d"></figure>



<h2 id="block-e2995432-719e-4ed6-8fad-a1db37670203">How To Play Wordle</h2>



<p id="block-da980997-0420-4527-946e-b66c49bf3d07">Wordle is a simple but addictive word puzzle. Each day, players have to guess a five-letter word answer in no more than six attempts. After each guess:</p>



<ul id="block-d0bea02d-4b9f-4991-b9db-3b35778ff3bf">
<li>Green letters are correct and in the right position.</li>



<li>Yellow letters are correct, but in the wrong position.</li>



<li>Gray letters are not in the word at all.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-5e597b53-af1c-4c06-a00c-6c5a4694e9e0">The goal is to guess the word in as few tries as possible. Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p id="block-cd7aaa7f-9491-4ad0-b994-72d0102c5bed">Wordle can only be played on the New York Times website. There is currently no app for you to download the official game.</p>



<h2 id="block-c6d4979d-f8eb-4473-a011-33019cb8da2c">Wordle Hints For Today, January 20, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-23b6a5a9-2c25-47c2-a0ea-e23a99c87abd">The Wordle answer for game #1676 is one of the harder puzzles. According to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/19/crosswords/wordle-review-1676.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NY Times Wordle review</a>, today’s answer takes an average of 6 of 6 guesses. That makes it even tougher than the 5.5-guess average from January 19.</p>



<h3 id="block-6777813b-1426-4c21-b507-3024542b4683">General Wordle Hints For January 20</h3>



<p id="block-b36e160d-6e5e-4dc8-aae9-5352ee681266">Without giving today’s Wordle answer completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul id="block-5c9f7d28-537c-424b-92c3-2a9906b57178">
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> This word is most often used as a <strong>verb</strong>, not a noun.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> It’s commonly used when talking about <strong>reputation or image</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong> The word suggests something being affected in a <strong>negative but not permanent</strong> way.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 4:</strong> You’ll often see it used in <strong>formal writing or headlines</strong> rather than casual speech.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-7fb794eb-0d89-4f8d-a7cf-082d0148b796">Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving <strong>Wordle #1676 for January 20, 2026.</strong></p>



<h3 id="block-73a1d2f5-fc2b-49b7-9c10-539e38a2b946">Starter Words For January 20, 2026</h3>



<p id="block-0853e28e-417e-4720-9526-9f2808a268be">If you want help getting started without having today’s Wordle answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you figure out some included letters. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul id="block-2ca8fb79-d1a4-43e4-8764-e4d238a3cc97">
<li>BULLY</li>



<li>FULLY</li>



<li>SILLY</li>



<li>LUSTY</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1676-on-january-20-2026">Today’s Wordle Answer For Game #1676 On January 20, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-4ee7c8b7-21fe-4613-8d40-bdf10f8881d0">If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answer to today’s Wordle below.</p>



<p id="block-b76151ef-98f3-4c71-a60b-a98dd0409997"><strong>Answer: </strong>SULLY</p>



<p id="block-0e0094cc-40a6-49a3-a98c-ee90172006ac">If you solved today’s Wordle without our answer, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="block-533370cc-a013-4a5a-896a-c5f325907fa7">What Does Today’s Wordle Answer Mean?</h2>



<p id="block-ba677ac6-ec30-46af-a15a-f4a6a01984f1">SULLY <a href="https://www.dictionary.com/browse/sully" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">is a verb</a> that means “to soil, stain, or tarnish”. In can also be used as a noun as “a stain”</p>







<h2 id="block-f2e30ac8-1612-450a-823c-335ce7bed157">Yesterday’s Wordle Answer</h2>



<p id="block-f109cc5e-d6d4-415d-8d6d-08f0f34fc10b">If you missed the previous game, here’s yesterday’s Wordle answer for <strong>Game #1675 on January 19, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-d4bfa5bc-7b25-45b4-b4ce-faa1410603ee"><strong>Answer:</strong> WAXEN</p>



<p id="block-284127ec-83a6-447c-acf6-16238986a1d4">While not always the case, looking at previous words can sometimes give you insight into common patterns or letter usage in Wordle puzzles.</p>



<h2 id="block-44882c9d-d6a6-4e4f-9b1a-8312ae0b3036">When Is The Next Wordle Game After #1676?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6">Wordle games are <strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before to give players a heads up. The game on <strong>January 21</strong> will be <strong>Wordle Game #1677.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-96ac6df0-5b63-4788-9eff-98ceece739ee">What Is Wordle?</h2>



<p id="block-cde2c274-bfd9-4d27-a0d9-3ebe6f1ff7f2">Wordle is a daily word puzzle created by Josh Wardle. Initially developed as a prototype in 2013, it wasn’t fully released until 2021. The game challenges players to guess a five-letter word in six tries or fewer, using hints from each attempt to narrow down the answer. Its straightforward concept, accessibility, and the thrill of solving a new puzzle each day helped it surge in popularity by late 2021. The success of Wordle inspired numerous spin-offs and social media challenges, leading to its acquisition by The New York Times in early 2022.</p>



<hr id="block-ef203a26-29c4-4ff2-9120-b9bbe59cd966">



<p id="block-9d1c4fad-eba9-422a-a628-5cb7b00aea3b">For even more Insider Gaming delivered straight to your inbox, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1676-hints-answer-january-20-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Release Date Made Official By Bungie]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-official-bungie/</link>
            <guid>1410100</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>After it was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-trailer-has-surfaced-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked online</a> over the weekend, Bungie has confirmed the release date of its upcoming extraction shooter Marathon.</p>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://x.com/marathonthegame/status/2013280290534244440" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">social media</a>, Bungie announced that Marathon will launch on March 5, 2026. In addition to that, they revealed pre-order details for players. </p>







<p>The game is available to pre-order on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. Should you decide to pre-purchase Marathon, you’ll get addition weapon cosmetics, an emblem, and background for the game. You’ll also get new rewards for Destiny 2.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Marathon | Pre-Order and Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PwRmLx1W_j0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-multiple-marathon-versions-to-pick-from">Multiple Marathon Versions To Pick From</h2>



<p>When Marathon launches, you have the option to purchase three different editions of the game. The Standard Edition comes with a copy of the game along with “all gameplay updates as the year progresses.” Should you pre-order the game, you’ll also receive:</p>



<ul>
<li>ZERO STEP 004 CE Tactical Sidearm Style</li>



<li>ZERO STEP RC Weapon Charm</li>



<li>ZERO STEP SHIFT Weapon Sticker</li>



<li>APOGEE INTERCEPT Background</li>



<li>APOGEE INTERCEPT Emblem</li>



<li>UESC Echo-type Shell Exotic Ghost (Destiny 2)</li>



<li>UESC Rover Exotic Ship (Destiny 2)</li>



<li>UESC Sprinter Exotic Sparrow (Destiny 2)</li>
</ul>







<p>A step above that is the Deluxe Edition. This version of the game includes:</p>



<ul>
<li>All Standard Edition content</li>



<li>1x Premium Rewards Pass Voucher</li>



<li>200 SILK Rewards Pass Tokens</li>



<li>Weapon Cosmetics:
<ul>
<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Misriah 2442 Pump Shotgun Style</li>



<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Overrun AR Style</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Runner Shell Cosmetics:
<ul>
<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Vandal Shell Style</li>



<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Destroyer Shell Style</li>



<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Assassin Shell Style</li>



<li>MIDNIGHT DECAY Thief Shell Style</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>Lastly, the Collector’s Edition comes with everything from the other two editions of Marathon along with  a 1/6-scale Thief Runner Shell statue, a collectible miniature WEAVEworm, an embroidered patch, postcards, and other digital rewards.</p>



<p>Are you going to pick up Marathon when it releases on March 5? Leave your thoughts down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the match types planned to come to WWE 2K26 when it launches in March. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-release-date-official-bungie/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>