<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 21:29:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Controller 2 Set To Enter Mass Production, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/steam-controller-2-set-to-enter-mass-production-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-controller-2-set-to-enter-mass-production-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1040025/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/steam-controller-2-set-to-enter-mass-production-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The next iteration of Valve’s Steam Controller appears set to enter mass production. According to a <a href="https://x.com/SadlyItsBradley/status/1858925211363553316" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">new claim from Valve insider</a> Brad Lynch, Steam Controller 2, codenamed “Ibex” is in deep development.</p>



<p>According to Lynch, Steam Controller 2 is “being tooled for a mass production” in factories and is in a “later [stage] of productization”.</p>



<p>In addition to the production news, Lynch says that the new controller from Valve will have symmetrical sticks and that it’s “not far off from Steam Deck input”.</p>



<h6 id="h-help-insider-gaming-take-our-2024-reader-survey">HELP INSIDER GAMING:&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/wvT7oBtvjZLVmrEv9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Take Our 2024 Reader Survey</a></h6>



<p>Aside from from the Steam Controller 2, Lynch touched on a controller codenamed “Roy” for Valve’s “Deckard” VR headset. Not only is that device also heading for mass production, but he says that it will have a directional pad, bumpers, grip buttons, triggers, ABXY buttons, and a system button. That’s lead to speculation that it will be able to work as a stand alone controller away from “Deckard”.</p>



<p>Lynch didn’t give a timeline on when players could expect to see or hear something official about either the Steam Controller 2, “Deckard”, or “Roy”.</p>



<p>Valve also hasn’t commented on the latest rumors or confirmed the existence of any of the devices.  </p>



<p>What do you think of a Steam Controller 2 heading to production? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/forums/tech.9/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read the latest rumors surrounding the PlayStation 6 and the GPU it’s expected to use. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s New in Starfield Update 1.14.74 (November 19)?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/whats-new-in-starfield-update-1-14-74-november-19/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what%E2%80%99s-new-in-starfield-update-1-14-74-november-19.1040022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/whats-new-in-starfield-update-1-14-74-november-19/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-69558">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Following recent news that, despite all the naysayers, Starfield is doing relatively well with more than <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-15-million-players-bethesda/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">15 million total players since launch</a>, Bethesda pushed out a brand-new update to the open-world exploration game. Starfield update 1.14.74, released on November 19, 2024, features a handful of bug fixes, performance improvements, and tweaks to Quests. It’s a relatively quick download, just over 1.2 GB on PC.</p>



<h2 id="h-starfield-update-1-14-74-full-patch-notes">Starfield Update 1.14.74 – Full Patch Notes</h2>



<p>Overall, the new update is small and straightforward. It features general performance and stability improvements that should make for a smoother experience for everyone, along with an uncapped frame rate option for Xbox Series X players, and console command fixes. Most importantly, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-start-shattered-space-starfield/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shattered Space</a> ownership on Steam is now resolved, so if you were struggling with the expansion appearing on your game and account, that should be fixed now.</p>



<h3 id="h-general">General</h3>



<ul>
<li>General performance and stability improvements.</li>



<li>The uncapped frame rate option is available again for Xbox Series X users.</li>



<li>The Message of the Day now displays more consistently on the Xbox.</li>



<li>Addressed an issue where some console commands did not disable certain achievements.</li>



<li>Shattered Space will now show ownership correctly for Steam users.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-features">Features</h3>



<ul>
<li>Creation Kit: Lipsync animation data generation is now available.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-gameplay">Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>The Annihilator Particle Beam damage-over-time effect no longer triggers companion reactions.</li>



<li>Resolved a Leadership skill issue that could cause companions to not speak up.</li>



<li>Improved function of the stealth bar while around crowd NPCs.</li>



<li>Addressed an issue where destroyed ships could load in without collision.</li>



<li>Addressed an issue where loading a save the relied on missing content could place the player in an undesirable location.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Roach will now accurately track the number of completed bounties.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Bounty targets will now appear in Akila, Gagarin, and Cydonia.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Fixed an issue where the player could receive additional credits by extorting the target and then killing them.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Bounty targets should now have a larger variety of appearances.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Bounty targets will now be removed after being dealt with and leaving the area.</li>



<li>Trackers Alliance – Extorting or bribing a bounty target is no longer a guaranteed success.</li>
</ul>



<h6 id="h-related-the-starfield-money-console-command-will-help-prep-you-for-shattered-space">Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-starfield-money-console-command-will-help-prep-you-for-shattered-space/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Starfield Money Console Command Will Help Prep You For Shattered Space</a></h6>



<h3 id="h-quests">Quests</h3>



<ul>
<li>The Starjacker – The correct quest objective will display when the player boards the Junker Watchdog.</li>



<li>Legacy of the Fang – Addressed an issue that could cause the key to no longer open the door if the player had left the area.</li>



<li>The Duel – If the player attacks Danika and gets arrested, they are now able to speak to her afterwards to complete the quest.</li>



<li>The Scaled Citadel – Anasko’s ID Key is now flagged as a quest item.</li>



<li>What Remains – Addressed an issue where having certain creations installed could make the hatch on The Oracle non-interactable.</li>



<li>What Remains – The Engineering Bay Access Card is now flagged as a quest item.</li>



<li>A House Divided – The doors in the Radiology center will stay unlocked during this quest if the player exits the area and returns.</li>



<li>A House Divided – The player can now obtain the keycard from Madri after the quest is completed.</li>



<li>Zealous Overreach – Fixed an issue that could occur if the Va’ruun Zealots at the exterior of Shadow Station Epsilon were killed before receiving the quest.</li>



<li>Zealous Overreach – Addressed an issue that could prevent the player from speaking to Razma or Viktor if the quest “Conflict in Conviction” is started at the same time.</li>



<li>Zealous Overreach – Vortex Phantoms will no longer spawn close enough to interrupt the negotiation scene.</li>
</ul>



<p>Are you <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games-like-starfield/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">done with Starfield or still exploring</a> the Settled Systems? Let us know in the comments below, or visit <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forum</a> to discuss the game with others!</p>



<hr>



<p>Hopefully, this new update resolved many of your woes, but if you’re still dealing with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-fix-starfield-stuttering-every-few-seconds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Starfield stuttering every few seconds</a>, we can hopefully help with that!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-score-point-blank-kills-in-bo6-zombies/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-score-point-blank-kills-in-bo6-zombies/">How to Score Point Blank Kills in BO6 Zombies</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Wondering how to get Point Blank Kills in Black Ops 6 Zombies? Here’s everything you need to know to complete the challenge.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rarest-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rarest-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/">Rarest Cards in Pokémon TCG Pocket</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokémon TCG Pocket has a monstrous amount of rare cards to pull, but only a handful of them are considered the best, and hardest, to pack.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/redragon-black-friday-deals-gaming-mice-keyboards/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/redragon-black-friday-deals-gaming-mice-keyboards/">Score Redragon Black Friday Deals on Gaming Mice, Keyboards, and More!</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Score big this holiday season with Redragon Black Friday deals on gaming mice, keyboards, headsets, speakers, and more!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-pokemon-tcg-pocket-on-pc/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-pokemon-tcg-pocket-on-pc/">How to play Pokémon TCG Pocket on PC</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The ability to play Pokémon TCG Pocket on PC is a game changer if you want to upgrade your experience to a bigger screen.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS6 Rumors Suggest Console Will Use AMD’s UDNA Architecture]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-rumors-suggest-console-will-use-amds-udna-architecture/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps6-rumors-suggest-console-will-use-amd%E2%80%99s-udna-architecture.1039986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-rumors-suggest-console-will-use-amds-udna-architecture/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The PlayStation 5 is four years old, and that means its time for rumors for the next-generation PlayStation 6 (PS6) to pick up more steam. According to a new rumor on a Chinese forum from <a href="https://www.chiphell.com/thread-2652187-1-1.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">known hardware leaker zhangzhonghao</a>, the PS6 will use AMD’s next-gen UDNA GPU architecture within the console.</p>



<p>It’s the same architecture AMD will use in its Radeon 9000 series GPUs starting in 2026. It was also reaffirmed that the console itself will utilize either a Zen4 or Zen5 CPU. The CPU decision, however, remains undecided, per the claim.</p>



<p>Rumors of the PS6 using AMD is nothing new. It was reported in September that the system would stick with AMD over Intel in order to preserve <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-6-will-have-amd-chip-with-backwards-compatibility-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">features such as backward compatibility</a>. Lastly, it was said that Sony’s PlayStation handheld, will also use AMD hardware. </p>



<h6 id="h-help-insider-gaming-take-our-2024-reader-survey">HELP INSIDER GAMING:&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/wvT7oBtvjZLVmrEv9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Take Our 2024 Reader Survey</a></h6>



<p>It’s important to keep in mind that none of this has been confirmed by Sony in any capacity as its far too early for the company to begin publicly commenting on its next system. Insider Gaming has also yet to independently verify the legitimacy of the rumor, so, please, take the information with a grain of salt.</p>



<p>As far as when to expect to see the PS6, the latest documents Insider Gaming has seen show a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-ps6-coming-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">back and forth on a potential release</a> year, though 2028 looks likely. There are also claims that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps6-2-socs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony has two SoCs</a> (Systems on a chip) in development for the next-gen console.</p>



<p>What do you think of the latest PS6 rumors circling? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/forums/gaming-leaks-and-rumors.15/">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our exclusive on what EA is doing to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-playtests/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">prevent another disastrous launch</a>&nbsp;for the next Battlefield game. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>