<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:46:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Announces SteamOS Is Available For Third-Party Devices]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valve-announces-steamos-is-available-for-third-party-devices/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-announces-steamos-is-available-for-third-party-devices.1076466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valve-announces-steamos-is-available-for-third-party-devices/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-82239">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Valve has announced that SteamOS is being made available and launched for third-party devices moving forward. The announcement comes alongside the <a href="https://news.lenovo.com/pressroom/press-releases/lenovo-legion-unleashes-next-gen-gaming-power-at-ces-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reveal of the Lenovo Legion Go S</a> at CES 2025.</p>



<p>It also comes just months after Valve <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valve-is-bringing-steamos-support-to-rival-handhelds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed that it was working</a> on bringing the operating system (OS) to other devices</p>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/593110/view/529834914570306831" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam’s website</a>, Valve says that the operating system was developed to “provide a seamless user experience optimized for gaming, while retaining access to the power and flexibility of a PC.” The OS isn’t available on other handheld devices yet, but Valve says the work being done for the Lenovo Legion Go S — which comes installed with SteamOS instead of Windows — will improve the operating system’s compatibility with other handheld PCs.</p>



<p>“Ahead of Legion Go S shipping, we will be shipping a beta of SteamOS which should improve the experience on other handhelds, and users can download and test this themselves,” Valve said. “And of course we’ll continue adding support and improving the experience with future releases.”</p>







<p>It’s unclear what other devices will be “powered by SteamOS” in the future, but it appears to be only a matter of time before they are announced. There’s also the recent rumors that Valve is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-pointing-to-a-new-steam-console-from-valve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working on bringing back Steam Machines</a>, a decade after they were first announced and released to consumers.</p>



<p>What do you think about Valve bringing SteamOS to other handheld PCs? Do you think it impacts the future of the Steam Deck in any way? Let us know down below, and join the discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">studio set to take over</a>&nbsp;former Private Division franchises and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest layoffs taking place</a> at Rocksteady. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-2025-new-agents-more-map-variety-ranked-protections/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-2025-new-agents-more-map-variety-ranked-protections/">VALORANT 2025 Season Will Include 2 New Agents, Map Variety, and Ranked Protections</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>VALORANT is fully embracing a new yearly seasonal model in 2025, and the first season is set to include a number of key improvements.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/">Rocksteady Suffers More Layoffs As Suicide Squad Support Winds Down</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>As support for Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League comes to an end, Rocksteady has suffered another round of layoffs.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/">VALORANT Ditches Episodes for Yearly Season Model</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>VALORANT will deliver a “perfectly curated season” of content each calendar year, and hopefully will provide some highly requested features.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/">Former Annapurna Staff To Take Over Private Division Franchises</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new report claims that former staff at Annapurna Interactive are set to lead a new company funded by the new owners of Private Division.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT 2025 Season Will Include 2 New Agents, Map Variety, and Ranked Protections]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-2025-new-agents-more-map-variety-ranked-protections/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-2025-season-will-include-2-new-agents-map-variety-and-ranked-protections.1076361/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-2025-new-agents-more-map-variety-ranked-protections/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Riot has confirmed that the VALORANT 2025 season, the first official “season” now that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the developers are pivoting away from episodes</a>, will be primarily focused on improvement. There will definitely be new content across the six acts planned for 2025, but the priority will be getting the the game into “its best shape ever,” according to the most recent dev diary.</p>



<p>What does this mean for VALORANT in 2025? It means balancing some of the most powerful and weak agents, improving the ranked experience, keeping the map rotation fresh, and saying hello to two new mystery agents.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-valorant-2025-agent-changes">VALORANT 2025 Agent Changes</h2>



<p>Agents continue to be the primary focus for VALORANT in 2025, as the unique cast of characters is what sets the game apart from other tactical shooters. After several balancing changes in 2024, more are set for 2025.</p>



<p>Iso, the recipient of a massive buff to his Double Tap shield in <a href="https://playvalorant.com/en-us/news/game-updates/valorant-patch-notes-811/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Patch 8.11</a>, will receive some “power budget redistribution.” The agent team for VALORANT was hesitant to commit to changes to Neon though. They will revisit her “if they need to” after her drastic but necessary <a href="https://playvalorant.com/en-us/news/game-updates/valorant-patch-notes-9-11/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Patch 9.11</a> nerfs.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="What’s New for Season 2025 // Dev Updates - VALORANT" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YpNsGFd74fk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The team did commit to improving two of the least popular and least powerful agents: Deadlock and Harbor. With Deadlock, the team says they are aiming to make Sound Sensors more valuable, and to give her more aggressive potential. With Harbor, they want to make him “more satisfying” to play as.</p>



<h2 id="h-ranked-and-map-pool-changes">Ranked and Map Pool Changes</h2>



<p>With six acts planned for the VALORANT 2025 season, Riot has committed to changing the active map pool each act. At the start of each act, Riot will rotate in two maps and swap two out, but have said the number “might change” throughout the year.</p>



<p>As for the VALORANT’s competitive mode, which is now the official entry point into the esports ecosystem, two crucial changes should make the climb easier. Players will now be granted a “rank shield” that protects them from dropping <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-valorant-ranks-how-to-get-radiant/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">between skill rank divisions</a> right away. This shield gives you one more opportunity to win before falling from Gold I to Silver III, for example. Finally, rank rating rollbacks (or refunds) will be added in 2025. If If a player is banned for cheating, you get refunded the RR you lost playing against them.</p>



<p>For more VALORANT coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorants-newest-agent-is-explosive-initiator-tejo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the full ability kit for the newest initiator agent, Tejo</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-ufc-5-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the&nbsp;new Xbox Game Pass titles</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rocksteady Suffers More Layoffs As Suicide Squad Support Winds Down]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down.1076292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-suffers-more-layoffs-as-suicide-squad-support-winds-down/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-82227">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Rocksteady has been hit by another round of layoffs. As support for Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-updates-will-end-with-season-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">comes to an end</a> with the final season, the studio has seen a number of employees let go across various departments.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-developer-rocksteady-hit-by-end-of-year-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a> was the first to report on the layoffs after “half a dozen staff” who were part of the layoffs confirmed to the outlet that they took place. According to the report, employees in QA, programming, and art have been let go.</p>



<p>An exact number impacted or when the layoffs actually happened is currently unknown. Insider Gaming has reached out to Warner Bros. Games and Rocksteady for comment on the layoffs. As of publishing, however, no response has been received.</p>







<p>The latest layoffs mark the second in a handful of months as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rocksteady-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">QA team saw staff reduced</a> by over 50% in September. Last May, during the company’s Q1 FY2025 earnings call, Warner Bros. revealed that Suicide Squad <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/suicide-squad-cost-warner-bros-200-million-in-revenue/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cost the company $200 million</a> in revenue due after a “disappointing” release. During its last earnings call, the company said that, moving forward, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-games-focusing-on-batman-mortal-kombat-and-hogwarts-legacy-moving-forward/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it’ll put more of a focus</a> on “strong” game franchises like Batman, Mortal Kombat, and Hogwarts Legacy.</p>



<p>What do you think of Rocksteady holding more layoffs? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">studio set to take over</a> former Private Division franchises. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-ditches-episodes-for-yearly-season-model/">VALORANT Ditches Episodes for Yearly Season Model</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>VALORANT will deliver a “perfectly curated season” of content each calendar year, and hopefully will provide some highly requested features.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/former-annapurna-staff-to-take-over-private-division-franchises/">Former Annapurna Staff To Take Over Private Division Franchises</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new report claims that former staff at Annapurna Interactive are set to lead a new company funded by the new owners of Private Division.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-devs-reveal-what-to-expect-from-season-1/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-devs-reveal-what-to-expect-from-season-1/">Marvel Rivals Devs Reveal What to Expect From Season 1</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The latest dev vision episode from Netease reveals what content we should expect from Marvel Rivals Season 1: Eternal Night Falls. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/6-games-leaving-xbox-on-january-15/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/6-games-leaving-xbox-on-january-15/">These 6 Games Are Leaving Xbox and PC Game Pass on January 15</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Xbox has announced that these 6 games will be leaving Xbox and PC Game Pass on January 15, 2025.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>