<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:33:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lionsgate Confirms AAA John Wick and SAW Games In Development]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lionsgate-confirms-john-wick-and-saw-games-development/</link>
            <guid>1395796</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>For years, fans of the high-octane gun-fu franchise, John Wick, have been crying out for a decent game tied to the series. The nature of the film franchise almost writes itself as a video game, but despite a couple of low-budget titles, nothing has really emerged in the space.</p>



<p>During a recent earnings call, Lionsgate Chairman Adam Fogelson confirmed that a ‘AAA John Wick game’ is in development and will be officially announced soon. He also mentioned that a new ‘SAW’ game is also incoming, the first since 2010’s SAW II: Flesh and Blood.</p>







<h2 id="h-john-wick-game-could-be-coming-soon">John Wick Game Could Be Coming Soon</h2>



<p>The recent earnings call at Lionsgate gave way to a solid revelation, and soon, we’ll have an official announcement of an all-new John Wick game <strong>and </strong>a SAW project. In a snippet pulled from the earnings call, Adam Fogelson, Chairman at Lionsgate, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Our AAA game opportunities and other gaming opportunities. around John Wick and Saw and some others that we’ll be announcing soon.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://tech4gamers.com/aaa-john-wick-game-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tech4Gamers</a> for the quote)</em></p>



<p>It was further mentioned that Lionsgate has acknowledged the ‘increased interest’ fans have in adaptations of the popular franchises under its belt, like <strong>John Wick</strong>.</p>



<p>What’s not clear is what a John Wick AAA game could look like. It’s up in the air, and fans are eagerly debating the possibilities, such as an extension of John Wick’s story, played out by Keanu Reeves, or a unique, original story that allows players to create their own diehard assassin character.</p>



<p>Being frank, it’s most likely the latter possibility, as this would allow the developers much more creative freedom, both in terms of the story and the setting.</p>



<p>Fans then set about pulling apart the rest of Lionsgate’s line-up, surmising what other IP could be yanked into the video game world. One concept saw The Hunger Games emerge as an all-new battle royale game or a dystopian, post-apocalyptic epic of sorts.</p>







<p>What do you expect from a John Wick game? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-rom-keys-leak-jailbreaking-concerns-claim/">PlayStation 5 ROM keys might have leaked</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lionsgate-confirms-john-wick-and-saw-games-development/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 ROM Keys Leak Raises Jailbreaking Concerns]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-rom-keys-leak-jailbreaking-concerns-claim/</link>
            <guid>1395730</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Recent claims have surfaced on social media suggesting that PlayStation 5’s ‘ROM keys’ have been obtained and leaked online. If the claims are accurate, it means that jailbreakers will now have a cakewalk of a time busting into the console’s operating systems. This has been reported as an ‘unpatchable issue’ that brings users one step closer to securing jailbroken PS5 consoles.</p>



<p>Later posts in the social space suggested that a new exploit surfaced tied to Star Wars Racer Revenge. The limited edition disc for the game is reportedly the trigger for the leak, but the technology behind it all is pretty complex.</p>







<h2 id="h-has-ps5-been-jailbroken">Has PS5 Been Jailbroken?</h2>



<p>On January 2, claims started surfacing online suggesting dire implications for Sony. It was said that PS5 ROM keys had been leaked online, presenting a major and irreversible security concern for the brand. As explained in an article penned by The Cybersec Guru:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>In the final hours of 2025, reports began flooding the internet that the&nbsp;<strong>PlayStation 5 ROM Keys</strong>—the deepest, most protected layer of the console’s security architecture—have been leaked.</p>



<p>This is not a kernel exploit that can be patched with a firmware update. This is the hardware root of trust. And it is out in the wild.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The leak has allegedly uncovered the BootROM code for the PlayStation 5, specifically the disc-based version of the console. As The Cybersec Guru <a href="https://thecybersecguru.com/news/ps5-rom-keys-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">explained</a>, ‘If you have the keys to the BootROM, you effectively own the hardware.’</p>



<p>On socials, some of the biggest names in the console modding and jailbreaking scene emerged to corroborate the leak. One user by the name of Gezine gave some technical context to the situation:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>mast1core based on disc game CUSA03474<br>This was the 12.00 dup exploit that was teased.</p><p>Will release code after polishing more.</p><p>Happy new year scene <a href="https://t.co/mskPXHQQ0b">pic.twitter.com/mskPXHQQ0b</a></p></div>— Gezine (@gezine_dev) <a href="https://twitter.com/gezine_dev/status/2006548152913215847?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 1, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>From what we know, the potential leak of the PS5 ROMs doesn’t mean that jailbroken consoles will start popping up online, as there are other security thresholds for jailbreakers to contend with, but this certainly is a foot in the door.</p>



<p>At the time of publishing, no publicly accessible repository appears to contain the leaked code or data, and neither Sony nor the PlayStation brand channels have addressed the claims.</p>







<p>Let us know what you think about this news on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-failed-secure-traction-fumbled-again/">Splitgate is failing again</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-rom-keys-leak-jailbreaking-concerns-claim/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate Has Fumbled Again and Failed to Secure Any Traction Following ‘Rebrand’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-failed-secure-traction-fumbled-again/</link>
            <guid>1395721</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Splitgate has had a rough couple of years. From the support ending on the more successful first title to the second game launching amid a wave of controversies, the problems for 1047 Games and their portal-toting shooter began very early on. Following a catastrophic downfall, the team ‘relaunched’ Splitgate 2 under a new identity, but that too has proven to be a failure.</p>



<p>What was once dubbed the game that would ‘make FPS great again’ has been reduced to a title on life support. Only a few hundred people are playing on some platforms, nobody is interested in watching the game on streaming sites, and the sentiments are lower than ever.</p>







<h2 id="h-splitgate-arena-reloaded-is-collapsing">Splitgate: Arena Reloaded is Collapsing</h2>



<p>On December 17, 1047 Games released Splitgate: Arena Reloaded, a rebrand of Splitgate 2, which was initially released in June to a disappointing reception and several damning scandals.</p>



<p>In July, Splitgate 2 was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-developers-say-its-going-back-to-beta/">pulled back to beta</a> as player counts imploded. The game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-analysis-condemns-tone-deaf-influencer-campaign/">creator-backed marketing</a> campaign was criticized, insanely <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-battle-royale-drops-fans-concerned-microtransactions/">expensive microtransactions</a> surfaced, and two rounds of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-developer-holds-another-round-of-layoffs/">layoffs were held</a> in just six weeks.</p>



<p>Following a series of tests, 1047 Games revealed that Splitgate 2 would be overhauled with a fresh identity, becoming known as Splitgate: Arena Reloaded. The relaunch of the game pulled in a few thousand players at best on some platforms, but any traction that was secured has already dissipated.</p>



<p>It’s impossible to know how well the game is doing on console platforms, but we can extrapolate based on the data we <strong>do </strong>have.</p>



<p>On Steam, Splitgate: Arena Reloaded hit 2,297 players on December 17 when the rebrand hit. At the time of publishing, only 390 players were exploring Splitgate: Arena Reloaded on Steam.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>While some of the more recent reviews stressed positivity about the changes applied to the game, the underlying concept is one of ‘too little, too late’.</p>



<p>Additionally, the game boasted a viewer count of just 134 users on Twitch at the time of writing. That’s a mighty comedown from the all-time high of 138,110 viewers. Put simply, nobody is interested in watching <strong>or </strong>playing Splitgate: Arena Reloaded.</p>







<p>Do you think Splitgate’s downfall was always inevitable, or do you still have hopes for the game? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-arc-raiders-player-count-debate/">debate between Battlefield 6 and ARC Raiders</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-failed-secure-traction-fumbled-again/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#936)—Clues and Answers for Friday, January 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-2-936/</link>
            <guid>1395718</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>How has your 2026 started? We’re only one day in, but hopefully things have kicked off how you wanted them to. There’s plenty of year ahead, but as always, it begins with you smashing another NYT Connections puzzle! Today, I’m here with the best NYT Connections hints and solutions you need to get your day started the right way.</p>



<p>Read on to find out today’s answers.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-january-2">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (January 2)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #936:</p>



<ul>
<li>HIVE</li>



<li>ROUTINE</li>



<li>RECORD</li>



<li>NUMBER</li>



<li>LOG</li>



<li>STANDARD</li>



<li>BIT</li>



<li>JOT</li>



<li>QUASH</li>



<li>BAR</li>



<li>NOTE</li>



<li>EEK</li>



<li>METRIC</li>



<li>GAG</li>



<li>ALE</li>



<li>EXAMPLE</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think of <strong>quick ways to capture information</strong>, whether you’re scribbling something down, keeping track of events, or making a brief reminder for later. Each word here is something you might <strong>produce</strong> when you’re trying to preserve a thought or detail.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – These are all words you’d use to describe a <strong>comic performer’s signature move</strong>, the little recurring bits that make their act recognizable. Whether it’s a short joke, a recurring segment, or a whole comedic persona, each term fits into the world of <strong>stage routines and comedic gimmicks</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>This set is all about <strong>measuring against a reference point</strong>. These words describe the things we use to judge quality, performance, or expectations — the <strong>yardsticks</strong> that define what’s typical, acceptable, or exemplary</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each of these looks strange at first glance, but imagine a <strong>common vegetable with its first letter chopped off</strong>. Once you mentally restore that missing initial, the original produce item becomes obvious.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, January 2:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-january-2-936">NYT Connections Answers for Today, January 2 (#936)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– JOT, LOG, NOTE, RECORD</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BIT, GAG, NUMBER, ROUTINE</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – BAR, EXAMPLE, METRIC, STANDARD</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – ALE, EEK, HIVE, QUASH</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">r</a></p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-2-936/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Year In Review: Forget GTA 6, 2026 is All About The Life-Sim Genre]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/year-in-review-forget-gta-6-2026-is-all-about-the-life-sim-genre/</link>
            <guid>1395505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s easy to look at 2026 as a year that will be dominated by the release of Grand Theft Auto 6, assuming there isn’t another delay from Rockstar, but while that stands as the biggest overall release of the year, 2026 itself could be defined by the life-sim genre.</p>



<p>Games like The Sims and Stardew Valley have achieved vast success over the years, with the genre now being extremely popular and attracting huge franchises into the scene, as seen with Disney Dreamlight Valley, but 2026 is going to be bigger than ever before.</p>



<p>Several big players are entering the scene with fresh games in the genre, the indie environment continues to grow, and fans are poised for news from arguably the biggest franchise in the entire genre.</p>



<h2 id="h-big-players-enter-the-scene">Big Players Enter The Scene</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Transforming the game. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>The mammoth year for life-sim gamers kicks off on January 15 with the release of the Nintendo Switch 2 edition of Animal Crossing: New Horizons, which adds new content for all players, regardless of system, alongside Switch 2 exclusive features like gamechat and multiplayer with up to 12 players.</p>



<p>Gamers will be hoping that this isn’t the only piece of big Animal Crossing news in 2026, with all eyes cast towards Nintendo for details on the next entry in the series following the launch of Switch 2, which could certainly come next year. Even if a release of a new Animal Crossing isn’t on the 2026 calendar, it’s still set to be a huge year on Nintendo.</p>



<p>In March, Pokémon enters the genre with the release of Pokopia, where players take control of a humanoid Ditto, bringing life back to a depleted region. Fans believe this is a post-apocalyptic version of Kanto, where players attract new Pokémon into the environment, learn new skills, and build a complete Pokémon village.</p>



<p>Pokémon’s entry into the genre makes a lot of sense, particularly with the franchise branching out into new experiences, and Pokopia could be one of the biggest hits of the year. However, The Pokémon Company isn’t the one big player set to make moves into the life-sim genre.</p>



<p>HoYoverse, the developers behind hit games including Genshin Impact, Zenless Zone Zero, and Honkai: Star Rail, is expected to launch Petit Planet in 2026, following the start of the closed beta in November 2025. While a precise release date has not been shared, it’s anticipated to land in the next 12 months, and, with the power of HoYoverse behind it, Petit Planet could be a huge hit.</p>



<h2 id="h-a-host-of-options">A Host of Options</h2>



<p>While the likes of Nintendo, Pokémon, and HoYoverse are set to make waves in the life-sim genre in 2026, they’re far from the only developers looking to make a splash, and there’s set to be an embarrassment of riches for those looking for their fix in the genre.</p>



<p>Starsand Island is due to release on multiple platforms on February 1, having raised over $300,000 in a Kickstarter campaign, presenting players with a new world to experience and various career paths to choose from, including an angler, explorer, farmer, or rancher. While the game is a new player on the scene, excitement levels are rising, and the success of games developed in China in recent years shows this isn’t a title to ignore.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Neverway, from Coldblood Inc, is also due to release in 2026, and has strong Stardew Valley aesthitics with the art style and lore, though there’s a fresh approach as the player-character, Fionna, becomes indebted to a dead god, becoming its immortal herald—which makes Tom Nook from Animal Crossing look extremely tame.</p>



<p>Both of those titles merely scratch the surface of what’s to come; however, with other releases to keep an eye on, including Moonlight Peaks, Sunkissed City, and Fields of Mistria, the latter of which has been in early access since 2024 and is poised for a full 1.0 release in 2026.</p>



<p>With so many titles to choose from in 2026, life-sim gamers will be spoilt for choice, so much so that the eventual release of GTA 6 could go unnoticed.</p>



<hr>



<p>What life-sim games are you most excited to see released in 2026? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/year-in-review-forget-gta-6-2026-is-all-about-the-life-sim-genre/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biggest Fortnite Collaborations We’d Love to See in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-fortnite-collaborations-wed-love-to-see-in-2026/</link>
            <guid>1395469</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fortnite is the undisputed king of collabs, regularly featuring huge crossovers with major franchises in the world of movies, TV, and gaming, but there’s still plenty of routes of collaborations to go down and skins that would be great additions in 2026.</p>



<p>From the world of movies to the major gaming franchises, Insider Gaming has selected the biggest Fortnite collaborations that would set 2026 alight.</p>







<h2 id="h-biggest-fortnite-collabs-we-d-love-to-see-in-2026">Biggest Fortnite Collabs We’d Love to See in 2026</h2>



<h3 id="h-avengers-doomsday">Avengers: Doomsday</h3>



<figure><figcaption>New era. Image via Marvel</figcaption></figure>



<p>Admittedly, this one is probably a guarantee for the back-end of next year, but Avengers: Doomsday is arguably the biggest movie release in decades, marking a huge shift in direction for the Marvel Cinematic Universe, and a Fortnite crossover in 2026 would be perfect.</p>



<p>Fortnite’s approach in Chapter 6 to deliver themed mini-seasons could be perfect for Avengers: Doomsday, which releases in December 2026, as Epic Games could introduce a Battleworld-themed map to star as the closing part of Chapter 7, featuring callbacks to various iconic moments and locations from MCU history.</p>



<p>There has already been a major Marvel collab with Doctor Doom as the main villain, however, so perhaps the best route for the collab would be to look back over MCU history, rather than solely tying into the film, but still having hints of what fans can expect from the huge movie.</p>



<h3 id="h-shrek">Shrek</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Swamp. Image via Dreamworks</figcaption></figure>



<p>Shrek returns to the big screens in 2025 with the release of Shrek 5, and it’s about time everyone’s favorite Ogre appeared in Fortnite, as it stands as one of the biggest animated movie franchises yet to be given an Epic Games’ makeover.</p>



<p>While skins and accessories would be a big hit, tying into the game directly and having a POI for Shrek’s swamp on the map would be excellent, especially if it came alongside the iconic voiceline of Shrek screaming ‘what are you doing in my swamp!?’ at any player who approaches.</p>



<p>The introduction of Sidekicks also opens the door for other characters like Donkey and the Gingerbread Man to feature, though I’d personally love to see Lord Farquad as a Sidekick, just for fun.</p>



<h3 id="h-toy-story">Toy Story</h3>



<figure><figcaption>You’ve got a friend in me. Image via Disney</figcaption></figure>



<p>Disney’s close relationship with Epic Games has brought a ton of major franchises and animated stars into Fortnite already but, so far, Toy Story hasn’t been touched, and 2026 is the perfect time to change that with yet another film in the franchise due to hit the big screens.</p>



<p>Toy Story is another great contender to feature in a larger collab with Fortnite in a full-island takeover, particularly if other Pixar titles are involved, but Disney, understandably, may be reluctant to allow Woody and Buzz Lightyear to run around with rifles, pistols, and other weapons.</p>



<p>Again, this is where Sidekicks could come in, as smaller versions of fan-favorite characters would be immensely popular, especially if they flopped to the floor when you stood still. Andy’s coming!</p>



<h3 id="h-pokemon">Pokémon</h3>



<figure><figcaption>The very best. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>We can dream, right? Nintendo is famously extremely protective of its IPs, and previous attempts to bring the likes of Samus from Metroid into Fortnite have failed due to Nintendo’s apparent desire to keep the franchise as platform-exclusive, but it’s Nintendo whoi really misses out from this.</p>



<p>If Nintendo was to relent and ease their restrictions, Pokémon would admittedly be much further down the list of obvious franchises to feature, as it’s highly unlikely we’d see Ash Ketchum running around with a rocket launcher anytime soon, but, again, this is where Sidekicks could come in.</p>



<p>Having popular Pokémon like Pikachu, Squirtle, Bulbasaur, and Charmander available as Sidekicks would be a huge boost, and, as the characters wouldn’t be directly involved in combat, it would save face for Nintendo.</p>



<h3 id="h-the-boys">The Boys</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Needed. Image via Amazon</figcaption></figure>



<p>Superhero collabs are a dime a dozen in Fortnite, with pretty much all of the biggest faces making appearances over the years, but, so far, The Boys is yet to star. With the final season of the popular series due to air in 2026, there’s no better time for the franchise to make a Fortnite debut.</p>



<p>Skins for the likes of Homelander, Starlight, Billy Butcher, Queen Maeve, and Hughie Campbell would definitely be big sellers in the Item Shop, and having Mythic weapons spawning on the map during a collab would be iconic, though I doubt there’s the potential of being able to pick up a baby and using it’s laser vision.</p>



<p>Regardless, it’s staggering that The Boys is yet to feature in Fortnite, and that needs to change in 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-super-mario">Super Mario</h3>



<figure><figcaption>It’s-a-me. Image via Universal</figcaption></figure>



<p>Ok, we’re back to the Nintendo problem again, and there would be a lot of logistics to sort out with a collab, but if Nintendo and Epic Games were to get on the same page, surely Super Mario would be near the top of the list.</p>



<p>There are some obvious issues surrounding the heights of characters like Mario and Luigi, but others, like Bowser, could instantly be made into a skin, and there’s a potential for the collab to include Mario-inspired skins for Fortnite characters, rather than direct copies. Princess Peach Hope anyone?</p>



<p>The potential in-game is also great, with yellow question mark blocks replacing chests, Goomba’s to stomp on to receive loot, and a Mario Kart POI would be iconic.</p>



<h3 id="h-wwe">WWE</h3>



<figure><figcaption>More needed. Image via Fortnite</figcaption></figure>



<p>WWE and Fortnite partnered for a small collab in 2025, bringing The Undertaker and Cody Rhodes into the game, but they were sub par. Frankly, how could you have Cody’s ‘WOAH’ Emote without the actual song lyrics? Rather than a brief collab, Fortnite should go all in.</p>



<p>The Fortnite x WWE roster includes the aforementioned duo along with The Rock, John Cena, Bianca Belair, and Becky Lynch, but there’s much, much more that could be done. Imagine the potential, with the likes of Rey Mysterio with various mask styles, Roman Reigns’ imposing figure, and R-Truth being hilarious.</p>



<p>If WWE and Fortnite were to really put their heads together, there are endless opportunities, even going as far as a full-on Fortnite Festival collab with a heap of entrance music made available.</p>



<h3 id="h-minecraft">Minecraft</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Block party. Image via Mojang Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>It does feel like that if we haven’t had a Minecraft collab in Fortnite yet, we’re never going to get one, particularly as LEGO Fortnite made the games a direct competitor, and the obvious opportunity for a collab with the release of the Minecraft movie in 2025 has passed.</p>



<p>Still, there are endless opportunities, and the chance for both iconic franchises to benefit. Skins for Minecraft characters would be a big win, though I can’t shake the feeling of how good a full-on Minecraft-inspired Battle Royale island would look like, featuring all the beloved biomes.</p>



<p>The likelihood of a Minecraft collab in Fortnite does seem extremely slim, but we’ll hold out hope anyway.</p>







<hr>



<p>What collabs would you like to see in Fortnite in 2026? Share your ideas in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaks-suggest-overwatch-crossover-could-happen/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaks suggesting an Overwatch crossover could happen</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaks-suggest-overwatch-crossover-could-happen/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get Lightning Ink in LEGO Fortnite</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-fortnite-collaborations-wed-love-to-see-in-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>