<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:15:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima Is Not Attending GDC 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-is-not-attending-gdc-2026/</link>
            <guid>1428055</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new announcement from Kojima Productions reveals that Hideo Kojima will not be attending the upcoming GDC Festival of Gaming event. </p>



<p>Hideo Kojima has two notable games in the pipeline at the moment: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/physint-new-update-kojima-playstation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Physint</a>, the title that will blur the lines between traditional game development and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-doesnt-know-if-od-will-work-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OD</a>, a horror title he is making with Xbox Game Studios and co-written by Jordan Peele. Many fans have been waiting to hear about both of these games from the man himself. </p>







<h2 id="h-kojima-productions-will-still-attend-gdc-2026">Kojima Productions Will Still Attend GDC 2026</h2>



<p>Kojima Productions has announced via a new post on <a href="https://x.com/KojiPro2015_EN/status/2019682481327239619" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) that Hideo Kojima will not be attending GDC 2026. The company stated, “We regret to inform you that Hideo Kojima will no longer be able to attend this year’s GDC Festival of Gaming.” Despite his absence, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/kojima-productions/" id="123">Kojima Productions</a> will still be present at the event, with members of the team scheduled to present throughout the week. Kojima has not shared any reasons for his absence.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Dear Porters and GDC Attendees</p><p>We regret to inform you that Hideo Kojima will no longer be able to attend this year’s GDC Festival of Gaming.<br>We understand that this will be disappointing for fans and attendees who were looking forward to hearing him speak, and we want to offer…</p></div>— KOJIMA PRODUCTIONS (Eng) (@KojiPro2015_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/KojiPro2015_EN/status/2019682481327239619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 6, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>The GDC Festival of Gaming 2026 is set to take place from March 9 to 13 at the Moscone Center in San Francisco, California. This conference focuses on the B2B games industry and will feature professionals from publishing, marketing, and investment sectors. This year, it will host over 1,000 speakers, including developers from notable companies such as Zynga, Obsidian Entertainment, DICE, Ubisoft, and more.</p>







<p>In other news, ASUS ROG recently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/asus-rog-announces-kojima-themed-gaming-laptop/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unveiled a new collaboration</a> with Kojima Productions. Additionally, Kojima has spoken about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-wouldnt-be-in-the-industry-without-super-mario-bros/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the connection he shares with Super Mario Bros</a>. What are your thoughts on Hideo Kojima not attending GDC 2026? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-switch-2-port-might-never-release-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Starfield Switch 2 port reportedly being delayed and the possibility it will never release</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hideo-kojima-is-not-attending-gdc-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Switch 2 Port Might Never Release, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-switch-2-port-might-never-release-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1427998</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to a new claim, Starfield’s Switch 2 port appears to be delayed and might never see the light of day. </p>



<p>A Starfield PlayStation 5 and Switch 2 port has been rumoured for a long time, but we have yet to hear any official details about it. This week, we have already heard a claim about Bethesda <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-playstatiion-5-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">planning an April 2026 release</a> for Starfield on PlayStation 5. We have now received claims about the Switch 2 Port as well. </p>







<h2 id="h-starfield-switch-2-port-reportedly-pushed-out">Starfield Switch 2 Port Reportedly ‘Pushed Out’ </h2>



<p>The claim that Starfield’s Switch 2 has a chance of never releasing comes from Shinobi602’s recent comments on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/ppe-pl-starfield-is-coming-to-ps5-on-april-7th.1426351/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ResetEra</a>. When asked whether the Switch 2 port will release at the same time as the PS5, Shinobi602 stated, “That’s been pushed out. And might not even come out at all.” When asked whether the delay was to target holiday sales, the insider replied, “They’re having problems with it, nothing to do with holidays or anything.” </p>



<p>The Starfield Switch 2 and PS5 ports are expected to release with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-2-0-could-be-real-after-all/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2.0 update</a> for the title, which will bring significant changes to some mechanics, help reduce load times, and be optimised for lower-power devices like handhelds. However, if the Switch 2 version is experiencing issues, the latter half of the 2.0 update might take longer than expected. Readers should take all the information with a grain of salt. </p>







<p>In other news, Starfield co-lead designer recently reflected on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-co-lead-designer-reflects-on-games-shortcomings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s shortcomings</a>.&nbsp;Additionally, the words ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/terran-armada-bethesda-starfield-anniversary-post/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Terran Armada</a>‘ were teased in an anniversary post. What are your thoughts on Starfield’s Switch 2 port being delayed and the possibility of it never releasing? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-super-bowl-commercial-leaks-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon’s Super Bowl LX commercial leaking early</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-switch-2-port-might-never-release-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Super Bowl Commercial Leaks Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-super-bowl-commercial-leaks-online/</link>
            <guid>1427968</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Pokémon commercial that was supposed to play at Super Bowl LX on Sunday has already leaked online, featuring a star-studded cast. </p>



<p>Pokémon is one of the franchises that gets leaked on all fronts. <span>We have seen the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-pokemon-company-coo-calls-for-pokemon-leaks-to-be-removed/" target="_blank">mainline games leaking</a></span>&nbsp;ahead of announcement, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-a4a-set-secluded-springs-leaks-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TCG Pocket cards</a>, packs, and so much more. Now, something really unexpected has happened: even their Super Bowl commercial leaked a few days earlier than planned. </p>



<h2 id="h-pokemon-super-bowl-commercial-features-lady-gaga-charles-leclerc-and-young-miko">Pokémon Super Bowl Commercial Features Lady Gaga, Charles Leclerc, and Young Miko</h2>



<p>Only a small clip of the Pokémon Super Bowl Commercial, posted by CentroLeaks on <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/2019650640088297854" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), has surfaced online, but it provides plenty of new information. The video features American singer, songwriter, and actress Lady Gaga, Puerto Rican rapper, singer, and songwriter Young Miko, and Formula 1 driver Charles Leclerc. All 3 personalities seem to be talking about their favourite Pokémon and what they like about it, but it could be something else. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Young Miko is first shown with a Gengar, with the words “He’s mischievous, that’s sort of his love language”. Then we see Charles Leclerc with a Growlithe, uttering the phrase “his loyalty, his speed.” We also see Lady Gaga with a Jigglypuff, but as this is just a clip, her statement wasn’t revealed. When asked whether the commercial was about a “specific game”, CentroLeaks responded, “It doesn’t promote a specific game…”</p>



<p>In other news, A Pokémon mod was recently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-is-getting-a-pokemon-mod/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed for Red Dead Redemption 2</a>. Additionally, here’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-day-2026-pokemon-presents/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what you need to know</a> about Pokémon Day and Pokémon Presents rumours. What are your thoughts on the Pokémon Super Bowl Commercial leaking early? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-enhanced-edition-still-coming-this-year-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Red Dead Redemption 2’s Enhanced Edition still releasing “this year”</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-super-bowl-commercial-leaks-online/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>