<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:24:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War: Sons of Sparta Roguelike Mode Can Be Unlocked Early]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-roguelike-mode-can-be-unlocked-early/</link>
            <guid>1447339</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Santa Monica has provided a code that players can use to access God of War: Sons of Sparta’s roguelike mode, The Pit of Agonies, early. </p>



<p>Santa Monica <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-son-of-sparta-shadow-drops-today/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shadow-dropped</a> God of War: Sons of Sparta during the latest Sony State of Play event, and fans have fun in the 2D metroidvania adventure ever since then. The title has always had the Pit of Agonies roguelike mode, but players had to finish the game to access it; now, they can do it earlier. </p>







<h2 id="h-god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-the-pit-unlock-code">God of War: Sons of Sparta The Pit Unlock Code</h2>



<p>As revealed in the new blog post, the only way previously to unlock God of War: Sons of Sparta’s Pit of Agonies roguelike mode was to beat the story. However, now players can unlock it early by entering a code in the starting menu. The code is a series of inputs on your DualSense controller that you can check out below: </p>



<p><strong>Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right, L1, R1, Touchpad</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="God of War Sons of Sparta - The Pit | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5oqO5WuxoVE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>For those unaware about the Pit, it is a separate rougelike mode where players battle different enemies to access new reward pools. The game mode can be played solo or with another player through local co-op as Kratos and Deimos take on this challenge. </p>



<p>The game mode also features a difficulty modifier called Agony, which can be chosen at the start of a run. This introduces variety to gameplay and changes how players approach the game. For example, “the Agony of Torment will manifest healing vessels that must be destroyed to prevent enemies from regenerating health, while the Agony of Calamity will cause defeated enemies to burst into a fiery explosion.” </p>



<p>After finishing each run in God of War: Sons of Sparta’s The Pit mode, players will be rewarded with a Symbol of Suffering for their chosen Agonies. When players hit thresholds of Symbols, they unlock new agones, and completion provides them with Ashes of Agony, which allows them to get permanent upgrades that last between attempts.</p>







<p>In other news, a God of War Ragnarok dataminer has seemingly <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-dataminer-seemingly-finds-link-to-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">found the link to the next game</a> with references to Athena and Egypt. Additionally, the upcoming remake trilogy features a new ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-trilogy-remake-features-new-fighting-system/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fighting system</a>.’ What are your thoughts on the devs of God of War: Sons of Sparta providing a code to unlock the Pit roguelike mode early?&nbsp;Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-overtakes-arc-raiders-in-steam-top-sellers-ahead-of-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon surpassing ARC Raiders in Steam Top Sellers</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-roguelike-mode-can-be-unlocked-early/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Overtakes ARC Raiders in Steam Top Sellers Ahead of Release]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-overtakes-arc-raiders-in-steam-top-sellers-ahead-of-release/</link>
            <guid>1447276</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Just over a week ahead of its release, Marathon is already climbing the Steam Top Seller charts, surpassing the likes of ARC Raiders. </p>



<p>Bungie’s new extraction shooter, Marathon, is all set to release on March 5, 2026, for all platforms. A week before the release, the developers are hosting a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-server-slam-test-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">server slam test</a> this weekend for players to try out the game one last time before the final release. However, the game is now already climbing the Steam Charts. </p>







<h2 id="h-marathon-ranks-third-in-steam-top-sellers-list">Marathon Ranks Third in Steam Top Sellers List</h2>



<p>At the time of writing, Marathon has climbed the Steam Top Sellers list to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/topselling/US" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">third rank in the United States</a>, and to the sixth rank in the United Kingdom. The title has managed to surpass another highly popular title in the extraction shooter genre, ARC Raiders, which currently sits in fifth position in the US. It is worth noting that Embark Studios’ extraction adventure was released almost 3 months ago. </p>



<p>Marathon is also ranking higher than other popular multiplayer titles, including Hellduvers 2, Marvel Rivals, Apex Legends, and more. The only games that are ranking higher than Bungie’s upcoming extraction shooter are Resident Evil Requiem (which releases tomorrow) and Counter-Strike 2. </p>



<p>The game’s title reaching number 3 on the Steam top sellers list speaks volumes about how the developers have successfully changed the public’s perception since its reveal. Bungie faced several challenges before the release, including the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-art-director-joseph-cross-bungie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">departure of top executives</a> and issues related to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plagiarism</a>. However, they have clearly managed to overcome these obstacles.</p>







<p>In other news, here are Bungie’s plans to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bungie-outlines-plans-to-counter-cheaters-in-marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">counter cheaters</a> in Marathon. Additionally, here’s a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-runner-shell-in-marathon-all-abilities-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">comprehensive guide</a> on all seven Runner Shells in the game. What are your thoughts on Marathon surpassing ARC Raiders in the Steam top sellers list? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;Windr<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windrose-release-date-will-be-announced-when-devs-are-confident-enough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ose developers announcing their release date when they feel ‘confident enough’</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>. </p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-overtakes-arc-raiders-in-steam-top-sellers-ahead-of-release/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>