<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 20:35:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BREAKING: Warner Bros. Games Cancels Wonder Woman, Shuts Down Multiple Studios]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/breaking-warner-bros-games-cancels-wonder-woman-shuts-down-multiple-studios/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/breaking-warner-bros-games-cancels-wonder-woman-shuts-down-multiple-studios.1118736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/breaking-warner-bros-games-cancels-wonder-woman-shuts-down-multiple-studios/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Warner Bros. Games has canceled its Wonder Woman game and shut down multiple studios. Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier broke the news on Tuesday afternoon that, in addition to the game, Monolith Productions, Player First Games, and WB San Diego are all being closed.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-25/warner-bros-shuts-three-video-game-studios-in-restructuring?srnd=undefined&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report from Schreier</a> states that the cuts “reflect a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-games-focusing-on-batman-mortal-kombat-and-hogwarts-legacy-moving-forward/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">refocusing of the games division</a> on major franchises such as Harry Potter,&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat</em>,&nbsp;<em>Game of Thrones</em>&nbsp;and DC Comics, primarily Batman.”</p>



<p>In an internal memo obtained by Schreier, Warner Bros.  head of games and streaming JB Perrette said that “too many” recent releases have “really missed the mark”.</p>



<p>“We need to make some substantial changes to our portfolio/team structure if we are to commit the necessary resources to get back to a ‘fewer but bigger franchises’ strategy,” he said.</p>



<p>In addition, Warner Bros. Games gave a statement to <a href="https://kotaku.com/monolith-productions-wonder-woman-multiversus-cancel-wb-1851766400" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kotaku</a>. Insider Gaming also received the same statement. Rather than cut it up, you can read it in full below:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><em>We have had to make some very difficult decisions to structure our development studios and investments around building the best games possible with our key franchises -– Harry Potter, Mortal Kombat, DC and Game of Thrones. After careful consideration, we are closing three of our development studios – Monolith Productions, Player First Games and Warner Bros. Games San Diego. This is a strategic change in direction and not a reflection of these teams or the talent that consists within them.</em></p>



<p><em>The development of Monolith’s Wonder Woman videogame will not move forward. Our hope was to give players and fans the highest quality experience possible for the iconic character, and unfortunately this is no longer possible within our strategic priorities. This is another tough decision, as we recognize Monolith’s storied history of delivering epic fan experiences through amazing games. We greatly admire the passion of the three teams and thank every employee for their contributions.</em></p>



<p><em>As difficult as today is, we remain focused on and excited about getting back to producing high-quality games for our passionate fans and developed by our world class studios and getting our Games business back to profitability and growth in 2025 and beyond.</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Wonder Woman was first announced at The Game Awards 2021, and was being developed by Monolith Productions. The game was set to feature the Nemesis system made popular by its Middle-earth games. Since its reveal announcement, news surrounding Wonder Woman had been scarce with it reported that the game had been completely rebooted sometime in 2024.</p>



<p>Monolith was formed in 1994 before becoming a subsidiary of Warner Bros. Games in 2004.</p>



<p>The closing of Player First Games comes after its debut game MultiVersus was canceled with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-is-officially-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shutdown happening in May</a>. Warner Bros. Games <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-games-acquires-multiversus-developer-player-first-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">acquired the studio</a> in July 2024. Lastly, WB San Diego was founded in 2019 and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/warner-bros-opens-new-mobile-studio-in-san-diego" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">focused primarily</a> on mobile and free-to-play games.</p>



<p>The news of the cancelation and closures also comes just weeks after it was announced that current Warner Bros. Interactive president David Haddad <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-david-haddad/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was leaving the company</a> this spring. His departure comes after 12 years in his division.</p>



<p>As of writing, there’s been no public statement from Warner Bros. Games. It’s also unclear if anyone from the closing studios will be moved, or if everyone will be let go. Insider Gaming has reached out to Warner Bros. Games for comment.</p>



<p>What do you think of Wonder Woman being canceled and Warner Bros. Games closing three studios? Let us know down below and over in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1698/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fable-delayed-into-2026-by-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox delaying Fable</a> out of 2025 and read&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-releases-statement-on-assassins-creed-shadows-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft’s response</a>&nbsp;to Assassin’s Creed Shadows getting in the hands of players early. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>