<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 13:37:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20 New Concept Arts of Battlefield 6 Leak Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-concept-art-leak/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/20-new-concept-arts-of-battlefield-6-leak-online.1148694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-concept-art-leak/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>20 new concept art images for Battlefield 6 have leaked online following a slew of people datamining the game.</p>



<p>The concept arts where uploaded to the 1|BF telegram channel and made their way to the Battlefield Reddit. You can see all of the images below:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>As pointed out by many of the users in the comments, the concept arts give off a very “gritty” vibe, something that players believe Battlefield 2042 failed to capture.</p>



<p>It appears that the leaks originated from datamining the game from the Battlefield Labs playtests, which started earlier this month for the first time.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-leaks-reveal-battlefield-4-vibe/">Images and videos of the next Battlefield game</a> have also been uploaded on masse and EA has been trying to DMCA the content as fast as possible. However, if you look on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/battlefield" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Battlefield reddit</a> or if you’re in a discord server, you’re almost certainly guaranteed to still find them. </p>



<p>Battlefield 6 (or whatever its called) is scheduled to release between April 1st 2025 – March 31st 2026, with most company’s waiting on the highly anticipated <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/if-gta-6-delayed-tank-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 to make a decision on when to release</a>.</p>



<p>In February 2024, Insider Gaming exclusively reported that the next Battlefield game is also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2025-battle-royale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scheduled to have a free-to-play Battle Royale component</a> in development by Ripple Effect. At the time of writing, EA is yet to make an announcement, but Insider Gaming understands that its still the plan to release.</p>



<p>According to sources, EA has “learned their lesson” when it comes to such an experience and the company wants to replicate the success of Call of Duty and Warzone, which proved to be tremendously successful. </p>



<p>What do you think of the Battlefield 6 concept images? Will you be picking up the game? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our latest exclusive on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current plans regarding the upcoming launch</a>&nbsp;of the Nintendo Switch 2. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Images From Respawn & Bit Reactor’s Star Wars Turn-Based Tactics Game Have Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/images-from-respawn-bit-reactors-star-wars-turn-based-tactics-game-have-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/images-from-respawn-bit-reactor%E2%80%99s-star-wars-turn-based-tactics-game-have-leaked.1148568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/images-from-respawn-bit-reactors-star-wars-turn-based-tactics-game-have-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ahead of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-bit-reactor/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the game’s official unveiling at the upcoming Star Wars Celebration in April</a>, images from the the turn-based tactics game from Respawn Entertainment and Bit Reactor have appeared online. The XCOM influences are abundant, which is unsurprising given <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/strategy/bitreactor-has-a-star-wars-tactical-strategy-game-in-the-works-15-xcom-veterans-on-its-team-and-an-ambitious-vision-for-the-future-of-the-genre/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the number of XCOM veterans</a> at Bit Reactor.</p>







<p>The images were first <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/respawn-bit-reactors-star-wars-turn-based-tactics-game-leaked" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">discovered by gaming news outlet MP1st,</a> who found the images within a Bit Reactor artist’s portfolio. The gameplay shown is reportedly dated to mid-2023, when the game went by the internal code name Bruno.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The screenshots show gameplay very reminiscent of the tactical, turn-based squad combat genre that XCOM: Enemy Unknown and XCOM 2 revitalized in the 2010s. In this kind of game, the player controls a squad of characters in turn-based combat, where each character has a limited number of actions and moves they can make. Even the iconic Mario franchise dipped its toes into the turn-based tactics genre with Mario + Rabbids: Kingdom Battle and Mario + Rabbids: Sparks of Hope.</p>



<p>The images of gameplay show the player controlling a Mandalorian character and targeting a Republic clone trooper, with a “95% hit chance” window above the enemy trooper. The window at the bottom of the screen shows a number of other combat actions the player could take, including the use of a thermal detonator (the Star Wars equivalent of a powerful grenade). Another images shows players using an ability taken straight from XCOM: overwatch. When a player activates overwatch on their turn, they wait for an enemy to move into their line of sight and fire automatically. An animated image also shows a makeshift headquarters, where the player can interact with an Armory, Holotable, Special Ops, or Black Market.</p>



<p>Respawn has been collaborating with Bit Reactor on the Star Wars tactical game project. The developers of the critically acclaimed Jedi series were previously working on a Star Wars shooter about a Mandalorian bounty hunter, before that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-mandalorian-game-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">project was canceled in February 2024</a>. </p>



<p>How excited are you for a turn-based-tactics Star Wars game? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our latest exclusive on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current plans regarding the upcoming launch</a>&nbsp;of the Nintendo Switch 2. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>