<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:49:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Little Nightmares 3 on PS4 or Xbox One? All Platforms, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-ps4-xbox-one-all-platforms/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-little-nightmares-3-on-ps4-or-xbox-one-all-platforms-explained.1321681/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>You only have to look at the previous platforms the Little Nightmares franchise has appeared on to see how inclusive the series is. As time moves on, so do business decisions. We’re seeing if Little Nightmares 3 is available on PS4, Xbox One, as well as current-gen consoles, and PC.</p>



<p>We remember the PS4 and Xbox One era like it was yesterday. It was a better time in many ways, with regular exclusive releases, brands genuinely competing to be the best, and before game and console price increases became the norm. Titles releasing on old-gen hardware—like the PS4 and Xbox One—are becoming more antiquated by the second, which brings us to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a>.</p>



<p>You’re here to see if Little Nightmares 3 is on PS4 and Xbox One—as well as other platforms—and we have the answer you seek.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-little-nightmares-3-on-xbox-one-or-ps4">Can You Play Little Nightmares 3 on Xbox One or PS4?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>This one certainly isn’t floating away from anyone. Credit to Supermassive Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Little Nightmares 3 is available to buy digitally and physically on both PlayStation 4 and Xbox One consoles.</strong></p>



<p>The love for old-gen continues with <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a>. It’s hard to believe that the PS5 and Xbox Series X|S came out five years ago. The PS4 and Xbox One generation feels like a lifetime ago. As such, many companies are foregoing old-gen development as it costs too much money, and the de-optimization required can be time-consuming.</p>



<p>We’d argue it’s easier for a title like Little Nightmares 3 to make this transition. Not to disrespect its graphics, it still clearly boasts a premium, high-quality polish—but not having to generate a large open-world should make development easier.</p>



<p>You only have to look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-game-size-pre-load-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s file size</a> to see this. With the Little Nightmares franchise already past the 20 million mark in lifetime sales, having PS4 and Xbox One versions will help bolster this number. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-little-nightmares-3-platforms-explained">All Little Nightmares 3 Platforms, Explained</h2>



<p><strong>You can buy and play Little Nightmares 3 on the PlayStation 4, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Series X|S, Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2, and PC.</strong></p>



<p>Short of a mobile port, or even VR, this is as complete as a release gets in 2025! PlayStation, Xbox, Nintendo, and PC owners can all procure and play! Its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-much-does-little-nightmares-3-cost-price-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price</a> is slightly greater than recent games, but it’s still a fair price for a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-little-nightmares-3-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game of its length</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>You certainly aren’t starved of options when it comes to buying Little Nightmares 3, then. With even more content on the way—thanks to previously announced <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-chapters-dlc-guide-secrets-of-the-spiral-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DLC chapters</a>—this is as good a time as ever to jump on the LN3 bandwagon. If you do, tell us through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more on the game, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-little-nightmares-3-connected-to-1-and-2-do-you-need-to-play-little-nightmares-1-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether Little Nightmares 3 is connected to the first two games</a>, and where to find <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/chapter-1-dolls-little-nightmares-3-necropolis-doll-locations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Necropolis Chapter 1 Doll locations</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-candy-factory-chapter-2-dolls-little-nightmares-3-locations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Candy Factory Chapter 2 Dolls locations</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-ps4-xbox-one-all-platforms/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Little Nightmares 3 Connected To 1 And 2? Do You Need To Play Little Nightmares 1 + 2 First?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/is-little-nightmares-3-connected-to-1-and-2-do-you-need-to-play-little-nightmares-1-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-little-nightmares-3-connected-to-1-and-2-do-you-need-to-play-little-nightmares-1-2-first.1321654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Little Nightmares 3 offers a new world with new characters. As this is the third game in the series, onlookers finally peeking into the franchise are curious as to whether this is a direct sequel, if the worlds are reconnected, and also if you need to play either of the first two games before hopping into Little Nightmares 3 for the first time.</p>



<p>This might surprise you, but the Little Nightmares franchise has sold over 20 million units worldwide! This is a phenomenal achievement for an indie title. However, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-little-nightmares-3-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3</a> is moving closer to AA territory with the introduction of Supermassive Games—a renowned horror expert.</p>



<p>But today, we’re seeing if there’s a disconnect between Little Nightmares 3 and the titles that came before it, and tell you everything you need to know if you’re on the fence about buying.</p>



<h2 id="h-do-you-need-to-play-little-nightmares-1-or-2-before-playing-little-nightmares-3">Do You Need To Play Little Nightmares 1 or 2 Before Playing Little Nightmares 3?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A lot to explore, but you’re not Alone. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You do not need to play Little Nightmares 1 or Little Nightmares 2 before playing Little Nightmares 3, as this is a new adventure independent of the first two games.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/little-nightmares/little-nightmares-iii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Little Nightmares 3</a> features two brand-new characters—Low and Alone. The side-scrolling puzzle-platformer also takes place in a fresh location—The Nowhere. None of these properties has featured in previous Little Nightmares games. </p>



<p>So if you’re worried about missing out on crucial story lore or not understanding the game due to missing a piece of the puzzle, we can assure you that everything is learned and uncovered as you play.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-little-nightmares-3-connected-to-the-first-two-games">Is Little Nightmares 3 Connected To The First Two Games?</h2>



<p><strong>The short is no, we don’t think Little Nightmares 3 is directly connected to either of the first two games.</strong></p>



<p>At best, there’s a loose sense that Low and Alone share the same world, although it’s not directly implied. Whereas Little Nightmares 1 and 2 are more overt, as Six—the main character in Little Nightmares 1—also appears alongside Mono in Little Nightmares 2.</p>



<p>The second game is a prequel to the first, which is why they tie together so nicely and fittingly. But Little Nightmare 2 is its own entity. Everything about it is fresh, and we think it symbolizes the new beginning as the series’ development shifts away from Tarsier Games to Supermassive Games.</p>



<p>There could be some subtle clues we’ve missed throughout our playthrough—which we discussed in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-review-a-familiar-dream-but-one-you-shouldnt-sleep-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Nightmares 3 review</a>—otherwise, you should be fine if this is your first LN experience!</p>



<hr>



<p>To recap, you don’t need to play either of the first two games before playing Little Nightmares 3. The world may be faintly connected, but this is a new adventure, and a new story. Let us know how you get on with Little Nightmares 3 via the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>We have much more Little Nightmares 3 content to check out: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/chapter-1-dolls-little-nightmares-3-necropolis-doll-locations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Necropolis Chapter 1 Doll locations</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-candy-factory-chapter-2-dolls-little-nightmares-3-locations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Candy Factory Chapter 2 Dolls locations</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-to-beat-little-nightmares-3-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How Long to Beat Little Nightmares 3</a>, and the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/little-nightmares-3-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trophy list</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/is-little-nightmares-3-connected-to-1-and-2-do-you-need-to-play-little-nightmares-1-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Studios 17-Year Veteran Leaves Company With Mysterious Warning]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-studios-veteran-leaves-company-with-warning/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-studios-17-year-veteran-leaves-company-with-mysterious-warning.1321579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Glenn Israel, a veteran of Halo Studios (previously 343 Industries) with more than 17 years under his belt in the universe, has departed the company and shared an ominous message on LinkedIn. In the message, he warns others in the industry about ‘staying strong and taking evidence’.</p>



<p>He also mentioned that he’s not able to talk about circumstances beyond a minor post, but said that next year, when it’s ‘absolutely safe to do so’, he’ll expand on his ‘story’.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-state-of-our-industry-seems-dire">‘The State of Our Industry Seems Dire’</h2>



<p>In a post on LinkedIn, Glenn Israel, former Art Director at 343 Industries (Halo Studios) wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>As of today and after seventeen long years, I am officially no longer contributing to the Halo universe. There is litle more I can say for the moment, though I intend to share this particular story in its entirety when it is absolutely safe to do so next year. In the meantime, I have a message for anyone and everyone who needs to hear it.</p>



<p>I know that the state of our industry seems dire, but never forget that you are *free to choose*. No illusion of security nor promise of wealth or fame or power is worth trading away your health, your dignity, your ethics or values – and no one can force you to. Stay strong, take evidence when necessary, and find where you belong.</p>



<p>As always, I’ll be here if you need to talk.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s most likely that Israel finds himself under an NDA after leaving Halo Studios, which is common practice to ensure that, for a time, developers aren’t discussing what they were working on or why they were let go from (or left) a company.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/glenn-israel-19696485_as-of-today-and-after-seventeen-long-years-activity-7379767940897959936-btQc?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAACr_MyIB0LsPQAIci9zs45L99nTb3k_h6f8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post was published</a> over a week ago at the time of writing, but recently found its way into social circulations.</p>



<p>Recently, in the Halo space, it was claimed that a Halo: Combat Evolved <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-ce-remake-virtuos-studio-claim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">remake was in co-development</a> by a Virtuos studio and is potentially set to be revealed during a Halo showcase at the Halo World Championship later this month.</p>



<p>Let me know what you want to see from the next Halo game on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/">Call of Duty maps are in Battlefield 6</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-studios-veteran-leaves-company-with-warning/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Took Mere Hours for Call of Duty Maps to Be Remade in Battlefield 6]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-took-mere-hours-for-call-of-duty-maps-to-be-remade-in-battlefield-6.1321567/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6’s new Portal mode is a UGC dream, featuring a full-fledged toolkit that tech-savvy individuals can use to make all manner of things from maps to immersive experiences. In a recent post on social media, it was revealed that one keen creator has rebuilt one of Call of Duty’s most iconic multiplayer maps <strong>in Battlefield 6</strong>.</p>



<p>The addition of this map to Portal means that anyone can find it and play on it, and from what has been shown, it’s a like-for-like replication of Shipment, a Call of Duty map first introduced in 2007’s Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare.</p>



<h2 id="h-shipment-is-in-battlefield-6-and-people-love-it">Shipment is in Battlefield 6, and People Love It</h2>



<p>The first thing folks did when responding to Matavatar’s post on social media was <strong>request</strong> <strong>more Call of Duty maps </strong>for Battlefield 6’s Portal platform.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>From the clips and shots above, you can see that Matavatar has painstakingly recreated Shipment in Battlefield 6, adding everything down to the minute details, and has promised that the map should be playable from day one of Battlefield 6 dropping, <strong>which is today</strong>.</p>



<p>In the comments under the post, Matavatar listed the other Call of Duty and retro Battlefield maps he intends to rebuild in Battlefield 6, all of which are pretty obvious:</p>



<ul>
<li>Nuketown</li>



<li>Ziba</li>



<li>Metro</li>



<li>Bazaar</li>



<li>Noshahr</li>



<li>Firing Range</li>
</ul>



<p>If nothing else, Matavatar’s creation is a perfect representation of how fluid and accessible the UGC platform is on Portal in Battlefield 6. He assembled this map in mere hours of the function going live, and it’ll be open to all Battlefield 6 players accessing Portal.</p>



<p>Do you think you’d like to play Battlefield 6 across a range of Call of Duty maps? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-launch-patch-notes-movement-nerfs-weapon-handling-rebalanced/">the latest Battlefield 6 patch notes</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-maps-remade-in-battlefield-6/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2 Preload Guide & File Size Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-and-file-size-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-guide-file-size-explained.1321558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Outer Worlds 2 will be released worldwide on October 29th, coming to Xbox Series, PC, and PlayStation 5 platforms. It’s the next iteration of the series started by Obsidian in 2019, which dropped and was dubbed ‘New Vegas in space’ by many.</p>



<p>In this ever-digital world, it’s always key to know when you can preload games, and the situation with The Outer Worlds 2 is no different. In this snapshot guide, I’ve got the information you need, including the data regarding The Outer Worlds 2’s file size on all platforms.</p>



<p>Read on to learn everything you need to know.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-can-you-preload-the-outer-worlds-2">When Can You Preload The Outer Worlds 2?</h2>



<p><strong>Preloads for The Outer Worlds 2 are available now on Xbox Series S, Xbox Series X, and Xbox on PC. </strong>I’m working to verify if preloads are available on PlayStation and PC via other platforms.</p>



<p>In a post published by <a href="https://xboxera.com/2025/10/10/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-is-up-on-xbox-its-a-chonky-boi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XboxEra</a>, the preload window was confirmed, as were the file sizes for The Outer Worlds 2. Be warned, this is a very hefty game, which might come as a surprise to some.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-outer-worlds-2-file-size-explained">The Outer Worlds 2 File Size Explained</h2>



<p><strong>The preload file size for The Outer Worlds 2 is 79.49 GB on Xbox Series S and Xbox Series X and 77.30 GB on Xbox on PC.</strong> It hasn’t been confirmed how much space the game will occupy on PlayStation 5, but it’s safe to assume it’s around the same mark.</p>



<p>We’ll update this guide once we’ve got that information.</p>



<p>The Outer Worlds 2 is a single-player title with open-world elements and plenty of RPG mechanics, but it still comes as a surprise that it’s almost 80 GB on some platforms. That’s a huge installation in any world, especially for a game expected to have a 30 – 40 hour range.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-preload-the-outer-worlds-2">How to Preload The Outer Worlds 2</h2>



<p><strong>If you want to preload The Outer Worlds 2, you can do so by heading to the Xbox Store on console or PC and clicking to preload the game. </strong>While we haven’t verified this yet, it’ll be the same process on PlayStation and other PC platforms like Steam.</p>



<p>If you don’t have Game Pass, you’ll need to purchase the game first. Those with Game Pass Ultimate can preload The Outer Worlds 2 <strong>right now</strong>.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord</a> server if you’re excited to play The Outer Worlds 2.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/">YouTube is suffering against rising competition</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-outer-worlds-2-preload-and-file-size-explained/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTube Has Dropped To a Low Point For The First Time ‘In Years’ as Competition Rises]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youtube-has-dropped-to-a-low-point-for-the-first-time-%E2%80%98in-years%E2%80%99-as-competition-rises.1321555/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In recent data, it was revealed that YouTube Live is suffering a comedown amid rising competition across the streaming space. In recent years, the likes of Kick.com and TikTok have come for the crowns claimed by YouTube and Twitch, and the video-based titans are starting to feel that pinch.</p>



<p>Steamscharts recently published a report for the Q3 2025 ‘Global Livestreaming Landscape’, and it revealed that quarter-over-quarter, YouTube Live saw a drop of more than 10% in hours watched, falling below the 50% market cap spot ‘for the first time in years’.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-streaming-space-is-becoming-saturated">The Streaming Space is Becoming Saturated</h2>



<p><a href="https://streamscharts.com/news/q3-2025-global-livestreaming-landscape" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Streamscharts’ report</a> included coverage of every major and growing minor streaming platform around the world:</p>



<ul>
<li>YouTube</li>



<li>TikTok</li>



<li>Twitch</li>



<li>Kick</li>



<li>SOOP Korea</li>



<li>CHZZK</li>



<li>Rumble</li>



<li>NimoTV</li>
</ul>



<p>The numbers represent a considerable drop in foothold for YouTube Live, which is crumbling under the competition represented by TikTok Live. In recent years, TikTok has become a powerhouse platform for streamers looking to make a buck, with intense monetization features that are just too lucrative for anyone to ignore.</p>



<p>That’s why TikTok Live now makes up 31.4% of the livestreaming market, 4.4% of which is dedicated to gaming, fast becoming one of the cornerstones of the platform that was once made up of teenagers dancing to popular music.</p>



<p>YouTube Live still has a 45% claim over the market, but as Streamscharts wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>YouTube Live remains the top platform but</strong>&nbsp;saw a 10.6% drop in Hours Watched (13.25B) and its share fell below 50% for the first time in years.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Kick continues to grow, despite constant controversies being raised on the platform. It’s still a site under intense scrutiny, but that hasn’t stopped streamers from flocking to the site as another option for their broadcasts.</p>



<p>Are you surprised that YouTube Live has seen a drop this year? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a former Assassin’s Creed actor <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-civil-war-former-actor-reacts/">has reacted to the canceled game</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/youtube-dropped-to-low-point-in-years/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>