<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 17:46:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Assassin’s Creed Shadows Have Early Access?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-assassins-creed-shadows-have-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-have-early-access.1119621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/does-assassins-creed-shadows-have-early-access/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The continuation of Assassin’s Creed takes us to Japan, and we’re curious to see if we can play hop on a quicker flight and secure Early Access for Assassin’s Creed Shadows.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a>‘ content will come to <em>light </em>soon enough. Ubisoft is looking to vacate the shadows after a turbulent 2024 where nothing went right. The company has seen better times with countless layoffs to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-xdefiant-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XDefiant</a> and other projects announcing their closure hitting hard.</p>



<p>But Ubisoft is looking to turn a corner with Assassin’s Creed Shadows. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pre-orders are red hot</a>, and interest in Shadows is almost scalding. Let’s see whether potential Early Access has had a say in the game’s pre-release success and hype.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-assassin-s-creed-shadows-early-access">Can You Play Assassin’s Creed Shadows Early Access?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Guess I’ll have to take measures into my own hands. Credit to Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There is no Early Access for Assassin’s Creed Shadows and it is set to release simultaneously for everyone.</strong></p>



<p>Shadows doesn’t have online multiplayer, so there’s no component for players to get an edge on each other. However, many single-player games are opting to negate Early Access. Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 and Baldur’s Gate 3 are classic examples of games being made for players.</p>



<p>They opted against Early Access, and it seems Ubisoft has decided to follow suit.</p>



<h2 id="h-do-we-know-why-assassin-s-creed-shadows-doesn-t-have-early-access">Do we Know Why Assassin’s Creed Shadows Doesn’t Have Early Access?</h2>



<p><strong>Curiously, Ubisoft hasn’t revealed why they’ve canceled Assassin’s Creed Shadows Early Access, merely stating that the Collector’s Edition no longer has the early bonus.</strong></p>



<p>Thanks to <a href="https://igamemag.com/assassins-creed-shadows-early-access-canceled-ubisoft-confirms-the-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">iGame Magazine</a>, we can see the original Discord Q&amp;A addressing the cancelation of Assassin’s Creed Shadows’ Early Access.</p>



<p>Under a question about the Collector’s Edition titled “Will I still get the 3 days of Early Access as advertised,” a Ubisoft developer says: “<strong>No, there is no Early Access for AC Shadows anymore.</strong>“</p>



<p>Is this out of the goodness and thoughtfulness of Ubisoft’s heart? Or is it a way to improve their standing and put gamers before business first? We may never get a proper answer to this question.</p>



<hr>



<p>It looks like we’re all diving into Assassin’s Creed Shadows blind. I’m interested to hear your thoughts: Should the concept of pre-order Early Access be scrapped for good? Or is it a worthwhile bonus for the most committed of fans? </p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-assassins-creed-shadows-coming-to-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows’ Xbox Game Pass</a> status is available to check out, as is our quick guide on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-assassins-creed-shadows-free-download-bonus-weapon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get yourself an exclusive bonus weapon</a> for the full Shadows launch.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hextech Chests Will Return to League of Legends After Mass Player Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hextech-chests-will-return-to-league-of-legends-after-mass-player-backlash/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hextech-chests-will-return-to-league-of-legends-after-mass-player-backlash.1119618/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hextech-chests-will-return-to-league-of-legends-after-mass-player-backlash/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hextech Chests are coming back to League of Legends, after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-devs-defend-unpopular-hextech-chest-changes-promise-better-battle-passes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">their removal at the start of 2025 sparked massive outrage within the player base</a>. In Riot’s most recent Dev Update, the League team acknowledged that many of their previous changes didn’t go over well with the community.</p>



<h2 id="h-hextech-chests-are-coming-back">Hextech Chests Are Coming Back</h2>



<p>Beginning in Act 2, with the release of patch 25.05 at the start of March, Hextech Chests will officially return. Going forward, there will be 10 Hextech Chests available for players to earn each act, which translates to 60 per year across six acts. </p>



<ul>
<li>Eight will be available in the free Pass of each act.</li>



<li>Two more can be earned through the Honor system.</li>
</ul>



<p>Previously, before they were removed, Hextech Chests were earned through the Champion Mastery system. The returning chests will be exactly the same as the ones previously earned through Champion Mastery, but they should be more “accessible” through the pass.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Hextech Chests, Rewards &amp; More | Dev Update - League of Legends" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sAVa467pHl8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>A number of other changes are being rolled back or addressed in the upcoming past. Blue Essence cost for all champions will be reduced by 50 percent, and more Mythic Essence is getting added to the pass rewards system. The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-h56OC1gqAM" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">initial announcement</a> that Hextech Chests were being removed drew a ton of backlash, with several players threatening to boycott the game altogether. Executive Producer Paul “Pabro” Bellezza and League head Andrei “Meddler” van Roon addressed the team’s goals for Riot’s flagship title:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We want to acknowledge that we know getting League to the right place isn’t about just one set of changes. It’s about continually refining and improving the game. We think today’s updates are an important step, and we’ll keep tracking how these changes feel, talking with all of you about how things are landing, and making adjustments. We’ve always built League along with all you, the community. Thank you for sticking with us and hearing us out, and we look forward to continuing to work with you to make sure League is the best game it can be. Thanks so much, and we’ll see you on the Rift.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Are the return of Hextech Chests enough to get you back into League of Legends? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>More more Insider Gaming coverage, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive interview with one of the developers behind Call of Duty’s skill-based matchmaking</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Free PlayStation Plus Games For March 2025 Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/free-playstation-plus-games-for-march-2025-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/free-playstation-plus-games-for-march-2025-announced.1119570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/free-playstation-plus-games-for-march-2025-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Sony has announced the three new games available for free for all PlayStation Plus subscribers for March 2025 will be Dragon Age: The Veilguard, Sonic Colors: Ultimate and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: The Cowabunga Collection</p>



<p>All <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/02/26/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-march-dragon-age-the-veilguard-sonic-colors-ultimate-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-the-cowabunga-collection/?sf276488366=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">three of the games</a> will be available for PlayStation Plus members starting March 4. As with past monthly games, once you add them to your library, they will be available to download at any time as long as you have an active subscription.</p>



<p>The games will be available until March 31.</p>



<h2 id="h-march-2025-s-free-playstation-plus-games">March 2025’s Free PlayStation Plus Games</h2>



<p>Of the games coming to the service in March, Dragon Age: The Veilguard is the most notable. Released in October 2024, Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s response was mixed from both critics and consumers. The game failed to meet EA expectations, with the company <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-says-dragon-age-the-veilguard-didnt-meet-revenue-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saying it missed targets</a> by nearly 50%. Developer BioWare has also since made changes, including layoffs at the studio.</p>



<p>Sonic Colors: Ultimate was released in September 2021 and sees you play as Sonic on a journey to free Wisps that were captured by Dr.  Eggman. Lastly, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: The Cowabunga Collection was release in  August 2022 and includes a collection of 13 games released between 1989 and 1994.</p>



<p>For those who haven’t picked up <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-february-2025-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February’s free games</a>—Payday 3, High on Life, and Pac-Man World Re-Pac—you have until March 3 to do so.</p>



<p>In addition to the new games for PlayStation Plus subscribers, those who are on Extra and Premium memberships <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-9-games-in-february/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">received nine new games</a> to the PlayStation Game Catalog this month.</p>



<p>What do you think of the free PlayStation Plus games for March 2025? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1704/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read our exclusive interview with a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developer responsible for skill-based matchmaking</a> in the Call of Duty franchise. &nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>