<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 06:48:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT To Appear at Esports World Cup Following New Riot Games Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-esports-world-cup-riot-deal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-to-appear-at-esports-world-cup-following-new-riot-games-deal.1105563/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-esports-world-cup-riot-deal/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Riot Games has signed a three-year partnership with the Esports World Cup Foundation to bring a trio of titles to the hyper-valuable event. From this year, League of Legends, Teamfight Tactics, and most importantly, <strong>VALORANT</strong> will appear at the Esports World Cup event in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>This will mark the first time that VALORANT has appeared at the event, as last year during the inaugural showcase, the game failed to surface.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-cultural-impact-of-competitive-gaming">‘The Cultural Impact of Competitive Gaming’</h2>



<p>The Esports World Cup is the biggest modern event in competitive gaming. It boasts a collective prize pool worth tens of millions of dollars, and it plays host to the industry’s biggest games and most talented players. For many, it’s an immoral event seen as ‘esportswashing’ and nothing more, but for others, it’s a monumental thing that’s set to become a staple of the wider business.</p>



<p>In a recent release, it was revealed that VALORANT will appear alongside League and TFT at the Esports World Cup 2025. During 2024’s event, VALORANT didn’t appear, so this will be the first time that the game has a place at the EWC:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Riot Games has <strong>shaped the cultural impact of competitive gaming</strong>, transforming esports into a global entertainment force.&nbsp;With League of Legends’ iconic World Championship — which continues to set new standards for immersive experiences, Valorant’s cultural collaborations, and Teamfight Tactics’ community-driven events, Riot has pioneered an ecosystem far beyond the competition. </p>



<p>By bringing these titles to the Esports World Cup, we are not just celebrating elite gameplay — we are, together, expanding esports as a global entertainment movement, creating deeper connections with fans across gaming, music, and digital culture</p>



<p>– Fabian Scheuermann, Chief Games Officer at EWCF.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Riot Games representatives explained that last year was an evaluation of sorts, and that’s why VALORANT wasn’t one of the games to appear at the Esports World Cup in 2024. In a post, the team explained, <em>‘The feedback we got from players and teams who participated last year was positive. The event’s significant prize pool offered crucial financial support for them, providing stability at a time when many esports organizations were working toward a stronger future.’</em></p>



<p>Are you excited to see VALORANT appear at this year’s Esports World Cup? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/vitality-stuns-spirit-3-0-in-grand-finals-of-iem-katowice/">Vitality has won at IEM Katowice</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Iconic MMO is Getting a New Class For The First Time Since 1997]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/iconic-mmo-new-class-1997-tibia-monk/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-iconic-mmo-is-getting-a-new-class-for-the-first-time-since-1997.1105560/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/iconic-mmo-new-class-1997-tibia-monk/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I’ve been playing Tibia since 2004 – but not <strong>consistently</strong>. I’ll dip in and out of the game around special events, but it remains my number one most-played game of all time simply because of how long I’ve been a user. Recently, Tibia’s developer, CipSoft, revealed that <span>the game is getting a ne</span>w character class –&nbsp;<strong>Monk </strong>– for the first time in almost thirty years.</p>



<p>Those familiar with Tibia’s four-class paradigm are about to have their worlds shattered.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-enter-the-monk">Enter the Monk</h2>



<p>CipSoft has unveiled Monk, an all-new character class coming to Tibia later this year. This humble MMORPG was released in 1997 with four core character pillars: Knight, Sorcerer, Paladin, and Druid. That structure has remained fundamentally unchanged for almost thirty years – until now.</p>



<p>With a very short trailer posted online, the CipSoft team revealed the Monk character class:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Tibia - Vocation Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DMzXYOz6o7I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>This new Tibia vocation promises to be a capable hand-to-hand fighter that can use ‘mystical abilities’ to heal allies while pummeling enemies into dust. Here’s the full description of the new character type:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The&nbsp;<strong>Monk</strong>&nbsp;will be a melee fighter capable of supporting and healing allies while using martial arts and mystical abilities to defeat enemies. The great truth seeker will have some very special features, such as&nbsp;<em>harmony</em>,<em>&nbsp;virtues</em>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<em>serene</em>.&nbsp;A&nbsp;<strong>Monk</strong>&nbsp;can be played in a very special way and, at the same time, is expected to integrate seamlessly into the Tibian world. In fact, one of our main goals was to ensure that the new vocation holds a unique position without undermining the value of others or rendering them obsolete.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>From February 25, CipSoft will be holding player tests for the Monk class, and later this year, the vocation will be permanently added to Tibia, which is still going strong after 28 years on the market.</p>



<p>It’s incredible to see CipSoft pouring so much love into Tibia after all these years. It was only a couple of years ago that the developers decided to add sound to the game, implementing audio effects and a soundtrack alongside countless other updates. The core aesthetic of Tibia has remained unchanged since 1997, but the game is still evolving today.</p>



<p>To learn more about the new Monk class,  check out the full breakdown from CipSoft’s ‘Niadus’ <a href="https://www.tibia.com/news/?subtopic=latestnews&amp;id=8215" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">on the Tibia website</a>.</p>



<p>Are you going to give the Monk a try in Tibia? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-did-psn-go-down-explained/">explanation as to why the PSN went down</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>