<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 08:54:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Has Free Rein to Create Original Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-has-free-rein-to-create-original-characters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-has-free-rein-to-create-original-characters.1273446/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Marvel Rivals developer Netease has free rein to create and introduce original characters to the game, it has been confirmed.</p>



<p>Though the game already boasts a stacked roster of fan-favorite characters, alongside an almost endless list of Marvel names that could be brought into the fray, the door is open for the developers to create original characters.</p>



<p>Confirmation came via game director Guangguang, who didn’t confirm whether it was something Netease has planned, but it was clear there was a possibility—though it remains to be seen whether it could happen in the next year, a period in which <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-marvel-rivals-devs-have-a-years-worth-of-characters-planned/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">characters have already been prepared</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-stay-tuned-for-marvel-rivals-original-characters">‘Stay Tuned’ For Marvel Rivals Original Characters</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Original characters could be created. Image via Netease</figcaption></figure>



<p>Speaking to <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/netease-green-light-marvel-create-original-characters-marvel-rivals" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MP1st</a>, Guangguang adopted his customary “stay tuned” response when asked if original characters were planned to be introduced, but confirmed Marvel has given permission for them to be created.</p>



<p>Though this might seem surprising given Marvel Rivals has over seven decades of comic book history and characters to fall back upon, it wouldn’t be the first time a new Marvel character has been introduced in a video game.</p>



<p>Luna Snow, who has become one of the most popular characters in Marvel Rivals, is the best example, having been created for Marvel Future Fight before making a comic book debut in 2019.</p>



<p>Marvel Rivals has shown that it can bring lesser-known characters into the limelight to become household names, as shown by the popularity of Jeff the Land Shark, so there’s every chance an original character could make waves.</p>



<p>Another example of a successful character being introduced outside of comic books comes from DC with Harley Quinn, who is now one of the most popular characters under the DC umbrella. She was first introduced in the Batman Animated Series in the 1990s.</p>



<p>Would you like to see original characters introduced to Marvel Rivals? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/3338/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-gooner-reputation-has-been-addressed-by-its-game-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Guangguang addressing the “Gooner” reputation of the game</a>, and read our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-marvel-rivals-planning-collaborations-with-other-marvel-titles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive on collaborations with other Marvel titles</a> being planned.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-has-free-rein-to-create-original-characters/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Trailer Leak Confirms Release Date, Vault Edition, and ‘Mega Jump’ Boost Pack]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-trailer-leak-release-date-vault-edition-boost/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-trailer-leak-confirms-release-date-vault-edition-and-%E2%80%98mega-jump%E2%80%99-boost-pack.1273431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Eagle-eyed users have found an ad for Black Ops 7 that seems to have aired too early, promoting the game’s pre-order availability, release date, and Vault Edition pack. In the short, fifteen-second ad, we get a first look at boost jump abilities, a mission containing hulking mech suits, and some kind of dream sequence pitting players against a human enemy several storeys tall.</p>



<p>This ad was mistakenly released mere hours before Black Ops 7 is set to be revealed during Gamescom’s Opening Night Live ceremony.</p>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-release-date-confirmed-in-leaked-ad">Black Ops 7 Release Date Confirmed in Leaked Ad</h2>



<p>On social media, users started circulating a screengrab of an ad for Black Ops 7. In this fifteen-second clip, we see highly vertical combat aided by ‘mega jump’ boost packs, <strong>not </strong>jetpacks. In the sequences that unfold, the player character leaps high into the air and coasts over the battlefield, which is a representation of the traversal in this year’s Call of Duty title.</p>



<p>We also see a snippet of a mission showing a fight against an enormous and heavily armed mech. In classic Black Ops style, things appear to get a little trippy as the player is forced into a battle against a Galactus-sized enemy in what looks like a dream sequence.</p>



<p>Here’s the trailer (might have been removed by the time you read this):</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The screen grab is low resolution, but we get a look at the Vault Edition components, too. It looks like the skins that were previously leaked, including <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-rely-on-17-year-old-reznov-pre-orders/">the Reznov Challenge Pack</a>, are all coming. When you pre-order, you’ll get early access to the beta, but the date for that test wasn’t revealed.</p>



<p>The release date was confirmed as November 14, which was suggested <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-releases-november-14/">in an earlier leak</a>.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to Call of Duty: Black Ops 7? Let me know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-code-gift-tease-release/">a new code for Tarkov has teased the game’s release</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-trailer-leak-release-date-vault-edition-boost/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>