<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 14:30:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Mix Fall Game Showcase 2025: Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-mix-fall-game-showcase-2025-everything-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-mix-fall-game-showcase-2025-everything-announced.1283979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-142575">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>PAX West is underway in Seattle, Washington, and with it comes even more games for fans to see and learn about. To kick the event off comes The Mix Fall Game Showcase for 2025 with dozens of upcoming independent games being shown.</p>



<p>The showcase starts at <strong>Noon ET/9am PT</strong> on August 29, and can be watch via Twitch or YouTube. For your convenience, the YouTube stream has been embedded below.</p>



<p>As far as what to expect, The Mix Summer Game Showcase 2025 lasted roughly two hours, and featured 75 upcoming indie games. That means, not only will it be a packed show, but there should be something for everyone, no matter what type of gamer your are.</p>



<p>While the show airs, you can find details of everything announced below, along with the trailers that were shown <strong>(make sure you refresh the page to get the latest trailers)</strong>. Be sure to let us know in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>&nbsp;what your favorite reveal was and what you are most excited for.</p>



<p>If you want even more showcase recaps and trailers, check out everything that was announced at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-everything-announced" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Opening Night Live 2025</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/future-games-show-gamescom-2025-everything-announced" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Future Games Show at Gamescom 2025</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The MIX Fall Game Showcase 2025" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cRm_IhS0r6M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-everything-announced-during-the-mix-fall-game-showcase-2025">Everything Announced During The Mix Fall Game Showcase 2025</h2>



<p><strong><em>We will be updating this article live during <a href="https://mediaindieexchange.com/showcases/the-mix-fall-game-showcase-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Mix Fall Game Showcase 2025</a>, with all the latest reveals added in the order they were shown.</em></strong></p>



<hr>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-is-about-to-get-even-harder-in-new-update/">
                                Elden Ring Nightreign Is About To Get Even Harder In New Update                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>If you thought Elden Ring Nightreign couldn’t get any harder, think again; an update is adding new difficulty settings.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-testing-is-back/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-testing-is-back/">
                                Battlefield Labs Testing Resumes Following End of BF6 Open Beta                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>EA has announced that Battlefield Labs is back and players can start testing the game again before its October 10 launch date.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-movie-paramount-seeking-rights/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-movie-paramount-seeking-rights/">
                                Paramount Seeking Rights To Make A Call of Duty Movie, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been claimed that Paramount is seeking to acquire the rights to make a Call of Duty movie, which is reportedly a ‘priority’.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-august-2025-patch-notes/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mafia-the-old-country-august-2025-patch-notes/">
                                Mafia: The Old Country Releases August 2025 Patch Notes                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The latest update for Mafia: The Old Country is out now and the patch notes have been released.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-mix-fall-game-showcase-2025-everything-announced/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is NBA 2K26 Coming to Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-nba-2k26-coming-to-xbox-game-pass.1283946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>September is a huge month for sports games with several big titles on the horizon, with NBA 2K26 among those poised for launch, and we’ve got the details on whether Game Pass subscribers have access to the game.</p>



<p>Releasing fully on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-release-date-explained-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September 5</a>, though it’s available from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">August 29 for those with early access</a>, NBA 2K26 is the latest entry in the long-running franchise and is always among the most popular games every year.</p>



<p>With September stacked full of big releases, a Game Pass subscription can save you some money, and we’ve got details on whether the service includes NBA 2K26.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-nba-2k26-on-xbox-game-pass">Can You Play NBA 2K26 on Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Not yet. Credit to 2K</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, NBA 2K26 will not be available to play with an Xbox Game Pass subscription when it launches on September 5th.</strong></p>



<p>NBA 2K26 is not an Xbox first-party title, which would see it immediately made available through the service. Unlike rivals EA Sports, there’s no free trial period with a Game Pass subscription either.</p>



<p>Although the first wave of titles launching on <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/xbox-game-pass" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Game Pass</a> in September is yet to be announced, NBA 2K26 is a huge release and, if it were to be on the service, we’d have been told by now. On top of this, the Xbox Store page would have a button that states the title would be ‘Coming to Game Pass’ alongside the purchase option.</p>



<p>With no such announcement and no Game Pass badge on the store page, the game will definitely not be on the service at launch.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-nba-2k26-come-to-xbox-game-pass">Will NBA 2K26 Come to Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<p><strong>NBA 2K26 could come to the Xbox Game Pass service in the future, although no official word has confirmed this.</strong></p>



<p>2K has a close relationship with Xbox, with a free-play weekend for Game Pass subscribers for NBA 2K25 last year, while NBA 2K24 had a six-month stint on the service previously. </p>



<p>Other 2K titles, like Borderlands, have also regularly appeared on the Game Pass service, and the cycle of sports games usually sees them move to the service in the final few months of their lifespan before the latest release is dropped.</p>



<p>Therefore, if NBA 2K26 is to come to the service, don’t expect it to occur before 2026, unless a free-play weekend or a similar incentive is announced later in the year.</p>



<p>Have you purchased NBA 2K26? What are your thoughts on the game? Let us know during the Insider Gaming forum.</p>



<p>For more NBA 2K26, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/full-nba-2k26-soundtrack-includes-43-songs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full soundtrack of 43 songs</a>, and take a look at the latest trailer for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-mycareer-mode-gets-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MyCareer mode</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nba-2k26-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Hollow Knight: Silksong on Nintendo Switch or Switch 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-hollow-knight-silksong-on-nintendo-switch-or-switch-2.1283904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The launch of Hollow Knight: Silksong is the type of gaming event that doesn’t come around very often. If you’re excited to get your hands on the sequel and you own a Nintendo Switch 1 or 2 console, let’s check if you can buy Silksong.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> is a long time coming—and that’s one of the biggest understatements of 2025. It’s been in development for years, its rabid fanbase is desperate for the sequel, and by the end of its run, the original Hollow Knight had launched on multiple platforms. </p>



<p>With exclusivity, consoles, and hardware up in the air more than ever, you might be wondering if Hollow Knight: Silksong is on the Nintendo Switch, Switch 2, both, or worst-case, neither!</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-hollow-knight-silksong-on-nintendo-switch-1">Can You Play Hollow Knight: Silksong on Nintendo Switch 1?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Time to Switch things up. Credit to Team Cherry</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong is still coming out for the original Nintendo Switch 1 console, despite its aging hardware.</strong></p>



<p>Nintendo is remaining steadfast in its desire to support the Switch 1. Its 150 million-plus lifetime sales suggest there’s plenty of potential for any game to succeed on it. Not everyone upgrades to the new gen right away—which is understandable given the console’s considerable price tag.</p>



<p>This is why <a href="https://hollowknightsilksong.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> deserves a Nintendo Switch 1 release. It may not run as smoothly as it will on other <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-platforms-ps5-xbox-pc-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platforms—such as the PlayStation, Xbox, and PC</a>, for instance—but you should be able to enjoy the fruits of Team Cherry’s years of hard labor and toil.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-hollow-knight-silksong-on-nintendo-switch-2">Can You Play Hollow Knight: Silksong on Nintendo Switch 2?</h2>



<p><strong>Nintendo Switch 2 owners also get to play Hollow Knight: Silksong when it launches on September 4.</strong></p>



<p>It’s going to become a common theme moving forward. The Switch 2 will be the de facto home for Nintendo players. It’ll eventually become a case of wondering if the game is also coming to the first Switch instead of the Switch 2. We’ve already seen the likes of Mario Kart World and Donkey Kong Bananza skip out on the first Nintendo Switch.</p>



<p>This is only the beginning, I can assure you. On the other hand, the Switch 1 has plenty of life left, so don’t worry about missing out on big third-party games anytime soon! Enjoy Hornet and her adventure across Pharloom on both Nintendo Switch consoles and see what the hype is all about.</p>



<hr>



<p>If you need some insight about Hollow Knight: Silksong, read up on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/do-you-need-to-play-hollow-knight-before-silksong/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether you need to play Hollow Knight before Silksong</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-hollow-knight-silksong-a-sequel-or-prequel/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether Silksong is a sequel or a prequel</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-physical-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">if there will be a physical release</a>.</p>



<p>You can also head to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a> to talk about the Hollow Knight universe. Share your biggest Hollow Knight theories, let us know why you love the first game, and why you’re excited for Silksong.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long to Beat Cronos: The New Dawn? Game Length Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-long-to-beat-cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length-explained.1283853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>With September stacked full of huge releases, knowing the amount of time it will take to complete games like Cronos: The New Dawn is important for you to plan effectively, so we’ve got the details on the game length.</p>



<p>Launching <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-release-date-explained-start-times-release-date-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September 5</a>, Cronos: The New Dawn impressed in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview</a>, but it lands in a packed release schedule that also includes the likes of Hollow Knight: Silksong and Borderlands 4.</p>



<p>If you’re planning to play multiple new releases in September, we’ve got everything you need to know on the game length of Cronos: The New Dawn.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-many-hours-to-beat-cronos-the-new-dawn">How Many Hours to Beat Cronos: The New Dawn?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Dark journey. Image via Bloober Team</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Cronos: The New Dawn will take around 18 hours to beat, according to the developer themselves.</strong></p>



<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.techradar.com/gaming/cronos-the-new-dawn-developers-reveal-that-it-will-take-around-18-hours-to-beat" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tech Radar</a> in April, game directors Wojciech Piejko and Jacek Zięba stated that the game was being completed by play tests in 18 hours. However, it was added that it could change as the team was still “balancing everything.”</p>



<p>It’s unclear whether the game length has extended or shortened since, but it should give players a decent indication of how long it will take to progress through the main story. Depending on how you play, it could take up to 20 hours or as little as 16.</p>



<p>If you want to uncover every secret hidden in the game, it will naturally take you longer until you reach the end, but it’s all down to your playstyle.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-long-is-a-cronos-the-new-dawn-full-completionist-run">How Long is a Cronos: The New Dawn Full Completionist Run?</h2>



<p><strong>The length of a full completionist run in Cronos: The New Dawn has not been stated, although players are encouraged to play through the main story at least twice.</strong></p>



<p>Replaying the game unlocks new skins, access to a higher difficulty option in New Game+, experimenting with the upgrade system, or trying out different approaches. Crucially, the developers have stated the game needs to be played “at least twice to understand most of it.”</p>



<p>Two playthroughs would total around 36 hours, giving you plenty of time to sink into the title, and it’s clear that replayability is a crucial feature.</p>



<p>How many times do you think you’ll play through Cronos: The New Dawn? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Cronos: The New Dawn, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether it will be available on Xbox Game Pass</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-gets-new-trailer-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">horrifying trailer shown at Gamescom</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-game-length/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>