<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 12:11:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Breaks Franchise’s Single-Player Record on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-single-player-record-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-breaks-franchise%E2%80%99s-single-player-record-on-steam.1092567/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-single-player-record-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth now has the highest all-time player peak on Steam compared to all single-player games from the series. </p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-sets-highest-steam-peak-for-series-single-player-games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth has amassed over 40,000 players on Steam, according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2909400/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>. This record is more than double the prequel, as Final Fantasy 7 Remake still sits at a peak of around 14,000. Final Fantasy 16 also lags behind, with the game’s peak ending at over 27,000 players. The only game with a higher player count is Final Fantasy 14, sitting at 95,000 players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reviews for Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth on Steam have also been favourable. Out of all the reviews, 77.4% are positive, and 22.6% are negative; overall, reviews for the PC port have been ‘mostly positive’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Surprisingly, even though Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth is the second game of the FF VII remake trilogy, it has still managed to pull in more concurrent players than the previous instalment. The sequel follows the journey of Cloud, Tifa, and the gang as they start exploring the planet on Chocobos after escaping from Midgar. They are chasing the fallen hero, Sephiroth; however, he will not make the journey easy for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, developers have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-developers-have-already-written-part-3s-story/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">already finished writing the story</a> for Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3. Additionally, Part 3 will not be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-release-on-a-wide-range-of-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive to PlayStation 6</a>. What are your thoughts on Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth breaking the franchise’s single-player record on Steam?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insomniac-refused-to-confirm-or-deny-marvels-wolverines-release-window/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel’s Wolverine developers refusing to confirm or deny the 2025 release window</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows’ Graphic Content Will be Censored in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shaodws-censored/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows%E2%80%99-graphic-content-will-be-censored-in-japan.1092564/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shaodws-censored/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The announcement came from Ubisoft, who said that some graphical content will be censored in Japan in order to comply with the Japanese rating board CERO.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/UBISOFT_JAPAN/status/1882611785775174070/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">statement</a> posted to X (formerly Twitter), and translated via <a href="https://www.deepl.com/en/translator/l/ja/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">deepl</a>, Ubisoft Japan said, “In order to comply with the regulations of the reviewing authorities, the Japanese version of “Assassin’s Creed Shadows” (CERO:Z) will differ in some of the game’s expressions.</p>



<p>“The game settings have been changed so that the player cannot amputate the head and limbs of enemies at any time during play. The expression of the cut surface of the body has been changed,” it continued.</p>



<p>Ubisoft’s decision comes following the Japanese rating board CERO’s ‘Z’ rating, which although means that the game cannot be sold to anyone over 18, CERO still determined that the game was too violent to be sold in Japan. Ubisoft’s change means that the game can now be sold in Japan, but still have the CERO Z rating.</p>



<p>This isn’t the first time that Japan has imposed such strict rules on games either. In 2023, CERO banned the Dead Space Remake due to violence and also banned The Callisto Protocol in 2022. On the other hand, Stellar Blade passed with a CERO D rating, meaning the game  is not suitable for those under the game of 17. </p>



<p>Following two delays, Assassin’s Creed Shadows officially launches March 20, 2025 on the PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X and PC.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft’s decision to censor the game in Japan? Do you agree with CERO’s rating on the game? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-more-xbox-games-multiplatform/">more Xbox games will become multi-platform</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redeption-2-breaks-steam-concurrent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Red Dead Redemption 2 Hits New Concurrent Record on Steam Thanks to $15 Sale<br></a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption 2 Hits New Concurrent Record on Steam Thanks to $15 Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redeption-2-breaks-steam-concurrent/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-2-hits-new-concurrent-record-on-steam-thanks-to-15-sale.1092378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redeption-2-breaks-steam-concurrent/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Red Dead Redemption 2 has topped a new record on Steam thanks to Rockstar Games’ sale, where the game is just $15.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, Red Dead Redemption 2 currently sits with a peak concurrent player count of 86,717 according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1174180/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, topping its previous record of 77,655 in November 2023.</p>



<p>Its success comes from the recent <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/rockstarpublishersale2025?snr=1_4_4__118&amp;tab=3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rockstar Games Steam sale</a>, where you can save up to 80% off on Rockstar Games. Red Dead Redemption 2 seems to be one of the better deals at a 75% discount and for a game considered as a masterpiece (and still very much holds up today, may I add).</p>



<p>Red Dead Redemption 2 first released in October 2018 on consoles, and released one year later for PC on November 5, 2019.</p>



<p>The western-themed action-adventure would go on to win over 175 game awards and by June 2024 has sold over <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-millions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">67 million units worldwide</a>.</p>



<p>As for what’s next with Rockstar Games, everyone is waiting for an update on the highly anticipated GTA 6, which will undoubtedly be The Game of the Year, no matter which year it launches. At the time of writing, the game is still slated to launch in 2025, but Rockstar Games’ lack of update has understandably got gamers, and the industry as a whole, wondering if a delay is imminent.</p>



<p>Its delay and lack of updates even resulted in one developer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-parody-grand-taking-ages-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launching ‘Grand Taking Ages’ on Steam</a> as a parody.</p>



<p>Will you be picking up Red Dead Redemption 2 for just $15? Or are you waiting for that all-important GTA 6 update? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-more-xbox-games-multiplatform/">more Xbox games will become multi-platform</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-not-open-world-because-zones-tough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed Isn’t Open-World Because The ‘Pacing is Really Tough’ Without Zones</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>