<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 18:07:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Strands #721 Hints and Answers for February 22, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-721-hints-and-answers-for-february-22-2026/</link>
            <guid>1443055</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/strands/" id="3586">Strands </a>is a daily word search puzzle game from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/new-york-times/" id="2981">The New York Times</a>. It is a relatively new game, launched in 2024, in which players seek a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid.</p>



<p>Whether it’s your first time playing or you’re a Strands veteran, today’s tips and strategies can help you find words faster. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Strands, don’t worry, below you’ll find some&nbsp;<strong>helpful hints and even the answers for Strands Game #721</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for Sunday, February 22, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-672014a9-ce75-4ea0-b98d-12b9214dbb53">To play today’s Strands,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/strands" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">head to the game’s website.</a></p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of Strands. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure id="block-5f20defe-2f05-4eb9-b880-6af2f94b324d"></figure>







<h2 id="block-e2995432-719e-4ed6-8fad-a1db37670203">How To Play Strands</h2>



<p id="block-da980997-0420-4527-946e-b66c49bf3d07">Strands is a daily word search that challenges you to find words with a common theme. There’s also a Spanagram that reveals the deeper theme behind the words.</p>



<ul id="block-d0bea02d-4b9f-4991-b9db-3b35778ff3bf">
<li>Words that are three letters and under do not count.</li>



<li>Words that reveal the correct theme appear in blue.</li>



<li>The Spanagram turns yellow when found.</li>



<li>Finding three words that don’t fit the theme will reveal a hint to help you find the proper words.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-5e597b53-af1c-4c06-a00c-6c5a4694e9e0">The goal is to string together as many words as possible. Every letter on the grid gets used! Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p id="block-cd7aaa7f-9491-4ad0-b994-72d0102c5bed">Strands can only be played on the New York Times website. You can also play on the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/crosswords/apps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NYT Games app.</a></p>



<h2 id="block-c6d4979d-f8eb-4473-a011-33019cb8da2c">Strands Hints For Today, February 22, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-23b6a5a9-2c25-47c2-a0ea-e23a99c87abd">The Strands’ answers for Game #721 are all related to the closing ceremony of the Olympics. Think about all your favorite athletes and events, but bear in mind that all the answers are generic terms related to the ceremony.</p>



<h3 id="block-6777813b-1426-4c21-b507-3024542b4683">General Strands Hints For February 22</h3>



<p id="block-b36e160d-6e5e-4dc8-aae9-5352ee681266">Without giving today’s Strands answers completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul id="block-5c9f7d28-537c-424b-92c3-2a9906b57178">
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;One of the answers to today’s puzzle is an obviously important symbol to every country participating in the Olympics</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> There are plenty of these each year, but the one that seems to take the spotlight is put on by a famous department store to kick off the holiday season in the United States.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;Every competitor in the Olympics considers themselves to be a top-tier <strong><em>__</em></strong>.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-7fb794eb-0d89-4f8d-a7cf-082d0148b796">Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving&nbsp;<strong>Strands #720</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for February 21, 2026.</strong></p>







<h3 id="block-73a1d2f5-fc2b-49b7-9c10-539e38a2b946">Words to Help You Find Strand Hints for February 22, 2026</h3>



<p id="block-0853e28e-417e-4720-9526-9f2808a268be">If you want help getting started without having today’s Strands answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you unlock some in-game hints. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul id="block-2ca8fb79-d1a4-43e4-8764-e4d238a3cc97">
<li>MALE</li>



<li>LADS</li>



<li>LATE</li>



<li>DEAR</li>



<li>GALA</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-strands-answer-for-game-721-on-february-22-2026">Today’s Strands Answer For Game #721 On February 22, 2026</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p id="block-4ee7c8b7-21fe-4613-8d40-bdf10f8881d0">If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answers to today’s Strands below. Check out the answers for yesterday’s puzzle <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-720-hints-and-answers-for-february-21-2026/" id="178474">here.</a></p>



<ul>
<li>PARADE</li>



<li>FLAME</li>



<li>ATHLETE</li>



<li>ANTHEM</li>



<li>FLAG</li>



<li>MEDAL</li>



<li><strong>SPANAGRAM</strong>: CLOSINGCEREMONY</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-0e0094cc-40a6-49a3-a98c-ee90172006ac">If you solved today’s Strands without our answers, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="block-44882c9d-d6a6-4e4f-9b1a-8312ae0b3036">When Is The Next Strands Game After #721?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6">All New York Times games are&nbsp;<strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before, giving players a heads-up. The game on&nbsp;<strong>February 23</strong>&nbsp;will be&nbsp;<strong>Strands Game #722.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-96ac6df0-5b63-4788-9eff-98ceece739ee">What Is Strands?</h2>



<p id="block-cde2c274-bfd9-4d27-a0d9-3ebe6f1ff7f2">Strands is a daily word search puzzle game created by The New York Times. Launched in 2024, Strands challenges players to discover a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid. The game’s original concept was developed by Juliette Seive, a research director on The New York Times Games team, with the aim of replicating Wordle’s success. Tracy Bennett serves as the puzzle editor for Strands, overseeing the creation and curation of daily puzzles since its launch.</p>



<hr>



<p id="block-9d1c4fad-eba9-422a-a628-5cb7b00aea3b">For even more Insider Gaming delivered straight to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-721-hints-and-answers-for-february-22-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlestate Head Responds to Tarkov Support Ticket in the Most Nikita Way Possible]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlestate-nikita-respond-tarkov-support-ticket/</link>
            <guid>1443049</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In case you’re not at all connected to the extraction shooter space, you should know that Nikita Buyanov, the head of the studio at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/battlestate-games/" id="1450">Battlestate Games</a>, can be a little confrontational on social media. The prolific developer, who has more than 350,000 followers on Twitter (now X) alone, has long been known for having zero filter when it comes to public-facing comments.</p>



<p>From suggestions on how to improve <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/escape-from-tarkov/" id="232">Escape from Tarkov</a> to condemnation of how Battlestate handles in-game issues, Nikita stares down hundreds of targeted posts and comments every day. Recently, one of those incoming comments was regarding a support ticket for Tarkov, which Nikita responded to in classic fashion.</p>







<h2 id="h-inflammatory-isn-t-the-word">Inflammatory Isn’t The Word</h2>



<p>On social media, Nikita Buyanov found himself, as he often does, sharing teaser clips of upcoming Escape from Tarkov updates. He often shares short mash-ups of real-world scouting, team activities, development footage, and weapons and attachments that are about to land in Escape from Tarkov, the spearhead extraction shooter game.</p>



<p>He did just that on February 21, uploading footage teasing the upcoming Tarkov event that will welcome Icebreaker to the game in a new, super-sized event.</p>



<p>In the comments, <a href="https://x.com/JborgKasper/status/2025177817642598489" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one user wrote</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I have been playing this game since 2019 and been supporting in, and im not getting the support i think i should!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Nikita, being a man of the people, took an interest in this user’s comment and asked what he needed from him. Lo and behold, a support ticket reference was handed over, and it took Nikita just an hour to deduce what was going on:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>you used radar cheat</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>The response has since racked up 150,000 impressions, many of which are the result of Nikita’s fans backing him in this very ‘Tarkov-like’ scenario. Many praised Nikita’s transparency and bagged on the original poster for exposing themselves. Shortly after, the player who posted the comment declared they’d never cheated in their lives, but it’s not hard for Battlestate to detect such activity.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Escape From Tarkov With Nikita - EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pcetkc8gq1w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Escape from Tarkov has long had a problem with cheaters, which Nikita himself has referred to as fighting a multi-headed hydra. It’s the fight of a lifetime for many multiplayer-focused developers, but Battlestate Games and Escape from Tarkov often get it in the neck more than your average studio.</p>



<p>Of course, Nikita went a bit wavy shortly after, when another user commanded him to get off Twitter and optimise Escape from Tarkov, to which <a href="https://x.com/nikgeneburn/status/2025236246625484871" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">he responded</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>don’t f***ing tell me what to do boy. i want to sit on twitter a little, before i will go and personally optimize the game</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>Nikita</em>.</p>







<p>Join us over on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> to discuss this news and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-digital-price-appears-online/">a new GTA 6 price placeholder has appeared online</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlestate-nikita-respond-tarkov-support-ticket/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Digital Price Surfaces Online At £89.99]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-digital-price-appears-online/</link>
            <guid>1443046</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Eagle-eyed gamers eager to determine the pricing structure for this year’s release of Grand Theft Auto 6 have stumbled on a digital listing for the game on Xbox. While it’s almost certainly a placeholder, the listing has the price of the standard game at £89.99, which would likely result in a $99.99 price tag in the United States.</p>



<p>It’s worth stressing that the same site also has an option to purchase a PC code for the <strong>Rockstar Games Launcher</strong>, and that version is boasting a more acceptable pricing point of £60.99, a random number indeed.</p>







<h2 id="h-placeholder-prices-are-pretty-common-for-gta-6">Placeholder Prices Are Pretty Common for GTA 6</h2>



<p>This isn’t the first proposed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/grand-theft-auto-6/" id="36">GTA 6</a> pricing point we’ve seen in recent months, and it certainly won’t be the last.</p>



<p>The latest indication regarding GTA 6’s expected price comes from Loaded, formerly CD Keys. The digital storefront has long been a purveyor of game and DLC codes for almost every major platform in the space. It’s favored heavily by PC gamers because it often offers cut-price codes, even at launch.</p>



<p>Grand Theft Auto 6 surfaced recently on the site, bearing an £89.99 tag for the Xbox version of the game, and a £60.99 tag for the <strong>PC </strong>code.</p>



<p>Right now, there’s no indication that GTA 6 will be launching on PC alongside console platforms in November. We’ve also seen <strong>no confirmation </strong>from Rockstar or Take-Two regarding the game’s price, which has long been a point of contention in the gaming space.</p>



<p>For some, this could be the most expensive ‘standard game’ ever released, with the bottom-most tier of the game running up a bill of anything from $70 to $100. If Loaded’s placeholder price is any kind of accurate, we’ll see the price edge towards the latter end of that scale.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Digging deeper into the <a href="https://www.loaded.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-pc-rockstar-games-launcher" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GTA 6 Loaded listing</a>, we can see basic descriptors about the game. There’s a summary, screenshots procured from Rockstar’s official slate, and information suggesting it will come with online multiplayer at launch.</p>



<p>It’s nothing to write home about, and you could bet safe money on this being an arbitrary placeholder, but you never know, right?</p>



<p>Case in point, Loaded also has a listing <a href="https://www.loaded.com/state-of-decay-3-pc-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">for State of Decay 3 on PC</a>, and that’s one of the most veiled games in the business right now. It was announced years ago and doesn’t have any kind of release window, but Loaded believes it’ll drop at £19.99 when it hits, which is almost <strong>definitely </strong>incorrect.</p>



<p>How much do you think GTA 6 will end up costing? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ceo-profile-one-month-old-suspicious/">the new Xbox CEO has a one-month-old Xbox account</a></p>






        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-digital-price-appears-online/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Strands #720 Hints and Answers for February 21, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-720-hints-and-answers-for-february-21-2026/</link>
            <guid>1442917</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/strands/" id="3586">Strands </a>is a daily word search puzzle game from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/new-york-times/" id="2981">The New York Times</a>. It is a relatively new game, launched in 2024, in which players seek a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid.</p>



<p>Whether it’s your first time playing or you’re a Strands veteran, today’s tips and strategies can help you find words faster. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Strands, don’t worry, below you’ll find some&nbsp;<strong>helpful hints and even the answers for Strands Game #720</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for Saturday, February 21, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-672014a9-ce75-4ea0-b98d-12b9214dbb53">To play today’s Strands,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/strands" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">head to the game’s website.</a></p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of Strands. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure id="block-5f20defe-2f05-4eb9-b880-6af2f94b324d"></figure>







<h2 id="block-e2995432-719e-4ed6-8fad-a1db37670203">How To Play Strands</h2>



<p id="block-da980997-0420-4527-946e-b66c49bf3d07">Strands is a daily word search that challenges you to find words with a common theme. There’s also a Spanagram that reveals the deeper theme behind the words.</p>



<ul id="block-d0bea02d-4b9f-4991-b9db-3b35778ff3bf">
<li>Words that are three letters and under do not count.</li>



<li>Words that reveal the correct theme appear in blue.</li>



<li>The Spanagram turns yellow when found.</li>



<li>Finding three words that don’t fit the theme will reveal a hint to help you find the proper words.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-5e597b53-af1c-4c06-a00c-6c5a4694e9e0">The goal is to string together as many words as possible. Every letter on the grid gets used! Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p id="block-cd7aaa7f-9491-4ad0-b994-72d0102c5bed">Strands can only be played on the New York Times website. You can also play on the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/crosswords/apps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NYT Games app.</a></p>



<h2 id="block-c6d4979d-f8eb-4473-a011-33019cb8da2c">Strands Hints For Today, February 21, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-23b6a5a9-2c25-47c2-a0ea-e23a99c87abd">The Strands’ answers for Game #720 are all about beer and the practice of making your own beer. This is the perfect puzzle for any microbrewers out there. This puzzle has nine answers, and I needed some help with some of them. So, if you need some guidance, just keep reading.</p>



<h3 id="block-6777813b-1426-4c21-b507-3024542b4683">General Strands Hints For February 21</h3>



<p id="block-b36e160d-6e5e-4dc8-aae9-5352ee681266">Without giving today’s Strands answers completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul id="block-5c9f7d28-537c-424b-92c3-2a9906b57178">
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;One of the answers for today’s puzzle is a basic necessity of life. Most of the Earth is comprised of this, and so are you.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> A famous song by The Archies is about this sweet ingredient.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;The Spanagram isn’t just related to brewing, but also about developing new games for old hardware and other fan projects.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-7fb794eb-0d89-4f8d-a7cf-082d0148b796">Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving&nbsp;<strong>Strands #720</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for February 21, 2026.</strong></p>







<h3 id="block-73a1d2f5-fc2b-49b7-9c10-539e38a2b946">Words to Help You Find Strand Hints for February 21, 2026</h3>



<p id="block-0853e28e-417e-4720-9526-9f2808a268be">If you want help getting started without having today’s Strands answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you unlock some in-game hints. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul id="block-2ca8fb79-d1a4-43e4-8764-e4d238a3cc97">
<li>HEAT</li>



<li>FLARE</li>



<li>MALL</li>



<li>HOPE</li>



<li>BARE</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-strands-answer-for-game-720-on-february-21-2026">Today’s Strands Answer For Game #720 On February 21, 2026</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p id="block-4ee7c8b7-21fe-4613-8d40-bdf10f8881d0">If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answers to today’s Strands below. </p>



<ul>
<li>WHEAT</li>



<li>BARLEY</li>



<li>MALT</li>



<li>WATER</li>



<li>SUGAR</li>



<li>HOPS</li>



<li>YEAST</li>



<li>FLAVOR</li>



<li><strong>SPANAGRAM</strong>: HOMEBREW</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-0e0094cc-40a6-49a3-a98c-ee90172006ac">If you solved today’s Strands without our answers, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="block-44882c9d-d6a6-4e4f-9b1a-8312ae0b3036">When Is The Next Strands Game After #720?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6">All New York Times games are&nbsp;<strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before, giving players a heads-up. The game on&nbsp;<strong>February 22</strong>&nbsp;will be&nbsp;<strong>Strands Game #721.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-96ac6df0-5b63-4788-9eff-98ceece739ee">What Is Strands?</h2>



<p id="block-cde2c274-bfd9-4d27-a0d9-3ebe6f1ff7f2">Strands is a daily word search puzzle game created by The New York Times. Launched in 2024, Strands challenges players to discover a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid. The game’s original concept was developed by Juliette Seive, a research director on The New York Times Games team, with the aim of replicating Wordle’s success. Tracy Bennett serves as the puzzle editor for Strands, overseeing the creation and curation of daily puzzles since its launch.</p>



<hr>



<p id="block-9d1c4fad-eba9-422a-a628-5cb7b00aea3b">For even more Insider Gaming delivered straight to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-720-hints-and-answers-for-february-21-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox CEO’s Profile is One Month Old and Shows ‘Suspicious’ Behaviour]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ceo-profile-one-month-old-suspicious/</link>
            <guid>1442896</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Internet sleuths have busied themselves digging into Asha Sharma’s Xbox profile, which was revealed by the new Xbox CEO herself on social media. Sharma, who has assumed the role after Phil Spencer suddenly <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-retires-from-xbox-sarah-bond-resigns/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced his retirement</a>, seemingly created her Xbox account just one month ago, and since then, has racked up more than 10,000 Gamerscore across a variety of games.</p>



<p>The problem is, the pseudo-detectives analysing Sharma’s profile have uncovered some strange behaviour, such as hitting 100% in Firewatch and Ball x Pit, the latter of which she played 43 hours in a single week. She has also unlocked rare achievements in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/minecraft/" id="442" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Minecraft</a> and has bounced between ‘random games’ at what must be an extremely busy time for her.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-asha-sharma-s-xbox-account-fake">Is Asha Sharma’s Xbox Account <em>Fake</em>?</h2>



<p>The leading assumption is that <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/play/user/AMRAHSAHSA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sharma’s Xbox account</a> is being artificially boosted to secure more ‘validity’ amongst the gamers sceptical of her new role as the CEO of Xbox. Fans have theorized that the account is being buffed by scores of achievements that can be unlocked easily, and in Minecraft, especially, certain tricks (such as achievement servers) are being used to tick more boxes.</p>



<p>This is conjecture, but <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/2025293858238525759" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">some things don’t entirely add up</a>.</p>



<p>For instance, in the month leading up to her announcement as Xbox CEO, Sharma pulled in more than 10,000 Gamerscore across games like Halo, Forza, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/fallout/" id="311">Fallout</a>, and, most recently, Borderlands. It was <strong>also </strong>noted that many of the games Sharma is playing are the bulk of Xbox’s biggest brands, which could be another attempt to ‘legitimize’ her assignment.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It appears, from the first Xbox Achievement unlocked by the profile, that the account was started on January 15, little more than four weeks before Sharma officially became the CEO of Xbox. We can also see the account’s friends list, which is very small but includes the likes of Stein, Senior Social Media Manager at Xbox, and, of course, Phil ‘P3’ Spencer.</p>



<p>With the mention of Phil Spencer, it’s worth pointing out that, after Sharma revealed her Gamertag, she almost admitted that she’d ‘just started touching games’. One user accused her of doing just that, and she <a href="https://x.com/asha_shar/status/2025262170339168355" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">simply replied</a> with, ‘I am no XboxP3’ (a reference to Phil Spencer).</p>



<p>When asked if the account was represented by some AI construct, <a href="https://x.com/asha_shar/status/2025269135517917261" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sharma wrote</a>, ‘Beep Boop Beep Boop.’ She also explained that her ‘favorite games’ are Halo, Valheim, and Goldeneye. </p>



<p>In a comment, a user explained how Borderlands 2 is a solid recommendation, and <a href="https://x.com/asha_shar/status/2025266343143243917" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sharma assured them</a> she’d try the game ‘today’. Lo and behold, an hour after that comment was made, the Xbox account had started playing Borderlands 2:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It could be a nothingburger, at the end of the day. It’s no big secret that something of a witch hunt started immediately after the news was dropped regarding these major Xbox changes.</p>



<p>Many accused Satya Nadella, Microsoft’s CEO, of being a puppet master, while others cried nepotism. With Sharma’s background being rooted most recently in AI and showing no signs of gaming experience, the new CEO was always going to be an easy target for die-hard gamers.</p>



<p>Of course, it could also be Sharma making a dedicated, determined effort to bone up on the products she’s going to be spearheading now that she’s the CEO of Xbox. It’s not hard to paint this in a positive light. Perhaps she had a month to grind games ahead of going hard on the job.</p>



<p>It’s easy to see some watching this Xbox profile like a hawk to see what unravels.</p>







<p>Do you think Asha Sharma’s Xbox profile is legit, and she has cranked out the hours in the last month to rack up the Gamerscore? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-vehicles-improved-testing-labs/">Battlefield 6 will get vehicle improvements</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-ceo-profile-one-month-old-suspicious/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>