<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:31:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another NetEase Studio, Bad Brain Games, Is Shutting Down After Two Years]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/another-netease-studio-shutting-down/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-netease-studio-bad-brain-games-is-shutting-down-after-two-years.1345687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>NetEase is shutting down yet another studio that was working on a game that, likely, won’t see a release. In a post on social media, studio head Sean Crooks announced that Bad Brain Game Studios will be closing its doors on November 17 after the parent company pulled funding. </p>



<p>That just so happens to be the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netease-is-closing-one-of-its-studios-after-just-two-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">same day as another NetEase studio</a>, Fantastic Pixel Castle, will be closed.</p>



<p>In his <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/bad-brain-game-studios_midnight-riders-sizzle-reel-activity-7391949948268834817-2Wyf?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAe8N2cBgr8yAdDlzNawvOXeqb-JdsGiQC4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post on LinkedIn</a>, Crooks said that the closure comes despite “best efforts” to find a new partner for the studio and its game.</p>



<div><p><strong>“Our team poured everything into this journey — pushing creative and technical boundaries every day with passion, imagination, and craft,”</strong> he said. <strong>“What we achieved together stands as lasting proof of this team’s extraordinary talent.</strong></p><p><strong>“The enthusiastic response our project has received is a direct reflection of that creativity and dedication. While the outcome may not be what we had hoped for, I’ve seen firsthand that we succeeded in reaching players and peers who believed in what we were building. To those who supported the game, shared encouragement, and championed our vision — thank you.”</strong></p></div>



<p>Bad Brain Game Studios was formed in May 2023 with Crooks, who was a producer on games like Watch Dogs: Legion, at the helm. The studio has been working on a game known as Midnight Riders, which was set to be open world action-adventure game with a 1980’s aesthetic. You can check out the game’s sizzle reel below, courtesy of Crooks.</p>



<figure><video controls="" src="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/output_progressive_4714c307-c825-4d16-903e-878b11680d13.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>For those interested, Crooks’ full statement can be found below, as well.</p>



<h2 id="h-sean-crooks-full-statement-on-bad-brain-game-studios">Sean Crooks Full Statement On Bad Brain Game Studios</h2>



<blockquote>
<div><p>An Update on Bad Brain Game Studios</p><p>It’s with a heavy heart that we share that Bad Brain Game Studios will be closing its doors. Our last official day of operation will be on November 17th.</p><p>Despite our continuing efforts to seek a new partner for the project, a path forward has yet to materialize. We are deeply grateful to NetEase Games for their support and for giving us runway to explore every possible opportunity. Our team poured everything into this journey — pushing creative and technical boundaries every day with passion, imagination, and craft. What we achieved together stands as lasting proof of this team’s extraordinary talent.</p><p>The enthusiastic response our project has received is a direct reflection of that creativity and dedication. While the outcome may not be what we had hoped for, I’ve seen firsthand that we succeeded in reaching players and peers who believed in what we were building. To those who supported the game, shared encouragement, and championed our vision — thank you.</p><p>As we close this chapter,&nbsp;the game and its underlying IP is still available for acquisition or partnership, and we/NetEase are open to discussions with publishers or studios who see potential in continuing its development. We believe strongly in what was created, and would love to see this world find its way to players.</p><p>To help support our people as they take their next steps, we’ll also be releasing a sizzle reel from the project publicly, giving everyone the chance to showcase their incredible work and open doors to new opportunities.</p><p>If you’re looking for world-class developers, artists, and storytellers, please reach out — we would be proud to connect you with them.</p><p>Finally, I want to extend my deepest gratitude once again to everyone who supported us along the way. Your encouragement and belief in what we were building meant the world to us. While this chapter is ending sooner than we had hoped, the spirit of what we created at Bad Brain will live on through the incredible people who made it possible.</p><p>Sean Crooks<br>Studio Head</p></div>
</blockquote>



<p>What do you think of NetEase shutting down another studio like Bad Brain Game Studios? Leave your thoughts down in the comments and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/square-enix-wants-ai-to-handle-70-of-qa-within-two-years/">Square Enix wanting 70% of QA and debugging</a> to be done by AI within two years. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/another-netease-studio-shutting-down/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>