<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 11:57:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws Switch 2 Port Reportedly Performed ‘Poorly’ Ahead of Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-reportedly-performed-poorly-ahead-of-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-reportedly-performed-%E2%80%98poorly%E2%80%99-ahead-of-launch.1285533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Star Wars Outlaws is scheduled to release for the Switch 2 on September 4, 2025, and just days ahead of launch, the game’s performance might not be up to standard. </p>



<p>Star Wars Outlaws for the Nintendo Switch 2 was announced during the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Partner Showcase</a> on July 31. Outlaws will be the first Ubisoft game to arrive for the new console. However, a new report reveals that the game’s performance is not the best, even with the release less than a week away.</p>



<h2 id="h-star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-framerate-dropped-several-times-below-30fps">Star Wars Outlaws Switch 2 Framerate Dropped Several Times Below 30FPS</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://gamerant.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-version-performance-issues-low-frame-rate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GameRant</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A5JbnfU0SVs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GVG</a> was present at PAX West 2025, where they were able to try Star Wars Outlaws for the Switch 2. Their new YouTube video states that Nintendo had all the games from Gamescom 2025 on display at PAX West 2025, with the only exception being Star Wars Outlaws. They were able to test the Star Wars Outlaws at this event, but were not allowed to capture any gameplay footage of the demo version.</p>



<p>GVG was not allowed even to have over-the-shoulder cameras to record footage; the only option was to play it and discuss it. Once, they played Star Wars Outlaws on the Switch 2, and it was evident that the performance was “kind of rough.” The video adds that Star Wars Outlaws runs “pretty poorly on the Switch 2.” </p>



<p>The demo only featured close sequences that included a Star Destroyer and a space fight. No open-world sequences were available, and even in the closed sequences, the framerate dropped below 30fps several times. The video clarifies that there was no way to analyse the drops as no footage was recorded, but the drops felt significant. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Star Wars Outlaws isn't Great on Switch 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A5JbnfU0SVs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, the Star Wars Jedi main character is making his <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-jedi-character-is-making-his-tv-debut-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TV debut next month</a>. Also, Ubisoft cancelled a Star Wars Outlaws sequel “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-cancelled-star-wars-outlaws-sequel-early/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">very, very early</a>.” What are your thoughts on Star Wars Outlaws Switch 2 port performing poorly ahead of launch? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-direct-will-take-place-in-september-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new claim that states a Nintendo Direct is planned for the second week of September</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-reportedly-performed-poorly-ahead-of-launch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Direct Will Take Place In September, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-direct-will-take-place-in-september-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-direct-will-take-place-in-september-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1285515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A reliable source has claimed that a Nintendo Direct is scheduled for the second week of September 2025. </p>



<p>The last Nintendo Direct was hosted in July 2025, and it was a partner showcase that featured 25 minutes of announcements from Nintendo’s publishing partners. Since then, SwitchForce has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rumors-of-the-next-nintendo-direct-pick-up-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed</a> that another Nintendo Direct showcase is planned for the second week of September, and another insider has just corroborated the information. </p>



<h2 id="h-the-next-nintendo-direct-should-arrive-in-the-second-week-of-september">The Next Nintendo Direct Should Arrive in the Second Week of September</h2>



<p>The corroboration about September’s Nintendo Direct comes from the reliable leaker, NateTheHate, through his latest post on <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1962214416339833244" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter). Nate has stated, “Yes, there is a Nintendo Direct in September.” The insider added that it will be held in the “second week of the month”. And, it would be “in the latter half on or around Sept 11 or 12th.” </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Yes, there is a Nintendo Direct in September. </p><p>When: The second week of the month, in the latter half on or around Sept 11 or 12th.</p></div>— NateTheHate2 (@NateTheHate2) <a href="https://twitter.com/NateTheHate2/status/1962214416339833244?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In the same thread, a user has also asked whether the Red Dead Redemption 2 Switch 2 port will be announced at this direct. To which Nate responded, stating, “Maybe? Depends if Nintendo was able to court Rockstar.” The insider added that RDR2’s Switch 2 port is “bound regardless of announcement/reveal venue.” </p>



<p>It is hard to tell which games will be at this event, but we have several Switch 2 titles releasing in the October/November period, including Pokémon Legends: Z-A, Kirby Air Riders, Borderlands 4, Little Nightmares III, and more. Regardless, players should take the information about the Switch 2 Direct with a grain of salt as it doesn’t come from an official source. </p>



<p>In other news, Cyberpunk 2077 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-sold-more-physical-copies-on-nintendo-switch-2-than-digital/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold more physical copies</a> on the Nintendo Switch 2 than digital. Also, Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade will release for the Switch 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-intergrade-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in 2025</a>. What are your thoughts on a Nintendo Direct arriving in the second week of September? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-free-look-weapon-mechanic-appears-youtubers-wild/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s weapon ‘free look’ mechanic</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-direct-will-take-place-in-september-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Borderlands 4 Have Early Access?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-borderlands-4-have-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-borderlands-4-have-early-access.1285470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>September is stacked full of huge releases, and Borderlands 4 is undoubtedly one of the biggest, so we’ve got the details on whether you can dive into the game ahead of others with early access.</p>



<p>Releasing September 12, Borderlands 4 caught our eye in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-preview-reveal-harlowe-demo-exclusive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hands-on preview at Gamescom</a>, and Gearbox CEO Randy Pitchford has high hopes for the game, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-randy-pitchford-100-million-units-borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predicting over 100m sales</a>.</p>



<p>If you can’t contain your excitement for Borderlands 4 and want to know whether there is any way to jump the queue and play early, we’ve got all the details.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-borderlands-4-with-early-access">Can You Play Borderlands 4 With Early Access?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Landing with a bang. Image via Gearbox</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, there are not any early access options for Borderlands 4. As such, the release date and time are the same for everyone.</strong></p>



<p>While many other games adopt an early-access stance, often as a pre-order bonus for a higher-priced edition of the game, neither the Deluxe Edition nor the Super Deluxe Edition of <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/en-GB/borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Borderlands 4</a> provide this incentive.</p>



<p>However, store listings for Borderlands 4 indicate the game will be <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-release-date-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staggered global release at midnight local time</a>, excluding Steam, so the doors won’t open for everyone at the same time.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-there-any-way-to-play-borderlands-4-early">Is There Any Way to Play Borderlands 4 Early?</h2>



<p><strong>Although there are no early access options for Borderlands 4, you may be able to play early by adjusting your time zone on your console.</strong></p>



<p>Xbox players have the easiest approach for the New Zealand trick, requiring only a change in location settings and restarting the console. With this approach, players will be able to play Borderlands 4 when the game launches in New Zealand, hours before the release time in their time zone.</p>



<p>PlayStation players can also take advantage of this approach, though it’s harder to do and potentially more costly. In order to play early on New Zealand, you must have a New Zealand account and purchase the game from the store in that region. However, you might not be able to transfer your save date over to your main account, so be careful.</p>



<p>Unfortunately for PC players, there’s no New Zealand trick and the Steam release, unlike on console, is set to be global at a set time. On the bright side, this does mean everyone on PC will start playing at the same time.</p>



<p>Which version of Borderlands 4 have you pre-ordered? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Borderlands 4, take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Pass status of the title</a>, and read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-randy-pitchford-more-involvement-now-you-see-me-borderlands-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Randy Pitchford’s involvement in the game</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/does-borderlands-4-have-early-access/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Weapon ‘Free Look’ Mechanic Will Have YouTubers Running Wild]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-free-look-weapon-mechanic-appears-youtubers-wild/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-weapon-%E2%80%98free-look%E2%80%99-mechanic-will-have-youtubers-running-wild.1285407/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>This weekend, videos emerged on social media showcasing Battlefield 6’s new ‘free look’ mechanic that allows users to examine their weapons from almost any angle. While holding the weapon, players can twist, tip, and turn the gun in any direction to get a better look at the weapon’s minute details, and it’s an element that’s going to have content creators running wild.</p>



<p>In almost every first-person shooter space, the most common thing for YouTubers to do for ‘thumbnails’ is to look up, reload, and capture a screenshot to showcase a weapon. It seems Electronic Arts’ studios are aware of this and have added a neat feature to add a little more diversity to the pot.</p>



<h2 id="h-get-creative-in-battlefield-6">Get Creative in Battlefield 6</h2>



<p>Some YouTubers are worse than others at this, but for years, the running theme has been the old ‘look-up-and-reload’ trick. It has served as the basis for FPS-based thumbnails on YouTube for the longest time, regardless of whether we’re talking about Battlefield, Call of Duty, Rainbow Six, Escape from Tarkov, or something in between.</p>



<p>The studios piecing together Battlefield 6 have tried to take that concept a step further, adding in a free look mechanic that allows players to actively manipulate how their weapon is being held.</p>



<p>A video surfaced on social media recently, perfectly showcasing this new mechanic:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Don't know if this was in the beta but you can inspect your gun and it's some kind of free look inspect, where your right stick will move the gun around <a href="https://t.co/b7SrCMGY2P">pic.twitter.com/b7SrCMGY2P</a></p>— bob. (@BobNetworkUK) <a href="https://twitter.com/BobNetworkUK/status/1961417910229897219?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>It wasn’t present in the Battlefield 6 beta, but it has been added now for the next round of Battlefield Labs tests. As you can see in the video above, it’s a pretty fluid, functional mechanic that screenshot lovers will adore, giving them much more accessibility in the thumbnail space.</p>



<p>I’m just excited that we might start to see <strong>differences emerge </strong>between YouTubers and the incessant reload-trick thumbs they’re uploading with each new video.</p>



<p>Are you excited to play with this feature in Battlefield 6? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/left-4-dead-coded-shooter-coming-from-game-creator/">new Left 4 Dead-style shooter is coming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-free-look-weapon-mechanic-appears-youtubers-wild/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Left 4 Dead Coded Shooter is Coming From The Game’s Creator]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/left-4-dead-coded-shooter-coming-from-game-creator/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-left-4-dead-coded-shooter-is-coming-from-the-game%E2%80%99s-creator.1285404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Mike Booth, the creator of Left 4 Dead, has emerged on social media to reveal he’s piecing together an all-new four-player co-operative shooter that is ‘built on the foundations of what made L4D special.’ He promoted an application process inviting prospective fans to jump into the project as playtesters, giving an indication of how far along the game’s development is.</p>



<p>Booth boasts a storied tenure in the games industry, but he’s currently at Bad Robot Games, which has links to JJ Abrams, best known for his work in the film and television industries.</p>



<h2 id="h-teamwork-tension-and-replayability">‘Teamwork, Tension, and Replayability’</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/l4d2/comments/1n3jvu3/from_the_creator_of_l4d/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">In a post</a> on the Left 4 Dead 2 Reddit channel, Mike Booth surfaced to promote his new game, but didn’t drop a title or any graphics.</p>



<p>He wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I’m Mike Booth (creator of Left 4 Dead), and I’m excited to share that I’m working on a brand new project —a 4-player co-op shooter built on the foundations of what made L4D special.</p>



<p>If you enjoyed the teamwork, tension, and replayability of my past games, you’ll probably find this one interesting. It expands on the co-op formula in ways I’ve wanted to explore for a long time.</p>



<p>We’re still in the early stages of development, but we’re opening up playtests to a limited number of players. If you’re interested in joining us on this next adventure and helping shape the game early on, we’d love to have you involved.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/left-4-deads-creator-is-making-a-comeback-to-create-the-next-big-co-op-shooter-3244290/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dexerto</a> for the spot)</em></p>



<p>The comment section exploded with excitement as users realized that it could be a spiritual successor to the franchise that effectively died a death in 2009 when Left 4 Dead 2 was released and promptly marked <strong>the end </strong>of the series.</p>



<p>In 2021, Back 4 Blood was released by Turtle Rock Studios, but despite being marketed as a twisted successor to Left 4 Dead, it fell flat on its face relatively quickly.</p>



<p>Coincidentally, Mike Booth was working at Turtle Rock more than a decade ago, before leaving for Blizzard. That post eventually fell through, and Booth <a href="https://x.com/_MikeBooth/status/627164439788138497" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">confirmed on social media</a> that his project ‘wasn’t a good fit’ for Blizzard.</p>



<p>There’s definitely room for another Left 4 Dead-coded game, but will Mike Booth deliver from his position at Bad Robot? It’s worth stressing that at no point does Booth mention <strong>zombies</strong>, but you never know.</p>



<p>Let me know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a> if you’re excited for this game.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-no-ray-tracing-might-not-get-it/">Battlefield 6 might not get ray tracing for a while</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/left-4-dead-coded-shooter-coming-from-game-creator/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>