<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:45:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[666 Players Can Buy DOOM on a Limited Edition Box That Plays DOOM]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/666-players-can-buy-doom-on-a-limited-edition-box-that-plays-doom/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/666-players-can-buy-doom-on-a-limited-edition-box-that-plays-doom.1163658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/666-players-can-buy-doom-on-a-limited-edition-box-that-plays-doom/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new DOOM 1 and DOOM 2 Edition from Limited Run Games could be the best yet. It’s become a running joke over the years to see what DOOM can run on. Now, it literally runs in a box, and only 666 people have the chance to secure this incredible bundle.</p>



<p>I’ve seen <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-can-run-the-original-doom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DOOM played in Fortnite</a>, on fridges and calculators, and I’m sure someone’s probably got it to work on a pencil at this point. DOOM is considered the father of first-person shooters (shout out to Wolfenstein too), and its impact is still being felt in 2025.</p>



<p>It’s not just old DOOM games either. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages-pc-specifications/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DOOM The Dark Ages</a> is one of the biggest games of 2025. But if you can’t wait, you might need to fight off Imps, Cacodemons, and people if you want to secure Limited Run Games’ DOOM Will It Run Edition.</p>



<h2 id="h-limited-edition-doom-will-it-run-is-very-limited">Limited-Edition DOOM “Will It Run?” is Very Limited</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You get so much cool stuff. Credit to Limited Run Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>Limited Run Games is doing a special DOOM 1 and DOOM 2 collection of the two original games lumped together in one physical package. It’s great for collectors and people who want to buy DOOM again for the umpteenth time.</p>



<p>If you want more, the Big Box Edition comes with Cassette Tapes and Trading Cards. But you’re here for the big gun, and the <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/products/doom-doom-ii-will-it-run-edition-switch-ps5-xbox-pc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Will It Run Edition</a> comes inside a giant box in the style of an old-school DOOM door.</p>



<p><strong>It’s $666.66 and is limited to the first 666 people who buy it!</strong></p>



<p>This demonic deal includes the following content:</p>



<ul>
<li>DOOM + DOOM II Game*</li>



<li>Box that Plays DOOM</li>



<li>Two Piece Big Box</li>



<li>Cassette Tape Soundtrack Set with Slipcase
<ul>
<li>Includes Base Soundtrack and full IDFKR Soundtrack&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Floating Cacodemon – on Magnetic Base
<ul>
<li>3’ Cacodemon with 5’ Base</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Handheld Cacodemon – Plays DOOM</li>



<li>Trading Card Pack includes five random cards</li>



<li>Certificate of Authenticity&nbsp;</li>



<li><em>*PC Edition includes Digital Steam Code</em></li>
</ul>



<p>The “Box that Plays DOOM” is easily the best feature. It’s tongue-in-cheek, it’s a remarkable piece of memorabilia in its own right, and it is a must-have for hardened DOOM fans.</p>



<hr>



<p>Will you be picking up any of these new Editions from Limited Run Games? Head to our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a> to let us know. Also, subscribe to our weekly newsletter so you don’t miss out on cool news that isn’t all DOOM and gloom.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2s Manufactured in China Reportedly Subject to 145% US Tariff]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2s-manufactured-in-china-reportedly-subject-to-145-us-tariff/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2s-manufactured-in-china-reportedly-subject-to-145-us-tariff.1163631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2s-manufactured-in-china-reportedly-subject-to-145-us-tariff/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-110644">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>According to a new report, Nintendo Switch 2 units manufactured in China will face a 145% US import tariff.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-switch-2s-from-china-could-face-145-us-tariff">Nintendo Switch 2s From China Could Face 145% US Tariff</h2>



<p><a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Technology/China-made-Nintendo-Switch-2-in-line-for-145-tariff-hit-supplier-warns" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Nikkei Asia</a> (via <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1jywikr/chinamade_nintendo_switch_2_in_line_for_145/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Zukhov-74</a>) reports that the Nintendo Switch 2 and other game consoles manufactured in China will fall victim to “the trade war between the world’s two biggest economies.” They recently reviewed an “internal assessment memo” from a “major Apple and Nintendo supplier,” and things don’t seem bright for Nintendo’s upcoming console.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The memo states that game consoles manufactured in China will still face the 145% US import tariff for goods made in China. This means the Nintendo Switch 2s from China are “in line for a massive hit.” This could be one reason why the company decided to delay pre-orders, as it wanted to “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-delays-switch-2-preorders-in-us-due-to-trump-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">assess the potential impact</a>” of the tariffs on the US market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report adds that a significant chunk of Nintendo Switch 2 consoles “are made in China” and a “relatively small proportion made in Vietnam.” Hence, it will be hard for the company to manoeuvre through such circumstances. This might also explain why pre-orders for the upcoming console have been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-delayed-in-canada/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed in Canada</a> at the last minute.&nbsp;However, there’s no official word from Nintendo at the moment.</p>



<p>In other news, Nintendo Switch 2 pre-order invites will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-invites/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">begin rolling out next month</a>. Also, ‘Breath of the Wild’ and its upcoming DLC cost <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/breath-of-the-wild-and-its-dlc-is-90-on-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$90 on the upcoming console</a>. What are your thoughts on China-made Nintendo Switch 2 consoles facing a 145% US tariff hit? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands director blaming COVID and Zoom calls for the movie’s failure</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/some-of-schedule-1s-popular-mods-include-malware/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/some-of-schedule-1s-popular-mods-include-malware/">
                                Some of Schedule 1’s Popular Mods Include Malware                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>An urgent PSA has surfaced, warning players about malware in some of Schedule 1’s popular mods. Here are more details.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/">
                                Borderlands Director Blames COVID and Zoom Calls for Movie’s Failure                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Borderlands director, Eli Roth, has stated that COVID and Zoom Calls were the reasons why the movie failed. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-warzone-range-single-keycap/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-warzone-range-single-keycap/">
                                Corsair’s Warzone Range Includes a Single Keycap Worth $79                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Corsair Warzone range is attractive enough, but real fans will want to secure the single keycap with a $79 price tag.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-open-world-survival-game-bears-history/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-open-world-survival-game-bears-history/">
                                New Open-World Survival Game Lets You Befriend Bears and Play With History                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>This new survival shooter from a two-person team in Japan is a little bizarre and very ambitious, but what’s it all about?</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some of Schedule 1’s Popular Mods Include Malware]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/some-of-schedule-1s-popular-mods-include-malware/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-of-schedule-1%E2%80%99s-popular-mods-include-malware.1163538/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/some-of-schedule-1s-popular-mods-include-malware/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-110620">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Schedule 1 players have been warned about malware in some of the game’s most popular mods.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/certain-schedule-1-mods-confirmed-to-contain-trojan-malware/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TheGamer</a>, the official Schedule 1 <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Schedule_I/comments/1jx6vl8/urgent_psa_malware_found_in_2_popular_schedule_1/?share_id=AvZ_njVPdRrRpo99mWvCM&amp;utm_content=2&amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;utm_name=ioscss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">subreddit</a> has released an “URGENT PSA” for its members, bringing their attention to malware found in popular mods. Players have been advised to uninstall these mods instantly, or they could get in trouble.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-schedule-1-mods-that-were-found-with-malware">Schedule 1 Mods That Were Found with Malware</h2>



<p>The first Schedule 1 Mod found with malware is Froggyp1’s “Increased Stack Size Limit.” The subreddit moderator has confirmed that the original creator has sold their account, and the new owner has introduced a version “which is VERIFIED to be a trojan.” The owner has been banned, and their malicious uploads removed; however, players should look through their files to be sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The next Schedule 1 mod in question is “Backpack Mod Reupload,” and this time, even NexusMods have confirmed that it is malware. After deleting the files and changing their passwords, players can take two suggested actions: First, they can use reputable anti-virus or anti-malware software to search individual files for malware. The other way is to use online virus scanning services.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, the creator of Schedule 1 has provided <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/schedule-1-creator-gives-console-port-update-after-imitations-appear-on-playstation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a console port update</a> after imitations appeared on PlayStation. Also, its recent update added <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/schedule-1-april-7-update-adds-pawn-shop-boutique/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a Pawn Shop and a Boutique</a>. What are your thoughts on Schedule 1 Mods featuring malware? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands director blaming COVID and Zoom calls for the movie’s failure</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/">
                                Borderlands Director Blames COVID and Zoom Calls for Movie’s Failure                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Borderlands director, Eli Roth, has stated that COVID and Zoom Calls were the reasons why the movie failed. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-warzone-range-single-keycap/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-warzone-range-single-keycap/">
                                Corsair’s Warzone Range Includes a Single Keycap Worth $79                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Corsair Warzone range is attractive enough, but real fans will want to secure the single keycap with a $79 price tag.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-open-world-survival-game-bears-history/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-open-world-survival-game-bears-history/">
                                New Open-World Survival Game Lets You Befriend Bears and Play With History                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>This new survival shooter from a two-person team in Japan is a little bizarre and very ambitious, but what’s it all about?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-to-increase-ps5-price-in-europe-australia-and-new-zealand/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-to-increase-ps5-price-in-europe-australia-and-new-zealand/">
                                Sony To Increase PS5 Price In Europe, Australia, And New Zealand                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced a price increase for the PlayStation 5 (PS5) in a number of regions including the United Kingdom and Europe.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands Director Blames COVID and Zoom Calls for Movie’s Failure]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movie%E2%80%99s-failure.1163532/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-director-blames-covid-and-zoom-calls-for-movies-failure/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Borderlands director has stated that the movie flopped because of COVID, as you can’t create a large-scale movie on Zoom Calls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During an appearance on <a href="https://puck.news/podcast_episode/director-eli-roth-will-kill-you-on-screen-for-1-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Town</a> podcast (via <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/movies-tv/eli-roth-on-why-the-borderlands-movie-sucked-you-cant-prep-a-movie-on-that-scale-over-zoom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PCGamer</a>), Borderlands director Eli Roth elaborated on how COVID and Zoom Calls hindered the movie’s development. Roth explained that none of them could have predicted “how complicated things were gonna be with COVID,” and the complications became visible not just while shooting but in other processes.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-borderlands-movie-failed-due-to-covid-and-zoom">Borderlands Movie Failed Due to COVID and Zoom</h2>



<p>Roth added that it was total chaos for them, having to do reshoots and pick-up shoots, having six people across different sets, and having each one shut down when a city opened up. More complications were added when there was a COVID outbreak in the area, which meant they “couldn’t prep in a room together,” meet their stunt people or do any pre-visualisation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Roth concludes, “ You can’t prep a movie on that scale over Zoom”. They thought that they would be able to pull off Borderlands with COVID and Zoom calls; instead, Roth explains, “We got our asses handed to us a bit.”</p>



<p>Borderlands movie had a disappointing release, standing at 10% on the Tomatometer on Rotten Tomatoes. Fans were highly disappointed with the deviation from the source material and some of the casting choices for their favourite characters. However, it wasn’t all bad, as Take-Two’s CEO recently stated that the movie <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-says-borderlands-movie-disappointing-but-helped-sell-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">helped sell games</a> even though it was ‘disappointing’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Borderlands 4 is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-4-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coming to Nintendo Switch 2</a> in 2025. What are your thoughts on the Borderlands director blaming COVID and Zoom calls for the movie’s failure? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-open-world-survival-game-bears-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the new open-world survival game that lets you befriend bears and play with history</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>