<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:15:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Won’t Launch on Nintendo Switch 2, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-wont-launch-on-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-won%E2%80%99t-launch-on-nintendo-switch-2-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1270968/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 won’t be landing on Nintendo Switch 2 at launch, though that doesn’t mean the door is closed to the platform permanently, according to a new report.</p>



<p>Set to be officially revealed at Gamescom’s Opening Night Live, Black Ops 7 will launch in November, once again part of the Xbox Game Pass catalog, but Nintendo Switch 2 players will miss out initially.</p>



<p>Though the improved performance of the Switch 2 has opened the door for releases on the platform for the likes of Cyberpunk 2077 and Star Wars Outlaws, Black Ops 7 won’t be joining them in November.</p>



<h2 id="h-unclear-whether-activision-plans-black-ops-7-on-switch-2-in-future">Unclear Whether Activision Plans Black Ops 7 on Switch 2 in Future</h2>



<figure><figcaption>No arrival yet. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p>A new report from <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/non-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ne-sera-pas-disponible-sur-la-nintendo-switch-2-a-sa-sortie-60383" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dealabs</a> confirms that Black Ops 7 will not arrive on Switch 2 when it launches in November, instead landing on PC, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PlayStation 4, and PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>Crucially, though, the report says it’s “unclear whether Activision plans a future port” to Switch 2 in the future, so it’s not known yet whether the door has been closed entirely for Switch 2. Earlier this year, Activision told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-says-its-working-with-nintendo-to-get-call-of-duty-on-switch-but-will-black-ops-7-be-on-switch-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IGN</a> they were “committed to getting the franchise on Switch.”</p>



<p>Nintendo has not had a Call of Duty game on its platform since the release of Call of Duty: Ghosts on the Wii U in 2013, and, if that barren run is to come to an end with Black Ops 7, players will have to wait a while longer after the release date.</p>



<p>Should Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 come to Nintendo Switch 2 in the future? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/3312/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Call of Duty news, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-avalon-map-campaign/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive report of the Black Ops 7 campaign and multiplayer merging</a> with a 32-player mode, and read about beliefs that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-and-call-of-duty-complement-each-other-says-developer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield and Call of Duty franchises “complement each other.</a>“</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-wont-launch-on-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony—Date & Times, How to Watch, & What to Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony-date-times-how-to-watch-what-to-expect/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony%E2%80%94date-times-how-to-watch-what-to-expect.1270935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The biggest weekend in the Pokémon calendar is here with the World Championships 2025 taking place in Anaheim, which of course means a closing ceremony that could bring plenty of news. Here are all the details.</p>



<p>Pokémon is set for a big year in the next 12 months with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release of Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> edging ever closer and 2026 marking the franchise’s 30th anniversary, which is expected to include the long-awaited release of Generation 10. Could we see some news and hints in Anaheim?</p>



<p>Whatever Pokémon has up its sleeves to showcase at the closing ceremony, you don’t want to miss it, so here’s everything you need to know.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony">When is the Pokémon World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Californiacation. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Pokémon</strong> <strong>World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony takes place on Sunday, August 17. As the name implies, it brings the event in Anaheim to a close.</strong></p>



<p>Action in Anaheim for the Pokémon World Championships 2025 begins on Friday, marking the start of three days of action from the TCG, VGC, and everything else in between.</p>



<p>The closing ceremony in previous events has featured news about upcoming titles and releases, so it should not be missed by fans.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-time-is-the-pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony">What Time is the Pokémon World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony?</h2>



<p><strong>The Pokémon</strong> <strong>World Championships Closing Ceremony begins at 7:00 pm PDT, meaning a late night for anyone on the east coast of the United States or elsewhere in the world.</strong></p>



<p>It is expected to begin bang on schedule, though it could be delayed if any of the finals earlier in the day run longer than planned. </p>



<p>Here’s an easier way to see the start times for the closing ceremony in your timezone.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">19:00</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">21:00</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">22:00</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">British Summer Time (BST)</td><td data-align="center">03:00 (Aug. 18)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Standard Time (AEST)</td><td data-align="center">12:00 (Aug. 18)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-to-watch-the-pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony">How to Watch The Pokémon World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony</h2>



<p><strong>The Closing Ceremony at the Pokémon</strong> <strong>World Championships 2025 will be broadcast live online through multiple platforms, including directly on the Pokémon</strong> <strong>website, on Twitch, and on YouTube.</strong></p>



<p>In our experience, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/pokemon" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Twitch</a> is the best place to watch as the streams are slightly ahead of other platforms, so tune in here if you don’t want to see any spoilers. All the big announcements will also be shared on social media.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-to-expect-from-the-pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony">What to Expect From The Pokémon World Championships 2025 Closing Ceremony</h2>



<p><strong>Previous announcements at the Pokémon World Championships Closing Ceremony</strong> <strong>have included details for upcoming releases across games and the physical TCG, as well as news on future World Championship events.</strong></p>



<p>The Closing Ceremony almost always announces the location of the following World Championships, though there will be no such reveal for 2026 as we already know the World Championships are heading to San Francisco next year. That announcement was made in Honolulu last year.</p>



<p>We could see more reveals for the Pokémon TCG, with last year revealing the return of Trainer’s Pokémon to the game, but all eyes will be cast towards Pokémon Legends: Z-A news. After the reveal of Mega Dragonite in the recent Pokémon Presents showcase, could we get another reveal?</p>



<p>The Closing Ceremony could also bring news of upcoming updates to existing live-service titles like Pokémon TCG Pocket, Pokémon Cafe Remix, and Pokémon EX Masters. Crucially, we could see more details of Pokémon Champions, which is set to be the formula used for future VGC events.</p>



<p>Pokémon does like to keep surprises up its sleeve, however, so it’s difficult to predict exactly what will be shown off.</p>



<p>What do you want to see announced at the Pokémon World Championships Closing Ceremony? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Done reading? Now check out all the details for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-start-date-times-how-to-watch-how-long-is-it/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-announced-for-gamescom-2025-black-ops-7-hollow-knight-silksong-ea-fc-26-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything announced for Gamescom 2025</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-world-championships-2025-closing-ceremony-date-times-how-to-watch-what-to-expect/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McDonalds Ends Pokémon Promotion Early After Huge Food Wastage]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mcdonalds-ends-pokemon-promotion-early-after-huge-food-wastage/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mcdonalds-ends-pok%C3%A9mon-promotion-early-after-huge-food-wastage.1270923/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>McDonalds has ended part of the Pokémon promotion early in Japan after huge queues outside of its stores and immense food wastage.</p>



<p>Last weekend’s launch of the Pokémon promotion earned criticism from across the world, with scalpers buying up Happy Meals in bulk to receive the exclusive Pokémon cards in the distribution, and many then dumping the meals. </p>



<p>McDonalds sold out of the exclusive Pokémon cards within hours of the promotion starting, despite plans for the event to run for three days, and plans have now been updated for the upcoming week.</p>



<h2 id="h-mcdonalds-places-restrictions-on-happy-meal-purchases">McDonalds Places Restrictions on Happy Meal Purchases</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’s over. Image via McDonalds</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.mcdonalds.co.jp/company/info/2025/0814a/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">statement</a>, McDonalds apologized to customers and store staff, along with announcing restrictions on purchasing Happy Meals that prohibit purchasing more than three per group. If four or more are ordered, “we will refuse your purchase and cancel the order.”</p>



<p>This weekend’s promotion will go ahead, though the big difference is there will not be any Pokémon cards and, instead, toys will be provided, which should result in a decreased demand for those looking for profit.</p>



<p>On the topic of scalpers specifically, McDonalds stated it “does not tolerate the purchase of Happy Meals for the purpose of resale, or the abandonment or disposal of food.”</p>



<p>This is not a problem unique to McDonalds, however, as the Pokémon hobby has become embroiled with supply problems due to high demand, with widespread videos of people purchasing products in mass to sell at inflated prices.</p>



<p>Pokémon has maximized its printing process to counteract this issue, but there is little evidence of results so far and, with the 30th anniversary of the franchise next year, demand could be higher than ever.</p>



<p>Are scalpers ruining the Pokémon hobby? Should McDonalds refuse to distribute Pokémon cards again? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/3311/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news, check out claims that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/chris-hansen-roblox-plans-documentary-predator-claim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chris Hansen is planning a Roblox documentary</a>, and take a look at hints that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-dlc-could-be-revealed-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Myth Wukong DLC could be revealed at Gamescom</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/mcdonalds-ends-pokemon-promotion-early-after-huge-food-wastage/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>