<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 22:04:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Madden 26 Have Crossplay? Cross-Platform Status Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/will-madden-26-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/will-madden-26-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained.1263912/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Madden 25 supported crossplay, but let’s see if EA decided to bring the feature back for Madden 26.</p>



<p>Several game modes were overhauled for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-launches-on-august-14-first-trailer-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Madden 26</a>. In&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-franchise-deep-dive-shows-new-coaching-updates-gameplan-changes-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Franchise</a>, some of the significant new changes include coach archetypes, weekly playsheet updates, a new weekly highlights show, and more. Superstar added Game Day Beats, Sphere of Influence, and Career Chapters, which challenge you to complete specific objectives and build relationships off the field. </p>



<p>As for Ultimate Team, EA promised more content than before post-launch, and the solo experience has been overhauled. Let’s take a look at if these game modes support crossplay. </p>



<h2 id="h-does-madden-26-have-crossplay">Does Madden 26 Have Crossplay?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Crossplay returns in Madden 26. Image via EA Sports</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Madden supports&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-college-football/college-football-26/faq" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossplay</a>&nbsp;between PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</strong>,&nbsp;<strong>and PC</strong>, <strong>meaning it is not a feature for the Nintendo Switch 2. </strong></p>



<p>In addition, this is the first year that Madden 26 will not be available on last-gen consoles, so that means crossplay is not necessary. </p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-use-crossplay-in-madden-26">How to Use Crossplay in Madden 26 </h2>



<p>Here is a step-by-step guide on how to use crossplay.</p>



<ol>
<li>Open the&nbsp;<strong>EA Connect menu</strong>&nbsp;in Madden 26. </li>



<li>Navigate to the&nbsp;<strong>Player Search</strong>&nbsp;tab.</li>



<li>Search for a player using their&nbsp;<strong>EA Identification number</strong>&nbsp;or by using their&nbsp;<strong>platform identifier</strong>&nbsp;(Xbox Series X|S gamertag or PSN ID).</li>



<li>Invite them to a game or Dynasty save.</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-which-madden-26-modes-support-crossplay">Which Madden 26 Modes Support Crossplay?</h2>



<p><strong>In Madden 26, you can play cross-platform in online Head-to-Head, Franchise, Ultimate Team, Superstar KO, and Superstar Showdown.</strong></p>



<p>In Ultimate Team, the Auction House does not support crossplay. As a result, PlayStation 5 players can only purchase cards from listings on the same console and vice versa. This might make cards more expensive, as there will be less supply and more demand because it doesn’t account for the entire player base.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-turn-crossplay-off-in-madden-26">Can You Turn Crossplay Off in Madden 26?</h2>



<p><strong>Crossplay is enabled by default, but you can opt out, regardless of which platform you are on.</strong></p>



<p>For players who opt in to cross-play, any leaderboard in any mode that supports cross-play will be a global leaderboard that includes players from all supported platforms. Players who opt out of cross-play will only see leaderboards for players on their own platform.</p>



<p>Here is a step-by-step guide on how to turn off crossplay.</p>



<h3 id="h-xbox-series-x-s">Xbox Series X|S</h3>



<ol>
<li>Go to your&nbsp;<strong>Xbox</strong>&nbsp;<strong>settings</strong>.</li>



<li>Scroll to&nbsp;<strong>Account&nbsp;</strong>and click on&nbsp;<strong>Privacy and Online Safety</strong>.</li>



<li>Click on&nbsp;<strong>Xbox Live Privacy</strong>.</li>



<li>Select&nbsp;<strong>View Details</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>Customise</strong>.</li>



<li>Choose&nbsp;<strong>Communications</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>Multiplayer</strong>.</li>



<li>Change “You can play with people outside of Xbox Live” to&nbsp;<strong>block</strong>.</li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-playstation-5">PlayStation 5</h3>



<ol>
<li>Go to the In-game&nbsp;<strong>Settings tab</strong>.</li>



<li>Select<strong>&nbsp;Gameplay Settings</strong>.</li>



<li>Toggle the crossplay option to off.</li>
</ol>



<p>Which game mode are you most excited to use crossplay for? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/will-madden-26-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained.3209/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more on Madden 26, check out which <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-madden-26-on-nintendo-switch-2-all-platforms-consoles-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platforms and consoles</a> the game is available on, and the full <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-26-pre-order-guide-all-editions-bonuses-prices/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pre-order guide</a>.   </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/will-madden-26-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty is the Easiest Shooter To Get Good At, Says Former Counter-Strike Pro]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-easiest-shooter-to-get-good-former-pro-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-is-the-easiest-shooter-to-get-good-at-says-former-counter-strike-pro.1263885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The first-person shooter world is a diverse one populated by so many games, many of which boast a competitive scene that feeds into the wider esports ecosystem. From VALORANT to Counter-Strike, Apex Legends to Rainbow Six, and Call of Duty to Overwatch, first-person shooters are ten a penny these days.</p>



<p>In a recent interview, a former Counter-Strike pro player took a dive into the spread of games on the market, ranking them by how tough they are to master, from the perspective of a successful esports athlete.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-it-s-pretty-easy">‘It’s Pretty Easy’</h2>



<p>Fredrik ‘roeJ’ Jorgensen sat down for a lengthy interview ahead of the <a href="https://thunderpick.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Thunderpick</a> World Championship to review his career and sum up the state of the industry. Jorgensen started competing professionally in 2017 and retired earlier this year, but not before claiming more than $300,000 in winnings.</p>



<p>He revealed in his interview that he was earning around $8,000 a month at ‘his peak’, even though his team wasn’t qualifying for many major tournaments or sizeable events.</p>



<p>When the conversation turned to which games are the hardest to master, Jorgensen offered a breakdown of the top seven titles put to him, with <strong>only one </strong>being something other than a first-person shooter: Fortnite.</p>



<p>According to Jorgensen, the toughest first-person shooter to master is Apex Legends:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Apex Legends is pretty hard to be honest. I think it’s like one of those battle royale games if you’re not good at the game or you don’t really understand what’s going on, I think you’re just gonna get killed instantly and you just spend your time flying down.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>At the other end of Jorgensen’s scale sat Call of Duty, one of the oldest and most popular first-person shooter franchises in the world:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>When I think about Call of Duty, I think about Modern Warfare 2, where you just go in and you just play a team deathmatch and you just basically have to kill and you respawn and repeat.&nbsp; I think that’s one of the easiest games you can play.</p>



<p>Obviously, actually killing people is probably a bit harder, but just, you know, the sheer mechanics of the game is pretty straightforward. So, I say Call of Duty on that one. <strong>It’s pretty easy.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Counter-Strike, which was the game that put Jorgensen on the map, came in just two spots beneath Call of Duty on the scale, beaten in the toughness stakes by Rainbow Six Siege.</p>



<p>Do you agree with roeJ that Call of Duty is the easiest shooter to get good at? Let me know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play/">Black Ops 7 will require Secure Boot to play</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-easiest-shooter-to-get-good-former-pro-says/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sekiro Anime Web Domain Registration Surfaces Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sekiro-anime-web-domain-registration-surfaces-online/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sekiro-anime-web-domain-registration-surfaces-online.1263867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Kadokawa Corporation has recently registered a web domain for Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice Anime. </p>



<p>Talks about a Sekiro anime have been circulating for a very long time; however, the latest development almost seals the deal. The only thing left now is an official announcement, which will also confirm who is involved in the upcoming project. Read more about the Sekiro anime web domain registration below. </p>



<h2 id="h-sekiro-anime-announcement-could-arrive-soon">Sekiro Anime Announcement Could Arrive Soon?</h2>



<p>Spotted on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-web-domain-for-the-long-rumored-sekiro-shadows-die-twice-anime-has-been-registered.1263348/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ResetEra</a> (via <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1953100767453220870" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Wario64</a>), Vestan has posted about the Sekiro Anime web domain registration on the forum. The domain has been registered by Kadokawa Corporation, which is the parent company of FromSoftware, the developers of Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice. The domain was registered on July 31, 2025, in Japan, and the name has been set as ‘SEKIRO-ANIME.JP’. It will expire on July 31, 2026. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The leaker has also provided more information about the upcoming Sekiro anime. It appears that a studio called Qzil.la, the creators of Hell’s Paradise, is bringing the Sekiro anime to life. As it is a relatively new studio, the anime adaptation is expected to have a low episode count. Moreover, as the domain has been registered, a reveal could arrive “soonish”. However, as this information doesn’t come from an official source, players should take it with a grain of salt. </p>



<p>In other news, FromSoftware is reportedly in “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fromsoftware-new-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">advanced development</a>” of an unannounced game that is expected to arrive next year. Additionally, Elden Ring’s movie director is likely more skilled at the game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-movie-director-better-than-you/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">than most players</a>. What are your thoughts on a Sekiro anime web domain being registered? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-vs-call-of-duty/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive report that states Activision leadership isn’t worried about Battlefield 6 as Call of Duty is “too big to fail”</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/sekiro-anime-web-domain-registration-surfaces-online/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Season 5 Update Patch Notes— Three New Multiplayer Maps & Zombies Reckoning Map]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-5-update-patch-notes-three-new-multiplayer-maps-zombies-reckoning-map/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-season-5-update-patch-notes%E2%80%94-three-new-multiplayer-maps-zombies-reckoning-map.1263783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Black Ops 6 Season 5 update introduces three new multiplayer maps, three new weapons, and adds the final Zombies map for this game. </p>



<p>The star of the show in BO6 Season 5 is the sixth and final Zombies map, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-does-the-new-black-ops-6-zombies-map-come-out-everything-we-know-about-reckoning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reckoning</a>. Set in the project Janus headquarters, the towers’ systems are on the verge of total failure, and it’s up to the team to stabilize the Aethor Reactors before the Aetherium leak gets out of hand. </p>



<p>Reckoning features a new Wonder Weapon that alters gravity, a new elite enemy, and adds several other surprises. Let’s jump right into what fans can expect. <br></p>



<h2 id="h-all-black-ops-6-season-5-update-patch-notes">All Black Ops 6 Season 5 Update Patch Notes</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Boxing gloves are a new melee weapon in BO6 Season 5. </figcaption></figure>



<p>Here are the complete Black Ops 6 <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2025/08/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-05-patch-notes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Season 5 Patch Notes</a>. </p>



<h3 id="h-new-multiplayer-maps">New Multiplayer Maps</h3>



<p><strong>Runway (6v6)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>A Pantheon mole attempts their escape via the Arzak Provincial Airport. All hell breaks loose as the Rogue Black Ops team pursues one of their final targets. Wreckage and luggage litter the tarmac, flames licking the sides of the terminal and black smoke rising from the fire in the airport control tower.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Exchange (6v6, 2v2)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Rogue Black Ops pursues a mole attempting to strike a deal in a vibrant Avalon marketplace. Crash the party and unleash havoc on this small-sized three-lane map centered around the Deli, its roof adorned with a marble statue of a mythic sea god.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>World Motor Dynasty (W.M.D.) (6v6)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>From its inception as a Nova 6 processing laboratory first introduced in the original Call of Duty: Black Ops, W.M.D. returns in a reimagined form as an Italian luxury car manufacturer in Avalon. Trade the snow of the original map for an overcast day around the Autofiorno plant, using your memories of the prior map to help navigate the larger area of operations.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-new-multiplayer-mode">New Multiplayer Mode</h3>



<p><strong>Aim High</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Aim high to survive across a variety of game modes — including Team Deathmatch, Domination, Hardpoint, and Kill Confirmed — where headshots land instant eliminations while full body armor minimizes damage dealt anywhere below the neck. As a bonus, this headshot training is likely to hone your talents when unlocking Weapon Camos.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-new-weapons">New Weapons</h3>



<p><strong>PML 5.5 – LMG (Battle Pass)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Full-auto light machine gun. Fast rate of fire and high lethality offset by low mobility and hefty recoil.</li>



<li>When a rival Operator is holding the trigger down on the PML 5.56, you’ll know, mainly due to the damage and huge ammunition reserves, mitigated somewhat by a lengthy reload.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>ABR A1 – Assault Rifle (Battle Pass)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Three-round burst assault rifle. Good handling and power. Moderate recoil and range. Configurable to full auto.</li>



<li>The iconic Assault Rifle returns! With a similar weapon being a fan-favorite staple of the Black Ops series, the ABR A1 combines a high damage output that can drop enemies in tight three-round bursts with a brief pause in-between, almost fast enough to be called automatic.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Boxing Gloves – Melee (In-Season, Event Reward)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Moderate damage. Fast attack speed. Long range.</li>



<li>Slip on the Boxing Gloves and knock out foes with a swift barrage of jabs and uppercuts.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-new-attachments">New Attachments</h3>



<p><strong>9mm PM Skull Splitter (Two Attachments, Battle Pass)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Bring the power and precision of a marksman rifle to your favorite pistol with the 9mm PM Skull Splitter Barrel. The Barrel greatly increases damage, especially to the head, reducing rate of fire. Pair with an extended magazine that gives the Operator additional ammo for this weapon at the expense of handling.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>PPSh-41 Helical Magazine (In-Season, Event Reward)</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fire to the beat of your own drum with this SMG attachment that puts other magazines to shame. Manage heat on this high-ammo count magazine that excels at spraying bullets in close and medium ranges.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-season-5-zombies-update-patch-notes">Black Ops 6 Season 5 Zombies Update Patch Notes</h2>



<h3 id="h-new-map-reckoning">New Map: Reckoning</h3>



<p>Looming over the once-sleepy settlement of Liberty Falls, the Project Janus Headquarters—three edifices known locally as Janus Towers— now teeters on the verge of collapse.</p>



<h3 id="h-new-enemies">New Enemies</h3>



<p><strong>Uber Klaus + Uber Klaus Core</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>The secret Research and Development program of Project Janus appears to have been more evolved than originally thought, developing many more robots in the Klaus Assembly Lab than first anticipated. The greatest of these threats is the Uber Klaus – a murderous automaton encased in a toughened, bulky exoskeleton – that maintains a cocky attitude, lethal efficiency, and super strength, all directed at newly-programmed threats.</li>



<li>Enemy takedown tactics are unknown at this point, though combat is likely to be focused on disrupting the Uber Klaus form’s heavy shielding and avoiding its melee attacks. Once the exoskeleton is broken, the Uber Klaus Core will eject, revealing its second deadly form.</li>



<li>The Uber Klaus Core increases in agility, sacrificing defenses for less lumbering locomotion and flying capabilities thanks to rocket-powered hover boots. It continues to employ energy-based, arm-mounted launchers, while its defensive shield can prevent your incoming attacks.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Kommando Klaus</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Preceded by a strange red mist, these automated enemies have had their higher functions disconnected and self-destruct sequences activated.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-new-wonder-weapon-gorgofex">New Wonder Weapon: Gorgofex</h3>



<p>Latest intel all but confirms Janus Towers may be hiding a new and grotesquely potent Wonder Weapon known as the Gorgofex. Partly charred experimentation notes discovered on microfiche indicate the existence of a “bio-aetheric” armament.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Combining fungal, floral, and insectile traits to deliver precise impact damage and gravity-defying disruption in close quarters, glowing membranes on the weapon show hints of motion and circulation under the surface. The weapon seems to pulse and breathe, with a beating central heart-like organ that “pumps” energy through the weapon. Due to the saturation of Dark Aether and other unknown energies, the weapon is said to emit faint psychic vibrations.</p>



<h3 id="h-new-field-upgrade-mister-peeks">New Field Upgrade: Mister Peeks </h3>



<p>Summon Mister Peeks to our reality to create chaos, as the deadly and distracting bunny busts out the moves and bashes undead brains to a raving disco beat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Once Mister Peeks arrives in your hands, throw this hairy helper into the fray, and he gleefully attracts normal and Special enemies and attacks any undead within his wandering radius, savaging foes until they explode in a shower of bright confetti.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Mister Peeks: Major Augments</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dance Party
<ul>
<li>Mister Peeks becomes the life of the party, attracting nearby zombies to him, before he detonates an Aether Pulse to thin out the crowd considerably.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Arcane Fury
<ul>
<li>Mister Peeks has become a master of the elements, enhancing his regular damage with a random Ammo Mod (with an Augment from that Ammo Mod).</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Apex Hunter
<ul>
<li>Mister Peeks focuses all attacks on the strongest nearby enemy other than bosses. For example, Uber Klaus would be targeted over regular foes, with increased damage inflicted.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Mister Peeks: Minor Augments&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Social Butterfly
<ul>
<li>Increase Mister Peeks’ attraction radius.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Peeks’ Favor
<ul>
<li>Mister Peeks is good to have around Mystery Box locations. Get a free box spin if you’re near one during activation!</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Party Animal
<ul>
<li>Increase Mister Peeks dance duration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>How do you feel about this update? Let us know on the Insider Gaming Forum. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more on Call of Duty, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-vs-call-of-duty/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Activision leadership isn’t worried about Battlefield 6</a>, and CoD is adding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Secure Boot</a>. </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-season-5-update-patch-notes-three-new-multiplayer-maps-zombies-reckoning-map/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Will Require Secure Boot To Play]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play.1263756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Activision announced that PC users will have to enable Secure Boot to play Call of Duty: Black Ops 7. </p>



<p>Secure Boot is a Windows 10 and Windows 11 security feature that ensures a PC only loads safe software during startup. Secure Boot enables Activision to detect and remove users of banned third-party devices or other cheating software. </p>



<p>EA also uses the security measure for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-secureboot-not-enabled-error/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6</a>, and players experienced difficulties because they couldn’t play the game without enabling it. Enabling Secure Boot varies depending on the manufacturer of your PC, which can make it a confusing process. Black Ops 6 players are about to experience the same confusion. </p>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-6-introduces-secure-boot-ahead-of-black-ops-7">Black Ops 6 Introduces Secure Boot Ahead of Black Ops 7</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Black Ops 7 players on PC must enable Secure Boot. Image via Activision </figcaption></figure>



<p>Starting in Black Ops 6 Season 5, which begins on August 7, PC users must have Secure Boot enabled. </p>



<p><a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/08/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-ricochet-anti-cheat-season-05" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Activision</a> explained, “Secure Boot makes cheating at a hardware level much more difficult, ensuring cleaner PCs at start and allowing for more trusted environments for RICOCHET Anti-Cheat to operate in.” </p>



<p>If you need more information on how to enable Secure Boot, Activision provided a <a href="https://support.activision.com/articles/trusted-platform-module-and-secure-boot" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">manual</a> on how to do so. You won’t be able to play BO6 without having the security measure enabled, and that also applies to Black Ops 7, when the upcoming game releases later this year. </p>



<p>In addition, the devs encouraged you to secure your account with email verification and two-factor authentication. Activision also introduced new detection tools targeted at rooting out boosting and teaming in BO6 multiplayer and Warzone Ranked Play, and confirmed that 22 additional individuals responsible for developing and selling cheats were cut off.  </p>



<p>Is Secure Boot enough to cut down on cheating? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play.3211/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forum</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>In other Black Ops 7 news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-in-game-rewards-codes-already-available/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in-game reward codes</a> are already available, and players believe <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-players-think-black-ops-6-purchases-carrying-over-to-black-ops-7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BO6 purchases</a> will carry over. </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-require-secure-boot-to-play/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE – Activision Leadership Isn’t Worried About Battlefield 6 Because Call of Duty is “Too Big to Fail”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-vs-call-of-duty/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-%E2%80%93-activision-leadership-isn%E2%80%99t-worried-about-battlefield-6-because-call-of-duty-is-%E2%80%9Ctoo-big-to-fail%E2%80%9D.1263753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Insider Gaming has learned that Activision leadership has been taking note of Battlefield 6’s recent hype, but is not worried that the franchise will surpass Call of Duty.</p>



<p>Speaking with sources who wished to remain anonymous because they were not authorised to talk about Activision’s internal conversations, it’s been said that although Activision is keeping a close eye on Battlefield, they are not worried about the game outcompeting its flagship franchise.</p>



<p>It’s said that Activision leadership believes that Call of Duty is “too big to fail” and will remain a profitable, annually released franchise for many years to come. At the time of writing, an annual Call of Duty title is penciled in for the next four years at least.</p>



<p>This year’s Call of Duty title, dubbed ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-revealed-during-xbox-games-showcase-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 7</a>‘, is said to be a “strong” title according to those familiar with the game’s plans, despite initial problems in development. </p>



<p>Interestingly enough, this year’s Call of Duty will take place in a slightly futuristic setting similar to Battlefield 6, with both games targeting a similar audience. Whether or not that direct competition will impact Call of Duty is unclear, but at the time of writing, Activision doesn’t think it will.</p>



<p>There’s also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s Battle Royale</a> to consider, which is believed to be a free-to-play component to the premium game. If EA can take a considerable chunk out of Call of Duty: Warzone’s playerbase, which has been depleting for the last couple of years, it could have a detrimental impact on Call of Duty’s long-term playerbase.</p>



<p>Call of Duty: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-watch-black-ops-7-reveal-event-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 7 is set to get a full reveal</a> at this year’s Opening Night Live on August 19th.</p>



<p>What do you think of Activision not being worried about Battlefield outcompeting Call of Duty? Should they be? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hollow-knight-silksong-wont-feature-at-upcoming-indie-world-showcase-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">&nbsp;a new claim stating that Hollow Knight: Silksong will not be featured at the upcoming Indie World Showcase</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>








    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-vs-call-of-duty/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>