<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:54:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Creative Director is Taking Time Off Before the Next Arrowhead Game]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-creative-director-is-taking-time-off-before-the-next-arrowhead-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-creative-director-is-taking-time-off-before-the-next-arrowhead-game.1093512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-creative-director-is-taking-time-off-before-the-next-arrowhead-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-86464">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The creative director of Helldivers 2 and Arrowhead Games has announced that he is taking a sabbatical before starting work on the studio’s next game.</p>



<p>Helldivers 2’s CCO, Johan Pilestedt, recently took to <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1884015181895983223" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) to announce that he is taking some time off. Pilestedt explained that while players started enjoying Helldivers 2 last year, he has worked on the game since 2016 and the Helldivers franchise since 2013. As he worked for 11 years “around the clock” on the same IP, Pilestedt had to sacrifice time with his family, friends, wife, and himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result, the Helldivers 2 CCO will take some time off to “redeem what was lost” from those who have been supporting him for more than 10 years. Pilestedt has ensured the community that all the developers at Arrowhead Game Studios will be hard at work to deliver amazing Helldivers 2 content to the players while he’s on sabbatical. And once he returns, work “on the next Arrowhead Game” will begin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pilestedt has also posted an <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1884016859676303815" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">update</a> since beginning his sabbatical, revealing that the first thing he did was start “a game jam with the most senior devs/founders” at Arrowhead Game Studios.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, the Helldivers 2 CEO wants <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-ceo-wants-a-list-to-be-violently-killed-in-the-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">A-listers to be violently killed</a> in the upcoming movie, as the director talks about Arrowhead’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-director-talks-about-their-involvement-with-the-upcoming-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">involvement with the adaptation</a>. What are your thoughts on the Helldivers 2 creative director taking some time off?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phoenix-labs-layoffs-closure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phoenix Labs laying off more than 50 employees</a>,&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/">WWE 2K25 Cover Officially Revealed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The official WWE 2K25 cover has been revealed, and it features one of the company’s most popular superstars.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phoenix-labs-layoffs-closure/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phoenix-labs-layoffs-closure/">Dauntless Developer Phoenix Labs Lays Off 50+ More Employees, With Studio Likely to Close</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The remainder of Phoenix Labs developers have been laid off, with the studios game ‘Dauntless’ and it’s studio likely to close.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-gameplay/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/split-fiction-gameplay/">Split Fiction receives a new gameplay trailer showcasing a sci-fi stage</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Split Fiction promises to offer one of the most diverse gameplay experiences ever seen.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/techland-dying-light-next-era-10th-anniversary/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/techland-dying-light-next-era-10th-anniversary/">‘The Next Era of Dying Light’ Revealed as Techland Celebrates 10th Anniversary</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Dying Light’s 10th anniversary celebrations are here, and Techland has started by celebrating ‘the next era of Dying Light’</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Posters—All Locations Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters-locations-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters%E2%80%94all-locations-guide.1093500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters-locations-guide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Many secrets lurk throughout Sniper Elite Resistance, including Propaganda Posters to track down. Although optional, they serve a great benefit if you find each one in Resistance, and I’ve pinpointed the location of each Poster in the main Campaign.</p>



<p>The sheer scale of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sniper Elite Resistance</a>‘s levels means there’s a lot to do. On top of main objectives and optional side tasks, you can do specific actions related to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-trophy-guide-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophies and Achievements</a> list and also track down the countless Collectibles most levels contain.</p>



<p>One of the most important though—other than Workbenches—are Propaganda Posters. This guide has the location of each Propaganda Poster, where to find them, and what they do in Sniper Elite Resistance.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-do-propaganda-posters-do-in-sniper-elite-resistance">What Do Propaganda Posters Do in Sniper Elite Resistance?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Fresh gameplay awaits. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Obtaining Propaganda Posters unlocks special Propaganda Challenges in Sniper Elite Resistance.</strong></p>



<p>You can see different gameplay options on <a href="https://sniperelite.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sniper Elite Resistance</a>‘s main menu. You’ve got the Campaign, Invasion, and Multiplayer, and it also mentions Propaganda Challenges. When you start Resistance, the Propaganda Challenge sub-menu looks uninviting and unreceptive.</p>



<p>This is because all seven challenges are locked from the get-go. <strong>You must find a Poster hidden in seven of the nine levels</strong> in the entire <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/full-sniper-elite-resistance-mission-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resistance Mission List</a>. Each one unlocks a brand-new challenge, but they can be serious time sappers to locate. This is where I step in to save your day.</p>



<h2 id="h-every-propaganda-poster-location-in-sniper-elite-resistance">Every Propaganda Poster Location in Sniper Elite Resistance</h2>



<p><strong>I’ve provided my location on each mission’s map below, and this is where the Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Poster is.</strong></p>



<p>Each Poster has a <strong>distinct gloss and shine</strong> which makes it obvious it’s the Collectible. Posters are scattered throughout the levels, but only a specific one is needed. If you want to skip the text, head to my player marker on the map screenshot to quickly and easily find the Posters.</p>



<h3 id="h-dead-drop-propaganda-poster-location">Dead Drop Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Dead Drop Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Start the level, carry on forward, follow the natural path to the castle, and get to the broken stone bridge. Take the wooden bridge to the left of it that takes you to the river, and <strong>break the planks covering the underground doorway</strong>. Head inside, move ahead, and lockpick the door ahead. Climb the ladder, lock pick the door directly in front of you once you get to the top, and the Poster is on the right on some stairs.</p>



<h3 id="h-sonderzuge-sabotage-propaganda-poster-location">Sonderzüge Sabotage Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Sonderzüge Sabotage Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>The Poster is on the building right next to the “<strong>Find the missing Resistance Cell” Optional Objective</strong>. Simply, head to this location, and go to my marker on the Map Location screenshot above. You can’t miss the Propaganda Poster.</p>



<h3 id="h-collision-course-propaganda-poster-location">Collision Course Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Collision Course Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Make your way through Collision Course until you reach the train tracks—you can’t miss them. I’m giving you the fastest route to the Poster, <strong>but it is a dangerous one</strong>. If you follow the tracks across the bridge, you <strong>unfortunately come face-on with a tank</strong>. Either take it out or run past it. Follow the tracks around the curved track, and the Poster is on a tunnel’s wall on the right-hand side.</p>



<h3 id="h-devil-s-cauldron-propaganda-poster-location">Devil’s Cauldron Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Devil’s Cauldron Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Another simple Poster to find in Devil’s Cauldron. Go to my map marker indicated above. It’s a relatively easy path to get there, and the Propaganda Poster is on the <strong>side of a church with a big watch tower at the top</strong>—fixed with a zip line.</p>



<h3 id="h-assault-on-fort-rouge-propaganda-poster-location">Assault On Fort Rouge Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Assault On Fort Rouge Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>This is probably the furthest Poster when it comes to travel distance from the start point. Cross the starting bridge, turn left, and go to the area I’ve highlighted. The Assault On Fort Rouge Poster is tucked away in alleys deep in the bottom-left corner of the level.</p>



<h3 id="h-lock-stock-and-barrels-propaganda-poster-location">Lock, Stock And Barrels Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Lock, Stock And Barrels Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>When Harry spawns, go forward, and immediately take the left path taking you <strong>down a hill and toward a wooden bridge crossing water</strong>. You can either go left or right, <strong>it doesn’t matter</strong>, as either one has Germans to get past. I went right, demonstrated my expert-killing skills (raising the alarm in the process), and went through an open wooden gate to the house the Poster is on. Use my reference point, as the <strong>Poster is hidden behind a decent amount of foliage</strong>.</p>



<h3 id="h-end-of-the-line-propaganda-poster-location">End Of The Line Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>End of the Line Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>This Poster gave the most trouble of all, despite the fact all Posters are found near the beginning of the level. I searched everywhere, but it was <strong>sneakily hidden at the top of a ladder!</strong> From the default starting location, head down the ladder on the left taking you to the East side of the level. You should be in the train yard now, and there’s a big, open hangar. Either climb the ladder on the side of the building, or head inside and go up a flight of stairs, and head to the platform that takes you outside. The seventh and final Poster is on the side of the wall.  </p>



<hr>



<p>You should now have all seven Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Posters and access to every Propaganda Challenge. Good luck trying to get Gold on every mini-mission, it’s not easy! Let me know how you get on and if you’re chasing all Collectibles.</p>



<p>Plan your time with Sniper Elite Resistance carefully as I’ve also whipped up a handy explainer on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-is-sniper-elite-resistance-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long Resistance is, and the game’s length</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next God of War Game Is Reportedly Centered Around Egyptian Mythology]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology.1093431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The next God of War game could be making its way to Egypt. According to a report from DanielRPK (<a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/120905575?utm_campaign=postshare_creator&amp;utm_content=android_share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">paywall</a>), Sony is casting currently casting for Middle Eastern Actors for a new game.</p>



<p>“Sony is casting Middle Eastern actors for an unknown AAA game, which is likely to be the next God of War that explores Egyptian mythology,” the report says.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that this information hasn’t been confirmed or independently verified by Insider Gaming. Until that happens, please take this news with a grain of salt.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST<strong>:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Developers Direct Us: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>Moving to Egyptian mythology wouldn’t be surprising should it happen. The God of War saga began in Greek mythology before shifting to Norse for the modern games. Moving to a new pantheon would make sense for next era of the franchise. </p>



<p>As far as Egyptian specifically, it’s been mentioned in the past (h/t <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-new-god-of-war-game-egyptian-mythology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>) that Sony Santa Monica originally considered centering the game around Egyptian mythology for the 2018 revival before settling on Norse.</p>



<p>“I think the first pitch I gave was that we wouldn’t even know what was happening,” creative director <a href="https://youtu.be/ra_R-K_IoUc?si=Exzp3X0DfFld-6pZ&amp;t=1192" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Cory Barlog said</a>. “So i t was Kratos walking through the desert—because we were, in my mind, still doing Egypt initially—wind, sand blowing all over the place as he’s kind of crawling through and then kind of stands up over a dune and checks out this really fantastic ancient city.”</p>



<p>What do you think about Egypt and its lore being the focus of the next God of War game? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cover and reveal trailer</a> for WWE 2K25. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 Cover Officially Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed.1093395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The WWE 2K25 cover has been officially revealed. As expected from the first tease earlier this month, Roman Reigns will grace the cover of the Standard edition of the game.</p>



<p>The Undertaker will feature on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-deadman-edition-undertaker/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deadman Edition</a> while the entire Bloodline will be included on the Bloodline edition of the game.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-nbsp-xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST<strong>:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Developers Direct Us: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>This is the second time Reigns will be featured on the game’s base cover, and the first time as the only wrestler. Both he and Becky Lynch were on the cover of WWE 2K20 back in 2019. This time around, however, he’s joined by his “Wiseman” Paul Heyman just outside of the ring.</p>



<p>You can check out the Standard Edition covers and the first trailer for the game, below.</p>



<figure><video controls="" poster="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/WWECover.jpg" src="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/j67CT_7BMS6aQJsk.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>With the cover finally shown, all that’s left is for the full reveal of the game. Luckily, fans won’t have to wait long as full details on the game will be announced on Tuesday, January 28.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will have full coverage of the reveal, including modes, features, and more.</p>



<p>What do you think of Roman Reigns being the cover athlete for WWE 2K25? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what studio is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/people-can-fly-is-co-developing-gears-of-war-e-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working with The Coalition</a> on Gears of War: E-Day, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phoenix-labs-layoffs-closure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest studio to hold layoffs</a> and possibly close.&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>