<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:19:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG’s Creator Reveals New Open-World Game and Free Earth-Sized Tech Demo]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/brendan-greene-pubg-creator-three-game-survival/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pubg%E2%80%99s-creator-reveals-new-open-world-game-and-free-earth-sized-tech-demo.1053117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/brendan-greene-pubg-creator-three-game-survival/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Brendan ‘PlayerUnknown’ Greene’s PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions has revealed a three-game plan that’s being kickstarted with an open-world survival game – <em>‘Prologue: Go Wayback!’</em> </p>



<p>This news was revealed today by Greene’s team, and it was accompanied by a six-minute trailer showcasing the future of these projects. In 2021, PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions was founded in Amsterdam to ultimately deliver an ambitious, massively multiplayer world dubbed Project Artemis.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-father-of-battle-royale">‘The Father of Battle Royale’</h2>



<p>Many consider Brendan Greene to be the father of the modern battle royale genre. He is responsible for the creation of PUBG, which was released in 2017 and went on to inspire the likes of Fortnite, Free Fire, Apex Legends, and Call of Duty: Warzone.</p>



<p>Brendan Greene <strong>is </strong>PlayerUnknown – it’s <strong>his </strong>Battleground that you’re occupying when you play PUBG.</p>



<p>PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions is working on building an ‘Earth-sized’ MMO called Project Artemis, but before it gets there, it’s working on a single-player, open-world survival game, the name of which has just been revealed as ‘Prologue: Go Wayback!’.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Since 2021, Greene’s projects have been kept more or less under wraps, and only a fireside chat here and there has served as a stage for players to get updates on PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions. In an article from PC Gamer published in September, it was revealed that the team had created an entire planet that uses advanced rendering technology to load vast swathes of land almost instantly.</p>



<p>In a press release, it was said that this technology ‘(allows for) the instant creation of millions of maps’. </p>



<p>In the same release, Greene explained:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>My vision for Artemis is challenging, but we plan to take it one step at a time and the three games aim to give us a solid tech foundation on which to scale up. </p>



<p>After Prologue, two more games are planned for release in the coming years, each addressing critical technical challenges that will bring the studio closer to the final product. With Prologue, we aim to engage players and introduce them to the emergent mechanics and expansive worlds we’re developing.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It was revealed in that article that Greene wants to create a world that can support thousands of concurrent players – with a long-term goal to accommodate <strong>millions </strong>of players. It’s hugely ambitious, but the groundwork is being laid as we speak.</p>



<p>Alongside the reveal of the three-game plan, it was announced that players will be able to explore a free tech demo called Preface: Undiscovered World, which has been built using PLAYERUNKNOWN Productions’ engine, Melba. </p>



<p>This tech demo is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2820060/Preface_Undiscovered_World/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">available now on Steam</a>, and Prologue: Go Wayback! is expected <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2943740/Prologue_Go_Wayback/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">to launch on PC</a> in early access in Q2 of 2025.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to what Brendan Greene’s team can produce? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>