<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:37:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Macaulay Culkin Joins Cast of Fallout Season 2 As a ‘Crazy Genius’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/macaulay-culkin-joins-cast-fallout-season-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/macaulay-culkin-joins-cast-of-fallout-season-2-as-a-%E2%80%98crazy-genius%E2%80%99.1030503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/macaulay-culkin-joins-cast-fallout-season-2/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Following the immense success of the live-action Fallout television series, thanks to Amazon Prime, it was only a matter of time before the series’ second season started attracting more high-profile names. Of course, season one ended on a cliffhanger, so we’re all beyond excited to dive in for more, and now we have a tidbit of information to run with. According to a recent report, Macaulay Culkin joins the cast of Fallout season two, apparently playing a ‘crazy genius-type’ character. I’m a little curious about the role, and something in me thinks his part involves the Enclave.</p>



<p>In the original report published by <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/11/macaulay-culkin-cast-fallout-season-2-1236170530/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Deadline</a>, Macaulay Culkin’s role in the television series based on the long-popular role-playing game franchise remains relatively new. The only information we have about his performance is that he’s a crazy genius of some sort.</p>



<p>That said, Culkin joins a large and growing roster of exceptional stars, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>Ella Purnell</li>



<li>Walton Goggins</li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-plays-knight-titus-in-the-fallout-tv-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aaron Moten</a></li>



<li>Kyle MacLachlan</li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-is-xelia-mendes-jones-in-fallout-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xelia Mendes-Jones</a></li>
</ul>







<p>Following the overwhelming reception to the first season, which debuted as one of Prime Video’s Top 3 most-watched series and received 16 Emmy nominations, a second season was almost immediately greenlit for production. While it’s still a ways off, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallouts-second-season-starts-filming-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">filming begins shortly</a>.</p>



<p>What did you think of the first season of Fallout? Let us know your thoughts on the show, along with the hopes for the second season, down in the comments! Don’t forget to visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a> to find like-minded Fallout fans!</p>



<hr>



<p>On the topic of Fallout, did you hear we’ll soon be able to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-ghoul-character-meta-change/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">play as a Ghoul in Fallout 76</a>? I’ll definitely roll a new character for the chance!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Overwatch 2 Ranks | How to Hit Top 500]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-overwatch-2-ranks-how-to-hit-top-500/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-overwatch-2-ranks-how-to-hit-top-500.1030416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-overwatch-2-ranks-how-to-hit-top-500/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Like all other competitive games, Overwatch 2 has a popular ranked mode that gamers can play and climb up the skill ladder. With multiple different ranks to hit, getting to the top is no easy feat. Here is a list of all the Overwatch 2 ranks and how you can hit them.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-all-overwatch-2-ranks">All Overwatch 2 Ranks</h2>



<p>Below is a list of all the ranks in Overwatch 2:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Bronze </strong>(V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Silver</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Gold</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Platinum</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Diamond</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Master</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Grandmaster</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Champion</strong> (V, IV, III, II, I)</li>



<li><strong>Top 500</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>The game follows a pretty standard ranking system, featuring five levels in almost all of them, with five being where you start and one being the final level before ranking up. The game uses Matchmaking Rating (MMR), which many other games use too to calculate ranks. </p>



<p>However, the final rank, Top 500, is quite impressive to hit. Not many games have a final rank that specifies what number you are in the world in the game. This gives players a global leaderboard to strive to get their name on, making the game just that much more competitive.</p>







<hr>



<h2 id="h-how-to-rank-up-in-overwatch-2-guide-to-top-500">How to Rank Up in Overwatch 2 | Guide to Top 500</h2>



<p>To rank up in Overwatch 2 you simply must play ranked matches. As you progress through the game’s ranked system, you will find games tend to get much more difficult, as ranked uses skill-based matchmaking when putting you in matches.</p>



<p>Getting your name on the Top 500 list is not something that can just be done overnight. Many competitive Overwatch players spend countless hours grinding ranked and never even hit the Top 500.</p>



<p>Still, by winning matches, players can move up in the ranks. </p>



<p>When you first start playing ranked mode in Overwatch 2, the game will have you unranked for a series of games before calculating what badge you should receive. </p>



<p>While your first rank will not be Grandmaster or Champion, some players may start at as high as Gold.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming guides on video game ranks, check out a list of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-dota-2-ranks-how-to-get-immortal/">all the ranks in Dota 2.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Black Friday Deals for Pokémon Fans | Save Money!]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-pokemon-fans-save-money/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-black-friday-deals-for-pok%C3%A9mon-fans-save-money.1030413/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-pokemon-fans-save-money/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Excited for Black Friday this year? Every year, loads of deals are released for both Pokémon cards and Pokémon games. So, what deals do Pokémon fans have to look forward to this year?</p>



<p>Here are the best 2024 Black Friday deals for Pokémon fans.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-best-pokemon-game-black-friday-deals">Best Pokémon Game Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>As of now, there have been no revealed Black Friday deals for Pokémon video games. However, games such as Brilliant Diamond/Shining Pearl, Arceus and others could easily be getting a deal this year.</p>



<h4 id="h-where-to-find-pokemon-game-black-friday-deals"><strong>Where to Find Pokémon Game Black Friday Deals:</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Walmart</strong></li>



<li><strong>Target</strong></li>



<li><strong>Best Buy</strong></li>



<li><strong>Amazon</strong></li>



<li><strong>Nintendo eShop</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>We will keep you updated as more information is released over the next few weeks.</p>







<hr>



<h2 id="h-best-pokemon-card-black-friday-deals">Best Pokémon Card Black Friday Deals</h2>



<p>Not worried about the games, but instead want to grab some Pokémon cards on Black Friday? Luckily, we already know of a few special deals for this year’s popular shopping holiday, many of which are available now.</p>



<h4 id="h-all-pokemon-card-black-friday-deals">All Pokémon Card Black Friday Deals:</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Stellar Crown Booster Box</strong> ($104.95 at Walmart)</li>



<li><strong>Trick or Trade BOOster Bundle</strong> ($12.97 at Walmart)</li>



<li><strong>Shrouded Fable Elite Trainer Box</strong> ($33.75 at Walmart)</li>



<li><strong>Battle Academy&nbsp;</strong>($10.99 at Miniature Market)</li>
</ul>



<p>While the deals listed above are the only current deals ahead of Black Friday, Pokémon fans should expect more to be announced just ahead of the day. In fact, we will probably see a few deals drop on Black Friday and Black Friday only.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-where-to-shop-for-pokemon-cards-black-friday">Where to Shop for Pokémon Cards Black Friday?</h2>



<p>Like the Pokémon games, the cards also have a set of stores that players should head to if they want Black Friday deals. Pokémon cards are a hot commodity, though, so expect any deals to go extremely fast.</p>



<h4 id="h-stores-with-black-friday-deals-on-pokemon-cards">Stores with Black Friday Deals on Pokémon Cards:</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Target</strong></li>



<li><strong>Walmart</strong></li>



<li><strong>Best Buy</strong></li>



<li><strong>Miniature Market</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>While the stores listed above are massive chains, you might have a local card shop in your area doing deals on Pokémon cards. It is always best to check those out and support local businesses.</p>



<p>Will you be buying anything Pokémon-related this Black Friday?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Pokémon news, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-promo-10-mewtwo-card-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/">how to get the Promo 10 Mewtwo card in Pokémon TCG Pocket.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Makes Changes To How Players Unlock Fighters]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-makes-changes-to-how-players-unlock-fighters/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-makes-changes-to-how-players-unlock-fighters.1030389/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-makes-changes-to-how-players-unlock-fighters/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>MultiVersus is making major changes to how players can unlock fighters in the game. </p>



<p>Developer Player First Games <a href="https://multiversus.com/en/news/multiversus-developer-series-fighter-road" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">has announced</a> the new “Fighter Road”. Starting November 12, this is the new way for players to unlock fighters in a more straightforward way than in the past.</p>



<p>“At its core,&nbsp;Fighter Road&nbsp;is a streamlined way to earn characters through an easy-to-follow progression track that players can tackle at their own pace,” the studio said. “This is a great way for&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus</em>&nbsp;players to get their hands on the game’s robust and diverse cast of characters.”</p>



<h6 id="h-related-warner-bros-games-focusing-on-batman-mortal-kombat-and-hogwarts-legacy-moving-forward">RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-games-focusing-on-batman-mortal-kombat-and-hogwarts-legacy-moving-forward/">Warner Bros. Games Focusing on Batman, Mortal Kombat, And Hogwarts Legacy Moving Forward</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-how-multiversus-fighter-road-works">How MultiVersus Fighter Road Works</h2>



<p>Fighter road has players earning progress towards unlocking one new fighter at a time. The progress is earned through Fighter Road XP that gets awarded via matches, events, and the battle pass. </p>



<p>Of course, if you don’t want to work to unlock a specific fighter in MultiVersus, you can always just buy them outright with Fighter currency or Gleamium. However, Fighter currency will no longer be available starting with Season 4 on November 12, so what you spend comes from what you’ve earned to that point.</p>



<p>As far as tracking the progress towards fighter unlocks, Player First Games says that characters will be broken down into tiers based on “a number of factors”.</p>



<p>“The first tier, for example, consists of Shaggy, Banana Guard, Wonder Woman, and Batman,” the said. “While characters are unlocked in a specific order in Fighter Road, some tiers allow for players to choose which character they want to work toward unlocking next. </p>



<p>“Characters that are already owned by the player, will be omitted from the Road and, if the player wants to unlock any characters within a tier using their existing character tokens, they can still do so. As players progress on the Fighter Road, their progress will be displayed on a post-match screen that highlights their progress on the reward track.”</p>



<p>Should you complete the Fighter Road and unlock all of the fighters, any additional earned Fighter Road XP will be converted to Battle Pass XP at a 40% rate.</p>



<p>What do you think of the new way to unlock fighters in MultiVersus? Let us know in the comments, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our extensive&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-game-director-talks-inspiration-the-sims-the-life-simulator-genre-appealing-to-the-west-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interview with inZOI Director and Producer</a>&nbsp;Hyungjun “Kjun” Kim. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>