<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 18:46:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1 Weapons—All New & Unvaulted Weapons]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-season-1-weapons/</link>
            <guid>1368625</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new Chapter has arrived in Fortnite with the launch of Chapter 7 Season 1, which brings the customary refresh of weapons and equipment found in the loot pool alongside it.</p>



<p>Fortnite Chapter 7 kicked off on the back of the huge Zero Point live event, attended by over 10 million players, which saw stars from the likes of Star Wars, Marvel, DC Comics, The Simpsons, and K-Pop Demon Hunters unite to fend off the Dark Presence.</p>



<p>Spring Break has now arrived in Fortnite as a result, and Insider Gaming has all the details on the new and unvaulted weapons in Chapter 7 Season 1.</p>







<h2 id="h-all-new-weapons-amp-equipment-in-fortnite-chapter-7-season-1">All New Weapons &amp; Equipment in Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Glide time. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There are eight new weapons and pieces of equipment added in Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1, including a new mobility item—Wingsuits.</strong></p>



<p>The importance of Wingsuits early in the season is vital following the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-happened-to-the-battle-bus-fortnite-chapter-7/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">destruction of the Battle Bus</a>, as surfing the waves onto the island provide limited landing spots. If you get your hands on a Wingsuit early, traversing the map becomes much easier and you can head to further locations to hunt for loot, where there’s likely to be less competition.</p>



<p>A full list of the new weapons and equipment found in Fortnite this season are below:</p>



<ul>
<li>Iron Pump Shotgun</li>



<li>Twin Hammer Shotguns</li>



<li>Deadeye Assault Rifle</li>



<li>Holo Rush SMG</li>



<li>Vengeful Sniper Rifle</li>



<li>Arc-Lightning Gun</li>



<li>Forsaken Vow Blade</li>



<li>Wingsuit</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-all-unvaulted-weapons-amp-equipment-in-fortnite-chapter-7-season-1">All Unvaulted Weapons &amp; Equipment in Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1</h2>



<p><strong>Five weapons have been unvaulted for Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1, alongside the return of the All Terrain Kart and a host of healing items.</strong></p>



<p>The likes of Chug Jugs, Shield Kegs, Med Kits, Bandages, and Shield Potions remain available, while players in Zero Build can continue to find Shield Bubble Jr and Port-a-Fort items to utilize.</p>



<p>On the weapon scene, the return of the Enforcer AR provides options from mid-to-long range, while there’s plenty of options for short-range combat with the Dual Micro SMGs and Tactical Pistol.</p>



<p>All the unvaulted weapons and equipment in Fortnite this season are below.</p>



<ul>
<li>All Terrain Kart</li>



<li>Enforcer AR</li>



<li>Tactical Pistol</li>



<li>Dual Micro SMGs</li>



<li>Shockwave Grenades</li>



<li>Clinger Grenades</li>



<li>Chug Jugs</li>



<li>Shield Kegs</li>



<li>Med Kits</li>



<li>Bandages</li>



<li>Shield Potions</li>



<li>Mini Shield Potions</li>



<li>Shield Bubble Jr (Zero Build Only)</li>



<li>Port-a-Fort (Zero Build Only)</li>
</ul>







<hr>



<p>What is your favorite weapon to use so far in Fortnite Chapter 7? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-custom-battle-bus-pieces-chapter-7-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to find custom Battle Bus pieces</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-season-1-battle-bus-wheels-pump-n-run/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">locations of all Pump N’ Run Gas Stations</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-season-1-weapons/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1 Roadmap—Return Dates For Blitz, Reload & Fortnite OG]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-roadmap-blitz-reload-og-delulu/</link>
            <guid>1368571</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Chapter 7 has kicked off in Fortnite, but an array of popular modes, including Blitz, Reload, and Fortnite OG, are not yet available in Season 1, but the roadmap has been detailed.</p>



<p>Fortnite brought an end to Chapter 6 with the thrilling Zero Point live event, showcasing a wealth of collabs with recognisable faces from K-Pop Demon Hunter, Marvel, DC Comics, Star Wars, The Simpsons, and more, all featuring.</p>



<p>Chapter 7 Season 1 is now underway, and, while not all game modes are available, Insider Gaming has the details on when to expect their return.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-does-reload-return-to-fortnite">When Does Reload Return to Fortnite?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New map. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Reload returns to Fortnite on December 4, once the Battle Bus is back in commission and available to take players to the new Surf City map.</strong></p>



<p>The Battle Bus was destroyed in the closing moments of the Chapter 7, Season 1 trailer, though Dummy is hard at work repairing the iconic mode of transportation, and <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-seven-pacific-break-v39-00-update-notes?lang=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Epic Games shared a Fortnite roadmap</a> for the coming weeks.</p>



<p>When Reload returns, the new map, Surf City, will be available, featuring a smaller version of the main map, with POIs including Sus Studios, Divey Dam, and Battlewood Boulevard.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-blitz-return-to-fortnite">When Does Blitz Return to Fortnite?</h2>



<p><strong>Blitz returns to Fortnite on December 4, the same day as Reload is back and when Ranked is available again, when the Battle Bus is back in commission.</strong></p>



<p>A new map, Starfall Island, will serve as the environment for Blitz this season, with POIs including Ritzy Redux, Holloway House, and Flowberry Fields.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-fortnite-og-return">When Does Fortnite OG Return?</h2>



<p><strong>Fortnite OG players will need to wait a little while longer for the return of the mode, as it will be out of commission until December 11.</strong></p>



<p>When Fortnite OG is back, Season 7 will kick off in the mode, and the arrival could come alongside the start of the fan-favorite Winterfest event, adding extra content to the game in preparation for the holiday season.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-delulu-return-to-fortnite">When Does Delulu Return to Fortnite?</h2>



<p><strong>Delulu players face the longest wait of all for the mode to return, as Delulu will not be available until December 12, Epic Games has confirmed.</strong></p>



<p>The proximity-chat mode is expected to stay permanently; however, following an introduction in Chapter 6, it adds to the plethora of game modes available in Fortnite.</p>







<hr>



<p>Which game mode are you most looking forward to playing in Chapter 7? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-most-expensive-physical-copy-ever-has-been-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sale of the most expensive copy ever</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-to-feature-quentin-tarantinos-dream-kill-bill-chapter-later-this-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming Kill Bill chapter</a>. </p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-7-roadmap-blitz-reload-og-delulu/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Happened to The Battle Bus in Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/what-happened-to-the-battle-bus-fortnite-chapter-7/</link>
            <guid>1368547</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new Chapter in Fortnite has begun, and significant changes have arrived alongside it, including the absence of the Battle Bus when launching into a game of Battle Royale.</p>



<p>Rather than the familar approach of hitching a ride on the Battle Bus, players instead ride a huge wave to arrive at the island, which impacts landing zones as the maximum distance of travelling is shorter.</p>



<p>If you’re wondering what has happened to the Battle Bus and whether the change is permanent, Insider Gaming has all the important details.</p>







<h2 id="h-where-is-the-battle-bus-in-fortnite">Where is The Battle Bus in Fortnite?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>RIP. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Battle Bus in Fortnite is no more, having been destroyed at the end of the launch trailer for Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1, marking the end of an era.</strong></p>



<p>After the climatic battle to defeat the Dark Presence in the Zero Point event, which saw a who’s who of collabs featuring the likes of Star Wars, Marvel, Superman, K-Pop Demon Hunters, Homer Simpson, Godzilla, Hatsune Miku, and more, it appeared that the band of misfits had gotten by unscathed.</p>



<p>However, that was not the case as in the closing seconds of the Chapter 7 Season 1 launch trailer, the Battle Bus was blown out of the sky, and now, instead of thanking the bus driver when entering a match, you pay respects instead as you surf the waves on the way to the island.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-the-battle-bus-coming-back">Is the Battle Bus Coming Back?</h2>



<p><strong>Yes, the Battle Bus is returning to Fortnite and is not gone permanently, and the absence of the Battle Bus is only for a few days, as it will be back in commission on December 4.</strong></p>



<p>The wreckage of the Battle Bus can be found on the island in Chapter 7, Season 1, and interacting with Dummy, an NPC, nearby results in a mini quest to gather materials to repair the bus, which Dummy intends to do.</p>



<p>At the start of Chapter 7, popular alternative modes to Battle Royale like Reload, Blitz, and Fortnite OG are not available, due to the bus being destroyed, but they will be back in the near future—which implies the bus will also be returning.</p>



<p>Expect the repair of the Battle Bus to play a major part in the early parts of the story in Chapter 7, Season 1, with more to be revealed in the coming weeks.</p>







<hr>



<p>What are your early impressions of Fortnite Chapter 7 Season 1? Share your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-most-expensive-physical-copy-ever-has-been-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details of the sale of the most expensive copy of the game ever,</a> and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-to-feature-quentin-tarantinos-dream-kill-bill-chapter-later-this-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming Kill Bill chapter.</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/what-happened-to-the-battle-bus-fortnite-chapter-7/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch’s Most Subscribed Streamers Are Tarkov Creators, And It’s Not Even Close]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/twitch-most-subscribed-streamers-tarkov-creators/</link>
            <guid>1368544</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov is once again blowing up as the game pushes through the 1.0 release window and into whatever comes next. Two weeks ago, the game graduated from a beta state it had sat in for almost eight years, moving into a full release format and being listed on Steam for the first time.</p>



<p>Now, thanks to an ongoing Twitch Drops campaign, the game is bigger than ever on the popular streaming platform, and the most-subscribed creators on the site are dedicated solely to Escape from Tarkov. They beat everyone from Kai Cenat to Caseoh, and from Jynxzi to Jason the Ween.</p>







<h2 id="h-escape-from-tarkov-on-top-by-almost-double">Escape from Tarkov On Top… By Almost Double</h2>



<p>The biggest streamer in the world right now by active subscriptions on Twitch is Pestily, arguably the most prolific Escape from Tarkov streamer in the business. Pestily has been streaming Tarkov since the earliest days and is almost synonymous with the extraction shooter, having become something of a personal friend to the title’s developers at Battlestate Games.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, Pestily boasted a whopping 132,310 subscriptions, all thanks to an ongoing Twitch Drops campaign that sees Escape from Tarkov players rewarded for gifting subs to streamers broadcasting the game.</p>



<p>This makes Pestily the most-subscribed streamer on the planet.</p>



<p>He’s closely followed by LVNDMARK (read: Landmark), a North American creator who sat on 90,404 subscriptions at the time of publishing.</p>



<p>The list doesn’t end there, though, as here are some other Escape from Tarkov creators <a href="https://twitchtracker.com/subscribers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">topping the leaderboard</a>:</p>



<ul>
<li>SheefGG – 53,942</li>



<li>Glorious_E – 31,240</li>



<li>WillerZ – 17,579</li>



<li>Gingy – 15,781</li>



<li>StankRat – 10,121</li>
</ul>



<p>Behind Pestily, the next closest streamer in terms of subscriptions is Kai Cenat, with 70,097.</p>



<p>Sure, most of these subscriptions will be short-lived, as they’ll have been gifted on a one-month basis that will see tens of thousands of them disappear when the renewal window rolls around next month, but it’s nothing if not indicative of the sheer power of Escape from Tarkov, even ten years after it hit the market in alpha.</p>







<p>Have you given any gifted subs to secure drops in Escape from Tarkov? Let us know which streamer you’ve backed on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-nikita-voice-hurry/">Nikita’s voicelines can be unlocked in Tarkov right now</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/twitch-most-subscribed-streamers-tarkov-creators/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Escape from Tarkov Code Unlocks Nikita’s Voice, But You Need to Hurry]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-nikita-voice-hurry/</link>
            <guid>1368469</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlestate Games has skipped over the issues plaguing one of the rarest rewards in Escape from Tarkov and just issued a code that will give you <strong>Nikita’s voicelines </strong>instantly in the spearhead extraction shooter title. This is in response to waves of people complaining that Twitch drops, which are supposed to unlock the voice, simply aren’t working as intended.</p>



<p>If you want to unlock Nikita Buyanov’s voicelines in Escape from Tarkov, the code you need is right down below.</p>







<h2 id="h-nikita-voice-code-for-escape-from-tarkov">Nikita Voice Code for Escape from Tarkov</h2>



<p>If you want to unlock Nikita’s voicelines in Escape from Tarkov, you need to use the following code: <strong>WILWILBE</strong>.</p>



<p>Like any other code, this <span>can be redeemed via the escapefromtarkov.com site&nbsp;<strong>or&nbsp;</strong>through</span> the launcher. Once you’ve entered the code, you’ll be met with a <strong>green message </strong>if it worked, just like the one below:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>However, there’s a huge catch. You’ve only got <strong>three days </strong>until the code becomes invalid, so if you’re reading this guide after December 2nd or 3rd, you’re out of luck, and you might never get the voicelines.</p>



<p>Escape from Tarkov recently launched into a 1.0 state after more than a decade in development. It was the biggest milestone in the game’s history, but it was somewhat marred by network issues, server instability, and a hefty assortment of bugs, all of which led to Battlestate Games <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bsg-apologize-escape-from-tarkov-launch-problems/">issuing a public apology</a>.</p>



<p>That being said, the game has now become more accessible and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-getting-easier-first-time-decade/">easier for newcomers</a>, and in our recent <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-review-ultimate-extraction-shooter/">Escape from Tarkov review</a> (which scored maximum marks), we wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Through thick and thin, Escape from Tarkov has prevailed. It’s an enormous, deep, and rich game that’s still evolving, it offers unparalleled emotional experiences, and it looks, sounds, and feels great while doing all that. It’s the most punishing game you’ll ever play, but if you put enough hours into understanding this gem of a title, you’ll come to appreciate that it is a generational masterpiece of the extraction shooter market.</p>
</blockquote>







<p>Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you managed to secure Nikita’s voice in Tarkov.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the mystery of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-mystery-statue-new-mexico-2025/">The Game Awards that everyone is trying to solve</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-nikita-voice-hurry/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>