<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:21:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Becomes First Game To Support DLSS 4]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4.1089990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-85476">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Nvidia is releasing its new GeForce RTX 5090 graphics cards on January 30, and with it comes the release of the next generation of Deep Learning Super Sampling (DLSS). On Thursday, CD Projekt Red released a new update for Cyberpunk 2077 to account for the new technology, making it the first game to officially support DLSS 4.</p>



<p>With support for DLSS 4 being added, Cyberpunk 2077 will allow the use of Nvidia’s new multi-frame generation technology that is launching exclusively for the next-gen RTX 50 series graphics cards. This technology helps with overall performance using AI to generate more frames while you play.</p>



<p>In addition to Cyberpunk 2077, DLSS 4 will be available with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dlss-4-to-launch-with-support-for-75-games-and-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at least 75 games</a> when it launches.</p>



<p>You can check out the PC-specific notes from CD Projekt Red below.</p>



<ul>
<li>Added support for DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation for GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards, which boosts FPS by using AI to generate up to three times per traditionally rendered frame – enabled with GeForce RTX 50 Series on January 30th. DLSS 4 also introduces faster single Frame Generation with reduced memory usage for RTX 50 and 40 Series. Additionally, you can now choose between the CNN model or the new Transformer model for DLSS Ray Reconstruction, DLSS Super Resolution, and DLAA on all GeForce RTX graphics cards today. The new Transformer model enhances stability, lighting, and detail in motion.</li>



<li>Fixed artifacts and smudging on in-game screens when using DLSS Ray Reconstruction.</li>



<li>The Frame Generation field in Graphics settings will now properly reset after switching Resolution Scaling to OFF.</li>
</ul>



<p>Are you going to pick up a new RTX 50 series GPU when they launch to take advantage of the new features in games like Cyberpunk 2077?&nbsp;Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1336/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the final year-end <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video game hardware sales data</a> for 2024.&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-david-haddad/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-david-haddad/">Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment President David Haddad is Leaving The Company</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment has announced that its president David Haddad will leave the company.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/">Video Game Hardware Sales Fall 29% For 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>After a small November boost, video game hardware sales ended 2024 on a down note, falling nearly 30% for the year in the United States.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-space-time-smackdown-expansion-reveal/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-space-time-smackdown-expansion-reveal/">Pokemon TCG Pocket Has Revealed Their Space-Time Smackdown Expansion&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokemon TCG Pocket has just revealed their Space-Time Smackdown expansion through a new trailer. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-was-decembers-best-selling-video-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-was-decembers-best-selling-video-game/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Was December’s Best-Selling Video Game</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 was the best-selling video game in the United States for December 2024, according to the latest sales data.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 is the Year of the RPG – Upcoming RPG Games We’re Excited About]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-upcoming-rpg-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-%E2%80%93-upcoming-rpg-games-we%E2%80%99re-excited-about.1089984/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-upcoming-rpg-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Like many of you, I don’t have much time these days to invest hundreds of hours into a single game. I usually run through a new release, play the campaign once, and enjoy multiplayer wherever possible. But when it comes to role-playing games, I can’t help myself. I collect them, leaving many in my backlog for a rainy day. Well, 2025 will be another big year for RPGs, with titles such as Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 and The First Berserker: Khazan on the way!</p>



<h2 id="h-upcoming-rpgs-in-2025-with-release-dates">Upcoming RPGs in 2025 – With Release Dates!</h2>



<p>First and foremost, it’s important to note that we don’t have official release dates for every RPG mentioned here. As such, many of them may be pushed out of 2025 to 2026 and beyond. For titles like The Elder Scrolls VI and The Witcher 4, we’re not even going to bother mentioning them past this point, as there’s no way they’ll realistically launch this year.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Tales of Grace f Remastered – January 17</strong></li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth – January 23</strong></li>



<li><strong>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector – January 23</strong></li>



<li><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 – February 4</strong></li>



<li><strong>The Legend of Heroes: Trails Through Daybreak II – February 14</strong></li>



<li><strong>Avowed – February 18</strong></li>



<li><strong>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii – February 21</strong></li>



<li><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds – February 28</strong></li>



<li><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows – March 20</strong></li>



<li><strong>Atelier Yumia: The Alchemist of Memories &amp; the Envisioned Land – March 21</strong></li>



<li><strong>The First Berserker: Khazan – March 27</strong></li>



<li><strong>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma – May 30</strong></li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-upcoming-rpgs-without-release-dates">Upcoming RPGs Without Release Dates</h2>



<p>Several upcoming role-playing games are rumored to be released in 2025, though there are no specific release dates yet. It’s still early in the year, so fingers crossed!</p>



<ul>
<li>ArcheAge Chronicles</li>



<li>Borderlands 4</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</li>



<li>Fable</li>



<li>Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</li>



<li>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</li>



<li>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</li>



<li>Wuchang: Fallen Fathers</li>
</ul>



<p>Oh, and here’s hoping we see Black Myth: Wukong on Xbox Series X|S this year, too!</p>



<p>What’s the one RPG you’re most excited to play? Let us know in the comments, or visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forums</a> to discuss RPGs with us!</p>



<hr>



<p>Speaking of upcoming RPGs, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rebel-wolves-dawnwalker-bandai-namco/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rebel Wolves’ Dawnwalker will be published by Bandai Namco</a>, but we don’t expect it in 2025.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>