<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:58:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7 Will Feature 16 6v6 Maps At Launch, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-feature-16-6v6-maps-at-launch-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7-will-feature-16-6v6-maps-at-launch-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1272777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The latest Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 leak has revealed that 16 6v6 maps will be available at launch. </p>



<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 leaks have been surfacing in large numbers recently, with several new details emerging over the past couple of days. We recently learned that the upcoming title will feature some remastered maps and also the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-leaks-remastered-maps-a-return-of-specialist/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">return of specialist abilities</a>. Now, we know how many 6v6 maps will be available at launch. </p>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-will-feature-13-original-6v6-maps">Black Ops 7 Will Feature 13 Original 6v6 Maps</h2>



<p>The details about Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 6v6 maps come from a reliable COD leaker/insider, TheGhostOfHope. According to their recent post on <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1957173644649488771" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), 16 6v6 maps will be available at launch. Out of these, there are 13 original maps and three remastered ones from Black Ops 2. </p>



<p>Moreover, two maps will be available at launch for large-scale Skirmish, which features the leaked <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-accidentally-reveals-20v20-wingsuit-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wingsuit mode</a>. Lastly, players can expect “plentiful” post-launch content. For comparison, Black Ops 6 had 12 6v6 maps at launch and 4 for Gunfight. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>There will be 16 6v6 maps at launch for Black Ops 7.</p><p>13 Original 6v6 maps &amp; 3 Remastered 6v6 maps that are from Black Ops 2.</p><p>There is also 2 maps at launch for the Skirmish large scale mode w/ wingsuits that was leaked before.</p><p>Post Launch content is expected to be plentiful. <a href="https://t.co/as6VP5TL4E">pic.twitter.com/as6VP5TL4E</a></p></div>— Hope (@TheGhostOfHope) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1957173644649488771?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 17, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-co-op-campaign-characters-leaked">Black Ops 7 Co-Op Campaign Characters Leaked </h2>



<p>Hope also provided players with a Black Ops 7 campaign <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1957124861173678175" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">leak</a> yesterday, which revealed which characters will be available for 4-person co-op. These include David “Section” Mason, Mike Harper, Eric Samuels, and Chloe “Karma” Lynch. However, as the information about the Black Ops 7 campaign characters and the launch maps doesn’t come from an official source, readers should treat it with caution. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The Four Characters that are available for the 4 person Co Op Campaign in Black Ops 7 are:</p><p>– David “Section” Mason<br>– Mike Harper<br>– Eric Samuels<br>– Chloe “Karma” Lynch <a href="https://t.co/7BHbpd1Fn6">pic.twitter.com/7BHbpd1Fn6</a></p></div>— Hope (@TheGhostOfHope) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1957124861173678175?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 17, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In other news, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-avalon-map-campaign/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s exclusive report</a> on Call of Duty: Black Ops 7’s campaign, which states it will merge with a 32-player mode on ‘Avalon’. Also, the game is set to release on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-releases-november-14/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">November 14, 2025</a>, and will reportedly not be available for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-wont-launch-on-nintendo-switch-2-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Switch 2 at launch</a>. What are your thoughts on Black Ops 7 featuring 16 6v6 maps? Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-datamine-reveals-larger-maps-and-new-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s latest datamine, which reveals larger maps and new vehicles</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-feature-16-6v6-maps-at-launch-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 Pass: All Exclusive BF6 Rewards & How to Get Them]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2042-road-to-battlefield-6-pass-all-exclusive-bf6-rewards-how-to-get-them/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-2042-road-to-battlefield-6-pass-all-exclusive-bf6-rewards-how-to-get-them.1272774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Battlefield 6 Open Beta may be over, but there’s still work to be done to prepare for the release, with a fresh slew of exclusive rewards available to earn through the Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 Pass.</p>



<p>Due to be released on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-release-date-officially-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">October 10</a>, Battlefield 6 is one of the most anticipated games of the year, which was proven by it taking just a few hours for over <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-battlefield-6-conucrrent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">half a million concurrent players</a> to assemble on Steam. </p>



<p>While it’s too late to earn the exclusive Battlefield 6 Open Beta rewards that were available, there’s now more loot to secure to bolster your locker before the game releases. Here are all the details.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-battlefield-2042-road-to-battlefield-6-rewards-amp-how-to-get-them">All Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 Rewards &amp; How to Get Them</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Loot to earn. Image via EA</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Six exclusive cosmetic bundles are available in the Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 pass, which will be immediately unlocked in Battlefield 6 on release.</strong></p>



<p>The rewards are cosmetic items, so won’t provide any boost to you in gameplay, but are a decent way of showing your support to the Battlefield franchise and you can flex on other players in the lobby with items they won’t be able to get their hands on.</p>



<p>The Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 Pass is available now and expires on October 7, just a few days before the release of Battlefield 6. In total, 30 exclusive rewards are available, as <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1957412193198100646]" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">announced on X</a> (formerly Twitter).</p>



<p>Check out all the exclusive rewards available in the pass in the table below.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Name</th><th data-align="center">Type</th><th data-align="center">Tier</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Western Front Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Weapon Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">8</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Muller Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Weapon Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">19</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Aurora Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Vehicle Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Blackburn Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Vehicle Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">40</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Commander Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Operator Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">49</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Sovereign Soldier Bundle</td><td data-align="center">Operator Cosmetic</td><td data-align="center">60</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-what-other-rewards-are-available">What Other Rewards Are Available?</h2>



<p><strong>While the highlight of the pass is undoubtedly the exclusive rewards available to secure for Battlefield 6, there’s plenty more up for grabs with 60 free tiers and over 50 new rewards.</strong></p>



<p>This includes a journey back in time through the Battlefield franchise, with rewards inspired by Battlefield 1, Battlefield Bad Company 2, Battlefield 3, and Battlefield 4.</p>



<p>There are still a few months to go until Battlefield 6 releases, so working through the Battlefield 2042 Road to Battlefield 6 Pass is a good way to kill time while you wait.</p>



<p>Are you planning on diving into Battlefield 2042 to unlock these exclusive Battlefield 6 rewards? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Battlefield, check out claims that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-annual-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the franchise is planning to become an annual release</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-datamine-reveals-larger-maps-and-new-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">huge maps revealed in a Battlefield 6 datamine</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-2042-road-to-battlefield-6-pass-all-exclusive-bf6-rewards-how-to-get-them/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter Movie Photo Teases WWE Superstar Cody Rhodes as Guile]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-photo-teases-wwe-superstar-cody-rhodes-as-guile/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-movie-photo-teases-wwe-superstar-cody-rhodes-as-guile.1272714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The 2026 Street Fighter 6 movie is shaping up nicely. Cody Rhodes has been touted as one of the big-name stars set to light up the Street Fighter stage, and while it’s not official, we think we’ve gotten an idea of how Guile could look, presumably, with Cody playing (and looking) the part.</p>



<p>It’s not uncommon for WWE superstars to transition from the hallowed grounds of the squared circle to the silver screen. The likes of Hulk Hogan, Andre the Giant, and Rowdy Roddy Piper famously paved the way. Dwayne ‘The Rock’ Johnson was the one to make the complete leap from professional wrestler to actor.</p>



<p>Others have followed suit—such as John Cena—and the new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-has-reportedly-lined-up-chun-li-balrog-actors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Street Fighter</a> movie could catapult Cody Rhodes into greater superstardom.</p>



<h2 id="h-first-cody-rhodes-teaser-as-guile-for-2026-street-fighter-movie">First Cody Rhodes Teaser as Guile For 2026 Street Fighter Movie</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Acting has more than one royal family. Credit to 2K</figcaption></figure>



<p>Actor and comedian <a href="https://www.instagram.com/andrewschulz/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Andrew Schulz</a> is playing Dan in the Street Fighter movie. They recently took to their personal Instagram page to share a story showing the shadow of someone sporting an iconic hairstyle—Guile from Street Fighter.</p>



<p>Guile’s inverted shaven style is equal parts bizarre and legendary. I’ve never tried to replicate it, and it’s not something I’m going to try—although it’s nothing a few cans of hairspray couldn’t sort.</p>



<p>Again, we’ve not had official confirmation that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-casts-m-bison-and-eyes-wwes-cody-rhodes-for-guile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cody Rhodes is playing Guile</a>. Eagle-eyed fans can infer this to be the case if they look at the song mentioned in the IG story. If you didn’t know, Kingdom by Downstait is Rhodes’ famous theme song he’s used for years. Put 2 and 2 together, and I think we get the picture.</p>



<div><article><p><span>A teaser of Cody Rhodes as Guile on the set of the Street Fighter movie 👀

(IG | andrewschulz) </span></p></article></div>



<p>The Street Fighter Movie cast also features more rumors and confirmed names, including Jason Momoa, 50 Cent, and fellow WWE star Roman Reigns.</p>



<p>Will the Street Fighter movie be a knockout? Or will it be a swing and a miss? Let me know through the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out more IG news, such as a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-poll-reveals-communitys-favorite-map/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 Open Beta poll revealing the community’s favorite map</a> and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-petition-ceo-resignation-removal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">petition calling for Roblox CEO’s to resign reaching 110,000 signatures in 10 days</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/street-fighter-movie-photo-teases-wwe-superstar-cody-rhodes-as-guile/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Direct For Kirby Air Riders Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-for-kirby-air-riders-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-direct-for-kirby-air-riders-announced.1272672/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Kirby Air Riders is taking center stage at the latest Nintendo Direct showcase, announced for tomorrow.</p>



<p>Due for release on Nintendo Switch 2 later this year, Kirby Air Riders is the first new game in the franchise since 2022’s Kirby and the Forgotten Land and is one of the big remaining Switch 2 launches this year.</p>



<p>The latest Nintendo Direct continues the approach of focusing on a single game rather than several titles, an approach already seen this year with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-revealed-during-mario-kart-world-direct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mario Kart World</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/donkey-kong-bananza-direct-announced-by-nintendo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, and plenty of details are set to be revealed.</p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-direct-announced-for-august-19">Nintendo Direct Announced For August 19</h2>



<figure><figcaption>More details coming. Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a social media <a href="https://x.com/NintendoUK/status/1957427985625088145" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post on X</a> (formerly Twitter), Nintendo announced the Kirby Air Raiders Direct would take place on August 19 at 6am PT/8am CT/9am ET/2pm BST/11pm AEST.</p>



<p>The announcement stated the livestream presentation will “last 45 minutes” and provides an “in-depth look” at the title, releasing exclusively on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<p>A social media <a href="https://x.com/KirbyAirRiders" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">account</a> for Kirby Air Riders then went live, which will share the “latest announcements and updates” for the title, which will likely be extremely active following the Nintendo Direct showcase.</p>



<p>Details on exactly what will be shown are unknown, though it’s highly likely that a release date will be provided given we’re approaching the latter end of 2025 and details so far have not been shared.</p>



<p>Further reveals from Nintendo for Switch 2 could be on the cards this week at Gamescom, where the company’s attendance is confirmed.</p>



<p>Are you planning on pre-ordering Kirby Air Raiders on Nintendo Switch 2? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/3327/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news, take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-petition-ceo-resignation-removal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">petitions for the resignation of the Roblox CEO</a> gathering more than 100,000 signatures, and read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-feature-ranked-battles-four-player-pvp-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online features confirmed for Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-for-kirby-air-riders-announced/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>