<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:22:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is Cursed Mode in Black Ops 7 Zombies? New Mode, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-what-is-cursed-mode-zombies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-is-cursed-mode-in-black-ops-7-zombies-new-mode-explained.1353478/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Black Ops 7 has landed, with Zombies once again returning to the Call of Duty franchise, and there is another way to play this time around with the addition of Cursed Mode—and we’ve got an explanation of exactly what it is.</p>



<p>Zombies in Black Ops 7 has plenty to uncover, with an in-depth narrative to follow that continues on from the events of Black Ops 6 and a wealth of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-zombie-camo-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive Camos to unlock</a>.</p>



<p>Cursed Mode in Black Ops 7 Zombies provides the biggest challenge of all, however, and we’ve got a breakdown of what you can expect from the mode.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-cursed-mode-in-black-ops-7-zombies">What is Cursed Mode in Black Ops 7 Zombies?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A new challenge. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Cursed Mode in Black Ops 7 Zombies is a hardcore version of the mode, providing a challenge for those familiar with the Zombies mechanics and turning back a more original style.</strong></p>



<p>Players are limited from the off, starting with just a Pistol, and can unlock Easter Eggs and Quests to unlock ‘Relics’—which have a similar style to Skulls in the Halo franchise. Once unlocked, they can be applied to the start of any Cursed run and provide extra challenge.</p>



<p>Each Relic provides debuffs to increase the challenge, and there are three difficulty tiers of Cursed mode that increase with the amount of Relics activated. However, there are also small buffs available at each difficult level, such as Golden Armor purchasable off the wall in Tier 1.</p>



<p>The core differences for cursed mode are detailed below:</p>



<ul>
<li>Players start the match with Pistol only.</li>



<li>Loadout weapons are unavailable.</li>



<li>Minimap is disabled.</li>



<li>Black Ops 3-style point system.</li>



<li>Modified ammo costs.</li>



<li>Maximum four active Perks.</li>



<li>No Ammo Caches.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-cursed-mode-in-black-ops-7-zombies">How to Unlock Cursed Mode in Black Ops 7 Zombies</h2>



<p><strong>Cursed Mode only becomes available in Black Ops 7 when the Ashes of the Damned main quest has been completed for the first time.</strong></p>



<p>This can be done by finding the steps and working your way through the Ashes of the Damned main quest yourself, or by waiting for the Directed Mode to release—which is expected to arrive in Season 1.</p>



<p>Once unlocked, Cursed Mode is permanently available for players to select as one of the four Zombies options alongside Standard Mode, Directed Mode, and Survival.</p>



<hr>



<p>Should Zombies return to the old style with only a pistol as a starting weapon? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-level-unlocks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to unlock every weapon an</a>d Perk, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-worlds-collide-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details of the campaign’s endgame mode</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-what-is-cursed-mode-zombies/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards 2025 Nominations Coming Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-nominations-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-game-awards-2025-nominations-coming-next-week.1353283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The reveal of the nominations for The Game Awards 2025 is coming next week, according to new social media. With the show coming out on December 11th, 2025, we won’t have to wait long to know the winners.</p>







<p>Started in 2014 after separating from SpikeTV, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2024-most-watched-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards</a> have grown in size and scope since then. Celebrating the best of the year, the show, hosted by Geoff Keighley, is home to several big reveals and moments, which can overshadow things a bit. Even still, with a year as big as 2025 was for games, the competition is sure to be worthy of watching. Plus, with Prime Video users now able to watch it, even more can tune in for the big ceremony. Well, we now know what games will be up for the big awards, including the highly-anticipated Game of the Year category, in less than a week. </p>



<h2 id="h-nominations-for-the-game-awards-2025-on-november-17th-2025">Nominations for The Game Awards 2025 on November 17th, 2025</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://x.com/thegameawards/status/1989073068938211349" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a Twitter/X post</a>, the official Game Awards account finally revealed that <strong>nominations for the awards show</strong> will go live on <strong>Monday, November 17th, 2025</strong>. A livestream announcing all of the titles will happen on <strong>Monday at 9 am PT/12 pm EST</strong>. To find out when it’s live in your time zone, <a href="https://everytimezone.com/s/99b6fbcf">click here</a>. In years past, the videos have ranged from 8-10 minutes and go over every category, lastly having Game of the Year. You’ll be able to watch it go down on YouTube, Twitch, and other social media. We at Insider Gaming will also post the full nominations once available, so stay tuned for that!</p>



<p>As mentioned before, 2025 has been host to several amazing games. From independent games <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/french-president-applauds-clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> and Blue Prince to AAA titles like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-final-launch-trailer-playstation-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei</a> and Donkey Kong Bananza, the competition is fierce. While The Game Awards isn’t the ultimate say-so for what’s the best game of the year, past winners have been called as such. 2024’s Astro Bot and 2022’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-expansion-dlc-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring</a> are still highly regarded. Though, with 2025, it won’t be as clear-cut as other ceremonies.</p>







<p>Are you going to watch The Game Awards nominations on November 17th? What games do you hope are nominated? Any games you think deserve GOTY? Let us know in the comments and on&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more awards, check out our articles on&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-indie-game-awards-2025-nominees-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Indie Game Awards</a> (which we are a part of!) and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/golden-joystick-awards-2025-all-award-nominees/">Golden Joystick</a>. Make sure to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>! Also, we just launched&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gaming-mobile-app-membership-tiers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new app for Insider Gaming</a>&nbsp;on Android (and soon iOS)! Check it out if you get a chance!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-nominations-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>