<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:19:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZywOo Passes S1mple in Major Counter-Strike Milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/zywoo-passes-s1mple-in-major-counter-strike-milestone/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zywoo-passes-s1mple-in-major-counter-strike-milestone.1136856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/zywoo-passes-s1mple-in-major-counter-strike-milestone/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Counter-Strike GOAT debate may never end, but French prodigy Mathieu “ZywOo” Herbaut has reasserted his case, passing a record held by the one and only Oleksandr “s1mple” Kostyljev. However, it could very well be CS2’s fastest rising star that eventually claims the record for himself.</p>



<h2 id="h-zywoo-sets-counter-strike-record-for-most-tournament-mvp-trophies">ZywOo Sets Counter-Strike Record for Most Tournament MVP Trophies</h2>



<p>At ESL Pro League Season 21, Vitality added their second trophy of the year to their case, after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/vitality-stuns-spirit-3-0-in-grand-finals-of-iem-katowice/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claiming IEM Katowice</a> just a month prior. ZywOo was named MVP of both tournaments by HLTV, bringing his MVP career total to 22, passing s1mple’s record of 2021. </p>



<p>To put in perspective how dominant s1mple was in his prime, his most recent MVP award was from IEM Cologne 2022. He hasn’t won an MVP award in more than two years, while ZywOo has won a staggering nine since the start of 2023, and only now has the French superstar finally passed s1mple. S1mple still owns the record for most MVP awards won in a single year, after winning eight in 2021, the same year where he finally won the Major. Both s1mple and ZywOo are also tied with just a single Major win, but ZywOo is in the better position to win a second considering how dominant Vitality is looking to start 2025.</p>



<p>“I’m one ahead of s1mple,” ZywOo <a href="https://www.hltv.org/news/41218/zywoo-i-wont-stop-just-because-i-am-one-in-front-of-s1mple" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told HLTV</a> after winning ESL Pro League Season 21. “I will just keep going, keep grinding, and I will never stop just because I am one in front. I will just show I can go 25, 30 MVPs.”</p>



<p>Right now s1mple’s career is at a crossroads. The 27-year-old is still officially on the NAVI bench, and hasn’t played in a professional match since November during his loan to Falcons. Either ZywOo will set a standard so high that no one will catch it, or a new contender for GOAT status will emerge. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2s-biggest-superstar-donk-dazzles-in-first-match-of-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The player many are watching out for is Danil “donk” Kryshkovets</a>, the rising star of Team Spirit, after a 2024 rookie campaign that saw him win a record-breaking Major and five MVP awards. Still, even if he maintains the pace he set last year, it will take him years to catch up to ZywOo’s record, and that’s assuming the French star stops winning. And given that he’s still only 24, I wouldn’t bet on it.</p>



<p>Will any player ever catch ZywOo’s MVP numbers? Is he the GOAT of Counter-Strike? Let us know in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/esports-world-cup-club-partner-program-2025-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coverage of the Esports World Cup 2025 Club Partners Program announcement</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Look At Johnny Cage, Kitana, and Shao Kahn In Mortal Kombat 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/first-look-at-johnny-cage-kitana-and-shao-kahn-in-mortal-kombat-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-look-at-johnny-cage-kitana-and-shao-kahn-in-mortal-kombat-2.1136742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/first-look-at-johnny-cage-kitana-and-shao-kahn-in-mortal-kombat-2/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A first look at classic Mortal Kombat characters in the upcoming movie has been revealed. In a new exclusive from Entertainment Weekly, Warner Bros. Pictures has released the first look at Johnny Cage, Kitana, and Shao Kahn in Mortal Kombat 2.</p>



<p>Johnny Cage will be played by Karl Urban from The Boys. Resident Evil star Adeline Rudolph plays Kitana while House of David actor Martyn Ford is Shao Kahn.</p>



<p>You can check out the new characters below (click to enlarge).</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<p>Mortal Kombat 2 is the follow up to 2021’s Mortal Kombat. After the first move followed Shang Tsung’s goal of killing Earth’s fighters before the tournament began, the sequel is where the tournament happens. Earth is at risk of losing its 10th-straight tournament. Should that happen, Shao Kahn will invade the planet and take over.</p>



<p>In addition to the tournament itself, franchise co-creator Ed Boon says that the battle between Scorpion and Sub-Zero isn’t finished.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-meet-the-creator-behind-call-of-duty-skill-based-matchmaking-insider-gaming-weekly">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/meet-the-creator-of-call-of-duty-skill-based-matchmaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Meet The Creator Behind Call of Duty Skill-Based Matchmaking—Insider Gaming Weekly</a></h6>



<p>“He’s certainly making appearances that are significant and necessary for the progress of other storylines,” Boon told <a href="https://ew.com/mortal-kombat-2-first-look-karl-urban-johnny-cage-kitana-shao-kahn-exclusive-11696968" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Entertainment Weekly</a>. “He plays a different role. He’s not part of the ‘Super Friends’ trying to defeat Shao Kahn, but his appearance is key and it is very essential for certain parts.”</p>



<p>And though they’ve given fans a look at three new characters coming in Mortal Kombat 2, they aren’t the only ones that will find themselves on the big screen. Jade and Queen Sindel will also play a role in the movie along with “other” characters that haven’t been announced yet.</p>



<p>Mortal Kombat 2 is scheduled to release in theaters on October 24.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-seeking-investors-for-new-entity/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft seeking investors</a> for a new entity. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Next Metro Game Has Been Made ‘Even Darker’ Since The Invasion of Ukraine]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-next-metro-game-darker-ukraine/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-next-metro-game-has-been-made-%E2%80%98even-darker%E2%80%99-since-the-invasion-of-ukraine.1136709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-next-metro-game-darker-ukraine/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Not much is known about the next Metro game, aside from the fact that it exists and in 2023, it was in a playable state. That was what we exclusively reported on, with our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metro-exodus-sequel/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tom Henderson learning</a> that the sequel to 2019’s Metro Exodus was well along the path of development.</p>



<p>In a recent blog post celebrating 15 years of Metro games, 4A Games reflected on the last decade-and-a-half, talking at length about the Russian invasion of Ukraine. It was stressed that, as the developers live through the situation that is ever unfolding, the story for the next Metro game has become ‘even darker’ to reflect what’s happening.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-dark-becomes-darker">Dark Becomes Darker</h2>



<p>The Metro titles, which are based on a book series of the same name from Dmitry Glukhovsky, a Russian author, have been on the market since 2010. The series kicked off with Metro 2033, then Metro Last Light was released in 2013. After a lengthier pause, Metro Exodus dropped in 2019, and in 2024, a VR title, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metro-awakening-review-meta-quest-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metro Awakening</a>, was also released.</p>



<p>Fans are eagerly awaiting the next instalment of this epic post-apocalyptic franchise, which many have dubbed ‘Fallout in Russia’ over the years. Metro might be set amidst a nuclear apocalypse, but it’s infinitely more morbid and stricken with horror influences than Bethesda Game Studios’ end-of-the-world series.</p>



<p>In a blog post <a href="https://www.4a-games.com.mt/4a-dna/2025/3/16/metro-15th-anniversary-update" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">paying tribute to 15 years of Metro</a>, the 4A Games team revealed how the franchise will become even darker when the next game hits the market:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>As we said in our last studio update, in 2022 a full-scale russian invasion changed how we wanted to tell the story of the next Metro game. As art became life for many of our developers in Ukraine, we drew from that lived experience <strong>to create an even darker story</strong>, those themes already present in Metro becoming ever-more apparent and important. </p>



<p>As conflict, the struggle for power, the horrors of tyranny, and the price of freedom have become part of our lives over the past 3+ years, we are still living and working during this wartime, and that inevitably shapes the games we make.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The next project is being created hand-in-hand with Dmitry Glukhovsky, the creator of Metro and currently a target of Russian law enforcement. The outspoken activist has been sentenced to jail for his opposition to the war in Ukraine. The team at 4A Games poured out their sentiments about Glukhovsky in the post:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Dmitry has always spoken out against the war in Ukraine from the start – a courageous decision for any Russian, that has seen him sentenced to jail (in absentia) – and we are proud to have him as a friend and co-creator as we tell this next, and never more relevant chapter of Metro together.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>No release window has been established for the next Metro title, and presently, we don’t have a clue what it’ll look like. As a fan of the franchise since day one, I’m certainly excited to see what comes next.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ai-upgrade-patch/">Escape from Tarkov’s AI upgrade has been released</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>