<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:01:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can’t Afford A Nintendo Switch 2? Buy A Switch 1, Nintendo Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cant-afford-a-nintendo-switch-2-buy-a-switch-1-nintendo-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/can%E2%80%99t-afford-a-nintendo-switch-2-buy-a-switch-1-nintendo-says.1158426/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cant-afford-a-nintendo-switch-2-buy-a-switch-1-nintendo-says/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders are opening up in various regions—not you, United States—today and tomorrow, meaning that, likely, millions of people are set to make the $450+ purchase on the new console. Unfortunately, however, there are plenty of others that won’t be able to afford the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/entertainment/nintendo-switch-2-price-tariffs-1.7503598" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CBC</a>, which took place prior to the console’s pre-orders being delayed in the United States, Nintendo of America’s president Doug Bowser was asked about the console’s price and what players who can’t afford it should do. His response? Play the original Switch.</p>



<h6 id="h-read-more-nintendo-addresses-nintendo-switch-2-game-prices">READ MORE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-addresses-nintendo-switch-2-game-prices/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Addresses Nintendo Switch 2 Game Prices</a></h6>



<p>“As we look at Nintendo Switch 2 and you think about the feature sets that I talked about … we believe that the pricing is appropriate for the value of the machine and the gameplay experience overall,” Bowser said.</p>



<p>“We recognize there are some people that may not be able to afford [the Switch 2’s] price point. That’s why we wanted to make the other Switch platforms available, so [people] still have an opportunity to come into our gaming universe, be a part of these characters in these worlds, and see value, if you will, in whatever rung of the platform they come in.”</p>



<p>While it’s not as direct as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J_JVVUnCWnY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Don Mattrick’s response regarding</a> the Xbox One requiring a constant internet connection in 2013, it still isn’t something that’s likely to sit well with a lot of players. </p>



<p>What do you make of Bowser’s comments towards people who may not be able to afford a Nintendo Switch 2? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1830/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what popular fan-requested feature the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-wont-have-achievements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2 won’t have</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Pre-Orders Delayed In Canada At The Last Minute]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-delayed-in-canada/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-delayed-in-canada-at-the-last-minute.1158372/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-delayed-in-canada/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-109134">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders in Canada were set to begin at 12:01am ET on April 9 in some stores. Unfortunately, players across the country will have to wait as Nintendo has delayed pre-orders for the console in the country at the last minute.</p>



<p>First reported by <a href="https://mobilesyrup.com/2025/04/08/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-canada-delay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MobileSyrup</a>, Nintendo confirmed the decision to wait until a later date.</p>



<p>“Pre-orders for Nintendo Switch 2 in Canada will not start on April 9, 2025 in order to align with the timing of pre-orders to be determined in the U.S. Nintendo will provide updated information at a later date. The launch date of June 5, 2025 is unchanged.”</p>



<p>The statement reads similar to the one provided when the company <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-delays-switch-2-preorders-in-us-due-to-trump-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed pre-orders in the United States</a> last week.</p>







<p>The Nintendo Switch is currently priced at $629 CAD for the base system and $699 CAD for the Mario Kart World Bundle. It’s currently unknown if there could be any change to pricing of the system in the country or if it will just be, as the company said, to align with United States plans.</p>



<p>What do you think of Nintendo also delaying pre-orders of the Switch 2 in Canada? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1829/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read what the company had to say <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-addresses-nintendo-switch-2-game-prices/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">about the pricing of its games</a> on the new console. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/schedule-1-april-7-update-adds-pawn-shop-boutique/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/schedule-1-april-7-update-adds-pawn-shop-boutique/">
                                Schedule 1 April 7 Update Adds Pawn Shop &amp; Boutique With an Eyebrow-Raising Name                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The April 7 update for Schedule 1 adds promised features, including a new Pawn Shop to make dealings, and an interestingly named Boutique.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hades-2-launching-as-nintendo-switch-2-console-exclusive/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hades-2-launching-as-nintendo-switch-2-console-exclusive/">
                                Hades 2 Launching as Nintendo Switch 2 Console Exclusive                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developer Supergiant Games has announced Hades 2 is launching as a console exclusive on Nintendo Switch 2 before PlayStation and Xbox.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/modern-warfare-2-3-rated-in-australia/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/modern-warfare-2-3-rated-in-australia/">
                                Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 &amp; 3 Rated In Australia                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With rumors circulating of a rerelease, both Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 and 3 have been rated in Australia.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-class-specialisations-revealed-in-new-datamine/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-class-specialisations-revealed-in-new-datamine/">
                                Battlefield Labs Class Specialisations Revealed in New Datamine                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Battlefield Labs new datamine reveals it will feature four levels of Class Specialisations, which seem a lot like Field Upgrades. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Clair Obscur Expedition 33 on Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/is-clair-obscur-expedition-33-on-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-clair-obscur-expedition-33-on-xbox-game-pass.1158369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/is-clair-obscur-expedition-33-on-xbox-game-pass/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Anticipation is high for Clair Obscur Expedition Expedition 33, an upcoming turn-based RPG with real-time fighting mechanics, and players want to know if the title will be available on Game Pass.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clair Obscur Expedition 33</a> is inspired by the Belle Epoque, a period in French history from 1871 to 1914. Since there was no war, the era is remembered for being peaceful, and technology flourished. For example, The Eiffel Tower and the Paris Subway system were created, but Sandfall Interactive’s debut project puts a dystopian spin on that quiet time.</p>



<p>In this universe, there is a paintress. When she paints a number on a monolith, everyone of that age turns to smoke and fades away. That number decreases every year, and one group sets out to stop her before she paints their age. </p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-clair-obscur-expedition-33-on-xbox-game-pass">Can You Play Clair Obscur Expedition 33 on Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>This isn’t the standard turn-based combat you are used to. Image via Sandfall Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Clair Obscur Expedition 33 is a day-one launch for <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/clair-obscur-expedition-33/9PPT8K6GQHRZ/0017" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Game Pass</a> subscribers on PC and Xbox Series X|S.</strong></p>



<p>To get access to games on the day they are released, you need to be a<strong> Game Pass Ultimate subscriber, which costs $19.99 monthly</strong>. </p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-qgOZDRDynw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reveal trailer</a> set the tone for what to expect from this unique take on a turn-based RPG. The Eiffel Tower and Arc de Triomphe are bent and distorted, and the expedition group needs to worry about more than just the paintress. </p>



<p>Strange marionettes and other large beasts have overrun France, and players have an arsenal of turn-based attacks but can also dodge, parry, and counter in real-time by timing the rhythms of attacks to take down every enemy. </p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-play-clair-obscur-expedition-33-on-xbox-game-pass">How to Play Clair Obscur Expedition 33 on Xbox Game Pass</h2>



<p><strong>Once South of Clair Obscur Expedition 33 launches, you need an Ultimate subscription to Xbox Game Pass and a working internet connection to play it.</strong></p>



<p>Here are quick step-by-step instructions showing you what to do once you have your membership:</p>



<ol>
<li>Check your Xbox Game Pass status via your Xbox account.</li>



<li>If it’s active, it’s time to go to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/microsoft-store?msockid=18c366288f2166303b0f72118e066724" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Store</a>&nbsp;on console or PC.</li>



<li>In the search function, look for<strong> Clair Obscur Expedition 33</strong>.</li>



<li>Click on the game page.</li>



<li>Once the option is available, press to download the title.</li>



<li>You can play Cair Obscur Expedition 33 once it’s live!</li>
</ol>



<hr>



<p>Even though Microsoft raised the Xbox Game Pass Ultimate price from $16.99 to $19.99 in 2024, the subscription service is still one of the best deals in gaming and consistently adds new titles to try out. <span>For example,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-south-of-midnight-coming-to-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank">South of Midnight</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-game-pass-this-month/" target="_blank">GTA 5</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hunt-showdown-1896-developer-is-laying-off-employees/" target="_blank">Hunt: Showdown 1896</a>&nbsp;are all joining the service in April</span>.</p>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming Forum</a> if you want to share your thoughts about Clair Obscur Expedition 33 or anything else about the upcoming Xbox Game Pass titles.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>