<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 18:38:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Developers Detail Season And Half-Season Ranks]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks.1105161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-developers-detail-season-and-half-season-ranks/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>With the first half of Season 1 drawing to a close, Marvel Rivals developer NetEase has published a new update regarding ranks. This update helps players understand what to expect at the end of the half and in the second half of the inaugural season and beyond.</p>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/devdiaries/20250210/40954_1210988.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s website</a>, the studio said that the first half of the season will end on February 21. At that time, all rankings will be locked and players ranked Gold and higher will get a costume reward. Those Grandmaster and higher as well as the Top 500 will receive the “Crest of Honor”.</p>



<p>“In the second half of the season, we will be rolling out new costume rewards for Gold rank players, along with brand new Crests of Honor,” NetEase said. “These Crests will recognize players at Grandmaster, Celestial, Eternity, and One Above All (the top 500), each with its own unique design to celebrate your skill!”</p>



<p>After the first-half ranks are settled, they will all be reason when the second half of Season 1 starts that day. When it starts, NetEase says  that players will see their rank drop by four divisions. In future seasons, that drop will be six divisions at the beginning and then a drop of four at the start of the second half of each season.</p>



<p>Lastly, the studio says that in order to make sure only players who actually play during the current season can earn rewards, players will need to play at least 10 matches in competitive mode along with meeting required ranking conditions.</p>



<p>What do you think of how Marvel Rivals is handling in-season ranks? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony turning down the Resistance 4&nbsp;pitch</a> and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phasmophobia-reveals-2025-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2025 roadmap for Phasmophobia</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia Reveals 2025 Roadmap]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/phasmophobia-reveals-2025-roadmap/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobia-reveals-2025-roadmap.1105044/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/phasmophobia-reveals-2025-roadmap/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>New updates for Phasmophobia aren’t ending anytime soon as developer Kinetic Games has released its planned roadmap for 2025.</p>



<p>In a post on <a href="https://www.kineticgames.co.uk/blog/phasmophobia-2025-roadmap" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s website</a>, Kinetic went into details on what Phasmophobia players can expect throughout the year. That includes two major updates, new maps and reworks, and seasonal events.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The first major update is called Chronicle. This update is a revamp to how evidence is recorded during your hunt such as replacing the Photos tab with a Media tab that captures photos, videos, and sound.</p>



<p>“Chronicle will also bring with it a few extra bits aside from what we’ve mentioned, but we’re keeping those a secret until we’re closer to launch,” they said while pointing to a <a href="https://www.kineticgames.co.uk/blog/phasmophobia-dev-preview-18" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">prior development diary</a> with more information.</p>



<p>Regarding player characters, the studio is “refreshing character models, improving animations and adjusting the overall experience when it comes to your Phasmophobia character.” A planned full character customization feature is being pushed to 2026 to allow focus on the Horror 2.0 update. </p>



<h2 id="h-more-map-changes-are-coming">More Map Changes Are Coming</h2>



<p>Moving on to the map changes coming this year, Kinetic Games is reworking 6 Tanglewood Drive, Bleasdale Farmhouse and Grafton Farmhouse. Bleasdale will be released first in March with the other two reworks coming later this year.</p>



<p>“These reworks are all about bringing these maps in line with our full vision for them,” the developers said. “So you can expect to see complete artistic overhauls of each map, including new assets and animations, a high level of visual detail as well as a few layout changes. They’ll still be the maps you’ve grown to love through endless investigations, however.”</p>



<p>There will also be a new small map added to the game.  The studio says that all future maps will be “relatively small”  in order to push out new maps more frequently.</p>



<h2 id="h-beyond-2025">Beyond 2025</h2>



<p>Despite the latest updates being about 2025, Kinetic Games is also focused on the future of Phasmobia, including what’s to come in 2026. The studio is working on its major Horror 2.0 update for the year that includes more new maps and reworks. Details on all of that will come later on, though no timeframe was given.</p>



<p>What do you think of the 2025 roadmap for Phasmophobia? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony turning down the Resistance 4&nbsp;pitch</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Might Be Cracking Down on ‘Shovelware’ Spam Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shovelware-playstation-crack-down-spam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-might-be-cracking-down-on-%E2%80%98shovelware%E2%80%99-spam-games.1105041/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shovelware-playstation-crack-down-spam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In recent months, digital storefronts across all gaming platforms have seemingly become inundated with AI-generated games, ‘shovelware’, and rip-off titles. Many games that make it to these storefronts are questionable at best, boasting copy-and-paste assets, paltry mechanics, and rinse-and-repeat content.</p>



<p>IGN carried out a recent investigation into the state of the quality assurance processes protecting these storefronts, focusing most specifically on PlayStation and Nintendo stores. It was noticed in the last couple of days that some of these ‘spam games’ have been silently stripped from the PS5 store.</p>



<p>Are we about to witness a mass exodus of shovelware games from our digital stores?</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-churn-them-out">Churn Them Out</h2>



<p>PlayStation users were complaining about a shovelware epidemic on the platform’s digital storefronts <strong>years ago</strong>. It’s a problem that has been brewing for a while, but it peaked recently with an investigation that was <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-could-make-fart-fart-boobie-fart-the-game-and-maybe-it-would-eventually-get-taken-down-devs-reveal-why-the-consoles-are-drowning-in-eslop" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">carried out by IGN</a>. It seems that QA processes are slacking, encouraging ‘developers’ to push dozens of asset-flip, AI-generated games to storefronts.</p>



<p>PS4 and PS5 users have noticed the vast amounts of shovelware winding up in their search results – and some developers are standing out as the key culprits.</p>



<p>For instance, <a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/publisher/RandomSpin-Games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">RandomSpin Games</a>, which releases multiple ‘games’ a month, all of which are low-effort, mostly pointless creations. <a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/publisher/breakthrough-gaming" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Breakthrough Gaming</a> is another name. This developer was releasing two or three ‘RPG’ games a month at its peak. How about <a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/publisher/zakym" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Zakym</a>, which in the last five or six weeks has released around a <strong>dozen games</strong> – you can likely imagine how bad they all are.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-quietly-removes-slop-shovelware-ps5-games-following-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a> noticed today that stacks of titles from RandomSpin Games, one of the biggest offenders on PlayStation, have been removed on the DL. It hasn’t been highlighted <strong>why </strong>they’ve been removed, but it <strong>could be </strong>a knock-on impact from IGN’s investigation, and PlayStation’s store operators are getting wiser about these deceptive practices.</p>



<p>Now, what will they do about the ‘scam’ copies that pop up, like the fake Black Myth game or the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-switch-clone/">rip-off version of The Last of Us</a> on Nintendo Switch? </p>



<p>Have you been troubled by shovelware on the PlayStation store? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-section-disney-plus/">Marvel Rivals has made it to Disney Plus</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>