<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:46:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atomfall Map Size Explained—How Big is The Map?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/atomfall-map-size-explained-how-big-is-the-map/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atomfall-map-size-explained%E2%80%94how-big-is-the-map.1144014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/atomfall-map-size-explained-how-big-is-the-map/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Atomfall map is split up into several key areas you’ll backtrack through. It’s a dense, detailed world, and well worth exploring. But if you want to know how big the map is and what it holds, we’ve got answers. </p>



<p>An RPG’s map size is an unavoidable question at this point. I’d say the sandbox stylings of GTA kickstarted the topic many years ago. Ubisoft popularized the construction of gigantic maps, and now it’s commonplace. We have reached a point where maps are getting too big, and it’s nice when an RPG cuts back on the square-feet of land.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/atomfall-review-rebellion-curveball/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Atomfall</a> promises an adventure through an alternate-history Cumbria. The area is quite a decent part of England, but has Rebellion brought Cumbria to life, to scale?</p>



<h2 id="h-is-atomfall-open-world">Is Atomfall Open World?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A wicked Wicker Man. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Atomfall is not a bona fide open-world title and is akin to a semi-open-world title featuring several interconnected biomes.</strong></p>



<p>The best way to describe <a href="https://atomfall.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Atomfall</a>‘s map is like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-we-know-about-borderlands-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands</a>. It has a ton of large-scale areas, but you need to go through a loading screen to get to them, so it’s not a completely open world. I prefer this kind of map in many ways as it allows the developer to concentrate their efforts on creating unique, focused biomes.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-big-is-atomfall-s-map-all-areas-explained">How Big is Atomfall’s Map? All Areas Explained</h2>



<p><strong>Collectively, Atomfall’s map is comparable to a medium-sized open world game and consists of six large areas.</strong></p>



<p>Atomfall is made up of six main biomes:</p>



<ul>
<li>Casterfell Woods</li>



<li>The Interchange</li>



<li>Sewer Tunnels</li>



<li>Slatten Dale</li>



<li>Skethermoor</li>



<li>Wyndham Village</li>
</ul>



<p>Outside of The Interchange and Sewer Tunnels, the remaining four areas are all outdoors. They feature an assortment of POIs, NPCs, enemies, hidden bunkers and underground areas, and mines. To explore one of the biomes inside out, you’re looking at several hours each, quite easily.</p>



<p>The Interchange is the basis of the story, whereas the Sewer Tunnels are an efficient way of getting from area to area.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-atomfall-area-pois">All Atomfall Area POIs</h2>



<p>Each main biome is split into several locations of interest. If you need reference points or reminders, we’ve put together a handy table showing you every key area and where they are.</p>



<h3 id="h-casterfell-woods">Casterfell Woods</h3>



<ul>
<li>Boatyard</li>



<li>Bunker L9</li>



<li>Casterfell Dam</li>



<li>Casterfell Dam Data Store</li>



<li>Castle Ruins</li>



<li>Cellar</li>



<li>Datlow Hall</li>



<li>Datlow Hall Grounds</li>



<li>Druids’ Camp</li>



<li>Garden Centre</li>



<li>Helicopter Crash Site</li>



<li>Logging Mill</li>



<li>Radio Tower</li>



<li>Remote Bunker</li>



<li>Sewer Tunnels</li>



<li>The Interchange</li>



<li>The Speaking Cave</li>



<li>The Old Mine</li>



<li>Trader Camp</li>



<li>Village Outskirts</li>



<li>Watermill Cellar</li>



<li>Wyndham Village</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-the-interchange">The Interchange</h3>



<ul>
<li>Central Processor</li>



<li>Crane Controls</li>



<li>Data Store Alpha</li>



<li>Data Store Bravo</li>



<li>Data Store Charlie</li>



<li>Data Store Delta</li>



<li>Medical</li>



<li>Medical Tunnels</li>



<li>Oberon Dig Site</li>



<li>Robotics</li>



<li>Slatten Dale</li>



<li>Skethermoor</li>



<li>Windscale Plant</li>



<li>Wyndham Village</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-slatten-dale">Slatten Dale</h3>



<ul>
<li>Bunker L6</li>



<li>Bunker L7</li>



<li>Convoy Wreckage</li>



<li>Derelict Bunker</li>



<li>Helicopter Crash Site</li>



<li>Interchange: Slatten Dale Entrance</li>



<li>Outlaw Camp</li>



<li>Outlaw’s Cave</li>



<li>Railyard</li>



<li>Sewer Entrance</li>



<li>Slate Mine Caves</li>



<li>Trader Camp</li>



<li>Waterwheels</li>



<li>Wyndham Village</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-skethermoor">Skethermoor</h3>



<ul>
<li>Brinsop Manor</li>



<li>Brinsop Manor Cellar</li>



<li>Cottage Cellar</li>



<li>Greenhouses</li>



<li>Nora’s Barn</li>



<li>Protocol Camp</li>



<li>Protocol Field Station</li>



<li>Protocol Workshop</li>



<li>Radio Tower</li>



<li>Road Blockade</li>



<li>Ruined Hamlet</li>



<li>Slate Mine Caves</li>



<li>Slate Mine Ruins</li>



<li>Skethermoor Prison</li>



<li>The Interchange</li>



<li>Trader Camp</li>



<li>Vehicle Storage Bunker</li>



<li>Wyndham Village</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-wyndham-village">Wyndham Village</h3>



<ul>
<li>Brewery Cellar</li>



<li>Casterfell Woods</li>



<li>Forgotten Cellar</li>



<li>Grendel’s Head</li>



<li>Mereview Hotel</li>



<li>Mill Grounds</li>



<li>Protocol Outpost</li>



<li>Sewer Tunnels</li>



<li>Slatten Dale</li>



<li>Skethermoor</li>



<li>St. Katherine’s Church</li>



<li>The Bakery</li>



<li>The Boathouse</li>



<li>The Interchange</li>



<li>The Little Tea Room</li>



<li>Village Hall</li>



<li>Village Green</li>



<li>Village Shop</li>



<li>Wyndham Garage</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>Check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-metal-detector-in-atomfall/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to get the Metal Detector</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-upgrade-weapons-in-atomfall/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to upgrade weapons</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-open-sewer-tunnels-in-atomfall-where-to-find-sewer-tunnels-key/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get the early-game Sewer Tunnels Key</a> in Atomfall.</p>



<p>Let us know if there’s any part of Atomfall you’re struggling with. Are you hoping Rebellion makes a sequel in the future?</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Ballistic is Finally Getting a New Map: Hammer Fall]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-ballistic-is-finally-getting-a-new-map-hammer-fall/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-ballistic-is-finally-getting-a-new-map-hammer-fall.1143951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-ballistic-is-finally-getting-a-new-map-hammer-fall/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fortnite’s early access FPS game mode, Ballistic, is finally getting a new map, Hammer Fall, three months after it launched.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fortnite’s Ballistic game mode was released in early access on December 11, 2024, and since that day, players have been messing about in just one map, Skyline 10. However, Fortnite has just announced v.34.20, which will introduce Ballistic’s first new map since launch, along with balancing changes, economy adjustments and bug fixes.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-hammer-fall-gets-added-to-fortnite-ballistic">Hammer Fall Gets Added to Fortnite Ballistic</h2>



<p>Hammer Fall is the latest castle-themed map introduced for Fortnite Ballistic, adding a medieval theme to the game mode. The “castle’s verticality” will differentiate this map from Skyline 10, providing “comfortable cover, angles to hold, and corners to play.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hammer Fall will first be released as a shell map, meaning it will arrive without any environmental art. This will allow the devs to quickly change the map’s layout if there’s any feedback. The final art and finishing touches will be added to Hammer Fall once Fortnite Ballistic players thoroughly test it.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-ballistic-balancing-and-economy-changes">Fortnite Ballistic Balancing and Economy Changes</h2>



<p>The new Fortnite Ballistic v34.20 update will add buffs to weapons like Hammer Pump Shotgun, Frenzy Auto Shotgun, Thunder Burst SMG and Striker AR. Some weapon prices have been adjusted, too.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-weapon-buffs">Weapon Buffs</h3>



<ul>
<li>Hammer Pump Shotgun’s fire rate has slightly increased, and its point-blank damage has increased significantly.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Frenzy Auto Shotgun’s point-blank and mid-range damage have increased.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Thunder Burst SMG’s damage and fire rate have slightly increased.&nbsp;</li>



<li>The range at which damage falloff begins has been reduced for the Striker AR.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-economy-adjustments">Economy Adjustments</h3>



<ul>
<li>Reaper Sniper Rife: Price decreased from 4700 to 4500 Credits.</li>



<li>Striker AR: Prince increased from 2500 to 2700 Credits.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Nemesis AR: Price increased from 2500 to 2700 Credits.</li>



<li>Drum Gun: Price decreased from 3500 to 3200 Credits.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-upcoming-changes-to-fortnite-ballistic-nbsp">Upcoming Changes to Fortnite Ballistic&nbsp;</h2>



<p>In the <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/ballistic-34-20-balance-changes-and-more" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> for the Fortnite Ballistic v34.20 update, the developers addressed all the feedback they have received so far. Players want new maps, weapons, gadgets, additional starter pistols, better ways to deal with AFK players, new additions to the HUD, and efficient inventory management.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The developers have stated that adding new weapons and gadgets to Ballistic is one of their main priorities, and they will arrive soon. New pistol options will also come. They are currently figuring out how to deal with AFK players. However, they have confirmed that an “option to surrender” is in development and will likely arrive in summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The devs have discussed new crosshair options and ways to improve inventory management regarding HUD additions. However, they don’t have concrete plans to share right now. They are working on a change to show which player on your team has the Rift Point device better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lastly, their other major priority is “dialing in the first-person feel and improving the core of how the game handles first-person weapons.” These are being worked on and will be revealed in the “improvements and fixes” sections of upcoming blog posts.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fortnite Ballistic Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wYdar6yxg7E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, Fortnite <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-og-season-3-officially-confirmed-and-arrives-in-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OG Season 3 is releasing today</a>. Also, a recent claim stated that Fortnite could get a ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-getting-a-kendrick-lamar-emote-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kendrick Lamar Emote</a>’. What are your thoughts on Fortnite Ballistic’s new map, Hammer Fall?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pacific-drive-next-major-update-endless-expeditions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pacific Drive adding their most-asked feature in the next update</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>