<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:57:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Patent Suggests DS Games Could Come To Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-ds-patent-nso/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-patent-suggests-ds-games-could-come-to-switch.1327078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If a new Nintendo patent is true, we may be seeing DS games on the Nintendo Switch 2 soon.</p>



<p>Released earlier this year, the Nintendo Switch 2 has become one of Nintendo’s best-selling consoles. With its catalog growing each month, with the latest being <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-hands-on-preview-the-new-battle-system-could-become-the-new-standard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a>, there’s a lot to enjoy. For those who pine for the past, the Nintendo Switch Online brings a treasure trove of classic titles from the Game Boy and N64. Even with the most recent addition, Virtual Boy, being outside the box, it seems it may get ever crazier and cooler, thanks to a newly discovered patent.</p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-ds-games-may-be-next-for-nintendo-switch-online-with-new-patent">Nintendo DS Games May Be Next for Nintendo Switch Online With New Patent</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Nintendo DS coming to NSO Confirmed! Patent Discovery of a lifetime! Breaking News! The following patent shows how Nintendo will manage the dual screen situation on Switch 2. You will have 3 options. <br>1. Dual Screen (Parent screen, child screen)<br>2. Single Screen Mode (Picture in… <a href="https://t.co/MH1Ytv4Kfo">pic.twitter.com/MH1Ytv4Kfo</a></p>— Mike Odyssey (@MikeOdysseyYT) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikeOdysseyYT/status/1978839968895074613?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In a post from user <a href="https://x.com/MikeOdysseyYT/status/1978839968895074613" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MikeOdysseyYT</a>, they discovered a new patent from Nintendo. The images they provided show the Nintendo Switch drawn up to have a second screen show up during gameplay. What’s interesting is that each image correlates to one of the ways you could do a dual screen, like picture-in-picture and dual screen. While it could just be for new mechanics, it’s more than likely that it’s a possible way to bring Nintendo DS titles to the console. </p>



<p>For many, the Nintendo DS was home to dozens of amazing titles and one of the coolest ways to experience a game. If true, it’ll be interesting to see how it plays in action. Most games on the DS used the second screen for a map or, in Pokémon’s case, the action menu. Given it’ll likely be all Nintendo-branded titles, they’ll likely tweak some things here and there to make it look good, much like they did for the other NSO games. As it is a patent, nothing is yet confirmed by Nintendo, so be wary.</p>



<p>Do you think Nintendo DS games are headed to the Nintendo Switch? What games would you like to see brought to NSO? Any favorite titles? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Nintendo news, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-modifies-patent-amid-ongoing-palworld-lawsuit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the patent dispute with Palworld</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doug-bowser-nintendo-retiring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Doug Bowser’s retirement</a>. Don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-ds-patent-nso/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Wind and Wave Will Have Turn-Based Gameplay, Leaks Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-wind-and-wave-will-have-turn-based-gameplay-leaks-reveal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-wind-and-wave-will-have-turn-based-gameplay-leaks-reveal.1327039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to information that wasn’t part of the leaks earlier this week, Pokémon Gen 10 Wind and Wave will have a turn-based battle system. </p>



<p>For those living under a rock, The Pokémon Company and Game Freak have experienced a massive leak, with tons of data about their upcoming games surfacing. We already have an idea about Pokémon Gen 10 Wind and Wave’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-gen-10-wind-and-waves-story-setting-new-mechanics-leak-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">story, setting</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-gen-10-wind-and-waves-story-setting-new-mechanics-leak-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mechanics</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-gen-10-leak-reveals-boss-fight-and-mmo-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">boss fight, and MMO details</a>. Now, new details about Gen 10’s battle system have surfaced online. </p>



<h2 id="h-pokemon-legends-z-a-s-real-time-battle-system-might-not-make-it-to-gen-10-wind-and-wave">Pokémon Legends: Z-A’s Real-Time Battle System Might Not Make it to Gen 10 Wind and Wave</h2>



<p>According to a new post by CentroLeaks on <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1978632737541271993" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), some of the information that wasn’t a part of the Teraleak has now surfaced online, revealing details about Pokémon Gen 10 Wind and Wave’s battle system. The post explicitly states that “the game is turn-based,” and if players like the new real-time battle system in Legends Z-A and want it to return for the next mainline instalment, then they should let the devs know. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>We have some new information about Pokémon Wind and Wave that wasn't part of the Teraleak documents released this week:</p><p>– The feature to ride all Pokémon has been scaled down significantly<br>– The character bios / story have changed a lot<br>– The game is turn based, if you enjoy the…</p></div>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/1978632737541271993?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>The post also discusses another feature from the Pokémon Gen 10 Wind and Wave leaks. The leaks had stated that all Pokémon could be ridden or touched; however, the new update states that the feature to ride all Pokémon has been scaled down significantly. Lastly, there’s another point in the post which states that character bios/story have changed a lot. </p>



<p>In other news, the leaks have also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-games-and-dlc-roadmap-allegedly-revealed-in-new-datamine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed the roadmap</a> for upcoming Pokémon games until 2030. Additionally, did you know that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-shinies-dont-disappear-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shinies don’t despawn</a> in Legends: Z-A? What are your thoughts on Pokémon Gen 10 Wind and Wave, featuring a turn-based battle system? Let us know through the official&nbsp;Insider Gaming&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/dLOFaEGOMl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/2k-hires-former-respawn-executive-producer-to-lead-project-ethos/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2K hiring the former Respawn executive producer to lead Project Ethos</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-wind-and-wave-will-have-turn-based-gameplay-leaks-reveal/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2K Hires Former Respawn Executive Producer To Lead Project Ethos]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/2k-hires-former-respawn-executive-producer-to-lead-project-ethos/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2k-hires-former-respawn-executive-producer-to-lead-project-ethos.1326997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It appears that the development of Project Ethos will move forward as 2K has hired a new studio head at developer 31st Union. According to a report from Variety, Ben Brinkman has been hired away from Respawn Entertainment to lead the game.</p>



<p>Brinkman comes in to replace former 31st Union president Michael Condrey, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/2k-fires-31st-union-president-after-project-ethos-poor-response/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who was fired back</a> in February.</p>



<p>A memo to staff, <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/project-ethos-update-31st-union-ben-brinkman-1236553878/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">acquired by Variety</a>, from 2K President David Ismailer called the community feedback to Project Ethos “enlightening.”</p>



<p><strong>“It affirmed the promise of a roguelike shooter but told us we still had work to do,” it continued. “It uncovered the need for a more distinct identity. It’s been inspiring to see how far you’ve come. You took the feedback to heart and reimagined Project ETHOS with a renewed vision – one that’s poised to deliver on its promise to our players. </strong></p>



<p><strong>“Our confidence in Project ETHOS grows every day. To further the incredible progress you’ve made, I’m excited to welcome Ben Brinkman as the new Studio Head of 31st Union. After several months of conversations, Ben officially joins us on Monday, October 20.”</strong></p>



<p>As mentioned, Brinkman comes to 31st Union from Respawn, where he served as an executive producer on Apex Legends since 2020. Before joining Respawn, Brinkman was a producer at Activision and Treyarch, working on the Call of Duty franchise since 2008. He’s been in the industry since the late 1990s, with other stops at EA and 2K over 20 years ago.</p>



<p>What do you think about Brinkman coming in as the new head of Project Ethos at 2K and 31st Union? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-calls-tencents-defense-in-horizon-clone-lawsuit-nonsense/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony describing Tencent’s defense in the Horizon clone lawsuit as ‘nonsense’</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/2k-hires-former-respawn-executive-producer-to-lead-project-ethos/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Reportedly Moving Surface Manufacturing Out Of China, Could Do Same With Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-surface-manufacturing-china-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-reportedly-moving-surface-manufacturing-out-of-china-could-do-same-with-xbox.1326982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Microsoft is reportedly making changes to where its hardware is built. According to Nikkei, Microsoft is looking to move manufacturing of its Surface devices out of China as early as 2026.</p>



<p>The report (<a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/spotlight/supply-chain/microsoft-aims-to-make-most-new-products-outside-china-from-2026-sources" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">paywalled</a>) says that Microsoft will look to move data center servers, component production, and device assembly out of the country. They say that Microsoft has asked multiple supppliers to help with preparation for the move.</p>



<p><strong>“The scope is quite wide and covers components, parts and product assembly for new product introductions of both notebook computers and server products,” </strong>a supply chain executive told Nikkei.<strong> “Microsoft hopes all of these can be manufactured entirely outside of China starting from 2026 at the earliest.”</strong></p>



<p>As far as server production, one source told the outlet that Microsoft had already started moving server production out of China. It’s said that Microsoft has requested <strong>“at least 80% of the bill of materials (BOM) for servers come from outside the country.”</strong></p>



<p>In addition to the Surface production, Nikkei says that Microsoft is “pushing to increase non-China production of the Xbox videogame consoles”. That said, there hasn’t been any sort of requirement made to bring all Xbox manufacturing out of China yet. </p>



<p>This report of Microsoft’s manufacturing plans comes as trade tensions between China and the United States intensify. Donald Trump has threatened to place 100% tariffs on goods from China on November 1st, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2025/10/13/trump-meeting-xi-china-tariffs/86672514007/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">though a meeting between</a> Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping could cool those threats.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Microsoft for comment on the report. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>What do you think of Microsoft moving Surface production out of China, and do you think they will do it with Xbox? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming tech, read about Valve’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valves-next-steamvr-headset-has-reportedly-entered-mass-production/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next SteamVR headset reportedly entering</a> mass production. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-surface-manufacturing-china-xbox/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>