<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:41:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Wordle #1597: Hints And Answer For November 2, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1597-hints-and-answer-for-november-2-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/today%E2%80%99s-wordle-1597-hints-and-answer-for-november-2-2025.1341412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Get ready for an easier Wordle answer than the past few days. Wordle challenges players to guess a fresh five-letter word each day in six tries or fewer. Whether you’re a beginner or a daily player, today’s tips and strategies can help you solve it faster and maintain your streak—if you’re open to a little extra help. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Wordle, don’t worry, you’ll find some <strong>helpful hints and even the answer for Wordle Game #1597 on November 2, 2025</strong>.</p>



<p>To play today’s Wordle, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/wordle/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to the game’s website.</a> If you want to go right to today’s answer without any tips or tricks, you <strong><a href="#h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1597-on-november-2-2025">can click right here</a>.</strong> If you’ve missed any days, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle Answer Archive</a> for every past answer.</p>



<p><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> The following information includes spoilers on today’s</em> and yesterday’s editions<em> of Wordle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure></figure>



<h2>How To Play Wordle</h2>



<p>Wordle is a simple but addictive word puzzle. Each day, players have to <strong>guess a five-letter word answer</strong> in no more than six attempts. After each guess:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Green letters</strong> are correct and in the right position.</li>



<li><strong>Yellow letters</strong> are correct, but in the wrong position.</li>



<li><strong>Gray letters</strong> are not in the word at all.</li>
</ul>



<p>The goal is to guess the word in as few tries as possible. Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p>Wordle can only be played on the New York Times website. There is currently no app for you to download the official game.</p>



<h2 id="h-wordle-hints-for-today-november-2-2025">Wordle Hints For Today, November 2, 2025</h2>



<p>The Wordle answer for game #1597 keeps the difficulty about the same as Saturday’s. According to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/01/crosswords/wordle-review-1597.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NY Times Wordle</a> review, today’s answer takes an average of 4 guesses out of 6 to get. That means it’s slightly higher than the 4.2-guess average on November 1.</p>



<h3 id="h-general-wordle-hints-for-november-2">General Wordle Hints For November 2</h3>



<p>Without giving today’s Wordle answer completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> The word contains <strong>two vowels</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> It includes <strong>at least one letter from the word “hotel.”</strong></li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong> It’s a <strong>place associated with travel</strong>.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 4:</strong> Similar to a hotel, but often found along <strong>highways</strong>.</li>
</ul>



<p>Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving <strong>Wordle #1597for November 2, 2025</strong></p>



<h3 id="h-starter-words-for-november-2-2025">Starter Words For November 2, 2025</h3>



<p>If you want help getting started without having today’s Wordle answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you figure out some included letters. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul>
<li>RADIO</li>



<li>BRAIL</li>



<li>BRAID</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-today-s-wordle-answer-for-game-1597-on-november-2-2025">Today’s Wordle Answer For Game #1597 On November 2, 2025</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answer to today’s Wordle below.</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> RABID</p>



<p>If you solved today’s Wordle without our answer, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-yesterday-s-wordle-answer">Yesterday’s Wordle Answer</h2>



<p>If you missed the previous game, here’s yesterday’s Wordle answer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1596-hints-answer-november-1-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game #1596 on November 1, 2025</a>:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> MOTEL</p>



<p>While not always the case, looking at previous words can sometimes give you insight into common patterns or letter usage in Wordle puzzles. Reminder, you can check out every past Wordle answer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wordle-archive-every-past-wordle-answer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in our official archive</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-wordle-game-after-1597">When Is The Next Wordle Game After #1597?</h2>



<p>Wordle games are <strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before to give players a heads up. The game on <strong>November 3</strong> will be <strong>Wordle Game #1598</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-wordle">What Is Wordle?</h2>



<p>Wordle is a daily word puzzle created by Josh Wardle. Initially developed as a prototype in 2013, it wasn’t fully released until 2021. The game challenges players to guess a five-letter word in six tries or fewer, using hints from each attempt to narrow down the answer. Its straightforward concept, accessibility, and the thrill of solving a new puzzle each day helped it surge in popularity by late 2021. The success of Wordle inspired numerous spin-offs and social media challenges, leading to its acquisition by The New York Times in early 2022.</p>



<hr>



<p>Need more help with other daily games? Let us know what games you’d like tips and clues for in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1597-hints-and-answer-for-november-2-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Casual Mode Added to Battlefield 6 with 32 Bots in Each Match]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-casual-mode-added-with-bots/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/casual-mode-added-to-battlefield-6-with-32-bots-in-each-match.1341328/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>EA DICE has added a new ‘Casual Breakthrough’ mode to Battlefield 6 with a new update, accessible via the core multiplayer menu. This new mode is designed to be a more comfortable entry point for new players, allowing them to rank up while fighting mostly <strong>bot </strong>enemies.</p>



<p>It was stated by EA that teams will consist of eight real players apiece and 16 bot characters per team.</p>



<h2 id="h-bots-are-making-life-easier">Bots Are Making Life Easier</h2>



<p>Die-hard Battlefield fans have argued that this kind of mode shouldn’t exist outside of Portal, but here it is. Electronic Arts has added Casual Breakthrough to Battlefield 6, introducing a bot-filled mode that allows users to earn career, weapon, and battle pass XP, all while completing challenges and grinding unlocks.</p>



<p>The key thing to note is that any actions against <strong>bot characters </strong>will reward reduced XP, while taking on human enemies yields the full rewards.</p>



<p>Initially, only Siege of Cairo and Empire State have been added to the map rotation, but it was stressed that EA DICE will be monitoring feedback to ‘determine if further adjustments are needed in the future.’</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Introducing: Casual Breakthrough</p><p>We understand that sometimes you want to jump into Battlefield but without the intensity of a full PvP lobby. To create a more relaxed way to play while still earning progression and completing challenges, we’re introducing Casual Breakthrough…</p></div>— Battlefield Comms (@BattlefieldComm) <a href="https://twitter.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1984667774430691819?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 1, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>The only things that don’t align with the core multiplayer experience are career stat updates, dogtag grabs, and accolades.</p>



<p>Fans were quick to share mixed feedback in the comments section under the post, with many defending the addition. The vibe is, ‘if you don’t like it, don’t play it,’ which makes sense.</p>



<p>One concern is that some players will find an inevitable way to turn Casual Breakthrough into an XP farm mode, but let’s hope that Electronic Arts has its eyes fixed firmly on the data to avoid that happening.</p>



<p>Will you give Casual Breakthrough a try, or are you comfortable enough with the standard mode? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-developers-game-pass-hike-positive/">COD developers like the Game Pass price hike</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-casual-mode-added-with-bots/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty Developers Think The Game Pass Price Hike is ‘a Positive’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-developers-game-pass-hike-positive/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-developers-think-the-game-pass-price-hike-is-%E2%80%98a-positive%E2%80%99.1341307/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Last month, Microsoft raised the price of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate by a whopping 50% and overhauled the face of the subscription service. It was a drastic event that led to rampant backlash hitting social media platforms worldwide, with many subscribers downgrading their tier or cancelling their subscription altogether.</p>



<p>In a new post, it has been claimed that some, such as Call of Duty’s developers, see the price hike as a positive for the studios making the games that are added to the Game Pass service when they launch.</p>



<h2 id="h-short-term-loss-long-term-gain">Short-Term Loss, Long-Term Gain</h2>



<p>In a post on social media, GhostofHope, a Call of Duty leaker, revealed that they’d spoken to a string of Call of Duty developers who had nice things to say about the Game Pass Ultimate price boost.</p>



<p>Last month, the price of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-raising-game-pass-ultimate-price-by-50-and-changing-tier-features/">Game Pass Ultimate swelled</a> from $19.99 a month to $29.99 a month.</p>



<p>GhostofHope <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1984636078729355503" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote on X</a> (formerly Twitter):</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I spoke to several Call of Duty developers who say that the recent price increase for Game Pass from $19.99 to $29.99 is a positive for the Call of Duty studios. </p>



<p>Financially, this will be a win for them as individuals because it will lead to more revenue which means they are more in control of their future and what they can achieve. </p>



<p>There is also a lot more financial upside with bonuses and such if they are successful now. The news of a price increase also means they need to rely on making games that sell more units to achieve these bonuses. </p>



<p>The vibe in Activision with regards to Black Ops 7 is pretty positive at the moment. A few months ago, the executive team was not happy and now they are feeling better.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In July, the founder of Arkane Studios <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arkane-studios-founder-game-pass-unsustainable/">went on the record</a>, labelling Game Pass ‘unsustainable and damaging’ and stressing that it doesn’t co-exist with other models.</p>



<p>It was also revealed in recent Xbox news that Microsoft’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-q1-2026-drop-113m-year-over-year/">console hardware sales</a> dropped by 29% in Q1 FY26, putting further stock in the company diving deeper into publishing, the cloud, and the flagship subscription service.</p>



<p>Do you think the price hike for Game Pass Ultimate was a good thing, or have you canceled your subscription? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-doubted-budget-time/">Red Dead Redemption 2 was once doubted by investors</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-developers-game-pass-hike-positive/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Getting SpongeBob Collab for Season 7, Leakers Claim]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-spongebob-collab-season-7-leak-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-getting-spongebob-collab-for-season-7-leakers-claim.1341244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>SpongeBob SquarePants may be heading to Fortnite, if notable leakers’ claims are correct. Furthermore, the collaboration is coming sooner than we’d expect.</p>



<p>If you grew up in the 2000s, you know <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/spongebob-squarepants-titans-of-the-tide-launches-november-18/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SpongeBob SquarePants</a> quite well. The hit Nickelodeon show has been airing for 26 years and still going. Entertaining both kids and adults, the legacy of the animated cartoon is enormous. So, naturally, it’s high time (or tide, in SpongeBob’s case, for the series to come to Fortnite. While a collaboration has happened between the two with UEFN, it seems like it could be much bigger in Season 7.</p>



<h2 id="h-spongebob-squarepants-decals-leaked-for-fortnite-hinting-at-possible-collab">SpongeBob SquarePants Decals Leaked for Fortnite, Hinting at Possible Collab</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>The rumor of SpongeBob SquarePants being in Fortnite was first said by <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1984659306851991621" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HYPEX</a>, a known leaker in the gaming community. Other insiders like SamLeakss reported the same, stating that the franchise would <a href="https://x.com/SamLeakss/status/1984669485534466115" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">be added with Season 7</a>, launching November 27th, 2025. However, the most concrete evidence comes from <a href="https://x.com/SpushFNBR/status/1984658819226476786?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1984658819226476786%7Ctwgr%5Ef357053515844a5306205f97171b8abb11aeca93%7Ctwcon%5Es1_c10&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Finsider-gaming.com%2Fwp-admin%2Fpost.php%3Fpost%3D155457action%3Dedit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SpushFNBR</a>, who had an art asset of a smushed Plankton. As some commenters have noticed, it looks like a wheel for the racing game, possibly hinting at what the collab may be for. It also helps that SamLeakss mentions that an SUV would be part of the addition, seemingly confirming it’s part of Rocket Racing.</p>



<p>Just today, The Simpsons were added to Fortnite, transforming the map to Springfield. Seeing how the game has grown into a big commercial success with collabs left and right is crazy. With recent ones being The Black Phone, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-festival-season-10-gorillaz-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gorillaz</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnitemares-2025-features-largest-ever-collabs-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Poppy Playtime</a>, every series under the sun seemingly wants in with Epic Games’ mulitplayer shooter. Whether SpongeBob appears on the battlefield or as cosmetics is unknown, but fans can expect the porous fellow to appear real soon.</p>



<p>What do you think of the SpongBob x Fortnite collab? What do you hope it looks like? Skins? Cosmetic items? Sidekicks? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Fortnite, check out our guide coverage for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-the-simpsons-battle-price-all-rewards-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Simpsons event</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rare-fortnite-skin-returns-to-shop-for-first-time-in-five-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the addition of a rare skin</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-spongebob-collab-season-7-leak-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Latest Poppy Playtime Chapter 5 Release Date Details]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/poppy-playtime-chapter-5-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/latest-poppy-playtime-chapter-5-release-date-details.1341214/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Even more psychological manipulation awaits in Poppy Playtime Chapter 5. If you’re eager to be reunited with Huggy Wuggy, we’ve got the latest release date details and when it could be expected.</p>



<p>Chapter 4 apparently wasn’t enough for Poppy Playtime fans, which is why <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/poppy-playtime-chapter-5-teaser-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chapter 5</a> is on the way. The lovingly-named Huggy Wuggy and his minions are waiting to massacre you once again, and no doubt you’re here because you’re excited at the prospect, instead of running away—you have ZERO survival instincts, people!</p>



<p>That said, if you’re eager to enter a new area of the factory, let’s get into it.</p>



<h2 id="h-do-we-know-when-poppy-playtime-chapter-5-comes-out">Do We Know When Poppy Playtime Chapter 5 Comes Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’ll happen, so be ready. Credit to Mob Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Mob Entertainment hasn’t revealed Poppy Playtime Chapter 5’s full release date yet, but Steam shows that we shouldn’t expect the new DLC until 2026 at the very earliest.</strong></p>



<p>If you head to Steam, you’ll see quite clearly: “<strong>Planned Release Date:&nbsp;2026</strong>,” under the usual launch details section.</p>



<p>A Halloween announcement for Chapter 5 understandably had the Poppy Playtime community excited. Was the new release a shadow drop? Was it an announcement to say that it was coming during Holiday 2025? Unfortunately not.</p>



<p>We’ve done the research, checked the game’s Poppy Playtime Chapter 5 – Teaser Trailer, and searched on the main website to no avail. Interestingly, all the top comments on the Chapter 5 teaser trailer are from fans and creators asking for the developer to <strong>take their time with the game</strong>.</p>



<p>Chapter 4 debuted with some technical issues and bugs at launch, which marred the game for many. If Mob Entertainment does this, we might not see Chapter 5 until well into 2026, maybe even closer to next Halloween.</p>



<p>You can check out the full Poppy Playtime Chapter 5 teaser trailer right here if you’ve not seen it.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Poppy Playtime Chapter 5 - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGSn5cY0o3k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-to-buy-poppy-playtime-chapter-5">How To Buy Poppy Playtime Chapter 5</h2>



<p><strong>There are currently two main ways to purchase Poppy Playtime Chapter 5: Through Steam, and the Epic Games Store.</strong></p>



<p>It’s the usual avenues when it comes to buying Chapter 5. We’ve provided quick links to the game page on each storefront, and you can wishlist them and be ready to buy when the time comes.</p>



<p>Check out the details right here:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4100940/Poppy_Playtime__Chapter_5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam</a></li>



<li><a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/poppy-playtime-chapter-1-poppy-playtime-chapter-5-ac315f?utm_source=marketing&amp;utm_medium=youtube&amp;utm_campaign=ch5egs1&amp;utm_content=video" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Epic Games Store</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Would you rather the developer rush the game so you can play Chapter 5 ASAP? Or is it better if Mob takes its time to ensure Chapter 5 is clean and crystal clear come release day? Share your thoughts and more through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more wonderful nightmare-inducing indie horror games, check out the latest news on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dont-scream-together-ps5-xbox-series-xs-console/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Don’t Scream Together And Its PS5 And Xbox Series X|S Console Status</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/poppy-playtime-chapter-5-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Don’t Scream Together Coming To PS5 or Xbox Series X|S? Don’t Scream Console Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dont-scream-together-ps5-xbox-series-xs-console/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-don%E2%80%99t-scream-together-coming-to-ps5-or-xbox-series-x-s-don%E2%80%99t-scream-console-status-explained.1341184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Don’t Scream Together brings back the terrifying horror of the original and amplifies the fear by allowing you to have multiple friends join you. We’re seeing if Don’t Scream Together has a PS5 or Xbox Series X|S future.</p>



<p>If you’ve somehow not heard of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dont-scream-is-taking-the-horror-world-by-storm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Don’t Scream</a>, it’s probably better for your sanity. The 2023 indie sensation quickly went viral with its retro-looking graphics, palpable tension, and the game’s simple premise: DON’T SCREAM. 2024 saw the game’s full 1.0 launch, and it’s been such a hit that developer Digital Cybercherries is working on Don’t Scream Together—and it would be better on PS5 and Xbox.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-don-t-scream-together-come-to-ps5-consoles">Will Don’t Scream Together Come To PS5 Consoles?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We’d run too. Credit to Digital Cybercherries</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>It can’t be ruled out for the future, but for now, Don’t Scream Together won’t be launching on PS5 consoles</strong>.</p>



<p>So far, developer Digital Cybercherries has made it quite clear that the new multiplayer version of Don’t Scream is targeting a Steam release, meaning it’s only on PC at launch.</p>



<p>On the game’s official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1128949867457302530/1156475689789304842/1431060015195881482" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord</a> server, a community post outlines this quite clearly:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We’re incredibly proud to announce DON’T SCREAM TOGETHER, an improved and expanded version of DON’T SCREAM will be <strong>launching on Steam soon!</strong>“</p>
</blockquote>



<p>There’s no mention of consoles, and it’s not even addressed anywhere in the news or info threads.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-don-t-scream-together-come-to-xbox-series-x-s-consoles">Will Don’t Scream Together Come To Xbox Series X|S Consoles?</h2>



<p><strong>We also have to say that Don’t Scream Together isn’t scheduled for any Xbox consoles right now: The Xbox Series X|S or even the Xbox One, to extend the reach a bit more.</strong></p>



<p>This answer is much the same as our PS5 verdict. It seems like Digital Cybercherries is firmly fixed on getting Don’t Scream Together right on PC before even contemplating a PS5 or Xbox Series X|S console release.</p>



<p>But keep reading, because interested Don’t Scream onlookers might like what we have to say next! </p>



<h2 id="h-is-don-t-scream-coming-to-ps5-or-xbox-consoles">Is Don’t Scream Coming to PS5 or Xbox Consoles?</h2>



<p><strong>A Don’t Scream developer has hinted that the original single-player experience “may find itself on other platforms in the future.”</strong></p>



<p>It’s not all doom and gloom then. While we’ll have to wait for Don’t Scream Together on console, a console port for 2024’s full Don’t Scream debut could be on the cards.</p>



<p>When asked about Don’t Scream Together crossplay, developer [DCC] Dec (on <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2692990" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam</a>) said this:</p>



<blockquote></blockquote>



<blockquote>
<p>“Crossplay is not in the works currently for this title. The classic DON’T SCREAM singleplayer experience may find itself on other platforms in the future though.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s up to you if you take this as a win. If you’re looking for a console port of Don’t Scream, you should at least be getting a taste of the OG game that set the Don’t Scream Together wheels in motion.</p>



<p>We’ll have more on its console port later when the news is announced. Are you picking up Don’t Scream Together at lunch? Or are you hungry for horror on PlayStation and Xbox consoles? Tell us everything through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming content, read about a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rockstar-games-co-founder-reveals-real-reason-why-agent-was-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rockstar Games Co-Founder Revealing The Real Reason Why Agent Was Canceled</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rare-fortnite-skin-returns-to-shop-for-first-time-in-five-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rare Fortnite Skin Returning For The First Time In Five Years</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/dont-scream-together-ps5-xbox-series-xs-console/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>