<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 15:06:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 Titles for February 2025 Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-wave-2-february-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-wave-2-titles-for-february-2025-revealed.1112097/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-wave-2-february-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Xbox has revealed the Wave 2 Game Pass titles for February 2025, which include Day 1 games like Avowed and other popular titles like Watch Dogs Legion, F1 24 and more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-game-pass-wave-2-games-february">Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 Games February</h2>



<p>Avowed is this month’s Day One Game Pass release, available for cloud, Xbox Series X/S and PC today, February 18, through Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass. The latest action RPG by Obsidian will take players through a mystical and dangerous adventure in the fictional world of Eora, which was first seen in the Pillars of Eternity franchise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next is EA Sports F1 24, which will be available for cloud consoles and PC on February 20 through Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass. F1 24 is the latest instalment in the popular racing series, featuring a Driver Career Mode, EA Sports Dynamic Handling, Challenge Career, and Fans Zones as the newest additions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the same day, players can also try out Warhammer 40,000: Rogue Trader, available for cloud, Xbox Series X/S and PC through Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass Standard and PC Game Pass. It is an isometric RPG by Owlcat Games with players commanding a starship, assembling a crew, exploring the Imperium and engaging in strategic turn-based combat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This month’s last Game Pass Wave 2 title is Watch Dogs Legion, which will arrive on February 25 for cloud, console, and PC through Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, and Game Pass Standard. It is the latest instalment in Ubisoft’s open-world cyber adventure series, where players strive to retrieve a fallen futuristic London.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, here are February’s Wave 1 Game Pass <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-titles-for-february-2025-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">titles</a>. Also, future Xbox showcases will highlight <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/future-xbox-showcases-multi-platform-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more multi-platform games</a>. What are your thoughts on the Wave 2 Game Pass titles for February 2025?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-will-remove-10-games-in-march-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Plus removing 10 games in March</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT 10.03 Patch Notes – Minimap and Slow Ability Changes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-10-03-patch-notes-minimap-and-slow-ability-changes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-10-03-patch-notes-%E2%80%93-minimap-and-slow-ability-changes.1112061/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-10-03-patch-notes-minimap-and-slow-ability-changes/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-91255">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Another small patch for VALORANT has been deployed, with patch 10.03 giving the minimap a visual upgrade and updating the effect of slow abilities. The smaller patch size is due to the soon-to-start <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-masters-bangkok-2025-teams-schedule-prize-pool-where-to-watch/">Masters Bangkok event</a>, and the patch will deploy a day later than usual due to a Riot holiday.</p>



<h2 id="h-full-valorant-10-03-patch-notes">Full VALORANT 10.03 Patch Notes</h2>



<p>The slowing abilities of Chamber, Skye, and Harbor will now slow dash abilities. Dash abilities include Jett’s Tailwind and Neon’s Slide. Previously, agents like Jett and Neon could dash at full speed even if they were caught by a slow, but now <strong>slowing abilities will slow a dash by 50 percent</strong>. These abilities now all slow dashes:</p>



<ul>
<li>Chamber’s Trademark</li>



<li>Skye’s Trailblazer</li>



<li>Harbor’s Cascade and High Tide</li>



<li><a href="https://valorant.fandom.com/wiki/Status_Effect#Concuss" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Concussive</a> abilities:
<ul>
<li>Astra’s Nova Pulse</li>



<li>Breach’s Fault Line and Rolling Thunder</li>



<li>Cypher’s Trapwire</li>



<li>Deadlock’s Sonic Sensor</li>



<li>Gekko’s Wingman</li>



<li>Harbor’s Reckoning</li>



<li>Neon’s Relay Bolt</li>



<li>Tejo’s Special Delivery</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>The minimap visuals have been updated, providing “increased gameplay clarity and fidelity.” The minimap now uses shading to clearly show elevated spots across the whole map, as well as ziplines.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-valorant-patch-10-03-bug-fixes">VALORANT Patch 10.03 Bug Fixes</h2>



<ul>
<li>Fixed issues where explosive damaging utility could kill sentinel trap abilities like Vyse’s Arc Rose from vastly outside its intended radius.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where you could not move/use the buy menu while the remake vote screen is displayed. This new voting widget also color corrects the confirmation button to be green and the decline button to be red.</li>



<li><strong>(Console):</strong> You can now add and edit friend notes for your Riot friends.
<ul>
<li>You can use the friends list search field to filter your friends list by player name or tag.</li>



<li>When you have more than four party invites, the friends list will now hide them so you can still see your friends. You can click ‘Show More’ to display any hidden invites.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>(Console): </strong>Fixed an issue where Remake-ended matches in Competitive queue would display incorrect end-of-game screens after the game.</li>



<li><strong>(Console): </strong>Fixed an issue where navigating players on the Leaderboard would sometimes highlight multiple players.</li>



<li><strong>(PC): </strong>Fixed an issue on the Premier tournament bracket screen where match score was occasionally displayed in black.</li>



<li><strong>PC: </strong>Fixed an issue where the Premier tournament bracket was not properly centered on some ultrawide displays.</li>
</ul>



<p>How nice is the new VALORANT minimap? Let us know what you think of patch 10.03 down below or in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest esports news</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-bans-fortnite-cheater-forces-them-to-apologize-and-give-back-winnings/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-games-bans-fortnite-cheater-forces-them-to-apologize-and-give-back-winnings/">Epic Games Bans Fortnite Cheater, Forces Them to Apologize and Give Back Winnings</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A Fortnite pro was forced to apologize and return his ill-gotten winnings after Epic banned them for account sharing in the FNCS.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-almost-caught-counter-strike-in-viewership-in-2023/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-almost-caught-counter-strike-in-viewership-in-2023/">VALORANT Almost Caught Counter-Strike in Viewership, But the Gap is Widening</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>VALORANT and Counter-Strike continue to wage war on each other in pursuit of viewers, and it got close at one point.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/faze-clan-wins-six-invitational/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/faze-clan-wins-six-invitational/">FaZe Clan Wins Six Invitational 2025 After a Dominant Performance</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>FaZe Clan has stormed into the top spot at the Six Invitational, securing the trophy after beating Team BDS with a 3 – 1 scoreline.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-texas-fail-win-map-pred-back/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-texas-fail-win-map-pred-back/">OpTic Texas Fails to Win a Map as Pred Steps Back Up</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>OpTic Texas has had a tough weekend in the CDL, failing to win a map as Pred returns into the roster after a couple of months away.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Elden Ring Nightreign Have PVP? Multiplayer Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-elden-ring-nightreign-have-pvp/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-elden-ring-nightreign-have-pvp-multiplayer-explained.1111998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/does-elden-ring-nightreign-have-pvp/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Nightreign incorporates a lot of what made the original so special. But one element players fight tooth and nail over is each other. I’m here to tell you if Elden Ring Nightreign features any PVP or if it’s solely PVE.</p>



<p>I got to experience the debut <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/after-technical-problems-more-elden-ring-nightreign-test-sessions-possible/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign Network Test</a>. I was blown away by how incredible it was and how much it differs from Elden Ring. It looks the same on the surface, but the overall feel, speed, and complexity make it a tough and tantalizing proposition.</p>



<p>You’re encouraged to team up, traverse The Lands Between, and take down familiar FromSoftware bosses. But some players want a break from AI to take on real people. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign</a> having PVP would scratch this painful itch, so let’s see if it’s possible.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-pvp-in-elden-ring-nightreign">Can You PVP in Elden Ring Nightreign?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>No time for PVP right now. Credit to FromSoftware</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Elden Ring Nightreign doesn’t include any PVP and the only combat in the game is played out in classic PVE fashion with human players against enemy AI.</strong></p>



<p>Yes, if you’re big into PVP, Nightreign might not be the Souls game for you. In an <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-fromsoftware-game-director-explains-why-the-spin-off-exists-reveals-whether-george-r-r-martin-was-involved-and-why-fans-shouldnt-call-it-a-live-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">interview with IGN</a>, game director Junya Ishizaki talked a lot about Nightreign and what the team wants to accomplish with it.</p>



<p>The topic of PVP came up when interviewer Tristan Ogilvie asked: “Are there any other sort of modes planned, like a PvP battle royale or anything like that?” Ishizaki responded: “<strong>Currently there are no plans</strong>. We wanted to first and foremost concentrate on this three-player co-op experience. So that’s the main focus for now.”</p>



<p>Nightreign will launch with no PVP features unless something changes between now and launch.</p>



<h2 id="h-will-pvp-be-added-to-elden-ring-nightreign">Will PVP be Added to Elden Ring Nightreign?</h2>



<p><strong>There’s no confirmation from FromSoftware about adding PVP to Elden Ring Nightreign in the future but never say never.</strong></p>



<p>Alluding to the IGN interview above, Junya Ishizaki was quoted saying “<strong>Currently</strong>” when it came to PVP ideas. This doesn’t mean the developer won’t look to add PVP in a future update. The sole focus is on delivering a complete and coherent three-player experience with working functionality.</p>



<p>But we know more content is going to be available at launch. Furthermore, additional content is arriving post-launch. PVP may eventually get added if the team can implement it effectively.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for any further updates on Elden Ring Nightreign’s PVP status.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the latest Elden Ring Nightreign details and questions including if you can <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/can-you-play-elden-ring-nightreign-with-two-players-or-solo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">play it Solo or with two players</a>.</p>



<p>Can Nightreign be the start of something special for the Souls genre? Or are you hoping this is a one-and-done deal for FromSoftware so it can move on to a new project?</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE – Ubisoft is Confident on Releasing Assassin’s Creed Shadows on March 20, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-%E2%80%93-ubisoft-is-confident-on-releasing-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-on-march-20-2025.1111971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Insider Gaming sources have said that the publisher and the developers are now confident that Assassin’s Creed Shadows will launch on March 20, 2025.</p>



<p>Of course, never say never of another delay, but Ubisoft has made preparations to increase its marketing of Assassin’s Creed Shadows ahead of its March 20, 2025 launch, including finalising the embargo dates for the games review.</p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows reviews will be live on March 18, 2025.</p>



<p>Speaking with several developers working on the game, they said that they felt confident that it will be ready for its March release date, with one source stating that the game is now “pretty much done”.</p>



<p>As mentioned during Ubisoft’s latest earnings call, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shadows is currently on par with that of Assassins Creed Odyssey</a> in terms of its pre-order numbers. “Early previews have been positive, praising its narrative and immersive experience, with both characters playing critical roles in the game’s storyline, as well as the quality and complementarity of the gameplay provided by the dual protagonist approach,” Guillemot said in the most recent earnings call.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, Shadows currently has around 300,000 pre-orders, said sources and Odyssey’s day one player numbers were between 400-450,000; a gap of around 100-150,000 that needs to be made up in the next four weeks.</p>



<p>In comparison, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/star-wars-outlaws-sales-1-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star Wars Outlaws, a game that failed to meet Ubisoft’s expectations</a> had less than half the pre-orders Shadows currently has in the same time period before launch, it was said.</p>



<p>Looking at the data, if Shadows continues the same trajectory as Odyssey throughout launch, it’s estimated that the game could sell approximately 3.5 million units in its first month. Valhalla, which was the series’ most successful Assassin’s Creed game had some eight million players in its first month, with more than 65% being attributed to past-generation consoles at the time.</p>



<p>Will you be buying Assassin’s Creed Shadows? Let us know in the comments or in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-user-generated-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 developers exploring user-generated content for their upcoming game</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>