<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:06:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Management To Blame For Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown Sales Issues, Baldur’s Gate 3 Exec Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-management-to-blame-for-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sales-issues-baldurs-gate-3-exec-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-management-to-blame-for-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sales-issues-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-exec-says.1019334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-management-to-blame-for-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sales-issues-baldurs-gate-3-exec-says/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Those looking to for a reason as to why Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown sold below expectations thus leading to a sequel being rejected need to look to the top of Ubisoft. </p>



<p>That’s what Michael Douse, the director of publishing at Baldur’s Gate 3 developer Larian Studios, had to say about the situation. </p>



<p>In a social media post (h/t <a href="https://80.lv/articles/baldur-s-gate-3-publishing-director-blames-ubisoft-for-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-s-poor-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">80 Level</a>), Douse pointed the fingers at Ubisoft management, saying that the decision to not release the game on Steam day one hurt any chance of the game’s success.</p>



<p>“The last notable game on their platform was arguably Far Cry 6 in 2021,” <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/1849147473354211400" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Douse said</a>. “The Crew, Mirage and Avatar came in 2023 and didn’t perform, so you can assume subscriptions were at a lull when PoP released by 2024. Which means people wouldn’t be launching their store all too much.</p>



<p>“If it had released on Steam not only would it have been a market success, but there would likely be a sequel because the team are so strong.”</p>



<p>He then went on to call out the game’s critical success across the board.</p>



<p>“It’s such a broken strategy,” he said. “The hardest thing is to make a 85+ game — it is much, much easier to release one. It just shouldn’t be done as it was.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="EXCLUSIVE: New Rayman Remake In Development &amp; What Happened With Prince of Persia" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HAPxI_j4E88?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown has sold around one million copies since its launch, far below what the internal expectations were for the game. Insider Gaming learned that Ubisoft was was expecting the game to sell on par, or better, than some of biggest Metroidvania’s in the market. When that didn’t happen right away, a decision was made to move on from the project.</p>



<p>Now, the team that developed Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is no more after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-three-new-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft disbanded them to move on</a> to different games.</p>



<p>What do you think of Douse’s comments on why Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown failed to sell better for Ubisoft? Let us know down below, or in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1099/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more  Insider Gaming, check out what r<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-esports-on-horizon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ecently launched game has hit the 1 million copies</a> sales mark. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Players Should Change this Setting for Better ADS]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-players-should-change-this-setting-for-better-ads/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-players-should-change-this-setting-for-better-ads.1019253/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-players-should-change-this-setting-for-better-ads/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-62798">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>A Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 player has figured out that Tactical Sprint Assist can cause a significant delay while aiming, and changing this setting can make the gameplay much faster for players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://x.com/Lightsfire_/status/1849520566715228207" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Lightsfire</a> on X (via <a href="https://www.vg247.com/this-one-setting-in-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-is-messing-up-players-aim-and-the-community-is-rushing-to-change-it" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VG247</a>), enabling Tactical Sprint Assist on Black Ops 6 increases the time it takes for players to pull up their ADS. His video includes gameplay comparisons of when Sprint Assist is toggled as ‘Tactical Sprint Assist’ or set as ‘On’. You can see a visible delay when using the former, while just setting Sprint Assist as ‘On’ makes players pull up their guns much faster.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>*BLACK OPS 6 IMPORTANT SETTINGS* </p><p>Tactical sprint assist is causing a massive delay when aiming down sights this is what you should change it to</p><p>Retweet to help someone out! <a href="https://t.co/6JP6LYRpPl">pic.twitter.com/6JP6LYRpPl</a></p></div>— Lightsfire (@Lightsfire_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Lightsfire_/status/1849520566715228207?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>To change this setting in Black Ops 6, players should open the ‘Settings’ menu and select the ‘Movement’ tab. Here, they will find a ‘Sprint Assist’ option under ‘Intelligent Movement’. They should open it and select ‘On’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If players still want to use Tactical Sprint while having faster ADS, there’s a way to do that, too. Players should head to ‘Movement Advanced Settings’, and under the ‘Movement Behaviours Tab’, they will find an option called ‘Tactical Sprint Activation’. The player should open it and select ‘Single Tap Run’. Now, players can have faster ADS while using Tactical Sprint.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, players will not have to wait long for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-nuketown-in-black-ops-6-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nuketown</a> in Black Ops 6. Also, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-fix-packet-burst-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to fix the Packet Burst issue</a> of the game. What are your thoughts on this Black Ops 6 setting?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-game-franchises/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft’s ownership of 20 game franchises that have exceeded $1 billion in revenue</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-game-franchises/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-game-franchises/">Microsoft Owns 20 Game Franchises That Have Exceeded $1 BILLION In Revenue</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft is a powerhouse of the gaming world, and the number of billion-dollar franchises it owns is staggering.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-esports-on-horizon/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-esports-on-horizon/">Undisputed Has Sold One Million Copies, Now Esports Is On The Horizon</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Undisputed has just sold one million copies, and now the game’s competitive future is up for exploration. Will this be the next best esports game?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/surgent-tales-of-kenzera-uso/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/surgent-tales-of-kenzera-uso/">Surgent Studios Unveils Tales of Kenzera: Project Uso</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Surgent Studios has revealed Tales of Kenzera: Project Uso, the next game from the team that requires funding.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-update-devlog/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-update-devlog/">Gray Zone Warfare’s Next Update Increases Risk-to-Reward Ratio</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>MADFINGER Games has offered a new devlog for Gray Zone Warfare’s incoming Night Ops update. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best LW3A1 loadout in Black Ops 6: Attachments, Perks & Equipment]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-lw3a1-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-lw3a1-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment.1019250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-lw3a1-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you’re after a devastating one-hit Sniper Rifle that delivers a single crushing blow to almost anywhere on the body, the best LW3A1 Black Ops 6 Sniper Rifle class is what you’re after, and we have the best way to maximize its strengths.</p>



<p>The LW3A1 Frostline reminds me of many, classic one-hit Sniper Rifles from CoD games down the years: The M40A3 from Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare, the Intervention from 2009’s Modern Warfare 2, and the KATT-AMR is a recent favorite of mine. Now, it’s the turn of the LW3A1 in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6</a>—designed to honor the legacy of previous Sniper stalwarts.</p>



<p>When you start Black Ops 6, the LW3A1 is probably going to be your main multiplayer Sniper Rifle for a while, so let’s make the most of it, and turn it into your opponent’s living nightmare.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-lw3a1-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best LW3A1 Attachments in Black Ops 6</h2>



<figure><figcaption>What a beauty. Credit to Activision</figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Barrel:</strong> Long Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Stock Pad:</strong> Lightweight Pad</li>



<li><strong>Magazine:</strong> Extended Mag I</li>



<li><strong>Comb:</strong> Quickdraw Riser</li>



<li><strong>Stock:</strong> Heavy Stock</li>
</ul>



<p>To start the best LW3A1 Sniper Rifle Class in Black Ops 6, I’ve gone for a tasty <strong>Long Barrel</strong> as it gives the LW3A1 a bit more range, allowing the gun a better chance to one-shot from miles away. The <strong>Lightweight Pad</strong> reduces sway, making our stability firmer and aiming tighter, whereas the <strong>Extended Mag I</strong> is a staple of a single-shot class in need of some extra shots in reserve.</p>



<p>The <strong>Quickdraw Riser</strong> Comb drastically decreases ADS speed, allowing us to zap an enemy quicker—which is extremely useful for a big brute such as the LW3A1. Finally, the <strong>Heavy Stoc</strong>k boosts our Flinch Resistance, meaning if we’re lining up a shot and our opponent lands a couple of lucky shots, our aim should be fairly steady, and make it easier to pop their head in the hunt for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-black-ops-6-mastery-camo-in-multiplayer-zombies-warzone-all-camos-listed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Camos</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-lw3a1-frostline">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment for LW3A1 Frostline</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Perk 1:</strong>&nbsp;Ghost</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2:</strong>&nbsp;Forward Intel</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3:</strong>&nbsp;Vigilance</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard:</strong>&nbsp;Overkill</li>



<li><strong>Lethal:</strong>&nbsp;Blast Trap</li>



<li><strong>Tactical:</strong>&nbsp;Stim Shot</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade:</strong>&nbsp;Spring Mine</li>
</ul>



<p>Recon Perks are the direction we’ve gone for with the LW3A1 Sniper Rifle as you want to be covert and have all the intelligence. <strong>Ghost</strong> naturally keeps you obscured as much as possible—protecting your position—<strong>Forward Intel</strong> makes the minimap bigger and gives us a handy look at where our targets are, and <strong>Vigilance </strong>produces a warning indicator if you are spotted—allowing you a split-second to take action.</p>



<p><strong>Overkill </strong>is the ideal Wildcard as we can pair our LW3A1 with something rapid for close quarters such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-tanto-22-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tanto .22</a>. The <strong>Blast Trap</strong> is another piece of explosive insurance to fortify our position, the Stim Shot is a perfect pick-me-up to tank a few hits, and I’ve picked the <strong>Spring Mine</strong> to add another layer of defense.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-secondary-for-lw3a1-frostline">Best Secondary for LW3A1 Frostline</h2>



<p>If for some reason you disagree with our Overkill Wildcard pick, that’s fine, we still like you. But if you decide to do this, go for the <strong>Grekhova</strong> fully automatic Pistol because once you unlock it, you’ll never go back. It becomes available at <strong>Level 13</strong> (unlucky for your enemies!) and should become a mainstay in your loadout.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-lw3a1-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock LW3A1 in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>Good news, the LW3A1 is unlocked from the beginning of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6. It’s the only one of the Sniper Rifles to be available from the get-go, so reach Level 4 to unlock Loadouts, add it to a class, and start accumulating all the attachments I’ve listed in our best setup.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-the-lw3a1-any-good-in-black-ops-6">Is the LW3A1 any good in Black Ops 6?</h2>



<p><strong>The LW3A1 is most certainly a very good gun</strong> as its one-hit-kill potential means it’s an extremely deadly weapon in even the most <em>average </em>of hands—and I mean this respectfully. If you can get to grips with the LW3A1, learn to keep your distance, and pick your shots, decent Killstreaks are mere fingertips away.</p>



<p>You have to be <strong>Level 25 to unlock the Dragunov</strong> as the next Sniper Rifle anyway, so you have plenty of time to become intimately acquainted with the LW3A1.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-alternatives-to-the-lw3a1-frostline-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives to the LW3A1 Frostline in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>Currently, Black Ops 6 only has three Sniper Rifles—with more likely to arrive as part of seasonal updates. That being said, once you unlock them, the <strong>SVD Dragunov</strong> and <strong>LR 7.62</strong> need to be on your radar if you love engaging at long-range, or desire one-shot one-kill firepower.</p>



<hr>



<p>Black Ops 6 has plenty to keep you busy: The&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-safe-code-and-complete-every-safehouse-puzzle-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Safehouse Puzzle Safe</a> in need of cracking, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-open-liberty-falls-vault-black-ops/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Liberty Falls Vault</a> are big standouts. For more general gaming news and guides, do subscribe to our free,&nbsp;<a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Tanto .22 Loadout in Black Ops 6: Attachments, Perks & Equipment]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-tanto-22-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-tanto-22-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment.1019205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-tanto-22-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Among all the other guns in the SMG category, the Tanto .22 stands out with a slow rate of fire but hard-hitting capabilities in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6</a>. To get the best out of the gun, you must use the ideal attachments, perks, and equipment to support your gameplay.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-best-tanto-22-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best attachments</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-perks-wildcard-equipment-for-tanto-22">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-secondary-for-tanto-22">Best Secondary for Tanto .22</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-how-to-unlock-tanto-22-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock Tanto .22 in Black Ops 6</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-is-the-tanto-22-any-good-in-black-ops-6">Is the Tanto .22 any good in Black Ops 6?</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-alternatives-to-the-tanto-22-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-tanto-22-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best Tanto .22 loadout attachments in Black Ops 6</h2>



<figure></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Muzzle</strong>: Compensator</li>



<li><strong>Barrel</strong>: Short Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Under Barrel</strong>: Ranger Foregrip</li>



<li><strong>Rear Grip</strong>: CQB Grip</li>



<li><strong>Stock</strong>: Balanced Stock</li>
</ul>



<p>The mentioned attachments will give you the best mobility while using the Tanto .22 in multiplayer lobbies. The <strong>Compensator</strong> will reduce the vertical recoil to improve accuracy while the <strong>Short Barrel</strong> will enhance in-air handling by improving Jumping Aim Down Sight and Jumping Sprint to Fire speeds.</p>



<p><strong>Ranger Foregrip</strong> will greatly improve Horizontal Recoil Control and slightly improve Sprinting Movement Speed. Use the <strong>CQB Grip</strong> to dominate in close-range combat as it significantly boosts Dive To Fire, Slide to Fire, and Sprint to Fire Speeds, making it a perfect attachment to use Omnimovement in the best way possible.</p>



<p>Lastly, use the <strong>Balanced Stock</strong> for maximum mobility as it will improve Aim Walking, Hipfire, and Strafing Movement speeds.</p>







<h2 id="h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-tanto-22">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment for Tanto .22</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Perk 1</strong>: Dexterity</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2</strong>: Assassin</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3</strong>: Double Time</li>



<li><strong>Perk 4</strong>: Enforcer</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard</strong>: Perk Greed</li>



<li><strong>Lethal</strong>: Semtex</li>



<li><strong>Tactical</strong>: Stim Shot</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade</strong>: Spring Mine</li>
</ul>



<p>Use <strong>Dexterity</strong> to reduce weapon motion while jumping, sliding, and diving while taking less fall damage. The <strong>Assassin</strong> perk will mark enemies with kill streaks on the minimap.</p>



<p><strong>Double Time</strong> significantly increases the Tactical Sprint, which is essential when multiple enemies are nearby. These three perks will activate the <strong>Enforcer</strong> specialty which grants a temporary buff to your movement speed and health regeneration rate upon killing enemies.</p>



<p>Coming to the Wildcard, during the initial levels you can use Tactical Expert (it gives you two <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-black-ops-6-game-modes-maps-equipment-field-upgrades/#h-all-equipment-in-black-ops-6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tactical equi</a>pment) but once you level up, get the <strong>Perk Greed</strong> to equip an extra Perk.</p>



<p><strong>Semtex</strong> and <strong>Stim Shots</strong> are a must when you’re running the Tanto .22 for quick damage and heal-up. I’d say the Field Upgrade is a personal choice. For me, I find the <strong>Spring Mine</strong> useful as it grants me free kills from time to time.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-best-secondary-for-tanto-22">Best Secondary for Tanto .22</h2>



<p>The <strong>Stryder .22</strong> is one of the best secondary weapons for the submachine gun. Want to finish off enemies when they are at one HP, use the Stryder to get the job done.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-tanto-22-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock Tanto .22 in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>Reach <strong>player level 16</strong> to unlock the Tanto .22 SMG in Black Ops 6. This is easy to achieve – all you need to do is play the game. You can <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-level-up-fast-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">level up fast</a> by playing some multiplayer matches and fulfilling all the objectives.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-the-tanto-22-any-good-in-black-ops-6">Is the Tanto .22 any good in Black Ops 6?</h2>



<p>Yes, despite being an SMG with a slow rate of fire, it’s an excellent choice for close and medium-range combat. You don’t have empty half of its magazine on a single enemy and is easy to control as well.</p>



<p>With the attachments mentioned above, you can achieve great mobility with the Tanto .22, making it hard for the enemies to knock you down.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-alternatives-to-the-tanto-22-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives to the Tanto .22 in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>If the slow fire rate bothers you, go with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-jackal-pdw-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jackal PDW</a> SMG. It dominated lobbies during the beta and is equally impressive after the full release of the game.</p>



<p>And if you want to ditch the SMG route and choose hard-hitting Assault Rifles instead, then the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-best-ak-74-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AK-74</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xm4-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/">XMR</a> are two of the best guns to use.</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay up to date with all the latest news and guides on Black Ops 6 by signing up for&nbsp;<a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>