<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:04:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld on Switch 2 is a Possibility If the Console is ‘Beefy Enough’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-%E2%80%98beefy-enough%E2%80%99.1143363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-96976">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Pocketpair will consider releasing Palworld for the Nintendo Switch 2 if the console is ‘beefy enough’.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-is-palworld-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2">Is Palworld Coming to Nintendo Switch 2?</h2>



<p>Pocketpair communications director John ‘Bucky’ Buckley spoke about Palworld on the Nintendo Switch 2 during an interview with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-communications-director-says-nintendo-switch-2-version-100-worth-considering-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IGN</a> at GDC San Fransisco. Bucky first talked about the console’s specs, stating that he has been “walking around GDC”, hoping that someone will reveal Switch 2’s specs to him. However, everyone he has interacted with has said, “They haven’t even seen them”. He stated they couldn’t make the game for the original Switch as Palworld is “a beefy game”.</p>



<p>Bucky added that Palworld on Nintendo Switch 2 is “100% worth considering”, provided the console is “beefy enough.” The developers already have experience with handheld optimisations with their release on the Steam Deck and are “happy with how it turned out”, even though there’s still some work to do. Pocketpair would like to get Palworld “on more handhelds if possible.”</p>



<p>At the same time, Nintendo’s patent infringement lawsuit against Palworld continues, with recent updates stating that the former has received a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-anti-palworld-patent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new patent</a> that might help their case. Pocketpair recently spoke about the lawsuit, saying it “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-devs-were-shocked-by-nintendos-patent-infringement-lawsuit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came as a shock</a>” for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Pocketpair publishing has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pocketpair-publishing-warn-not-more-palworld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">warned players</a> not to expect ‘more Palworld’. Also, the game recently released its much-awaited <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworlds-cross-play-update-is-now-available-on-all-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cross-play update</a>. What are your thoughts on Palworld releasing for the Switch 2?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle arriving for PS5 in April</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/">
                                Indiana Jones and The Great Circle Releases on PS5 Next Month                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle releases for PS5 this April. Check out the editions, pre-order bonuses and other details here. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-rocket-returns-to-pokemon-tcg-with-upcoming-destined-rivals-set/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-rocket-returns-to-pokemon-tcg-with-upcoming-destined-rivals-set/">
                                Team Rocket Returns to Pokémon TCG with Upcoming Destined Rivals Set                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokémon TCG’s new Destined Rivals set will bring back Team Rocket to the game along with over 240 cards. Here are more details.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-mod-adds-gta-6-removed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-mod-adds-gta-6-removed/">
                                Take-Two Interactive Copyrights GTA 5 Mod That Put GTA 6 Map Into The Game                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Following a YouTube copyright strike from Take-Two Interactive, a GTA 5 modder has decided to remove his mod that adds GTA 6 into GTA 5. The video in question was a FiveM mod that added the GTA 6 map into GTA 5, which was based on the massive hack that Rockstar Games faced a couple […]</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-bring-27-new-mega-evolutions-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-bring-27-new-mega-evolutions-its-claimed/">
                                Pokémon Legends Z-A Will Bring 27 New Mega Evolutions, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that Pokémon Legends Z-A is set to introduce 27 new Mega Evolutions. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Esports is Already Building Strong Rivalries and Solid Viewership]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership.1143285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Marvel Rivals esports scene is still in its very early days, but the early results have been very positive. The fledgling scene is attracting numerous organizations, strong viewership numbers (thanks to co-streaming), and some exciting rivalries.</p>



<p>The first competitive tournaments have featured plenty of highlights and trash talking, and there’s nowhere to go but up for Marvel Rivals esports.</p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-esports-is-heating-up-quickly">Marvel Rivals Esports is Heating Up Quickly</h2>



<p>After a month of action across the world, the Marvel Rivals Invitational series has ended, crowning five champions across each of the main regions. Arguably the most interest in Marvel Rivals esports has been in North America, which has attracted the most viewership and the most interest from established organizations.</p>



<p>Excluding the streamer-focused events like Creator Cup and Twitch Rivals, the Marvel Rivals event with the highest viewership peak was the NA Invitational that just concluded yesterday. The event <a href="https://escharts.com/tournaments/mr/marvel-rivals-invitational-north-america-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached 71,099 concurrent viewers at its peak</a>, according to Esports Charts. This number was aided by co-streamers like Shroud, who has become so interested in Marvel Rivals that he <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-roster-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">founded a team that competed in the event: Shroud-X</a>. But the event included a trove of larger organizations with dedicated fanbases: Sentinels, Envy, FlyQuest, and 100 Thieves.</p>



<p>100 Thieves have been dominating the competition in North America. Since the squad formerly known as Mutants signed with Nadeshot’s brand, they haven’t lost a single match, thanks in part to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/one-of-marvel-rivals-best-pro-tank-players-plays-on-controller/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the few Vanguard players playing (and winning) on controller</a>. The rivalry between Sentinels and 100 Thieves in VALORANT has carried over to Marvel Rivals, complete with the<a href="https://x.com/MRivalsEsports/status/1903651194196676821" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> expected amount of social media back-and-forth</a>. The trash talk is at the perfect level: not too far to be deemed personal or inappropriate, but above the basic level of normal banter.</p>



<p>There’s still plenty of room for Marvel Rivals to grow, but NetEase has committed to investing in the game itself for “10 years and beyond.” And with seasonal tournaments baked into the game’s competitive mode itself, that implies that esports will be a priority for years to come.</p>



<p>What do you make of Marvel Rivals’ aspirations in esports? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle’s PS5 announcement</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>