<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 20:07:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Players Can Finally Exchange Their Battle Pass Chrono Tokens]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens.1112460/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-players-can-finally-exchange-their-battle-pass-chrono-tokens/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-91455">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Marvel Rivals players will finally be able to exchange their leftover Chrono Tokens from the battle pass into something more useful. After having to let those extra tokens go to waste earlier, players that complete the Season 1 pass can get rewarded for their extra efforts.</p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-adds-new-chrono-token-exchange-system">Marvel Rivals Adds New Chrono Token Exchange System</h2>



<p>In the developer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FMPCzylKgc8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video</a> for the upcoming Marvel Rivals Season 1.5 update, the team at NetEase confirmed the new Chrono Token redemption system. Players that own the Luxury battle pass and redeem all the rewards can convert leftover Chrono Tokens into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-launching-perfect-couples-costumes-on-valentines-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Units used in the store</a>. “Luxury” just refers to the paid pass itself: you did not need to buy the more expensive version that came with extra Chrono Tokens to be eligible for the new redemption system. Any player who buys the pass and redeems all its awards will be able to convert excess Chrono Tokens into Units.</p>



<p>This issue was a major community talking point during Season 0. The shortened season features a much smaller battle pass that could be completed rather quickly, but players were still completing daily and weekly challenges and earning Chrono Tokens that completely went to waste. With the new system, it should encourage players to continue playing and completing challenges even if they’ve completed the pass.</p>



<p>Potentially, this change could result in a little bit less spending of Lattice at the store. However, that all depends on what the ratio of Chrono Tokens to Units will be, which NetEase hasn’t revealed yet. Marvel Rivals fans should temper their expectations now, as it’s very unlikely that it will even be close to a 1:1 ratio. Season 1.5 officially goes live on February 21.</p>



<p>Inspired to complete the seasonal battle pass now? Let us know down below in the comments or on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out what&nbsp;our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-is-nerfing-the-new-triple-strategist-meta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coverage of the nerfs to the triple-initiator meta coming to Marvel Rivals</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-is-nerfing-the-new-triple-strategist-meta/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-is-nerfing-the-new-triple-strategist-meta/">Marvel Rivals is Nerfing the New Triple Strategist Meta</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The extremely powerful triple-strategist meta is getting some much-needed balancing in the next Marvel Rivals update.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shuhei-yoshida-choice-was-to-lead-indies-or-leave-playstation/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shuhei-yoshida-choice-was-to-lead-indies-or-leave-playstation/">Shuhei Yoshida: Choice Was To Lead Indies Or Leave PlayStation</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>When Shuhei Yoshida moved from first-party games to indies at PlayStation, it wasn’t fully his decision to make.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/another-vr-studio-suffers-layoffs-as-toast-interactive-closes-office/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/another-vr-studio-suffers-layoffs-as-toast-interactive-closes-office/">Another VR Studio Suffers Layoffs As Toast Interactive Closes Office</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Australian VR studio Toast Interactive is the latest VR studio to suffer mass layoffs as it also closes its studio.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/devonta-smith-cheating-claims-warzone-super-bowl/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/devonta-smith-cheating-claims-warzone-super-bowl/">DeVonta Smith: From Winning The Super Bowl To Facing Warzone Cheating Claims</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>DeVonta Smith, a superstar athlete who won the Super Bowl a week ago, is facing accusations of cheating in Call of Duty: Warzone.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>