<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:12:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can You Access Outpost Zone In Marathon Server Slam Playtest?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/can-you-access-outpost-zone-in-marathon-server-slam-playtest/</link>
            <guid>1448833</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Marathon Server Slam Playtest is finally here, and it gives players a huge glimpse into what the full game will be like at launch. From early quests to the full roster of guns, there’s plenty for fans to dip their feet into, but there does seem to be one major point of confusion.</p>



<p>The maps. When you load up the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/marathon/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon</a> Server Slam Playtest and prepare for a run, you’ll see three maps available: Perimeter, Dire Marsh, and Outpost. There’s no trouble accessing the first two, but Outpost seems to be causing some problems.</p>







<p>If you’re confused, then don’t worry, you’re in the right place. Here’s whether you can access the Outpost map during the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-marathon-server-slam-playtest-dates-times-platforms-content/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-marathon-server-slam-playtest-dates-times-platforms-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon Server Slam Playtest</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-access-the-outpost-zone-in-the-marathon-server-slam-playtest">Can You Access The Outpost Zone In The Marathon Server Slam Playtest?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Take your pick. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Unfortunately, despite it appearing on the map selection screen, you cannot play on the Outpost map during the Marathon Server Slam Playtest. </strong></p>



<p>It might come as a disappointment to some fans out there, especially since it’s teased for all to see, but Bungie did warn players which maps will be playable during the Playtest—and Outpost didn’t make the cut. </p>



<ul>
<li>More Insider Gaming: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-runner-shell-in-marathon-all-abilities-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Every Runner Shell In Marathon</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Still, it does pose a new question for fans of the Server Slam: When will Outpost be playable? </p>







<h2 id="h-when-will-outpost-be-playable-in-marathon">When Will Outpost Be Playable In Marathon?</h2>



<p><strong>The Outpost map will be fully playable when Marathon releases on March 5, 2026. It will be one of the three maps available at launch, alongside both Perimeter and Dire Marsh.</strong></p>



<p>With that in mind, it’s honestly quite crazy that Bungie made two of the three maps playable during what is essentially a glorified beta test for the game. That doesn’t leave a whole lot left to uncover when the game officially releases, but there is still the largely unknown endgame map—the Cryo Archive. </p>



<ul>
<li>More Insider Gaming: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/factions-in-marathon-explained-how-to-unlock-new-factions-increase-rank/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Factions In Marathon, Explained</a></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/bungie/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/bungie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bungie</a> have described this as the ultimate endgame for Marathon, and it should be playable just a few weeks after launch. Fingers crossed that it’s worth the wait, and that Outpost is just as fun to explore as the other two maps.</p>



<hr>



<p>How are you finding the Marathon Server Slam Playtest? Share your thoughts and chat to fellow Runners in the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" id="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>. </p>



<p>For more Marathon content, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-duos-matchmaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the matchmaking options</a>, as well as&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-earn-marathon-server-slam-playtest-twitch-drops-all-rewards-how-to-get/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to claim the Twitch Drops</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/can-you-access-outpost-zone-in-marathon-server-slam-playtest/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon 30th Anniversary TCG Set Release Date Period Details & What To Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-30th-anniversary-tcg-set-release/</link>
            <guid>1448824</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you can’t get enough of the real-life Pokémon Trading Card Game, then you need to get ready for a Pokémon 30th Anniversary TCG Set, and early release period details are out for it.</p>



<p>Collectors everywhere don’t care how many new Pokémon sets are released in the TCG; packs will be bought, cards will be pulled, and binders will be stacked. We learned so much from the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-presents-february-2026-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon&nbsp;Presents&nbsp;February 2026 showcase</a>, and one of the biggest surprises was the announcement of a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-30th-anniversary-tcg-set-revealed-for-2026-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">30th anniversary set</a>.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-pokemon-s-30th-anniversary-tcg-set-coming-out-release-period-explained">When Is Pokémon’s 30th Anniversary TCG Set Coming Out? Release Period, Explained</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Pokémon Company has indicated that the set is arriving at some point in 2026, but based on historical data, it’s believed the set is destined for a Fall 2026 release—between September and November.</strong></p>



<p>Everyone hates vague release windows, especially ones that span a full year!</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-things-we-learned-from-pokemon-winds-pokemon-waves-first-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 Things Learned From Pokémon Winds &amp; Waves Trailer</a></li>
</ul>



<p>But a closer look at dedicated Pokémon TCG social media pages might give more useful insight into when it’s arriving. Pokemon TCG Restocks &amp; News said: “If it follows the past Celebrations set, it will likely release in the fall!”</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">If it follows the past Celebrations set, it will likely release in the fall!</p>— Pokemon TCG Restocks &amp; News (@PokemonRestocks) <a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonRestocks/status/2027388937170268503?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>Furthermore, Pokémon Deals, Stock &amp; News UK offered a similar sentiment:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“They just said 2026. I expect around September/October.”<a href="https://x.com/pokemondealsuk/status/2027387540752237017"></a></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Obviously, this doesn’t mean it’s guaranteed, but with Perfect Order and Chaos Rising arriving next, we know the 30th Anniversary set isn’t releasing anytime soon. A Fall 2026 window looks very likely, so it would be wise to assume it’s another few months off yet.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">They just said 2026 😅 I expect around September/October</p>— Pokémon Deals, Stock &amp; News UK (@pokemondealsuk) <a href="https://twitter.com/pokemondealsuk/status/2027387540752237017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<h2 id="h-what-to-expect-from-pokemon-30th-anniversary-tcg-set">What To Expect From Pokémon 30th Anniversary TCG Set</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Inject it into our veins. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Pokémon 30th Anniversary TCG Set is expected to be a reprint of many of the TCG’s most iconic cards over the last three decades, immortalized with a special 30th anniversary logo or stamp.</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-winds-and-waves-gen-10-starters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Pokémon Winds &amp; Waves Starters</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s every card shown in the set reveal trailer to give you an idea of what’s coming:</p>



<ul>
<li>Charizard (Base Set)</li>



<li>Lugia (e-Series Crystal)</li>



<li>Palkia Lv. X</li>



<li>Uxie (Diamond &amp; Pearl)</li>



<li>Giratina &amp; Darkrai (Legends)</li>



<li>Genesect EX</li>



<li>Solgaleo GX</li>



<li>Zacian V</li>



<li>Pikachu &amp; Zekrom GX (Tag Team)</li>



<li>Raikou (Amazing Rare)</li>



<li>Arceus VStar</li>
</ul>



<p>This is merely a taster of what’s likely to be a full 200-300 card set, littered with Holos, Full Arts, and many more insanely valuable rares—there’s got to be some Charizards, right?</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Celebrating 30 Years 🎉 in the Pokémon TCG!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kz5vu1TwuNk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Will you be hoarding packs and Trainer Boxes for the 30th Anniversary set? Which cards are you hoping are included? Share your predictions and thoughts on the set via the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more fun Pokémon content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-game-music-collection-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get the Pokémon Game Music Collection</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-running-shoes-in-pokemon-fire-red-leaf-green/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get Running Shoes in Pokémon Fire Red &amp; Leaf Green</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-30th-anniversary-tcg-set-release/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Things We Learned From Pokémon Winds & Pokémon Waves First Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/7-things-we-learned-from-pokemon-winds-pokemon-waves-first-trailer/</link>
            <guid>1448743</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Pokémon Day 2026 was full of big announcements, with the most significant being the reveal of the 10th generation, Pokémon Winds and Waves.</p>



<p>As part of the 30th anniversary celebrations, marking three decades since the release of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/pokemon/" id="181" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon</a> Red and Green in Japan, a major showcase on Pokémon Day detailed a wide array of what fans can look forward to.</p>



<p>The first Pokémon Winds and Waves trailer was packed with information, and Insider Gaming has highlighted the main things we learned.</p>







<h2 id="h-7-things-we-learned-from-pokemon-winds-amp-waves-first-trailer">7 Things We Learned From Pokémon Winds &amp; Waves First Trailer</h2>



<h3 id="h-new-starter-pokemon">New Starter Pokémon</h3>



<figure><figcaption>New faces. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>One of the biggest standouts from the Pokémon Winds and Waves first trailer was the reveal of three starter Pokémon that players will choose from at the beginning of their journey.</p>



<p>Pokémon does not always reveal the starters immediately when dropping the first tease for a new generation, and doing so this early is eye-catching. However, the trio are already starting to make an impression on fans.</p>



<p>Browt, Pombon, and Gecqua are the three Pokémon available at the start of the journey in Winds and Waves, and while they’re already fully revealed, there’s still plenty of mystery.</p>



<h3 id="h-costumed-pikachu">Costumed Pikachu</h3>



<p>The Pokémon Wind and Waves trailer began by showcasing artwork from the various locations seen in previous games, before a knock on the door from two costumed Pikachu. </p>



<p>It turns out that they weren’t just there for the holiday vibes, as the two costumed Pikachu will appear in Gen 10. The exact version of the costumed Pikachu depends on which game you purchase.</p>



<p>No details have been shared on further details on the costumed Pikachu and how they fit into the game, but more is sure to be revealed soon.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/free-pokemon-legends-z-a-update-reveals-mega-garchomp-z-at-pokemon-presents-2026/" id="180871" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokémon Legends: Z-A Finally Adds Mega Garchomp Z</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-returning-pokemon">Returning Pokémon</h3>



<p>While Pokémon Wind and Waves will be headlined by a new generation of Pokémon, adding to the already-bloated list of 1025 to find and collect, there will also be returning Pokémon. During the trailer, plenty were shown.</p>



<p>The likes of Wailord, Tangela, Wingull, Sandygast, Tympole, and Duskull were among those seen, which confirms their evolution lines will also feature, meaning there will be a host of familiar faces to encounter on your journey.</p>



<p>More Pokémon<strong> </strong>returns are certain to be shown in the future, and we could also see the debut of new regional forms.</p>



<h3 id="h-island-landscapes">Island Landscapes</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Sea and Sky. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>Pokémon Winds and Waves will be an island-sprawling adventure, similar to what fans experience in Sun and Moon on the Nintendo 3DS, but with the added gem of being an open-world title.</p>



<p>Pokémon has moved away from the traditional linear structure in recent years, debuting a semi-open-world in Pokémon Legends: Arceus before a fully-fledged open-world adventure in Scarlet and Violet, and Winds and Waves will take this up a notch.</p>



<p>Further details on the environment will be revealed in the future, but there are already some stand-out landscapes.</p>



<h3 id="h-underwater-exploration">Underwater Exploration</h3>



<p>Pokémon Winds and Waves, as the name suggests, has big ties to the ocean, so bringing underwater exploration back for the 10th generation of the franchise was a natural step.</p>



<p>Although not explicitly stated to be the case, underwater exploration in Winds and Waves was leaked previously, and a tease toward the end of the trailer heavily suggested it will feature.</p>



<p>The footage showed the camera diving beneath the surface of the waves, with a variety of Pokémon swimming along and walking along the sandy floor.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-presents-february-2026-everything-announced/" id="180847" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Everything Announced In Pokémon<strong> </strong>Day 2026 Presents</a></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-switch-2-exclusive">Switch 2 Exclusive</h3>



<p>Unsurprisingly, the trailer confirmed that Pokémon Winds and Waves will be a Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive, with no mention of the original Switch console.</p>



<p>This was to be expected, considering Pokémon Pokopia is a Switch 2 exclusive, albeit also playable on the original Switch with gameshare, but similar features are unlikely to be present for Winds and Waves.</p>



<p>There’s plenty of time to secure a Switch 2 before Pokémon<strong> </strong>Winds and Waves releases, however.</p>



<h3 id="h-2027-release-window">2027 Release Window</h3>



<p>While there was a lot of expectation that Pokémon Winds and Waves would be released this year, that is not the case, and a tentative 2027 release window has been set.</p>



<p>That would make it a five-year gap between the release of Gen 9, Scarlet and Violet, to Gen 10, the biggest gap between two generations of the Pokémon franchise. However, considering the performance problems Gen 9 had at launch, there’s unlikely to be many complaints.</p>



<p>A more precise release window will be announced in time, and it does leave the door open for Pokémon to drop something else in Fall 2026.</p>







<hr>



<p>What stood out for you from the Pokémon Winds and Waves first trailer? Share your thoughts in the Insider Gaming Discord.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-go-bringing-back-almost-all-pokemon-for-anniversary-event/" id="180719" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">huge returns coming in Pokémon Go</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-30th-anniversary-tcg-set-revealed-for-2026-release/" id="180716" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details of the 30th anniversary TCG set</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/7-things-we-learned-from-pokemon-winds-pokemon-waves-first-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>