<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 13:11:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of the Ronin’s PS5 Pro Update is Now Live]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rise-of-the-ronins-ps5-pro-update-is-now-live/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rise-of-the-ronin%E2%80%99s-ps5-pro-update-is-now-live.1020873/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rise-of-the-ronins-ps5-pro-update-is-now-live/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-63138">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Rise of the Ronin is now among the few games that have received support for the PS5 Pro, thanks to update 1.08. Check out the features of the new patch below.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rise of the Ronin’s update <a href="https://x.com/TeamNINJAStudio/status/1850504304446304502" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">1.08</a> brings two new settings for PS5 Pro users, taking advantage of the mid-gen console refresh’s “enhanced visual fidelity.” The two new settings are “Prioritize FPS” and “Prioritize Graphics,” featuring “sharper and clearer visuals as well as higher and more stable framerates during combat”. Ver 1.08 also introduces some minor bug fixes for the title.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Rise of the Ronin is an open-world action RPG developed by Team Ninja for the PS5. In the game, players embody the role of a Ronin, who gets to shape their destiny in 19th-century Japan. Players experience the “Bakumatsu” period and the end of the Shogunate era.</p>



<p>During this journey, you interact with several historical figures, creating allies and enemies while mastering the game’s intuitive combat. Most importantly, your choices allow the story to unfold in different ways. Players can choose whether to assassinate or protect influential figures of this period and change the course of their journey.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Rise of the Ronin received <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rise-of-the-ronin-is-getting-new-features-and-missions-this-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new features and missions earlier this year</a>. Also, check out the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rise-of-the-ronin-trophy-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">complete trophy list</a>. What are your thoughts on Rise of the Ronin’s PS5 Pro update?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/888/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mrbeast-allegations-fbi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rosanna Parks sending MrBeast allegations to the FBI</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mrbeast-allegations-fbi/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mrbeast-allegations-fbi/">Rosanna Pansino Sends MrBeast Allegations To The FBI</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Rosanna Pansino, a YouTuber, has forwarded MrBeast allegations to the FBI after obtaining an ‘inappropriate’ private chat log.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/life-is-strange-double-exposure-leak-ending/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/life-is-strange-double-exposure-leak-ending/">Life is Strange: Double Exposure Will Have a Sequel, Leaks Suggest</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Life is Strange: Double Exposure is in the wild and leaks are surfacing, unveiling the game’s ending and a potential sequel.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/san-andreas-secret-maps-former-developer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/san-andreas-secret-maps-former-developer/">Former Rockstar Dev Reveals San Andreas Secret On Game’s Anniversary</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obbe Vermeij, a former Rockstar Games legends, has spilled another San Andreas secret on the game’s 20th anniversary.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-preservation-effort-us-copyright/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-preservation-effort-us-copyright/">US Copyright Office Shoots Down Video Game Preservation Effort</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The US Copyright Office has gunned down an attempt to legitimise video game preservation. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Kompakt 92 Loadout in Black Ops 6: Attachments, Perks & Equipment]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-kompakt-92-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-kompakt-92-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment.1020843/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-kompakt-92-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>There’s a lot of great <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-black-ops-6-weapons-every-gun-and-how-to-unlock/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">weapons to unlock in Black Ops 6</a>, but the Kompakt 92 is one of the last weapons you’ll unlock on your way to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-progression-and-prestige-system-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prestige</a>. It’s a very close-range SMG with a lot of potential, but you’ll need to use the best attachments, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-black-ops-6-game-modes-maps-equipment-field-upgrades/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Perks, and Equipment</a> to get the most out of it.</p>



<p>With that said, here’s the best Kompakt 92 loadout to use in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/">Black Ops 6</a>.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-best-kompakt-92-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best attachments</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-kompakt-92">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-secondary-for-kompakt-92">Best Secondary for Kompakt 92</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-how-to-unlock-kompakt-92-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock Kompakt 92 in Black Ops 6</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-is-the-kompakt-92-meta-in-black-ops-6">Is the Kompakt 92 any good in Black Ops 6?</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-alternatives-to-the-kompakt-92-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-kompakt-92-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best Kompakt 92 loadout attachments in Black Ops 6</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Barrel</strong>: Integrated Suppressor Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Underbarrel</strong>: Vertical Foregrip</li>



<li><strong>Magazine</strong>: Extended Mag I</li>



<li><strong>Rear Grip</strong>: Commando Grip</li>



<li><strong>Fire Mods</strong>: Recoil Springs</li>
</ul>



<p>For our best <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/uk/en/playnow/blackops6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Black Ops 6</a> Kompakt 92 SMG loadout, you’ll want the <strong>Integrated Suppressor Barrel</strong> as it keeps you off the enemy’s radar while also improving bullet velocity and damage range.</p>



<p>Next, the <strong>Vertical Foregrip</strong> tames the weapon’s strong vertical recoil, allowing you to stay on target while <strong>Extended Mag I </strong>gives you enough ammo to take on multiple enemies.</p>



<p>The <strong>Commando Grip</strong> provides a boost to handling, improving aim down sight and sprint to fire speeds. Lastly, the <strong>Recoil Springs </strong>Fire Mod provides more control for the gun’s rapid fire rate.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Activision.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-kompakt-92">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment for Kompakt 92</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Perk 1</strong>: Gung-Ho</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2</strong>: Assassin</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3</strong>: Double Time</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard</strong>: Overkill</li>



<li><strong>Lethal</strong>: Molotov</li>



<li><strong>Tactical</strong>: Stim Shot</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade</strong>: Sleeper Agent</li>
</ul>



<p>As the Kompakt 92 SMG is a very close-range weapon, I found it most effective when paired with Perks that improve mobility and handling. <strong>Gung-Ho</strong> improves your sprint speeds while reloading and using Equipment, <strong>Assassin</strong> reveals enemies on a kill streak, and <strong>Double Time</strong> greatly increases the duration of Tactical Sprint so that you can get behind enemy lines fast. </p>



<p>Using these 3 Perks also unlocks the <strong>Enforcer Combat Specialty</strong>, which is great for an aggressive SMG loadout such as this one, as it replenishes your health upon every kill and gives you a speed buff.</p>



<p>When it comes to Equipment, the <strong>Molotov</strong> is a Lethal that burns enemies on impact and leaves a deadly pool of fire behind for a short period, catching unsuspecting enemies who walk into it. For the Tactical, a Flashbang is perfect for breaching rooms and areas of the map when running and gunning.</p>



<p>Lastly, the <strong>Sleeper Agent</strong> Field Upgrade disguises you as an enemy teammate which is perfect for sneaking behind enemies and getting as close as possible before unloading the rapid-fire Kompakt 92 SMG.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-secondary-for-kompakt-92">Best Secondary for Kompakt 92</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-xm4-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XM4</a> is an excellent Secondary to use with the Kompakt 92, as it allows you to take on enemies at those medium-to-long range distances where the Kompakt 92 struggles. </p>



<p>This, of course, is only possible with the Overkill Wildcard equipped, if you opt for a different Wildcard, the <strong>9mm PM </strong>Pistol<strong> </strong>has the best damage range of all the handguns in the game, so it’s a wise choice.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-kompakt-92-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock Kompakt 92 in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>You will need to reach <strong>Level 49</strong> to unlock the Kompakt 92 SMG in Black Ops 6. This may take some time, but if you continue playing objective-based game modes that get you a lot of XP, you’ll eventually reach the rank.</p>



<p>If you’re looking to level up fast, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-level-up-fast-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guide on how to get XP and climb the ranks quickly</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-alternatives-to-the-kompakt-92-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives to the Kompakt 92 in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>Another fast-firing SMG that can dominate up close is the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-ksv-loadout-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KSV</a> making it a great alternative to the Kompakt. You could also use the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-c9-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">C9</a>, which is also a top close-range weapon. If you want something with a bit more range, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-gpr-91-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/">GPR 9</a> is an Assault Rifle with SMG-like handling and mobility.</p>



<hr>



<p>For the latest on Black Ops 6, sign up for&nbsp;<a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s weekly newsletter</a>. If you want a break from Multiplayer, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-complete-liberty-falls-music-easter-egg-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to complete the Liberty Falls music Easter egg</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rosanna Pansino Sends MrBeast Allegations To The FBI]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mrbeast-allegations-fbi/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rosanna-pansino-sends-mrbeast-allegations-to-the-fbi.1020765/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/mrbeast-allegations-fbi/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Rosanna Pansino’s crusade against Jimmy ‘MrBeast’ Donaldson and his team has reached a new level as she forwarded her recent allegations to the FBI for further investigation. It started with Pansino slamming MrBeast’s new ‘Lunchly’ line for containing mould, and now, she has obtained and shared details of a claimed ‘official MrBeast work chat’.</p>



<p>In this chat, thousands of messages are revealed, many of which are ‘inappropriate, especially for a company that targets children’.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-another-one">Another One</h2>



<p>Earlier this year, MrBeast came under scrutiny when <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ava-kris-tyson-predator-allegations/">‘Ava Kris Tyson’</a>, a close member of his team, was outed by allegations of ‘sexual messaging with a minor’, which the creator partially admitted to before leaving MrBeast’s production team.</p>



<p>One of the most damning claims from Pansino is that MrBeast <strong>must have </strong>known about Tyson’s behaviour given the nature of some of the messages and memes shared in the chat she obtained. Per her report in a recent video, she has ‘verified the legitimacy of these chats’, but some MrBeast fans have claimed it’s nothing more than a smear campaign.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I have reported what I found and my concerns to the authorities <a href="https://twitter.com/FBI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FBI</a>.  Hopefully they will look into these  MrBeast Telegram Company Chats Logs and other concerns. <a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Youtube</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamYouTube?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TeamYouTube</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mrbeast?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mrbeast</a></p>— Rosanna Pansino (@RosannaPansino) <a href="https://twitter.com/RosannaPansino/status/1850650883027239117?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In August, it was revealed that MrBeast’s channel suffered a monumental revenue and performance decrease as various controversies surfaced. After the news about Ava Kris Tyson, other participants in MrBeast’s videos came forward to make claims of human rights abuses and poor working conditions while working with the super-sized creator.</p>



<p>It was estimated that in August 2024, amid the scandals, his channel lost around $2.6 million in expected revenue, based on estimations and prior performance. </p>



<p>MrBeast’s team is yet to respond to Rosanna Pansino’s allegations.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-worlds-grand-final-t1-bilibili/">the stage is set for the LoL Worlds finals</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bilibili and T1 Through To League Worlds Grand Final]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/league-worlds-grand-final-t1-bilibili/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bilibili-and-t1-through-to-league-worlds-grand-final.1020651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/league-worlds-grand-final-t1-bilibili/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Following an intense knockout stage that has unravelled over two weeks, the grand finalists have been revealed in the League of Legends World Championship 2024. For the trophy, and the $445,000 grand prize, <strong>Bilibili and T1</strong> will face off on November 2, live in London at the O2 Arena.</p>



<p>This could be the ultimate opportunity for Faker to secure his <strong>fifth </strong>world championship title, forever cementing him as one of the greatest esports competitors of all time.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-heavy-is-the-crown">Heavy is the Crown</h2>



<p>It has been one hell of a journey to get this far. This year’s League of Legends World Championship event started on September 25, and there’s still just under a week until it’s all wrapped up. When that day comes, either Bilibili Gaming will have claimed its first LoL Worlds trophy, or T1 will have secured its <strong>fifth </strong>championship.</p>



<p>The last barrier for T1 to get this far was Gen.G, and social media managers were quick to promote the contest between T1’s Faker and Gen.G’s Chovy.</p>



<p>In the numbers, Faker and Chovy are putting out similar win-loss records, and their head-to-head figures over the years have ebbed and flowed dramatically. This year, Chovy was proving to be a thorn in Faker’s side, but when it counted most, Faker was able to gut up and push Chovy and his team out of League Worlds.</p>



<p>In 2022, the pair competed side-by-side during the Asian Games.</p>



<p>Now, all that stands between Faker, T1, and a fifth world championship trophy is Bilibili, an organisation that’s yet to secure a T2 finish at Worlds. Not one member of the all-Chinese team has claimed a League Worlds trophy yet, and despite a lacklustre Swiss Stage, Bilibili has recouped some momentum and stormed through the Knockout Stage.</p>



<p>One series is all it’ll take to decide this year’s champion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-esports-on-horizon/">Undisputed is eyeing up an esports ecosystem</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best KSV Loadout in Black Ops 6: Attachments, Perks & Equipment]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-ksv-loadout-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-ksv-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment.1020615/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-ksv-loadout-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The KSV is a meta SMG in Call of Duty <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-ops-6-guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6</a> and gives great results in close-range combat. The best thing about this gun is it’s available early in the game. You can get started with it and tweak the loadout from there on.</p>



<p>However, to get the most out of the weapon, here’s the best KSV loadout in BO6 with the right set of attachments, Perks, and Equipment.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="#h-best-ksv-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best attachments</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-ksv">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-secondary-for-ksv">Best Secondary for KSV</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-how-to-unlock-ksv-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock KSV in Black Ops 6</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-is-the-ksv-any-good-in-black-ops-6">Is the KSV any good in Black Ops 6?</a></li>



<li><a href="#h-best-alternatives-to-the-ksv-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-ksv-loadout-attachments-in-black-ops-6">Best KSV loadout attachments in Black Ops 6</h2>



<figure></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Muzzle</strong>: Suppressor</li>



<li><strong>Barrel</strong>: Long Barrel</li>



<li><strong>Rear Grip</strong>: Quickdraw Grip</li>



<li><strong>Stock</strong>: Infiltrator Stock</li>



<li><strong>Magazine</strong>: Flip Mag</li>
</ul>



<p>Starting with the <strong>Suppressor</strong>, this attachment not only suppresses the firing sounds but also hides you from the mini-map. It unlocks at level 2 which is very easy to do.</p>



<p><strong>Long Barrel</strong> increases the firepower of the SMG by increasing the damage range. It unlocks when the KSV reaches level 3 and helps deal with more damage in medium-range combat. Right after this one, the <strong>Quickdraw Grip</strong> will unlock at level 6, attach it immediately. This attachment significantly increases the Aim Down Sight speed of the gun and helps you aim faster, enhancing its handling.</p>



<p>The <strong>Infiltrator Stock</strong> unlocks at level 8 and will improve your mobility by enhancing the Aim Walking Movement Speed. Lastly, get the <strong>Flip Mag</strong> after reaching weapon level 17 to improve the reload speed of the KSV.</p>







<h2 id="h-best-perks-wildcard-amp-equipment-for-ksv">Best Perks, Wildcard &amp; Equipment for KSV</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>Perk 1</strong>: Ghost</li>



<li><strong>Perk 2</strong>: Tracker</li>



<li><strong>Perk 3</strong>: Cold-Blooded</li>



<li><strong>Perk 4</strong>: Gung-Ho</li>



<li><strong>Wildcard</strong>: Perk Greed</li>



<li><strong>Lethal</strong>: Semtex</li>



<li><strong>Tactical</strong>: Stim Shot</li>



<li><strong>Field Upgrade</strong>: Tactical Insertion</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Ghost</strong> leaves you undetected by Scout Pulse or UAV and <strong>Tracker</strong> allows you to see enemy footsteps. Use <strong>Cold-Blooded</strong> as the third Perk to remain undetected under thermal optics. These perks will activate Recon – the ability to see enemies through walls briefly.</p>



<p>Use the fourth Perk slot to equip <strong>Gung-Ho</strong>. This will increase Sprinting speeds while reloading or using Equipment. <strong>Semtex</strong> will add more firepower to the loadout while <strong>Stim Shot</strong> will help you heal up quickly. For the Field Upgrade, use the <strong>Tactical Insertion</strong> for custom spawn points in the map.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-best-secondary-for-ksv">Best Secondary for KSV</h2>



<p>The ideal secondary weapon options for the KSV are Stryder .22 and GS45.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-ksv-in-black-ops-6">How to unlock KSV in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>You can unlock the KSV after reaching player level 7 in Black Ops 6. You don’t need to wait too long for this weapon as only a few multiplayer matches would unlock the weapon and you can start grinding from there on.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-the-ksv-any-good-in-black-ops-6">Is the KSV any good in Black Ops 6?</h2>



<p>Yes, at the time of writing, the KSV is one of the meta weapons in BO6. Although it comes with a high recoil, controlling it is easy and on the positive side, you get a fast TTK and high mobility with it – two crucial aspects for intense multiplayer lobbies.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-alternatives-to-the-ksv-in-black-ops-6">Best alternatives to the KSV in Black Ops 6</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-jackal-pdw-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jackal PDW</a> is easily one of the best alternatives to the KSV. However, if you want to try something different, a weapon that’s slower but hits hard, give the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-tanto-22-loadout-in-black-ops-6-attachments-perks-equipment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tanto .22</a> a try.</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay up to date with all the latest news and guides on Black Ops 6 by signing up for&nbsp;<a href="https://s0lkh.mjt.lu/wgt/s0lkh/x29u/form?c=d1dc471a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s weekly newsletter</a>. Since the game has finally dropped, check here <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-level-up-fast-in-black-ops-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to level up fast in BO6</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>