<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:07:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 Has A Limited Edition Watch That Costs Around $1500]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-has-a-limited-edition-watch-that-costs-around-1500/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-has-a-limited-edition-watch-that-costs-around-1500.1130463/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-has-a-limited-edition-watch-that-costs-around-1500/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hamilton has partnered with Hideo Kojima and Yoji Shinkawa to release the&nbsp;American Classic Boulton Death Stranding 2 Limited Edition watch, which costs around $1500.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Death Stranding 2’s pre-order announcement arrived yesterday, finally providing players with the sequel’s long-anticipated release date. Along with the announcement, players also received a new 10-minute trailer, which showcased a bit of the game’s narrative and gameplay sequences. Luca Marinelli is introduced around the 8-minute mark and looks like a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-luca-marinelli-solid-snake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spitting image of Solid Snake</a>. Interestingly, the watch Marinelli wore in the Death Stranding 2 pre-order trailer is now on sale.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership, spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/neils-watch-in-death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-to-be-made-into-real-timepiece-by-hamilton-and-kojima-productions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action/you-can-look-like-solid-snake-with-this-death-stranding-2-watch-but-itll-cost-you-over-usd1-500/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+</a>), includes a 36x48mm black PVD titanium Death Stranding 2 Limited Edition watch. The design “embraces the game’s futuristic spirit” and features an orange seconds hand, a sleek black dial, and seven sapphire crystals for light play. Only 2,000 pieces of the watch were made.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-death-stranding-2-limited-edition-watch-price-and-release-date">Death Stranding 2 Limited Edition Watch Price and Release Date</h2>



<p>The Death Stranding 2 Limited Edition watch is priced at USD 1,495 and will be available from Hamilton’s website when the game releases on June 26, 2025.&nbsp;Players can check the availability on Hamilton’s <a href="https://www.hamiltonwatch.com/en-us/h13605130-american-classic-boulton-titanium-death-stranding-two.html" rel="nofollow">website</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-death-stranding-2-watch-features-nbsp">Death Stranding 2 Watch Features&nbsp;</h2>



<p>As mentioned, the watch features seven sapphire crystals and a titanium case. It has a primary display and two slide columns. The highlight is the exclusive case back, which features a custom design of the Death Stranding logo and a unique engraved number on each piece.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It is a self-winding watch. Your wrist movements transfer energy to the mainspring, making the inner rotor swing. The watch also has a Nivachron balance spring and three-hand automatic movement with a power reserve of 80 hours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Death Stranding 2 Collector’s Edition <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-release-date-platforms-editions-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">costs $229.99</a>. What are your thoughts on the Death Stranding 2 Limited Edition watch?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/control-ultimate-editions-new-update-introduces-hideo-kojima-mission-for-all-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Control releasing the Hideo Kojima mission for all platforms</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Tier Two CS2 Team Has Already Played 100+ Maps in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/a-tier-two-cs2-team-has-already-played-100-maps-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-tier-two-cs2-team-has-already-played-100-maps-in-2025.1130289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/a-tier-two-cs2-team-has-already-played-100-maps-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Counter-Strike 2 competitive scene is known for its dauntingly stacked calendar, but one team is racking up official maps played at a breakneck pace. Unsurprisingly, it’s a tier two team that has to play a marathon of matches just to qualify for events like the illustrious Majors.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-tier-two-bc-game-could-break-the-cs2-record-for-most-official-maps-played-in-a-year">Tier Two BC.Game Could Break the CS2 Record for Most Official Maps Played in a Year</h2>



<p>It’s not even halfway through March, and the European veteran roster playing for BC.Game has already <a href="https://www.hltv.org/stats/teams/12878/bcgame?startDate=2025-01-01&amp;endDate=2025-12-31" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">played 107 official maps</a> of professional Counter-Strike in 2025. BC.Game, a crypto casino website, entered CS2 in the summer of 2024. In the second half of that year, the team played 94 maps, but they have already beaten that number this year in less than half the time.</p>



<p>107 official maps played so far averages out to more than 1.55 maps per day. While that doesn’t sound like a lot to a casual player, that’s only taking into account official matches as part of a tournament or qualifier. It doesn’t include the hours spent practicing, scrimming, or traveling. In 2024, the team that played the most official maps was Polish team Permitta, who played 467. But at their current rate, BC.Game could pass 500 official maps played before the end of the year.</p>



<p>Tier two teams like BC.Game are burdened with having to play far more maps of Counter-Strike than the higher ranked tier one teams. In comparison, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-spirit-win-shanghai-cs-major/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reigning Major champions Team Spirit</a> have only played 35 maps so far this year, less than a third of the total that BC.Game has accrued. Tier two teams such as BC.Game consistently have to play through open qualifiers to reach prestigious CS2 events, as they don’t have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-vrs-in-cs2-valve-regional-standings-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Valve-determined ranking</a> to receive a direct invite to playoffs or later stages of certain events. Even Fnatic, who once dominated Counter-Strike a decade ago, had to play <a href="https://www.hltv.org/team/4991/fnatic#tab-matchesBox" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">seven best-of-three series</a> across the past two days.</p>



<p>Will BC.Game, or any CS2 team, reach 500 official maps played in 2025? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cache-is-returning-to-counter-strike-but-only-once-valve-approves-it-for-cs2/">Cache is coming back to CS2</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next-Gen Xbox Console Release Planned For 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-gen-xbox-console-release-planned-for-2027/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-gen-xbox-console-release-planned-for-2027.1130283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-gen-xbox-console-release-planned-for-2027/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The next-generation Xbox console is two years away from release. According to a new report from Windows Central’s Jez Corden, Microsoft is currently targeting 2027 for release of its next mainline Xbox consoles.</p>



<p>Per <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/xbox-hardware-report-project-keenan-next-gen-xbox-2027" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the report</a>, the new systems are in full production at Microsoft. </p>



<p>“[Our] sources also indicate that Microsoft’s internal successor to the Xbox Series X|S platform has been fully greenlit all the way up to CEO Satya Nadella,” Corden writes.</p>



<p>He adds that it’s believed that the current plans for the next generation of Xbox include a “premium successor” to the Xbox Series X along with its own in-house developed handheld console. There are also plans for “several” new controllers.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-future-of-call-of-duty-insider-gaming-weekly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Future Of Call of Duty—Insider Gaming Weekly</a></h6>



<p>Corden’s report also follows up <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-not-a-console-at-all-insider/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">his earlier claims</a> that new Xbox consoles will be “closer to Windows than ever before”.  The new systems will also still support backwards compatibility to allow older games to be played.</p>



<p>In addition to the new consoles, Microsoft is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-launching-partner-gaming-handheld-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reportedly planning to launch</a> an Xbox-partnered handheld gaming system later in 2025.</p>



<p>None of these plans have been officially announced by Microsoft. Until that happens—and even after they become public—, understand that targets can always change. Insider Gaming has reached out to Xbox for comment on the claims. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>What do you think of the next generation Xbox consoles targetting a 2027 release date? Let us know down below and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1734/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked/">leaked release date</a> for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle on PlayStation 5. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Launching Partner Gaming Handheld This Year, Report Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-launching-partner-gaming-handheld-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-launching-partner-gaming-handheld-this-year-report-claims.1130280/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-launching-partner-gaming-handheld-this-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Xbox is finally getting into the gaming handheld space. According to a new report from Jez Corden of Windows Central, Microsoft is working to launch an Xbox-branded handheld later in 2025.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/xbox-hardware-report-project-keenan-next-gen-xbox-2027" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report states</a> that it won’t be a Microsoft produced device. Instead, the company is working with a partner OEM (Original Equipment Manufacturer).</p>



<p>The device, under the codename “Keenan”, “will look unmistakably Xbox”, the report says. The device will even feature an Xbox Guide button that is featured on Xbox controllers.</p>



<p>Not much was given regarding features. However, there was speculation from the report.</p>



<p>“Given that this is a partner device, similar to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lenovo-legion-go-s-is-the-first-third-party-steamos-handheld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lenovo’s SteamOS partnership with Valve</a>, I expect this handheld to be more PC-oriented,” Corden says. “It’ll most likely run full Windows, putting the Microsoft Store and PC Game Pass front and center, alongside the ability to install things like Steam.”</p>



<p>In addition to the plans for an Xbox-themed handheld this year, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-gen-xbox-console-release-planned-for-2027/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft is targeting 2027</a> for its next-gen console.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Xbox for comment on the claims. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>What do you think of Microsoft working on launching an Xbox gaming handheld this year? Is it something you’ll pick up? Let us know down below and in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1733/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked/">leaked release date</a> for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle on PlayStation 5. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>