<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:54:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kick Has Hit 50 Million Users Worldwide After Two Years]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kick-users-50-million-worldwide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kick-has-hit-50-million-users-worldwide-after-two-years.1083657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/kick-users-50-million-worldwide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Kick.com surfaced in 2022, emerging as a legitimate competitor to platforms like Twitch and YouTube. After a rocky and controversial birthing period, Kick stabilised, pulling in many users thanks to a lucrative revenue-sharing scheme that promised to reimburse creators for their time spent on the site.</p>



<p>Fast forward to today, and Kick has secured 50 million users, proving it’s not just a flash in the pan and it’s most likely here to stay, controversy or not.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-consistent-growth">Consistent Growth</h2>



<p>Kick was a stigmatised platform from the outset. It was plagued by issues such as a lack of content moderation and the adoption of controversial creators, some of whom were responsible for the platform receiving a negative brand very early on.</p>



<p>Things have more or less turned around for the site, and while it’s not yet as powerful as Twitch, it’s trailing just behind the Amazon-backed streaming site.</p>



<p>In a recent social media post, the team at Kick revealed that 50 million users have found their way onto the streaming platform, which is not a number to be scoffed at. It’s always tough to build a <strong>new </strong>site like this, as the first people to make their way on board will be streamers, which means you inevitably build a user base made up entirely of <strong>creators </strong>and not <strong>viewers</strong>.</p>



<p>That doesn’t seem to be the case with Kick.com.</p>



<p>Recently, the team also revealed an intention <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-intends-to-buy-tiktok-us/">to purchase TikTok US</a> from ByteDance, a shocking revelation that could have drastic implications for the content creation market. TikTok is the number one ‘shorts’ video-sharing platform in the world, and it has access to 170 million users in the United States.</p>



<p>Have you got a Kick.com account, or are you not interested in the platform? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-outperforming-consoles/">PC gaming is overwhelming console gaming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kick Intends to Buy TikTok US From ByteDance, It’s Suggested]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kick-intends-to-buy-tiktok-us/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kick-intends-to-buy-tiktok-us-from-bytedance-it%E2%80%99s-suggested.1083654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/kick-intends-to-buy-tiktok-us/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It has been revealed on social media – perhaps in jest – that the Stake-backed streaming platform, Kick.com, intends to procure TikTok’s US assets from ByteDance Ltd. This revelation was uncovered in an image uploaded in response to Mr Beast suggesting he and ‘some billionaires’ are preparing to buy TikTok’s US platform ahead of the application’s nationwide ban.</p>



<p>Kick.com emerged in December 2022 as a competitor to YouTube and Twitch, and it has grown pretty quickly in a relatively short time. Is there enough in the platform’s coffers to purchase a US ‘version’ of TikTok? This post suggests there is.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-proposal">The Proposal</h2>



<p>On Twitter (X), Kick’s social media team shared a semi-redacted image of a ‘letter of intent’ to purchase a business. In this case, the business is ‘TikTok U.S.’, and it’ll be acquired from the grip of ByteDance Ltd, the Beijing-based tech titan that owns the TikTok application, amongst many others.</p>











<p>The image suggested the document is 69 pages long and that the transaction would include ‘real estate’ in California in the form of a 120,000-square-foot campus.</p>



<p>The amount Kick.com would be paying for TikTok wasn’t disclosed, but judging from the length of the redaction, it looks as though it would be in the billions of dollars. It’s also noted that the purchase is for a ‘percentage ownership interest in the business’, which suggests it might not be an outright acquisition.</p>



<p>The full document was kept hidden, with Kick.com sharing only the top page.</p>



<p>Do you think this is legitimate, or is it just Kick’s social media team having fun with Mr Beast and everyone involved? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a> and learn <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/will-tiktok-be-banned-us-and-when/">what the TikTok ban means</a> for US application users.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-outperforming-consoles/">PC gaming has been outperforming consoles for years</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PC Gaming Has Been Outperforming Console For Years – And It’s Getting Stronger]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-outperforming-consoles/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pc-gaming-has-been-outperforming-console-for-years-%E2%80%93-and-it%E2%80%99s-getting-stronger.1083645/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-outperforming-consoles/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A recent report published by Epyllion sums up the state of the games industry in more than two hundred pages. This gargantuan analysis examines everything from consumer spending to hardware records, giving readers critical insights into the last decade or so of gaming knowledge.</p>



<p>It reveals that, based on key data points from multiple sources, PC gaming has become increasingly powerful over the last decade or so, breezing past console platforms and generating more content spending and revenue.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-pc-power">PC Power</h2>



<p>In <a href="https://www.matthewball.co/all/stateofvideogaming2025">Epyllion’s report</a> (tracked down by <a href="https://fictionhorizon.com/pc-gaming-outsells-consoles-and-becomes-the-industrys-bright-spot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">FictionHorizon</a>), the cold, hard facts are made clear.</p>



<p>One slide revealed that since 2011, PC’s content spend has dominated ‘living room’ console revenue by more than 65%, and it has earned 225% more than ‘combined console’ spend. That’s a total of $30 billion if you want to put a number on it.</p>



<p>Those numbers <strong>exclude </strong>hardware and accessories.</p>



<p>The report also showed that mobile gaming is leagues ahead of both PC and console platforms, representing the number one money maker in the games industry.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Credit: Epyllion</figcaption></figure>



<p>This stat has been recorded despite an $18 billion increase in spending on console platforms in 2024 compared to 2011. That 75% increase is still trumped by content spend on PC platforms.</p>



<p>But why is PC becoming increasingly popular and much more profitable?</p>



<p>Epyllion suggested it boils down to a few core reasons:</p>



<ul>
<li>PC platforms have a much larger library of games and ‘near-full backwards compatibility’</li>



<li>On a PC, you can multi-task (stream, communicate, alt+tab, multiple monitors)</li>



<li>Lower entry price point than consoles</li>



<li>Higher top-end performance</li>



<li>Better for esports and competitive gaming</li>



<li>Able to play more early-access games</li>



<li>More annual game releases</li>



<li>Console ‘exclusives’ are now finding their way to PC</li>
</ul>



<p>It’s easy to see where some of the money comes from. For instance, Counter-Strike’s ‘skin market’, which debuted in 2013, is now worth around $5 billion, and it’s tied exclusively to PC.</p>



<p>Home console sales have slumped somewhat in this generation compared to previous ‘eras’, while PC gaming continues to consistently show growth. With the rise of content creation, streaming, and UGC, everyone wants to play on a PC, and technological leaps are making hardware more readily available, powerful, and in many cases, affordable.</p>



<p>Do you have a PC, or are you reliant on home consoles? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/100t-valorants-boostio-says-nrg-cant-win-championships-with-fns/">our esports interview with VALORANT’s Boostio</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: 100T VALORANT’s Boostio Says It’s ‘Not Possible’ for NRG to Win Championships with FNS]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/100t-valorants-boostio-says-nrg-cant-win-championships-with-fns/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-100t-valorant%E2%80%99s-boostio-says-it%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98not-possible%E2%80%99-for-nrg-to-win-championships-with-fns.1083504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/100t-valorants-boostio-says-nrg-cant-win-championships-with-fns/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>At the start of last year’s season, reigning VALORANT champion Kelden “Boostio” Pupello was one of several players to leave Evil Geniuses. In his first year with 100 Thieves, Boostio and the team won the first VCT Americas split, and barely missed out on Champions.</p>



<p>Ahead of his second season with 100T, Boostio took the time to talk to Insider Gaming. And rather than just talk about the upside of his own team, he also had something to say about a long-time rival.</p>



<hr>



<p>The following interview has been edited slightly for clarity and length.</p>



<p><strong>Q: I <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eg-coach-potter-says-yay-has-to-prove-hes-not-a-chamber-main/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spoke to your former coach Potter earlier</a></strong>. <strong>We talked about the importance of keeping a roster core together between seasons. From the in-game leader’s perspective, how important is it to you to have that familiarity between players already?</strong></p>



<p>It’s really important. It’s more important for the one or two people joining, because they’re going to be the ones out of comfort coming into our system. So when you keep a core, those players are going to be comfortable and [they] know what needs to happen in order to win.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So for us four, we won split one [last year], we know how to win. When we were winning we were considered one of the best teams in the world; we were owning everyone. Since we kept the coach, IGL, and three other players, it makes it easier on us and the new player. We just need to execute like we did before.</p>



<p><strong>Q: How do you avoid replicating the slow start you had at Kickoff last year?</strong></p>



<p>[Smiles] Yeah I hope we don’t go 0-2. I hope we make Masters. This first tournament is so early on in the year, that anyone can really luck out, to be honest. I feel like a lot of teams could get lucky, like LOUD last year. They were clearly not a top team but they ended up making it to [Masters] Madrid.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><figcaption>Boaster has never shied away from talking trash. Photo by David Lee/Riot Games.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Q: Did <a href="https://x.com/Sentinels/status/1843418707244265495" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bang’s departure</a> catch the rest of the team off guard?</strong></p>



<p>Me, bang, and Asuna all hang out in a Discord all the time, and we knew bang was leaving before the org knew or before the coach knew. When [Sentinels] contacted him, [since] he’s a younger kid and he doesn’t really know what he wants, he asked for advice. And so Peter and I told him: “Bro, go try out. You’re gonna get paid way more, you’re gonna be way more popular on Sentinels, go fucking do it. If you have to leave us, it sucks, but there’s no way you say no to that.”</p>



<p><strong>Q: It was a very light offseason for you guys with just one official series played at an event. With VCT less than a week away, how prepared do you feel you are, especially with the new agent now in play?</strong></p>



<p>I feel good. I think we are strong. Like I said, when we’re playing well, I think we’re the best team in the world, or [at least] one that can contend for a championship. And I think you have to be a pretty special team to even be in the argument to contend.</p>



<p>Like NRG, and this is clickbait but I fully believe it, are going to be a good team, probably. You have FNS on your team, and I think he’s the best NA IGL of all time, but with his mechanics, when you’re playing in championship matches, you’re not gonna win with someone like him on your team. It’s just not possible.</p>



<p>So for us, I think all five players are insane, if we just keep up mechanically like we normally are, which is better than a lot of teams, and keep our team play at a decently high level, we’ll just win.</p>



<hr>



<p>Which teams from VCT Americas are going to reach Masters ? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p>For more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>, stay tuned to Insider Gaming, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-tejo-in-valorant-tips-and-tricks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out the newest VALORANT agent, Tejo</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports FC 25 To Get “Most Significant” Gameplay Overhaul This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-fc-25-to-get-most-significant-gameplay-overhaul-this-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sports-fc-25-to-get-%E2%80%9Cmost-significant%E2%80%9D-gameplay-overhaul-this-week.1083402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-fc-25-to-get-most-significant-gameplay-overhaul-this-week/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-83888">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>EA Sports has announced that it will be bringing its “most significant mid-season gameplay overhaul” ever to EA Sports FC 25. Launching on January 16, this update features dozens of changes to various aspects of the game.</p>



<p>According to EA, players will see changes like updates to “core gameplay systems” like shooting, passing, defending, and goalkeeping. Changes to gameplay fluidity will allow players to move the ball better while there will be reduced tacklebacks and AI interceptions. EA also addressed concerns such as defenders catching up to dribblers “too often”. </p>



<p>You can check out the full details of the gameplay overhaul coming to EA Sports FC 25 via the <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-fc/fc-25/news/fc-25-pitch-notes-gameplay-refresh-update" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">game’s official website</a>. You can see read a preview of some of the bigger changes below.</p>



<h2 id="h-ea-sports-fc-25-gameplay-updates">EA Sports FC 25 Gameplay Updates</h2>



<p><strong>More Fluid Offensive Positioning And Better Attacking Support</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Improved AI teammate attacking run quality when trying to beat the offside line.
<ul>
<li>AI teammates can now better hold their runs when near the line and get back onside more quickly.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Increased intelligence of attacking and supporting runs made by AI teammates.</li>



<li>Improved effectiveness of Inside and Advance Forwards.
<ul>
<li>They can move farther up the pitch.</li>



<li>They can better evaluate when to run into space or occupy a position.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Offensive players can now operate in attacking spaces near other attackers instead of stopping their runs.</li>



<li>Players are now able to provide quicker support when they are familiar with their Role.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Reducing Tacklebacks</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Defenders with the Anticipate PlayStyle are now more likely to tackle the ball towards a teammate with more space if stopping the ball in place would be disadvantageous.</li>



<li>Improved the quality of touches defenders can make on tackles.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Faster Passing, Balance Changes, And Issues Addressed</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Slightly increased speed of normal Ground Passes.</li>



<li>Slightly increased accuracy of short Ground Passes to open players.</li>



<li>Significantly increased effectiveness of Semi Assisted Through Passes.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Significantly reduced effectiveness of first-time Lofted Through Passes.</li>



<li>Significantly increased effectiveness of Semi Assisted Through Passes.</li>



<li>Moderately reduced accuracy of headed passes in contested situations.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p>What do you think of the gameplay changes coming to EA Sports FC 25? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pga-tour-2k25-revealed-releases-february-28/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out the first details</a>&nbsp;for the upcoming release of PGA Tour 2K25. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-spiderman-suit-coming/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-spiderman-suit-coming/">One of the Best Spidey Suits is Coming to Marvel Rivals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>NetEase has announced that a new Spider-Man suit is coming to Marvel Rivals, and it’s one of the nicest Spidey suits around.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-liberty-city-preservation-project-shut-down/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-liberty-city-preservation-project-shut-down/">The GTA 5 Liberty City Preservation Project Has Been Shut Down by Rockstar Games</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Last month, the Liberty City Preservation Project brought GTA 4 as a Mod to GTA 5 and gained mass social media attention.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortunes-run-dev-prison-sentence/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortunes-run-dev-prison-sentence/">‘I Was a Very Violent Person’: Indie Dev Gives Up Game to Serve 3-Year Prison Sentence</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The sole developer of a ‘Very Positive’ indie game on Steam will put updates on hold as they serve a 36-month prison sentence.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-list-of-known-issues/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-list-of-known-issues/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 List of Known Issues (UPDATED)</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developers Treyarch and Raven Software have released a list of the known issues in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>