<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:57:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment Gets New Trailer, Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-new-trailer-nintendo-switch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-new-trailer-characters.1334317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Nintendo has released a new trailer for Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment. In it, we see intense combat, including two newly revealed characters, such as a talking Korok, joining the roster.</p>



<p>The Hyrule Warriors series has been going strong for more than 10 years, combining the beautiful world of Legend of Zelda and the hack-and-slash gameplay of Dynasty Warriors. The last release, Age of Calamity, adapted Breath of the Wild and told the story of the Guardians during the Great Calamity. Now, we get to see the original Guardians that took a stand against Ganon, which is shown in flashbacks in Tears of the Kingdom. With its November 6th, 2025 release coming up, a new trailer for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-release-date-direct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> shows off more of the game’s story and Musou gameplay, alongside some fresh faces.</p>



<h2 id="h-new-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-trailer-reveals-playable-korok-zonai-warrior">New Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment Trailer Reveals Playable Korok, Zonai Warrior</h2>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment – Unite Against the Demon King – Nintendo Switch 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WYpLBmy7xMw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In the trailer, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WYpLBmy7xMw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">shown above</a>, we get some new footage of Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment, including story and gameplay. We see the first Guardians battle it out with Ganon’s limitless forces, with King Rauru at the helm. As Zelda is transported there after being attacked by Ganon during the beginning of Tears of the Kingdom, she, like us, will be learning as we go. Still, some new faces have joined the fight, including a traveling talking Korok named Calamo and a transforming Zonai called the Mysterious Construct.</p>



<p>As it takes place during the battle between Rauru and Ganon, we see fresh faces not shown in Tears of the Kingdom. There is a lot of room for the narrative to go, so fans will be in for a big treat. Even still, Koei Tecmo, it’s developing team, have been on a roll recently with Dynasty Warriors: Origins and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-world-record-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden 4</a>. Seeing as Hyrule Warriors: Age of Calamity was great, Age of Imprisonment looks to be just as good, if not better.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment? Have you played any of the series? Have a favorite one? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Zelda news, check out our articles on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/link-and-zelda-actors-confirmed-nintendo-legend-of-zelda/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Legend of Zelda film</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-announces-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-for-september-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LEGO sets</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>, as well!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-new-trailer-nintendo-switch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Have Skill-Based Matchmaking? BLOPS 7 SBMM, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-skill-based-matchmaking-sbmm/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-have-skill-based-matchmaking-blops-7-sbmm-explained.1334311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Black Ops 7 SBMM conversation has dominated the lead-up to the game’s launch, so let’s see if Activision has finally pulled back on skill-based matchmaking.</p>



<p>If you’re in the gaming circle and you’ve never heard the term ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Skill-based matchmaking</a>,’ you’re a lucky cat. The FPS community can’t go a week without bringing up SBMM. The more people learn about it, the more it becomes talked about, and the more mainstream it becomes, the more of an issue it becomes in shooters.</p>



<p>With Black Ops 7 needing a big push to match <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6</a> this year, a lack of SBMM could be the key.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-sbmm-in-black-ops-7">Is SBMM In Black Ops 7?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Breakthrough. Credit to Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is finally doing away with skill-based matchmaking, as the default matchmaking system will no longer just take into account a player’s skill level when forming lobbies.</strong></p>



<p>There it is. The one thing the CoD community has been crying out for over the last few years. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-have-non-disbanding-lobbies-at-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 7 will use ‘Open Matchmaking’</a> to create online multiplayer lobbies. On paper, this is going to be the most open and lottery-esque Call of Duty multiplayer title in years.</p>



<p>Here’s the official statement from Call of Duty:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We can confirm that Open Matchmaking with minimal skill consideration will be the default for Black Ops 7 Multiplayer. Additionally, to help keep players together from match to match more often, persistent lobbies will be coming to Black Ops 7 at launch on November 14.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The persistent lobbies change is also a welcome addition for many. Activision is seemingly throwing two Hail Marys to win over players and ensure it reigns supreme in the FPS war for the next year.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-does-skill-based-matchmaking-do-in-call-of-duty">What Does Skill-Based Matchmaking Do In Call of Duty?</h2>



<p><strong>Skill-based matchmaking is an algorithm that uses player data to determine matchmaking factors ahead of everything else in Call of Duty and other leading multiplayer titles with SBMM.</strong></p>



<p>Let’s simplify this: In Black Ops 6, the lobbies you were put into were predominantly determined by how the game adjudged your individual skill level. Let’s say that your combined K/D and W/L for the last 10 matches have been decent, and the game has given you a skill rating of 1.25 (for argument’s sake), Black Ops 6’s matchmaking would then try to put you in a lobby with other players that also have a 1.25 skill rating—give or take a few points.</p>



<p>If you have several bad games in a row, your skill rating could drop, and then you’re suddenly put in with players who (on average) are much worse than you. This means you should be able to dominate the lobby and be the MVP. But doing so would catapult your skill rating again and put you back with players on your level.</p>



<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 has followed in XDefiant’s path by removing SBMM by default. This means you’ll spend the full year being put into lobbies with players of all skill levels, with an emphasis likely on regional proximity over player similarity.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The Call of Duty community is unmatched, and we thank you for joining us in the Black Ops 7 Beta over the last week. This Beta has provided Treyarch the opportunity to try new things and rapidly test and implement player feedback. </p><p>Building on this feedback, we can confirm that… <a href="https://t.co/BKDWLCtoR2">pic.twitter.com/BKDWLCtoR2</a></p></div>— Call of Duty (@CallofDuty) <a href="https://twitter.com/CallofDuty/status/1976285658672136344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>You’ve all wanted it, so now you can’t complain this year! Black Ops 7 has officially gone rogue, and all bets are off where matchmaking is concerned. Are you one of the many who wanted SBMM to be removed? Let us know through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming Discord</a>. Tell us if you think this could single-handedly make this the best Call of Duty in a long time.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out if <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Has Early Access</a> and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-season-one-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season One Roadmap</a> for more answers and guides.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-skill-based-matchmaking-sbmm/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Will Not Mandate the Use of AI, Confirms Phil Spencer]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-will-not-mandate-the-use-of-ai-confirms-phil-spencer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-will-not-mandate-the-use-of-ai-confirms-phil-spencer.1334269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Phil Spencer has revealed that there is no top-down mandate to use AI for Xbox.</p>



<p>Some new details about Xbox have surfaced recently through an interview with the president, Sarah Bond. Bond recently stated that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-president-says-console-exclusives-are-antiquated/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">idea of exclusive games is now antiquated</a>. She also confirmed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-president-confirms-series-x-s-successors-are-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Series X/S successors</a> are in development. Now, a new interview with Phil Spencer talks about Xbox’s approach to AI. </p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-lets-creative-teams-choose-whether-they-want-to-use-ai">Xbox Lets Creative Teams Choose Whether They Want to Use AI</h2>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://in.ign.com/xbox-series-s/245018/news/xbox-boss-phil-spencer-on-ai-use-much-more-operational-than-it-is-in-the-creative-space" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IGN</a>, during a panel at the Paley International Council Summit in Palo Alto, California (moderated by Double Fine Studio Head Tim Schafer), Phil Spencer spoke about the use of AI at Xbox. Spencer first spoke about how most use is focused on the “security and protection” of their networks. He added that the scale has grown so much that people alone cannot ensure safety. </p>



<p>Which is why they use AI to keep a check on the conversation and topics, protect child accounts, see who gets to talk to those people, and whether the account is locked down by parents or guardians who are setting those controls. </p>



<p>On the creative side of things at Xbox, AI use is left to the teams. Spencer explains that he has&nbsp;“found that creative teams will use tools that make their job easier when it makes their job easier, and any top-down mandate that ‘Thou must use a certain tool’…is not really a path to success.” The process is to make tools available for the teams and let things “organically percolate”. </p>



<p>In other news, Fallout 76’s Xbox <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-upgrade-coming-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Series X/S upgrade</a> will arrive in 2026. Additionally, Microsoft wants Xbox to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-xbox-profit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">achieve a 30% profit margin</a>, well above the industry standard. What are your thoughts on Xbox not mandating AI usage? Let us know through the official&nbsp;Insider Gaming&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/dLOFaEGOMl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-could-potentially-come-to-the-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Baldur’s Gate 3 potentially coming to the Switch 2</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-will-not-mandate-the-use-of-ai-confirms-phil-spencer/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Could Potentially Come to the Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-could-potentially-come-to-the-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-could-potentially-come-to-the-switch-2.1334266/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It seems that 2023’s Game of the Year, Baldur’s Gate 3, could make its way to the Nintendo Switch 2. </p>



<p>The Switch 2 is set to receive a whole bunch of new titles in the coming days, with Metroid Prime 4 and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-nintendo-switch-2-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows </a>arriving in December 2025, followed by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-4-nintendo-switch-2-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fallout 4 anniversary edition in 2026</a>. It seems that the next title Nintendo could be looking to add to its third-party collection is Larian Studios’ critically acclaimed hit. </p>



<h2 id="h-baldur-s-gate-3-could-be-a-great-third-party-addition-for-the-switch-2">Baldur’s Gate 3 Could be a Great Third-Party Addition for the Switch 2</h2>



<p>The talk about Baldur’s Gate 3 coming to the Switch 2 originates from NateTheHate’s recent reply on <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1980357667035181154" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter). In one of his recent replies, the insider was asked whether he had any updates for Red Dead Redemption 2’s launch for the platform. To which he replied, stating he doesn’t have anything new on RDR2, but he has “heard something on BG3 for SW2”. However, he needs “more verification” before he can share anything. In a later reply, Nate stated that he will update on this topic soon. </p>



<p>Baldur’s Gate 3 is a solid choice for Nintendo Switch 2 as it’s one of the most decorated titles out there. In April 2024, the title became the first game to win Game of the Year at all five major award ceremonies, including the Golden Joystick Awards, the Game Developers’ Choice Awards, the DICE Awards, the BAFTAs, and The Game Awards. The game has also received a lot of post-launch love from the developers, including loads of new content and enhancements to improve the gameplay experience. </p>



<p>In other news, Metroid Prime 4 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-gameplay-new-unlisted-ads/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gameplay has surfaced</a> through unlisted Switch 2 ads. Additionally, here is what Baldur’s Gate 3’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-publishing-lead-comments-on-nintendos-new-character-summons-patent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">publishing lead</a> has to say about Nintendo’s character summons patent. What are your thoughts on Baldur’s Gate 3 coming to Switch 2? Let us know through the official&nbsp;Insider Gaming&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/dLOFaEGOMl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-is-battlefield-6s-new-battle-royale-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6’s battle royale mode being called Battlefield: RedSec</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-could-potentially-come-to-the-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 Dates, Location, and Information]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/copenhagen-gaming-week-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/copenhagen-gaming-week-2026-dates-location-and-information.1334218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 is one of the smaller international gaming events, attracting tens of thousands of attendees to the Bella Center in Copenhagen, Denmark. Described as “fun for the whole family”, it’s an event that you don’t want to miss if you’re local to the area or visiting Denmark around the same time it’s running.</p>



<p>In this quick guide, we’ll be telling you everything you need to know about Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-copenhagen-gaming-week-2026-dates">Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 Dates</h2>



<p>The dates for Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 have been confirmed to take place from <strong>February 12th to February 14th, 2026</strong>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-copenhagen-gaming-week-2026-location">Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 Location</h2>



<p>Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 will be held at the Bella Center in Copenhagen, Denmark. The full address for Bella Center Copenhagen is&nbsp;Center Boulevard 5, 2300 Copenhagen S, Denmark.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The closest airport to Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 at the Bella Center is Copenhagen Airport (CPH), which is a ten-minute taxi ride to the venue. Hotels, restaurants, bars, and other activities are all located fairly close to the event, but be quick, hotel accommodations closest to the event usually fill up fast.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-can-i-get-copenhagen-gaming-week-2026-tickets">When Can I Get Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 Tickets?</h2>



<p>Tickets for Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 can be found on the <a href="https://www.ticketmaster.dk/event/copenhagen-gaming-week-fredagsbillet-tickets/20434206?language=en-us" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ticketmaster Danmark here</a>, or alternatively on <a href="https://www.stubhub.com/copenhagen-gaming-week-tickets/grouping/150165484/copenhagen-city/1605" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Stubhub here</a>. At the time of writing, tickets are currently not available, but make sure you double-check the links above as they may have since gone live.</p>



<div><p>Overall, Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026 is an excellent event for all of the family with plenty of video games, technology, and more to check out. The official event description for the event reads,</p><p>“Enter a world where games, sports, play, and technology meet, and experience this year’s festival for the whole family. Copenhagen Gaming Week is more than gaming – it’s a celebration of community and the joy of playing, whether you’re into esports, trading cards, football, or board games. Here you can experience the latest technologies, explore digital trends and be inspired by talks and debates that focus on gaming and culture.”</p></div>



<p>Will you be going to Copenhagen Gaming Week 2026? If you found this guide helpful, you can find all the other games industry events for 2026 on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/calendar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming calendar</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/copenhagen-gaming-week-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield: RedSec Is Battlefield 6’s New Battle Royale Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-is-battlefield-6s-new-battle-royale-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-redsec-is-battlefield-6%E2%80%99s-new-battle-royale-mode.1334191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A fresh story has revealed that Battlefield: RedSec is the name for the rebranded battle royale game mode coming in Battlefield 6. ‘Firestorm’ is now a thing of the past, and BF 6 is gearing up for its strongly rumored October 28 battle royale shadow drop.</p>



<p>We’ve known for weeks that Battlefield 6 is getting a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-free-to-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battle Royale</a> mode. It features an innovative insta-death circle mechanic, and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-datamine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">datamine revealed that the Battle Royale is to release on October 28</a>. Now, we’ve learned the new game mode’s full title. </p>



<h2 id="h-battlefield-redsec-is-the-name-of-battlefield-6-battle-royale">Battlefield: RedSec Is The Name Of Battlefield 6 Battle Royale</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It will be war. Credit to EA</figcaption></figure>



<p>Get ready to enter Battlefield: RedSec! </p>



<p>Thanks to <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ModernWarzone</a>‘s exclusive story, we’ve learned that this is the new name for EA’s rebranded, free-to-play battle royale mode in Battlefield 6.</p>



<p>Here’s what they’ve said about the news:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“EXCLUSIVE: The F2P Battlefield 6 battle royale is officially named “Battlefield: RedSec”. Releasing October 28th as previously reported, however, it looks like there won’t be any trailers or official announcements until the 28th itself, instead of a day before. Full on shadowdrop.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This doesn’t alter the gameplay in any way, but it is a cool name. It’s unclear if this is a way to get clear of Firestorm and start anew, or if Battlefield Studios is simply looking for a fresh relaunch.</p>



<p>Either way, the shadow drop is looking less like a shadow drop and more like a surprise birthday party where everyone knows it’s happening. Still, EA will be looking to right the wrongs of Firestorm and hope Battlefield: RedSec is the start of something special.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>EXCLUSIVE: The F2P Battlefield 6 battle royale is officially named “Battlefield: RedSec”.</p><p>Releasing October 28th as previously reported, however it looks like there won’t be any trailers or official announcements until the 28th itself instead of a day before.</p><p>Full on shadowdrop <a href="https://t.co/blP6NQR3jW">pic.twitter.com/blP6NQR3jW</a></p></div>— ModernWarzone (@ModernWarzone) <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone/status/1981741907387523203?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 24, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>So, what do you think of the new name? Is it in keeping with the military aspect of the Battlefield brand? More importantly, is it an improvement over Firestorm? Let us know your thoughts and more through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a> and the comments section below.</p>



<hr>



<p>Don’t stop here with your hot gaming news. Insider Gaming has more stories, such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-season-1-patch-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 Season 1 Patch Notes, Which Include Changes to Progression, Visibility, and Weapons</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-redsec-is-battlefield-6s-new-battle-royale-mode/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>