<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:07:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2 Console Delay Is Due To Hardware Limitations, Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations-developer-says.1044975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you have been waiting to play Cities: Skylines 2 until it launches on console, you’re going to be waiting a bit longer. In an update <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/949230/view/4486243201365051600" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">released on Steam</a>, the game’s developer Colossal Order says that it still doesn’t have an update on a release date for the console version of the game on Xbox Series and PlayStation 5. </p>



<p>In its latest message to players, the developer says that while the game’s console release continues to be a “top priority”, its delay continues to be due to “hardware limitations” of the consoles themselves.</p>



<p>“Currently, we are experiencing both simulation issues (CPU) and graphics issues (GPU) which become noticeable when players take certain actions that cause frame rate drops or memory overload,” they said. “These issues are particularly challenging due to the hardware limitations of consoles.”</p>



<p>They then continued with an example of one issue consoles pose, saying, “When placing larger buildings that involve numerous entities, the system struggles to handle the data load. During the calculation process (e.g., checking if there’s enough space or if any entities overlap with existing assets), performance bottlenecks arise, resulting in these noticeable issues.”</p>



<p>The studio says they’ve gotten the game to a “playable state” by lowering the overall graphics quality “significantly”, but it brings it to a level of compromise that they “are not willing to make”.</p>



<p>“Once we get it to an acceptable level, further optimizations are needed for both simulation and memory usage before we are ready to share the console version,” they said. “Until they are resolved, we cannot provide a release estimate to avoid it being premature and potentially misleading. The console release remains a top priority for us, we have multiple solutions being explored with experts actively involved, and we’re working hard to bring you the console version of Cities: Skylines II.”</p>



<p>Cities: Skylines 2 was originally supposed to release on console alongside the game’s PC release over a year ago. Instead, it has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-release-delayed-pc-still-on-target/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">been met with multiple delays</a>.</p>



<p>When do you think we’ll see Cities: Skylines 2 released for console? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft being sued over its recent return to office</a> mandate. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Endgame Activities in Early Access Promise Hundreds of Hours of Play]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access-promise-hundreds-of-hours-of-play.1044900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The true testament to an ARPG’s longevity is always in the endgame. While the campaign is an excellent appetizer, it’s often only meant to introduce the world, mechanics, and gameplay to new players. Once you complete the story mode, the game opens up. Thankfully, you don’t have to fret because Path of Exile 2 endgame activities offer hundreds of hours of playtime. It’s a lot to take in!</p>



<h2 id="h-exploring-the-endgame-in-path-of-exile-2">Exploring the Endgame in Path of Exile 2</h2>



<p>Once you finish the multi-act campaign in Path of Exile 2, the game opens up with various endgame activities. You can explore unique biomes, uncover robust crafting mechanics, challenge optional bosses, and run mysterious dungeons with varying difficulty levels, challenges, and rewards. </p>



<figure><figcaption>Image via Grinding Gear Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>The game’s endgame includes Trial of the Sekhemas, The Trial of Chaos, Breach, Expedition, Ritual, Delirium, and the Pinnacle Threats.</p>



<h3 id="h-trial-of-the-sekhemas">Trial of the Sekhemas</h3>



<p>If you intend to evolve your class with one of the many available Ascendencies, you must run The Trial of Sekhemas—a challenging gauntlet that tests your resolve. It features rogue-like mechanics, with every room posing a unique trial, and every floor offers a potent boss fight at the end. The rewards will help you push to new heights, though.</p>



<h3 id="h-the-trial-of-chaos">The Trial of Chaos</h3>



<p>Throughout the Vaal Jungle, you’ll uncover the Temple of Chaos, another test that allows you to unlock class Ascendencies. To gain access, you require a token from the Trialmaster. From there, every room within the ordeal poses a hazard to your health, and you can go double or nothing on rewards.</p>



<h3 id="h-breach">Breach</h3>



<p>An endgame Breach is a portal from another dimension in which demons and monsters await. Upon entering a Breach, you will bridge the worlds and enter the opposing realm, slaying demons to keep the Breach open while unlocking XP and rewards for killing mobs.</p>



<h3 id="h-expedition">Expedition</h3>



<p>Expeditions task you with uncovering rare artifacts dug up using explosives. But the site isn’t clear of enemies, which means you’ll utilize your class abilities to punish corpses and put down monsters before reclaiming artifacts from the area. The more you uncover, the more mobs you draw to the dig site. </p>







<h3 id="h-ritual">Ritual</h3>



<p>Scattered across Wraeclast, you’ll discover Ritual Altars built by the King in the Mists. These altars require a tribute in the form of monster kills, which feed the ritual site and resurrect the King in the Mists’ dark forces. You’ll squash everything in sight for mighty rewards.</p>



<h3 id="h-delirium">Delirium</h3>



<p>Endgame maps in Path of Exile 2 may occasionally succumb to Delirium, in which a mysterious entity reworks the zone, creating a nightmarish landscape. The longer you remain in the Delirium, the greater the rewards, but the more powerful the enemies you face with every passing minute.</p>



<h3 id="h-pinnacle-threats">Pinnacle Threats</h3>



<p>As you explore the various areas in PoE2, you’ll encounter a Fortress of flame and ash, with a maze full of mystery, danger, and potential rewards. If you’re willing to venture into Pinnacle Threats, you’ll be rewarded for your efforts, but the challenge is not without perils that could end your adventure.</p>



<p>Which endgame mode are you most excited to play? Let us know over at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Before you run off excitedly, don’t forget to check out everything included in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heres-whats-inside-each-of-the-path-of-exile-2-supporter-packs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Path of Exile 2 Supporter Packs on Steam</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Sued Over Return To Office Mandate]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate.1044897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-70269">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>As if things couldn’t get more interesting for Ubisoft, the company now finds itself with a lawsuit on its hands. Unions at Ubisoft Barcelona have sued the French publisher over its recent return to office mandates.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-ubisoft-barcelona-unions-file-lawsuit-against-return-to-office-mandate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesIndustry.biz</a> (GIBiz), the unions — for both AAA and mobile teams —  are demanding Ubisoft ensure protections for remote work and walk back the recent policy changes. </p>







<p>The changes that were announced back in September mandated that all Ubisoft employees work in office <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-mandating-3-days-in-office-for-all-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at least three days per week</a>. At the time, Ubisoft said these changes were being done to “enhance creativity and teamwork”. Under the old remote work policy, employees were able to chose up to 60% of days to be worked remotely. On top of that, there were also fully-remote workers on staff. The new mandate was to be followed by all employees, even t hose with prior full-time remote agreements.</p>



<p>According to the unions via GIBiz, the change by Ubisoft was done “suddenly and without transparency”. It would also “create logistical problems as offices aren’t prepared to accommodate all remote workers at once.”</p>



<p>It was added that both parties were ready for negotiations. However, Ubisoft management hadn’t submitted a proposal before the lawsuit was filed on October 14.</p>



<p>Ubisoft has yet to comment on the lawsuit.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft being sued by union employees over their return to office mandate? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our full&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-review-heart-of-chornobyl/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review of STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">Conor McGregor’s Hitman Partnership Cut After Sexual Assault Verdict</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Conor McGregor’s character has been eliminated from Hitman: World of Assassination following his guilty sexual assault verdict.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">Troy Baker ‘Will Return’ For Naughty Dog’s Next Project</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been reported that Troy Baker WILL return to Naughty Dog to work with Neil Druckmann once again. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">Latest Windows Update Stops Ubisoft Games from Working</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The new Windows 11 24H2 update is causing issues while playing certain Ubisoft games. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>