<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:54:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resistance 4 Was Pitched By Insomniac, But PlayStation Turned It Down]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down.1103643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Insomniac Games wanted to develop Resistance 4, but PlayStation turned it down. That’s according to soon-to-be president of Insomniac Games Ted Price.</p>



<p>In a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/ZWKbHKCUkpw?t=1311s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kinda Funny Games</a>, Price was asked about a favorite game of his that was pitched but never greenlit.</p>



<p>“Yeah, I’ll share one,” Price said after a brief pause. “Resistance 4.”</p>



<p>He continued: “We did pitch that one and it was a wonderful concept, and, it just, in terms of timing and market opportunity, didn’t work out. But it was the result of a lot of Insomniac  team members being passionate about extending the story further because I do believe that Resistance has set up a really cool alternate history base where anything can happen with the Chimera and where they go and what their origins are.”</p>



<p>Price said that they spent a lot of time working on backstory and brainstorming on where the series could go in the future.</p>



<p>“Personally, I love this franchise,” he said.  “I was fortunate enough to be creative director on the first two Resistances. And I will remember many, many moments—good and bad—when it comes to development that taught us all a lot about how we can elevate ourselves under some pretty difficult situations.”</p>



<p>Resistance, which first debuted with 2006’s Resistance: Fall of Man, hasn’t seen a mainline game since 2011’s Resistance 3. Price said that there’s no answer to the question of if the studio will ever develop another Resistance game, but it’s something he hopes will happen in the future.</p>



<p>What do you think of Price and Insomniac wanting to develop Resistance 4? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-plans-to-support-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Take-Two’s CEO had to say</a>&nbsp;about the Nintendo Switch 2 and check out what Balatro developer LocalThunk said about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-balatro-update-details-intentionally-being-kept-under-wraps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s next major update</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Balatro Update Details Intentionally Being Kept Under Wraps]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-balatro-update-details-intentionally-being-kept-under-wraps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-balatro-update-details-intentionally-being-kept-under-wraps.1103622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-balatro-update-details-intentionally-being-kept-under-wraps/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>There is going to be a major update coming to Balatro sometime in the future. What’s included in that update, however, is currently unknown, and that’s by design.</p>



<p>In a new interview with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-02-07/maker-of-smash-indie-hit-balatro-talks-about-what-s-next?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczODk1NTUwNCwiZXhwIjoxNzM5NTYwMzA0LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTUkJVTUxEV1gyUFMwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.vnpDPy2eO2srUo1cO71bFTutl-JvFojih-o2zs4niu4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier</a>, Balatro developer LocalThunk gave a small update on the next update he’s working on. </p>







<p>The update, which he calls a “1.1” update for the game will include new Jokers along with various other features. LocalThunk didn’t want to get into exactly what those features will be because of potential constraints that would put on him such as the ability to “pivot if something new doesn’t work.”</p>



<p>“I think it’s healthier for the game that I keep my cards close to my chest, then give you the best version of whatever this new content update is,” he said.</p>



<h6 id="h-listen-gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">LISTEN: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 Still On Track For 2025: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>Despite not wanting to give anything away, he did reveal two changes that will come with the update. The first is a change to the “blue stake” modifier while the second is a change to the Matador Joker—Earn $8 if played hand triggers the Boss Blind ability. As far as what those changes will involve, that wasn’t said. Details on that, along with everything else players can expect, will come closer to its release.</p>



<p>The update is expected to arrive sometime this year.</p>



<p>What are you hoping to see in the next Balatro update? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-plans-to-support-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Take-Two’s CEO had to say</a> about the Nintendo Switch 2 and check out what a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/patent-shows-nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-used-as-wireless-mouse/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recently discovered patent shows</a> for the Switch 2’s Joy-Con controllers. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VALORANT Star Derke Pulls Off Sensational Fake Yoru Clone Play]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-star-derke-pulls-off-sensational-fake-yoru-clone-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-star-derke-pulls-off-sensational-fake-yoru-clone-play.1103592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-star-derke-pulls-off-sensational-fake-yoru-clone-play/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a VALORANT match with massive qualifying implications, Vitality star Nikita “Derke” Sirmitev busted out the silliest play in the playbook. And somehow, the gamble worked, leaving his opponents embarrassed, and insuring a spot for his own team at the first Masters event of the year.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-derke-does-the-unthinkable">Derke Does The Unthinkable </h2>



<p>In the upper bracket final of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-esports-lands-sony-inzone-sponsorship-for-next-2-seasons-of-vct-emea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">VCT EMEA Kickoff</a>, Vitality and Team Heretics went haed-to-head for one of two spots at Masters Bangkok. To beat Heretics, a two-time grand finalist at international events in 2024, Vitality would need to play with the utmost confidence. </p>



<p>Derke, the former star of Fnatic who switched to Vitality this past offseason, certainly didn’t lack confidence when he caught Heretics off guard with the fake Yoru clone. Typically, when a Yoru player uses their Fakeout ability, they send a clone forward that will hit enemies that shoot it with a blinding flash. So normally, enemy players just ignore the clone walking completely straight forward. </p>



<figure><video controls="" src="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/20250207_CrackyStormyCrocodilePJSalt-cXdQVUEvEo_Sf8k7_source.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>Unfortunately for Heretics, it wasn’t Derke’s clone that walked onto the site, it was Derke pretending to be his clone. To make matters worse, Heretics’ Ričardas “Boo” Lukaševičius teleported right next to Derke before he turned, gifting him an additional kill. It’s a play that VALORANT fans have sometimes seen during streams and maybe in their own ranked games, but never on a pro stage as big as this one. The play also gifted Vitality a bonus round win, taking a third straight round to start Haven despite not completely buying. Vitality ended up winning Haven, and then owned Heretics’ own map pick of Abyss to claim the series, and the Masters spot, in dominant fashion.</p>



<p>Have you ever fallen victim to the Yoru fake clone play? Let us know what you think down below or in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out more of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest esports news</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Still On Track For 2025: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast.1103589/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Welcome everyone to Insider Gaming Weekly: A Video Game Podcast for February 7, 2025. In this week’s episode: MultiVersus is shutting down, Battlefield is cooking, and Grand Theft Auto 6 is still planned for this year.</p>



<p>Mike, Grant, and Albert also get the Bragging Rights trivia contest underway with…underwhelming results. And Tom Henderson joins as we bring the latest on Sony Santa Monica’s plans for the God of War franchise as well as talk about what we think and hope we’ll see at the next PlayStation State of Play event.</p>



<p>It’s Insider Gaming Weekly: A Video Game Podcast!</p>



<p>If you enjoy the show, please consider subscribing (links below) and leaving a rating and review. You can also submit questions for future shows and your feedback to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d1a1beb5b2b0a2a591b8bfa2b8b5b4a3fcb6b0bcb8bfb6ffb2bebc">⁠<span data-cfemail="b6c6d9d2d5d7c5c2f6dfd8c5dfd2d3c49bd1d7dbdfd8d198d5d9db">[email&nbsp;protected]</span>⁠</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-subscribe-to-insider-gaming-weekly-a-video-game-podcast">Subscribe To Insider Gaming Weekly: A Video Game Podcast</h2>



<p><strong>Spotify</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5ZUR0ceSgsypXkiCjCCNMa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://open.spotify.com/show/5ZUR0ceSgsypXkiCjCCNMa</a></p>



<p><strong>Apple Podcasts:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/insider-gaming-weekly-a-video-game-podcast/id1792334405" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/insider-gaming-weekly-a-video-game-podcast/id1792334405</a></p>



<p><strong>iHeartRadio:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/269-insider-gaming-weekly-a-vi-260791941/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://www.iheart.com/podcast/269-insider-gaming-weekly-a-vi-260791941/</a></p>



<p><strong>Amazon Music:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/af55ef9d-5255-4f72-a2a0-50bf333e8dc4/insider-gaming-weekly-a-video-game-podcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/af55ef9d-5255-4f72-a2a0-50bf333e8dc4/insider-gaming-weekly-a-video-game-podcast</a></p>



<p><strong>Pocket Casts: </strong><a href="https://pca.st/oem3367c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://pca.st/oem3367c</a></p>



<h2 id="h-about-the-show">About The Show</h2>



<p>Each and every Friday, Senior Editors Mike Straw and Grant Taylor-Hill alongside Senior Producer Albert Perkins bring you the latest in video game news, events, rumors and more.</p>



<p>From friendly debates to challenges for the audience and each other, you don’t want to miss a single thing from Insider Gaming Weekly. Even Insider Gaming Co-Founder Tom Henderson will stop by from time to time to talk the latest in gaming rumors that players need to know about.</p>



<p>Don’t forget to share the show and leave a rating to help us grow this new venture. You can also submit questions for future shows and your feedback to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ed9d82898e8c9e99ad84839e8489889fc08a8c8084838ac38e8280">⁠<span data-cfemail="fc8c93989f9d8f88bc95928f9598998ed19b9d9195929bd29f9391">[email&nbsp;protected]</span>⁠</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-join-the-discussion">Join the Discussion</h2>



<p>If you want to talk about the latest episode of the show with the hosts and staff, head on over to the Insider Gaming Forums where you can hangout with other gamers and listeners, and talk about everything from your favorite games and shows to even sharing your best in-game artwork. It’s all there <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at the Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering Film and TV Universe Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/magic-the-gathering-film-and-tv-universe-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-film-and-tv-universe-announced.1103496/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/magic-the-gathering-film-and-tv-universe-announced/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hasbro has partnered with Legendary Entertainment to create a Magic: The Gathering live-action film and TV universe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to a report by <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/02/magic-the-gathering-legendary-hasbro-film-tv-universe-1236280886/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Deadline</a> (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hasbro-announces-magic-the-gathering-film-and-tv-series-wants-it-to-be-the-next-cinematic-universe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>), Hasbro and Legendary Entertainment will first work on a Magic: The Gathering film, followed by a TV series and other content. Legendary Entertainment has extensive experience in adaptations, with movies like Dune, Detective Pikachu, and more under its belt. It is also currently working on several video game adaptations, such as the Minecraft movie and Street Fighter film.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zev Foreman, Hasbro Entertainment’s Head of Film, has called the partnership with Legendary Entertainment “exciting and complementary”. As the franchise has “inspired decades of epic world-building and creative storytelling”, Foreman believes that Magic the Gathering’s film and TV universe will be “a perfect match for Legendary’s diversified approach to marquee IP”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mary Parent, Legendary’s Chairman of Worldwide Production, stated that the company prides itself “on being thoughtful caretakers of singular, beloved IP”, and Hasbro’s highly popular trading card game matches that description. Hasbro and Legendary Entertainment wish to create a Magic: The Gathering “multimedia universe that thrills longstanding fans and creates a broad wave of new ones.”</p>



<p>Magic: The Gathering is the <a href="https://investor.hasbro.com/magic-gathering" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">world’s first trading card game</a>, released in 1993 by Wizards of the Coast. By February 2023, it had gathered a staggering 50 million players and generated more than $1 billion annually since 2022. Magic: The Gathering is known for being highly strategic and customisable in gameplay, which suits all types of players. The game has received decades of expansions and collaborations with franchises like Dungeons &amp; Dragons, Lord of the Rings, and more. A partnership with Final Fantasy is coming this year, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Take-Two Interactive reconfirmed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-fall-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 is launching in Fall 2025</a>. Also, Project Arc has been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pubg-blindspot-new-name-from-krafton/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">renamed to PUBG: Blindspot</a>. Will Magic: The Gathering film and TV universe become the new MCU?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prime-gaming-has-20-free-games-for-you-in-february-heres-what-they-are/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">20 free Prime Gaming titles for February 2025</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>