<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:34:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Winterfest 2025 Yule Trooper Boss Location—Where to Find & All Loot]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-winterfest-yule-trooper-location-drops/</link>
            <guid>1386898</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fresh content has arrived in Fortnite with a strong festive feel following the start of the Winterfest event, and Yule Trooper is the latest boss waiting to be found in Chapter 7 Season 1.</p>



<p>Winterfest 2025 kicked off on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-december-18-winterfest-2025-patch-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">December 18 with a new patch</a>, bringing map changes, new weapons, and a host of new content to the game, including a new boss to defeat and turn into.</p>



<p>If you’re on the hunt for Yule Trooper in Fortnite and want to know where he can be found and the rewards he drops, Insider Gaming has all the details.</p>







<h2 id="h-where-to-find-yule-trooper-in-fortnite-winterfest">Where to Find Yule Trooper in Fortnite Winterfest</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Start your hunt. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Similar to the other bosses in Fortnite Chapter 7, the Yule Trooper boss does not have a specific set spawn location. Instead, there are several points across the island where they can be found.</strong></p>



<p>When hunting the Yule Trooper, the best bet is to stick to the snow-covered landscapes in the north of the map, which is home to the majority of Yule Trooper’s spawn points.</p>



<p>Clawsy Lodge, a new location added in the Winterfest update, is a decent place to start hunting, as there’s a decent chance one of the bosses will spawn there. Additionally, it’s fairly close to other potential spawn locations, like Painted Palms, and there’s a large chunk of loot available to claim.</p>



<p>In general, stick to the north of the map and the snowy environments for the best chance of encountering Yule Trooper, though the lack of a guaranteed spawn location can make it tricky to get to him first.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-yule-trooper-drops-in-fortnite-winterfest">All Yule Trooper Drops in Fortnite Winterfest</h2>



<p><strong>Yule Trooper has an array of loot dropped when defeated, with the main reward being the item that allows you to transfer into the boss yourself.</strong></p>



<p>When transformed into Yule Trooper, the Jolly Sprint ability can be activated, which grants increased stamina and vitality. However, like the other boss transform items, the downside is you will be marked on the map for nearby enemies, though you will have additional health and Shields.</p>



<p>In terms of weapons, defeating Yule Trooper provides Yule Trooper’s Holo Rush SMG, a Mythic version of the weapon that can be found elsewhere on the map, and, like other bosses available this season, he also drops a Chug Jug when eliminated.</p>







<hr>



<p>What is your favorite addition to Fortnite in the Winterfest update? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-winterfest-2025-all-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all of the available free rewards during the event</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-og-crackshots-cabin-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to find Crackshot’s Cabin in Fortnite OG</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-winterfest-yule-trooper-location-drops/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Flickering Flames Project Guide—All Requirements & Rewards, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-flickering-flames-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/</link>
            <guid>1386895</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Cold Snap update for ARC Raiders has introduced a wave of new content, headlined by a brand-new Project called Flickering Flames. This limited-time Project is split into five distinct steps, each requiring you to track down and submit a specific set of items in order to progress.</p>



<p>Completing Flickering Flames isn’t just about lending a helping hand, either. There are some genuinely worthwhile rewards on offer for those willing to put the time in. That said, the challenge shouldn’t be underestimated—several of the item requirements are demanding, and gathering everything before the deadline will take careful planning and consistent raiding.</p>







<p>With the clock ticking, knowing exactly what to prioritise can make all the difference. Follow this guide to see every requirement and reward tied to the Flickering Flames <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/check-stash-value-arc-raiders-expedition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project in ARC Raiders</a>, along with how long you have left to complete it before the event comes to an end.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-complete-the-arc-raiders-flickering-flames-project">How To Complete The ARC Raiders Flickering Flames Project</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Stage 2 of the Project. Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There are five stages to the Flickering Flames Project in ARC Raiders, with each one having four requirements to fulfil.</strong></p>



<p>None of the requirements at any stage is extensively rare or hard to come by—at least, none other than the Candleberries. In total, you’ll need 260 Candleberries across the five stages of the Project. These can be tricky to come by, but follow <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-to-find-candleberries-in-arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s Candleberries Guide</a> and you’ll be ready to blitz through the Flickering Flames Project in no time.</p>



<p>Here’s the full list for every stage of the Project, including the requirements as well as the rewards.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Project Stage</th><th data-align="center">Project Requirements</th><th data-align="center">Project Rewards</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 1: Candlelight</td><td data-align="center">– 1 Empty Wine Bottle<br>– 25 Plastic Parts<br>– 5 Durable Cloth<br>– 20 Candleberries</td><td data-align="center">– 5 Firecrackers<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 50 Raider Tokens</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 2: Decorations</td><td data-align="center">– 3 Candle Holders<br>– 3 Light Bulbs<br>– 1 Industrial Battery<br>– 50 Cnadleberries</td><td data-align="center">– 1 Red Light Stick Blueprint<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 50 Raider Tokens</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 3: Presents</td><td data-align="center">– 5 Snap Blast Grenades<br>– 10 Duct Tape<br>– 1 Film Reel<br>– 60 Candleberries</td><td data-align="center">– 3 Trailblazers<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 50 Raider Tokens</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 4: Beverages</td><td data-align="center">– 2 Coffee Pots<br>– 10 Fireball Burners<br>– 2 Water Filters<br>– 60 Candleberries</td><td data-align="center">– 1 Vita Spray<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 50 Raider Tokens</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 5: Meals</td><td data-align="center">– 7 Mushrooms<br>– 2 Frying Pans<br>– 2 Music Albums<br>– 70 Candleberries</td><td data-align="center">– 1 Snap Hook<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 1,000 Merits<br>– 50 Raider Tokens</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>There’s a high chance you’ve got some of these items lying around in your stash, so make sure you don’t recycle or sell them before you use them in the Project!</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-the-arc-raiders-flickering-flames-project-end">When Does The ARC Raiders Flickering Flames Project End?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It won’t be around forever. Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Flickering Flames Project for ARC Raiders expires on January 13, 2026. </strong></p>



<p>With the event launching on December 16, 2025, that leaves just under a month to make meaningful progress. While that may sound generous on paper, the reality is a bit more demanding. The Project requires a long list of specific upgrades and materials, many of which can only be obtained through consistent raiding and successful extractions.</p>







<p>If you’re aiming to complete the Flickering Flames Project in full, it’s best to start chipping away at the requirements as early as possible. Spreading your runs out over the course of the event not only reduces the grind but also gives you more flexibility to adapt if luck isn’t on your side during raids.</p>



<hr>



<p>How are you finding the Cold Snap update in ARC Raiders? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-find-guitars-shakers-in-arc-raiders-buried-city-easter-egg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how you can find the Legendary Guitars and Shakers</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-flickering-flames-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Is Generously Giving Players Lots Of Free Raider Tokens]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-is-generously-giving-players-lots-of-free-raider-tokens/</link>
            <guid>1386883</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>To celebrate the Holiday season, Embark Studios is giving all ARC Raiders players a lot of Raider Tokens to claim, allowing you to buy items usually reserved for those who spend real money.</p>



<p>ARC’s developer is giving you a chance to <em>raid </em>the item store for free! That’s right, the next time you log into <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-next-season-arc-raiders-new-raider-deck/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, you should have the opportunity to claim 1,000 Raider Tokens in Embark’s ARC Raiders.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-claim-free-raider-tokens-for-the-holidays-in-arc-raiders">How To Claim Free Raider Tokens For The Holidays In ARC Raiders</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Free? Yes, please. Credit to Embark Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>Simply open up ARC Raiders, check your emails, and claim 1000 free Raider Tokens to enjoy now and over the Christmas Holidays.</p>







<p>Check out the full instructions right here:</p>



<ol>
<li>Start up ARC Raiders.</li>



<li>Go to the main menu.</li>



<li>Press on the&nbsp;mail icon&nbsp;in the top-right corner of the screen.</li>



<li>Find and click on the <strong>Happy Holidays!</strong> email from the developer.</li>



<li>Click the&nbsp;<strong>claim</strong>.</li>



<li>This automatically adds 1000 Raider Tokens to your player profile.</li>
</ol>



<p>There’s no limit on how to spend the Tokens, so go and check to see if you can buy a cosmetic you’ve been eyeing up.</p>



<p>Even with the success of the game, this is a lovely surprise for all players. This is around $10 worth of Raider Tokens, and Embark doesn’t need to do this. If you continue to play and support the shooter, who knows, maybe the free gifts are only just beginning! After all, it was only recently that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-free-arc-raiders-red-ryder-skin-the-finals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free ARC Raiders Red Ryder Skin</a> was made available for the community.</p>



<p>What are you going to spend your free Raider Tokens on? Tell IG your favorite thing about the game through the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should also definitely check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-find-guitars-shakers-in-arc-raiders-buried-city-easter-egg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to find Guitars &amp; Shakers in ARC Raiders for the Buried City Easter Egg</a>. Furthermore, make sure you know the most efficient ways <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-to-find-candleberries-in-arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to find Candleberries</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-is-generously-giving-players-lots-of-free-raider-tokens/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Fortnite Winterfest 2025 Rewards & How to Get Them]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-winterfest-2025-all-rewards/</link>
            <guid>1386865</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The festive season is officially upon us with the release of Fortnite’s annual Winterfest celebration, which brings a host of new rewards, all available for free, during the event.</p>



<p>While a lot of the hype has been surrounding the exciting collabs Fortnite has on the horizon this holiday season, players are being spoiled with a heap of free rewards, including two brand-new skins to provide a fresh look.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has all the details on every Fortnite Winterfest reward in 2025 and how to get your hands on them all.</p>







<h2 id="h-all-fortnite-winter-2025-rewards">All Fortnite Winter 2025 Rewards</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Lots of goodies. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There are 16 total free rewards available in Fortnite during the Winterfest 2025 event, including Outfits, Jam Tracks, and more.</strong></p>



<p>14 of the rewards are distributed by opening presents daily in the cabin, with the final two rewards, both Outfits, becoming available when specific thresholds have been met during the event.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, if you were holding out hope for free collab skins with the likes of Harry Potter, Hatsune Miku, and Sabrina Carpenter, you’ll be disappointed, as they’re available in the Item Shop and not via Winterfest rewards.</p>



<p>The table below shows all of the Winterfest 2025 free rewards.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Name</th><th data-align="center">Type</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Cheeks</td><td data-align="center">Outfit</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Glacial Dummy</td><td data-align="center">Outfit</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winterfest Bow</td><td data-align="center">Back Bling</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Wrapped Axe</td><td data-align="center">Pickaxe</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Festive Bat</td><td data-align="center">Pickaxe</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Warm &amp; Peely</td><td data-align="center">Emote</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Just A Holiday in Battlewood</td><td data-align="center">Jam Track</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Festive Gwinny</td><td data-align="center">Back Bling</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Glacial Groove</td><td data-align="center">Instrument</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bard’s Gem</td><td data-align="center">Instrument</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winterfest Letter</td><td data-align="center">Glider</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Shadowstorm</td><td data-align="center">Contrail</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Fire-Born</td><td data-align="center">Emote</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">No Sweat, Snowfish</td><td data-align="center">Emote</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">A Snowman!</td><td data-align="center">Wrap</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winterfest Gift</td><td data-align="center">Emote</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-fortnite-2025-winterfest-rewards">How to Get Fortnite 2025 Winterfest Rewards</h2>



<p><strong>One Fortnite Winterfest reward</strong> <strong>can be claimed daily, with a refresh of 9 AM ET, starting at the beginning of the Winterfest event on December 18.</strong></p>



<p>Rewards can be selected in any order, so you can choose what you want to get first. However, you can’t jump straight to the new Outfits, as their distribution is slightly different.</p>



<p>The Glacial Dummy Outfit is unlocked after you open seven other presents, while the Cheeks Outfit is unlocked once 13 presents have been opened.</p>



<p>While you won’t specifically be shown what you’re about to unlock, the shape of the presents is a big giveaway, so use that to your advantage.</p>







<hr>



<p>What do you think of the Winterfest 2025 free rewards? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-og-crackshots-cabin-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to find Crackshot’s Cabin in Fortnite OG</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lightning-ink-lego-fortnite/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get Lightning Ink in LEGO Fortnite</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-winterfest-2025-all-rewards/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stardew Valley 1.7 Update Includes New Farm Type & ‘Lots More’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/first-stardew-valley-1-7-update-includes-new-farm-type-lots-more/</link>
            <guid>1386862</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Stardew Valley 1.7 update is still on the way, and while there’s still no approximate timeframe for the new content, the game’s developer has let the community in on certain features and aspects to expect.</p>



<p>Eric Barone’s—AKA ConcernedApe—solo creation of Stardew Valley needs to be studied. It’s unbelievable that one person made such a staggeringly big and timeless game. They could realistically walk away from the title at any point now. Instead, the game goes from strength to strength.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/among-us-collaboration-announced-with-stardew-valley/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Among Us collaboration with Stardew Valley</a> was one thing, but the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stardew-valley-1-7-update-coming-confirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1.7 update</a> is huge.</p>











<figure><figcaption>Still more to come. Credit to ConcernedApe</figcaption></figure>



<p>The 2017 life-sim title is readying itself for the upcoming 1.7 update. ConcernedApe remains coy on a release date or launch window, but when asked if the dev could “Give any hints about the newest update that we could look forward to or a sneak peek?” Concerned Ape obliged:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“There will be some more character/social stuff, it’s also traditional to add a new farm type. Lots more but I don’t want to reveal much yet.”<a href="https://x.com/ConcernedApe/status/2001186320765583409"></a></p>
</blockquote>



<p>It means we need to wait longer for more details on the 1.7 update, and the content is presumably a while away yet. It’s all the more impressive when you consider the developer is also working simultaneously on a new game—Haunted Chocolatier.</p>







<p>Speculation continues to run rife over whether this will be the final, major Stardew Valley update. Many were shocked when 1.7 was announced, and every subsequent update will raise the same question.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">there will be some more character/social stuff, it's also traditional to add a new farm type. Lots more but I don't want to reveal much yet</p>— ConcernedApe (@ConcernedApe) <a href="https://twitter.com/ConcernedApe/status/2001186320765583409?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 17, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>What do you hope to see from the Stardew Valley 1.7 update? Do you think this could be Concenred Ape’s Stardew Valley swansong before moving onto pastures new? Share your thoughts and wishlist ideas through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bethesda-todd-howard-confirmed-fallout-5-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first Fallout 5 details being confirmed by Bethesda’s Todd Howard</a>, and a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-crossover-announced-for-black-ops-7-season-1-reloaded/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fallout crossover being announced for Black Ops 7 Season 1 Reloaded</a>, for more gaming news.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/first-stardew-valley-1-7-update-includes-new-farm-type-lots-more/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite December 18 Update & Winterfest 2025 Patch Notes—All New Content, Map Changes & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-december-18-winterfest-2025-patch-notes/</link>
            <guid>1386838</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s the most wonderful time of the year, with Fortnite officially kicking off the Winterfest 2025 celebrations with a new update on December 18, bringing a host of additions in the patch notes.</p>



<p>The annual Fortnite celebration brings new collabs, free rewards, new weapons, and map changes, along with plenty of other tweakls, and Insider Gaming has a full breakdown of all the biggest changes.</p>







<h2 id="h-fortnite-december-18-update-winterfest-2025-patch-notes">Fortnite December 18 Update Winterfest 2025 Patch Notes</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Freebies. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>We’ve broken down all the major changes to Fortnite with the December 18 update, which marks the start of Winterfest 2025 and is the final patch of the year, into sections below.</p>



<h3 id="h-winterfest-2025-rewards">Winterfest 2025 Rewards</h3>



<p>Fortnite’s annual celebration around the festive season has begun, with free rewards available to claim as a result, including Skins, Emotes, and more.</p>



<p>A total of 14 rewards are available to claim, along with two skins once you have claimed seven and 13 rewards. One gift can be opened daily, with a refresh at 9 AM ET.</p>



<h3 id="h-shop-collabs">Shop Collabs</h3>



<p>A host of big collabs are available in the shop during Winterfest, including festive-themed skins for Sabrina Carpenter and Hatsune Miku, but the big addition is the Harry Potter franchise, with customizable skins for your favorite Hogwarts house.</p>



<p>There’s even more on the horizon, too, with Sidekicks coming for SpongeBob SquarePants and Patrick Star, while Batman Beyond is also poised to appear.</p>



<h3 id="h-map-changes">Map Changes</h3>



<p>The main Battle Royale island has seen some changes with the update, with snow spreading around the northern section of the map.</p>



<p>Areas modified for Winterfest 2025 include Wonkeeland, Tiptop Terrace, Latte Landing, and Painted Palms, with fresh secrets to uncover as you fight for victory.</p>



<h3 id="h-bleach-collab">Bleach Collab</h3>



<p>Winterfest 2025 has a bunch of returning collabs, including new skins for the likes of Sabrina Carpenter and Hatsune Miku, but there’s also a brand-new collab landing in the Item Shop, along with in-game content.</p>



<p>Bleach is the latest major anime to receive a collab in Fortnite for 2025, following on from the likes of Kaiju No. 9, Cowboy Bebop, and One Punch Man.</p>



<p>Alongside items to purchase in the Item Shop, two new Mythic weapons will be available at an undetermined date: the Fully-Hollowfied Ichigo Mask and Dual Zangetsu.</p>



<h2 id="h-festive-weapons">Festive Weapons</h2>



<p>Two festive weapons have been added to rotation in the Winterfest 2025 update, with Blizzard Grenades and Snowball launchers available for players.</p>



<p>It’s not clear yet whether there is any specific method to obtaining the weapons, or whether they are random loot from chests and the ground.</p>







<hr>



<p>What is your favorite part about the Fortnite Winterfest 2025 update? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-og-crackshots-cabin-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to find Crackshot’s Cabin in Fortnite OG</a>, and check out details of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-announces-2-5m-reload-elite-series-with-finals-at-esports-world-cup/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$2.5m Reload Elite Series</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-december-18-winterfest-2025-patch-notes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>