<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[COD SBMM Creator Debunks Black Ops 7 Conspiracy Theories]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-sbmm-cod-creator-debunk-conspiracies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-sbmm-creator-debunks-black-ops-7-conspiracy-theories.1364176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty’s Skill-Based Matchmaking model (SBMM) has long been the source of <strong>much debate </strong>and contention in the wider industry. It’s believed that these days, Activision’s studios want to punish you for being good at your game while trying to shoehorn players into matches with those closest to their current performance metrics, which makes things ‘sweatier’ for almost everyone on a streak.</p>



<p>It’s why people feel that a single good game in Call of Duty leads to you being ‘punished’ by SBMM. In a recent video, Charlie Olson, one of the original creators of the Call of Duty SBMM algorithms as we know them, took a dive into these very topics and debunked some of the SBMM-related conspiracy theories circulating Black Ops 7.</p>



<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-sbmm-is-all-over-the-place">Black Ops 7 SBMM is All Over The Place</h2>



<p>In a new video shared by Charlie Olson of Invokation, the ‘Dark Art of SBMM’ was explored. Olson is credited with creating the current (or close to) <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SBMM model for Call of Duty</a> during a ten-year stint at Raven Software. He left a few years back to focus on his own company, but has remained in the realms of SBMM, MMR, and multiplayer gaming.</p>



<p>In the 40-minute video, Olson runs through the technical know-how behind MMR and SBMM, explaining why the systems are viewed both positively and negatively by the wider gaming community, even <strong>beyond </strong>Call of Duty.</p>



<p>Here’s the full walkthrough:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Dark Art of SBMM" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NpCmr8a9uuE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Towards the end of his run-through of all things matchmaking, Charlie Olson addressed some of the ‘conspiracy theories’ that have surfaced in Call of Duty since Black Ops 7 was released midway through November.</p>



<p>On October 9, Treyarch posted on social media that ‘open matchmaking’ was confirmed to be coming to Black Ops 7, prompting many to fear that the game would be a casual crapfest. This is what Olson addressed first:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Some players are leaving because they thought this tweet meant SBMM had been completely removed from the game, and then they felt betrayed by the inclusion of one standard matchmaking playlist, and then blamed it for stealing ‘fodder’ from the open playlist.</p>



<p>What’s really going on here is there aren’t enough casual players at launch to make open matchmaking the pubstomp that was expected or promise. If open lobbies are sweaty, it’s because it’s mostly sweats playing.</p>



<p>Open matchmaking really does have minimal skill consideration and you can be sure that standard matchmaking isn’t pulling too many players yet, because most casual players just want the one or two modes they’re most comfortable with.</p>



<p>If you’re looking for noobs to stomp, my advice would be to try the open TDM playlist, that’s probably the best place to look.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He then jumped into the outright conspiracy theories surrounding SBMM in Black Ops 7. This core conspiracy theory suggests that Activision’s studios <strong>LIED </strong>about removing SBMM in open matchmaking.</p>



<p>Olson suggested that the evidence people are using to back up this theory is to be expected:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>This usually comes with three pieces of ‘evidence’. One, open lobbies are sweaty. Two, wait times are longer than in the beta. Three, connections are worse than in the beta.</p>



<p>But those are <strong>just trade-offs from bringing back persistent lobbies</strong> for launch, assuming they don’t want low-pop playlists to starve.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Olson wrapped with predictions, suggesting that Black Ops 7 will ‘get sweatier’ and that the player count will mirror XDefiant’s performance before the game bombed out.</p>



<p>Do you believe the conspiracy theories surrounding Black OPs 7’s SBMM mechanics? Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/most-realistic-shooter-bodycam-update-even-more/">Bodycam has received a major update</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-sbmm-cod-creator-debunk-conspiracies/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 5 Is Up For A GOTY Award In 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-auto-5-is-up-for-a-goty-award-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-5-is-up-for-a-goty-award-in-2025.1364173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>GTA 5 can be nominated for the GOTY category in the Steam Awards 2025, thanks to the Enhanced Edition releasing this year. </p>



<p>Rockstar’s Grand Theft Auto 5 has been one of the most relevant titles in gaming for over a decade. The first iteration of the title was released for the PS3 and Xbox 360, with newer versions released with each successive generation of consoles and PCs. Now, the latest version of the game is up for the Game of the Year award on Steam. </p>







<h2 id="h-you-can-nominate-gta-5-for-goty-for-steam-awards-2025">You Can Nominate GTA 5 for GOTY for Steam Awards 2025</h2>



<p>The nomination window for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/steamawards/nominations/2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Steam Awards</a> is now open and will be live until December 1, 2025, 10:00 AM Pacific. During this time, players will be able to nominate games across 11 categories, including Game of the Year, VR Game of the Year, Labor of Love, Best Game on Steam Deck, Better With Friends, Outstanding Visual Style, Most Innovative Gameplay Award, Best Game You Suck At,  Best Soundtrack Award, Outstanding Story-Rich Game, and Sit Back and Relax. Winners will be announced on January 3, 2026, at 10:00 AM Pacific. </p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://gameranx.com/updates/id/557864/article/apparently-grand-theft-auto-v-is-eligible-for-steams-goty-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gameranx</a>, players have the option to nominate GTA 5 for GOTY in the first category. For those who don’t know, Steam Awards work differently from other award shows. Instead of a panel of judges deciding the nominations, Steam Awards selects nominees solely through player votes. Which means, theoretically, if players vote to nominate GTA 5 for GOTY and it receives the most votes again once the nomination period is over, it can win GOTY. The only reason it is eligible for this award is that GTA 5 Enhanced Edition was released on Steam on March 4, 2025.  </p>







<p>In other news, GTA Online <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-online-fivem-mods-can-now-be-converted-for-enhanced-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FiveM mods can now be converted</a> for the Enhanced Edition thanks to a new tool. Additionally, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/leaked-discord-messages-reveal-why-rockstar-fired-34-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked Discord messages</a> reveal why Rockstar fired 34 employees. Will you be nominating GTA 5 for GOTY at The Steam Awards? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-to-officially-relaunch-in-2025-after-beta-ends/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Splitgate 2 relaunching in 2025 with beta ending soon</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-auto-5-is-up-for-a-goty-award-in-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Rockstar Co-Founder Says Using AI For Gaming Isn’t “That Useful”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/former-rockstar-co-founder-says-using-ai-for-gaming-isnt-that-useful/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-rockstar-co-founder-says-using-ai-for-gaming-isn%E2%80%99t-%E2%80%9Cthat-useful%E2%80%9D.1364131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Dan Houser has been on a media cycle to promote his new book. Obviously, gaming questions and quandaries are being thrown his way, and the Rockstar Games co-founder has opened up on AI usage in gaming, how he’s using it for his new game, and how it’s not all that.</p>



<p>AI is everywhere. You can’t get away from it. We’ve gone from harmless ChatGPT prompts to full-blown AI use across all media. AI’s use in gaming is causing a constant stir, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dan-houser-left-rockstar-games-due-to-disagreement-with-brother-over-companys-direction-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dan Houser</a> has discussed how his new game with Absurd Ventures is using it, and why it’s not as useful as it seems.</p>







<h2 id="h-dan-houser-using-ai-for-new-game-at-absurd-ventures">Dan Houser Using AI For New Game At Absurd Ventures</h2>



<figure><figcaption>GTA 6 likely features AI. Credit to Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>In an interview on the Sunday Brunch talk show, Houser was asked about his new book, called ‘A Better Paradise,’ aptly all about AI and an aspiring developer creating the perfect computer game:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We are making a game, set in the same world, but not exactly the same story. We’ve begun work on that about 18 months ago, and that’ll be another few years in development.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Rockstar co-founder was asked about the use of AI in his upcoming game. He’s very candid about using it, but offers some pushback on the technology:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“We are dabbling in using AI, but the truth is it’s not as useful as some of the companies would have you believe yet. It’s not going to solve all of the problems.”</p>
</blockquote>







<p>The progression of AI and whether he thinks it’s moving faster than it ever has before also came up:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“In specific areas, yes, and in other areas when we have a whole field of areas we need technology for, and AI is great at some of the tasks and can’t do the other tasks yet. So people will claim that is [AI] can solve every problem, but it really can’t yet. As far as I understand it, it’s a hold all term for future computing, and it’s not really doing a lot of the stuff yet. But if we all give it all of our money, it might do it in the future.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The interview with former Rockstar co-founder Dan Houser and the AI exchange can be watched below.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Dan Houser Interview Sunday Brunch" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/taaJ8EIebQ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>What do you think about the use of AI in gaming? Is it going too far? Or is this merely the beginning of a gradual transition to an era fueled mostly by AI tools and development? The <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> is the perfect place to strike up this controversial topic.</p>



<hr>



<p>Keep reading more IG news, such as the leaked <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-gameplay-presentation-leaks-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake Gameplay Presentation</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/treyarch-making-big-changes-to-improve-black-ops-7-battle-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Treyarch Making Big Changes To “Improve” The Black Ops 7 Battle Pass</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/former-rockstar-co-founder-says-using-ai-for-gaming-isnt-that-useful/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: Dispatch Developers Talk Game’s Success, Company Leadership, Future Hopes, and More!]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-dispatch-adhoc-studio/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-dispatch-developers-talk-game%E2%80%99s-success-company-leadership-future-hopes-and-more.1364128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Adhoc Studio’s Dispatch is one of the biggest hits of the year. The episodic game launched in October, and recently wrapped its eight-episode season. </p>



<p>Since its release on October 22, the game has received wide praise from players and critics alike. Insider Gaming’s Mike Straw even called it one of the best-looking and most enjoyable games of the year.</p>







<p>Now, in the latest episode of the Insider Gaming Developer Spotlight, Straw sits down with AdHoc Studio’s Dennis Lenart and Charles Marcolim. In this nearly 40-minute interview, Mike, Dennis, and Charles talk about Dispatch’s sales success, the state of the gaming industry, evolution in technology from the time at Telltale to now, future hopes for the franchise, and so much more.</p>



<p>Check out the full interview below, and be sure to go <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to Insider Gaming</a> on YouTube. And don’t forget to download the new Insider Gaming App. It’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/insider-gaming-app-android/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">available for free on Android</a> devices with the iOS release coming soon.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Talking Dispatch With The Creators - Developer Spotlight" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iyHL4QZrMaI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<h2 id="h-dispatch-interview-timestamps">Dispatch Interview Timestamps</h2>



<p>Below you can find general timestamps for the conversation. If you want more detailed chapters, open the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iyHL4QZrMaI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">directly on YouTube</a> or in the YouTube App.</p>



<p><strong>00:00 – </strong>Introduction and guest introductions<br><strong>02:47 –</strong> Industry layoffs and studio survival pressure<br><strong>08:51 –</strong> Episodic release strategy and live adjustments<br><strong>13:37 –</strong> Tech evolution and integrating gameplay with story<br><strong>23:30 –</strong> Tone shifts, episode 4’s opening, and characters<br><strong>31:01 – </strong>Future of Dispatch, attachment to the world, and Beef</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-selling-xbox-360-games-all-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best-selling Xbox 360 games</a> of all-time. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-dispatch-adhoc-studio/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splitgate 2 To Officially Relaunch In 2025 After Beta Ends]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-to-officially-relaunch-in-2025-after-beta-ends/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/splitgate-2-to-officially-relaunch-in-2025-after-beta-ends.1364125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The developers of Splitgate 2 have announced that the beta season will end on December 4, 2025, and the game will relaunch later that month. </p>



<p>For those unaware, the developers of Splitgate 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-developers-say-its-going-back-to-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed earlier this year</a> that they will be “going back to beta” to rebuild significant parts of the game. It seems the developers have now spent enough time retesting the title and are confident enough to bring it back to the market. </p>



<h2 id="h-splitgate-2-beta-ends-on-december-4">Splitgate 2 Beta Ends on December 4</h2>



<p>The beta end date for Splitgate 2 was revealed through a new update on their <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2918300/view/590662508143970096" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam page</a>. The announcement shows that the Beta Season &amp; active Battle Passes will be ending, alongside seasonal “rank” progress on December 4. Moreover, the beta servers will be taken down on the same day to prepare for the relaunch later that month. Details for Splitgate 2’s final beta playlist are live, and it kicked off on November 22. </p>



<p>The final Beta playtest for Splitgate 2 features Karman Station, a new power weapon, and some party modes. Karman Station was the first map ever made at 1047 games and features thoughtful adjustments to fit the modern sandbox. The final beta will also bring back the Rail Gun and will focus on a Party Mix playlist featuring updated versions of Team SWAT, Team Fiesta &amp; Shotty Snipers with more to come.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-has-going-back-to-beta-changed-splitgate-2">How Has Going Back to Beta Changed Splitgate 2?</h2>



<p>The developers also spoke about how the beta has helped the title, revealing that they have “rebuilt the entire foundation around what makes Splitgate special: portals, movement, and pure gunplay.” Factions have been removed entirely, and abilities have been reimagined as power-ups. Classic roundless modes like King of the Hill, Domination, and Team Deathmatch are back and added Classic Arena. </p>



<p>Moreover, the developers have introduced new maps, new weapons, reworked the menus, and refined systems based on Player feedback. They have also added portal overloading and EMPs, which change how map control works. Equipment has been streamlined for combat clarity, controller feel has been tuned, critical bugs have been fixed, and countless optimizations have been made. </p>



<p>In other news, the Splitgate 2 devs have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-devs-beg-fans-give-us-one-more-chance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">begged fans for one more chance</a> at their relaunch. Additionally, 1047 Games held <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-developer-holds-another-round-of-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another round of layoffs</a> to go back to beta. What are your thoughts on Splitgate 2’s beta ending soon and the relaunch happening in 2025? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-leak-reveals-pac-man-dlc-release-window/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Sonic Racing CrossWorlds leak revealing the Pac-Man DLC’s release window</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/splitgate-2-to-officially-relaunch-in-2025-after-beta-ends/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>