<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:51:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario’s Voice Actor Debunks ‘Weird Online Narrative’ About Nintendo Directs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marios-voice-actor-debunks-weird-online-narrative-about-nintendo-directs/</link>
            <guid>1407799</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Mario’s modern-day voice actor, Kevin Afghani, debunks a rumor about his involvement with Nintendo before taking on the role of voicing several iconic Nintendo characters. He’s also discussing what it means to him to carry on the legacy of Mario, Luigi, and others.</p>



<p>Kevin Afghani began voicing Mario and Luigi with the 2023 release of Super Mario Bros. Wonder on the Nintendo Switch. He also voices the nefarious Wario. He replaced the retired Charles Martinet, the legendary voice actor who had voiced the characters for decades. However, he recently stated that, despite an online narrative, he had never worked for Nintendo before 2023. Specifically, he denied ever narrating the Nintendo Direct presentations.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I’ll give you one. I was never in Nintendo Direct,” he told <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/movies/2026/01/14/nintendo-new-mario-kevin-afghani-video-games/88185428007/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">USA Today</a>. There’s this weird narrative online I was in Nintendo Directs, I narrated Nintendo Directs. I never worked for Nintendo before being Mario.”</p>
</blockquote>







<h2 id="h-kevin-afghani-has-nothing-but-respect-for-the-og-mario-charles-martinet">Kevin Afghani Has Nothing But Respect For The OG Mario, Charles Martinet</h2>



<p>Discussing his fandom that led him to this dream role, he says he’s living his dream, but he has nothing but respect for the man who came before him, and in his mind, Charles Martinet is Mario.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Look, Charles, as far as I’m concerned, IS Mario. He created something that is so unbelievably iconic. And he did it so masterfully. If I wasn’t nervous, then I’m the wrong guy,” he said. “I’m the second guy who’s doing Mario. Charles is THE guy. There is such an unbelievable respect for Charles. He is amazing.”</p>
</blockquote>







<p>Kevin Afghani will be back in the roles of Mario, Luigi, and Wario in the upcoming Mario Tennis Fever game, set to release in February 2026 on the Nintendo Switch 2. Learn more about that upcoming release <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-unveils-new-features-and-characters-in-mario-tennis-fever-gameplay-overview-trailer/">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>How do you like Kevin Afghani as the voice of Mario? What do you expect from the next 3D Mario release? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marios-voice-actor-debunks-weird-online-narrative-about-nintendo-directs/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Says Black Flag Music Reupload Was Due To “Technical Issues”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-black-flag-music-reupload-was-due-to-technical-issues/</link>
            <guid>1407760</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Ubisoft says its recent upload of the Assassin’s Creed Black Flag soundtrack to Ubisoft Music’s YouTube account was due to technical issues with some of its videos.</p>



<p>On January 14, 2026, the Ubisoft music account on YouTube uploaded 18 songs from the Assassin’s Creed: Black Flag soundtrack. Naturally, the move excited fans and sparked speculation that the game developer may be preparing to announce the much-anticipated remake of the 2013 game, dubbed Assassin’s Creed: Black Flag Resynced.</p>



<p>Ubisoft has now commented on the uploads, stating in <a href="https://t.co/WYPZTZZtZW">a community post on their music YouTube channel</a> that the songs were re-uploaded due to technical issues with some of their prior videos.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Hi there music lovers! We encountered some technical issues with a few of our videos, which we had to reupload. Apologies for the trouble, and hope you enjoy the music.</p>
</blockquote>







<h2 id="h-where-things-stand-with-ubisoft-s-assassin-s-creed-black-flag-remake">Where Things Stand With Ubisoft’s Assassin’s Creed Black Flag Remake</h2>



<p>In January 2024, it was first reported that a remake of the game was in development. Insider Gaming later confirmed that the Remake, codenamed Obsidian, was on track to be released before April of this year. Sources familiar with the situation originally said that marketing for the release was scheduled to begin this month, with the release set for March. Learn more about where things stand with the forthcoming remake <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-leaks-rumors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">at this link.</a></p>



<p>Ubisoft is also working on a Prince of Persia: Sands of Time remake. Check out the latest news on that release <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-rated-by-esrb/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you looking forward to this release? Are you more interested in Prince of Persia? Would you rather Ubisoft focus on new releases in either franchise? Leave your thoughts in our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord server.</a></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-black-flag-music-reupload-was-due-to-technical-issues/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#950)—Clues and Answers for Friday, January 16]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-16-950/</link>
            <guid>1407706</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s Friday – you made it! As another week ends, hopefully your NYT Connections streak <strong>doesn’t</strong>. If I can help you out today, I’ll consider my day a success, and to facilitate that, I’ll direct you to the clues and solutions below. To answer today’s NYT Connections challenge, simply scroll down and tick those boxes.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-january-16">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (January 16)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will prompt your brain to take action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #950:</p>



<ul>
<li>PANAMA</li>



<li>ALABAMA</li>



<li>BATH</li>



<li>BAHAMA</li>



<li>SANTANA</li>



<li>BANANARAMA</li>



<li>SLAM</li>



<li>PAJAMAS</li>



<li>PIANO</li>



<li>PORKPIE</li>



<li>BRUSHNG</li>



<li>KANSAS</li>



<li>DERBY</li>



<li>STORY</li>



<li>CANYON</li>



<li>FEDORA</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>Think classic headwear you might see at a horse race, a jazz club, or on a 1920s gangster.</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>Picture the checklist a parent runs through before lights out.</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>These are all band names where <em>every</em> vowel sound is the same.</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each word can follow the same adjective to form a familiar phrase.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, January 16:</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-explained-for-today-january-16-950">NYT Connections Answers Explained for Today, January 16 (#950)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– DERBY, FEDORA, PANAMA, PORKPIE</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BATH, BRUSHING, PAJAMAS, STORY</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – ALABAMA, BANANARAMA, KANSAS, SANTANA</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BAHAMA, CANYON, PIANO, SLAM</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord serve</a><a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">r</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-january-16-950/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders’ Confusing New Skin Makes Sense, It Seems]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-new-skin-makes-sense/</link>
            <guid>1407703</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Recently, Embark Studios unveiled the ‘Abyss’ skin bundle in ARC Raiders, introducing an outfit that fans had been waiting for since the game came out. It featured a unique, armored skin that was shown in earlier marketing materials, and the company dubbed it ‘highly anticipated’ when it dropped.</p>



<p>However, the <strong>lower portion </strong>of the skin had fans disappointed. It featured what many described as ‘leg corsets’, and the memes and AI rewrites flowed within minutes of the bundle being revealed. As it turns out, the Abyss outfit is pretty damn accurate.</p>







<h2 id="h-abyss-skin-is-an-old-fashioned-anti-g-suit">Abyss Skin is an Old-Fashioned Anti-G Suit</h2>



<p>The Abyss bundle was added to the ARC Raiders store for a premium price recently, rewarding those who’d waited an age (read: a couple of months) to get their hands on it. It’s a unique outfit that includes a bizarre, otherworldly helmet, a mess of tubing, pouches, and small machines, and of course, the <strong>leg corsets</strong>.</p>



<p>Each leg is adorned with a tightly-laced wrap, open at the knees to allow for a range of movement, and admittedly, it looks pretty ridiculous.</p>



<p>But a little internet sleuthing <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ARC_Raiders/comments/1qd1jis/just_gonna_leave_this_here/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">by eagle-eyed fans</a> has uncovered a fact about the Abyss outfit.</p>



<p>It’s actually accurate, and it’s based on an old-fashion ‘anti-g’ suit, worn by pilots to ensure high levels of compression along the legs when sitting and flying for long periods of time. It would ensure optimum blood flow to the brain and prevent pooling in the legs. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The running theory is that the suit applies to those raiders leaving Speranza in their high-speed capsules, rocketing along rails at breakneck speed. That doesn’t necessarily make sense, given the fundamental purpose of the ‘anti-g’ suit.</p>



<p>That’s the topic resolved, then. It might look silly, but no, the ARC Raiders Abyss skin <strong>is not </strong>some kind of gimp suit or skewed, sexy lingerie. It’s a legitimate, retro-futuristic element based on something that genuinely existed – and in some ways, continues to exist today.</p>



<p>Case closed.</p>







<p>Did you invest in the Abyss bundle? Let us know if you’re enjoying the skin on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-life-is-strange-game-reveal-next-week/">a new Life is Strange is being revealed next week</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-new-skin-makes-sense/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenny Kravitz Talks Inspiration For 007: First Light Character]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lenny-kravitz-talks-inspiration-for-007-first-light-character/</link>
            <guid>1407679</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Lenny Kravitz has commented on the inspiration for his character in 007: First Light and has given some insight into the recording process.</p>



<p>In December 2025, IO Interactive confirmed that Lenny Kravitz would voice one of the game’s main villains, an exclusive character named Bawma. The Grammy award-winning artist is now providing some insight into his inspiration for the role and the process of recording lines for the character.</p>







<h2 id="h-lenny-kravitz-pulls-the-curtain-back-on-bawma">Lenny Kravitz Pulls The Curtain Back On Bawma</h2>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/8M3Xc-RBv-I" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">During an interview with IGN,</a> Kravitz explained that some of the inspiration for the character came from some of the people he grew up around.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I grew up in the Bahamas as well as New York City. There were guys that had that vibe and that were doing things in the islands that I’d known, so I had a little bit of reference,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>He also revealed that he did not have the opportunity to record lines alongside the rest of the cast. Instead, he just had the direction from those leading the project.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“I hadn’t seen any other footage or heard any other voice-overs. So it was really sort of just in the dark, you know? They know, thus the director knowing kind of what he wants, because they know the balance, they know what all the other people are doing. I didn’t get to hear that.”</p>
</blockquote>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Lenny Kravitz On His Real Life Inspiration for Bawma - 007 First Light" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8M3Xc-RBv-I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Players will have to wait a little longer for 007: First Light, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/007-first-light-delay-may-2026/">which was recently delayed to May this year from the original March release date.</a> Learn more about that here. And other 007 news: it was previously rumored that<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/007-first-light-theme-song-lana-del-rey-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> Lana Del Rey would provide the theme song for the forthcoming game.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>Are you excited for the next video game presentation from the James Bond franchise? Do you think that this story will have any bearing on the next James Bond film release? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lenny-kravitz-talks-inspiration-for-007-first-light-character/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>