<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - insider-gaming_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/insider-gaming_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for insider-gaming_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:52:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards Statue Mystery Might Have Been Solved]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-statue-mystery-possibly-solved-report/</link>
            <guid>1377592</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>According to a new report, <strong>it seems like the mystery of the Game Awards statue may have been solved</strong>. Furthermore, if true, it comes from a studio fresh off huge wins at the event.</p>



<p>Since last month, a weird statue in the middle of New Mexico has appeared out of nowhere. Both The Game Awards and Geoff Keighley hinted at its true nature, but fans have been going berserk figuring out what it means. From God of War and Diablo to Saros and The Elder Scrolls, guesses <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-mystery-statue-new-mexico-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have been all over the place</a>. Some theories had some real weight to them, though many were shut down by industry figures like Jason Schreier and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-director-reveals-if-the-game-awards-2025-statue-has-anything-to-do-with-franchise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cory Barlog</a>. However, <strong>a new trademark for a legendary RPG series has been spotted</strong>, with the designs matching the statue perfectly.</p>







<h2 id="h-new-divinity-game-possibly-being-revealed-at-the-game-awards-via-mystery-statue-new-report-details">New Divinity Game Possibly Being Revealed at The Game Awards via Mystery Statue, New Report Details</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>The report comes from <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/report-tga-statue-mystery-solved-new-divinity-trademark-uncovered-as-new-icon-matches-statue" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MP1st</a>, who previously did pieces on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-dead-rising-hollywood-possible-capcom-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dead Rising</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/contraband-screenshots-canceled-xbox-avalanche/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Contraband</a>. In it, the outlet found <strong>trademarks for a new Divinity game</strong>, directed by Baldur’s Gate 3’s Larian Studios. From the looks of it, <strong>the logo and accompanying images look strikingly similar to those of the statue</strong>. The picture of the listings, as well as the statue for reference, <a href="https://imgur.com/a/0BhWOdo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">can be found here</a>.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that <strong>the connection has not been confirmed by Larian or The Game Awards</strong>, so <strong>take it with a grain of salt</strong>. In any case, a new Divinity is something many fans will be pumped about. The last release, Divinity: Original Sin 2, came out in 2017 for last-gen consoles. The acclaimed RPG series took players to a new medieval fantasy world with turn-based combat and an isometric perspective. While the logo and all do look new, it could be a remaster of sorts for newer consoles. Still, Larian Studios has been on a roll after the success of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-bafta-games-awards/">Baldur’s Gate 3</a>, so, needless to say, if true, it’s one to keep a giant glowing eye on.</p>







<p>Do you think The Game Awards mystery statue is related to Divinity? Does it match up? Would you like to see a new entry from the franchise? Ever played it? Leave a comment below and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more on The Game Awards, check out the coverage on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-director-bruce-straley-wildflower-interactive-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ex-The Last of Us director’s new game</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-tomb-raider-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the future of Tomb Raider</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-statue-mystery-possibly-solved-report/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is Xbox Wrapped 2025 Coming Out? Expected Release Date & How To Check Stats]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-xbox-wrapped-2025-coming-out-expected-release-date-how-to-check-stats/</link>
            <guid>1377562</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Everyone is obsessed with ‘wrapping up’ more than just presents now as the Holiday season approaches. Xbox Wrapped 2025 is the best way to see how much time you’ve spent on your Xbox, what you’ve done on it, and accessing Xbox Wrapped is nice and easy.</p>



<p>The Xbox brand probably hasn’t had the hottest 2025, and the whole <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-founder-describes-game-pass-price-hikes-as-greed-over-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Pass price increase</a> probably wasn’t the best of news. Despite these setbacks, there’s still a more than healthy player base on Xbox, and this is why Xbox Wrapped’s Year in Review could unearth some fascinating stats about your playtime.</p>



<h2 id="h-xbox-year-in-review-2025-expected-release-date">Xbox Year in Review 2025 Expected Release Date</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New year, new stats. Image via Microsoft</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You should expect the Xbox Year in Review 2025 to arrive during the week of December 8, as this lines up with the last couple of editions of Xbox Wrapped.</strong></p>



<p>Unlike other ‘Wrapped’ round-ups, the biggest consistency about Xbox’s Year in Review is the inconsistency. Looking back at previous releases, you can see that the Xbox Year in Review 2023 was <strong>Tuesday, December 12</strong>, and last year it was <strong>Wednesday, December 4</strong>.</p>



<p>You could guesstimate that it’ll be Wednesday, December 10, for the 2025 edition of the round-up. If it’s not the first week of December, then it has to be the second. We’ve already passed Tuesday, leaving a reasonable assumption of Wednesday, December 10.</p>



<p>Note: Insider Gaming is not claiming this is the date, but is assuming a logical conclusion. Stay tuned and keep checking back for updates.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-check-xbox-wrapped-2025-stats">How To Check Xbox Wrapped 2025 Stats</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Once the official Xbox Wrapped 2025 notice is up, there should be an easy-to-access link where you sign in and claim your full Xbox Year in Review 2025 analysis.</strong></p>



<p>This is based on the last couple of years, but it’s hard to imagine the process changing too much. Here’s how you potentially check your Xbox stats in 2025:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/YearinReview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Year in Review</a> site.</li>



<li>Log in to your Xbox account.</li>



<li>This should automatically trigger your custom Xbox Wrapped journey.</li>



<li>You can read and share details of your Xbox gaming in 2025.</li>
</ol>



<p>You only have a limited time to check the review once it’s live. Make sure you do so, and take a screenshot or share the link to keep the stats as memories or future comparisons!</p>



<p>Share your results once the Xbox Year in Review 2025 is live. Apart from social media, you’re encouraged to head on over to the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a> to discuss your stats with other Xbox users.</p>



<hr>



<p>Insider Gaming also has full guides for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-spotify-wrapped-coming-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spotify Wrapped 2025</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-wrapped-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Wrapped 2025</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-wrapped-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fortnite Wrapped 2025</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-xbox-wrapped-2025-coming-out-expected-release-date-how-to-check-stats/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former The Last of Us Director’s New Game Being Revealed at The Game Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-director-bruce-straley-wildflower-interactive-the-game-awards/</link>
            <guid>1377559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Bruce Straley’s studio, Wildflower Interactive, will be revealing its debut game at The Game Awards. Straley’s resume includes creating The Last of Us and directing Uncharted 2: Among Thieves and A Thief’s End for Naughty Dog.</p>



<p>The Game Awards are no strangers to The Last of Us. With the Naughty Dog IP winning multiple awards, including Game of the Year in 2020 for Part 2, it’s not surprising to see why. Last year, Naughty Dog even revealed its next project, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>, at the end of the show. However, one of The Last of Us’ co-creators, Bruce Straley, wasn’t there, having left the company in 2017. He started Wildflower Interactive in 2021, an indie studio, but didn’t give more information than that. Now, fans can expect to see what the studio has been working on come December 11th.</p>







<h2 id="h-new-game-from-wildflower-interactive-run-by-the-last-of-us-bruce-straley-to-premiere-at-the-game-awards-2025">New Game from Wildflower Interactive, Run by The Last of Us’ Bruce Straley, To Premiere at The Game Awards 2025</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1998452590397501921?s=46&amp;t=hX1f8t9VMLBATttRMgQR3A" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a post on Twitter</a>, Game Awards host Geoff Keighley announced that <strong>the debut title from Wildflower Interactive will be revealed at the show</strong>. The video, only 30 seconds long, shows off the game’s cel-shaded style and a neat wilderness setting. In the back, some dialogue can be heard, including a bear-like roar and some reassurance. No details, like the title or release, have been revealed, though it’s likely to appear during the show on December 11th.</p>



<p>Interestingly enough, Bruce’s co-director on The Last of Us, Neil Druckmann, will likely be in attendance. The TV adaptation of The Last of Us’s second season is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2025-all-award-nominees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nominated for Best Adaptation</a>, in which Neil helped direct. Bruce’s legacy at Naughty Dog goes beyond The Last of Us, as he directed Uncharted 2: Among Thieves and A Thief’s End, which many claim to be the best in the series. Either way, an ambitious new project with a talented director at the helm is always something to look forward to.</p>







<p>What do you think about Wildflower Interactive’s new title? Excited to see what’s next for The Last of Us’ co-director at The Game Awards? Leave a comment below and on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Naughty Dog, check out the coverage for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-2026-debunk-claim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intergalactic’s release timing</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-in-awe-of-clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Neil’s opinion on Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-director-bruce-straley-wildflower-interactive-the-game-awards/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>