<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 22:29:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hear Me Out, Mario Kart 9 Should Be An RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-9-switch-2-rpg-best-argument-all-time-1851743253</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hear-me-out-mario-kart-9-should-be-an-rpg.1087098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-9-switch-2-rpg-best-argument-all-time-1851743253<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo made an interesting decision with <em>Mario Kart 8</em>. They chose to make it so good, and so comprehensive, that it removed the need to make any more. It has now been over ten years since <em>Mario Kart 8</em> first released, more than double the length that’s ever come between an entry in the series before. Honestly, they could re-re-release <em>8</em> for the Switch 2, and it’d still sell millions. Given this, here’s an idea: why not do something <em>dramatically </em>different with <em>Mario Kart 9</em>?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196599,196001" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>All I’m saying is make it into an RPG.</p><p>It’s really hard to underline properly how unprecedented is the success of <em>Mario Kart 8</em>. This game was first released for the Wii U in 2014, then re-released for the Switch in 2017 as <em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>. Now, it was an embellished version, with all previous DLC, new characters, let you hold two items, and a rejuvenated battle mode, but it was still very much the same game. The Wii U version is thought to have sold almost 8.5 million copies, and the Switch release is one of the best-selling games ever made, at an astonishing 64 million copies. With frequent new content, and endless fixes and tweaks, the game is still receiving patches even since what appears to be its final content update when it hit version 3.0.0 in November 2023.</p><p>It’s been such a phenomenon that Nintendo has very wisely not attempted to usurp it, doubling the longest ever gap between entries, the previous longest stretch being from 1996's <em>Mario Kart 64</em> to 2001's GBA title, <em>Mario Kart: Super Circuit</em>. And listen, remember when Nintendo formerly announced the Switch 2 last week, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-9-nintendo-switch-2-announcement-trailer-1851740833&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-9-nintendo-switch-2-announcement-trailer-1851740833">everyone spent a couple of hours arguing over whether the game footage shown was <em>Mario Kart 8</em> or something new</a></span>? People seemed like they’d be happy with just some more of <em>8</em>.</p><p>So why not? May as well just tip that numeral over and call it <em>Mario Kart ∞</em>. Add a whole bunch more tracks, update something else, call it a day. And for <em>Mario Kart 9</em>, let’s go deep.</p><p>One of my all-time favorite games is 2004's <em>Mario Golf: Advance Tour</em>. I have never played a real game of golf in my life, and have no interest in golf games in general, but that Game Boy Advance game was utter joy from start to finish. You played as one of two kids, Neil or Ella, who join the Marion Clubhouse as potential star golf students. There you meet an eclectic mix of humans and <em>Mario</em> characters, with the ultimate aim of beating Mario himself in the final championship. And it’s wonderful! Utterly bonkers, with splendid writing, the vast majority of the time you’re actively playing the core golf game, but all within a narrative, and surrounded by RPG elements.</p><p>When developers Camelot returned with 2014's <em>Mario Golf: World Tour</em>, I was so excited! Ten years later there was to be another entry! And then I found out this was a follow-up to the GameCube’s <em>Toadstool Tour</em>, no RPG at all, and I went off and sulked. I went through much the same in 2021 with <em>Mario Golf: Super Rush</em>. I’m still sulking now. But I still hold hope in my heart. I still believe that every single <em>Mario</em> game can be massively improved by being an RPG. So let me sell you on this idea for <em>Mario Kart</em>.</p><figure id="" data-id="c980208198f4af5e679f637b8700851c" data-recommend-id="image://c980208198f4af5e679f637b8700851c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1000" data-height="667" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mario Golf Advance Tour, with Mario about to hit a ball." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario Golf Advance Tour, with Mario about to hit a ball." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c980208198f4af5e679f637b8700851c" data-recommend-id="image://c980208198f4af5e679f637b8700851c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1000" data-height="667" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mario Golf Advance Tour, with Mario about to hit a ball." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>You pick a character, whether it’s a Neil or an Ella or a Toad, and you get your first kart. You have just arrived at the Marion Gran Prix Academy, a location that has four local racetracks, Luigi Raceway, Moo Moo Farm, Koopa Troopa Beach and Kalimari Desert. You’re tasked with completing various training races, learning skills like jumping and skidding, as well as how best to use the various item drops. Once you’ve completed these tasks, you can take part in each track’s big race, and once you’ve won trophies in all four, you unlock access to the next site, the one that has Toad’s Turnpike, Frappe Snowland, Choco Mountain, and Mario Raceway.</p><p>Along the way, you gain levels, letting you spend points in speed, drift, bounce, steering, and the all-important luck. You develop your character according to your own preferred approach to <em>Mario Kart</em>, the relatively minor tweaks letting you lean in to your own skills.</p><p>Each site has <em>Mario</em> characters scattered about, people to talk with, little secrets to discover. And each has its own unique bonus rounds, time trials, and extra challenges. The ultimate goal is, of course, to beat Mario on the Rainbow Road, but that’s a distant dream when you begin. You’ll need to have developed your kart into something really special to manage that, tweaked its brakes and drift to your ideal settings, and gained the best skills in a starting boost.</p><p>Obviously this is the greatest idea anyone has ever had, but alongside my rightfully being given a million-billion dollars and a crown, I imagine there are a few ne’er-do-wells who would argue, “But I want a PROPER <em>Mario Kart 9</em>!” That’s because they didn’t read the first half of this perfect argument properly, and realize they just already have it. It’s <em>Mario Kart Infinite</em>, remember? When Nintendo is building me my throne made of Master Swords, I’ll remind them they have to make that Switch 2 upgrade for <em>8</em>/<em>Infinite</em>, with the handful of new tracks, and that’ll keep them distracted while the rest of us have <em>the best time ever</em>.</p><p>Glad we could get this sorted.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Severance Creator Assures Us The Show Won't End Like Lost]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/severance-season-2-explained-dan-erickson-1851743150</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/severance-creator-assures-us-the-show-wont-end-like-lost.1087029/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/severance-season-2-explained-dan-erickson-1851743150<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="6886e764831c63084adcbc7b63059856" data-recommend-id="image://6886e764831c63084adcbc7b63059856" data-format="jpg" data-width="6000" data-height="3375" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Irving on the phone" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Irving on the phone" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Apple</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6886e764831c63084adcbc7b63059856" data-recommend-id="image://6886e764831c63084adcbc7b63059856" data-format="jpg" data-width="6000" data-height="3375" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Irving on the phone" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/miss-huang-severance-season-2-apple-tv-1851738787?_gl=1*1dawc1n*_ga*MzkwOTg1NzQxLjE3MzEyNTczMTE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNzM4NzQ5MS42Ni4xLjE3MzczODc1NjQuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/miss-huang-severance-season-2-apple-tv-1851738787?_gl=1*1dawc1n*_ga*MzkwOTg1NzQxLjE3MzEyNTczMTE.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczNzM4NzQ5MS42Ni4xLjE3MzczODc1NjQuNjAuMC4w"><em>Severance</em></a></span> has enough unanswered questions and detailed fan theories to make even the most faithful viewer concerned about the series ultimately sticking the landing. In a recent <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/severance-recap-season-2-episode-1-why-helly-lies-1236276867/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/severance-recap-season-2-episode-1-why-helly-lies-1236276867/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with <em>Variety</em></a></span>, series creator Dan Erickson gives reassurance that the sci-fi drama won’t have an ending like the historically derided denouement to ABC drama <em>Lost</em>.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>To remind the few people unaware (<em>Lost </em>ending spoilers follow!), <em>Lost</em>’s sixth and final season<em>&nbsp;</em>pissed off a bunch of people who had dedicated hundreds of real hours watching the show about a group of plane crash survivors stranded on a mysterious tropical island. In the final season, the show introduced a confusing parallel timeline where the stranded characters live normal lives, only to find out it wasn’t a parallel timeline but some sort of purgatory-like afterlife where they can all reunite. We never find out why all that weird stuff happens on the island, what the deal was with all of those numbers, or where Jacob (Mark Pellegrino) got the powers to grant immortality and leave whenever he wanted. </p><p>Erickson promises <em>Severance</em> won’t turn into <em>Lost</em>, but dances around fully committing to answering all of the show’s mysteries. “I promise the show will not literally turn into <em>Lost</em>. We won’t put them on an island and have Sawyer show up. No—we’re very conscious of that fact that we need to know where we’re going, and we need to reward people’s patience and faith.”</p><p>That <em>Severance </em>fan theories multiplying quicker than Apple can pump out episodes almost guarantees there will be questions unanswered, mainly because they were questions Erickson never posed. The series can have a satisfying ending without explaining how many departments there are in the Lumon building that houses the main cast, or why there is a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/miss-huang-severance-season-2-apple-tv-1851738787&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/miss-huang-severance-season-2-apple-tv-1851738787">child working on the Severed Floor</a></span><em>. </em>Those mysteries are ancillary and not central to the drama of the show. But, there remain quite a few mysteries they’ll need to clear up by the end of the series if they want to avoid <em>Lost</em> levels of ignominy. </p><p>We need to know what these severed workers are actually working on, and what Lumon’s ultimate plan is. The whereabouts of Ms. Casey (Dichen Lachman) seem to be a focal point of the current season, but we also need to know if and how Lumon faked her death given the facts Mark S (Adam Scott) says he identified her body. Under no circumstance can this series end without explaining what the fuck is the deal with the goats. </p><div><p>Those are just a few of the core mysteries that need to be resolved but the time the show wraps up. Lucky for us <em>Severance </em>fans, Erickson says Season 3 shouldn’t have the nearly three-year wait Season 2 had. Let’s just hope this whole series isn’t all just happening in Kier’s comatose mind in some Lumon nursing home. </p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>