<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 14:48:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Addresses Ongoing Controversy Around Cultural Sensitivity With Day-One Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-day-1-patch-notes-shrine-1851771221</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-addresses-ongoing-controversy-around-cultural-sensitivity-with-day-one-patch.1140045/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-day-1-patch-notes-shrine-1851771221<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A day-one patch for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647"><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadow</em></a></span><em>s</em> will address criticisms of how the open-world RPG allows players to go on a violent rampage through religious shrines in 1500s Japan. Parts of specific buildings will no longer be destructible, and the monks inside will no longer bleed when hit, following recent comments on the topic by Japan’s Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,196345,195928" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The controversy stems from <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/shoheikondo/status/1885391745854173688&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/shoheikondo/status/1885391745854173688" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a clip that went viral</a></span> back in January, showing one of the game’s two protagonists, the samurai Yosuke, attacking people and breaking furniture at the Itatehyōzu Shrine outside the historic Himeji Castle in<strong>&nbsp;</strong>Hyōgo Prefecture. The gameplay is voluntary and not part of any quest, but <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-antiwoke-ubisoft-rpg-1851770511&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-antiwoke-ubisoft-rpg-1851770511">was leveraged by some online</a></span> as evidence that <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> was being disrespectful toward Japanese culture following previous complaints about<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-statement-yasuke-1851602337&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-statement-yasuke-1851602337"> other culturally insensitive&nbsp;details</a></span> in the game. </p><p>Ubisoft, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delay-release-date-star-wars-1851657285&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delay-release-date-star-wars-1851657285">whose corporate fortunes</a></span> over the next year will be heavily determined by the relative success of <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, isn’t taking any chances, and has tried to address the concerns of Japanese officials in a day-one patch that will prevent players from recreating the footage that went viral back in January. The patch notes, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shared with <em>IGN</em></a></span> ahead of the March 20 release, include the following:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Citizens without weapons no longer bleed when attacked, reducing unintended blood spill in temples/shrines</li><li>Tables and racks in temples/shrines are now indestructible (Some objects like drums or bowls can still be broken as they are generic ones present everywhere in the world) (Tables are still dynamic objects, so players can still move/push them).</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="h737871"><a id=""></a>The shrine destruction controversy, explained</h2><p>Though it may have started as an online debate, the controversy surrounding the ability to deface sacred historical sites in Japan reached the upper echelons of Japanese government earlier this week. Prime Minister Ishiba was asked about the topic during a budget meeting by House of Councillors member Hiroyuki Kada, who represents the region where the Itatehyōzu Shrine is located, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">according to a report by <em>IGN</em></a></span>.</p><p> “I fear that allowing players to attack and destroy real-world locations in the game without permission could encourage similar behavior in real life,” Kada told Ishiba. “Shrine officials and local residents are also worried about this. Of course, freedom of expression must be respected, but acts that demean local cultures should be avoided.” </p><p>The Prime Minister responded, “Defacing a shrine is out of the question—it is an insult to the nation itself. When the Self-Defense Forces were deployed to Samawah, Iraq, we ensured they studied Islamic customs beforehand. Respecting the culture and religion of a country is fundamental, and we must make it clear that we will not simply accept acts that disregard them.”</p><p>The concern seems to be primarily about the potential for the features in the game to encourage copycat attacks in real life, as politicians the world over have frequently worried about with regard to other games—primarily <em>Grand Theft Auto—</em>that mix hyper-realistic simulations with the freedom to commit violent acts. Another issue expressed in the meeting was the lack of express permission from the Shrine to have its name and likeness included in the first place. </p><p><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, originally scheduled to come out last fall, has already been delayed twice. Developers at Ubisoft have worked on adding extra layers of polish and fine-tuning to avoid any potential snags at launch that might derail the blockbuster’s early momentum. Following disappointing sales for <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> and <em>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</em>, and mounting financial pressures from other delays and cancellations, reports have swirled about a potential sale or break-up of the French publisher. <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows </em>currently has an 81 on Metacritic, in line with previous games in the franchise, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647">while our own review</a></span> lauded it as “one of the most dynamic, fun, and best-looking open-world games of the current console generation.”</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stand Back 'Peaches,' Jack Black Has A New Rock Anthem For A Minecraft Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-jack-black-i-feel-alive-song-rock-1851771190</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stand-back-peaches-jack-black-has-a-new-rock-anthem-for-a-minecraft-movie.1139904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-jack-black-i-feel-alive-song-rock-1851771190<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It would frankly be silly at this point not to get Jack Black to release his vocal chords if he’s starring in a movie. Following the viral success of ‘Peaches,’ Black’s gloriously silly ditty sung as Bowser in <em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em>, it looks like <em>A Minecraft Movie</em> is trying to capture some of the same magic. Will it though?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Well, OK, probably not. Where ‘Peaches’ was inherently funny, the overwrought rendition of asinine lyrics, sung in the plaintiff voice of a lovelorn Bowser, <em>Minecraft</em>’s ‘I Feel Alive’—despite being fine--feels overwritten and, well, smells a touch of desperation. But, and it’s an important but, only in the context of the cynical exercise we can see being deployed. The song itself is competent, extremely well-performed, and could easily have been a Whitesnake B-side in the mid-80s.</p><p>See, the joke is, “rock” means both rock music <em>AND</em> a thing you use in <em>Minecraft</em>! GEDDIT? Beyond that, it’s very much an ‘80s movie credits fare, the plot of the film sung to family-friendly rock riffs, and it seems inevitable that it’ll play over the credits when <em>A Minecraft Movie</em> releases April 4.</p><p>And yet, at the same time, you can totally see an enthusiastic crowd jumping up and down as they roar out the catchy chorus. Children everywhere will find the album on Spotify after they’ve seen the film and enjoy air guitar rocking out during the bridge. It’ll do its job. And, in this sense, it’s rather emblematic of the movie as a whole.</p><figure id="" data-id="f494fd31e153d7a4229b53d2a2b8aae5" data-recommend-id="image://f494fd31e153d7a4229b53d2a2b8aae5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1011" data-height="566" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jack Black as Steve in front of a portal." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jack Black as Steve in front of a portal." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros. Pictures / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f494fd31e153d7a4229b53d2a2b8aae5" data-recommend-id="image://f494fd31e153d7a4229b53d2a2b8aae5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1011" data-height="566" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jack Black as Steve in front of a portal." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Now, I was in no sense at all expecting to generate any controversy when I pointed out, in September last year, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-trailer-jack-black-kids-1851640395&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-trailer-jack-black-kids-1851640395">that the movie wasn’t trying to win over an audience of 20 and 30-somethings</a></span> who played <em>Minecraft</em> in their youths. Yet, gosh, people were rather cross. Apparently every game-related film ever made should cater exactly to each specifically entitled manbaby who might see its trailer, and any other notion is blasphemy. The greatest heresy is to point out this is a film aimed at the current generation of children who are currently propelling <em>Minecraft</em> to being one of the biggest toy and gaming franchises in the world. This is largely because each entitled manbaby has an imaginary 12-year-old nephew who thinks the trailers look <em>terrible</em>.</p><p>Anyway, the point is, <em>A Minecraft Movie</em> is being met with a lot of bad faith, and it’s going to be very interesting to see how it performs heading into this storm. Obviously no one has any idea if it’s any good at this point, although it was reported <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-live-action-first-trailer-reaction-1851703382&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-live-action-first-trailer-reaction-1851703382">that test screenings went well</a></span>, and indeed that the movie didn’t match the tone of that first trailer. If it’s genuinely bad, rather than that tedious movie critic faux-weariness that is so often deployed for kids’ films, then it could obviously hurt the juggernaut’s progress.</p><p>My 10-year-old is absolutely hyped for this, each following trailer deliberately spotlighting <em>Minecraft</em> memes that are currently huge on YouTube, of which you and I are completely unaware. Which again is to say, I have a strong feeling that the creators know what they’re doing here, making a movie that’s not for those of us who were passing code for the Java edition to friends in 2009, but rather the kid on the bus today wearing a&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> school bag over their <em>Minecraft </em>joggers and hoodie, watching Skeppy on their phone. </p><p>And yeah, that’s inherently cynical. Much like the accompanying song. Then again, anyone holding out hope that this was ever going to be a Jim Jarmusch-like moody indie sleeper-hit was perhaps being a little naive. Anyway, here’s the far more excellent ‘Peaches.’</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>