<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 14:37:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Comes To Xbox Exactly 1 Year After PS5 Debut, Reigniting Conspiracies About Exclusivity]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-ps5-exclusivity-date-sale-1851783817</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-comes-to-xbox-exactly-1-year-after-ps5-debut-reigniting-conspiracies-about-exclusivity.1209273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-ps5-exclusivity-date-sale-1851783817<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>One of 2024's biggest hits, the boss fight-fueled action adventure <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>, is finally coming to Xbox Series X/S. It releases there on August 20, exactly one year after it made its original console debut on PlayStation 5, once again stoking rumors that a Sony exclusivity deal was what it kept it off the competing platform.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197533" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why People Are Rushing To Sell Their Xbox Series X To GameStop Right Now" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="197533,196181,197567" data-current="197533"><div><p>Why People Are Rushing To Sell Their Xbox Series X To GameStop Right Now</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197533/197533_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197533/197533_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197533/197533_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23065.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Microsoft randomly broke the news of the upcoming port on Thursday night, just a few days ahead of its big summer showcase. <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> will be available to pre-order on Xbox starting June 18, with the game 20 percent off until July 11. That discount will also be available on PS5 and PC, developer Game Science saying it wanted to give players a heads up in case they were planning on buying the game before then. </p><p>But the real question remains why <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> took so long to arrive on Xbox in the first-place. Many assumed the only explanation was an exclusivity deal with a Sony, whose Hero Initiative focuses on scouting high-quality games in the Chinese market and helping bring them to a global audience. However, <em>Black Myth </em>was never announced as one of those. Microsoft helped fuel those rumors with an opaque comment released back in summer 2024 ahead of the game’s launch</p><p> “We’re excited for the launch of <em>Black Myth Wukong</em> on Xbox Series X|S and are working with Game Science to bring the game to our platforms,” a Microsoft spokesperson told<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/hotly-anticipated-black-myth-wukong-is-delayed-on-xbox-for-optimizations-and-now-microsoft-has-responded&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/hotly-anticipated-black-myth-wukong-is-delayed-on-xbox-for-optimizations-and-now-microsoft-has-responded" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Windows Central</em></a></span><em> </em>at the time. “We can’t comment on the deals made by our partners with other platform holders, but we remain focused on making Xbox the best platform for gamers, and great games are at the center of that.” </p><p>While Game Science has always claimed it was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-series-x-s-release-delay-1851731006&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-xbox-series-x-s-release-delay-1851731006">optimization issues on Xbox Series S</a></span> that was holding the port up, <em>Forbes</em>’ Paul Tassi <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/PaulTassi/status/1829211594108350790?t=xQkqpU3DJI9iMMrrNljuRA&amp;s=19&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/PaulTassi/status/1829211594108350790?t=xQkqpU3DJI9iMMrrNljuRA&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reported</a></span> that an exclusivity agreement of some kind was in place. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-xbox-delay-due-to-sony-exclusivity-deal-not-tech-issues-according-to-source&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-xbox-delay-due-to-sony-exclusivity-deal-not-tech-issues-according-to-source" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em> contradicted Game Science’s position</a></span> and reported that “no tech issue” that would delay<em> Black Myth </em>on Xbox had been reported to Microsoft. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/YOf7LJRiDww?t=1432s&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/live/YOf7LJRiDww?t=1432s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Giant Bomb</em>’s</a></span> Jeff Grubb, however, claimed there was no marketing agreement in place between the two companies. The whole saga left everyone confused and let console warriors on both sides claim vindication. </p><p>So why is <em>Black Myth</em> now just happening to drop on Xbox Series X/S exactly 365 days after it came to PS5 if there wasn’t an exclusivity deal in place? “Bringing <em>Black Myth:</em>&nbsp;<em>Wukong</em> to Xbox Series X|S—and ensuring the experience met our internal quality standards—was no easy feat,” the Chinese studio wrote in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.heishenhua.com/news/detail?id=194&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.heishenhua.com/news/detail?id=194" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a newly published FAQ</a></span>. “Fortunately, we were able to complete this challenging task smoothly within the first year of the game’s official release.”</p><p>Others, meanwhile, have suggested August 20 just happens to be a special date for the studio. “Game Science has been using August and the 20th for announcements since 2020,” gaming consultant Daniel Camilo <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.comboinfinito.com.br/principal/black-myth-wukong-no-xbox-exclusividade/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.comboinfinito.com.br/principal/black-myth-wukong-no-xbox-exclusividade/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Infinite Combo</em></a></span>. X user ignusthewise <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/ignusthewise/status/1930903503888662795&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/ignusthewise/status/1930903503888662795" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pointed out</a></span> that the development team has been using August 20 for all its big drops, including gameplay trailers and reveals, for years. Not everyone is convinced, and they probably never will be unless Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer himself comes out and denies the rumors. Until then, millions of new players will get a chance to finally see why<em> Black Myth</em> won 2024's Player Voice award at The Game Awards. <br></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune Awakening Proves A Massive PC Hit, Despite Competition From Switch 2 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-survival-mmo-funcom-advanced-access-1851783808</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-proves-a-massive-pc-hit-despite-competition-from-switch-2-release.1209240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-survival-mmo-funcom-advanced-access-1851783808<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Realizing your big-budget, high-risk online game is coming out at the same time as the most anticipated new console in half a decade can’t be a great feeling. But I bet discovering that nearly one hundred thousand people played it at the same time anyway, almost a week before it’s officially released, made all the dread worthwhile. <em>Dune Awakening</em>, Funcom’s MMO-cum-survival game, is proving astonishingly popular, despite some hefty competition.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197527" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="169" data-playlist="197527,195301,196790" data-current="197527"><div><p>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Part 2 Is Short, Shocking, And Strangely Satisfying</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197527/197527_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23057.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Making an MMO in 2025 seems brave in and of itself. Funcom has had a mixed history with the format, from the story-focused <em>Anarchy Online</em> and <em>Secret World Legends</em> to the more widely successful <em>Conan Exiles</em>, but it’s been a long seven years since the company created a new game. <em>Dune Awakening</em>, born admidst the popularity of Denis Villeneuve’s movies, picks up what <em>Conan</em> put down (then pushed around in a big circle for years), expanding on the mix of crafting and survival simulation set in a massively multiplayer world.</p><p>The game is officially out on June 10, but the scourge of “Advanced Access” means that those who buy a more expensive version of the unreviewed game can start playing before anyone has the chance to tell them if it’s worth their money. And how. Last night saw over 93,000 people playing simultaneously, and that number has already picked back up to 55k at the time of writing, as the Western world wakes up once again. </p><p>Funcom has been a little bit canny here. Usually, Advanced Access on PC is a benefit you only get if you fork out the cash for some kind of “special edition” that sees the cost of a game soar above its vanilla $60 launch price, likely hitting $90 to $100. However, in the case of <em>Dune Awakening</em>, prices started lower. People playing today likely bought the Deluxe Edition that’s “only” $70, still a significant bump over the $50 the game will cost you on Tuesday, but certainly more enticing to larger crowds, and does include the season pass. Then there’s an Ultimate Edition, at $90, to make sure the big spenders still have somewhere to throw away their cash: on top of playing the game earlier, you’ll also get four in-game dress-up assets and a digital artbook and soundtrack. </p><p>That more sensible pricing structure is likely a big part of why the game is performing so extraordinarily well ahead of full launch, and hopefully will get noticed by those who believe that increasing prices is the only way to make more money. Bang a drum with me: Larger. Numbers. Of. People. Can. Afford. Lower. Prices.</p><p>It’ll be very interesting to see if the game sustains this kind of player population, and whether it can smash even these splendid numbers on official release. Games like <em>Dune Awakening</em> are make-or-break on launch (or at least have a monstrous hill to climb should it go badly), and given that the 100k who showed up last night all went in pretty blind (they may have played a beta, but still), not knowing if they would find a game that’s up to standard, it remains to be seen what the consensus will be. It’s currently sitting on 84 percent positive reviews, from almost 4,000 people, so not too shabby. </p><p>This is all the more impressive considering it was done against the backdrop of the Switch 2 arriving in everyone’s homes. Sure, the Venn circles might not have the <em>biggest</em> overlap between PC multiplayer survival players and Nintendo fanciers, but given the Switch 2 now has mouse controls...It really demonstrates that gaming is a far broader church than people usually credit, with plenty of room for vast amounts of variety to be simultaneously successful.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>