<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:48:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Runs Secret iPad Air Sale on Amazon, Best Apple Tablet Now Going for All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-quietly-ditches-ipad-air-pride-on-amazon-own-site-still-pretends-nothing-changed-2000648171</link>
            <guid>1366978</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple maintains its tradition of avoiding Black Friday deals on their own retail website while quietly liquidating inventory through Amazon with more generous discounts than previous years.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4214/"> At $449, down from $599, this 11-inc 128GB/WiFi iPad Air (M3 chip) joins Apple discounting</a> spanning MacBooks, AirPods, Apple Watches, and iPads. The only product category notably absent from Amazon’s Black Friday Apple selection remains the iPhone 17 series, which still hasn’t launched on Amazon’s platform despite being available through carriers and Apple directly. This 25% discount on the<strong> iPad Air represents a record-low price</strong> for Apple’s mainstream tablet that balances capability with accessibility.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3760/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Between the Basic iPad and the Pro Models</h2>
<p>The basic iPad costs about $329 and comes with an A14 chip from the previous generation and a standard Retina display, and it’s for people who want a cheap device for browsing and basic productivity. The <strong>M3 chip in the iPad Air gives it a lot more processing power</strong> because it has desktop-class architecture that can handle demanding games and creative applications that would be too much for the basic model. The <strong>Liquid Retina display with P3 wide color and True Tone is better</strong> than the basic iPad’s display because it has more colors, better viewing angles, and adaptive white balance.</p>



<p>The iPad Pro positioned above the Air commands $800+ through M4 chip, mini-LED ProMotion displays reaching 120Hz and Face ID replacing Touch ID. Professional photographers, video editors, and digital artists justify Pro pricing through workflow advantages including ProRes video recording, LiDAR scanning, and reference-quality displays. <strong>But most users find the Air’s M3 chip provides more than adequate performance</strong> for typical tablet workflows and the $350+ savings compared to iPad Pro base models enables purchasing Magic Keyboard or Apple Pencil accessories for instance.</p>
<p>The M3 chip made for Apple Intelligence has an <strong>8-core CPU and a 10-core GPU architecture</strong> that makes it almost as powerful as a desktop computer. When you edit videos in iMovie or LumaFusion, the effects happen in real time and the timeline scrubbing is smooth.</p>



<p>The <strong>11-inch Liquid Retina display has a resolution of 2360 x 1640 at 264 PPI</strong> which makes individual pixels impossible to see. The P3 wide color gamut shows more colors than the standard sRGB display, and it makes colors that look washed out on other displays stand out more in photos and videos. The ultralow reflectivity coating keeps the screen visible outside where glossy screens wash out completely. The True Tone technology <strong>changes the white balance based on the lighting around you</strong> to make it easier on your eyes when you use it for a long time.</p>
<p>Stage Manager is one of the features of iPadOS that makes real work possible: It <strong>lets you create resizable and overlapping app windows</strong> like those on desktop operating systems instead of forcing you to switch between apps in full screen. Support for external displays makes the workspace bigger by adding monitors, and Scribble turns handwriting into text wherever you can type.</p>
<p>At $449, the iPad Air 11-inch is the best value for money iPad you can get during Black Friday. If you need tablet computing with good performance, this record-low price makes Apple’s mainstream iPad accessible without compromise.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3760/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-quietly-ditches-ipad-air-pride-on-amazon-own-site-still-pretends-nothing-changed-2000648171]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Gave Up on Fire 10-Inch HD Tablet, Own Hardware Burned With Zero Margin]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-gave-up-on-fire-10-inch-hd-tablet-own-hardware-burned-with-zero-margin-2000648193</link>
            <guid>1366969</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The <strong>Fire HD 10</strong> packs a 10.1-inch Full HD display, octa-core processor with 3GB RAM and 13-hour battery life into a package that <strong>costs seven times less than entry-level iPads</strong>. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4205/">At $69, down from $139, this tablet has become the #1 bestseller across Amazon’s entire computers and tablets category</a> while hitting a record-low price that makes it cheaper than many restaurant dinners. Amazon removes profit margins on own-brand hardware during Black Friday to drive Alexa and Fire OS adoption. The <strong>50% discount transforms tablets</strong> from considered purchases into impulse buys that justify owning multiple units for different family members.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4205/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Full HD Display That Works</h2>
<p>The <strong>10.1-inch screen has a resolution of 1920 x 1080</strong> which means that Netflix, Disney+, and YouTube look clear instead of blurry. Text stays clear while you read instead of making your eyes hurt by being fuzzy. Rich colors make photos, videos, and games come to life with levels of saturation that are as good as those of tablets that cost a lot more.</p>



<p>With an octa-core processor and 3GB of RAM, <strong>this Fire HD 10 is 25% faster than previous generations</strong>. It can handle web browsing with multiple tabs, video streaming, and casual gaming without any lag. Kids use educational apps, parents watch cooking videos, and students read textbooks, and the tablet’s performance is always responsive, so it never feels like a limitation.</p>
<p>The <strong>battery lasts for 13 hours which is enough for a few hours of streaming</strong> and browsing each day. This means you can go on weekend trips, long flights, or full days without worrying about running out of battery. The 32GB of base storage is enough for basic apps, downloaded videos, ebook librarie, and photos, so you don’t have to add more right away. The <strong>microSD slot can hold up to 1TB of extra storage</strong> for growing content libraries.</p>
<p>Parents can also set up <em>Amazon Kids</em> parental controls to make tablets safe for kids by filtering content, setting time limits, and choosing educational content. With easy-to-use controls, parents can limit access to apps and videos that are appropriate for their child’s age and stop them from making purchases or seeing inappropriate content.</p>
<p>At $69, this is the lowest price Amazon has ever offered on its own brand on Black Friday. The combination of real Full HD quality, real performance improvements, and incredible durability at half the already-low retail price makes it a better deal than any other iPad competitor. The fact that this is the #1 best-selling item on all computers and tablets shows that buyers know a great deal when they see one.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4205/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-gave-up-on-fire-10-inch-hd-tablet-own-hardware-burned-with-zero-margin-2000648193]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Stuck With Too Many AirPods Pro 3, Now Selling Newest Earbuds at All-Time Low to Clear Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-stuck-with-too-many-airpods-pro-3-now-selling-newest-earbuds-at-all-time-low-to-clear-stock-2000648166</link>
            <guid>1366960</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>This year marks a turning point in Apple’s historically rigid pricing strategy where discounts remained rare and controlled. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4214/">At $219, down from $249, the AirPods Pro 3 that launched just months ago join Apple’s unprecedented Black Friday selloff</a> happening exclusively on Amazon rather than through official channels.</p>
<p>The entire AirPods lineup received aggressive discounting including the <strong>AirPods Max at $399</strong>, <strong>AirPods 4 with ANC at $99</strong>, <strong>standard AirPods 4 at $69</strong>, and these flagship Pro 3 models. Apple appears determined to clear inventory quickly but discreetly through Amazon’s platform rather than diluting brand perception on their own website where premium pricing remains intact.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4214/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Live Translation That Lets You Talk to Anyone</h2>
<p>With<strong> the real-time translation feature</strong>, you can talk to people who don’t speak English face-to-face. The earbuds translate speech right away and show the text on your paired iPhone: Ordering food, asking for directions or doing business in a foreign language is less scary when AI can help with these things. The feature works for <strong>phone calls as well and translates both sides of conversations in real time</strong> for international calls with coworkers, family or business contacts who don’t speak your language.</p>



<p>The <strong>heart rate sensor turns AirPods from simple audio devices into health monitoring tools</strong> that can keep track of heart health metrics during workouts without the need for chest straps or wrist-worn devices. The optical sensors measure blood flow through the ear canals and send heart rate data to Apple Health so you can keep track of your fitness in real time.<strong> Runners can see their heart rate zones</strong> in real time while they train without having to wear an Apple Watch.</p>
<p>The <strong>hearing aid feature is a huge step forward</strong> in accessibility because FDA-approved hearing aids can now work through regular earbuds instead of expensive medical devices. The feature runs built-in tests to figure out your hearing profile, then boosts certain frequencies where you have hearing loss while keeping the sound quality natural. People with mild to moderate hearing loss can get help with everyday tasks without the stigma or cost of traditional hearing aids, which can cost thousands of dollars.</p>



<p><strong>Active noise cancellation works better</strong> now because the processing has been improved to sample background noise and make anti-phase sound waves that are more accurate. The noise of airplanes, people talking in the office and traffic all fade away into silence and let you fully concentrate on music, podcasts or work without any outside noise. The <strong>adaptive transparency mode</strong> lets in background noise when you need it for conversations or to be aware of your surroundings – and it changes automatically based on how loud the noise is around you.</p>
<p>With dynamic head tracking, <strong>Spatial Audio makes three-dimensional soundstages</strong> where sounds seem to come from certain places in space around you. Directional audio cues that put dialogue in the center of the screen and sound effects that pan left and right make movies and shows more immersive than flat stereo can. More and more music producers are using spatial audio which means that artists mix tracks specifically for this format to make immersive experiences where instruments are in different places.</p>
<p>If you want Apple’s most advanced earbuds, this record-low price represents the best value available.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4214/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-stuck-with-too-many-airpods-pro-3-now-selling-newest-earbuds-at-all-time-low-to-clear-stock-2000648166]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Goes Zero-Profit on AirPods Max, Price So Low It Makes You Forget Bose and Sony Exist]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-zero-profit-on-airpods-max-price-so-low-it-makes-you-forget-bose-and-sony-exist-2000648175</link>
            <guid>1366948</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon officially launched Black Friday last Thursday, November 20th, when the AirPods Max dropped from $549 to $479, surprising everyone since Apple rarely discounts premium products. This <strong>Thanksgiving Thursday brought an even more aggressive markdown</strong> as Amazon pushed these flagship noise-cancelling <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4532/">headphones down to $399, down from $549, representing nearly 30% immediate savings</a>.</p>
<p>At $399, these over-ear headphones have hit <strong>an unprecedented record-low price</strong> that shatters all previous discounting patterns for Apple’s premium audio hardware.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4532/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Noise cancellation at the pro level</h2>
<p>The <strong>active noise cancellation can get rid of up to twice as much background noise as previous Apple models</strong>: This is because eight microphones work with the H1 chip to sample ambient sound and create precise anti-phase waves. The computer audio processing happens all the time, every microsecond and it changes to fit the noise level as you move from one place to another or as the sounds around you change.</p>



<p>The<strong> transparency mode lets ambient sound through with little processing latency</strong> which makes people more aware of their surroundings: This lets people talk without taking off their headphones or missing important environmental cues. The mode uses the same microphone array and computational audio pipeline as ANC to process outside sound which keeps the sound quality instead of just lowering the cancellation.</p>
<p>The iPhone’s <em>TrueDepth</em> camera scans your ears to figure out their shape, and then<strong> personalized spatial audio adjusts the sound delivery to fit your body</strong> so that you can hear it in the <strong>best three-dimensional way</strong>. Directional audio cues are great for movies and TV shows because they keep dialogue in the middle of the screen while sound effects move left and right, and this makes the experience much more immersive than flat stereo. <strong>Dynamic head tracking keeps the audio in the same place</strong> as your connected device so when you turn your head, the soundstage doesn’t change.</p>



<p>The acoustic-first design philosophy puts sound quality first by <strong>using custom 40mm dynamic drivers that give you high-fidelity audio</strong> across the entire frequency range. Deep bass reproduction goes all the way down to sub-bass frequencies without distortion. Midrange clarity makes sure that vocals and instruments sound natural instead of colored. Treble detail shows subtle differences in recordings that headphones that are compressed or poorly tuned hide.</p>
<p>The <strong>computational audio uses the H1 chip’s processing power</strong> and advanced algorithms that change the sound in real time based on how well it fits, how loud it is, and what type of content it is. The system keeps the sound balanced at any volume by changing the frequency response as you change the volume. It also makes up for changes in the seal as the cushions compress or move, and it processes music, movies, and podcasts differently based on their content.</p>
<p>When you<strong> integrate your ecosystem with your iPhone, iPad, and Mac</strong>, you get seamless experiences because your devices switch automatically and follow your attention without having to pair them manually. Start music on your iPhone while you’re on the bus, switch to your Mac for work without changing any settings, and then switch to your iPad for streaming in the evening: Your headphones will automatically connect to the devices that are currently in use.</p>
<p>If you want Apple’s best audio quality with unmatched noise cancellation, this record-low deal makes premium over-ear headphones accessible without the usual premium pricing.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4532/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-zero-profit-on-airpods-max-price-so-low-it-makes-you-forget-bose-and-sony-exist-2000648175]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP Forgot How Math Works, 15.6″ 512GB Laptop Drops 72% From $2K to Almost Nothing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hp-forgot-how-math-works-15-6-512gb-laptop-drops-72-from-2k-to-almost-nothing-2000648161</link>
            <guid>1366927</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>HP keeps premium positioning in the Windows laptop segment where finding capable machines under $1,000 proves challenging, particularly on their official website where aggressive discounting rarely appears. The good news is that <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6024/">at $569, down from a typical $1,999, this 15.6-inch touchscreen laptop</a> featuring <strong>Intel’s 13th Gen i3-1315U processor, 16GB RAM, 512GB SSD, and Windows 11 Pro</strong> has <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6024/">crashed 72% below typical pricing</a> during Black Friday on Amazon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6024/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Can Handle Real Workloads</h2>
<p>The<strong> Intel Core i3-1315U processor has 6 cores</strong> that are split between performance and efficiency designs, and this hybrid architecture speeds up demanding tasks while keeping battery life. The performance cores take care of heavy tasks like video conferencing, photo editing, and data analysis while the efficiency cores take care of light tasks and background tasks without wasting power.</p>



<p>The <strong>15.6-inch HD touchscreen makes it easy to use Windows by letting you pinch, zoom, swipe, and tap</strong> to navigate – and it changes how you use the keyboard and trackpad. The touchscreen makes<strong> Windows 11’s touch-optimized interface elements</strong> even better: These elements are made for finger use, not mouse precision. The <strong>display has an 85% screen-to-body ratio</strong> which means that the bezels are very thin and the viewable area is as large as possible.</p>
<p>The 16GB DDR4 RAM gets rid of memory bottlenecks that annoy people who use memory-heavy programs like virtual meetings, big spreadsheets, or a lot of professional software at once. This amount of memory<strong> lets you run Windows 11 Pro and a lot of productivity apps at the same time</strong>, do a lot of research in your browser, and keep your communication tools running without slowing down the system.</p>
<p>The 512GB SSD has enough space for the operating system, professional software suites, project files and media libraries, so you don’t have to rely on external drives all the time. The <strong>solid-state storage boots up in less than 15 seconds</strong> and opens applications in less than 10 seconds because NVMe speeds are faster than those of regular SATA drives. High-speed storage subsystems speed up the transfer of large files, the saving of video projects, and the operation of databases.</p>



<p><strong>Windows 11 Pro has business</strong> features that Windows Home editions don’t have like BitLocker encryption, Remote Desktop and Active Directory support. The built-in Copilot AI assistant helps you come up with ideas, organize your tasks, write documents and answer questions in a way that feels natural. For tasks that need privacy, <strong>the AI runs on your computer</strong>.</p>
<p>HP’s premium brand quality combined with Amazon’s zero-margin Black Friday strategy creates exceptional value that rarely materializes on current-generation hardware. If you need capable daily computing without premium pricing, this record-low deal makes professional Windows laptops accessible.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6024/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hp-forgot-how-math-works-15-6-512gb-laptop-drops-72-from-2k-to-almost-nothing-2000648161]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Philips Skipped Profit on Hue Smart Bulbs, 3-Pack Color Lights Now Cost What Basic Bulbs Do]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/philips-skipped-profit-on-hue-smart-bulbs-3-pack-color-lights-now-cost-what-basic-bulbs-do-2000648180</link>
            <guid>1366921</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Philips Hue represents the premium brand in smart lighting where default pricing remains consistently high enough that shoppers wait specifically for Prime Day or Black Friday to make purchases.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/">At $69, down from $109 (36% off), this 3-pack of white and color smart bulbs</a> costs barely more than a <strong>single bulb at regular pricing which runs at $54</strong> <strong>individually</strong>. This record-low pricing transforms smart lighting from luxury upgrade into practical home improvement that justifies outfitting entire rooms or homes rather than installing single bulbs as experiments.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>16 million colors that change the look of a room</h2>
<p>The white and color ambiance range lets you control the whole spectrum with <strong>millions of color combinations and white temperatures</strong> that can be changed from <strong>warm 2700K to cool 6500K</strong>. This flexibility lets you match the lighting to your activities, moods and times of day instead of being stuck with fixed color temperatures that make you compromise.</p>



<p>The<strong> 24-hour natural light scene changes its color temperature and brightness</strong> automatically during the day to match the patterns of sunlight. This keeps your circadian rhythm in sync which helps you sleep better and stay alert during the day. In the morning, the light slowly gets brighter, like the sun rising, instead of waking you up with a loud alarm. In the evening, the light slowly gets warmer and dimmer and signals that it’s time to go to bed.</p>
<p>With Hue Bridge integration, you can use advanced <strong>features like automation based on schedules or sensor triggers</strong>, remote control from anywhere with an internet connection, and rock-solid Zigbee connectivity that doesn’t slow down WiFi networks. The secure, dedicated wireless protocol stops the connection drops and delays that WiFi-based bulbs have when they are on busy home networks. <strong>Matter protocol support lets Philips products </strong>work with a wider range of smart home systems, making them compatible with other platforms and protecting investments from being locked into a single ecosystem.</p>



<p><strong>Voice control with Alexa, Google Assistant, and Siri</strong> lets you use natural language commands to control things without having to touch anything. This is easier than navigating apps. This voice integration is especially useful when your hands are full cooking, carrying things or getting ready for bed and you don’t want to have to grab your phone.</p>
<p>Dynamic light effects <strong>make subtle animations like slow color changes, breathing pulses, or candlelight flickers</strong> that make the lighting more interesting than just being static. These effects turn regular rooms into lively spaces where lighting is more than just a tool. When combined with Hue Sync software, immersive effects that sync with on-screen action make gaming setups better.</p>
<p>These<strong> bulbs can be used as main light sources because they are bright enough (800 lumens) for general room lighting</strong>, not just accent lighting. The LED technology <strong>uses only 9 watts of power</strong> while giving off the same amount of light as a 60-watt incandescent bulb. This saves a lot of money on electricity over the 25,000-hour life of the bulb.</p>
<p>This three-for-one price makes it possible to buy premium smart lighting for whole rooms instead of just one bulb.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/philips-skipped-profit-on-hue-smart-bulbs-3-pack-color-lights-now-cost-what-basic-bulbs-do-2000648180]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Quietly Dumps Thousands of iRobot Vacuums, Roomba 105 Now Going for All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-quietly-dumps-thousands-of-irobot-vacuums-roomba-105-now-going-for-all-time-low-2000648154</link>
            <guid>1366909</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Robot vacuums span a massive price spectrum where premium models costing $1,000 to $2,000 deliver great performance across all metrics while budget options fluctuate wildly in quality and reliability. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/">At $249, down from $449, the iRobot<em> Roomba 105</em> (with auto-empty dock) represents the sweet spot where proven brand reliability meets accessible pricing during Black Friday</a> on Amazon.</p>
<p>iRobot dominates the category through decades of refinement that established <strong>Roomba as the generic term for robot vacuums</strong>, similar to how Kleenex represents tissue. This r<strong>ecord-low deal includes the game-changing auto-empty dock</strong> that transforms occasional convenience into genuine hands-off cleaning.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>75-Day Self-Emptying That Changes Everything</h2>
<p>The auto-empty dock empties the robot’s dustbin automatically after each cleaning session, and it compresses the dirt into a <strong>big bag that needs to be changed about every 75 days in normal household conditions</strong>. This longer maintenance schedule turns robot vacuums from things that need to be cleaned every week into real <em>“set-and-forget”</em> cleaning tools that can run on their own for months.</p>



<p>The<strong> 70x power-lifting suction of the new Roomba 600 series creates real cleaning power</strong> that pulls embedded pet hair out of carpet fibers, lifts dirt that has been ground into tile grout lines and picks up fine dust particles from hardwood floors. This suction power is on par with that of upright vacuums and it comes from small robotic shapes. This means that robot vacuums can do the same job as traditional vacuums without needing to be used with them.</p>
<p>The <strong>three-stage cleaning system</strong> has a strong suction and a brush that works on both carpet and hard floors. It also has an edge-sweeping brush that pulls dirt out of corners and baseboards that the main brushes can’t reach.</p>
<p><em>ClearView</em><strong> LiDAR navigation maps your home</strong> by measuring distances with lasers, and this makes accurate floor plans that let you clean each room in a planned way instead of randomly bumping into things. The LiDAR sensor accurately measures how far away walls and other obstacles are, and this makes cleaning paths that cover the whole floor plan without missing any spots or having to clean the same areas over and over.</p>



<p>You can<strong> program certain rooms to be cleaned based on your daily schedule</strong> so you can focus on cleaning the areas where you actually live instead of spreading the battery evenly across the whole house: Plan to clean the kitchen after dinner, the bedroom before bed or the living room before guests arrive. You can change the cleaning passes and suction levels to fit the area: For example, you can use the most power on carpets that get a lot of traffic and save battery on areas that don’t get used as much</p>
<p>The <strong>iRobot Home app gives you full control over your robot</strong> and allows you to set up custom cleaning schedules, get time estimates for different tasks, keep an eye on the filter’s life, and set up virtual keep-out zones that stop the robot from going into certain areas. Without physical barriers getting in the way, you can make invisible walls around pet food bowls, fragile floor vases, or rooms that are being remodeled.</p>
<p>At $249, the iRobot Roomba 105 is at 45% below retail this Black Friday. If you want great hands-off floor cleaning with proven brand quality, this record-low price makes premium robotic cleaning accessible without the usual four-figure investment.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-quietly-dumps-thousands-of-irobot-vacuums-roomba-105-now-going-for-all-time-low-2000648154]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung 65″ OLED S90F TV Hits All-Time Low, 2025 Model Now Cheaper Than Last Year’s Version]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-65-oled-s90f-tv-hits-all-time-low-2025-model-now-cheaper-than-last-years-version-2000648184</link>
            <guid>1366882</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Samsung committed fully to Black Friday by discounting every product category and Amazon delivering the most aggressive pricing across smartphones, tablets, earbuds, and TVs. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6025/">At $1,397, down from $1,997 ($600 off)</a>, the <strong>65-inch OLED S90F featuring the NQ4 AI Gen3 processor, 4K AI upscaling, OLED HDR+, and 144Hz Motion Xcelerator</strong> is the pinnacle of Samsung’s display technology at a record-low price.</p>
<p>This deal applies across all size variants, though the <strong>65-inch model dominates sales</strong> through optimal balance between screen real estate and living room proportions. The 30% discount makes OLED technology accessible at pricing that approached mid-tier LED TVs just years ago.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6025/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Neural Network Processing That Changes Content</h2>
<p>The <strong>NQ4 AI Gen3 processor uses 128 dedicated neural networks</strong> that have been trained on millions of images to look at content frame by frame and make smart improvements that make the picture quality much better. The AI can tell the difference between sports, movies, news, and games and then it processes each type of content in the best way for that type: Sports broadcasts get motion smoothing that cuts down on blur when the camera pans quickly; Movies keep the cinematic frame cadence without the soap opera effect that aggressive processing makes.</p>



<p>The <strong>4K AI upscaling uses the same neural network architecture</strong> to look at lower-resolution content and intelligently fill in missing details to make it look like it was shot in 4K. Cable broadcasts, streaming services that deliver 1080p and older content libraries all get sharper and clearer when you play them back because of edge enhancement, texture synthesis, and noise reduction. The upscaling is especially useful because the content mixes true 4K productions with upscaled or natively lower-resolution material, which keeps the visual quality the same no matter where it comes from.</p>
<p>OLED technology uses self-emissive pixels that <strong>turn completely off when showing black</strong> instead of backlights that leak through, and this gives you perfect blacks and infinite contrast. This basic benefit makes picture quality that LCD panels with local dimming can’t match: It shows shadow detail in dark scenes while keeping bright highlights without blooming or haloing. With HDR content, stars shine against really black space backgrounds, and horror movies show intentional shadow detail instead of washing everything gray.</p>



<p>Motion <em>Xcelerator</em> 144Hz makes motion look smooth by using high refresh rates and smart frame interpolation to cut down on judder and blur during fast action. VRR support <strong>up to 4K 144Hz is good for gaming</strong> because it stops screen tearing and keeps input lag low, which is important for competitive play. When cameras move quickly, sports broadcasts become clearer.</p>
<p>Samsung <em>Vision AI</em> uses scene-by-scene analysis to adjust brightness, contrast and color saturation based on the content and the lighting in the room. The system makes the screen brighter when you watch it during the day in bright rooms and less bright when you watch it at night to keep your eyes from getting tired. Dark scenes get targeted brightening that shows shadow detail without making the whole picture look washed out.</p>
<p>The full range of connections, such as HDMI 2.1 ports, USB inputs, Ethernet, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth, works with modern gaming consoles, streaming devices, sound systems, and wireless accessories without the need for adapter dongles or connection issues.</p>
<p>If you want the best picture quality Samsung produces, this record-low price makes flagship OLED TVs attainable without waiting years for depreciation.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6025/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-65-oled-s90f-tv-hits-all-time-low-2025-model-now-cheaper-than-last-years-version-2000648184]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Goes Full Liquidation on Santa’s Sleigh Set, Now Selling at Zero Profit to Clear Before Christmas]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-goes-full-liquidation-on-santas-sleigh-set-now-selling-at-zero-profit-to-clear-before-christmas-2000648144</link>
            <guid>1366783</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Thanksgiving brings a welcome surprise as <strong>LEGO’s most popular Christmas set returns to Amazon inventory</strong> after two weeks of complete stock depletion that frustrated holiday shoppers. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6021/">At $25, down from $39, the Santa’s Sleigh building set hits a Black Friday price</a> that likely removes LEGO’s profit margin entirely as they race to clear seasonal inventory before Christmas passes and demand evaporates.</p>
<p>The aggressive pricing reflects LEGO’s urgency to move remaining units rather than holding stock that becomes instantly obsolete on December 26th. With over <strong>30,000 units already sold</strong> and limited time remaining before the holiday, this inventory replenishment at record-low pricing creates the optimal purchasing window.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6021/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>343-Piece Build That Is Fun and Challenging</h2>
<p>The <strong>343-piece count gives builders a lot of time to build, about 2 to 3 hours for experienced builders</strong> and even longer for kids working on their first multi-hour LEGO projects. This piece count strikes a good balance between being fun and easy to use. It has enough pieces to keep kids ages 9 and up happy without overwhelming younger builders with too many pieces that make them angry.</p>



<p>The <strong>Santa minifigure and four poseable reindeer figures</strong> that come with it let kids act out Christmas Eve delivery scenes instead of just looking at static displays. The saddles can be taken off and decorated, which lets you personalize them. The<strong> eight wrapped gifts</strong> that can be built also give you props for storytelling which makes the toy more fun to play with after it’s been built. The <strong>guitar, skis, and teddy bear accessories</strong> hint at certain story elements, but they also leave room for people to use their imaginations to figure out whose gifts these are and where Santa brings them.</p>
<p>The <strong>sleigh is 3 inches high, 11.5 inches long, and 2.5 inches wide</strong> which makes it a great holiday decoration that doesn’t take up too much space on mantels or shelves. The size is perfect for showing off on fireplace mantels, entry tables, or holiday vignettes without needing special furniture. LEGO’s precise manufacturing tolerances guarantee that the structure will stay strong even when it is handled carefully and stored once a year.</p>



<p>The set works just as well as a <strong>hands-on gift that the recipient puts together themselves or as a decoration that the gift-giver</strong> puts together before giving it. Kids who get the unbuilt set get to build it and use it at the same time while adults who get pre-assembled sets like how they look right away without having to spend time building them, which they may not have during busy holiday seasons.</p>
<p>Because it’s seasonal, the set naturally follows a pattern of being displayed in December and then packed away with other holiday decorations. This way, it stays fresh each year instead of becoming stale decorations that are always there. This cyclical use makes the perceived value last longer by building up excitement around yearly unpacking traditions that kids look forward to along with other holiday traditions.</p>
<p>LEGO Santa’s Sleigh comes with 343 pieces, a Santa mini-figure, four reindeer and the ability to display Christmas decorations. LEGO’s zero-margin seasonal clearance pricing combined with restocked inventory after 2-week depletion creates the optimal moment to secure this popular set before final sellout.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6021/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-goes-full-liquidation-on-santas-sleigh-set-now-selling-at-zero-profit-to-clear-before-christmas-2000648144]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Razer Ergonomic Gaming Chair Just Hit a Black Friday Record Low, Not Even Prime Day Went This Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bag-the-razer-iskur-v2-x-ergonomic-gaming-chair-while-its-going-for-just-250-on-amazon-2000647135</link>
            <guid>1366759</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As someone who’s in front of the screen for several hours a day, six days a week, I can tell you just how important a good-quality chair is. You’re not just sitting on it; it’s providing your upper and lower back, plus arms, the support they need so you can keep working comfortably.</p>
<p>As you’d expect, the best options on the market don’t come cheap. On a regular day, you can expect to pay over $300 for a top-rated option from a known brand. Thankfully, that changes today. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6019/">Right now, you can grab the Razer Iskur V2 X ergonomic gaming chair for just $250, after a nice 17% discount on its retail price of $300.</a></p>
<p>It’s a Black Friday deal, and the offer applies to both black and dark gray color options. The discount, however, ends soon, so it’s best to bag it as soon as you can.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6019/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Adjustable Design With Plush Fabric</h2>
<p>The fabric is cool to the skin and smooth to the touch. Thicker cushion padding molds to the unique shape of your body, while the breathable, multi-layered fibers prevent sweat and moisture buildup during those longer, intense work and play sessions.</p>
<p>The wide seat base is sculpted with reduced edges that distribute the pressure around evenly, which prevents soreness in the buttocks and thighs. It also promotes healthy blood flow, so you won’t have to change positions every few minutes to keep those uncomfortable numbness or tingling sensations away. There’s an integrated lumbar arch that encourages a neutral sitting position with lower back support, because it’s high time you start taking your posture seriously. We don’t mean to creep you out, but Tech Necks don’t just look awkward; they can lead to long-term spine damage and nerve pinching if you don’t make necessary adjustments.</p>
<p>Of course, sitting upright for longer hours can get tiring. To tackle that, the Razer Iskur V2 X has an adjustable recline of up to 152 degrees. Stretch out a bit, and use this mode for relaxing gaming or streaming sessions that don’t require intense focus.</p>



<p>Arms get a break, too. The 2D armrests can be adjusted in height and rotated inwards or outwards for a neutral position. When typing long documents, adjust the height to match your desk and keep them in the outward position for proper arm and wrist support. Planning to relax with a quick gaming session? Pull them inwards for a bit more stability with the console.</p>
<p>The chair is available in two color options, so you can pick whichever suits your aesthetics the best. Go for the black one for a cleaner, classic look. Like your gaming setup with a bit more personality? The dark gray version is going to upgrade the overall look instantly!</p>
<p>This gaming chair does not come pre-assembled, so you’ll need to put it together yourself. The process is straightforward (instruction manual included), and should not take more than 30 minutes. If you’d rather skip the hassle, you can get professional assembly through Amazon for an additional $100.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6019/"> To wrap it up, this Black Fridy deal brings the price of this ergonomic gaming chair down to just $250, after a nice $50 discount.</a> It’s great for gamers, work professionals, creatives, and even casual users looking for better support as they use their PC or laptop. It ends soon, though, so it’s best to grab yours before the price goes back up, or the stock ends for good.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6019/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bag-the-razer-iskur-v2-x-ergonomic-gaming-chair-while-its-going-for-just-250-on-amazon-2000647135]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>