<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 19:03:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 12 Best Games On Xbox 360]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-xbox-360-5878837</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-12-best-games-on-xbox-360.1361785/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>You have an Xbox 360 controller waiting for you in your living room and a console hungry to entertain you. It’s an older console, sure. But it still has a ton of great games.</p> <p><em>This list was published on April 21, 2016. We’re re-posting it today in honor of the Xbox 360’s 20th anniversary.</em></p> <p>As of April 2016, <a href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-ends-xbox-360-production-1772042864">Microsoft has ceased production of the Xbox 360 console</a>. It had a great run—red rings and Kinect 1.0 notwithstanding—and it got a ton of great games. These dozen games have occupied our Bests list for a long while, and at this point there’ll probably never be another update. (Never say never, though!)</p>

 <p>Here are our recommendations for the 12 best games on Xbox 360. Enjoy.</p> <h2 data-textannotation-id="9201ab5b178b5c0b91005e103f75f309"><em>Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646524" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646524"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646524">Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p>After years of changes both minor and major, the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> series had begun to feel in a rut. (For example: We’d had <em>Assassin’s Creed II</em> on this list since its inception.) Finally this year, with the pirate-themed <em>Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag</em>, the series has taken a major and unequivocal step forward. It doesn’t lose <em>all</em> of the series’ bad habits—hello follow missions—but it improves many longstanding problems with better stealth, easier-to-navigate cities, and sidequests that actually feel like they help make your character more powerful. Best of all, it adds naval combat and a vast Caribbean overworld that make the game feel like, in the words of Luke Plunkett, “<em>Wind Waker</em> for grown-ups.”</p>

 <p><strong>A Good Match For: </strong>Pirate fans, history buffs, anyone who’s ever wanted to pull up alongside a British frigate, grab a rope and swing from one deck to the other before fighting your way up the deck to take on the captain. So basically, anyone who’s ever wanted to be a pirate.</p>

 <p><strong>Not a Good Match For: </strong>Those who demand precision controls. The on-foot controls in <em>Black Flag</em> are probably the best of the series, but they’re still a far cry from where a third-person stealth/platformer should be. It’s time for a crouch button, Ubisoft.</p>

 <p><a href="http://bit.ly/17WsnAu" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Borderlands 2</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646525" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646525"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646525">Gearbox Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p>With an even bigger, wackier, lootier <em>Borderlands</em>, Gearbox has proved that their hybrid RPG/shooter franchise isn’t just a one-hit wonder. Three years after the first release, Gearbox put out a <em>Borderlands 2</em> that doesn’t just have thousands more guns. It’s more complex. It’s even got <em>heart</em>. And yet <em>Borderlands 2</em> still manages to strike a balance between being more soulful while retaining the slapstick, make-no-excuses-for-itself humor for which the series is known. The characters you meet are often borderline (if not full-blown) psychotic, but in the most endearing of ways. Enemies are just as raunchy as they are diverse. It’s colorful, it’s tough, it’s meaty, and it’s a joy to play with up to 3 friends in co-op. It’s also got TONS of extra, downloadable content to keep you busy once you finish the main game.</p>

 <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Gamers who want a fun co-op experience to play through with friends. There are plenty of quests, plenty of guns, and plenty of laughs to be had.</p> <p><strong>Not A Good Match For</strong>: People who want to burn through a game easily. <em>Borderlands 2</em> can be pretty tough, especially without backup. And if you aren’t willing to spend some time churning out sidequests, you just might catch yourself at the tail-end of the game without the chops or stats to finish without getting burnt out.</p>

 <p><a href="http://bit.ly/18xf2Cr" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Burnout: Paradise</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646526" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646526"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646526">Criterion Games</figcaption></figure> <p>Automotive destruction’s never looked as sexy as it does in Criterion’s hi-speed racing game <em>Burnout: Paradise</em>. You’re tasked with driving against traffic, scraping against civilian cars and shoving competitors into signature crashes called Takedowns. But, <em>Paradise</em> also deserves praise for a seamless integration of multiplayer where dropping into a showdown can be quick as tapping a button.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Street racing fans. If you’ve ever pulled up to a stoplight and imagined what it’d be like to burn rubber on a wide-open stretch of asphalt—and survive any ensuing mishaps—this is your game.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> To tune the specs of their rides. It may be <em>Paradise</em> but these aren’t real-world cars. You can’t do much more than swap out paint jobs, so those wanting to make changes to brakes, shock or engines will need to get their grease-monkey fix elsewhere.</p>

 <p><b><a href="https://kotaku.com/burnout-paradise-didnt-need-a-remaster-but-its-nice-1823840738">Read</a> our review.</b></p> <h2><em>Grand Theft Auto V</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646527" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646527"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646527">Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure> <p><em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> is an impressive crime game. Not perfect, but impressive. The game gives players one of the richest, most beautiful open worlds we’ve ever been able to play in. In this case, the landscape is a fictionalized version of Los Angeles and the California desert. Go anywhere in this vast game. Grab a car, plane, truck, bicycle, boat or tank. Head off in any direction. You’re bound to see extraordinary sights and stumble into some sort of good and probably violent time. The game looks amazing even on the old Xbox 360 hardware. It also plays better than any <em>GTA</em> before it. <em>GTA V</em>’s innovative, swappable three-protagonist system creates the feel of a true ensemble adventure, though crazy man Trevor steals the show.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Players who like to go into a game to break the rules. GTA is still at its best when it’s a playground for virtual misbehavior.</p>

 <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Anyone who can’t stomach the game’s mockery of, well, pretty much everyone.</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/1aLDtf9" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646528" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646528"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646528">Starbreeze Studios</figcaption></figure> <p><em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em> came out of nowhere this year, surprising everyone with its strange control scheme, smart (if simple) puzzles and devastating ending. Can game mechanics be emotionally affecting? Turns out yup, they can be. It’s a nice, short game with almost no fat—and despite the fact that the two main characters don’t communicate in a language anyone could understand, they still manage to communicate a great deal of context and backstory. You’ll never think of your thumbs and your controller triggers the same way.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For: </strong>People looking for something different, those who like weird controls schemes, fans of old-school fairy tales.</p>

 <p><strong>Not a Good Match For: </strong>Those hoping for a long game—it’s a few hours long and offers no real replayability—people who like their characters to speak actual languages.</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/18xsbsi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our thoughts</strong><strong>.</strong></p> <h2><em>The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646529" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646529"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646529">Bethesda</figcaption></figure> <p>Bethesda Softworks’ hit role-playing game does nothing so much as deliver a giant, Tolkien-styled possibility space to its players. The high-altitude climes of Tamriel feel alive with wonder and threat. The ability to customize your warrior outcast with a singular mix of mystical skills and melee mastery feels as broad as <em>Skyrim</em>’s horizon.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Dungeon &amp; Dragon players. Adventuring in <em>Skyrim</em> feels like spinning your own epic yarn, as songs of your feats spread digitally from town to town in a game world that reacts to your actions. You can spend weeks meandering in its fascinating sidequests, leaving the main story.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Those who play with urgency. The drive to wander and discover overpowers the drive to complete in <em>Skyrim</em>. If you’re the kind of player who wants those two vectors to meet in a meaningful way, you’ll find <em>The Elder Scrolls V</em> a bit frustrating.</p>

 <p><a href="http://bit.ly/1cdDyGs" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Gears of War 3</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646530" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646530"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646530">Epic Games</figcaption></figure> <p><em>Gears 3</em> fills the marquee spot held by Bungie’s <em>Halo</em> games and with good reason. Epic Games’ scifi shooter threequel represents hardcore shooter nirvana: a tightly-polished campaign that plays great solo or coop and some of the best multiplayer found anywhere. Moreover, the game’s been robustly supported with both campaign and multiplayer DLC designed to deepen an already hearty release, particularly with the addition of many of the best maps from <em>Gears of War 2</em></p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Dedicated online shooter fanatics who play every day. The more you play, the more <em>Gears 3</em> rewards you.</p>

 <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Those who want deep character development or intriguing story structure. Gears games have always been meat-and-potatoes in terms of plot</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/194lQIl" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Halo: Reach</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646531" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646531"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646531">Bungie</figcaption></figure> <p>Bungie created the best goodbye possible with a “final” <em>Halo</em> title that both looks forward and backward in the blockbuster FPS franchise’s history. Pairing up a health system similar to that of the first <em>Halo</em> game with all-new abilities like jetpacks and holographic decoys makes the decade-old series feel simultaneously familiar and fresh.</p>

 <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Sci-fi fans. To play a <em>Halo</em> game is to be introduced to an expansive fictional universe. <em>Reach</em> places you inside one of the <em>Halo</em>-verse’s pivotal battles and imbues its lead characters and environments with more personality than in previous games.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Anyone who wants Master Chief. The Spartan you control in <em>Halo: Reach</em> isn’t as invulnerable or powerful as the Xbox mascot and the feel of certain weapons gets tweaked when compared to previous games.</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/194m1Dv" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Mass Effect 2</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646533" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646533"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646533">BioWare</figcaption></figure>  <p><em>Mass Effect 2</em> was the one that made you believe. Its predecessor drew players in with expansive world-building and a tense storyline, but it was also a clunky, rough-hewn slab of a game. BioWare’s 2010 follow-up polished the combat, introduced characters who’d become fan favorites and streamlined the overall experience to a fine focus. The first game made you want to experience all the sci-fi action and drama, but the second game made it a lot easier to do so. Pack in a huge number of varied and often terrific downloadable content packs and you’ve got one beefy, galaxy-spanning chunk of video game to play.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Fans of the <em>Star Wars</em> Expanded Universe. Like George Lucas’ signature creation, <em>Mass Effect</em>’s fictional cosmos has multitudes of tales to tell. The extremely good post-campaign DLC chapters expose players to side stories centered on both new and familiar characters, just like Timothy Zahn’s Thrawn Trilogy and the other <em>Star Wars</em> extensions. <em>Overlord</em>, <em>Lair of the Shadow Broker</em> and the other add-ons really made it feel like millions of little lives were at stake in Shepard’s fight against the Reapers.</p>

 <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> People who need closure. <em>Mass Effect 2</em> tells plenty of small stories, but the main narrative arc is still essentially a set-up for the 2012 follow-up.</p> <p><a href="http://www.bit.ly/1bSg7rz" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Red Dead Redemption</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646534" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646534"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646534">Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure> <p><em>Red Dead Redemption</em>, the most assured work by the makers of the <em>Grand Theft Auto</em> games finds its success by shedding the trappings of the modern-day world and giving players a vast virtual Southwest to roam in search of revenge. When your lonely ambles suddenly get shattered by an ambush or the plea to stop an unjust hanging, it’s a bittersweet adrenaline rush unlike anything else in modern video games. Silence, then gunfire, then more fleeting silence again.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Admirers of killer endings. The denouement for the turn-of-the-century saga stands as an emotionally powerful finish that can stand amongst the cowboy cinema that inspired it.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Fans of brevity. Redemption’s plot takes a long amount of playtime to resolve and you’ll often feel like you’re doing busy work in the nooks and crannies of its spaghetti Western game world.</p>

 <p><a href="http://bit.ly/194mwNR" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>Portal 2</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646535" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646535"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646535">Valve</figcaption></figure> <p>Call it the <em>Superman 2</em> or <em>Empire Strikes Back</em> of video games. Valve’s follow-up to a classic improves on the humor, characterization and puzzle-solving of its predecessor to deliver a tight, focused experience full of poignancy and humor.</p> <p><strong>A Good Match for:</strong> Comedy lovers. The voicework alone—performed in stellar fashion by Stephen Merchant and Ellen McLain—will make you laugh out loud but the brain-teasing puzzles and embedded gags keep the chuckles coming even when everything else in the game goes quiet.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Mediocrity fans. People who argue with <em>Portal 2</em>‘s greatness are like folks complaining that diamonds came from dirt. Their argument is invalid.</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/19mLgNI" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review.</strong></p> <h2><em>XCOM: Enemy Within</em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000646536" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646536"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646536">Firaxis</figcaption></figure> <p>There it is: proof that a multiplatform game released in 2012 can recapture the glories of a 1994 PC classic. The re-imagined <em>XCOM</em> delivers graphical upgrades and interface refinements like you might expect but what really makes it sing is the added attachment that you feel to the battles and the soldiers who fight them. If you’re considering picking up the game now, get <em>Enemy Within</em> instead, as it contains the original game as well as the terrific 2013 expansion. It’s sold as a standalone for consoles, so be sure to buy the new version.</p>

 <p><strong>A Good Match For:</strong> Efficiency lovers. This version of human-vs-aliens warfare streamlines gameplay when compared to its predecessor. And the importance of cover in combat and clever deployment of perks makes you consider every decision intensely.</p> <p><strong>Not a Good Match For:</strong> Those who want skirmishes. The combat in 2012 <em>XCOM</em> can stretch on way longer than is necessary. Because the battles require active engagement, you can feel chained to a session.</p> <p><a href="http://bit.ly/ISUJq0" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Read</strong></a><strong> our review and our review of </strong><a href="http://bit.ly/ISUN9d" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>the latest expansion.</strong></a></p> <p><em><strong>How has this list changed? Read back through our update history:</strong></em></p> <p><strong>Update 12-9-13: </strong>With a new year comes an updated bests design and with it, the chance to go back and do a one-time overhaul of each list. After much arguing and debating, many changes have been made. Gone are <em>Batman: Arkham City</em>, <em>BioShock</em>, <em>Dishonored</em>, <em>Super Street Fighter IV</em>, <em>NBA 2K12 </em>and <em>Assassin’s Creed II</em>. Taking their place are: <em>Borderlands 2</em>, <em>Portal 2</em>, <em>Assassin’s Creed IV: Black Flag</em>, <em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons</em>, <em>Mass Effect 2</em> and <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em></p> <p><strong>Update 11/13/12: </strong>As promised, we’re swapping out older good games from new good games. Goodbye, <em>Lego Star Wars III</em> and <em>Toy Soldiers: Cold War;</em> hello, <em>XCOM</em> and <em>Dishonored</em></p> <p><strong>Note: 12/28/12:</strong> We’re bumping up this list of Xbox 360 Bests for those folks who may have just gotten an Xbox 360 during this holiday season. Some great games have come out for the system since the last update—like <em>Far Cry 3, Halo 4</em> and <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops II</em>. <em>Kotaku</em>’s editorial team considered these games but couldn’t reach a consensus as to whether they deserve a spot just yet. We’re keeping our eyes and minds open as new releases keep hitting Microsoft’s platform.</p> <p><em><strong>Want more of the best games on each system? Check out our complete directory:</strong></em></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-pc-5878852">The Best PC Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-games-for-the-playstation-4-1500350643">The Best PS4 Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-games-for-the-xbox-one-1500422046">The Best Xbox One Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-games-for-the-nintendo-switch-1794881447#_ga=2.216688532.384795882.1500229770-1796887270.1484784940">The Best Nintendo Switch Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-the-wii-u-5971060?tag=the-bests">The Best Wii U Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-3ds-and-2ds-5878903">The Best 3DS Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-the-playstation-vita-5886630">The Best PS Vita Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-xbox-360-5878837">The Best Xbox 360 Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-the-playstation-3-5877932">The Best PS3 Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-the-wii-5878845">The Best Wii Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-the-iphone-5878819">The Best iPhone Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-the-ipad-5878797">The Best iPad Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-android-5878879">The Best Android Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-psp-5878869">The Best PSP Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-facebook-5878915">The Best Facebook Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-the-ds-5878896">The Best DS Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-for-mac-5878890">The Best Mac Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-6-best-games-on-web-browsers-5878907">The Best Browser Games</a> • <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-mods-for-pc-games-5979860">The Best PC Mods</a></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-xbox-360-5878837]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WD 20TB External Hard Drive Goes for Mere Pennies, Now Cheaper Than a SanDisk 4TB SSD]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wd-20tb-external-hard-drive-goes-for-mere-pennies-now-cheaper-than-a-sandisk-4tb-ssd-2000646515</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wd-20tb-external-hard-drive-goes-for-mere-pennies-now-cheaper-than-a-sandisk-4tb-ssd.1361764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>External hard drives solve the eternal problem of running out of storage space on computers that never seem to have enough room for everything you accumulate. Photos, videos, games, backups, and work files consume gigabytes faster than anyone anticipates, and cloud storage subscriptions add up to serious money over time. The WD <em>Elements</em>&nbsp;drive offers a massive 20TB capacity that can handle years of storage needs in a single reliable device. After<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5832/"> launching at $599 before dropping down to the standard price of $349, Amazon just crushed it to $269 for Black Friday</a>. This <strong>record-low pricing is the deepest discount</strong> this popular drive has ever seen.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5832/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>20TB Capacity Eliminates Storage Anxiety Forever</h2>
<p>Twenty terabytes are ample to the extent that <strong>storage management can be forgotten</strong>. You store around 400,000 high-resolution photos, 5,000 hours of HD video, or even complete media libraries that would fill up in decades. The capacity manages full system backups for several computers and still leaves room for ongoing file build-up. This much space turns your relation to digital files from decisions about what to delete to simply hoarding without consequences.</p>
<p>The USB 3.0 interface provides transfer speeds good enough to move big files in fairly reasonable times, considering the mechanical drive inside. You connect to any computer with standard USB ports without requiring special cables, adapters, or driver installations. The plug-and-play functionality means the drive works immediately on Windows and Mac systems out of the box.</p>



<p>The desktop form factor prioritizes capacity and reliability over portability. The drive would sit on your desk, connected to power and USB, serving as a permanent storage expansion rather than as a travel companion. This allows for larger platters and better cooling than portable drives crammed into smaller enclosures.</p>
<p>WD has developed its brand over decades of manufacturing hard drives, and most people associate the company with reliable data storage. The Elements line represents their value-oriented offering, where there is core functionality provided without any premium features that inflate pricing. You get proven WD reliability without paying for software bundles, hardware encryption, or other extras that many users don’t need. The <strong>4.6-star rating across over 332,000 reviews</strong> confirms this reliability extends to real-world usage over years of service.</p>



<p>At this price, the cost per gigabyte beats cloud storage subscriptions within months of ownership. The <strong>cloud plan for 2TB is around $10-15 a month</strong>&nbsp;while equivalent cloud storage would cost hundreds of dollars annually. This drive quickly pays for itself compared to cloud alternatives, and you own the hardware with no recurring fees. Local storage also provides faster access speeds than the internet-dependent cloud services.</p>
<p>Setup involves the<strong> connection of two cables and waiting for your operating system to recognize the new drive</strong>. Windows and Mac both automatically mount the drive without the installation of software or configuration. Drag files to the new drive immediately, and you’re using capacity within minutes of opening the box. The simplicity makes this accessible to anyone regardless of technical expertise.</p>
<p>At $269, you’ll get 20TB of reliable WD storage for more than 50% off its original $599 launch price and 23% off its current list price. The per-terabyte price reaches levels where massive local storage becomes truly affordable. This Black Friday pricing makes the decision to get rid of storage limitations an easy investment that pays dividends for years through avoided cloud subscriptions and permanent file access.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5832/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wd-20tb-external-hard-drive-goes-for-mere-pennies-now-cheaper-than-a-sandisk-4tb-ssd-2000646515]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung 57″ Odyssey Curved Gaming Monitor (240Hz, 1ms) Is $800 Off, Hardcore Gaming’s Holy Grail at a Record Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-57-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-240hz-1ms-is-800-off-hardcore-gamings-holy-grail-at-a-record-low-2000646508</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-57%E2%80%B3-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-240hz-1ms-is-800-off-hardcore-gaming%E2%80%99s-holy-grail-at-a-record-low.1361746/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A 57-inch Dual 4K display with 240Hz refresh rate, 1ms response time, and Quantum Mini-LED backlighting. If those specs made your pulse quicken, you already understand what the <strong>Samsung Odyssey Neo G9</strong> represents. This is the monitor that replaces a dual-screen setup with one massive curved panel delivering 7,680 x 2,160 resolution. DisplayPort 2.1 and AMD Freesync Premium Pro complete a spec sheet that reads like a wish list. And the good news, Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5831/">has slashed the price to $1,499 for Black Friday, down from $2,299</a>. That’s a 35% discount and the lowest this flagship gaming monitor has ever been.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5831/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Best 57-Inch Monitor</h2>
<p>The <strong>57-inch panel gives you two 32-inch 4K monitors fused into one</strong> seamless ultrawide display. No bezels interrupting your view, no alignment issues between screens, and no messing with software to manage multiple inputs. The <strong>dual UHD resolution</strong> means you get the exact same pixel density and clarity across the whole surface. Spreadsheets, video editing timelines, and game worlds all enjoy that ridiculous amount of horizontal space.</p>



<p>The <strong>1000R curvature</strong> wraps the screen around your field of view in a way flat monitors simply cannot replicate. This aggressive curve matches the natural shape of human vision to reduce eye strain during marathon sessions. The edges of the screen stay equidistant from your eyes, which keeps everything in focus without constant head position adjustments. Immersion in racing games and flight simulators goes to a new level.</p>
<p>The backlighting is powered by <strong>Quantum Mini-LED technology that features 2,392 individual local dimming zones</strong>. These zones independently govern their brightness to provide deep blacks alongside brilliant highlights, with no blooming or halo effects. The Quantum Matrix processing drives these zones at 12-bit precision, yielding more than 4,000 levels of brightness gradation. Dark scenes in horror games are rendered with inky shadows, while bright elements pop without washing out the surrounding areas. Traditional edge-lit monitors seem flat and lifeless compared to this.</p>
<p>The DisplayHDR 1000 certification<strong> guarantees 1,000 nits of peak brightness</strong> and a 1,000,000:1 contrast ratio. These numbers equate to visible detail in both the darkest corners and brightest explosions of any game that you play. Enemies that were hiding in the shadows now become visible without cranking gamma settings that wash out everything else. HDR content finally looks the way it was intended by creators when you have hardware capable of showing the full dynamic range. Movies and streaming content also benefit massively from this level of contrast performance.</p>



<p>The<strong> 240Hz refresh rate, combined with a 1ms response time</strong>, means competitive-grade responsiveness on this massive panel. Fast-paced shooters and racing games show fluid motion with no ghosting or blur trails behind moving objects. DisplayPort 2.1 provides the bandwidth necessary to push Dual 4K resolution at these refresh rates with support for variable refresh rates.</p>
<p>Connectivity options cover every scenario you might encounter: <strong>DisplayPort 2.1</strong> handles the heavy lifting for maximum performance gaming, while <strong>HDMI 2.1 ports</strong> connect current-gen consoles at their highest output capabilities. The integrated USB hub reduces cable clutter by letting you plug peripherals directly into the monitor. If you need to monitor different sources, picture-by-picture mode can display two separate inputs simultaneously.</p>
<p>The Samsung Odyssey Neo G9 is an incredible value at $1,499 for such cutting-edge display tech. This Black Friday price knocks off a whopping $800 compared to retail and brings a flagship monitor into reach for serious gamers.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5831/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-57-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-240hz-1ms-is-800-off-hardcore-gamings-holy-grail-at-a-record-low-2000646508]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Philips Hue Is Offloading Its 10ft Smart Lightstrips at 40% Off, Now Cheaper Than No-Name Alternatives]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/philips-hue-is-offloading-its-10ft-smart-lightstrips-at-40-off-now-cheaper-than-no-name-alternatives-2000646503</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/philips-hue-is-offloading-its-10ft-smart-lightstrips-at-40-off-now-cheaper-than-no-name-alternatives.1361725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Smart lighting turns any room from ordinary to extraordinary with a tap of your phone. Philips Hue lightstrips tuck behind TVs, under cabinets, along staircases or around ceiling edges to create ambient glow that sets the perfect mood. The trick is buying several to really tie a space together and Black Friday finally makes that affordable: Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5828/">has dropped the 10-foot <em>Solo</em> light strip to $46, down from $76 (40% off)</a>. This is the lowest price ever recorded and you won’t find Philips Hue discounts anywhere else during this sale period.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5828/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Premium Quality</h2>
<p>Cheap LED strips are flooding the market but Philips Hue earns its reputation through <strong>superior color accuracy and build quality</strong>. That sets this strip apart from basic RGB alternatives that inevitably have issues delivering clean white light. Most budget strips attempt to achieve white tones by blending red, green, and blue LEDs together which is what causes that weird purple or green tint you’ve probably seen. Philips includes dedicated warm and cool white LEDs solely to deliver pure, natural whites alongside the full color spectrum.</p>



<p>Brightness counts when you’re lighting up larger spaces, and the <strong>Philips light strip delivers 1700 lumens of output</strong>. That’s enough to serve as functional accent lighting rather than just decorative glow. You can use it as under-cabinet task lighting in the kitchen or soft ambient illumination behind a media center. The premium silicone sleeve with a milky white finish diffuses the light for even dispersion, eliminating those harsh LED hotspots that make cheaper strips look cheap.</p>
<p>Installation takes minutes with the adhesive backing built into the strip: Just peel off the protective layer, stick it where you want it, and plug it in. You can cut this strip to size for your particular space, but you won’t be able to reconnect the pieces once they’re cut. Do your planning in advance to save a headache. The 10-foot length works perfectly for TV backlighting, bed frames, desk setups, or shorter ceiling runs around a room.</p>
<p>The Philips Hue app unlocks your lightstrip’s full potential once you’re all set up. You can <strong>choose from 16 million colors and adjust brightness levels</strong> to your liking with real precision. Once you start creating scenes that match your activities, it gets addictive: Be it movie nights with a warm orange glow, morning routines with energizing daylight tones or late-night gaming with deep purple ambiance-all in one strip.</p>



<p>Voice control integration through A<strong>lexa, Google Assistant, and Apple Homekit works seamlessly</strong>. Telling your speaker to dim the lights or change colors feels genuinely futuristic the first few times you do it. Hands-free control proves especially useful when you’re cooking, lounging on the couch, or turning in for bed. The lightstrip responds quickly to commands with no noticeable lag. You can also group it with other smart devices for coordinated whole-home automation.</p>
<p>Adding a Philips Hue Bridge extends the functionality of your lightstrip even further: The Bridge enables various forms of automation such as having the lights sync with sunrise and sunset times, or having specific scenes turn on when you arrive home. It offers you much more stable connectivity and allows for control from anywhere through the cloud. Compatible with Matter, your Hue system will work seamlessly with other smart home ecosystems.</p>
<p>At $46, this Philips Hue Solo light strip is a great value in premium smart lighting. You’re getting true RGBWW color accuracy, impressive 1700-lumen brightness, seamless smart home integration, and the reliability of an established brand.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5828/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/philips-hue-is-offloading-its-10ft-smart-lightstrips-at-40-off-now-cheaper-than-no-name-alternatives-2000646503]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11 Memories That Made The Xbox 360 A Console We’ll Never Forget]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-favorite-memories-mw2-bastion-halo-2000646286</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/11-memories-that-made-the-xbox-360-a-console-we%E2%80%99ll-never-forget.1361722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Mountain Dew green colors. The loud marketing campaigns. The Xbox 360 felt like Microsoft trying to <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-mtv-special-20-years-elijah-wood-future-gaming-1851780248">but its way</a> into the console gaming big leagues. Through the unexpected collision of developer-friendly tech, consumer affordability, and digital-first initiatives, the <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-console-update-more-ads-20-years-old-series-x-1851785111">Xbox 360</a> organically bootstrapped its way into being one of the best consoles ever.</p> <p>It didn’t just capture the late 2000s gaming imagination, it defined the zeitgeist and forged experiences that feel as formative as the early days of the NES or PlayStation 1. To mark the console’s 20th anniversary and lasting impact, here are the Xbox 360 memories that still stick with us:</p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>1.</strong> The first time I earned an in-game achievement, something clicked in my brain. I believe it was for completing the training level in </span><i><span>Call of Duty 2</span></i><span>. I remember how nice it felt to get a little pop-up reward from the game. I then spent the next many, many years collecting achievements on Xbox 360, subjecting myself to games like </span><i><span>Full Auto</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Perfect Dark Zero</span></i><span> in the hunt for more points. And while I think achievements aren’t that exciting anymore, I do still love the idea of having this record of things I’ve played and done across now three generations of Xbox consoles. I’m happy every other platform stole this idea, too. (Zack Zwiezen)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>2.</strong> When the incredible </span><i><span>Pac-Man Championship Edition </span></i><span>came out, I became embroiled in a fierce high score battle with a few acquaintances. Every night I’d get home from work to see that one of them had just barely slipped past me, and so I’d lose myself for hours in the neon vibes and clubby beats of its arcade action, relying on pure instinct, trying again and again and again until I finally secured my victory over them on the leaderboards. It was pure arcade bliss. (Carolyn Petit)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>3.</strong> The first and last time I ever ordered a pizza on a video game console happened in 2013. Pizza Hut launched an app on the Xbox 360 and offered a promotion that let you get a pizza for 15 percent off. I ordered a pepperoni pie, stuffed-crust of course, and consumed it while playing B</span><i><span>lack Ops 2.</span></i><span> Little did I know life would rarely be this good again. (Zack Zwiezen)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>4.</strong> My first 360 memory was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-tdu-x360">Tom Bramwell</a> bringing his pre-release machine over to my flat before it was out, and we played <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-condemned-pc"><em>Criminal Oranges</em></a> and <em>Kameo</em> and worried for the machine’s chances. </span><span>But then after that, all <em>Geometry Wars</em>, all the time. (John Walker)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><strong>5.</strong> My girlfriend’s roommate’s boyfriend moved into their apartment during the last year of college. He had an Xbox 360 with <em>Modern Warfare 2</em>. I slept over often staying up with him until one or two in the morning fighting Juggernauts in Special Ops missions and running Model 1887 Akimbo through Terminal while drinking a case of Lion’s Head. <span>(Ethan Gach)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>6.</strong> It might sound silly now, but </span><i><span>Gears of War 3 </span></i><span>is burned into my brain because of one character’s death. Late in the game, spoilers for those who haven’t played it, Dom sacrifices himself to save Marcus and the others from doom. My brother and I had played through the first two games multiple times and had developed a connection with this world and the characters. He was always Dom. I was always Marcus. And there was something oddly compelling and sad about watching my digital brother sacrifice himself to save me. (Zack Zwiezen)</span></p> <hr> <p><strong>7.</strong> I’m still chasing the high of that first <em>Dungeon Defenders</em>. It came to XBLA in late 2011 when I was living in my first apartment after college. My best friend and I were hooked on the tower defense RPG loop, hoovering up crystals and maxing every character. I’ve never played anything as intensely since. <span>(Ethan Gach)</span></p> <hr> <p><span><strong>8.</strong> The foundational memory I have of the Xbox 360 was that, when the box launched in 2005, I wasn’t allowed to play it. My twin brother and I got one the following January because they were on back order, so I spent a couple months staring wistfully at the games we’d bought ahead of time. But I had recently failed my seventh-grade math class with a 64, and rather than investing in tutoring or anything to support me in a subject I clearly struggled with, my mother decided to punish me by not allowing me to play the shiny new console. </span></p>

 <p><span>I still did, obviously. I just waited until my mother went to sleep. I beat </span><i><span>Kameo: Elements of Power </span></i><span>in the dead of night and honed my skills in </span><i><span>Dead or Alive 4</span></i><span> when no one was awake to notice. My mother eventually found out because my local youth minister was a narc and was listening in on every conversation my friends and I were having. But I beat 360 games months earlier than I was supposed to. In retrospect, that was a lot of drama for something so insignificant as a middle school math class. But hey, those late-night play sessions were worth it. (Kenneth Shepard)</span></p> <hr> <p><strong>9.</strong> I borrowed <em>Catherine</em> from a friend and played it at the exact time my girlfriend and I were on a break over my own commitment issues. That precise combination of puzzle platforming panic, existential dread, and demonic nightmares will never leave me. I can still hear the music as Vincent sits in the bar bathroom watching his low-stakes life unravel over text message. <span>(Ethan Gach)</span></p>

 <hr> <p><span><strong>10.</strong><i> Halo 3</i></span>. I don’t think there’s ever going to be a multiplayer experience quite like that one again. I have many good memories of killer matches and chill hang out sessions. But I’ll always remember when folks started spotting players wearing the “Recon” helmet and were obsessed over trying to figure out how to unlock it long before the armor piece became available to the public. Me, being the kind of person I was at the time (and maybe still am?) would often hop onto social, unranked matches to try and convince people I knew how to get the armor. No, I didn’t scam them. I just wasted their time, taking them to various corners of the game’s maps and asking them spin around in circles, empty all their ammo in the corner, stand on top of each other to build a ladder to where I promised them the Recon armor was hiding, or recite strange cryptic sounding sentences I made up on the spot. I’m sorry if you were one of those people whose time I wasted. But it was really, really funny to me. Thanks for the memories. (Claire Jackson)</p> <hr> <p><strong>11.</strong> Waiting for <em>Bastion</em> to come to XBLA’s Summer of Arcade felt like being back in the ’90s. Digital downloads still felt novel. They were giving birth to an entirely new generation of retro-inspired indie giants. I played it my SD TV left over from college up in my parent’s attic during July with no air conditioning. I was still sweating even in the middle of the night as Logan Cunningham raspy voice unfurled a broken world hope, despair, and beautiful colors. It felt like I was looking at the past and the future simultaneously. <span>(Ethan Gach)</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-favorite-memories-mw2-bastion-halo-2000646286]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bose Goes Nuclear, QuietComfort Noise Cancelling Headphones Now Cheaper Than Budget Alternatives]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bose-goes-nuclear-quietcomfort-noise-cancelling-headphones-now-cheaper-than-budget-alternatives-2000646499</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bose-goes-nuclear-quietcomfort-noise-cancelling-headphones-now-cheaper-than-budget-alternatives.1361719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The noise-cancelling headphones market has become incredibly crowded with Sony, Bose, Apple, Sonos and others fighting for your attention. Each brand also offers multiple models at many different price points and if I’m being honest, the differences between them have gotten increasingly tough to justify.</p>
<p>At a certain point, when premium ANC headphones are all performing fantastically, the smartest move is finding the best deal and pulling the trigger. And the great news is <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4702/">that the Bose QuietComfort headphones have dropped to $199 for Black Friday, down from $349</a>. That’s 43% off a legendary pair of cans, and the lowest price Amazon has ever offered on these.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4702/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The Name That Defined Noise Cancellation Still Delivers</h2>
<p><strong>Bose invented the category of consumer noise-cancelling headphones</strong> and has refined the QuietComfort line over decades. That heritage shows in how effortlessly these headphones eliminate ambient noise: the hum of airplane engines, office chatter, city traffic, and noisy coffee shops-all just fade into silence when you put them on. At the same time, the ANC technology automatically changes intensity with your surroundings, increasing or decreasing as needed.</p>



<p>Sound quality lives up to the Bose <strong>reputation for rich, balanced audio</strong>. Deep bass hits with authority without overwhelming mids and highs, which keeps music sounding natural across genres. Acoustic tracks feel intimate while electronic and hip-hop deliver the punch you’d expect. Bose tuned these headphones to sound great out of the box<strong> without requiring EQ adjustments</strong>, though the app lets you tweak things if you want.</p>
<p><strong>With 24 hours of battery life</strong>, you can make it through an entire week of commutes and work sessions on a single charge. When you’re in a rush, a quick 15-minute top-up adds roughly 2.5 hours of playtime. USB-C charging keeps things suitably simple and compatible with the cables you already own. Should you somehow manage to drain the battery completely during a long-haul flight, the headphones also work in wired mode.</p>
<p>Comfort is a huge factor when you’re having to wear headphones for long periods of time, and Bose really nailed the ergonomics here. The<strong> plush ear cushions create a seal without excessive clamping pressure</strong> against your head. The headband distributes weight evenly around your head, so you won’t feel soreness building up after a few hours. It feels premium in terms of build without being heavy, treading a nice line between durability and wearability.</p>



<p>The <strong>on-board microphone handles calls clearly</strong> enough for professional conversations. Colleagues and family members will hear you sans that muffled, distant quality that plagues many Bluetooth headphones. Wind noise reduction helps when you’re taking calls outdoors or in less-than-ideal conditions. It won’t replace a dedicated desktop setup for podcasting, but the mic performs quite well for everyday voice communication.</p>
<p>Bluetooth connectivity has been rock solid in real-world use: <strong>the headphones pair quickly</strong> and connections have remained stable even in busy wireless environments. Multipoint pairing lets you stay connected to two devices at once, perfect for toggling between your laptop and your phone. The Bose app offers further customizations, including adjustable EQ, ANC levels, and shortcut button assignments.</p>
<p>At $199, the Bose QuietComfort headphones are outstanding value in the premium ANC category. You’re getting legendary noise cancellation, refined sound quality, all-day battery life, and exceptional comfort from a brand that pioneered this entire product segment.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4702/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bose-goes-nuclear-quietcomfort-noise-cancelling-headphones-now-cheaper-than-budget-alternatives-2000646499]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EcoFlow Goes Full Chaos Mode on the Delta 2 Power Station, 1800W of Portable Power for Pocket Change]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ecoflow-goes-full-chaos-mode-on-the-delta-2-power-station-1800w-of-portable-power-for-pocket-change-2000646495</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ecoflow-goes-full-chaos-mode-on-the-delta-2-power-station-1800w-of-portable-power-for-pocket-change.1361698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The portable power station market gets fiercely competitive during Black Friday, with brands like <em>Jackery</em> and <em>Anker</em> dropping prices to the $350-400 range. Here’s the thing though: most of those deals cap out at 1,500W output. Ecoflow just <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/">changed the equation by slashing the Delta 2 to $349, down from $699</a> and you’re getting here <strong>1,800W of continuous power</strong> for less than competitors charge for their smaller units. This<strong> 50% discount marks the all-time lowest price</strong> for a power station in this performance class, and it probably won’t last long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Raw Power That Competitors Can’t Match at This Price</h2>
<p>The 1,800W output puts the Delta 2 in a different league than most portable power stations in this price range. That extra 300W compared to 1,500W competitors might sound modest on paper but it opens up a whole new category of appliances you can run. Power-hungry devices like microwaves, coffee makers, and small space heaters suddenly become viable options. The <strong>2,700W surge capacity</strong> handles startup spikes from compressors and motors without breaking a sweat. You’re essentially getting mid-tier performance at entry-level pricing.</p>



<p>The 1,024Wh capacity provides enough juice to keep your essentials running during extended outages or off-grid adventures. A full charge can power a mini fridge for about a day or keep your phones and laptops topped up for a week. Ecoflow designed the Delta 2 to be expandable too, so you can add extra batteries down the line if your needs grow.</p>
<p>LiFePO4 battery chemistry gives the Delta 2 a serious longevity advantage over traditional lithium-ion power stations: This type of battery maintains over <strong>80% capacity after 3,000 charge cycles which translates to roughly a decade of regular use</strong>. The chemistry is also inherently safer with better thermal stability and reduced fire risk. You can store it in your garage or RV without worrying about temperature extremes causing problems.</p>



<p>Charging speed is where EcoFlow really flexes its engineering muscle: The <strong>Delta 2 goes from empty to 80% in just 50 minutes</strong> using a standard wall outlet, with no bulky external brick required. Solar charging maxes out at 500W input, so a couple of panels can fully recharge the unit in a few hours on a sunny day. You can even combine AC and solar charging simultaneously for maximum speed. That rapid turnaround keeps you powered up and ready to go when time matters.</p>
<p>The port selection covers pretty much every charging scenario you might encounter. <strong>Six AC outlets handle your larger appliances and power tools, while the 100W USB-C port delivers laptop-level charging speeds</strong>. Four additional USB-A ports and a 12V car outlet round out the options. Everything can run simultaneously without juggling or prioritizing devices. The built-in display shows real-time input and output wattage along with remaining capacity.</p>
<p>At $349, the EcoFlow Delta 2 delivers unmatched value in the portable power station category. You’re getting 1,800W output, LiFePO4 durability, ultra-fast charging, and expandable capacity for less than competitors charge for inferior specs. This Black Friday deal essentially gives you a $700 power station at half price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5693/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ecoflow-goes-full-chaos-mode-on-the-delta-2-power-station-1800w-of-portable-power-for-pocket-change-2000646495]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govee TV Backlight Is Going for Pocket Change, Netflix Hits Different With Lights That React to Your Screen]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/govee-tv-backlight-is-going-for-pocket-change-netflix-hits-different-with-lights-that-react-to-your-screen-2000646475</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/govee-tv-backlight-is-going-for-pocket-change-netflix-hits-different-with-lights-that-react-to-your-screen.1361677/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For years, Philips Hue dominated the smart lighting space but Govee quietly stole the crown by innovating faster and pricing lower than the legacy giant could match. The brand brings fresh ideas into connected lighting that Hue never considered, <strong>like TV backlights which react in real-time to on-screen content</strong>.</p>
<p>Govee <em>TV Backlight 3 Lite</em> wraps colors around your television that match what you’re watching, crafting immersive viewing that makes regular TVs feel incomplete. Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5825/">dropped this to $46 for Black Friday, down from $69, a record low that brings cinema-style ambiance to any living room</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5825/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Camera Sync Technology Matches Colors Instantly</h2>
<p>It has a <strong>built-in camera that would capture your TV screen and analyze colors in real time</strong> and projects matching hues onto the wall behind. Explosions glow orange across your wall, ocean scenes spread blue throughout the room, and forests extend green beyond the screen edges. This reactive lighting creates immersion that static backlights cannot achieve, pulling you deeper into whatever you’re watching. The fish-eye correction function improves color accuracy along the edges where older systems struggled.</p>



<p>Full compatibility means the system <strong>works with any TV content from whatever source</strong>. Streaming services, cable boxes, gaming consoles, and Blu-ray players all work easily without special setup or compatibility concerns. The camera captures whatever appears on screen without requiring HDMI passthrough or software integration.</p>
<p>This universal approach avoids the frustration of backlights only working with specific apps or devices. Gravitational hanger design facilitates camera installation on ultra-thin TVs, difficult to achieve with traditional mounts. The camera hangs securely, and adhesive stabilization inhibits wobble that would affect color detection accuracy.<strong> Installation takes minutes</strong>&nbsp;as opposed to the complicated mounting other systems require.</p>
<p>Govee <em>DreamView</em> syncing <strong>connects up to seven additional Govee lights for a 360-degree immersive experience</strong>. Floor lamps, table lights, and more from Govee also sync with your TV backlight to extend the color matching of your room.</p>



<p>Smart control via the Govee Home app supports scene modes, eliminates black bars, and detects a blank screen. You’ll be able to change settings, set custom scenes, and fine-tune the experience from the comfort of your couch. Voice control via Alexa and Google Assistant allows for hands-free operation to make any necessary quick adjustments during viewing.</p>
<p>You’re getting camera-synced reactive lighting with fish-eye correction and DreamView compatibility at $46, which is 33% off. Philips Hue Play gradient strips offer less flexibility with similar functionality and will set you back a minimum of US$200. With real-time color matching, multi-device syncing, and universal compatibility, the end result is cinema immersion at a fraction of the premium alternatives.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5825/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/govee-tv-backlight-is-going-for-pocket-change-netflix-hits-different-with-lights-that-react-to-your-screen-2000646475]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’ll Never See A Console Reveal Like The Xbox 360’s Ever Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-mtv-special-20-years-elijah-wood-future-gaming-1851780248</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we%E2%80%99ll-never-see-a-console-reveal-like-the-xbox-360%E2%80%99s-ever-again.1361665/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-best-worst-arcade-games-netflix-store-closing-1851610163">20 years ago on May 12, 2005, the Xbox 360</a> and the future of video games was unveiled on MTV, and it was hosted by Elijah Wood. And while going back to this 20 minute show is a bit embarrassing now, it’s wild how Microsoft and Xbox really did see the future coming before the rest of the industry.</p> <p><em>This article was originally published on May 12, 2025. We’re re-posting it today in honor of the Xbox 360’s 20th anniversary.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>But before we praise <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-celebrates-20th-anniversary-with-a-museum-that-mig-1848113162">Xbox</a> for predicting the online future of games and get really sad at how cosmetic microtransactions were already part of the plan in 2005, let’s make fun of this weird 20 minute infomercial that is the most ‘00s thing ever created. Here’s the full special if you’ve not seen it:</p>

  <p>“Fact: Gaming isn’t just a hobby. It is a lifestyle,” says an unnamed narrator during a short video at the front of the special. It explains video gaming started with <em>Pong</em> and Atari, some other stuff happened, then the original Xbox launched and don’t worry about that thing called the PlayStation.</p>

 <p>After that, the funniest moment in the entire special happens. Remember, up until this point we didn’t know the console was to be called the Xbox 360. It was just the “Next Gen Xbox.” So young Zack, who watched this MTV special back in 2005, was excited to learn more about the next Xbox. Elijah Wood yells, <a href="https://youtu.be/LTs0AoaMYGA?t=166" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“The future of gaming!” and points off screen</a>. The camera cuts to a…woman carrying a gray bag. Can you imagine the online chuds today watching this? Their heads might explode.</p>

  <p>In reality, the woman is carrying the Xbox 360 in her shoulder bag. She saunters up to a podium and pulls out the console. Sets it up. Hits a button. Green lights turn on. And the console’s name is revealed.</p>

 <p>The rest of special is mostly MTV nonsense, celebrities, and The Killers performing music. The only segment that is actually somewhat interesting happens about 11 minutes into the show: Sway from MTV is invited to talk to the designers behind the Xbox 360 and J Allard (one of the OG Microsoft execs behind the Xbox project.) It’s during this segment that we see a bunch of 360 prototypes and learn about why it looks the way it does. And then Allard walks Sway through the idea of buying digital content on a video game console using the internet.</p>

 <p>Today, this is something every device can do. Back in 2005, this was the future. It was hard for young Zack to believe that one day we’d buy games digitally on a console. 20 years later, it’s clear Microsoft was on to something with Xbox Live, the marketplace, a single username that follows you from game to game, and hanging out online with friends in voice chat. Though, the moment when Allard mentions buying clothes for your digital character, I realized microtransactions were being invented in front of my eyes and got sad.</p> <p>At the end of the event, Wood got on stage and signed off by saying: “I think we can all agree on one thing tonight: Xbox 360 is going to be amazing and I look forward to meeting all of you in the Xbox 360 universe.” I never met Elijah Wood online. But I do agree, the Xbox 360 was amazing and will likely be the one and only time Microsoft was at the top of the console gaming market.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-360-mtv-special-20-years-elijah-wood-future-gaming-1851780248]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Goes Savage on Apple, Beats Studio Pro Sinks Nearly 60% Off and Sells for Budget Money]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-savage-on-apple-beats-studio-pro-sinks-nearly-60-off-and-sells-for-budget-money-2000646466</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-goes-savage-on-apple-beats-studio-pro-sinks-nearly-60-off-and-sells-for-budget-money.1361644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Competition in premium headphones has never been as fierce as it is currently with Apple, Sonos, Bose, Sony, and Beats in a heated contest over the over-ear market. Each brand brings legitimate quality to the table which makes choosing sound alone an increasingly difficult decision. The tiebreaker becomes price when comparable products are competing at similar performance, and Beats just made that decision incredibly easy. Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5824/">just crushed the Beats Studio Pro to $149 for Black Friday, down from $349, delivering a 57% discount no competitor can match</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5824/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>40-Hour Battery Life Outlasts Every Competitor</h2>
<p>The <strong>battery endurance is up to 40 hours of playback with active noise cancellation on</strong>, beating what Sony, Bose, and Apple offer at any price. You charge these headphones once and use them for an entire week of commuting, working, and exercising without seeing low battery warnings. The extended runtime transforms how you think about wireless headphones since charging becomes a weekly ritual rather than a daily annoyance. Fast Fuel charging adds 4 hours of playback from just 10 minutes of charging when you forget to plug in overnight.</p>
<p><strong>Lossless audio via USB-C</strong> (paired with compatible sources over cable) provides audio quality that even an audiophile can appreciate. Wired mode switches off Bluetooth compression entirely, ensuring studio-quality playback that simply can’t be replicated by wireless transmission. Three built-in sound profiles allow the listener to tailor the listening experience to the content or personal preference.</p>



<p>This custom acoustic platform creates rich and immersive sound that is on par with many headphones costing considerably more. The bass response remains controlled without bleeding into midrange frequencies, and the vocals sit clearly atop the mix. High frequencies extend smoothly without any harshness to cause fatigue in long listening sessions.</p>
<p><strong>Fully adaptive active noise cancellation continuously adjusts based on your environment</strong> and fit on your head. The system monitors external noise and internal seal and optimizes cancellation in real time as conditions change. Transparency mode lets outside sound through naturally when you need awareness of your surroundings. Switching between modes happens instantly through on-ear controls without interrupting playback.</p>
<p>Personalized spatial audio with <strong>dynamic head tracking provides a fully immersive 360-degree listening experience</strong>. The system interacts with your head movements and adjusts audio placement to maintain the exact positioning of the sound elements, even as you move your head to either side. This technology works with compatible content to accurately place instruments and vocals in three-dimensional space around you.</p>



<p>Improved compatibility<strong> works seamlessly across both Apple and Android ecosystems</strong>. One-touch pairing connects straight away to iPhones via the Apple chip inside, while similar quick-pairing functionality is in place for Android devices. Native features work across the board, unlike some competitors, where specific operating systems receive the best features.</p>
<p>On-ear controls manage music playback, phone calls, and voice assistant activation without reaching for your phone. The physical buttons offer a type of tactile feedback that touch controls can’t compete with, enabling adjustments to be done without looking or removing the headphones. Siri, Google Assistant, or other voice assistants are activated with the press of a button for hands-free queries.</p>
<p>For $149, you get premium noise-cancelling headphones with 40-hour battery life and lossless audio for 57% off of its MSRP, which puts it below budget competition offering far less value. Sony’s WH-1000XM5 and Bose QuietComfort Ultra are $300-$400 options that don’t offer near the same level of battery life.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5824/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-savage-on-apple-beats-studio-pro-sinks-nearly-60-off-and-sells-for-budget-money-2000646466]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portable Gaming Monitor Drops to Nearly Free, Amazon Clears Stock at a Loss for Prime Only]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/portable-gaming-monitor-drops-to-nearly-free-amazon-clears-stock-at-a-loss-for-prime-only-2000646461</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/portable-gaming-monitor-drops-to-nearly-free-amazon-clears-stock-at-a-loss-for-prime-only.1361641/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><strong>Amazon saves its best Black Friday deals for Prime members</strong>, and this portable monitor shows why the membership pays for itself, quite literally. Non-subscribers see regular pricing, while Prime members unlock exclusive discounts that slash products down to absurd lows. The <em>KYY</em> 15.6-inch portable monitor handles both <strong>gaming and productivity with a Full HD IPS display</strong> that travels anywhere your laptop goes. Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4362/">dropped this to $66 for Black Friday, down from $99, but only Prime members access this record low pricing</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4362/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Desktop-Quality Visuals Anywhere</h2>
<p>The <strong>Full HD display gives 1920×1080 resolution for sharp text and clear images throughout the 15.6-inch display</strong> panel. The IPS technology assures accurate colors and consistent brightness from any viewing angle of up to 178 degrees. You see the same image quality whether you look straight on or from the side, which counts if you do group work or adjustable setups. HDR technology enhances contrast between bright and dark areas, making games and movies look more dynamic. The display reduces blue light radiation and eliminates flickering to protect your eyes against fatigue during extended viewing.</p>



<p><strong>USB-C connectivity enables single-cable connections</strong> that handle video signal and power delivery in tandem on compatible devices. You plug in one cable to laptops supporting Thunderbolt 3 or USB-C 3.1, and the monitor works immediately without external power. The two USB-C ports make way for different device connections and cable routing preferences. Mini-HDMI input accommodates devices lacking USB-C video output, ensuring compatibility with older laptops, gaming consoles, and desktop computers.</p>
<p>The<strong> ultra-slim profile of 0.3 inches and a weight of 1.7 pounds</strong>&nbsp;make this portable, rather than just technically portable. You slip this into a laptop bag beside your computer without adding any noticeable bulk or weight. The slim build fits in the same compartments as tablets or thin ultrabooks do. This kind of portability changes the way you think about workspace setup, as bringing a second monitor along becomes simple.</p>



<p>The <strong>included smart cover protects the screen</strong> during transport and converts into an adjustable stand for desktop use. Being budget-friendly, the exterior uses PU leather that resists scratches and feels premium. Two grooves in the bottom of the cover provide different viewing angles for comfort with multiple setups. The magnetic frameless design of this keeps the cover attached securely without adding bulk or interfering with the display.</p>
<p><strong>Compatibility with gaming consoles</strong> extends the monitor’s usability beyond laptop productivity. You hook up a Playstation 4, Xbox, or Switch directly to this for portable big-screen gaming anywhere. Hotel rooms, guest bedrooms, or any space with a power outlet becomes a gaming station. The native 1080p resolution of the console output is matched and color accuracy from the IPS panel is better than many hotel TVs.</p>
<p><strong>Connectivity to your smartphone transforms the monitor into a desktop experience</strong> for your mobile device. You will connect compatible phones via USB-C and expand your mobile workspace into a proper screen size. This feature works great for presentations, video watching, or using mobile apps on larger displays. You need no apps or drivers for this setup; it works immediately via plug-and-play functionality.</p>
<p>Built-in dual speakers provide audio without requiring external speakers or headphones. The sound quality handles video calls, casual entertainment, and basic gaming adequately. <strong>A 3.5mm audio jack</strong> houses headphones or external speakers when you need better audio quality. The speakers add in convenience for quick setups where carrying additional audio equipment isn’t practical.</p>
<p>At $66 for Prime members, you’re getting a full-featured portable monitor with an IPS panel, smart cover, and multi-device compatibility for 34% off. Competing portable monitors with similar specs sell for $100-150 without the included accessories.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4362/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/portable-gaming-monitor-drops-to-nearly-free-amazon-clears-stock-at-a-loss-for-prime-only-2000646461]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Goes Hard on Watch Ultra 2, Now Selling at New All-Time Low for Black Friday Day 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-goes-hard-on-watch-ultra-2-now-selling-at-new-all-time-low-for-black-friday-day-2-2000646455</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-goes-hard-on-watch-ultra-2-now-selling-at-new-all-time-low-for-black-friday-day-2.1361626/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For a long, long time, the premium adventure watch market was dominated by Garmin and Suunto, but then Apple came to the party with the <em>Ultra</em> series and hasn’t looked back since. The <strong>Apple Watch Ultra 2 competes directly with flagship models from both brands</strong>&nbsp;and adds in smartphone integration that those dedicated sports watches just can’t match.</p>
<p>Apple keeps strict pricing on their own website and in Apple Stores, so it’s a complete waste of your time checking there for deals. But Amazon<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5821/"> just dropped the Ultra 2 to $599 for Black Friday, down from $799, which marks a record low and saves you $200 on Apple’s most rugged wearable</a>. This 25% discount is the deepest cut this watch has ever seen.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5821/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Titanium Construction Survives Everything You Throw at It</h2>
<p>A <strong>49mm case made of titanium</strong> resists corrosion and impacts that would destroy aluminum watches within months of serious outdoor use. The sapphire front crystal laughs at scratches regular glass couldn’t survive, maintaining clarity through years of adventure abuse. Verification through military standard MIL-STD 810H testing shows the watch handles extreme temperatures, shocks, and conditions that exceed those most users ever encounter. <strong>Water resistance reaches a depth of 100 meters</strong>, enabling serious diving alongside swimming and water sports.</p>
<p>The 49mm size provides space for a bigger battery and a more luminous display than standard Apple Watch models have. The <strong>Always-On Retina display peaks at 3000 nits of brightness</strong>, and remains readable under direct sunlight where other screens totally wash out. The larger Digital Crown and customisable Action button work with gloves on, as well as in cold weather where touch-only controls fail.</p>



<p>Precision<strong> dual-frequency GPS</strong> delivers accuracy that serious athletes and navigators require. By utilizing both L1 and L5 satellite frequencies, the system reduces errors from signal reflection off buildings and terrain. The recorded routes of your runs better match the actual paths you run, rather than placing you directly through buildings or zigzagging all over.</p>
<p>The running features compete directly with dedicated running watches from Garmin and Coros. Advanced metrics track running form, including ground contact time, vertical oscillation, and stride length. Automatic track detection senses when you’re running on a standard track and makes adjustments accordingly. Support for custom workouts accommodates structured training, like warmups, intervals, recovery periods, and cooldowns. Training load analysis shows how your workouts are affecting your body over time to help you avoid overtraining.</p>



<p><strong>Cellular connectivity lets you leave your iPhone behind</strong> while maintaining communication capabilities. You call, text, stream music, get directions, and access apps without your phone nearby. That sense of freedom completely changes outdoor activities where carrying a phone would add bulk or create risk. Emergency SOS works anywhere with cellular coverage, providing safety during solo adventures.</p>
<p>That means <strong>battery life reaches 36 hours of normal use with the Always-On display active</strong>, extending to 72 hours of runtime in Low Power Mode for multi-day adventures. This is considerably beyond the typical Apple Watch models and closer to what dedicated adventure watches can manage. The extended battery life makes the Ultra 2 a practical choice for ultra-long hikes, ultra-marathons and multi-day trips in general.</p>
<p>Health monitoring includes tracking heart rate, the measurement of blood oxygen, ECG capability, and sleep analysis. Fall detection and crash detection provide automatic emergency alerts in case of accidents. Temperature sensing tracks overnight variations useful for cycle tracking and illness detection. All of these features run continuously without affecting battery life much.</p>
<p>At $599, you’re getting Apple’s flagship adventure watch with titanium construction and precision GPS for 25% off its standard price. Comparable Garmin watches cost between $800-1000 without the smartphone integration that Apple provides.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5821/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-goes-hard-on-watch-ultra-2-now-selling-at-new-all-time-low-for-black-friday-day-2-2000646455]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>