<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:37:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Is Getting A New Map But Players Have To Work To Unlock It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-stella-montis-community-shredder-matriarch-2000643465</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-is-getting-a-new-map-but-players-have-to-work-to-unlock-it.1351195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Since the game launched on October 30, one map on <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ rotation has remained locked. That’s about to change. The mysterious “Stella Montis” map will soon be available following a community event to unlock it. And when players arrive, there’ll be new Arc to contend with. They don’t sound friendly. The new community event kicks off tomorrow, November 13, 2025. Here’s everything you need to know.</p>

 <p>Developer Embark Studios has revealed what’s in store for <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ first major post-launch content update and community event (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-first-major-update-north-line-goes-live-tomorrow-heres-what-to-expect">h/t <i>IGN</i></a>). But before anyone can step foot on the new frontier of Stella Montis, players will have to work for it via “Breaking New Ground,” described as a “multi-phase community event leading to a Stella Montis unlock.”</p>

 <p>There aren’t too many details about what, exactly, players will be doing during the event. But the developer has promised “rare resources, new gameplay items, and potential weapon blueprints.” The event will feature its own currency, “Merits,” and will only be available until December.</p> <p>Once accessible, Stella Montis will be home to an exclusive Arc, the Shredder. Embark describes the threat as something that will force “Raiders to stay sharp in close-quarters encounters.” Good news for those tired of shooting drones and rolly things that go pop. Other than that, the “Matriarch” Arc is being described as a “hulking Arc that makes the Queen look friendly.”</p> <p>Oh. How joyous.</p> <p>The new community event goes live on November 13 at 10:30 A.M. EST.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-stella-montis-community-shredder-matriarch-2000643465]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Lowering Skin Prices And Issuing Refunds After Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-skins-cosmetics-decks-battle-pass-duos-2000643456</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-lowering-skin-prices-and-issuing-refunds-after-backlash.1351192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>While <i>Arc Raiders</i> certainly isn’t alone in featuring paid cosmetics and, soon, battle passes, the game has come under fire from fans since launch for its pricey skins and concerns that some items in the upcoming premium battle passes will be “pay-to-win.” In a blog post outlining some pricing changes, however, developer Embark Studios is responding to player feedback and concern, lowering prices on existing cosmetics and clarifying what fans can expect when premium battle passes arrive.</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-gifts-premium-currency-after-server-struggles-2000640888">Backlash against expensive skin pricing</a> in <i>Arc Raiders</i> swiftly followed the game’s release on October 30. With the game selling for $40 rather than being free-to-play, fans weren’t too happy about skins in the premium store costing half that. Meanwhile, the limited customization options associated with cheaper items like face paints have seemed to discourage folks from getting too excited over them.</p>

 <p>But <a href="https://arcraiders.com/en/news/duo-and-store-update/">according to an official blog post</a> today, Embark Studios is lowering prices on skins and refunding folks (in premium currency) who purchased them at the older, more expensive price. Furthermore, the studio has clarified that any usable gameplay items found in upcoming battle passes will be in the free versions available to all players. “The focus for premium [battle passes] are based on cosmetics and convenience,” the developer wrote.</p>

 <p>As some fans have pointed out, since you can lose gear in an extraction shooter just as easily as you can find it, gameplay items in a premium battle pass wouldn’t be locked to a player and thus wouldn’t be as unfair in theory, but it’s still nice to see the game avoid any accusations of being pay-to-win.</p>

 <h2>Duo matchmaking was secretly enabled</h2> <p>Since launch, players have asked for duo-only matchmaking, allowing pairs of folks to venture out into games populated by other pairs. Embark Studios confirmed that it has “silently tested and enabled Duo prioritized matchmaking” earlier this week. While it cautioned that “you may [still] run into differing constellations of players other than your own,” the developer described the matchmaking system like this:</p> <blockquote><p>First, we prioritize Solos and Squads to play separately. After that, we prioritize Duos to play with other Duos, and for Trios to play with Trios.</p></blockquote> <p>As a solo player, I haven’t been too bothered by mismatched player counts in squads out there, but hopefully this will help balance out PvP skirmishes in the near future.</p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-skins-cosmetics-decks-battle-pass-duos-2000643456]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ Just Hit a Price Apple Would Never Offer, Selling Out Fast After 10K+ Units Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/snag-the-top-rated-11-inch-samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-for-under-150-with-this-deal-2000643098</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-just-hit-a-price-apple-would-never-offer-selling-out-fast-after-10k-units-sold.1351138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A tablet can come in handy when your phone feels too small, but you don’t want to carry your laptop around. These screens are great for being productive on the go, and even keeping your kids entertained (for a while at least). That said, you don’t always have to spend $300+ to get something that’s powerful enough to get through your busy days, yet easy to carry around.</p>
<p>Thankfully, early Black Friday deals are already rolling in, making it easy to grab a high-end option without paying the full price. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/">Amazon has now dropped the price of the 11-inch Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ to just $149, after a massive 32% off its regular price of $220.</a> This deal applies to the Graphite model, but if you prefer the Silver version, that one’s just a dollar more at $150. The only catch? It’s already selling fast, and stock might run out before the deal ends. It’s best to grab it while it’s still live!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>



<h2>Portable, Yet Powerful</h2>
<p>This sleek tablet comes with an 11-inch screen that’s big enough to open multiple windows side-by-side without feeling cramped. The WUXGA display (1920 x 1200) pushes vibrant, detailed visuals that bring content to life, whether you’re playing a game or watching a TV show. The 90Hz refresh rate keeps everything running smoothly, while the 480 nits of brightness ensure you experience exceptional clarity in both bright and dim settings.</p>
<p>Of course, good visuals are only half the experience. You will also enjoy quality sound with the tablet’s quad-speaker setup with Dolby Atmos support. Every movie dialog (even the whispers) will come through clearly, kids’ songs are going to sound better, and even video calls will feel more natural. Speaking of video calls, there’s a solid front camera as well, which makes you look your best while catching up with family and friends.</p>



<p>For power, the Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ packs a Snapdragon 695 processor, paired with <strong>4GB of RAM </strong>and<strong> 64GB of internal storage</strong>. That’s enough for some light multitasking, plus storing all your important files or media content in one place. If you ever need more space, you can always expand it up to 1TB with a microSD card.</p>
<p>It supports Smart View, which means you can cast your screen to a Samsung TV whenever you want to enjoy a bigger viewing experience, easily. And finally, the battery also lasts all day, plus charges back up quickly when you need it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/snag-the-top-rated-11-inch-samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-for-under-150-with-this-deal-2000643098]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s 40″ Fire TV Already Matches Last Year’s Black Friday Price, Practically Free Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazons-40-fire-tv-already-matches-last-years-black-friday-price-practically-free-right-now-2000643064</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon%E2%80%99s-40%E2%80%B3-fire-tv-already-matches-last-year%E2%80%99s-black-friday-price-practically-free-right-now.1351087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’re in mid November which can only mean one thing. It’s time to lock in and get done all your holiday shopping for your friends, family, and loved ones. While we’re still a couple short weeks out from the big savings events of the season happening over Black Friday weekend and the following Cyber Monday, that doesn’t mean you can find some excellent deals right now in the meantime. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5477/">Amazon happens to have its 2-Series 40-inch Fire TV on sale for a solid 40% off.</a> That actually takes the price down from it’s starting level of $250 down to just $150. You end up saving an even $100 for a limited time.</p>
<p>Now let’s set the expectations when it comes to this display. This isn’t some expensive OLED TV which can go for multiple thousands of dollars. You can still get a picture that’s fairly big, displays in high definition, and has a wide color gamut without having to take out a second mortgage on your home. This 1080p 43-inch TV has support for HDR 10, HLG, and Dolby Digital Audio which can further enhance your image and sound quality.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5477/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>



<p>Fire TV let’s you keep all of your entertainment in one place. You’ll have access to apps for all your favorite streaming services ranging from Netflix to Prime Video to Disney Plus, so long as you have the proper subscription. At a default, with no extra charge, you have access to a ton of free streaming content as well. Watch TV show episodes and movies for free over on various apps like YouTube, Tubi, Pluto TV, and more.</p>
<h2>Alexa-enabled</h2>
<p>Being an Amazon product, the remote for this TV is built with Alexa voice support. All you need to do is just hold down the button of the little microphone and speak into it the title of the movie or TV show you’re looking to watch. That’s significantly easier than trying to type out the entire phrase, “<em>The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford</em>,” one letter at a time on those on-screen keypads. Just speak it into the remote and you’re there.</p>



<p>The TV is equipped with two standard HDMI inputs, allowing you to connect to a gaming console, cable box, or satellite service provider. One of the inputs is HDMI ARC which allow for pairing with audio equipment like a soundbar for advanced sound.</p>
<p>Speaking of sound, this Fire TV even supports wireless Bluetooth listening. You can pair a set of headphones for private listening when you don’t want to disturb others you share the space with.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5477/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazons-40-fire-tv-already-matches-last-years-black-friday-price-practically-free-right-now-2000643064]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>