<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:58:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MacBook Air M4 Price Played Yoyo Lately, But Now Goes to New Record Low Price on Amazon Only]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/macbook-air-m4-price-played-yoyo-lately-but-now-goes-to-new-record-low-price-on-amazon-only-2000654145</link>
            <guid>1385752</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>MacBook Air pricing has bounced around considerably on Amazon over the past few weeks while Apple’s own store maintained full retail pricing. Right now, the <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/">2025 MacBook Air with the M4 chip and 256GB storage sits at a record low of $749 on Amazon, down from its standard $999 price tag</a>, which beats even last week’s previous record of $799. Shipping estimates show <strong>delivery arriving after Christmas</strong> but before New Year’s, so this works perfectly as a self-gift or for anyone who doesn’t need the laptop wrapped under the tree on December 25th.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>M4 Chip Performance</h2>
<p>The M4 chip is Apple’s fourth generation of custom silicon and makes things go faster than the M3 in both single-core tasks and long-term workloads. The built-in GPU runs graphically demanding games and 3D rendering tasks smoothly while using just the right amount of power to keep that famous MacBook Air battery life. Apple’s unified memory architecture lets the CPU and GPU share the 16GB of RAM without the problems that come with traditional memory systems that are separate.</p>
<p>You can use it for up to 18 hours on a single charge which means you can get through a full workday, an international flight, or a long study session without having to look for outlets. You won’t notice any performance changes when you’re plugged in or running on battery power alone because many Windows laptops slow down when they’re not plugged in. The M4 lasts a long time because it is efficient, not because it has huge batteries inside and keeps the laptop very thin and light at only 2.7 pounds.</p>



<p>The 13.6-inch Liquid Retina display supports one billion colors and has amazing picture quality that makes videos and graphics stand out with deep contrast and accurate color reproduction. The high pixel density makes text very clear, which makes it easier on the eyes when you read or write for a long time. The screen can get as bright as 500 nits, so you can work comfortably in bright places or near windows without having to squint to see what’s on the screen. The edge-to-edge glass and thin bezels give you the most screen space possible while keeping the laptop’s small size, which makes it easy to fit into bags and backpacks.</p>
<p>Apple Intelligence integration throughout macOS adds AI-powered features that help you write and automate tasks that you do over and over again without sending your data to external servers. The M4’s neural engine runs the system locally, so your personal information stays on your device instead of being processed in the cloud, where it could be accessed or compromised. Privacy protections keep even Apple from seeing your data.</p>



<p>Connectivity has all the basics with two Thunderbolt 4 ports that can be used for charging, data transfer and display connections through one flexible interface. MagSafe charging is back, and it has a magnetic connection that safely comes apart if someone trips over the cable instead of pulling your laptop to the floor. The headphone jack works with wired headphones or external speakers without needing dongles. Wi-Fi 6E and Bluetooth 5.3 make sure that networks and peripherals can connect quickly over wireless. The laptop can connect to up to two external displays and turns it into a powerful workstation when you’re at a desk but still being portable when you need to work somewhere else.</p>
<p>Right now, you can get Apple’s newest laptop generation for $749 instead of $999 and this is a savings of $250. This price makes the 2025 MacBook Air competitive with mid-range Windows laptops that look cheaper on paper but have worse build quality, shorter battery life, and less powerful processors.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/macbook-air-m4-price-played-yoyo-lately-but-now-goes-to-new-record-low-price-on-amazon-only-2000654145]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Pushes Final Clearance on Wireless Controllers (2025), Even Lower Than Black Friday as Stock Runs Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-pushes-final-clearance-on-wireless-controllers-2025-even-lower-than-black-friday-as-stock-runs-low-2000653990</link>
            <guid>1385746</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If there’s an Xbox showing up under your tree and you’re going to have more than one very eager gamer dying to get at it, we’re about to save you from a potentially sticky situation. The Xbox consoles come with only one controller. Thankfully there’s still time to get a second controller to avert the epic sibling clashes that come from attempts at sharing, and it’s <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/">the 2025 model Xbox Wireless Gaming Controller in Carbon Black, on sale at Amazon for a sweet 42% off.</a></p>
<p>This is the model that comes with the Xbox console, so you’re also avoiding the “why can’t I use the cooler controller” fights — you would have two identical cool controllers that look good, play great, and come with a long list of great features and customizations. Even if your console is going to a solo gamer, buying a backup controller while it’s just $38 — down from $65 — is a super smart move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Console, PC, Smartphone…</h2>
<p>Surprisingly, one of the best features of the Xbox Wireless Gaming Controller is how much use you get out of it&nbsp;<em>apart</em> from the Xbox. It’s an Xbox controller that’s widely compatible away from the console, able to hook up via Bluetooth or with a USB-C cable to Android and iOS devices, Windows PCs, Fire TV Sticks, Smart TVs, and VR headsets. For compatible gaming headsets, there’s a 3.5mm audio jack built into the Xbox controller. While they’re just $38, you can make a solid case for picking up an Xbox Wireless Controller even if you don’t have an Xbox console.</p>
<p>Regardless of which platform you’re using the Xbox Wireless Controller for, you’re going to deeply appreciate its design for both performance and comfort. The curved design is intended to fit your hands with maximum comfort and control, and there’s a textured grip finish on the triggers, bumpers, and back case so you’re not missing those key moves or shots because your hand slipped off. The new hybrid D-pad is another new enhancement.</p>



<h2>Customize, Play, Share</h2>
<p>Customization is key if you want to make the Xbox Wireless Controller play the way you truly want it to, and that’s now easily done with the custom mapping feature that’s part of the Xbox Accessories app. Custom mapping lets you program the buttons the way you want, as many times as you want. One button you will not be wanting to alter, however, is the Share button that lets you capture screenshot, recordings, and more from your gaming adventures, and then share them with friends.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/">The number of reasons to go to Amazon and buy an Xbox Wireless Controller while it’s just $38 far outnumber the excuses not to</a>. Even if it doesn’t arrive until after Christmas, it’s going to be very well received, and used on a daily basis for years to come.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-pushes-final-clearance-on-wireless-controllers-2025-even-lower-than-black-friday-as-stock-runs-low-2000653990]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>