<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:04:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Boss Says Only ‘Terminally Online Culture Warriors’ Care About Controversies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-boss-terminally-online-culture-warriors-controveries-gay-repersenation-2000658501</link>
            <guid>1401970</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The boss behind the studio that developed one of 2025’s best RPGs, <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-swen-vincke-larian-bruce-straley-ai-warhorse-2000654591">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a>,</em> says that online controversies about the game and its predecessor involving representation likely didn’t hurt the game’s sales and only mattered to “a handful” of people who are online 24/7.</p> <p>Some quick history. <a href="https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-the-kotaku-review-1823606430">In 2017, in the lead-up to the launch of </a><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance,</em> developer Warhorse Studios was criticized by some online for not including people of color in the game. The studio defended this by claiming it was <a href="https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-owes-its-popularity-to-realism-and-conserv-1823420208">historically accurate</a> that in early 15th-century Bohemia, especially in the countryside where the game was set, it was rare to see non-white people. Some scholars agreed, others weren’t sure, and people online yelled about it, with some right-leaning gamers very invested in protecting the studio from the “woke agenda.” Fast forward to 2025, when a lot of the people who had previously defended Warhorse’s dedication to historical accuracy were now mad that the studio was including more people of color. The studio explained that it made sense as the sequel involved a large city that would have brought in more people from around the world. There were also some folks angry about the ability to have a gay relationship.</p>

 <p>So, did any of this controversy affect the game sales? <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/attacks-on-kingdom-come-deliverance-for-gay-romance-representation-only-mattered-to-a-handful-of-terminally-online-culture-warriors-reckons-kcd2s-exec-producer-and-probably-didnt-impact-the-games-reception/">That’s what <em>PC Gamer</em> recently asked</a> Martin Klíma, Warhorse’s co-founder and the executive producer on <em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>“I would really, really like to know the answer to this one. You can really convincingly argue both ways,” Klíma told the outlet. “You can convincingly argue that we got some extra visibility—that it doesn’t matter what they say about you, as long as they spell your name right.” At the same time, he said, you could argue that “any controversy is hurtful, and you want to speak about the game, and you don’t want to explain some…tangled reasoning.”</p>

 <p>Klíma further explained that he personally felt that the online controversies surrounding both games “only mattered to, really, a handful of terminally online culture warriors” and believed that they are “an insignificant intersection with the gaming public writ large.”</p>

 <p>“The real players really don’t care about it at all, and probably most of them never really even heard about these pseudo-controversies,” said Klíma.</p> <p>Considering the fact that <em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</em> has sold over 10 million copies since 2017, and that its sequel has already sold over four million, I think Klíma might be right. It’s a good reminder that most people aren’t online as much as your favorite journalists, content creators, or posters. That’s not to say they don’t care about things like representation, but they aren’t really hearing about most of this stuff, and instead are just buying that game that people said was good or that has a cool cover. Honestly, I’m jealous.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-boss-terminally-online-culture-warriors-controveries-gay-repersenation-2000658501]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Would You Pay Over $1,000 For A Steam Machine?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-machine-price-leak-division-3-fable-ps5-2000658489</link>
            <guid>1401889</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Valve is supposed to reveal pre-order options for the <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-machine-valve-console-price-ps5-pro-2000643554">Steam Machine</a> in early 2026 but PC gaming prices are getting out of control. Ubisoft is already hyping up <em>The Division 3</em>. And a mystery game is set to appear at the first Xbox showcase of 2026. <em>Pentiment 2</em>? It’s another edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture.</p> <p>While it’s been the case for years now that physical games come with almost nothing inside the case but the disc, I still feel a brutal pang of disappointment <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/1q7a7rg/the_excitement_of_opening_up_a_video_game_sure/">every time I encounter it</a>. I recently bought a handful of discounted games <a href="https://kotaku.com/rpg-sale-cheap-ff12-kingdom-come-2-ps5-switch-2000653958">over the holidays</a> and while their presence on my shelves pleases me, I can’t totally shake the disturbing void hiding within. It makes the rare game that does come packed full of inserts <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-binding-of-isaac-on-nintendo-switch-has-a-gorgeous-1793423566">all the more special</a>.</p>

 <h2>A Czech retailer has placeholder pricing for the Steam Machine starting at $950</h2> <p><a href="https://clawsomegamer.com/retailer-leak-puts-steam-machine-price-at-over-1000/">Clawsomegamer discovered</a> the detail in the source code for the web listing at Smarty.cz. That’s not an official retail partner for the device, making it extra unlikely that this is actually reflective of Valve’s pricing strategy rather than retailers just inserting placeholder guesstimates (Smarty.cz has $1,070 for the 2TB version). Still, it does have people worried about what kind of sticker shock they might eventually see as recent RAM shortages propel PC gaming component prices <a href="https://kotaku.com/asus-rog-ally-price-increase-nvidia-amd-ai-ps6-delay-2000656448">through the roof</a> at the start of 2026.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Big grain of salt:</p> <p>A Czech retailer (<a href="https://t.co/XIPdLHBOif">https://t.co/XIPdLHBOif</a>) has already put up a preliminary listing for the upcoming Valve Steam Machine (512GB) 👀</p> <p>The product page doesn't display a public price yet, but checking the site's source code via browser developer tools reveals a… <a href="https://t.co/QRqJxbnT6x">pic.twitter.com/QRqJxbnT6x</a></p> <p>— Clawsomegamer (@Clawsomegamer) <a href="https://twitter.com/Clawsomegamer/status/2009619612280017118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Valve previously promised to reveal more information about its new living room console early this year, but those plans could be pushed back if the current supply chain issues are making it harder to get the first wave of devices manufactured at an affordable price point. While Valve has hinted that Steam Machines would be priced more like a gaming PC than a $500 console, no one knows if that means closer to $700 or closer to $1,000. The company <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-machine-price-console-linus-skillup-valve-2000646965">did hint that it’s not going to be</a> using profits from Steam to subsidize the price.</p>

 <h2>An Xbox showcase later this month hides a mystery game reveal</h2> <p>A fourth game at the Dev Direct taking place on January 22 was first teased <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-studios-bethesda-abk-ot36-oops-all-obsidian.1310962/page-215#post-149812867">by Shinobi602</a>.&nbsp;VGC corroborated the hint and <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/the-xbox-developer-direct-will-feature-a-secret-unannounced-fourth-game/">reports</a> that the mystery release is “a smaller-scale original game from one of Xbox Game Studios’ first-party developers.” That suggests it could be a side project in the mold of Obsidian Entertainment’s <em>Pentiment</em>.</p>

 <h2><em>Fable</em> will come to PS5, too</h2> <p>But there’s more! Alongside<em> Forza Horizon 6</em> and Game Freak’s <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>, both already confirmed for PS5, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/the-xbox-developer-direct-will-feature-a-secret-unannounced-fourth-game/"><em>VGC</em> also reports</a> that <em>Fable</em> is in development for the Sony platform as well. Xbox exclusivity is dead, yes, but the question remains whether Microsoft will push to start getting these multiplatform releases out day-and-date or still stagger them where it sees fit.</p>

 <h2><em>Helldivers 2</em> kicks off its deadliest year yet</h2> <p>Strange new Illuminate structures <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1q7mfl4/new_squid_structures_23_seconds_into_star_of/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=post_title&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/after-helldivers-2-boss-teased-death-and-destruction-in-upcoming-update-new-illuminate-structures-ominously-appear-in-a-blink-and-youll-miss-it-moment-in-super-earth-media/">are popping up</a> in the extraction shooter after Arrowhead Game Studios promised players that 2026 would be even bloodier for the forces of space fascism. “A lot of Helldivers will die,” CEO Shams Jorjani recently teased on the game’s Discord when talking about the studio’s upcoming plans. Arrowhead will have its work cut out for it after fans spent the early part of last summer <a href="https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-eos-prosperity-china-steam-reviews-1851782983">beating back an invasion of Super Earth</a>.</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Where Winds Meet</em> starts 2026 off strong</strong></h2> <p>The surprise open-world hit on console and PC has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IfrGu8nZ3i8">dropped its 1.2 update</a> that adds a new boss fight, Guild Battles, and other activities ahead of additional chapters coming later this month and next.</p> <h2><em>The Division 3</em> is shaping up to be a “monster”</h2> <p>That’s according to executive producer Julian Gerighty. “It’s shaping up to be a monster,” he told fans in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SCiMJQkjV2M">new Ubisoft vidoc</a>. “I can’t really say anything more than that. But within these walls [at] Massive, we are working extremely hard on something that I think will [have] as big an impact as <em>The Division 1</em> was.” There’s no release date in sight for the sequel and Massive is still producing new content for <em>The Division 2</em>. Finding a way to combine the innovation and novelty of the first game with the gameplay polish and scope of the second could be a recipe for something special. Also something that takes a long time to make.</p> <h2>Warner Bros. Games has laid off staff at its San Francisco studio</h2> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tonyperkins14_hey-everyone-at-the-end-of-the-month-my-activity-7403888579174916096-pS9-?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAoO_OkB-VfPR7dhiZ-PZ-9sf_EfWliEy1k"><em>Game Developer</em> reports</a> that an unknown number of staff at the mobile studio that works on games like <em>DC Worlds Collide</em> were fired back in December.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/hooded-horse-gen-ai-art-ban-4x-strategy-steam-2000658179">Hooded Horse CEO “fucking hates” gen AI art and bans it from the strategy publisher’s games</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-christmas-holiday-sales-down-europe-uk-us-nintendo-2000658223">The Switch 2 had a rough holiday season despite tons of new exclusives&nbsp;</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-minigames-remake-trilogy-3-game-2000658234"><em>FFVII Rebirth</em>‘s director explains why they went all-in on mini-games</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steam-machine-price-leak-division-3-fable-ps5-2000658489]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian Explains Why Baldur’s Gate 3’s Most Underserved Companion Felt Shortchanged]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-wyll-rewrite-cut-content-scene-story-2000658493</link>
            <guid>1401886</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The companions who join you on </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491"><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i></a><span>’s </span><i><span>epic journey along the Sword Coast</span></i><span> are a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-video-game-characters-of-2023-1851085884"><span>wonderful bunch</span></a><span>, but one character definitely got the short end of the stick: Wyll. The Warlock was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-character-creator-bear-romance-wyll-1850616671"><span>famously rewritten</span></a><span> ahead of the game’s launch in 2023 when developer Larian decided his story in the early access release wasn’t quite working. Some things stayed the same, such as his character design, Warlock status, and where the player would ultimately recruit him, but his story was completely revamped, his voice actor was changed, and he was given ties to other characters, such as Tiefling party member Karlach.</span></p> <p><span>In </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1q870w5/comment/nylf1wn/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=comment_embed&amp;utm_content=whitespace&amp;embed_host_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thegamer.com%2Fbaldurs-gate-3-lack-of-wyll-content-larian-response%2F"><span>an ongoing Reddit AMA</span></a><span>, the team at Larian provided some insight into the process and also explained why Wyll has notably less content than other party members as a result. It turns out Wyll’s story was finally coming together right when most other members of the player’s traveling party were being solidified, and some storylines the team planned on implementing him into ended up being cut. Senior writer Kevin VanOrd also explains that he had health issues during some of those iteration phases, which meant that he lost precious time that was meant to be spent fleshing out Wyll’s role. Overall, it sounds like VanOrd loves the character but wishes he could have done more with him.</span></p>

 <blockquote><p><span>As you probably know, we weren’t connecting with Wyll’s Early Access recruitment and initial questing, so we started over at a point when most of the other companion stories were fairly solid. A lot of decisions came later in development than was ideal – and there was a key situation near Baldur’s Gate that I intended to heavily involve Wyll in (the Red War College) that got cut. That meant back to the drawing board again. We eventually tied him to Duke Ravengard and started to work on that element of his arc just in time for me to get unexpectedly ill. I was out of the office for quite a while, and again after the epilogue’s release.</span></p> <p><span>I think that Ansur’s lair was Swen’s idea – we did have the resources for a standalone dungeon, so we got to work on tying Wyll to the Wyrmway, but I couldn’t get more than a dungeon boss out of it. Once the situations were in place, that was that – I had to start writing them.</span></p> <p><span>Wyll’s content is sparser than I’d have liked as a result. He’s also split into two stories, really – the Mizora story and the Ravengard story, and that might have been a mistake in hindsight. I also wish I could [have] given him a stronger endpoint – it always bugged me that he can end up just as he started, as the Blade of Frontiers, without any meaningful difference. All that said, I love the Blade and I am really proud of him, his sincerity, his good nature, and his eager heroism. I’m truly sorry I didn’t give you more quality time with him.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>In the years since </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i><span>, Larian has patched in some new content for Wyll and other companions, but he has always felt like he was a few steps behind the rest of the crew. But based on VanOrd’s explanation, it sounds like the character was mostly a victim of circumstance, though that may not satisfy his diehards who have watched other characters get more scenes, interactions, and love over the course of the game.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-wyll-rewrite-cut-content-scene-story-2000658493]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>