<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:22:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors Dev Publishes Surreal Roguelike About Shooting Human Brick Heads You Can Play Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vampire-survivors-balatro-kill-the-brickman-poncle-roguelike-2000619132</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-dev-publishes-surreal-roguelike-about-shooting-human-brick-heads-you-can-play-right-now.1276878/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Kill the Brickman</em> takes the basic premise of the arcade classic Breakout and adapts it to a <em>Baltro</em>-style deckbuilder roguelike where you shoot custom bullets to break bricks, win cash, collect upgrades, and extend your run. So far, so neat. But no small part of <em>Kill the Brickman</em>‘s staying power is its surreal presentation that puts Blendo Games-looking faces on all the violence. The bricks you kill? Human. The bullets you shoot? Human. It all adds up to a punchy bite-sized arcade experience published by <em>Vampire Survivors</em> dev Poncle that’s just weird enough to keep me coming back.</p> <p>Revealed during the Microsoft Gamescom showcase on Thursday, <em>Kill the Brickman</em> is out August 21 on Xbox and PC. In keeping with its publishing partner’s tradition, the game is only $5. It’s made by Doonutsaur, a small U.S.-based team whose only other project on Steam is a similarly offbeat roguelike called <em>Meow Legion</em>. Poncle director&nbsp;Luca Galante apparently got an email about the game, immediately fell in love, and signed it just a few days later. “Imagine <em>Tetris</em>, but if the bricks had anger issues and a taste for human flesh,” reads the tag line in the press release.</p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="poncle presents | Kill the Brickman - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8NHXV2qa9jE?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><em>Kill the Brickman</em> has you control a revolver at the bottom of the screen that you load custom bullets into. Some do more damage. Some have more bounces. Others can deal corrosive damage, and so on. Think the original <em>Breakout</em>, or one of its many clones, but instead of bouncing a ball to break bricks like a spin-off of <em>Pong</em>, you’re playing a turn-based puzzle shooter infused with light <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> RPG elements.</p>

 <p>Why are you killing the Brickman? Well, if they get to close they will hurt you and deplete your health. Once all your hearts are gone the run is over. But like any good roguelike, skill and intuition will only get you so far. You try to complete mini-objectives in each level to score extra cash, which compounds interest just like in <em>Balatro</em>, to purchase the sorts of upgrades that will make or break your run later on. There are relics to collect that provide special bonuses, and different gun chambers that will augment bullet effects based on the pattern you reload them in.</p> <p>I’ve only played a couple hours (Poncle provided Kotaku with access to an advance copy), but it’s one of those games I’ve been trying to make 10-15 minutes for at the end of each day and end up playing way longer than I expected. <em>Kill the Brickman</em> is a tight set of gameplay concepts wrapped up in a cool CRT pixel art aesthetic and a bizarre sense of humor, or is it horror? I’m excited to keep playing and see where it goes.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vampire-survivors-balatro-kill-the-brickman-poncle-roguelike-2000619132]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Fans Face Burnout As Battlefield 6 Hype Soars]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-bad-bf6-battlefield-6-hype-trailer-2000618912</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-fans-face-burnout-as-battlefield-6-hype-soars.1276806/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>This week was a big one for Activision and all the studios that work on the popular <a href="https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-the-call-of-duty-games-from-worst-to-best-1844765026"><em>Call of Duty</em> franchise</a>. At Gamescom, devs took to the stage of Opening Night Live to show off our first real look at <a href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-onl-opening-night-live-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-trailer-2000618479"><em>Black Ops 7</em></a>, the new main entry in the franchise. But due to various reasons, including hype for EA’s <em>Battlefield 6</em> and fans feeling burned out, the vibes are all off, and for the first time in years, it feels like the <em>Call of Duty</em> empire is shaking.</p> <p>Even before <em>Black Ops 7</em>‘s big gameplay reveal at Gamescom, the upcoming shooter was being targeted online by fans and critics who loved the <a href="https://kotaku.com/oh-thank-god-the-battlefield-6-open-beta-is-back-2000617797"><em>Battlefield 6</em> open beta</a>. Players, myself included, praised <em>BF6</em>‘s gritty combat, boots-on-the-ground action, sharp visuals, squad gameplay, and snappy shooting. For many players online, it felt like a return to the realistic military sims that once dominated the industry back in the early to mid aughts. I’m talkin’ games like <em>Battlefield 3</em>, <em>Call of Duty 4: Modern Warfare</em>, <em>Ghost Recon: Advanced Warfighter</em>, and<em> Rainbow Six Vegas.&nbsp;</em></p> <p><em>BF6′</em>s beta, its popularity, and the reaction to it led to <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/former-blizzard-president-predicts-battlefield-6-is-going-to-boot-stomp-black-ops-7-because-call-of-duty-has-become-lazy/">former Blizzard president Mike Ybarra tweeting</a>: “<em>Battlefield</em> [6] will boot stomp <em>CoD</em> this year. But the real win here is <em>CoD</em> won’t be lazy anymore, and we’ll all get better FPS games for it.” It didn’t help that during the <em>BF6</em> beta, <a href="https://x.com/CallofDutyWire/status/1954624776921894980">a <em>Call of Dut</em>y rollercoaster gun went viral</a> for all the wrong reasons. And before that, players were upset over expensive crossover skins, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zmvByyks-Fc">including<em> American Dad</em> and <em>Beavis &amp; Butthead c</em>osmetics</a>, that some felt were turning<em> Black Ops 6</em> and <em>Warzone</em> into <em>Fortnite</em>, a game famous for its wild IP sandbox that features Goku, Batman, and more.</p>

 <p>This all led to Tuesday, when <em>Black Ops 7</em>‘s first gameplay trailer premiered at Gamescom. It did so under a lot of scrutiny and in an atmosphere where even longtime vets of the series weren’t happy about the state of the game. So when the trailer showed off wild, trippy gameplay involving dream worlds and robots and strange sci-fi tech, it went over very, very poorly online. On Reddit, you can find fans saying they are done.</p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 | Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9txkGBj_trg?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>Another indicator that this new <em>Black Ops 7</em> reveal isn’t landing with fans is how poorly it has been received on YouTube. The comments below the trailer are filled with players claiming they are going to pre-order <em>BF6</em> instead and wondering what happened to <em>Call of Duty.</em> <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1958183849877201177">As reported by <em>CharlieIntel</em></a>, the <em>Black Ops 7</em> reveal trailer has only around 36k likes. That makes it one of the least liked trailers in the franchise’s history.</p> <p>Things only got worse when <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-devs-paying-attention-to-community-feedback-on-goofy-skins"><em>IGN</em> asked Miles Leslie</a>, associate creative director on the game, if<em> Black Ops 7</em>&nbsp;was going to feature silly crossover skins. Leslie claimed that the devs were “always looking at community feedback” and then proceeded to offer up a nothingburger answer about trying to “calibrate” future skins based on “feedback” and making sure “all fans feel represented.”&nbsp; This answer didn’t go over well with players, especially when <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/it-has-to-be-grounded-battlefield-6-devs-say-cosmetics-wont-be-as-goofy-as-call-of-duty-but-that-sounds-almost-too-good-to-be-true/">compared to the response given by <em>BF6</em>‘s design director Shashank Uchil</a> when asked a similar question about cosmetics.</p>

 <p>“It has to be grounded. That is what <em>BF3</em> and <em>BF4</em> was—it was all soldiers, on the ground,” said Uchil. “It’s going to be like this. I don’t think it needs&nbsp;Nicki Minaj. Let’s keep it real, keep it grounded.”</p> <p>It would be foolish to count <em>Call of Duty</em> out in 2025. The franchise is still incredibly popular, especially with people who aren’t online every day, posting on Reddit and Discord. In 2024, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2djbq4c2n"><em>Black Ops 6</em> was still the best-selling premium video game of the year</a>, and the overall franchise sold more games last year than any other series. I would be shocked if <em>Battlefield 6</em> outsells<em> Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em> this holiday season. Still, it’s clear that the vibes are rotten with this year’s <em>Call of Duty.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>It feels like fans are getting burned out on back-to-back direct sequels (something the franchise avoided for nearly 20 years), expensive cosmetics, <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-generative-ai-call-duty-gamescom-2025-slop-2000618833">AI-produced slop</a>, the series getting wackier and weirder, and a sense that the people making the games aren’t listening to the people playing the games. This isn’t entirely new. For as long as<em> Call of Duty</em> has been popular, people have been hating on it. But this year, grumpy fans and tired vets have<em> Battlefield 6</em> to rally around, an FPS that feels like it was designed in a lab to recreate the experience of playing those old Xbox 360-era military shooters people loved so much. In a way, it almost feels like <em>CoD</em> fans are hoping for <em>BF6</em> to punish<em> Black Ops 7</em>, and they seem willing to pay money to help kick Activision in the gut.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-bad-bf6-battlefield-6-hype-trailer-2000618912]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>