<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:16:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gaming Mini PC with Ryzen 7, 32GB DDR5 RAM, 1TB Is Cheaper Than a Mac Mini, Amazon Clears Out Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gaming-mini-pc-with-ryzen-7-32gb-ddr5-ram-1tb-is-cheaper-than-a-mac-mini-amazon-clears-out-stock-2000638156</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gaming-mini-pc-with-ryzen-7-32gb-ddr5-ram-1tb-is-cheaper-than-a-mac-mini-amazon-clears-out-stock.1331521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Desktop gaming (usually) means building a tower PC or shelling out premium prices for something capable. The <em>GMKtec K8 Plus</em> flips that equation by packing serious gaming hardware into a mini PC that now costs less than Apple’s base Mac Mini, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4925/">Amazon just dropped it to a record low of $519 (down from $738)</a>. With an AMD Ryzen 7 8845HS processor, 32GB of DDR5 RAM, integrated Radeon 780M graphics, and a 1TB SSD, this pocket-sized system handles AAA gaming at 1080p.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4925/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>What Makes This Mini PC Punch Above Its Size</h2>
<p>The AMD Ryzen 7 8845HS processor brings <strong>8 cores and 16 threads with a boost clock up to 5.1GHz</strong> which puts it in the same performance bracket as many full-sized desktop chips. The 16MB L3 cache helps the CPU access frequently used data faster and reduces bottlenecks during gaming and heavy multitasking. What separates the 8845HS from the similar 8745HS model is the <strong>inclusion of an NPU</strong>, a dedicated chip designed to handle AI workloads like Windows Studio Effects, Copilot tasks, and local AI processing without burdening the main CPU cores. If <strong>you’re experimenting with AI tools</strong> or running productivity features that leverage machine learning, this NPU accelerates those tasks considerably.</p>
<p>32GB of 5600MHz DDR5 RAM provides you the breathing room you require to run your games, dozens of tabs open in your browser, Discord, stream software, and your video editor all at the same time without lag. <strong>DDR5 is also higher bandwidth than the older DDR4, so data travels between the CPU and the RAM more quickly</strong>&nbsp;and this provides you better game frame times and better application responsiveness.</p>



<p>Storage arrives through a <strong>1TB PCIe 4.0 M.2 SSD which gives read speeds of 5,000-7,000 MB/s</strong> or so, depending on the drive you choose. This makes a difference when you are loading bigger game files, launching Windows, or transferring footage to where you’ll be editing it. PCIe 4.0 is double the speed of PCIe 3.0, and the ability to upgrade to 8TB makes it so you won’t have to replace the original drive should you decide you want to add another drive.</p>
<p>The AMD Radeon 780M integrated graphics is where this system surprises people: Built on the <strong>RDNA3 architecture with 12 compute units and 768 stream processors clocked up to 2,700MHz, it outperforms the previous generation</strong> 680M by a significant margin. This GPU handles demanding titles like Cyberpunk 2077 at minimum settings around 30-40 fps at 1080p, and less demanding games like FIFA 23 or Fortnite run at medium to high settings with smooth frame rates.</p>



<p>The Oculink interface is something you won’t usually find on retail mini PCs: Oculink gives you a high-bandwidth external GPU connection so <strong>you can attach a full desktop graphics card</strong> in an external enclosure should you, someday, desire increased gaming muscle. It carries exponentially higher bandwidth than Thunderbolt or USB4 where external GPUs are connected, and gives you much less loss of performance and providing you with a real upgrade path without having to replace the whole system.</p>
<p>What’s more,<strong> two USB4 ports at 40Gbps each have Power Delivery 3.0 and DisplayPort 1.4</strong>&nbsp;so you can attach fast storage, charge gear, and power displays all out of the same port. HDMI 2.1 and DisplayPort 2.1 outputs have 60Hz 8K resolution support, and the system can power four displays at 4K resolution. For multi-monitor productivity configurations or creative applications where you want the extra desktop real estate, this connectivity makes the K8 Plus into a real workstation.</p>
<p>Dual i226V 2.5 Gigabit Ethernet ports support the speedy and rock-solid wired connections of 2.5 gigabit Ethernet, which makes a difference for big file transfers or reducing latency in internet gaming.</p>
<p>At $519, the system costs you less than an entry-level Mac Mini but gives you gaming power Apple’s system lacks and expansion-room flexibility so you’ll have wiggle-room later to upgrade.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4925/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gaming-mini-pc-with-ryzen-7-32gb-ddr5-ram-1tb-is-cheaper-than-a-mac-mini-amazon-clears-out-stock-2000638156]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-the-kotaku-review.1331449/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>Earlier this year, I was interviewing the creators of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-balls-monster-catchin-musical-professor-oak-2000617768"><i><span>BALLS: The Monster-Catchin’ Musical Comédy</span></i></a><span> about the parody show’s spoofing of the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>universe. We talked about how, in the ‘90s, Game Freak probably wasn’t designing the world of its monster-taming RPGs to be interrogated, or expecting the core concept of capturing magical monsters in balls to become the source of a heated moral quandary. Established norms like </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-starters-chikorita-tepig-totodile-2000637637"><span>dumping your unused Pokémon in a PC box</span></a><span> were probably not meant to make a kid think about the existential dread their seventh-favorite monster might experience in captivity, where they had to put it because they could only hold six Poké Balls on their belt at a time. The </span><i><span>BALLS</span></i><span> writers, however, extrapolated this rote procedure into a scene in which its legally distinct “Collectabuddies” are going mad from being stranded in storage for so long. It’s a dark, disturbing fate that </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>hasn’t explored, and in the decades since </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>, the dissonance between </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s need to maintain an upbeat depiction of its world’s monster-catching status quo and its exploration of a world in which Pokémon and humanity co-exist peacefully as equals has only become louder and harder to ignore, especially as stories like </span><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Arceus </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Detective Pikachu </span></i><span>have put these dynamics under a microscope.</span></p> <p><span>Enter </span><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</span></i><span>, a sequel to the 3DS games </span><i><span>X </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Y</span></i><span>, set entirely in the Paris-inspired metropolis of Lumiose City. After the near-apocalyptic events that occurred the last time we were in the Kalos region, the people of Lumiose are undergoing an urban redevelopment plan to make it an accommodating home for both humans and wild Pokémon. This ranges from the cutest Pikachu to the most dangerous dragon, like Salamence. Certain areas of the city are designated “Wild Zones” where these untamed monsters live, and humans are free to explore them and battle the wildlife, or catch them, add them to their party, and have them take part in battles in the local competitive scene. That…doesn’t sound like the sort of equal co-existence Lumiose is touting. If the relationship between humans and Pokémon has only changed in terms of proximity, what is their shared city aspiring to that is actually moving the needle of progress?</span></p>

 <p><span>Interestingly enough, </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>seems unsatisfied with its own answer. The </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>series has been gesturing at this issue for over a decade, with </span><i><span>Pokémon Black </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>White </span></i><span>(</span><a href="https://jakesteinberg.substack.com/p/pokemon-black-and-white-is-a-reddit"><span>ineloquently</span></a><span>) introducing a villainous team whose entire goal was to free these creatures from their spherical prisons, only to dial that all back by the end. The </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/detective-pikachu-returns-pokemon-review-switch-1850915720"><i><span>Detective Pikachu </span></i><span>games</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-detective-pikachu-returns-live-action-movie-1850907630"><span>live-action film</span></a><span> take place in Ryme City, a place where Pokémon battling is outlawed, and there, these critters have day jobs like any other human. As a result, that subseries still offers the most revolutionary vision of a world where man and ‘mon walk side by side.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>But in </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>, the core verbs are still “catch” and “battle,” and the game has more questions than answers about what the dynamic between the human and Pokémon citizens of its new city even looks like. Lumiose’s redevelopment feels like a half-step toward a new ideal, but the game’s sense of hope for a brighter future in the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>world primarily manifests elsewhere, both in the story it tells and in the new ways it illustrates the bond between Pokémon and trainer when you’re in the thick of battle. Like most things it has going for it, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s vision of the Pokémon universe is experimental, testing the waters for a future it’s not quite ready to boldly walk into, held back by expectations of what it’s supposed to be. But what’s here still manages to solidify the </span><i><span>Legends </span></i><span>subseries as the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games to watch, ones that appeal to the diehard lore enthusiasts, the casuals who are tired of repeating the same format, and the ones who have felt burned by the technical fumbles of recent years.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000637722" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000637722"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000637722">© The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>Welcome back to Lumiose City</b></h2> <p><span>When I first began my vacation to Lumiose City, I was greeted by Taunie, a sprightly leader of Team MZ, a group of youngsters operating out of a mostly unremarkable hotel to handle a much more remarkable problem. As the city is undergoing its redevelopment, some of the wild Pokémon who are migrating to the Wild Zones are undergoing a painful, forced Mega Evolution in the city streets. These usually temporary transformations are supposed to be activated by a trainer, but the wild Pokémon are undergoing Mega Evolution against their will and need to be pacified so they can return to their original state, as I’m told, these Rogue Mega Evolutions threaten the stability of the entire redevelopment plan.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The existence of that supposed stability, however, is debatable. As I weave through the scaffolding of unfinished construction work, hop across the rooftops, and insert myself into the citizens’ business with my Raichu by my side, almost all I hear from residents is dissatisfaction with the entire project. People love their partner Pokémon, but they’re unsure if Lumiose’s redevelopment plan is as righteous as it sounds on paper. Some folks are concerned about what happens if a powerful Pokémon gets out of the Wild Zones, and others find all the construction and noise of the late-night Z-A Royale tournament battles in the street an annoying distraction in their already hectic city life. Still others claim that sequestering these monsters into their own designated spaces isn’t actually solving anything. But no one seems to agree on how to truly integrate Pokémon and humanity.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>In its own way, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> underlines how the more you think about it, the more it becomes clear that this entire world is kind of fundamentally broken. Pokémon are friends, but they are dangerous. Humans want to co-exist with them as equals, but still get to capture them in Poké Balls. I don’t think this is some pretentious CinemaSins “gotcha” moment; I think it’s a sign of a world that has, as time has gone on, started to reckon with itself, but is still struggling to find the happy medium between the central monster-catching premise people know and love and the monster-loving world it wants to depict. I would have been floored if </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>had completely upended everything the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>franchise has ever been, but I think I find its honest admission that it doesn’t know what the answer is to be just as compelling. Yeah, you can point to all the external factors of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span> being a worldwide phenomenon of multimedia, merchandising, and moneymaking as the reason that nothing truly revolutionary comes out of Lumiose City, but given that </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-leak-generation-10-wind-wave-galar-legends-mmo-2000635337"><span>will continue long after </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i></a><span>, I think I like the idea of watching a world slowly inching toward a new historical era. Progress is often slow, and maybe I’m intrigued by watching the series grapple with questions about how to move forward, rather than finding an easy answer and solving the universe’s problems in 30 hours.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000637724" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000637724"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000637724">© The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>It might not be quite as idyllic as its leaders want it to be, but Lumiose houses one of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s most memorable casts, full of characters who have a vested interest in helping it get there. Game Freak has always excelled at creating memorable trainers, but the series is typically so transient that most of the characters you meet only get a bit of time to shine before you head to the next town. </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> is set entirely in Lumiose, however, so as I work my way up the ranks of the Z-A Royale and save Rogue Mega Pokémon, I’m meeting what feels like a real assortment of unlikely friends bonded by proximity and a sense of home. Lumiose is still reeling from the events of </span><i><span>X </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Y</span></i><span>, and after a near-cataclysmic event, you’d think most people would be looking to put some distance between themselves and the Prism Tower at the city’s center. And to be fair, several of them have. While there are a few returning characters from previous games, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s cast</span> <span>is mostly made up of fresh faces, with a lot of the old Kalos region staples having moved on and just being referenced with a wink in passing dialogue. Those who are still here from </span><i><span>X </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Y </span></i><span>are usually a somber echo of who they once were, lingering because they have nowhere else to go. The people who are left cleaning up the wreckage do so because this city is their home, and they’ll stand by it even as dubious corporate interests flock to it.</span></p> <p><span>Maybe I’m just a sentimental fool who </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-night-city-new-york-city-1850879791"><span>only recently moved to a big city</span></a><span>, but seeing </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s cast of proud Lumiose residents come together to protect their city and its population hit me like a truck. One endgame sequence resonated with me so deeply, I just put my Joy-Cons down and stared at the ceiling, realizing that living in New York City for almost three years elicits a similar feeling of unity and camaraderie with my people here. </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>has always been about the power of friendship, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-tcg-vendor-scalper-reseller-stream-shows-2000630658"><span>but those bonds are also the foundation of community</span></a><span>, and </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s cast is one of the series’ best examples of it. Seeing folks in different industries, with different Pokémon training skills, and from different walks of life come together in service of the people is pretty inspiring, even when the individual stepping up is someone whose Pokémon’s attacks I’d been on the wrong side of hours prior. Lumiose and its citizens are still figuring things out, but when I see people like Corbeau, the pseudo mob boss of the city, working alongside local celebrities like the streamer Canari, in service of a place and of people they’ve grown to care for, I can’t help but believe they might find a way to make the city the best version of itself eventually.</span></p> <p><span>There’s been much debate about the size of Lumiose City </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-small-boring-map-how-big-time-to-walk-around-2000636148"><span>as an open-world video game space</span></a><span>, but I really don’t mind a walkable city that doesn’t require me to hop on a Pokémon steed to get from one side to the other. I’ve never been a player who finds the act of getting to a destination as interesting as whatever it is I’m actually going there to do, and </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> has plenty to do between filling up your Pokédex with monsters in the Wild Zones, battling in the Z-A Royale, doing (sometimes menial) side quests, dressing up and taking cute pics with your Pokémon, and eavesdropping on some of the </span><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-legends-za-lumiose-city-secret-npc-dialogue-sinister/"><span>batshit things</span></a><span> citizens have to say. It’s a small map, sure, and as they often do, </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>fans and haters alike are combing through it and noting the lack of environmental details. Windows </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/trees-have-become-the-pokemon-fandoms-ultimate-brain-wo-1847541501"><span>are the new trees</span></a><span>, as these fixtures appear to be a texture plastered on the sides of buildings rather than actually rendered. Maybe it was helpful that I played the game on Switch 2 and had a smooth ride, but this is the first time I’ve played a </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>game since the jump to 3D that didn’t make me grimace at moments of ugliness. Yeah, it’s not going to win any awards for its graphics, and there are </span><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hessianlobo.bsky.social/post/3m3pp3pwfdc2e"><span>plenty of bugs that people will clip</span></a><span>, but it’s a far cry from the technical and visual mess of </span><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span>, and when it wants to flex, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s more visually striking moments really pop on Switch 2.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Despite my smooth ride, I’m seeing players talk about what sounds like a completely different game than I’ve experienced. To some, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> is a technical mess on the same scale that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-bugs-performance-paldea-nintendo-1849798801"><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span> were at their horrendous 2022 launch</span></a><span>, and yet, I’ve experienced almost none of the issues they’re reporting. Even with </span><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span>, my playthrough wasn’t buggy; it was just ugly and ran like shit. Video game bugs are a dice roll, as they’re often born of very specific scenarios that a developer might not see in testing, and if neither I nor a QA worker saw it, that doesn’t mean it’s not happening to someone else. But if I’m evaluating </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>based on my own experience playing it on Switch 2, all I can tell you is that I have no technical complaints. In fact, it ran so smoothly on the device that it was actually jarring after having spent over 160 hours enduring </span><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span>’s jank.&nbsp;</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000637726" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000637726"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000637726">© The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>Get in the ring, trainer</b></h2> <p><span>That buttery smooth performance allowed me to get the most out of </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s new real-time battle system. While Lumiose is struggling to come up with a more groundbreaking solution to its city infrastructure, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s battle system is one of the most inspired changes Game Freak has ever put onto a cartridge. Rather than the turn-based battles fans know from previous games, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> has you issuing commands to your Pokémon in real-time, cycling through cooldowns, focusing on positioning, and making quick, reflex-based plays on top of all the usual strategic elemental strategizing. As you tell your Pokémon what attacks to use, you’re also running around the battlefield alongside them. In a way, the co-existence </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> aspires to is best encapsulated in putting trainers in the thick of the scrap, and I loved how cooperative it felt to dodge and reposition as I quickly thought on my feet about what moves to use.</span></p>

 <p><span>This shift fundamentally changes the way you have to think about your Pokémon’s movesets and how they interact with others on the field. For example, I taught my Raichu attacks that would allow him to move throughout the battlefield at a quick pace. If an enemy got too close, I’d have him use Volt Switch, which would shock an opponent and allow him to quickly teleport to my side. I usually kept my distance from other trainers’ Pokémon, so this was a guaranteed escape for him if he got overwhelmed by an enemy. If I needed him to close the distance, I’d have him use Play Rough and slap enemies around, then use Volt Switch again to return to safety, then throw a long-range Thunderbolt at a foe for good measure. I created builds that were about more than just type coverage, but instead formed archetypes like Raichu’s “hit-and-run” attacker or my “keep away” Starmie, whose entire moveset kept it at a distance to accommodate its slow movement. The result is that fights are frantic, exhilarating, and sometimes over much sooner than I’d like them to be.&nbsp;</span></p> <div>           <ul>                           <li>                 <p>Back-of-the-box quote:</p>                 <p>"We built this city on Mega Rocks and Roll."</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Developer:</p>                 <p>Game Freak</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Type of game:</p>                 <p>Monster-taming RPG with a new, real-time battle system.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Liked:</p>                 <p>Battle system is a challenging and rewarding spin on an old formula, memorable cast, compelling follow-up on the fallout from X and Y.</p>               </li>                               </ul><ul>                                         <li>                 <p>Disliked:</p>                 <p>Focus on Mega Evolution makes party choices more restrictive, not all Mega designs are made equal, Lumiose is a more compelling stage for thematic exploration than a video game map for literal exploration.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Platforms:</p>                 <p>Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 (played on)</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Release Date:</p>                 <p>October 16, 2025</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Played</p>                 <p>~30 hours to hit credits</p>               </li>                                     </ul>         </div>  <p><span>Where the system really shines is in the Rogue Mega Evolution fights, which are longer battles against one large, superpowered Mega Evolved Pokémon that usually requires multiple trainers to take down. These guys will often focus fire on you, so you’re constantly on the move, dodging powerful attacks while also trying to give orders to your Pokémon so they can dish out damage. That’s hard for most Pokémon, though, as Rogues have heightened defenses that are only easily broken by other Mega-evolved Pokémon. Unlike in </span><i><span>X </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Y</span></i><span>, Mega Evolution is not a one-and-done mechanic you can only use once per battle. Instead, </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>makes Mega Evolution a gauge you fill up and deplete multiple times throughout a fight, allowing you to transform multiple Pokémon into these beefed-up forms in one battle.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Because of this, </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>encourages you to have multiple Mega Evolution-capable Pokémon in your team. The game has almost every Mega Evolution in its roster, with a few notable exceptions like legendary Pokémon Mewtwo and Rayquaza. With </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s addition of another couple dozen new forms, there are around 70 available to you throughout the game, but that does mean that a lot of the Pokémon end up either fairly useless or at least suboptimal in major boss fights. Non-Mega Pokémon are given the ability to use the Mega gauge to power up their moves to try and break through the ceiling, but it’s a far more limited resource compared to transforming one of your other monsters into a powerful version of themselves to make every attack they use stronger.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>My party ended up being five Mega Evolution Pokémon and my Raichu, who, yes, will get to join their ranks in the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-raichu-evolution-x-y-paid-dlc-2000625371"><i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>DLC</span></a><span>, but when I went several story battles without using him, it felt like my choices were more restricted than in previous games. There are a lot of Pokémon in </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> who can’t pull off these transformations, and it means they all inherently fall behind. I appreciate how these mechanics gel in some truly spectacular fights, but it does come at the cost of some of that freedom to define your party. Unless you like banging your head against a hard wall until it breaks.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000637725" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000637725"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000637725">© The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>This focus on Mega Evolution also sticks in my craw when, frankly, a lot of the new Mega forms are duds. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-starmie-patrick-star-jokes-2000636057"><span>Mega Starmie’s human-like arms and legs</span></a><span> are an abomination, even though its quick movement does make up for Starmie’s biggest weakness. Mega Feraligatr’s toilet-seat-like helmet only looks interesting when it’s closed. And who even asked for a Mega Eelektross? There are some bangers, though. Hawlucha’s upgraded luchadore outfit makes him look like a real pro wrestler, Dragonite’s head wings help bridge the gap between it and its gorgeous pre-evolutions, and Falinks making all of its interlocked bodies into a sword-and-shield-wielding soldier is such a cool riff on its concept. Looking back at the original Megas from Generation VI, their designs were also filled with peaks and valleys, but maybe it’s </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>’s lopsided focus on the goofiest transformations Game Freak could think of that has me feeling colder. Hopefully, </span><i><span>Mega Dimension</span></i><span>’s additions help diversify the roster. Mega Raichu X and Y are already a pretty promising start.</span></p> <p><span>I can’t talk about the battling without also diving into the Z-A Royale, the game’s substitute for the usual gym leader run in most games. This tournament has competitors fighting over a lettered ranking to determine the top-standing trainers in Lumiose. You start at Z and make your way to A at the top. Each ranking jump requires you to earn enough points by battling randos in the Battle Zones that pop up every night, then face a more powerful trainer who holds a letter ranking higher than you. Battle Zones are limited-time pop-ups that will disappear when the sun rises, so it’s an exciting challenge to have to accumulate enough points each night in hopes that you won’t have to come back tomorrow to make up the difference.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> helps you earn more points by pulling off specific challenges, such as using particular elemental attacks, ambushing enemies through stealth, or defeating foes with Mega Evolved Pokémon. I love taking part in these races against time that require me to use my whole team, rather than just one or two aces, and the progression system is immensely satisfying…at first. One of the most deflating moments in </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> is when, for plot reasons, you skip several Z-A Royale rankings to jump right to rank F. This is because </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>only has five more major characters for you to face, and when all of these trainers are lined up next to each other for you to count, you realize there are about as many of them as there are gym leaders in your average </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>game. For all the posturing of its new ideas, </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span> can’t help but fall back on old reliables, and it’s a real bummer when you realize the entire progression system is mostly a facade.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000637723" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000637723"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000637723">© The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>We’re now two </span><i><span>Legends </span></i><span>games in, and it’s not entirely clear what it means for a </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>game to be part of this subseries. </span><i><span>Arceus </span></i><span>was set in the past and maintained turn-based battles, but had a fluid, action-based capture and traversal system. </span><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>moves the timeline forward and has much more restricted traversal, but also an excellent real-time battle system, unlike anything the series has done before. Perhaps the </span><i><span>Legends </span></i><span>moniker just ends up being a name that differentiates these games from the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games everyone expects. They’re experimental, show us new sides of places we’ve already been to before, and dive deep into the world in a way the usual Pokémon League run doesn’t typically allow. </span></p> <p><i><span>Z-A </span></i><span>is a game of trying new things and hoping for the best. Not everyone agrees on what the best course of action is, but nevertheless, Lumiose City has to move forward and carve out a future for itself, much like the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>franchise has been trying to do in recent years. It has started abandoning long-held traditions, both in the games and elsewhere, in the hopes that it can be something greater than </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-van-gogh-go-remote-raids-1851128900"><span>the corporate machine has forced it to be for so long</span></a><span>. Maybe not every change is going to work for everyone, and it will take time for a series that was stuck in its ways for so long to find its footing. But at least the people of Lumiose are trying, and so is Game Freak.</span></p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Charge 3 Devices at Once with This Anker Wall Charger, Now Selling for Pennies on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/charge-3-devices-at-once-with-this-anker-wall-charger-now-selling-for-pennies-on-amazon-2000638152</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/charge-3-devices-at-once-with-this-anker-wall-charger-now-selling-for-pennies-on-amazon.1331446/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Modern homes never seem to have enough outlets and dragging around multiple chargers for your laptop, phone, and tablet turns every trip into a cable management nightmare. The Anker 735 charger solves this frustration by <strong>consolidating everything into a single 65-watt, three-port wall charger</strong> that’s compact enough to toss in your bag without thinking twice.</p>
<p>Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4567/">just dropped it to an all-time low of $25 (down from $39)</a>, and at this price, you can finally retire that collection of mismatched charging bricks cluttering your nightstand.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4567/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why Three Ports and 65 Watts Changes Everything</h2>
<p>The 65-watt output makes the difference because it’s the optimal level for powering current laptops full-speed. A MacBook Pro 13-inch takes just 61 watts for best-possible charging speed and this charger provides it with headroom to go around when you’re only using a single outlet. Most cell phone chargers only go 20 watts and lower-end multi-port chargers frequently only go 30-45 total watts which makes you decide between <strong>charging your laptop fast and powering other devices.</strong></p>
<p>When you plug three devices at once, the <strong>power distribution system of the charger automatically distributes wattage intelligently</strong> according to the requirement of each device. Plug in your laptop, smartphone, and tablet, and the charger automatically varies the output of each port, favoring the device capable of accepting the highest power but still making the rest charge at decent rates.</p>



<p>Addition of PPS support is just one of the technical features that significantly boosts charging efficiency and compatibility. PPS enables the charger to exchange information directly with your device and make real-time adjustments to voltage as opposed to fixed voltage steps. This translates into fewer heat emissions, higher charging speeds and better long-term battery life. Devices such as Galaxy smartphones and the latest iPhones fully benefit from PPS to reach their claimed fast-charging speeds, and you would be limited to lower charging rates even with the higher-wattage charger without it.</p>
<p>GaN II technology is what allows this <strong>charger to pack 65 watts into a package roughly the size of an AirPods Pro case</strong>. Traditional silicon-based chargers require much larger components to handle high wattage without overheating. Gallium nitride operates at higher frequencies and temperatures with better efficiency, meaning the components can be smaller and packed more densely without thermal issues. The second generation of GaN technology in this charger improves upon the original by increasing operating frequency by 100%.</p>



<p>The three-port configuration <strong>includes two USB-C ports and one USB-A port</strong> and covers both newer and legacy devices. Most modern laptops, tablets, and phones use USB-C, but plenty of accessories like wireless earbuds, smartwatches, and older devices still rely on USB-A. Having that USB-A port available means you don’t need to carry adapters or separate chargers for those holdout devices that haven’t made the USB-C transition yet.</p>
<p>At $25, this charger is cheaper than purchasing two standard phone chargers individually, but it replaces your laptop charger, phone charger, and tablet charger with the same device.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4567/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/charge-3-devices-at-once-with-this-anker-wall-charger-now-selling-for-pennies-on-amazon-2000638152]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Budget Pick to Practically Free, Acer Wireless Gaming Headset Drops Nearly 50%]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/from-budget-pick-to-practically-free-acer-wireless-gaming-headset-drops-nearly-50-2000637414</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/from-budget-pick-to-practically-free-acer-wireless-gaming-headset-drops-nearly-50.1331440/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Gaming with a headset is my preferred way to play. Sure, when playing in a squad where communication is key you’re going to want to have a headset. Though even when I’m hitting solo queues or playing through a single player game, I’m usually reaching for my headphones. The more intimate audio allows me to immerse myself more easily into the game, plus you can get a better sense of your in-game surroundings than when using your TV’s built-in speakers. You can even get yourself a solid pair without breaking the bank. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4921/">Amazon happens to have the Acer wireless gaming headsets for PlayStation consoles, PC, and Nintendo Switch discounted by nearly 50% off for a limited time.</a></p>
<p>These wireless gaming headphones with mic come in a handful of colors too. Most of the options are predominately black with variations in their highlight color. You can get the headset in black with an accent of either red, pink, blue, green, or orange. Additionally, there is an option for solid pink and and option for solid white. The discounts vary a little bit between the different color options, but none of them are more expensive than $32 during this sale. The lowest price right now is for the black with the red accent, currently listed at $27. They’re normally sitting at $50 so that’s quite the jump down.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4921/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Connect Multiple Ways</h2>
<p>The Acer wireless gaming headset gives you a few options for how to connect to your games audio. The headset can be paired to your console or PC over Bluetooth, or you can plug in the USB-A dongle which pairs with your headset over 2.4GHz wireless. Then, of course, we’ve got ol’ reliable — the AUX cord.</p>
<p>The headset is able to deliver exceptional sound over its 50mm drivers. You’ll hear your teammates and have them hear you with a a low latency of 20ms.</p>



<p>The earpads and head bar are designed for all day comfort so you can keep them on as you work or game without even noticing they are there. They’re designed with a soft leather texture and memory foam cushioning which also helps with soundproofing.</p>
<p>You’ll be able to listen all day too and then some. T<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4921/">he Acer wireless gaming headset has a battery life that will take you up to 100 hours of game time (or 100 hours of music time).</a> When battery is approaching low levels of under 3%, it will play a voice alert so you can find a plug or make accommodations before they die on you. When you do find them without charge, you can bring them back up to full in around four to six hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4921/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/from-budget-pick-to-practically-free-acer-wireless-gaming-headset-drops-nearly-50-2000637414]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This 1800W Anker Power Station with 200W Solar Panel Drops 50% Off, Say Goodbye to Winter Outages]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-1800w-anker-power-station-with-200w-solar-panel-drops-50-off-say-goodbye-to-winter-outages-2000638147</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-1800w-anker-power-station-with-200w-solar-panel-drops-50-off-say-goodbye-to-winter-outages.1331395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Winter storms, ice buildup and grid overload during cold snaps can knock out power for hours or even days and leave you scrambling for ways to keep essential devices running. The <strong>Anker Solix C1000</strong> portable power station bundled with a 200W solar panel tackles this exact problem and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4924/">Amazon just slashed it to an all-time low of $671, down from $1,299)</a>. This combo gives you 1,056 watt-hours of backup capacity with the <strong>ability to recharge from the sun</strong>, which means you can keep your furnace controls, internet router, medical devices or space heaters running during an outage.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4924/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Perfect Solution During Wintertime Disasters</h2>
<p>The <strong>1,800-watt continuous power through SurgePad technology</strong> (which peaks to 2,400 watts) covers almost all appliances you would have to power through the duration of a blackout. That surge ability accommodates power startup demands of refrigerators or battery-powered heaters which frequently have 2-3 times their operating wattage for 1-2 seconds the moment they are switched on.</p>
<p>The 1,056 watt-hour LiFePO4 battery has a rating of well over 3,000 charge cycles before the battery falls to 80% capacity. In practical terms, if you discharge and charge this station once each week, you’ll have spirited performance well into the 10-year term. LiFePO4 chemistry has far better stability than typical lithium-ion, owing to increased cold-temperature handling and far lower propensity toward thermal runaway.</p>



<p>UltraFast mode charges the station to 80% capacity in 43 minutes and <strong>full power in 58 minutes</strong> on the connection of AC power and by the activation of the Anker app. That gives you the ability to recharge fast whenever there are fleeting interludes of power availability and the next blackout approaches. Normal power stations take 6-8 hours to be fully charged, and this does not help much where the grid power remains unstable.</p>
<p>This <strong>200W solar panel included makes this truly an off-grid solution</strong>: Monocrystalline cells of 23% efficiency draw significantly more power from ambient sun than older polycrystalline panels, which rarely achieve higher than 15-17% efficiency. You have four adjustable pitch angles of 30, 40, 50, and 80 degrees, allowing you to dial in the best position relative to the sun’s arc throughout the day and throughout the seasons.</p>



<p><strong>IP67 weatherproof grading</strong> of the panel means it won’t fail because of snow, rain, or dust. You’ll be able to leave it outdoors even for charging periods should the weather shift, but you’ll still have to cover the power station unit itself, which lacks a rating for direct exposure.</p>
<p>With <strong>11 total ports including six AC outlets</strong>, you can run multiple devices simultaneously without needing power strips or prioritizing what stays on. During a winter outage, this means keeping your router and modem online for communication, charging phones and laptops, running a CPAP machine overnight and powering a small space heater in one room, all from the same unit. The variety of ports <strong>(AC, USB-A, USB-C, car outlet)</strong> accommodates everything from full-size appliances down to small electronics without adapters.</p>
<p>At $671 for both the power station and solar panel, you’re looking at less than half the original $1,299 price. Comparable systems with similar capacity and solar charging capability typically run $900-1,200 even on sale.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4924/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-1800w-anker-power-station-with-200w-solar-panel-drops-50-off-say-goodbye-to-winter-outages-2000638147]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>