<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:43:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s Being Real Weird About Pikmin All Of A Sudden]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pikmin-5-free-update-sequel-switch-2-miyamoto-2000638244</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-being-real-weird-about-pikmin-all-of-a-sudden.1331944/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Nintendo has a history of making weird announcements out of the blue. Remember last year’s alarm clock? But even in its current chaotic era of tweeting out game reveals and doing hour-long follow-up livestreams for games like <em>Kirby Air Riders</em>, Wednesday’s <em>Pikmin 4</em> announcement is low-key bizarre.</p> <p>The <em>Mario</em> maker revealed its 2023 strategy adventure game will be getting a free update two years later. But not for the newly released Switch 2. Instead, <em>Pikmin 4</em> will get new content in November for the original Switch version. That game can be played on the new hardware, obviously, but an official Switch 2 upgrade remains nowhere in sight. Hmmm.</p>

 <p>The meat of the update revolves around new cross-functionality between <em>Pikmin 4</em> and <em>Pikmin Bloom</em>, the augmented-reality mobile spin-off by the creators of <em>Pokémon Go</em>. Decor Pikmin, which wear funny outfits and were previously only available in <em>Bloom</em>, can now be found in <em>Pikmin 4</em> and transferred back and forth between both games. Meanwhile, <em>Pikmin 4</em>‘s Ice Pikmin will be joining <em>Bloom</em> for the first time to mark that game’s fourth anniversary.</p>

  <p>The rest of the update includes a camera mode for <em>Pikmin 4</em> and new difficulty settings to make the game easier or more challenging. There’s also now a free demo for the game on the eShop. <em>Pikmin 4</em> sold <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2023/231107_4e.pdf">over 2.5 million copies</a>, making it the best-selling game in the franchise that began back on the GameCube, but still far from one of the platform’s bigger first-party sellers.</p>

 <p>So why <em>Pikmin</em>? Why now? And why on the original Switch? Nintendo hasn’t shied away from making DLC and packaging it with paid “next-gen upgrades” to push sales of older Switch games on the new hardware. At the same time, this seems unlikely to feed into any meaningful holiday resurgence in<em> Pikmin 4</em> for the original console, with the update wedged in-between <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> and <em>Metroid Prime 4</em>.</p>

 <h2>Is Nintendo laying the groundwork for <em>Pikmin 5</em> or something completely different?</h2> <p>There’s also the extra weirdness with this update coming just after Nintendo released a couple of Pixar-like <em>Pikmin</em> shorts. <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-pikmin-short-animated-film-mario-zelda-app-2000633651">It claims</a> those were tests to prove out the capabilities of its new internal Nintendo Pictures team, but the company rarely does random one-offs on a whim. Could this all be laying the groundwork for Nintendo’s next <em>Pikmin</em> project? And will that be a full-fledged <em>Pikmin </em>sequel, a <em>Pikmin</em>-centric movie or TV series, or a more unorthodox venture in the toy or theme park realm?</p>

 <p>There’s also the Shigeru Miyamoto factor. The famed Nintendo developer created the <em>Pikmin</em> franchise and it clearly lives near and dear to his heart. Would <em>Pikmin 4</em> have even happened without him pushing for it? He told press it was close to completion back in 2015, only for it to lay dormant until it was suddenly re-revealed in 2022 and released the following year.</p>

 <p><em>Pikmin 4</em> is also notable among Nintendo’s first-party projects for being made in Unreal Engine 4. There’s also that mysterious MMO playtest Nintendo performed exactly a year ago this week. It included <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-playtest-switch-2-mario-mmo-1851677142">world-crafting mechanics and user-generated content references</a> that suggested things like <em>Minecraft</em> and <em>Roblox</em> were possible inspirations.</p> <p>Could Nintendo be prepping a <em>Pikmin</em> crossover with <em>Fortnite</em>? Will the next <em>Pikmin</em> game be Nintendo’s ambitious take on the survival crafting MMO genre? Will Miyamoto return to development to make it the last game he ever directs? Or is Nintendo just throwing hardcore <em>Pikmin 4</em> stans one last bone before the franchise goes dark for another decade?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pikmin-5-free-update-sequel-switch-2-miyamoto-2000638244]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6‘s First New Map Is Fine, But The Rest Of Season One Is Much Better]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-first-new-map-review-season-1-blackwell-fields-eastwood-update-2000638228</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6%E2%80%98s-first-new-map-is-fine-but-the-rest-of-season-one-is-much-better.1331902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-steam-record-login-queue-multiplayer-download-issue-2000634042">Battlefield 6</a>‘</em>s first season launches soon across consoles and PC, and it promises new maps, modes, vehicles, and weapons. I was recently invited to check out some of this new content ahead of next week’s release. If you’ve been wanting a new, giant map, this season will give you that. Eventually.</p> <p>Season one of <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-review-steam-ps5-campaign-multiplayer-2000633379"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a> launches on October 28 and brings with it a lot of new and completely free content. <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-two-new-maps-modes-roadmap-free-updates-dlc-2025-ea-2000630301">As outlined in EA’s previously released roadmap</a>, <em>BF6</em>‘s first season (and all future seasons) will be split into multiple phases with different themes and battle passes. Season one’s first phase is titled “Rogue Ops” and will add three new weapons, a new armored APC, a new mode, and, perhaps most excitingly for fans, a new map.</p>

 <p>Earlier this week, EA and Battlefield Studios held an hour-long preview session for <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/10/22/battlefield-6-season-1-first-details-and-hands-on-report/"><em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s upcoming first season</a>. In this preview, we were able to go hands-on with the content being added in Rogue Ops, as well as some of the content coming in phase two of season one. I played a few matches of <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-reverts-conquest-ticket-change-48-hours-angry-backlash-2000636658">Conquest</a> on the first new map coming this season, Blackwell Fields, and came away unsure of it, but then played Eastwood, which will be added later, and had a fantastic time.</p>

  <h2><em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s first new map is just fine</h2> <p>The new map, which is located in an oil field in California, doesn’t feel very big. It’s also a very empty and sparse map, with rolling hills often being the only cover you can hope for when crossing the map to reach a new area. Snipers and aircraft were extremely deadly on this map, and I often found myself frustrated by how much the infantry was at a disadvantage. The map just feels too barren and small to support a mode like Conquest. Perhaps with more time, I’ll learn to love Blackwell Fields, but for now, I’m lukewarm on the map. At the very least, it’s a very pretty map as the sun is setting during your fight, leading to some gorgeous colors and shadows.</p>

 <p>While checking out the new map, I played around with the new armored APC, the Traverser Mk. 2. This vehicle came in handy on Blackwell Fields as it provides a safe way for soldiers to get around the battlefield quickly, is packed with mounted weapons, and can even support an integrated med bay to heal allies who hop in. The new APC is such a perfect fit for <em>BF6</em>, offering something more powerful than a jeep, but less bulky than a tank, that I’m a bit shocked it didn’t ship with the game earlier this month.</p>

 <p>I also checked out the new weapons. The new Glock pistol is fine, but who really cares about a pistol in <em>Battlefield 6</em>? That’s just the gun you pull out when you are desperate or need to complete a daily challenge. The other two new weapons are the SOR-300C carbine and the Mini Fix sniper rifle.</p>

 <p>I played a lot of the preview with the carbine, and I’m still not sure if it will dethrone the M4, but I did enjoy it. Its slower rate of fire and heavier-hitting bullets make it feel more like an assault rifle than a carbine, and it can hold its own in midrange fights. However, in close-quarters combat, I felt like SMGs and faster-firing carbines often beat me in one-on-one fights. Meanwhile, the Mini Fix sniper rifle seems like it might become the rifle of choice for recon players as it hits hard, fires fast, and is extremely accurate. In the hands of a skilled sniper, this might be too powerful. I could see EA nerfing it a tad in a future update. We’ll have to wait and see how things shake out.</p>

 <p>The other bit of Rogue Ops I played during the preview was Strikepoint, a 4v4 mode king-of-the-hill-like mode with limited respawning. It’s…certainly a new game mode. I just don’t understand why<a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-reveal-la-event-behind-the-scenes-brie-larson-ea-2000614190"> EA and Battlefield Studios</a> continue to spend so much time and energy on these tiny, tactical modes. <em>Battlefield</em> is all about big moments, chaotic warfare, and silly moments involving tanks, choppers, bombs, and more.</p> <h2>Eastwood is a new map that people are going to love</h2> <p>The best part of the preview was when I got to play the other new map, Eastwood. This map is set in a rich Southern California suburb, complete with McMansions, pools, and even a golf course nearby with drivable golf carts. This map felt very big, is filled with vehicles, and has plenty of houses and buildings for infantry to duck into during more explosive or dangerous moments. After playing it for just an hour or so, I quickly fell in love with it and can’t wait to play more. Sadly, this map won’t be added to the game until phase two of the first season, which launches on November 18.</p> <p>I personally would have led with Eastwood as the first new map added to <em>BF6</em>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-bigger-maps-leak-datamine-eastwood-mirak-ea-bf-labs-2000618202">as it seems to offer the giant, vehicle-filled chaos that some fans believe the new entry lacks.</a> It’s also just a visually distinct, super memorable, and fantastic map with lots of places to fight and wild moments to get involved in. At one point during the preview, some folks from both teams orchestrated a golf cart race. Well, they tried. A helicopter pilot flew by and wiped out some of the racers. Another great moment involved a tank crashing through the large mansion I was hiding in and then getting trapped in the backyard pool, letting me destroy it with some rockets. No idea why EA isn’t shipping this map first, but at least we all have something to look forward to next month.</p> <p>After playing a lot of season one’s new content, I came away excited for<em> Battlefield 6</em>‘s future, even if some of the new content<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->like the new tiny modes and boring pistol<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->don’t do much for me. I’m just happy to see that so soon after launch, EA has big plans and new stuff for its popular online shooter. And if future maps can be as great as Eastwood, I think the next year for <em>Battlefield 6</em> will be a good one. And who knows, maybe I’ll end up liking Blackwell Fields eventually.<em>&nbsp;Battlefield 6</em> is out now on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. Season one launches on October 28 on all platforms.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-first-new-map-review-season-1-blackwell-fields-eastwood-update-2000638228]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky Goes Full Space Pirate In Latest Free Update]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-nms-breach-corvette-update-2000638257</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-man%E2%80%99s-sky-goes-full-space-pirate-in-latest-free-update.1331899/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s free update time for <i>No Man’s Sky</i> again. Keep your wallet in your back pocket or purse, because Hello Games just shipped “Breach” which, among other things, allows you to harvest materials from stranded shipwrecks out there in the infinity of simulated space.</p> <p>Announced via a <a href="https://youtu.be/eNaY10DQkJw">brisk 51-second trailer on YouTube</a>, “<a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/2025/10/expedition-twenty-breach/">Breach</a>” is the latest free <i>NMS</i> update from developer Hello Games. The update boasts a new expedition as well as the introduction of drifting space wrecks from which you can salvage new ship parts. It feels like a subtle update in some ways, but one that builds well on the foundations laid in <a href="https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-voyagers-6-0-star-trek-mass-effect-2000620674">the previous update, Voyagers,</a> which included epic <a href="https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-corvette-ship-build-voyagers-update-star-wars-2000630689">custom ship build options</a> and the ability to spacewalk.</p>

  <p>As always, the new update’s release followed a trail of cryptic tweets from managing director Sean Murray, this time with a series of closed-door emoji. It naturally sent the community into a frenzy of speculation.</p>

   <p>Unfortunately for those on the r/LightNoFireHelloGames subreddit, which is dedicated to the studio’s upcoming <a href="https://youtu.be/jKQem4Z6ioQ">full-scale planet sim</a>, the doors had nothing to with <i>Light No Fire</i>. Some <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LightNoFireHelloGames/comments/1o9grvf/guys_guys_this_is_it/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">folks had speculated that the door</a> was a reference to the band The Doors who have a song called “Light My Fire.” Things are desperate over there, ya’ll.</p>

   <p>Sorry, guys. That wasn’t it.</p> <h2>Also, check out these awesome user-made ships</h2> <p>Look, I’m probably not gonna get away with writing a “15 Awesome Ship Builds” showcase every week, much as I would like to. But I see so much cool shit coming out of the <i>NMS</i> community that I just have to share this stuff with you.</p>

 <p>Here’s the complete Death Star build I <a href="https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-voyagers-death-star-star-wars-2000635367">told ya’ll about last week</a>. Too sick:</p>   <p>This “Venator Class Star Destroyer” looks clean and awesome:</p>   <p>This mod-free build is a whole damn natural wildlife habitat just cruising through space like it’s no big deal.</p>

   <p>Fancy a solid X-Wing build?</p>   <p>Or how about an original build inspired by <i>Star Wars</i>’ weathered space junk aesthetic?</p>   <p>A’right, that’s enough outta me. If you spot something cool in this game, please don’t hesitate to shoot me an email at cjackson [at] kotaku [dot] com. Safe travels out there!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-nms-breach-corvette-update-2000638257]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>