<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:40:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS Goes All-In on Gaming Handheld Console, ROG Xbox Ally 7″ Hits a Record Low as 2026 Begins]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-all-in-on-gaming-handheld-console-rog-xbox-ally-7-hits-a-record-low-as-2026-begins-2000656361</link>
            <guid>1395862</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Tired of being forced to sit by your computer if you want to play your favorite games? A portable PC like the Steam Deck is a great alternative. But that’s not the only gig in town. The ASUS ROG Xbox Ally 7″ FHD Gaming Handheld Console is a great alternative, and you can get one for a great price right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6646/">In fact, you can get it at Amazon for the time being for for $909.99 (a savings of $90 and approximately a 9% discount) versus its typical retail price of $999.99.</a> That’s not too shabby.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6646/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A flexible portable PC that can play all your favorite games</h2>
<p>This isn’t in any way a budget handheld, so it’s premium in just about every way. It has a 7-inch full HD resolution display that can make all your favorite titles super bright and detailed, and you get plenty of screen real estate. Regardless of whether you’re playing action-packed video games, exploring vast open world RPGs, or participating in fast-paced racing games, the display provides crystal-clear images and vibrant colors.</p>
<p>One of the main advantages of the ASUS ROG Xbox Ally is its processing performance. It has a powerful processor for (very necessary) graphics capabilities, so it can run all the latest games. That means you’ll notice smooth frame rates and quick response times, which are important when you’re fighting in action games, performing combos, or competing in timed matches. Performance also allows for multitasking, enabling you to easily transition between video games, applications and media content, without having to deal with slow-down due to lag.</p>



<p>A common problem associated with handheld gaming devices is battery life. Luckily, the. ROG Xbox Ally provides you with sufficient battery life for multiple gaming sessions before needing to be charged again. In addition to this, when you do need to charge the device, the included AC power adapter will recharge the battery quickly, so you don’t spend a lot of time waiting for it to fully charge and then resume your gaming session.</p>
<p>Overall, the combination of the ROG Xbox Ally’s powerful performance, sharp display, and comfortable controls positions it as a premium handheld gaming system suitable for serious gamers. It’s also a fantastic alternative to the Steam Deck that isn’t beholden to the constraints of the Steam platform.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6646/">All you have to do is make sure you grab one now that it’s gone down in price.</a> For just $909.99 on Amazon (from the regular price of $999.99), it’s one of the best picks you can get right now in terms of both portability and power so that you can play your favorite games wherever you go.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6646/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-all-in-on-gaming-handheld-console-rog-xbox-ally-7-hits-a-record-low-as-2026-begins-2000656361]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Pixel Buds Pro 2 Drop to All-Time Low to Start the New Year, Now Priced Like Older Models Despite Being 2025’s Latest ANC Earbuds]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-drop-to-all-time-low-to-start-the-new-year-now-priced-like-older-models-despite-being-2025s-latest-anc-earbuds-2000656364</link>
            <guid>1395832</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Looking for a new set of earbuds that sound absolutely fantastic? If money is a concern, you should skip some of the more expensive models and try the Google Pixel Buds Pro 2. They’ll offer some extra sound for the price and some serious oomph. All you have to do is lock yours in before they’re no longer on sale.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6645/">You can get the Google Pixel Buds Pro 2 at Amazon for $179 right now. That’s $50 less than the typical $229 price.</a> That represents a $50 discount and a savings of about 22% compared to retail.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6645/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Excellent, comfortable earbuds with great noise cancellation</h2>
<p>These earbuds are extremely light with soft ear tips, so they’re comfortable to wear for long periods of time. They’re able to seal the ear canal better than other earbuds of this caliber, which gives you more bass and more accurate midrange sounds, so you can turn the volume back down and still be able to enjoy your music.</p>
<p>Fast songs sound alive, so to speak, with clean and distinct vocals. Even complex song mixes sound clear, with podcasts and audiobooks are also a pleasure to listen to because voices sound very natural and easy to understand.</p>
<p>Noise cancellation is another feature that helps you concentrate on whatever you’re listening to by blocking out surrounding distractions such as street noise, conversation, or train noises, allowing you to be able to listen to your audio at lower volumes. With Transparency Mode, you can also listen to ambient noise by allowing the surrounding environment to seep into the earbuds, to let you to hear traffic, or talking if you need to make sure you know what’s going on around you.</p>



<p>The battery life is excellent for wireless earbuds and gives you plenty of hours of playback per charge. The charging case is also a bonus as it gives you additional power when needed and also serves as a portable charging station, allowing you to charge the earbuds on-the-go via a USB-C cable or wireless charging pad.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Pixel Buds Pro 2 work seamlessly with applications and intelligent features that make customizing your experience easy. You can fine-tune sound settings, configure the earbuds’ controls, and even upgrade the earbuds’ firmware remotely. That alone saves some precious time where you need it the most.</p>
<p>For under $200, the Google Pixel Buds Pro 2 are super affordable and a great option if you want good audio. Give them a try and save some serious cash while reaping the benefits of excellent earbuds.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6645/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/google-pixel-buds-pro-2-drop-to-all-time-low-to-start-the-new-year-now-priced-like-older-models-despite-being-2025s-latest-anc-earbuds-2000656364]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel’s Next Big Show Finally Has A Trailer Well Worth Watching]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marvels-wonder-man-trailer-ben-kingsley-disney-plus-2000656416</link>
            <guid>1395823</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Wonder Man and Trevor in very different reactions.</span> © Marvel / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Marvel’s&nbsp;<em>Wonder Man</em> finally arrives on Disney+ January 27, and somewhat belatedly has received a trailer that actually gives us an idea of the show. And it looks&nbsp;<em>really</em> good! The new trailer, that introduces the three main characters, is delivered with wit and—at last—some action. We’ve got Wonder Man himself Simon Williams (Yahya Abdul-Mateen II), former <em>Iron Man&nbsp;</em>fake terrorist Trevor Slattery (Ben Kingsley), and maverick director Von Kovak (Zlatko Buric), in a program that intends to send up the production of superhero movies, while telling a superhero story of its own.</p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-wonder-man-trailer-disney-mcu-2000634087">Previous trailers</a> have been weirdly shy of showing Simon Williams at all, instead peculiarly focusing on the secondary leads, and absolutely avoiding showing even a hint of Wonder Man’s wonder. Thank goodness that’s now over. The promo playfully riffs on Rossini’s <em>The Barber of Seville</em>, introducing us to the main players, and then at long last setting up the actual ongoing story of the show. Things begin with Williams auditioning to play Wonder Man in a remake of a (fictional) 1970s cult hit, while hiding the fact that he himself has superpowers. The director of the movie is the eccentric Von Kovak, a former Oscar winner now lowering himself to the popularism and tired field of superhero movies in an attempt to revive the genre. Meanwhile, actual Oscar winner Ben Kingsley reprises his role of Trevor, the actor hired to play terrorist Mandarin in <em>Iron Man 3</em>, who then also appeared in&nbsp;<em>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</em>, as well as his own one-shot&nbsp;<em>All Hail the King</em>.</p>

 <p>We get to see Williams’ powers appearing, from his purple sparkles in his eyes (perhaps rather unfortunately reminiscent of DC’s&nbsp;<em>Black Lightning</em>), and then an awful lot of rumbling, wobbling rooms, and explodifying a table.</p>  <p>I’ve not quite known what to think before now, mostly because the preview coverage has seemed so afraid to show us Wonder Man at all, making me suspicious it was trying to hide something. But seeing Abdul-Mateen II at last shows anything but. The actor, best known for playing Manta in the <em>Aquaman</em> movies and Morpheus in the lackluster <em>The Matrix Resurrections</em>, demonstrates excellent comedy chops in the short clips.</p>

 <p>There’s only a few weeks left to find out if it all comes together, and if Marvel can add a new compelling live-action Disney+ show to its slate following eight months of nothing, to accompany last year’s splendid <em>Daredevil: Born Again</em>, but following&nbsp;the confused and disappointing <em>Ironheart</em>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marvels-wonder-man-trailer-ben-kingsley-disney-plus-2000656416]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Keeps the M5 iPad Pro at Its Year-End Clearance Pricing, Extending the Lowest Deal Into the New Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-keeps-the-m5-ipad-pro-at-its-year-end-clearance-pricing-extending-the-lowest-deal-into-the-new-year-2000656226</link>
            <guid>1395811</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A powerful and visually impressive device for those who want professional grade capability at home and on the road; the Apple iPad Pro 13-inch (M5) is the perfect tablet. It’s also a viable replacement for a laptop if you need it for those types of work or play on the go. And right now, you can save a significant amount of money on one.</p>
<p>It’s true: you can get <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6644/">the Apple iPad Pro 13-inch (M5) on Amazon today for the low price of $1,199, which represents a savings of $100, or approximately 8%, from its original price of $1,299</a>. If you’ve been waiting on a good time to lock one in for yourself, it’s right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6644/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A luxurious and powerful iPad that can handle anything</h2>
<p>It has an eye-catching display that you’ll appreciate the first time you unbox it and turn it on. It’s smooth, responsive, and massively colorful. So no matter if you’re working on the go, creating art, or just playing games, you’ll be doing it in style.</p>
<p>Performance-wise, the M5 processor gives the iPad Pro 13-inch plenty of power Apps load quickly, switching between applications happens smoothly, and resource intensive processes such as video editing, and 3D modeling are also processed by the processor with no issues. That means you won’t have to worry about unnecessary lag.</p>
<p>In addition to the capabilities provided by the M5 processor, the iPad Pro’s ability to be paired with accessories further enhances its versatility. For example, you can attach a Magic Keyboard and type on it like you would on a laptop, use the Apple Pencil to draw or write with precision, and attach to external monitors or storage devices to increase your workspace.</p>



<p>It has a lengthy battery life, too. It’ll let you continue using your device throughout a full day of work, play, and browsing, without having to charge it again. You can easily switch back and forth between phone calls, movie streams, and web surfing without being tied to a charger.</p>
<p>When the time does come to recharge, the iPad Pro 13-inch has a fast charging system to get you ready to go again quickly and efficiently.</p>
<p>Features like Wi-Fi and optional cell service help you stay connected to the internet regardless of where you choose to work, relax, etc. Additionally, you can connect an Apple Pencil, controller, headphones, and other peripherals with Bluetooth if you need.</p>
<p>This is a tablet that features a gorgeous screen, lengthy battery life, and easy connectivity to the iOS ecosystem, if you’re already on it. An iPad always makes for a great piece of tech, so if you’re interested in upgrading or just want a tablet for the first time, you’re making a great decision by getting an iPad.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6644/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-keeps-the-m5-ipad-pro-at-its-year-end-clearance-pricing-extending-the-lowest-deal-into-the-new-year-2000656226]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>