<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:10:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard And Other Developers Pay Tribute To A Legend: ‘Vince Was The Real Deal’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vince-zampella-metal-gear-hideo-kojima-2000667819</link>
            <guid>1432987</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Some of the best-known names in game development are in Las Vegas this week for the annual DICE Summit and one of the first orders of business is <a href="https://kotaku.com/vince-zampella-death-car-crash-tributes-reactions-2000655379">paying tribute to the late Vince Zampella</a>. “His legacy isn’t just in the franchises or awards,” EA Entertainment president Laura Miele said, according to <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/vince-zampella-dice-tribute">an on-the-ground report by <em>Game File</em></a>. “It lives in every studio that chooses trust over fear, craft over shortcuts, people over ego.”</p> <p>Bethesda’s Todd Howard, <em>Metal Gear</em> creator Hideo Kojima, and others appeared via pre-recorded video segments to share memories of and tributes to the man who helped shape and shepherd some of the biggest studios and franchises in gaming. “Vince was the real deal,” Howard said.&nbsp;“I would always seek his advice with every game that I did, or how to maneuver on all that is going on in the industry.”</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">At DICE, Hideo Kojima revealed that he had many discussions with Vince Zampella about creating a first person Metal Gear Solid game together after the release of Metal Gear Solid 4. <a href="https://t.co/hhjbCqG7T2">pic.twitter.com/hhjbCqG7T2</a></p> <p>— Geoff Keighley (@geoffkeighley) <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffkeighley/status/2021671381382181056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 11, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Zampella died tragically and unexpectedly <a href="https://kotaku.com/report-vince-zampella-battlefield-boss-and-call-of-duty-co-creator-killed-in-car-crash-2000655216">in a car crash last December</a> that also claimed the life of his passenger. He worked on <em>Medal of Honor</em> in the early 2000s before cofounding Infinity Ward to lead<em> Call of Duty</em>. He later cofounded a new studio, Respawn Entertainment, amid an acrimonious split with Activision over studio bonuses. At the time of his death he had become an executive president at EA overseeing <em>Battlefield</em> and other franchises.</p> <h2>The first-person <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> that wasn’t</h2> <p>Kojima, who had his own messy split with publisher Konami back in the 2010s, said Zampella took him on a tour of Respawn while he was in the process of getting <em>Death Stranding</em> maker Kojima Productions off the ground. “He gave me a lot of support and advice,” Kojima said, <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/vince-zampella-dice-tribute">according to <em>Game File</em></a>. “He showed me his studio, and I incorporated some of the good aspects into our own studio.”</p>

 <p>Kojima <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/2021671381382181056">even revealed</a> that the two had at one pointed talked about possibly collaborating on a first-person <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> shooter sometime after <em>Metal Gear Solid 4</em> was released in 2008. Howard added that he’d previously nominated Zampella for a lifetime achievement award, but he’d refused to accept the honor.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vince-zampella-metal-gear-hideo-kojima-2000667819]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch’s New Hero Is Basically Master Chief And Turns The Game Into Halo]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-new-heroes-emre-halo-master-chief-rifle-grenade-2000667827</link>
            <guid>1432951</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>One of the best ways to get someone into a hero shooter is to compare a character they don’t know to one they have intimate knowledge with. I haven’t played a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-campaign-master-chief-release-date-2000651439"><i><span>Halo </span></i><span>game</span></a><span> in over a decade, so I didn’t clock that Emre, one of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-new-heroes-story-sigma-dialogue-sombra-talon-2000667771"><i><span>Overwatch</span></i><span>’s new heroes</span></a><span>, feels a lot like Master Chief from Bungie’s classic shooters. But some friends I was playing with last night made the comparison, and then I woke up this morning to find the internet is </span><a href="https://x.com/bentoDRAWS/status/2021347046469533930?s=20"><span>running wild with it</span></a><span>.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Very nice of them to add a Halo guy to Overwatch <a href="https://t.co/3IKSLenHXQ">pic.twitter.com/3IKSLenHXQ</a></p> <p>— bento (comms open!!) (@bentoDRAWS) <a href="https://twitter.com/bentoDRAWS/status/2021347046469533930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 10, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Emre is definitely cut from the Soldier: 76 cloth in that his kit is one of the more straightforward shooter movesets in the game. He’s got a three-round burst rifle on which he can aim down sights without losing any of his movement speed, a side arm that fires explosive rounds and makes him run fast, and an ultimate that lets him fly and rain fire down on his enemies. But he also has frag grenades that bounce around just like Master Chief’s do in </span><i><span>Halo</span></i><span>, and both those and his rifle seem to be immediately activating long-dormant muscle memory for those who haven’t played as Microsoft’s mascot for a bit.</span></p>

   <p><span>If you upgrade his perks accordingly, Emre’s grenade can also stick to enemies, much like the plasma grenades from </span><i><span>Halo</span></i><span>, so the comparisons just keep coming. If you were considering getting into </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-spotlight-new-heroes-perks-stadium-returning-2000665736"><i><span>Overwatch </span></i><span>after its soft reboot</span></a><span> this week and don’t know who to pick first, Emre might be an easy place to start. There are 50 heroes now with varying degrees of complexity, and starting with more simple heroes is a good way to acclimate yourself to all the chaos. Just don’t panic when you see </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-jetpack-cat-tether-bob-dva-ultimate-flight-2000666163"><span>a flying cat</span></a><span> carrying a giant German man with a hammer over the battlefield.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-new-heroes-emre-halo-master-chief-rifle-grenade-2000667827]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Devs Dance While Striking: ‘Yves Guillemot Has No Knowledge Or Understanding Of His Company’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-strike-assassins-creed-delay-cancel-rto-layoffs-2000667820</link>
            <guid>1432930</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Ubisoft developers are striking outside the company’s Paris offices this week. Over 1,200 of them, according to union reps. They’re dancing, too, as they call on the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> maker to reverse its controversial return-to-office policy and call for <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-earnings-layoffs-delays-canceled-ai-2000661869">accountability from its top executives</a>, including co-founder Yves Guillemot.</p> <p>“At this stage, it seems clear to us that Yves Guillemot has no knowledge or understanding of his company or its employees,” Solidaires Informatique union representative at Ubisoft Paris Marc Rutschlé <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/at-least-1200-ubisoft-workers-strike-in-response-to-recent-restructuring">told <em>Gamesindustry.biz</em></a>.&nbsp;“The company is continuing its cost reduction and layoff plan. Our teams are already working under pressure, often understaffed. After several years without pay rises (or very small increases), we understand that once again, employees will not receive a raise this year.”</p>

 <p>On February 10, the first day of the this week’s strike, speakers were blaring the 2014 Game Boy chiptune banger “<a href="https://soundcloud.com/kenobit/kenobit-disco-sanwa-2014">Disco Sanwa” by Kenobit</a>. Developers danced even in the rain while protesting the direction of the company.</p>   <p>The three-day strike this week includes developers at Ubisoft Milan as well and comes after the French publisher announced a new emergency pivot that included delaying some big games and cancelling many others. In addition to a fresh cost-cutting program that amounts to another 200 layoffs, and annual raises that have shrunk during hard times, Ubisoft is calling for employees to go back to being in the office full-time by the end of 2026.</p>

 <p>That message, delivered by CEO Yves Guillemot in an internal email and recent townhall meetings, <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-stock-restructure-layoffs-cancel-delay-2000662684">has gone over like a lead balloon</a>, not least of all because of the person who’s delivering it. Despite saying the company needs to change and evolve, Guillemot and his brothers, who founded it back in the 1980s, remain in charge thanks in part to a $1 billion bailout by Tencent.</p>

 <p>One employee in Canada <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-montreal-lead-fired-david-michaud-cromp-work-from-home-linkedin-2000665081">was fired for the way he criticized the new policies</a> in work channels, which Ubisoft said violated the company’s code of conduct. Unlike France, Ubisoft’s major Canadian studios in Montreal, Quebec, and Toronto are not unionized. Ubisoft’s smaller mobile gaming team in Canada briefly unionized earlier this year <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-halifax-shutdown-unionized-rainbow-six-mobile-2000657752">but was subsequently shut down</a>. The company said the closure had nothing to do with the labor organizing.</p> <p>Unions <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/stjv.fr/post/3mejkg2umyl2q">blamed this week’s walkout</a> on the “arbitrary decision of the CEO who doesn’t even dare talking to employees anymore.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-strike-assassins-creed-delay-cancel-rto-layoffs-2000667820]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>