<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:24:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie’s Marathon Will Be Free To Try During A Server Slam Ahead Of Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marathon-free-demo-beta-weekend-server-slam-2000668383</link>
            <guid>1434685</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A new trailer for&nbsp;<em>Marathon</em> showed off the <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-runner-shells-trailer-abilities-bungie-2000660170">grim trauma lurking beneath the surface of the extraction shooter’s colorful Tau Ceti IV planetary environments</a>, but it teased more than just sci-fi horror worldbuilding. Bungie also revealed the dates for the game’s pre-launch beta, giving players one last chance to go hands-on before deciding whether to fork over $40 for Sony’s latest live-service multiplayer game.</p> <p><em>Marathon</em>‘s pre-launch “server slam” goes live on February 26 and will run through March 2, just a few days before the game’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-release-date-trailer-leak-bungie-2000660975">full release date on March 5</a>. Players will be able to dive into the game for free on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC with the limited demo coinciding with the upcoming Steam Next Fest. While you don’t need to pre-order the game to get in, you’ll need a PS Plus or Game Pass Core subscription to access the server slam on consoles.</p>

  <p>The open beta will feature a “limited selection of maps, Runner shells, and contracts” for players to test out, with more maps, factions, contracts, gear, and other content coming at launch and during Season 1. While progress won’t carry over to the full game, players can earn tiered gear packages that will then come in handy when they get started in the loot extraction shooter once it’s out.</p> <p>PS Plus subscribers will also get the chance to unlock a handful of exclusive rewards to show they participated in the server slam: special emblems and banners linked to other PlayStation franchises. Those include weapon charms from <em>Helldivers 2</em>,<em> Death Stranding 2</em>, and <em>Ghost of Yotei</em>. Xbox and PC players will be able to earn them too at some point, though it’s not clear how yet. <em>Marathon</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-art-director-budget-development-2000661252">went through a rough patch last year</a> but recent leaks of a playtest in China suggested things have improved quite a bit since the original alpha test.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marathon-free-demo-beta-weekend-server-slam-2000668383]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Saw At Today’s PlayStation State Of Play]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/playstation-state-of-play-sony-ps5-god-war-castlevania-kena-castlevania-2000668291</link>
            <guid>1434607</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I feel like these digital showcases keep getting longer, and Sony’s latest State of Play was a beefy. hour-long show of new games coming to the PS5. If you weren’t able to catch the stream live, you can watch it below, but if you just want the highlights, read on.</p>  <h2><em>Kena: Scars of Kosmora</em></h2>  <p>Kicking off the show is&nbsp;<em>Kena: Scars of Kosmora</em>, a sequel to <em>Kena: Bridge of Spirits</em>. We see a bit of its fantasy action and its open world, all with a slightly older Kena leading the way. Gosh, it sure is pretty. Was the first one this <em>Horizon</em>-esque? It’s coming to PS5 and PC later this year.</p>

 <h2><em>Ghost of Yotei Legends</em></h2>  <p>Sucker Punch is up next with <em>Legends</em>, the co-op multiplayer side of <em>Ghost of Yotei</em>. We saw four playable classes working together in what looks like raids against demon armies. It launches on March 10.</p> <h2><em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em></h2>  <p>Kojima’s latest is making the leap from PS5 to PC on March 19.</p> <h2><em>4: LOOP</em></h2>  <p>Bad Robot Studios is up next with <em>4: LOOP</em>, a cooperative sci-fi shooter with gross monsters, roguelike-esque routes, and endlessly replayable missions. The game will get a beta test later this year.</p>

 <h2><em>Pragmata</em></h2>  <p>Next up we get a look at Capcom’s upcoming puzzle shooter&nbsp;<em>Pragmata</em>. This trailer had a bit of a character-driven focus, with its two leads talking about their pasts before getting chased by some gross-ass monsters. The game launches on April 24, and a demo is available now.</p>

 <h2><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em></h2>  <p><em>Resident Evil Requiem </em>is just about two weeks away, so I guess Capcom wanted one more chance to put it in front of people. The game stars Grace and Leon in a dueling story of methodical horror and high-octane action. We also see Leon returning to his old Raccoon City police department.</p> <h2><em>Legacy of Kain: Defiance Remastered</em></h2>  <p>A remaster of <em>Legacy of Kain: Defiance&nbsp;</em>is coming to PS4 and PS5, bringing a new coat of paint, photo mode, third-person camera, and some behind-the-scenes special features. It launches on March 3.</p>

 <h2><em>Brigadine Abyss</em></h2>  <p>The latest entry in the fantasy strategy RPG series is coming to PS5 later this year.</p> <h2><em>Dead or Alive 6 Last Round</em></h2>  <p><i>Dead or Alive 6&nbsp;</i>is getting an update with&nbsp;<em>Last Round</em>, which adds new characters, costumes, and a photo mode, and it’ll get further updates in the following months. It launches on June 25 with both a paid premium version and a free-to-play edition.</p>  <p>Also, a new&nbsp;<em>Dead or Alive. </em>game is officially in development.</p> <h2><em>Control Resonant</em></h2> <p>Next we got a lengthy gameplay showcase for&nbsp;<em>Control Resonant</em>, the upcoming action sequel to&nbsp;<em>Control</em>. It looks like it will scratch a&nbsp;<em>Devil May Cry&nbsp;</em>itch you might be feeling…ya know, if we get to the end of this presentation and we’re still lacking on that front.</p>

 <h2><em>Crimson Moon</em></h2>  <p>I thought they were about to announce a new <em>Devil May Cry&nbsp;</em>right after I said, what with the metal music and all the talk in this trailer of being a demon half-breed. But no, it’s <em>Crimson Moon</em> and the dark fantasy action game is coming in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Beast of Reincarnation</em></h2>  <p>Oh look, Game Freak is showing up on another non-Nintendo showcase with <em>Beast of Reincarnation</em>, a fantasy action RPG from the team behind <em>Pokémon</em>. It’s launching on August 4.</p>

 <h2><em>Rayman: 30th Anniversary Edition</em></h2> <p>If you want to play multiple versions of the original&nbsp;<em>Rayman</em>, the sidescroller is being packaged with a bunch of behind-the-scenes special features. It’s coming out tomorrow digitally, with physical copies coming to stores on June 26.</p> <h2><em>Mina the Hollower</em></h2> <p>After several delays,&nbsp;<em>Mina the Hollower&nbsp;</em>is coming out later this year. You can play Yacht Club Games’ next project tomorrow with a PlayStation-exclusive demo.</p> <h2><em>Neva: Prologue</em></h2>  <p>A prequel to the 2024 puzzle platformer&nbsp;<em>Neva&nbsp;</em>is coming out on February 19.</p> <h2><em>Yakoh Shinobi Ops</em></h2>  <p><em>Yakoh Shionobi Ops&nbsp;</em>is a pretty violent stealth action co-op game coming to PS5 in 2027.</p>

 <h2><em>Project Windless</em></h2>  <p><em>Project</em> <em>Windless</em>, based on the Korean fantasy series <em>The Bird That Drinks Tears</em><em>, </em>basically looks like a musou game starring a sword-swinging bird man as he fights entire armies on his own.</p> <h2><em>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</em></h2>  <p>We got a look at the gameplay in upcoming <em>Star Wars </em>game&nbsp;<em>Galactic Racer</em>, and it looks like a pretty action-heavy arcade racer with a story set in a galaxy far, far away. It will launch later this year.</p> <h2><em>007: First Light</em></h2>  <p>Next we got a new look at <em>007: First Light</em> from&nbsp;<em>Hitman&nbsp;</em>developer IOI Interactive. The trailer focuses on how green and reckless the secret agent is in this origin story. The game launches on May 27.</p> <h2><em>Metal Gear Solid: Master Collection 2</em></h2>  <p>Konami got its own dedicated segment, which included a look at&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid</em>‘s second&nbsp;<em>Master Collection</em>. This will bring&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots&nbsp;</em>to PS5, liberating it from the PS3 for the first time. The compilation will also include <em>Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker</em>. The collection launches on August 27. The first <em>Master Collection&nbsp;</em>is also getting an update which bring a high-resolution option to the first and third <em>Metal Gear Solid&nbsp;</em>games.</p>

 <h2><em>Darwin’s Paradox</em></h2> <p>Taking a hard left turn, we see&nbsp;<em>Darwin’s Paradox</em>, a puzzle platformer starring an octopus. A demo is available now, with the full game coming on April 2.</p> <h2><em>Castlevania: Belmont’s Curse</em></h2>  <p>Perhaps the most exciting thing Konami brought to the show, however, was&nbsp;<em>Castlevania: Belmont’s Curse</em>, the first new 2D&nbsp;<em>Castlevania&nbsp;</em>game since 2008’s <em>Order of Ecclesia</em>. Konami is making the game with the help of Evil Empire and Motion Twin as a celebration of the series’ 40th anniversary.</p>

 <h2><em>Silent Hill: Townfall</em></h2>  <p>Okay, damn, I guess Konami’s just bringing out all its big guns.&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill: Townfall&nbsp;</em>is a collaboration between Konami and Annapurna, and it’s a first-person, methodical horror game. It’s coming in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Rev. Noir</em></h2>  <p>Alrighty, let’s get back into anime RPG mode with <em>Rev. Noir</em>. It’s a new JRPG that looks to draw heavily from games like <em>Tales&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy</em>, but we didn’t see much of it beyond a teaser that showed off its cast.</p>

 <h2><em>John Wick</em></h2>  <p><em>John Wick&nbsp;</em>is getting a new video game, and while we didn’t get to see much of the game itself in action, we did get to see Keanu wrecking dudes. It seems like Keanu Reeves is reprising the role for the game, too.</p> <h2><em>Marathon</em></h2>  <p>Next we got a new trailer for Bungie’s upcoming shooter <em>Marathon</em>. It leans into a pretty compelling sci-fi psychological thriller vibe. A preview weekend will take place from February 26 to March 2, all leading up to launch on March 5.</p> <h2>PlayStation Plus</h2> <p>As previously reported,&nbsp;<em>Spider-Man 2</em> is coming to PlayStation Plus on February 17. <em>Tekken: Dark Resurrection</em> is also coming to the the classics catalog in March, with&nbsp;<em>Time Crisis</em> joining in May.</p> <h2><em>Big Walk</em></h2>  <p><em>Big Walk&nbsp;</em>will launch as a PlayStation Plus game when it comes to PS5 in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Saros</em></h2>  <p>Housemarque showed up to show off more of&nbsp;<em>Saros</em>, its upcoming roguelike shooter starring&nbsp;<em>Fall of the House of Usher </em>actor Rahul Kohli, and got real into the nitty-gritty of its systems. It seems like a pretty tough game, which is par for the course for the <em>Returnal&nbsp;</em>developer, though with persistent upgrades available here, it may also be considerably more approachable for those who bounced off that last one.</p>

 <h2><em>Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls</em></h2>  <p>Next we have new&nbsp;<em>X-Men</em>&nbsp;fighters joining the roster of Arc System Works’ <em>Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls</em>, including Storm, Magik, Wolverine, and Danger. The game is coming to PS5 and PC on August 6.</p> <h2><em>God of War</em></h2>  <p>The original <em>God of War&nbsp;</em>trilogy is getting a full remake for PS5, but that’s all we know. TC Carson, the original voice actor for Kratos, showed up to&nbsp;tease the project, which is in the “early stages.”</p>  <p>Mega Cat Studios also showed off a sidescrolling&nbsp;<em>God of War&nbsp;</em>game called&nbsp;<em>Sons of Sparta</em> set in Greece, which follows a much younger Kratos, and is out today.</p> <p>Damn. No&nbsp;<em>Devil May Cry</em>, despite the rumors. Well, that went by quicker than I thought. And hey, I have one more&nbsp;<em>God of War&nbsp;</em>game to play than I did an hour ago.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/playstation-state-of-play-sony-ps5-god-war-castlevania-kena-castlevania-2000668291]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Surprise-Drops A Retro 2D God Of War Prequel You Can Play Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/god-war-sons-sparta-prequel-2d-retro-shadowdrop-2000668367</link>
            <guid>1434601</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’re not getting a new 3D <em>God of War</em> just yet, but Sony did end today’s big PlayStation Showcase with a surprise shadowdrop for a 2D spin-off. <em>God of War Sons of Sparta</em> is a retro action platformer that takes Kratos’ story back to the beginning.</p> <p>“<em>God of War Sons of Sparta</em> is a 2D action platformer with a canon story set in Kratos’ youth during his brutal training at the Spartan Agoge alongside his brother Deimos,” reads the official description. “They must overcome threats that will put all their training to the test while confronting the true meaning of duty and honor.”</p>

 <p>Take a look:</p>  <p>Kratos will take on various beasts from Greek mythology with his sword and shield as he acquires Gifts of Olympus to unlock new abilities. It looks like how you remember beautiful pixel art action games from the Sega Genesis era looking, but way better. Hopefully it plays well too.</p> <p>It’s been developed by Mega Cat Studios, which shipped 2023’s <em>WrestleQuest</em> and recently brought back the <em>Backyard</em> sports games, in partnership with Santa Monica Studio. It’s currently available to download on PlayStation 5 for $30.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/god-war-sons-sparta-prequel-2d-retro-shadowdrop-2000668367]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Original God Of War Trilogy Getting A Full Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/original-god-of-war-trilogy-getting-a-full-remake-2000668356</link>
            <guid>1434598</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>During today’s PlayStation State of Play, the first of the year, Sony Santa Monica Studio announced it has started work on a remake of the original <em>God of War</em> trilogy.</p> <p>Here’s the trailer for this newly announced project.</p>  <p>There’s not much to see in this new trailer, which is really just a tiny teaser announcement for the project. By far the best part of the teaser is TC Carson, the original voice actor for Kratos, showing up to be cool as heck and almost distracting me from the fact that this game is years away from release. Almost.</p> <p>“This project is still in the early stages,” teased Carson. “Next time we come back, we’re coming with something big.” The voice actor also confirmed he’ll be back as the voice of Kratos for this new project, and uh…that’s really it.</p>

 <p>While I’m excited for Carson’s return, I am definitely depressed to see another big video game franchise returning to the past with a remake instead of pushing forward with something new. It reminds me of <em>Halo’s</em> recently announced remake of the OG game, which is coming to PS5 and Xbox later this year. While I get that some fans are excited to replay these games and others are happy to have a new way to hop in, I’m just sitting here worrying that we have entered an era when even massively popular franchises are unable to take risks on new ideas and have to rely on what came before them to stick around.</p> <p>On the other hand, during this same teaser reveal for a <em>God of War</em> trilogy remake, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2026/02/12/god-of-war-greek-trilogy-remake-in-development-god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-out-now/">PlayStation announced and released a new 2D <em>God of War</em> prequel</a> that looks fun and is the kind of thing I want to see more of from big companies. Let other studios play around with your franchises via smaller games with smaller budgets and less risk. That’s cool. <em>God of War: Sons of Sparta</em> is out today on PS5. The remake trilogy is years away, but in development.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/original-god-of-war-trilogy-getting-a-full-remake-2000668356]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>