<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 18:10:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stardew Valley And Two Other Great Games Will Be Free On PlayStation Plus Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-and-two-other-great-games-will-be-free-on-playstation-plus-next-week-2000620727</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stardew-valley-and-two-other-great-games-will-be-free-on-playstation-plus-next-week.1282212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The next batch of PlayStation Plus freebies is arriving next week and it’s a darn good haul of games, including the beloved indie blockbuster <em>Stardew Valley.</em></p> <p><a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/08/27/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-september-psychonauts-2-stardew-valley-viewfinder/">On August 27</a>, as is usual around the end of the month, Sony announced what next month’s free PS Plus games will be. These games are available to all tiers of PS Plus subscribers and will be available to grab and download starting September 2.&nbsp; All of these games can be played on PS5 or PS4.&nbsp; Here’s the full list:</p> <ul> <li><em>Psychonauts 2</em> – PS4</li> <li><em>Stardew Valley</em> – PS4</li> <li><em>Viewfinder</em> – PS4, PS5</li> </ul> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-past-present-and-future-of-stardew-valley-1766238624">The star of the show is likely to be <em>Stardew Valley</em>,</a> which appears to have never been given away as a PlayStation Plus game before. That seems wild to me! But hey, if you have not yet played this wildly popular cozy pixel-art life sim that features RPG combat, farming, and more, now is the perfect time to give it a shot. Personally, I’m more excited that more people will get a chance to play <a href="https://kotaku.com/psychonauts-2-the-kotaku-review-1847533536"><em>Psychonauts 2</em></a><a href="https://kotaku.com/psychonauts-2-the-kotaku-review-1847533536">, a fantastic 3D platformer</a> from Double Fine that I enjoyed a lot back in 2021. I highly recommend you set some time aside to play it. Finally, there’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/viewfinder-puzzle-game-pc-ps5-impressions-sad-owl-1850649178"><em>Viewfinder</em></a>, a neat first-person puzzle game with an interesting mechanic involving taking pictures and stepping into them. If you like <em>Portal</em> or other similar puzzle games, check this one out, too!</p> <p>Oh, and don’t wait around too much longer to grab last month’s collection of PlayStation Plus free games. <em>Lies of P, Day Z, </em>and <em>My Hero One’s Justice 2</em> won’t be free after September 1, so add them to your game library before then if you want to play any of them in the future. Also, keep in mind that you can only play these PS Plus games if you have an active PlayStation Plus Essential, Extra, or Premium membership.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-and-two-other-great-games-will-be-free-on-playstation-plus-next-week-2000620727]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Is About To Get Better For A Bunch Of People]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/game-pass-cloud-benefits-pc-handheld-streaming-2000620715</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-is-about-to-get-better-for-a-bunch-of-people.1282158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s been <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-price-increase-standard-console-ultimate-1851583866">just over a year</a> since Microsoft fractured its very good, very straightforward Game Pass subscription into a bunch of differently priced tiers that seemed designed to be as confusing as possible. The company is now throwing players who are subscribed to the cheapest Game Pass tiers a bone: increased access to PC and cloud gaming perks.</p> <p><a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/27/xbox-insiders-can-stream-and-play-in-new-ways-with-xbox-game-pass-starting-today/">The company is experimenting with</a> giving Game Pass Core ($10 a month) and Game Pass Standard ($15 a month) members limited access to certain games via the cloud and PC. Xbox Insiders can begin testing this initiative today, with a version of it seemingly planned to roll out to everyone in the not too distant future. The new benefit essentially adds cloud gaming support to all games in the Core (around 50 games) and Standard (over 400 games) libraries. It’ll also let players use cloud gaming for games they own that support the feature, something that was previously a benefit exclusive to Game Pass Ultimate.</p> <p>Microsoft says it will also make PC versions of some Core and Standard games as well. So if you’re already playing a game on console like <em>Grounded</em>, you can switch to playing the PC version without needing to buy it. This is also neat, though a bit less impressive. Many of the Game Pass Core and Game Pass Standard game are already Play Anywhere titles, meaning buying them on console gets you the PC version and vice-versa, so there’s an argument to be made that the Game Pass versions should have worked the same way. Plus all of this is a raw deal when you consider Game Pass PC, which gives people who didn’t buy an Xbox Series X/S access to way more games, including day-one releases, at a much cheaper price than their console-playing peers.</p> <p>Still, the latest Insider pilot program is the first step toward beginning to fill in many of these gaps as Microsoft tries to re-unify the gaming experience across different platforms. The Xbox Ally PC gaming handheld arrives in October with an Xbox-like OS layer, and the company’s next generation of hardware is expected to more closely resemble the openness of PC gaming. Of course, the biggest test of that vision lies in whether or not the company will be finally willing to do away with its requirement that console players pay to access multiplayer, a big component of why Game Pass is so expensive to begin with and one that doesn’t exist on PC.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/game-pass-cloud-benefits-pc-handheld-streaming-2000620715]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Bloodlines 2  Paid Day-One DLC Controversy Takes A Familiar Turn]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-dlc-clans-locked-paywall-2000620705</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-bloodlines-2-paid-day-one-dlc-controversy-takes-a-familiar-turn.1282107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Last week, it was revealed that upcoming open-world RPG <a href="https://kotaku.com/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-vtm-chinese-room-1851787361"><em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</em></a> would launch in October with two of its important, playable vampire clans locked behind $22 day-one DLC. This didn’t go over well with folks online. Now, the devs behind the sequel are planning to make some changes.</p> <p>On August 19, <em>Bloodlines 2</em> developers The Chinese Room and publisher Paradox announced at <a href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-onl-2025-resident-evil-silent-hill-silksong-2000618460">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a> that the long-awaited RPG sequel was finally launching on PC and consoles on October 21. This followed a lengthy and rocky development cycle, so for many fans, it was just nice to know<em> Bloodlines 2</em> was actually going to come out. However, <a href="https://kotaku.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-day-1-dlc-clans-2000618832">people soon discovered that two of the RPG’s six playable vampire clans would be locked behind a paywall</a>, which led to a backlash from fans. Now, likely in an attempt to calm everyone down before a scheduled upcoming stream, the studio is promising changes.</p> <p>On August 27, the official <em>World of Darkness T</em>witter account posted a link to a <em>Bloodlines 2</em> livestream happening today and <a href="https://x.com/worldofdarkness/status/1960639863432085868">shared this message</a> about the DLC controversy as a reply:</p>

 <blockquote><p>We are listening to you about <em>Bloodlines 2</em> &amp; the Lasombra &amp; Toreador clan access, &amp; we’re making adjustments to reflect this. We will share more information about this as soon as possible. Until then, join us TODAY on Twitch at 5PM CEST, where we’ll be showing off the game!</p></blockquote> <p>This is similar to a message that was posted by a community manager in the official Discord server for Va<em>mpire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</em>, as spotted by <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-developer-is-adjusting-its-plans-for-paid-clan-dlc/1100-6534304/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f"><em>GameSpot</em> and ResetEra users</a>.</p> <p>Fans were so upset about the clans being locked behind day-one DLC because in<em> Bloodlines 2</em>, vampire clans are a very big part of the RPG. They help determine your playstyle, affect the game’s story, and offer unique powers and abilities. And sure, you can <em>technically</em> get any clan’s powers by leveling up and spending enough resources, but it’s much harder to get abilities that aren’t offered by your selected clan. So locking two of them behind a paywall that requires you to buy an extra DLC or the most expensive version of<em> Bloodlines 2</em> was a frustrating choice.</p> <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-chinese-room-defend-bloodlines-2s-paywalled-vampire-clans-we-have-been-expanding-it-from-where-we-originally-planned-to-land-it">Last week, the devs told <em>RPS</em></a> that the reason for locking some content behind DLC was that <em>Bloodlines 2</em> had expanded beyond what was planned, and extra work had gone into making more and more content for the RPG. I also imagine Paradox wanted extra dollars after years and years of <a href="https://kotaku.com/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-new-release-date-1850804491">rocky development and delays</a>. While I get that making games ain’t cheap, locking clans behind a paywall was never going to go over well.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-dlc-clans-locked-paywall-2000620705]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>