<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:53:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s Not Too Late To Save Beloved Gaming Franchises That Have Become Too Big To Fail]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/too-big-to-fail-dead-space-titanfall-2-deus-ex-budget-2000657134</link>
            <guid>1414483</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Simon Dead Space fighting a monster.</span> © EA
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Dead Space </span></i><span>was revealed to be</span><a href="https://gamingbolt.com/dead-space-franchise-is-on-ice-ea-has-zero-plans-for-a-revival-rumor"> <span>permanently on ice</span></a><span> last year. We haven’t seen a non-VR version of the </span><i><span>Thief </span></i><span>franchise since 2014. </span><i><span>Deus Ex</span></i><span> has lain dormant for a decade. </span><i><span>Titanfall 2</span></i><span> also came out ten years ago. There hasn’t been a new 3D </span><i><span>Prince of Persia </span></i><span>for 16 years, and with</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-cancels-long-delayed-prince-of-persia-remake-black-flag-remake-delay-2000661866"> <span>this week’s news</span></a><span> it’s looking unlikely to return. So many massive, deeply loved gaming franchises are routinely being shelved by companies too afraid to gamble the nine-figure sums publishers believe is necessary for success. Yet there’s such an obvious solution!&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Every time I read a headline about a game franchise being shelved because it’s become too expensive, too big of a risk for a publisher to gamble $200 million on, I want to scream into the sky at the obviousness of the solution. But now, following the 2025 success of games like </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Arc Raiders</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Lies of P</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Helldivers 2</span></i><span>, surely the answer is clear to everyone? License these once big-name franchises to proven mid-size AA teams, and don’t interfere.</span></p>

 <p><span>In the wake of</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-earnings-layoffs-delays-canceled-ai-2000661869"> <span>Ubisoft’s latest</span></a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-share-price-crash-prince-of-persia-ai-2000662169"><span>disastrous</span></a><span> plan to rearrange itself by cancelling multiple projects, and the seemingly constant drip of major publishers shelving major franchises, all while giant company buys giant company for imaginary money, the industry has clearly got itself into a very bad place. Right now, during this grotesque phase of consolidation, with multi-billion-dollar sales seeing publishers consume one another, a financial black hole is being formed.</span></p> <p><span>With the colossally over-inflated prices involved in these deals, those buying are either borrowing heavily from predatory investors or gambling huge stakes of their own fortunes, such that the sheer notion of creating a new game in a once-loved series (let alone an original IP) becomes fantastically risky. To match the ridiculous valuations, the games these companies make are burdened with a need for justification, and every project must be predicted to bring in at least half a billion bucks to be worth even storyboarding. Ubisoft has just declared that it intends the games it makes to annually bring in a billion dollars each! Development costs therefore become self-destructively high, with expectations of figures of at least $200 million being spent to create something with enough spectacle to dazzle a hypothetical mainstream audience. Everything now needs to be the next </span><i><span>Call of Duty</span></i><span> at a time</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-sales-activision-2000652111"> <span>when even </span><i><span>Call of Duty</span></i><span> can’t manage that</span></a><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>Sure, welcome to capitalism 101: It doesn’t work. The need to always grow bigger, for share values to always increase, is a model so unsustainable that a pre-schooler could explain why. But here’s the thing, also easily grasped by toddlers: a moderately successful game that costs around $50 million to develop will make an awful lot more money than no game at all.</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Dead Space</i></b><b> Needn’t Be Dead</b></h2> <p><span>The most recent example of a beloved game series being shelved is </span><i><span>Dead Space</span></i><span>. In late 2025,</span><a href="https://gamingbolt.com/dead-space-franchise-is-on-ice-ea-has-zero-plans-for-a-revival-rumor"><span> following rumors some months before that </span></a><a href="https://kotaku.com/dead-space-2-remake-canceled-sales-motive-battlefield-1851400721"><span>a </span><i><span>Dead Space 2 </span></i><span>remake had been cancelled</span></a> <span>after the supposedly disappointing sales for 2023’s remake of the original game, </span><a href="https://gamingbolt.com/dead-space-franchise-is-on-ice-ea-has-zero-plans-for-a-revival-rumor"><span>word went around</span></a><span> that EA had put the franchise “on ice.” In December 2024 we’d also learned that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dead-space-4-ea-remake-horror-1851727387"><span>the series’ original creators had tried to pitch a </span><i><span>Dead Space 4</span></i><span> to EA</span></a><span>, but had been immediately rejected. One of those original creators, Glen Schofield, still didn’t give up,</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dead-space-creator-sees-chance-make-dead-space-4-ea-saudi-deal-2000636125"> <span>maintaining in October last year that he was attempting to buy the IP back from EA</span></a><span> in the wake of</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-sale-saudi-arabia-madden-pif-jared-kushner-2000629829"> <span>the company’s attempted sale to Saudi Arabia</span></a><span>, but by December 2025</span><a href="https://gamingbolt.com/dead-space-franchise-is-on-ice-ea-has-zero-plans-for-a-revival-rumor"> <span>this looked incredibly unlikely</span></a><span>. Which is crazy! Because a new </span><i><span>Dead Space </span></i><span>is not something EA needs to be the least bit afraid of.</span></p> <p><span>The original </span><i><span>Dead Space</span></i><span>, released in 2008,</span><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2017/10/18/ex-visceral-dev-reveals-dead-space-2-cost-60-million-and-underperformed-on-4-million-sales/"> <span>cost approximately $37 million to make</span></a><span>. Adjusted for inflation, that’s $55 million in 2026 money.</span><span> And that was an in-house Electronic Arts studio, spending EA money within EA’s ludicrous corporate structure. I truly believe, with my whole lovely heart, that a well-established AA team would be easily capable of making a game of the caliber of that first, excellent horror-shooter for even less money than that, especially if innovative and novel ideas are used in place of the very fanciest modern graphics.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000662618" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000662618"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000662618">© Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Here’s another thing my heart believes: That </span><i><span>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</span></i><span> remake that Ubisoft</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-ubisoft-leak-2000647174"> <span>was unable to make for six agonizing years</span></a><span> before eventually</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-cancels-long-delayed-prince-of-persia-remake-black-flag-remake-delay-2000661866"> <span>killing it entirely</span></a><span>, could have been turned around by any number of excellent smaller teams. I’m not suggesting for a moment it would be </span><i><span>easy</span></i><span> to do so—it would be fantastically hard, just like making any other top-quality game—but it would be eminently achievable. Not least because, not being made internally at Ubisoft, it wouldn’t have Ubisoft constantly getting in the way. By all reports, </span><i><span>Sands of Time</span></i><span>‘s remake went through multiple iterations, scrapped and started over at least twice, and eventually was the victim of so much feature-creep that it was adding all-new powers, making Farah an entirely different character (for the better, I should add, but in the most complex way), and adding all-new content.</span></p> <p><span>However, in the hands of a super-capable and proven AA team with a proclivity for the genre and a love of the original, it could have been a far more straightforward process. That 2003 original doesn’t need new powers, nor new levels, because it was </span><i><span>fantastically good</span></i><span>. It’s one of the best third-person action games ever made, and featured a time-manipulation gimmick that should have become industry standard. At 23 years old, the original is still a great game, but a clunky and dated one that would benefit so wonderfully from a modern refresh. And that’s all anyone had ever been hoping for from Ubisoft.</span></p> <p><span>I’m sure there are many throwing up their arms and claiming that I’m over-simplifying things here. And yes, I’m being perfunctory, but I’d argue that’s because this is all relative. You might be surprised to learn just how needlessly complicated Ubisoft has made making games, even as far back as the 2000s. . I remember visiting Ubisoft Montreal for the announcement of </span><i><span>Splinter Cell: Double Agent</span></i><span> in 2005, and sitting in their offices as executives explained that development of the game was taking place 24 hours a day by being spread across at least three international studios. When Montreal finished work, they tagged in Ubisoft Milan, who would then pass the baton to Ubisoft Shanghai, and then back to Montreal. There were multiple daily video calls (2005 video calls at that) to try to manage this. Throughout the creation of the game it was </span><i><span>also</span></i><span> worked on by Ubisoft Toronto, Paris-based Gameloft, and North Carolina’s Red Storm. Imagine working like that. Try to imagine a more chaotic way to develop a game. (I remember asking developers how it could possibly work, and the rather taut smiles as they explained that it “wasn’t easy.”)</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000662616" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000662616"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000662616">© Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>Something &gt; Nothing</b></h2> <p><span>So no, a AA team making a $50 million (or even a $5 million) game won’t deliver the spectacle and mainstream breakthrough appeal of </span><i><span>Battlefield</span></i><span>, but nor does it need to. If you’re spending $400m on a game (before you even factor in the cost of a global promotional campaign and wildly expensive influencer events), you need it to be bringing in numbers as close to a billion dollars as possible. If that’s not at all realistic, then the project can’t get greenlit in the first place. But if you’ve spent $50m, and justifiably charge $60 for a top-quality product, you are in the black with so many fewer sales. If your game hits (and let’s remember, we’re in this mess because of all the $200m+ gambles that have missed), you could be in for vast profits.</span></p> <p><span>And it’s not fantasy figures, either! </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-trigger-nade-kettle-pvp-nerfs-2000659269"><i><span>Arc Raiders</span></i><span> announced this month that it has sold 12 million copies</span></a><span>, which at $40 a pop amounts to $480,000,000. Yup. Half a billion bucks. Sure, minus store fees that’s “only” $336 million. We don’t know its development costs, but developers have stated it was nowhere near AAA budgets. And this is a game with optional in-game cosmetic purchases, meaning that figure is going to be </span><i><span>so</span></i><span> much higher.</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span>’s developers </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/11/arts/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sandfall.html"><span>claim</span></a><span> it cost less than $10 million to make, and it had sold over 6 million copies by the end of 2025. That means the $50 game has brought in at least $300,000,000 before store tithes. That’s a 3000 percent profit, and these are the numbers from </span><a href="https://thisweekinvideogames.com/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sees-sales-spike-following-game-awards-success/"><i><span>before</span></i></a><span> the game won all the 2025 GOTY awards and the sales that will have resulted from that.</span></p> <p><span>These are certainly stand-out examples from last year (although only some of them), but these are figures Ubisoft or EA would sell their grandchildren’s souls to see. The point is, I’m not talking out of my hat here about the potential of spending far less on a far smaller team.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000662617" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000662617"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000662617">© EA</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Many AA teams wouldn’t be interested in making a licensed game using someone else’s IP, and honestly, I wouldn’t want to trust a big-name publisher right now even if I were one who did. But many would! If you’re a small team with a $10 million project that didn’t catch fire, you’re in a very difficult place no matter how incredibly talented you might be. Many, many mid-size studios fold at that point, but what if there was the route of being trusted with the next </span><i><span>Dead Space</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Legacy of Kain</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Sleeping Dogs</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Thief</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Trespasser</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Command &amp; Conquer</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Titanfall</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Splinter Cell</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>SSX</span></i><span>, or </span><i><span>Red Faction</span></i><span>, or…</span></p>

 <p><span>Maybe there’s some big, fatal flaw with this concept that would come to the surface on trying. But I’m really doubtful. The issue is the complete lack of ever trying! And honestly, in their crumbling, fire-sale-driven state, what does an Ubisoft or an EA have to lose?! There hasn’t been a </span><i><span>Splinter Cell</span></i><span> game since 2013, meaning for the last 13 years precisely $0 has been made on new </span><i><span>Splinter Cell </span></i><span>games. I realize that’s perhaps somewhat obvious, but it’s a really rather important point! A $10,000,000 </span><i><span>Splinter Cell</span></i><span> that “only” sells a million copies at $50 a pop: that’s a 500 percent profit. And even if it might seem like small change in a world where (very, very few) games bring in a billion dollars, it’s a heck of a lot more than $0.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/too-big-to-fail-dead-space-titanfall-2-deus-ex-budget-2000657134]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld Studio Has Devs Share Screenshots Of Steam Playtime To Prove They’re ‘True’ Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/palworld-pocketpair-steam-mhw-patch-pc-performance-2000662592</link>
            <guid>1414435</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Do you want to work on <em>Palworld</em>? Do you have an embarrassingly long Steam history to prove it? Will BioWare use a similar test to hire its new production director for <em>Mass Effect 5</em>? And can the next <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> patch finally fix performance on PC? It’s the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint,<em> Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news, rumors, and culture. This is my new favorite <a href="https://x.com/tct_adventures">behind the scenes game tease</a>. Game companies should spend less time firing people and more time being silly.</p> <h2>Gamers without Steam achievements need not apply</h2> <p>What makes a good game designer? For<em> Palworld</em> maker Pocketpair it’s people who play a lot of Steam games and can explain why their favorite ones are good. Don’t have a Steam game history? Don’t even bother applying. CEO Takuro Mizobe says people have to submit screenshots of their playtime and those without any are screened out.</p>

 <p>“In the interview, we ask them to explain the game mechanics of the titles that rank high in their Steam playtime, why they think those specific mechanics were adopted, and what makes that title stand out when compared to other games in the same genre,” Mizobe <a href="https://x.com/urokuta_ja/status/2014593734827246006">wrote on X</a> (via <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/palworld-developer-pocketpair-requires-game-designer-candidates-to-provide-screenshots-of-their-steam-libraries-and-playtime-according-to-ceo/"><em>Automaton</em></a>). “Pocketpair is recruiting game creators who are true Steam gamers!”</p> <h2><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>‘ next big performance patch arrives next week</h2> <p>“This patch will include optimization improvements for Steam-specific processes and options to reduce processing load,” reads an <a href="https://x.com/MHStatusUpdates/status/2011732622435557475?s=20">announcement on the server status account</a> for an outage starting January 27. “It will also include a review of presets.” Another update will follow quickly after on February 18. Fans are hoping this is the one that finally makes a big difference with how the game runs on PC, especially after one modder apparently discovered <a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-framerate-dlc-2000660149">a weird DLC check bug</a> that was killing framerates.</p>

 <h2>BioWare is hiring for <em>Mass Effect 5</em></h2> <p>“We are looking for a Production Director&nbsp;with a passion for the&nbsp;<em>Mass Effect</em>&nbsp;universe to serve as a high-impact leader on our next&nbsp;<em>Mass Effect</em> title,” reads a new job posting. “You will partner closely with creative leadership, studio teams, and internal and external partners to champion the game’s vision and ensure its execution at the highest quality bar.” That person will report directly to project lead Michael Gamble. “It’s gonna be awesome,” he <a href="https://x.com/GambleMike/status/2014438853273387358?s=20">wrote on X</a>.</p>

 <h2><em>Vampire Crawlers</em> will have a free demo next month</h2> <p>The <em>Vampire Survivors-</em>turned-3D-deckbuilder dungeon crawler spin-off will be free-to-try starting on February 23 on Steam and Xbox Game Pass. The 3D pixel-art genre mash-up has been looking very neat and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Ael4oMaKQM">has a new trailer</a> explaining more of how its gameplay will work.</p> <h2>Epic has a secret $800 million deal with Google</h2> <p>“Epic’s technology is used by many companies in the space Google is operating in to train their products, so the ability for Google to use the Unreal Engine more fulsome…sorry, I’m blowing this confidentiality,” CEO Tim Sweeney told a court questioning its settlement with the search giant, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/866140/epic-google-fortnite-android-unreal-deal-antitrust-settlement"><em>The Verge</em> reports</a>. The deal, which is for Epic buying Google’s services, is apparently related to “the metaverse” and will include both companies marketing one another’s products. It’s definitely not part of some sweetheart arrangement of the kind that Sweeney <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23996474/epic-tim-sweeney-interview-win-google-antitrust-lawsuit-district-court">previously railed against</a>.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><strong><a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-share-price-crash-prince-of-persia-ai-2000662169">Ubisoft’s stock is on life support&nbsp;</a></strong></li> <li><strong><a href="https://kotaku.com/yakuza-3-remake-ugly-alleyway-has-fans-concerned-graphics-downgrade-fix-mod-2000662269">Fans can’t figure out why one of the<em> Yakuza 3</em> remake’s back alleys is so ugly</a></strong></li> <li><strong><a href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-steam-epic-games-publishing-deal-tim-sweeney-2000662259">Remedy defends Tim Sweeney’s honor over <em>Alan Wake 2</em> not being on Steam</a></strong></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/palworld-pocketpair-steam-mhw-patch-pc-performance-2000662592]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fable Is Abandoning One Of The RPG Series’ Defining Mechanics And Fans Aren’t Happy]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fable-reboot-appearance-morality-good-evil-horns-halo-2000662597</link>
            <guid>1414363</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>During yesterday’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-developer-direct-fable-forza-horizon-6-game-freak-2000662291"><span>Xbox Developer Direct</span></a><span>, we got the most expansive look at the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/fable-reboot-features-open-world-release-date-fall-xbox-ps5-2000662295"><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>reboot</span></a><span> we’ve seen yet. Playground Games is picking up the series after original developer Lionhead Studios shut down in 2016, and it definitely feels like the studio is modernizing the action RPG series with an open world and a new morality system. With that new morality system, </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>is changing what was one of the core pillars of the series: your appearance will no longer be determined by whether or not you’re making good or evil decisions. In fact, it’s abandoning the idea that any of your actions are objectively good or evil altogether.</span></p> <p><span>For those that didn’t play any of Lionhead’s </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>games, like many games of the early 2000s they have a binary “hero or villain” morality system where doing things like helping people in need would move you toward the “good” side of the spectrum while doing things like skinning people alive in front of their weeping mother would move you toward the “evil” side. </span></p>

 <p><span>In the </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>games, the decisions you made would gradually alter your character’s look, with good characters appearing pristine and almost angelic, and evil players growing horns and turning into a monster. I tended to play evil characters in these games and wasn’t thrilled that my characters were turning into uggos, but that’s the contract you sign when you play these games. Playground Games’ </span><i><span>Fable</span></i><span>, however, is approaching morality differently, and so this mechanic is going out the window.</span></p> <p><span>As illustrated in the showcase, </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>is trying to handle morality in a more “subjective” way, which essentially means the game won’t treat your actions as simply “good” or “evil,” but rather that NPCs will react to the things you do based on their own proclivities. So you can kick people out of their homes as their landlord, and some rich idiot who lives for that shit might still think you’re a standup guy. Since things aren’t so black and white this time around, Playground’s Ralph Fulton tells </span><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/weve-been-working-on-this-game-for-a-really-really-long-time-the-big-fable-interview-with-microsoft-developer-playground"><i><span>IGN</span></i></a><span> it’s abandoning the morality-based appearance-changing system of previous games because there is no “objective” morality system to attach them to.</span></p>

 <blockquote><p><span>That sort of character morphing feature, obviously a really central part of the original games. It’s not in ours. And I’ll tell you why. There’s probably a couple of reasons. One, I guess it’s about that high level principle I was talking about, that there is no objective good and evil. And the original games were predicated on there being an objective good and an objective evil, and you were somewhere along that scale, and that’s what determined how your appearance changed.</span></p> <p><span>But for us, that doesn’t really work. The way I’ve described our morality system working, you’re never that thing, absolutely. You’re different things to different people based on what they like or what they choose to value. So, that’s one reason that it didn’t work.</span></p> <p><span>There’s another reason, which is in our game, you build reputation based on the settlement, the town, the city that you’re in, the part of the world that you’re in. But when you go to a new place, a place you’ve never been to before, you walk in without any reputation and thus nobody knows what to think about you. And you can almost, through your behavior, through your choices, form completely different reputations, a completely different identity, if you like, in that place from the place that you were last time. And you can do that across all the locations in the game.</span></p> <p><span>Now, you couldn’t do that if you walked in with horns and a trident. Your reputation would precede you in that instance. And honestly, that ability to be completely in control of your identity and thus what people think of you felt more important to us than that legacy feature. So, it worked great in those games. It didn’t seem to fit in ours, so we don’t have it.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>From a roleplaying perspective, I get why this decision was made, and I’ll be glad that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-cyberpunk-mass-effect-character-creator-1851422575"><span>my future bald, bearded gay</span></a><span> won’t have to look like a demon while I’m trying to woo the men of Albion. But it is leaving behind what was a core pillar of the </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>series back in the day, and long-time fans who have been waiting over a decade for a new </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>are reacting accordingly.</span></p>

   <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">they've confirmed in an IGN interview that your actions will not transform your appearance. 😠 That's a core part of why I love Fable and I'll miss that.</p> <p>Everything else looks fantastic, though. Smart evolutions, faithful vibe, incredible environments. I'm happy to be excited. <a href="https://t.co/aqiDTHLR2o">https://t.co/aqiDTHLR2o</a></p> <p>— Jake Baldino (@JakeBaldino) <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeBaldino/status/2014445728001630593?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 22, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">wait what?? that's like Fable's whole deal! <a href="https://t.co/E9mzl8OvZO">https://t.co/E9mzl8OvZO</a></p> <p>— Paul Tassi (@PaulTassi) <a href="https://twitter.com/PaulTassi/status/2014470703605584029?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 22, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>“NPC’s and how your character looked reflecting your actions was pretty important for me,” Disastrous_Fig5609 wrote on </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fable/comments/1qk9zj3/rip_to_the_main_feature_that_set_fable_games_apart/"><span>Reddit</span></a><span>. “You watch the character grow up from childhood, then you watch them grow into a hero or a villain. You might not be able to plant an acorn and watch it grow into a tree as you play the game, but that element of shaping the world around you with your actions still somewhat persisted with shaping your character with your actions.”</span></p> <p><span>“The location based reputation is cool, but it absolutely could have just been a dual system,”&nbsp; ForestBrah01209 wrote in the same thread. “One town will see you one way, another town will see you a different way. However, if I’m absolutely evil and move to another town, I’m still absolutely evil, even if my new neighbors think I’m just another stranger or even a nice guy. Shame that I won’t be able to rock the devil horns anymore.”</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>is the first game in the series to have a character creator, so at least it’s not like everyone’s characters are going to look the same. We’ll see if there are enough character customization options to let players at least manually emulate some of those old </span><i><span>Fable </span></i><span>transformations when the game launches in the fall. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fable-reboot-appearance-morality-good-evil-horns-halo-2000662597]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roku Wireless Video Doorbell With Chime Drops Back to Its Black Friday Low, an Affordable Way to Build a Smart Home]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roku-wireless-video-doorbell-with-chime-drops-back-to-its-black-friday-low-an-affordable-way-to-build-a-smart-home-2000662537</link>
            <guid>1414360</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Roku Smart Home Wired Video Doorbell &amp; Chime features an ultrawide-angle lens with a 180° horizontal field of view, letting you capture what’s happening at your front door. Night vision keeps you seeing a high-quality image regardless of the time of day. Motion and sound detection automatically send notifications to your mobile device, tablet, and compatible Roku devices when someone approaches your door. In addition to receiving notifications, you can communicate with visitors using two-way audio from your mobile device or tablet.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6850/">You can now purchase the Roku Smart Home Wired Video Doorbell &amp; Chime for $50, down from its regular price of $70, saving you $20 or 28% off.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6850/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A reliable security method to see everyone who darkens your doorstep</h2>
<p>This hardwired Roku Smart Home Wired Video Doorbell &amp; Chime uses your existing wiring for continuous power, eliminating the need to replace batteries. After installation, you can check the live feed of your front door and review past events on your mobile device or tablet using the Roku Smart Home app. You can also receive notifications on your compatible Roku TV or streaming player, so you know who is approaching your front door, whether your phone is nearby or across the house.</p>
<p>Videos captured by the camera are recorded in 1080p HD. The lens covers a wide area of your front porch with an ultrawide-angle 180° horizontal view, so you don’t need to adjust the camera angle to see both items on the mat and a visitor’s face when they are standing near the door. Night vision lets you capture clear images at night, showing details such as clothing and purses rather than obscuring them in shadows.</p>



<p>Beyond basic motion and sound detection, the built-in smart features notify you as soon as motion or sound is detected at your door. This means you’ll know right away when someone approaches, and if they press the doorbell, you’ll be notified immediately of who pressed it.</p>
<p>The included plug-in chime alerts you when the doorbell is rung, or motion is detected, regardless of your phone’s status. You can choose from 20 available sounds to play when the doorbell is activated and place the chime anywhere in your home to maximize volume. The chime carries an IP65 rating for durability and includes both corner and flat mounting plates to improve stability in inclement weather.</p>
<p>The Roku Smart Home Wired Video Doorbell &amp; Chime includes everything you need for a successful installation, such as a complete hardware kit, guided setup through the Roku Smart Home app, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6850/">and is on sale now for $50, down from the typical $70 retail price.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6850/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roku-wireless-video-doorbell-with-chime-drops-back-to-its-black-friday-low-an-affordable-way-to-build-a-smart-home-2000662537]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bose Goes on ANC Headphone Clearance, New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds (2nd Gen) Crash to an All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bose-goes-on-anc-headphone-clearance-new-quietcomfort-ultra-earbuds-2nd-gen-crash-to-an-all-time-low-2000662534</link>
            <guid>1414327</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Bose New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds feature an Active Noise Control system and an immersive audio system, and they fit well for extended periods. They also include soft ear tips that seal against the ear to eliminate ambient noise, but do not feel too tight. These earbuds feature Bluetooth compatibility for phones, tablets, laptops, and other devices. Additionally, the earbuds have a white smoke finish, have touch controls, and a compact charging case that is small enough to carry in a pocket. They were made to be portable while keeping the audio front and center.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6849/">You can find the Bose New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds for $249 at Amazon.</a> This is a $50 discount from their normal price of $299. So this represents a 17% discount.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6849/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Earbuds with the style, comfort, and quality of Bose headphones</h2>
<p>The noise-cancellation on the Bose New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds works to cancel out engine noise, conversations, and other background noise. If you would rather hear some outside noise, then the Aware Mode provides an alternative. It allows you to hear what is happening outside and smooths out sudden spikes in decibel levels caused by loud noises, such as clanging dishes and slamming doors. In addition to providing awareness of your surroundings, if you prefer more isolation, Quiet Mode reduces ambient noise so you can enjoy your playlists, calls, podcasts, etc., at a lower volume.</p>
<p>CustomTune technology in the Bose New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds determines how sound behaves in your ears and adjusts noise cancellation and equalization accordingly. The earbuds produce a test tone when you insert them and measure the response. Then it sets the bass, midrange, and treble to match your ear shape. Bose Immersive Audio provides a spatial effect that creates the illusion that music and video are coming from in front of you rather than inside your head.</p>



<p>The fit and comfort of the earbuds are due to the combination of the soft silicone eartips and the flexible stability bands. There are multiple sizes of each component, and they can be combined in 9 ways. The umbrella-shaped tips provide additional blockage of ambient noise. Plus, they are rated IPX4, so they are suitable for use during sweating or light rain.</p>
<p>The call quality of the Bose New QuietComfort Ultra Earbuds depends on the noise-rejecting microphones and processing specifically tailored to ensure your voice is heard clearly. The microphones are focused on capturing your voice while rejecting wind and background noise; therefore, the caller hears you, not the surrounding noise.</p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, battery life and charging capabilities are configured to provide you with enough time to listen to whatever content you desire. Battery life is approximately 6 hours in Quiet, Aware, or Immersive Modes, and about 4 hours in Immersive Mode. The case supports 3 charging cycles and can be charged via a USB-C port or a wireless charging pad. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6849/">These are great headphones, and you’ll want to take advantage of the $249 sale price instead of the regular list price of $299 now.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6849/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bose-goes-on-anc-headphone-clearance-new-quietcomfort-ultra-earbuds-2nd-gen-crash-to-an-all-time-low-2000662534]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>