<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:49:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Pushes the Razer Customizable Gaming Keypad to Its Lowest Price as Stock Runs Out]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-pushes-the-razer-customizable-gaming-keypad-to-its-lowest-price-as-stock-runs-out-2000650248</link>
            <guid>1373068</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>With Black Friday and Cyber Monday having passed, you might be thinking times up for finding great deals on tech and gaming stuff. But oh, my friend, you could not be more wrong. Amazon still has a number of deals still active following the huge savings weekend. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6204/">For instance, this Razer Tartarus V2 gaming keypad went on sale just before Black Friday to its lowest price on record and has remained since</a>. The gaming keypad usually goes for $80, so that 25% ends up chopping off $20—bringing the price you pay to only $60. No telling when the price will jump back up, so if you’re still shopping for the right gift for your gamer pal or are just looking to upgrade your own gaming setup, now’s the time to do it.</p>
<p>Let’s chat about mice, keyboard and controller for a moment. For some genres, the best way to play is obvious. A real-time strategy game? That’s gotta be mouse and keyboard. Racing games? Need to go with controller for those analog triggers. Though, some genres are debatable—particularly the first-person shooter.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6204/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>With a mouse, you have pin-point control over your aim, able to accelerate naturally, as fast as you can move the mouse. And yet, movement is limited. the W, A, S, D, control scheme doesn’t allow for precise control over your walking speed. Plus you’re limited to exactly eight directions of movement.</p>
<p>On controller, you can decide how fast you move, and have a full 360-degree range of movement with the left analog stick. However, your view relies on the right analog stick, which can only turn so fast and offers a much more limited control.</p>
<h2>Best of Both Worlds</h2>
<p>Hannah Montanna knew best. You need the best of both worlds—and the Razer Tartarus V2 is just that.</p>
<p>The Tartarus looks like someone hacked up a keyboard and glued a joy-stick to the side (complimentary). With it, you now have a directional thumbpad for more natural controls, closer to what console-oriented players are used to. And then your remaining four fingers can still have access to all the keys you need. There’s also a scroll wheel.</p>



<p>The Razer Tartarus V2 features 32 mecha-membrane keys. They provide the tactile feedback and satisfaction of pressing down a mechanical key. They are are individually programmable so you can set it however you like to support your gaming or for use in creative workflows such as video or photo editing. You can even program macros, allowing for multiple key and keypress combinations in order to execute complex commands.</p>
<p>The gaming keypad is built with an ergonomic palm rest which is both adjustable and detachable, so you can customize your set up to whatever best matches your preferences and comfort.</p>
<p>And it of course would not be a proper Gamer with a capital G accessory without proper RGB lighting. The Razer Tartarus V2 gaming keypad offers full Razer Chroma supports. You can have the keypad fully synchronize with the game you’re playing or even with your Philips Hue lights if you’d got them.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6204/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-pushes-the-razer-customizable-gaming-keypad-to-its-lowest-price-as-stock-runs-out-2000650248]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Can’t Catch A Break: ‘All Year Call Of Duty’s Numbers Have Been Quite Low’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-helldivers-2-lava-skyblivion-delay-2000650525</link>
            <guid>1373065</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The analysts have seen enough: <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review-campaign-is-it-good-zombies-multiplayer-2000645198"><em>Call of Duty</em>‘s having a bad year</a>. Also <em>Helldivers 2</em> is sending players into lava pits and a major <em>Elder Scrolls</em> fan game gets another understandable delay. It’s the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, our daily roundup of gaming news and culture. It’s a big day for new game releases with <a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-reviews-is-it-good-switch-2-nintendo-2000649621"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em></a>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-0-the-kotaku-review-2000650015"><em>Octopath Traveler 0</em></a>, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/routine-alien-isolation-sci-fi-horror-review-creepy-scary-moon-xbox-pc-2000649242"><em>Routine</em></a> all coming out at the same time. I wish I could find the time! Instead, I’ll be busy facing new bosses in<a href="https://kotaku.com/nightreigh-forsaken-hollows-dlc-launch-time-patch-notes-2000650150"><em> Elden Ring Nightreign</em>‘s first DLC</a> and muddling my way through a good but all-too-brief new <a href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-renegades-star-wars-power-reset-2000632488"><em>Destiny 2 Star Wars</em> campaign</a> called&nbsp;<em>Renegades</em>.</p> <h2>The biggest<em> Elder Scrolls</em> mod project going gets another delay</h2>  <p><em>Skyblivion</em>, to almost no one’s surprise, won’t make its planned 2025 release date after all. The long-standing fan project that recreates <em>The Elder Scrolls IV</em> inside <em>Skyrim</em> using the latter’s engine needs a bit more time to cook. Considering it’s the work of over 70 unpaid volunteers, I think the wait is understandable. Plus, it will give it more of a buffer from Bethesda’s own <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> launch earlier this year.</p>

 <h2>Sony is publishing JJ Abrams’ production company’s first game developed by Left 4 Dead’s director</h2> <p>It’s a buzzy mouthful indeed. Here’s the press release: “Sony Interactive Entertainment (SIE) today announced a partnership with video game studio Bad Robot Games, a division of Bad Robot, the film, television and theater production company founded by JJ Abrams, for SIE to produce and publish the studio’s upcoming project, an unannounced four-player, cooperative shooter directed by Mike Booth&nbsp;<em>(Left 4 Dead</em>).”</p>

 <p>The game will come to PS5 and PC, but there’s currently no other information known about it. Maybe a tease at The Game Awards?</p> <h2>“Fewer people are playing <em>Call of Duty</em> this year than they have been before”</h2> <p>That’s according to Chris Dring of<em> The Game Business</em> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-sales-expert-opinion">who spoke to<em> Eurogamer</em></a> about the <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-player-count-battlefield-6-2000646316">relative crickets</a> around <em>Black Ops 7</em>‘s launch. Activision hasn’t shared any hard data on player counts or sales figures, though the metrics analysts are tracking and estimating sound much worse than usual.</p>

 <p>“But actually, I track daily active users, and all year <em>Call of Duty</em>‘s numbers have been quite low-lower than usual. There have been some exceptions though, January was great coming off <em>Black Ops 6</em>, there was a boost in April / May, but generally speaking, fewer people are playing <em>Call of Duty</em> this year than they have been before,” Dring said. “That’s despite <em>Black Ops 6</em> as the previous game being brilliant in people’s eyes. In fact, in September, it was the lowest point I’ve seen <em>Call of Duty</em> since the launch of their <em>Call of Duty HQ</em>.”</p>

 <p>He and Alinea Analytics’ Rhys Elliot blame a lack of innovation, a <a href="https://kotaku.com/cod-blops-7-campaign-coop-always-online-pause-co-op-xp-challenges-2000644358">bad, always-online campaign</a>, poor marketing, lots of competition in the shooter space, and general franchise burnout for the lackluster response. Will any of that actually stop <em>Black Ops 7</em> from being one of this year’s top-sellers? <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-review-impressions-2000647644">Probably not</a>.</p>

 <h2><em>Helldivers 2</em> just got lava planets</h2>  <p>The extraction shooter’s latest “Into the Unjust” update has taken players into a fight with the automatons on <em>Helldivers 2</em>‘s version of <em>Mustafar. “</em>Too hot for humans, too unstable for farming, too explosive for tourism—yet rich in minerals,” reads the description. “Minerals the Automatons steal with every drill. Their unsanctioned mining not only threatens humanity’s expansion, but the very survival of managed democracy itself.”</p>

 <h2>The AI bubble continues to threaten gaming</h2> <p>SSD and RAM maker Micron announced it’s getting out of the consumer business to focus on manufacturing for companies’ AI computing needs. “The AI-driven growth in the data center has led to a surge in demand for memory and storage. Micron has made the difficult decision to exit the Crucial consumer business in order to improve supply and support for our larger, strategic customers in faster-growing segments,” said Chief Business Officer Sumit Sadana <a href="https://investors.micron.com/news-releases/news-release-details/micron-announces-exit-crucial-consumer-business">in a statement</a>.</p> <p>The news comes as wider RAM shortages seem poised to jack up the prices of PC and console gaming even further, with pricing pressure hitting companies like AMD which is already the confirmed tech partner for PlayStation 6, Steam Machine, and the next-gen Xbox.</p> <h2>Hideo Kojima will talk about going indie at GDC 2026</h2> <p>The <em>Death Stranding 2</em> director was named the keynote speaker for a talk titled “Restarting from Zero: A Message to Creators Considering Independence.” Scheduled to kick off GDC’s revamped “Festival of Gaming” taking place March 9 through 13, the presentation is expected to detail the famed developer’s journey after leaving Konami and the “pitfalls” his team overcame after starting from scratch.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-rebirth-aerith-voice-actor-smut-2000650164"><em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>‘s voice actor is tired of being sent Aerith porn&nbsp;</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/where-winds-meet-ai-npc-llm-chatgpt-steam-2000650074">Generative AI NPCs are getting tricked with sex prompts&nbsp;</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/mcdonalds-new-grinch-meal-shaker-shake-fries-pickle-holiday-christmas-meal-2000650144">McDonalds has new fries and they’re actually very, very good</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-helldivers-2-lava-skyblivion-delay-2000650525]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Banjo-Kazooie Fan Project Inside Sony’s Abandoned Game Maker Looks Surprisingly Great]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-banjo-kazooie-sequel-remake-game-built-in-dreams-impressive-2000650541</link>
            <guid>1373020</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It seems very unlikely that we’ll get a new <em>Banjo-Kazooie</em> game from Rare and Xbox anytime in the near future. And while an impressive-looking fan-made <em>Banjo</em> game created in <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-fan-made-courage-the-cowardly-dog-game-perfect-creepy-dreams-ps4-2000640924"><em>Dreams</em></a> isn’t quite the sequel or remake people might want, it’s probably the best we can hope for in 2025. It’s also wildly impressive for something made in Sony’s five-year-old abandoned game maker.</p> <p><a href="https://x.com/Eupholace/status/1996263228205080843">On December 3,</a> William Butkevicius, a level designer at Moon Studios, shared a trailer for <em>Banjo-Kazooie: Mumbomania</em>, a new non-official one to two-hour game starring everyone’s favorite bear and bird. It looks really good.&nbsp; <a href="https://x.com/Eupholace/status/1996347110762106931">According to the creator</a>, it took about “14 months” and “800+ hours of work” to make <em>Mumbomania</em>. Here’s the trailer for the game, which is out now and available exclusively in <em>Dreams</em> on PS5 and PS4.</p>

  <p>Impressive stuff, right? In fact, if you had shown this to me without telling me it was made in <em>Dreams</em>, a PlayStation-published game-creation tool from the devs behind<em> Little Big Planet,</em> I’d have likely just assumed this was created in Unity or something by a talented team of people. And in a way, it was created by a talented team of creators, as <em>Mumbomania</em> contains various assets built by other <em>Dreams</em> users, <a href="https://indreams.me/dream/mSFcdDKSMkr">all of whom are listed in the game’s credits page</a>. This was one of the coolest things about <em>Dreams:</em> The way it let people collaborate and made sure everyone got credit for their input.</p>

 <p>As for the game’s plot, here’s the setup according to Butkevicius: “The bear and bird are back for their first buddy-trio adventure! Mysteriously disembodied, Mumbo joins Banjo and Kazooie to help collect, fight, and transform into a variety of strange beings.”</p> <p>Sadly, because Sony never did much with <em>Dreams</em>, like porting to PC, the only way to play <em>Mumbomania</em> is to own <em>Dreams</em> on PS5 and PS4 and<a href="https://indreams.me/dream/mSFcdDKSMkr"> play the <em>Banjo</em> fan game</a> there. If you don’t own <em>Dreams</em>, <a href="https://youtu.be/I8GogASuUqE">you can watch this walkthrough of the <em>Banjo-Kazooie: Mumbomania</em></a> to see just how much work went into making this thing look, sound, and play like an authentically Rare <em>Banjo</em> sequel.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-banjo-kazooie-sequel-remake-game-built-in-dreams-impressive-2000650541]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Breaks Its Gaming Monitor Price History as the 27″ Odyssey G3 Series Drops to an All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-breaks-its-gaming-monitor-price-history-as-the-27-odyssey-g3-series-drops-to-an-all-time-low-2000650245</link>
            <guid>1373017</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>An old, slow, or just subpar monitor is one of the surest ways to completely kill a fun PC gaming sesh. That’s especially true if you’re in a multiplayer online game where your quick hand reflexes need to translate to quick game reflexes, and a laggy moment or worse will spell your (virtual) demise.</p>
<p>Gaming monitors are usually a “get what you paid for” proposition — the cheap ones are mediocre, and the high-end ones are pricey. That equation doesn’t apply here, because the Samsung 27-inch Odyssey G3 Series FHD Gaming Monitor comes with a terrific picture, AMD FreeSync, and killer response time and refresh rate, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6205/">right now it’s only $143 thanks to a limited-time Amazon deal that cuts the price down by 38%.</a> That puts it right at the intersection of budget price and great performance, which is of course the best place to buy from.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6205/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Real-Time Reactions</h2>
<p>Even more than the size, resolution, and picture sharpness, the refresh rate and response time are by far the most crucial components of a gaming monitor. The Odyssey G3 Series comes in with an exceptionally brisk 180Hz refresh rate and 1ms response time to keep all of your moves happening in real time and your screen blur- and freeze-free. Those numbers aren’t usually associated with a gaming monitor with a $230 price tag like the Odyssey G3 Series usually carries, and virtually never with the $143 price it’s carrying now during this limited-time Amazon deal.</p>
<p>The Odyssey G3 Series gaming monitor adds AMD Radeon FreeSync to the package as an additional guard against lag and other game-killing visual delays. FreeSync keeps the monitor and the graphics card of your PC or console in perfect lockstep to thwart both lag and image tearing. The result is a smooth, seamless picture that endures even during the fastest action and most detailed scenes.</p>



<h2>Use the Crosshairs</h2>
<p>With the Virtual Aim Point in place, your shooting accuracy in battle royal and melee action will never be better. Virtual Aim Point puts actual crosshairs on the screen to help guide your shot with amazing precision. And when your foe finds a dark corner to hide in, the Odyssey G3 Series’ Black Equalizer feature allows you to adjust even the blackest areas on the screen to expose the danger.</p>
<p>The borderless design of the Odyssey G3 Series extends your gaming field to the absolute limit of the monitor’s frame, and it also allows you to line up a second borderless monitor to create a massive, seamless screen. Deploy the Eye Saver Mode and the monitor’s blue light is minimized and the screen flicker reduced, so you can play longer and more safely.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6205/">The Samsung Odyssey G3 Series comes with far more features and performance than any 27-inch gaming monitor should at its current price of just $143 at Amazon</a>. But the fat 38% discount is only good for a limited time, so don’t miss out.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6205/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-breaks-its-gaming-monitor-price-history-as-the-27-odyssey-g3-series-drops-to-an-all-time-low-2000650245]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Leak Is Fueling Speculation That The Pokémon Animal Crossing Game Turns Your Childhood Into A Graveyard]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-map-kanto-region-post-apocalypse-leak-2000650529</link>
            <guid>1372972</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Ever since The Pokémon Company </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-animal-crossing-switch-2-nintendo-direct-2000625331"><span>announced </span><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a><span>, the </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span>-style life sim game has seemed a little off. Your character is helping rebuild a small town so Pokémon can live there, but the space is filled with desecrated buildings, and humans are nowhere to be found. Fans have been speculating that the cozy game might not be so cozy after all, and that it may take place in a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400"><span>post-apocalyptic version of the Kanto region</span></a><span> from the original </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games. Now, a leak may have confirmed this.</span></p> <p><span>A leaked map outlines the status of Kanto in </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>, with descriptions for each “area,” named after the cities and towns that once stood there. A translation posted by Pokémon leak account Centro Leaks describes these desolate areas, and each of them sounds like they’ve succumbed to the elements. Fuschia city, which fans have speculated might be the first area shown in most of </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>‘s trailers, is said to be “dried up and unfertilized fieldland.” Vermillion City, which was once occupied by Lt. Surge’s electric gym and a harbor city for ships to arrive and depart from, is roughly translated as a “constant raining electrical harbor.”&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The rest of the descriptions sure do make it sound like humanity has been gone for a long time. Saffron City’s metropolitan area is “covered with plants,” Pewter City has been “abandoned” and is covered in rocks, and Lavender Town’s Pokémon Tower is now “rotten” but believed to reach heaven.&nbsp;</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Pokópia is post-apocalyptic Kanto CONFIRMED!</p> <p>➡️ Base game areas:<br>Area 1 – Fuscha Area – Dried up and unfertilized fieldland<br>Area 2 – Vermillion Area – Constant raining electrical harbor<br>Area 3 – Pewter Area – An abandoned mine covered by rocks<br>Area 4 – Saffron Area – Bunch of… <a href="https://t.co/JPySgYGnBW">https://t.co/JPySgYGnBW</a></p> <p>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/1996007165002199320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Just how much </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>will reckon with this remains to be seen, but the environment isn’t the only indicator that something terrible happened in Kanto in this game. The game includes </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-pikachu-pale-form-peakychu-white-2000644025"><span>new forms for Pikachu, Snorlax, and Smeargle</span></a><span> that have elements to their character design that imply a lot of time has passed since they last interacted with humans. I’m really curious to see how deep this game goes into its tragic “what if” storyline when it comes to Switch 2 on March 5.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-map-kanto-region-post-apocalypse-leak-2000650529]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS Goes Full Clearance on Its Graphics Cards as the GeForce RTX 5070 Drops to a New Record Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-full-clearance-on-its-graphics-cards-as-the-geforce-rtx-5070-drops-to-a-new-record-low-2000650188</link>
            <guid>1372969</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Those looking to game better or push some creative boundaries this holiday season; we’ve got good news. The top-rated ASUS GeForce RTX 5070 just hit its lowest price ever, and it’s even better than what it dipped to during Black Friday!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6203/">This graphics card sits at $710, but you can currently grab it for just $570 at Amazon, after the retailer took 20% off its price</a>. The deal is open to all shoppers, and there are no delivery charges to worry about. Even better, this isn’t one of those complicated-to-score discounts. You don’t need to enter any complicated coupon codes or follow long checkout steps to grab the discount. Just throw it in your cart, and the offer applies automatically. The only thing to note is that the retailer has marked the deal as a fast-selling one. That means the stock, or the drop itself, is only going to be around for a short time, and it won’t be long before we see them wrap up. It’s better to act now if you don’t want to run into last-minute disappointments later on.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6203/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Great Visuals, Even Better Performance</h2>
<p>RTX is the most advanced platform for full ray tracing and neural rendering tech that completely upgrades the way you work and play. The graphics card is powered by the NVIDIA Blackwell architecture and DLSS 4, featuring fifth-gen tensor cores for better AI performance, latest streaming multiprocessors that are optimized for neutral shader, and fourth-gen ray tracing cores specifically built for mega geometry. DLSS4 uses AI to boost FPS, reduce latency, and make the overall image quality top-notch, while the Blackwell architecture makes cinematic quality visuals at unbelievable speeds possible.</p>
<p>The 2.5 slot design of the card offers better build compatibility while maintaining cooling performance, regardless of how intense things get. Cooling mechanism includes a premium phase-change GPU thermal pad that softens under heat to fill the gaps between the GPU and thermal module effectively, resulting in superior thermal conductivity and better heat dissipation throughout your sessions. The axial-tech fans come with longer blades, alongside a barrier ring to increase the downward air pressure, while the 0db tech stops the fans automatically when the temperature of the GPU goes 50 degrees. The latter makes it easy to focus on light tasks without any distracting sound, and puts the fans back to work at 55 degrees when things start to heat up. You can also switch between Quiet and Performance BIOS profiles manually; the former offers a calmer operation, while the latter maximizes performance for resource-intensive tasks.</p>



<p>The card comes with a GPU guard that applies adhesive to secure all four corners of the GPU to keep it firmly in place. Dual-ball bearings are designed to last up to twice as long as sleeve bearings, while the protective backplate does a good job of keeping the components safe from external damage. What’s more, the Tuning tool makes overclocking, cooling control, and monitoring the performance of your card a breeze. It even comes with MuseTree, which is an AI-powered image-generation app that gives the creative inside you a boost by letting you create images, manage ideas, and unlock new inspirations as you go.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6203/">You can now grab the graphics card for just $570, after an impressive $140 discount on its retail price of $710.</a> This makes the upgrade much more affordable, but only for a short time. Don’t miss out on the chance to grab it for less, as this is one of the lowest prices we have seen the card drop to.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6203/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-full-clearance-on-its-graphics-cards-as-the-geforce-rtx-5070-drops-to-a-new-record-low-2000650188]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>