<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reviews For Netflix’s Witcher Season 4 Are Pretty Bad]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/netflix-witcher-season-4-reviews-liam-hemsworth-2000640506</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reviews-for-netflix%E2%80%99s-witcher-season-4-are-pretty-bad.1340728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There has been a Witcher-sized hole in my heart for several years now. Unfortunately, the return of <a href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-witcher-season-4-liam-hemsworth-henry-cavil-1851493745">Netflix’s live-action adaptation</a> is unlikely to help fill it. <em>The Witcher</em> season 4 is finally out and bingeable on the streaming service, and almost no one seems to be happy about it.</p> <p>Liam Hemsworth has debuted as the grizzled monster hunter Geralt of Rivia. Netflix even went ahead and retconned him into old scenes for the recap. Does the <em>Hunger Games</em> star earn his keep after all the <a href="https://kotaku.com/liam-hemsworth-witcher-henry-cavill-geralt-netflix-battlefield-6-2000633232">drama surrounding Henry Cavill’s seemingly tumultuous exit</a>? Doesn’t sound like it. One of the most glowing things early watchers have to say about Hemsworth is that, while he ain’t great, he’s at least not the worst thing about season 4.</p>

 <p>It’s everything else that’s apparently a weird mess. The new episodes, which started streaming on October 30, pick up with a recovering Geralt searching a war-torn countryside for surrogate daughter Ciri who is trying out life with a group of bandits while the mage Yennefer rallies others to her campaign to take down the rogue member of the member of the&nbsp;Brotherhood of Sorcerers named Vilgefortz.</p>

 <p>The show was trending in the wrong direction even during its bumpy season 3, which was awkwardly split in half, thus I’m not entirely surprised that season 4 is the Netflix adaptation’s most poorly reviewed yet. It’s currently sitting at a positive rating of just 58 percent <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/tv/the_witcher/s04">on Rotten Tomatoes</a>. Fan sentiment is even worse, with a user rating in the teens. “The problem isn’t that the show has a new lead actor; it’s that it continues to be a bloated mess,” writes Andrew Webster <a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/810151/the-witcher-season-4-review-netflix-liam-hemsworth">at<em> The Verge</em></a>. “No amount of imaginative swordplay or inventive creature design can prevent the sense that The <em>Witcher</em> is now what all sword and sorcery epics fear becoming: pure bilge,” wrote Nick Hilton <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/arts-entertainment/tv/reviews/the-witcher-season-4-netflix-liam-hemsworth-review-b2854691.html">at <em>The Independent</em></a>.</p>

 <p>The problems go beyond Hemsworth, though. “The tone remains wildly uneven, lurching as it does between steeple-fingered <em>Game of Thrones</em>-y glumness and those early-90s Saturday afternoon series in which an uncommunicative hunk wanders between small communities, rescuing imperiled innocents from baddies while learning about the true meaning of friendship,” wrote Sarah Dempster <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2025/oct/30/the-witcher-season-four-review-liam-hemsworth-replaces-henry-cavill-review">at <em>The Guardian</em></a>. Solving that contradiction was what<em> The Witcher 3</em> video game did so well, and what the show has failed at more and more with each successive season.</p>

 <p>Not everyone’s so down on <em>The Witcher</em>‘s return. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-the-witcher-season-4-review-liam-hemsworth"><em>IGN</em></a>‘s Matt Fowler called it “incomplete” but congratulated it on “more successes than missteps,” while <a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/tv/netflix/the-witcher-season-4-review"><em>Paste Magazine</em></a>‘s Lacy Baugher called it “wildly satisfying” as a spin-off about the tormented mage Yennefer, played by the excellent Anya Chalotra. But many fans aren’t having it. “Don’t mind Hemsworth as Geralt,” <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/tv/the_witcher/s04/reviews?type=user">conceded</a> one Rotten Tomatoes user. “It’s tough being second and he’s notable different to Cavill. The real issue with season 4 is the direction. It’s corndog crap. Witches on brooms, swearing birds, priests that burn children being aided by the crew of the Black Pearl, it’s just nonsense.”</p>

 <p>Beyond these eight new episodes, a season 5 is still supposedly in the works. After that? It sounds like Netflix is ready to call it. “By the time we wrap Season 5 fully, it will have been nine years of my life,” showrunner Lauren Schmidt-Hissrich <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/tv-movies/the-witcher-could-netflix-show-survive-without-geralt-henry-cavill-exit-3277462/">told <em>Dexerto</em></a>. “I think there are so many more stories to be told in <em>The Witcher</em> universe, truly.  But I also think you have to step back and accept gracefully, what is the end of this story that we’ve been telling?”</p> <p>At least by then, CD Projekt Red’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-ciri-trailer-gameplay-ue5-tech-demo-1851783467"><em>The Witcher 4</em></a> will probably be out. It will similarly be moving from one lead to another, focusing on Ciri instead of Geralt. Hopefully, that transition goes much smoother.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/netflix-witcher-season-4-reviews-liam-hemsworth-2000640506]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s Halloween Again, Let’s Rank The Best Ghost-Type Pokémon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-ghost-type-gengar-mimikyu-giratina-yamask-1850968054</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-halloween-again-let%E2%80%99s-rank-the-best-ghost-type-pok%C3%A9mon.1340725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The end of October is here, which means the spooky decorations are about to make way for snow, presents, and mistletoe. But before we say goodbye to the jack-o-lanterns and trick-or-treating, we can still pay tribute to the spookiest, the scariest, the ghouliest(?) of Pokémon: the ghost types.</p> <p>Over the years, ghost Pokémon have exploded in number, starting from just <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-gastly-anime-episode-ghost-of-maidens-peak-1850892373">the Gastly line</a>, which was their sole representative in the original games, to now dozens of critters haunting the Pokémon world. Ghost-type Pokémon Pokédex entries include some of the most <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-horror-trailer-creepy-2000619530">terrifying lore dumps</a> in this typically all-ages series, and that’s what makes them some of the most interesting. But while we’d love to give every ghost-type friend their due, today we’ve narrowed it down to the 10 creepiest, spookiest, and most memorable lines in the first nine generations of Pokémon. That was a tough challenge, because there are some pretty remarkable ghosts in these games. But before we get to the honorees, here are the honorable mentions:</p> <ul> <li>Aegislash</li> <li>Cursola</li> <li>Dragapult</li> <li>Drifblim</li> <li>Froslass</li> <li>Galarian Marowak</li> <li>Gholdengo</li> <li>Golurk</li> <li>Hisuian Typhlosion</li> <li>Houndstone</li> <li>Mismagius</li> <li>Polteageist</li> <li>Rotom</li> <li>Skeledirge</li> </ul> <div> <p>Welcome to Exp. Share, <em>Kotaku</em> ’s <em>Pokémon</em> column in which we dive deep to explore notable characters, urban legends, communities, and just plain weird quirks from throughout the <em>Pokémon</em> franchise.</p></div>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-ghost-type-gengar-mimikyu-giratina-yamask-1850968054]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[31 Terrific Movies That Are Perfect For Spooky Season]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/best-halloween-movies-disney-scary-spooky-1851654060</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/31-terrific-movies-that-are-perfect-for-spooky-season.1340632/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Can you feel that chill in the air? Are the trees in your neighborhood shifting shades from verdant greens to crisp reds and oranges? Notice that the sun is setting earlier? Though these are all markers of the beginning of fall AKA the beginning of my seasonal depression, they are also, gratefully, signs of spooky season. Yes, we are entering the period of Halloween, of candy and costumes and creepy things, and the colder temps mean it’s also the perfect time to curl up on the couch with some warm apple cider and a thematically appropriate movie.</p> <p><em>This round-up originally ran on September 23, 2024. We are re-publishing it in case you need some last minute recommendations for your Halloween 2025 watchlist.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>Elsewhere, we’ve <a href="https://kotaku.com/tim-burton-movies-ranked-beetlejuice-big-fish-halloween-1851637754">ranked every Tim Burton film</a>, and gathered a few scary <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=best+sci+fi+ktoaku&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_en&amp;oq=best+sci+fi+ktoaku&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUyBggAEEUYOTIJCAEQIRgKGKABMgkIAhAhGAoYoAEyCQgDECEYChigATIJCAQQIRgKGKAB0gEIMjEyOWowajeoAgCwAgA&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sci-fi flicks in our list of the best ones</a> in the last 50 years, so if you don’t see those flicks here, that’s why.</p> <p>This list has 31 spooky-season movies that are absolute must-sees this Halloween season, from terrifying tales to cutesy capers. Expect some classics, like <em>The Exorcist</em>, the OG <em>Halloween</em>, and <em>The Addams Family</em>, as well as some newer and cult-ier stuff like <em>Jennifer’s Body</em> and <em>Near Dark. </em>Whatever kind of mood you’re in, we’ve got a movie here for you—hell, there’s one for every day in October! You can start early if you want, or wait until the month kicks off and start getting through the list, the choice is yours. Click through for 31 movies to help you celebrate spooky season.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/best-halloween-movies-disney-scary-spooky-1851654060]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>