<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 11:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sells at a Loss, LEGO Star Wars Ahsoka T-6 Jedi Shuttle Reaches a New All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-sells-at-a-loss-lego-star-wars-ahsoka-t-6-jedi-shuttle-reaches-a-new-all-time-low-2000620762</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-sells-at-a-loss-lego-star-wars-ahsoka-t-6-jedi-shuttle-reaches-a-new-all-time-low.1282743/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Labor Day</em> is here and Amazon is in the mood to clean out its shelves with some deals that feel almost unreal. These record-low prices even beat what we saw during Prime Day in July, which says a lot. And if you’re into LEGO, you probably know Star Wars sets are the ones everyone pays attention to.</p>
<p>Right now, the <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3759/">LEGO Star Wars Ahsoka Tano’s T-6 Jedi Shuttle has plummeted to an all-time low price of just $47, from a previous price of $80</a> (41% off), with a whopping <strong>4.8 out of 5 stars across more than 1,500 reviews</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Must-Have LEGO Set</h2>
<p>The T-6 Jedi Shuttle (75362) tips the scales at <strong>over 600 pieces</strong> and springs to life as <strong>Ahsoka Tano’s spaceship in the Disney+ series</strong>. LEGO made sure that the shuttle is not a special one that you build and never touch again. Wings are folded up to flight position, there is an opening cockpit, and the set makes space for play scenarios that Star Wars fans will recognize straight away.</p>
<p>One of the highlights for collectors is the lineup of mini-figures included in the kit: <strong>Ahsoka Tano herself is featured with her dual white lightsabers</strong>, but with her as well is Sabine Wren with blasters, Professor Huyang with his unique droid model, and Marrok, one of the show’s antagonists, with a double-bladed lightsaber. Minifig fans alone are already made this set worth a purchase because exclusive figures inflate aftermarket values.</p>



<p>Design-wise, the T-6 has the details you’d hope for in a modern LEGO Star Wars release: The <strong>ship measures over 10 inches long, about 9 inches wide, and stands 3 inches tall in its landed form</strong>. That makes it a satisfying build that looks good on display without taking over your entire shelf. The play features (like stud shooters and the adjustable wings) are intuitive enough for younger builders to use frequently without frustration.</p>
<p>It’s also a great gift option. With Disney+ placing Ahsoka at the center of Star Wars storytelling momentum, there’s a safe bet kids (and a decent number of adults) will have this ship on their holiday list. At under fifty dollars, it’s one of those deals you don’t hesitate at.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-sells-at-a-loss-lego-star-wars-ahsoka-t-6-jedi-shuttle-reaches-a-new-all-time-low-2000620762]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>