<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:09:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Shuts Down Studio Behind Critically Acclaimed Demon’s Souls And Shadow Of The Colossus Remakes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bluepoint-sony-playstation-ps5-god-war-2000671390</link>
            <guid>1440862</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Bluepoint Games, the PlayStation first-party team involved in the remakes of console exclusives like <a href="https://kotaku.com/demons-souls-on-ps5-has-still-got-it-1845648877"><em>Demon’s Souls</em></a> and<a href="https://kotaku.com/shadow-of-the-colossus-the-kotaku-review-1822531522"><em> Shadow of the</em> <em>Colossus</em>,</a> is closing in March, a source tells <em>Kotaku</em>.</p> <p>As first reported by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3mfaauf5pek2b"><em>Bloomberg</em>‘s Jason Schreier</a>, the move comes five years after Bluepoint Games released its last project, a launch exclusive for the PlayStation 5. It was also a support studio on 2022’s <i>God of War Ragnarök</i>.</p> <p>“Following a recent business review, the decision was made to close Bluepoint Games in March,” a spokesperson for Sony wrote in an emailed statement. “Bluepoint Games is an incredibly talented team and their technical expertise has delivered exceptional experiences for the PlayStation community. We thank them for their passion, creativity, and craftmanship.”</p> <p>The Texas-based studio was acquired by Sony only a few years ago in 2021 and was most recently working on a live-service project. That game, which was reportedly <a href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-multiplayer-bluepoint-days-gone-2-concord-1851742012">a multiplayer <em>God of War</em> spin-off</a>, was canceled early in 2025.</p> <p>Fans had been hoping for years that Sony would use Bluepoint Games to revive other PlayStation classics, including the PS4 exclusive <em>Bloodborne</em>. Throwing it onto a live service project was baffling to many, but of a piece with the PS5 maker’s disastrous campaign to create online multiplayer hits internally.</p>

 <p>Bluepoint Games was founded back in 2006 and its first game was a PSN downloadable shooter about fighting biological infections called <em>Blast Factor</em>. While that game never made the studio a household name, it quickly became a key player in helping Sony ship remasters of its back catalog. Bluepoint was responsible for the original <i>The Ico &amp; Shadow of the Colossus Collection</i> on PS3 and getting <em>Gravity Rush</em> off of PS Vita and onto PS4.</p> <p>By last count, the studio employed roughly 70 people. It’s unclear if they are all getting laid off or if some of those developers will be shifted to other parts of PlayStation Studios.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bluepoint-sony-playstation-ps5-god-war-2000671390]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>