<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:36:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Might Have To Raise The Price Of The Switch 2 At The Worst Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-tariff-ai-ram-stock-price-2000661382</link>
            <guid>1411360</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Nintendo may be about to “<a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-gta-6-price-switch-2-trump-tariff-2000618881">follow in Sony and Microsoft’s footsteps</a>” and announce a Switch 2 price hike, according to a report from video game consumer insights firm Niko Partners. Although the new system is currently outselling the original Nintendo Switch by a wide margin in its first year, spiking RAM costs and ongoing tariffs could change all that.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Niko Partners notes <a href="https://nikopartners.com/niko-partners-2026-predictions/">in a recent report</a> (via </span><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/nintendo-switch-2-faces-a-price-increase-in-2026-research-firm-predicts/"><i><span>VGC</span></i><span>) that</span></a> <span>Nintendo opted “to maintain [the Nintendo Switch 2’s] $449 entry price” when the system launched in June 2025, even as a trade war between the U.S. and China fueled price hikes on its competition. It now expects Nintendo to have to match those increases in 2026 due to high import taxes, increased memory costs, and other market conditions. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/amazon-ceo-says-tariff-price-increases-likely-to-hit-your-wallet-this-year-2000712020">Even Amazon’s CEO is</a> warning that this is the year companies start passing on more of the pain of tariffs to consumers.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Nintendo President Shuntaro Furukawa </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-hike-nintendo-sale-discount-2000642086"><span>previously told investors last November</span></a><span> that the company could keep the Switch 2 at $450 and “maintain the current level of profitability for hardware for the time being unless there are significant changes in external factors.” That time may have now passed. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-nintendo-ram-shortage-2000658946"><span>Earlier this year</span></a><span>, he said the company was monitoring the current RAM situation and didn’t commit to not raising the price in the near future.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>These rumblings continue to suggest that anyone thinking of buying a Switch 2 in the next year might be better off doing it sooner rather than later, though Niko Partners notes that Nintendo might just start exclusively selling the $500 Switch 2 bundle rather than raising the price of the standalone SKU. In the meantime, the second half of the device’s launch year has been decidedly more uneven than the first.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Despite having the </span><a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-switch-2-sets-record-selling-over-3-5-million-units-globally-in-first-four-days/"><span>fastest sales of any Nintendo console ever</span></a><span>, and </span><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pierre485.bsky.social/post/3mbwj5lp24s2o"><span>currently outselling</span></a><span> the original Nintendo Switch in Japan by almost 2:1 in its first 30 weeks on the market, Nintendo’s stock has been tanking. </span><span>The company’s Switch 2’s Christmas hardware sales were reportedly </span><a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/nintendo-switch-2-sales-stumble-over"><span>down by 35 percent</span></a><span> compared to hardware sales in 2017 (the Nintendo Switch’s release year). Hardware sales numbers might be strong overall, but </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-11/nintendo-s-software-sales-aren-t-keeping-up-with-hardware-boom"><i><span>Bloomberg </span></i><span>reported</span></a><span> that game sales and attach rates were actually down compared to the first Switch’s debut.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Meanwhile, Nintendo’s stock price has dipped </span><a href="https://www.tipranks.com/news/the-fly/game-on-nintendo-stock-drops-in-japan-over-past-five-months-thefly"><span>by a whopping 23.45 percent</span></a><span> over the last three months. With pressure mounting from the AI-driven RAM shortages and a weird holiday season for the Switch 2, Nintendo is in the awkward position of needing to maintain the existing launch-window sales momentum while also being expected to increase the hardware’s price tag. The only thing that could square that circle is a new </span><i><span>3D Mario</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>Zelda </span></i><span>adventure, but neither of those have been officially announced yet. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-tariff-ai-ram-stock-price-2000661382]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Took Five Years For Forza Horizon 5 To Become My Antidote To Doomscrolling]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/forza-horizon-5-backlog-pulse-music-ps5-xbox-2000661365</link>
            <guid>1411345</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>2012’s </span><i><span>Forza Horizon </span></i><span>is one of my lifetime favorites. Earlier games like </span><i><span>Grand Theft Auto 3 </span></i><span>had shown me how much I could enjoy the simple experience of driving around a game’s world with a great song on the radio, but </span><i><span>Horizon </span></i><span>took it to the next level with its gorgeous Colorado setting, its impeccable driving model, and the relentless stream of exceptional pop tunes on Horizon Pulse, the game’s best radio station.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet, despite loving the original, I’ve been largely uninterested in its many sequels. Whenever a new one has landed, I’ve spent a bit of time with it and then walked away, feeling like each one was a solid game but also just more </span><i><span>Horizon</span></i><span>, and that wasn’t enough to pull me back. </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>came the closest, with its inviting slice of Mexico just calling out to be explored, but even then, cruising around an open world didn’t feel like an experience I needed to return to in 2021.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>And so the series has languished on my backlog, with me thinking that maybe someday I might find a reason to truly dive back in and rediscover the spark that made me fall in love with the original. At last, that time has come: I’m playing and enjoying </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>every day, and the experience has taught me to think about my backlog in a different way. Rather than viewing it as a list of games that I really want to push myself to play and complete as soon as the opportunity arises, I’m coming to accept the idea that with some games, you just have to be in the right mindset. Maybe a game’s time will come and maybe it won’t, but you shouldn’t try to force it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Right now, my life feels like a game that mostly takes place in corridors. I get up in the morning, I walk down the same familiar streets to the same train line that takes the same route into the city each day, and at night, I make the same trip back home. Of course I’m aware that there’s a whole world beyond the confines of the narrow pathway I follow day in and day out, but the routine of my days remains pretty rigid. The constant barrage of political horrors and acts of evil, alongside the global embarrassments that come from having a raving lunatic as your president, only exacerbate the feeling that I need to escape, hit the open road without destination or obligation and focus more on the gorgeous scenery around me than I do on whatever nightmares are unfolding in the news and on my social media feeds.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000661368" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661368"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661368">When you’re playing an Xbox game on a PlayStation console, only one customized license plate will do.</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I bought </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>on PlayStation 5 as part of the recent winter sale, not long after the news had broken that we’d attacked Venezuela. I’ve stress-eaten pints of ice cream before but this was, I think, my first time ever stress-buying a video game. I just wanted to be someplace else. Not fighting my way through the hostile world of some combat-heavy video game but someplace gorgeous and welcoming, where I was free to go anywhere and the scenery was full of rejuvenating natural beauty. And that’s exactly what </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>is giving me.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s probably not going to become lodged into my consciousness the way the first game did, both because the experience felt fresh and new back in 2012 and because </span><a href="https://youtu.be/RhJJjbLzfuk?si=PzZiYatJmI35xdav"><span>the original’s Horizon Pulse is still undefeated</span></a><span>, its shimmery pop bangers becoming fused with my sense memory of cruising around Colorado. There’s some decent tunes in </span><i><span>Horizon 5</span></i><span> but nothing that’s making the pilgrimage over to my own personal playlists the way so many songs from the original did.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet, don’t get me wrong, I’m having a great time with </span><i><span>Horizon 5</span></i><span>. The racing in it is excellent, of course, but I actually bought a fairly ordinary car, a Nissan Skyline, so I could do my favorite thing: just drive around at a reasonable speed and take in the scenery. Sometimes when I’m on the subway on my way home from work, I close my eyes and see the game’s world, with those vast, breathtaking skies, already calling to me. And yes, of course getting home and diving into </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5</span></i><span> is just me replacing one screen with another. I know that. But the screen that lets me escape into that gorgeous Mexican landscape isn’t going to fry my brain with a litany of all the latest horrors. It’s going to let me forget all that for a little while, savor the pleasure of hitting the open road, and remember why I think this world is worth fighting for.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s also helping me make peace with my backlog. For years, games like </span><i><span>Returnal </span></i><span>and the </span><i><span>Demon’s Souls </span></i><span>remake have sat there, waiting patiently for my attention, and yet tackling them has just never felt right. I have little doubt that if and when I do play them, I’ll find a great deal to admire and I may even fall in love with them and wonder what took me so long, but I’ve just never yet felt them calling to me. Sometimes I’ve felt bad for not forcing myself to play them, telling myself that maybe if I just push myself over the initial hump of my indifference, everything would click and I’d be glad that I dove in.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Maybe I would, but now I feel like maybe it’s okay to let go of that pressure, and to tell myself that if there comes a time in my life when </span><i><span>Returnal </span></i><span>is the game I need to play, the right game for where my mind and my heart are at in that moment, I’ll know it. For now, I have to go drive a car into a sandstorm.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/forza-horizon-5-backlog-pulse-music-ps5-xbox-2000661365]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Already Brought Anthem Back To Life And Has It Running On A Private Server]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anthem-revival-private-servers-shutdown-bioware-fan-2000661358</link>
            <guid>1411327</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>While ex-BioWare producer Mark Darrah </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-single-player-offline-mode-bioware-ea-mark-darrah-2000659773"><span>made a whole pitch</span></a><span> about how EA could still salvage </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>for relatively cheap, it does seem more likely that BioWare and its parent company are going to let the game </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-server-shutdown-final-hours-videos-clips-stream-2000659367"><span>die a meaningless death</span></a><span>. However, some fans are looking into how the game could remain playable despite the servers being shut down, and one person has already managed to get it running on a P2P server.</span></p> <p><span>YouTuber And799 has posted a video of the game running on local servers. Though some of the online features, such as looking at your online profile, didn’t work, And799 was able to get the game running with two players in the same matchmaking space. According to the video description, this is all just for “research” and an “experiment,” and shouldn’t be considered indicative of any kind of </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>revival process. However, it is exciting to see that a playable version of the game is still possible, even if EA and BioWare aren’t helming it themselves.</span></p>

  <p><span>If that’s already possible mere days after </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>was shut down on January 12, hopefully fan efforts to preserve the game bear fruit in the coming months. Even if you </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-server-shutdown-bioware-dragon-age-mass-effect-1851786136"><span>didn’t like </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i></a><span>or thought BioWare </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-bioware-mark-darrah-interview-rpg-shutdown-2000661337"><span>shouldn’t have made it</span></a><span>, a game shouldn’t disappear without a trace afterpeople paid money for it and hundreds of developers spent years working on it. Fans may get the game’s unfinished campaign back up and running, but it’s unclear how much of the online experience they’ll be able to rebuild.</span></p> <p><i><span>Anthem</span></i><span>’s shutdown comes about a year after </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-bioware-layoffs-mass-effect-1851784416"><span>BioWare was subject to significant downsizing</span></a><span> following the launch of </span><i><span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</span></i><span>, with remaining developers all working on the next </span><i><span>Mass Effect</span></i><span>. The studio put out a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-n7-day-bioware-blog-teaser-url-krogan-2000642122"><span>small tease for the game on N7 Day last year</span></a><span>, but was completely silent when </span><i><span>Dragon Age</span></i><span>’s equivalent fan day </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-day-bioware-layoffs-december-4-2000650888"><span>came and went in December</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anthem-revival-private-servers-shutdown-bioware-fan-2000661358]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Games Are Forever Stuck In Your Backlog?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/backlog-forever-game-stuck-cyberpunk-2077-daggerfall-2000661313</link>
            <guid>1411261</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Video game backlogs vary wildly from person to person. Some folks have massively long lists of games they want to play. Others might only have a few that they are dedicated to crossing off. But one thing I find true across all gaming backlogs is that there’s always one game that, for whatever reason, remains stuck on the list and seems unlikely to ever be finished.</p> <p>So we at <em>Kotaku, </em><a href="https://kotaku.com/reviews/backlog">in honor of our ongoing Backlog Week</a>, want to know what game or games are forever trapped in your backlog and why? Maybe its because you love it and <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-how-long-to-beat-2000657800">can’t bear to watch credits roll</a>, or maybe it has an excruciating <a href="https://kotaku.com/13-bad-boss-fights-zelda-mass-effect-kingdom-hearts-1850334686">difficulty spike or story twist</a> that made you completely bounce off it.</p>

 <p>Speaking personally, I have two games that remain permanently stuck on my backlog like tiny splinters unable to be removed. The first is a more recent-ish title: <em>Cyberpunk 2077.</em></p> <p>I’ve now tried on three separate occasions to start playing <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-the-kotaku-review-1845946628">Cyberpunk 2077</a>.</em> And each time I get about two to three hours in and reach the moment when the game goes fully “open world,” I quickly fall off.&nbsp; There’s something about <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>‘s city and world that just feels lifeless and dull. Walking around it doesn’t do much for me. Then I try to explore and find quests and I just get bored and stop. This annoys me a lot. There are people whose opinion I trust a lot who love<em> Cyberpunk 2077.</em> They adore it. They’ve played it more than once. And yet I can’t even get past the opening hours. Perhaps I’ll never cross this one off my list.</p>

 <p>The other game in my backlog is an old one: <em>Daggerfall</em>. I’m a big fan of the<em> Elder Scrolls</em> games, but I started with <em>Morrowind</em>. Each time I’ve tried to play <em>Daggerfall</em>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-daggerfall-unity-oblivion-remastered-1851779519">even the great Unity port,</a> I’m just unable to push through the ancient mechanics, menus, and design ideas. But again, I know people who love this game and find it super special. And as a big <em>Elder Scrolls</em> fan, I want to experience it. Sadly, that hasn’t happened yet, despite trying a few times in recent years.</p>

 <p>Anyway, leave your backlog games that won’t leave in the comments below, and tell us why they’re stuck forever on your list.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/backlog-forever-game-stuck-cyberpunk-2077-daggerfall-2000661313]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>