<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:21:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govee Christmas LED Lights Go for Peanuts, Holiday Decor Basically Comes Free Thanks to Exceptionally Low Black Friday Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/light-your-outdoors-up-with-the-govee-christmas-lights-2-for-just-130-today-2000647131</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/govee-christmas-led-lights-go-for-peanuts-holiday-decor-basically-comes-free-thanks-to-exceptionally-low-black-friday-pricing.1364137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Holiday shopping is on the rise, and if you haven’t grabbed a fun string of Christmas lights to brighten up your outdoor and indoor space, today is a good time to make the move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5918/">Govee, a brand that offers some of our favorite smart lighting solutions out there, is now offering its outdoor-friendly, 164-foot Christmas Lights 2 for $130 on Amazon</a>. That’s after a sweet, straightforward 35% discount on the retail price of $200, thanks to an early Black Friday deal.</p>
<p>These are already high in demand on regular days, and the current discount makes them an even more popular pick. It’s best to grab yours before the stock disappears for good, which could be any moment now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5918/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>AI-Generated Light Show</h2>
<p>These aren’t your average, golden string lights. The string comes with 500 LEDs, each of which has a built-in IC chip to realize single control. Govee adds white LED beads to the color mix for a brighter setting with high color accuracy. There are 16 million color options to choose from (you read that right), meaning you can have a different one every single day of the year and still have plenty left to explore. Go with neon green in the morning, red in the evening, and wind down with a subtle golden at night; the possibilities are endless.</p>
<p>If plain, solid colors start to feel boring, especially during festivities, there are over 130 animated lighting effects for every possible occasion. For instance, the Thanksgiving option features warmer colors for cozy gatherings and hearty meals, while the Christmas one brings brighter colors to lift the energy of the whole house instantly. You can switch colors and patterns, plus create your own effects when feeling a bit creative. Not sure what to go for? Share your vision with the Govee AI Lighting Bot, and it’s going to create one based on your preferences. You can even upload some images to give it an idea of the vibe you’re hoping to achieve. Say something like “Give me a dancing Christmas effect”, and wait for the ultimate showdown.</p>



<p>As for the installation, setting the lights up is fairly straightforward. The 164-foot length is enough to line the roof, wrap around your Christmas tree, or frame the main door. It’s ideal for most homes, but if you need another size, these lights also come in 66ft, 99ft, and 328ft size options. The prices vary, but almost all the options are going for less right now. Once you have the lights up, you can manage them using the dedicated smartphone app or through your voice with Alexa and Google Assistant. You can ask the voice assistants to turn the lights on/off, change the patterns, adjust the brightness, and more, without even getting up from your couch.</p>
<p>Finally, Govee has designed the lights to be both waterproof and dustproof. They can handle extreme weather conditions (rain, harsh sunlight, snow) like a champ, so nothing is going to dim that spark, pun intended.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5918/">The current Black Friday deal brings the price down to just $130, which is quite affordable considering all the features you’re getting.</a> Even though these are labelled as “Christmas lights”, you can use them all year round for every occasion, whether it’s birthdays, anniversaries, or even just casually at home. The brand is also offering plenty of its other top-rated lighting solutions for less, so now is a great time to stock up on both indoor and outdoor smart lights. Just be sure to act fast, as early deals tend to wrap up quickly.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5918/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/light-your-outdoors-up-with-the-govee-christmas-lights-2-for-just-130-today-2000647131]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Goes Final Clearance on Anker iPhone Charger, Basically Giving It Away for Free at This Point]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-final-clearance-on-anker-iphone-charger-basically-giving-it-away-for-free-at-this-point-2000647203</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-goes-final-clearance-on-anker-iphone-charger-basically-giving-it-away-for-free-at-this-point.1364092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>This Anker charging bundle has become the <strong>#1 bestselling charger on Amazon over Black Friday</strong> and the pricing explains the overwhelming popularity immediately. Apple asks for $20 for a single 20W charger that doesn’t even include a cable and forces separate purchases that drive total costs upward quickly.</p>
<p>At <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3718/">$11, down from $18, you’re getting here two complete 20W Anker chargers + two USB-C to USB-C cables</a> in a single package that costs less than one official Apple charger alone. Anker’s good reputation as an <strong>Apple-approved accessory manufacturer</strong> sold in the Apple Stores instills confidence that these chargers meet quality and safety standards without paying Apple Tax premiums.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3718/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>20W Fast Charging That Meets Apple’s Official Specs</h2>
<p>This 20W power output provides the <strong>fastest charging speed supported by the USB-C ports</strong> of the iPhone 15, 16, and 17 models-just like Apple’s own charger specifications. Compared to the old 5W adapters that came packaged with earlier iPhones, this wattage offers noticeably quicker charging: by up to 50% for most devices.</p>
<p>You will be able to charge your iPhone 17 to about 50% in roughly 30 minutes when paired with a 20W charging system. For phones supporting fast, seamless top-ups during daily routines or during stopovers at home between activities, the charging speed works just as well with iPads, Samsung phones, and other USB-C devices equipped with Power Delivery fast-charging protocols.</p>



<p>The compact<strong> dual-port design includes both USB-C and USB-A outputs</strong> to charge two devices at once with no compromise in speed and without occupying multiple wall outlets. A configuration like this proves to be a real asset in homes where wall outlets remain scarce and several family members fight for a chance to charge their devices.</p>
<p>Charge your iPhone through USB-C while powering AirPods, Apple Watch, or older Lightning devices via the USB-A port with the appropriate cables. The intelligent power distribution ensures that both ports deliver optimal charging speeds rather than splitting power inefficiently, which would slow both devices down.</p>



<p>Anker has several safety features including <strong>overvoltage protection</strong> to prevent excessive voltage from damaging connected devices, temperature control that reduces power output if overheating occurs, and short circuit protection to shut off power during fault conditions. Such protections count because many no-name low-cost chargers have inadequate safety implementations and poses the risk of fire or even device damage through poorly regulated power delivery.</p>
<p>The <strong>included 5-foot USB-C-to-USB-C cables</strong> are long enough to support comfortable device use while charging, from floor outlets to desks or bedside tables, without tight stretching. The length of the cable balances portability for travel and practicality for daily use at home, where often 3-foot cables can be frustratingly short.</p>
<p>At $11, the Anker 2-pack includes four pieces in total: two 20W dual-port chargers and two 5-foot USB-C cables, all at 41% below retail this Black Friday. Apple sells its single 20W charger sans cables for nearly double which makes Anker’s value proposition for buyers needing more than one charging point absurdly favorable.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3718/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-final-clearance-on-anker-iphone-charger-basically-giving-it-away-for-free-at-this-point-2000647203]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Tab S10 FE Drops to Record Low for Pennies, Might Be Time to Offload That iPad Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-tab-s10-fe-drops-to-record-low-for-pennies-might-be-time-to-offload-that-ipad-now-2000647199</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-tab-s10-fe-drops-to-record-low-for-pennies-might-be-time-to-offload-that-ipad-now.1364089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Samsung and Apple battle relentlessly across every product category from smartphones to laptops to tablets, with each company trying to outdo the other on features, performance, and ecosystem integration. The <strong>Galaxy Tab S10 FE launched just months ago</strong> as Samsung’s direct challenge to standard iPads and offers comparable performance and features at more aggressive pricing.</p>
<p>The <em>Fan Edition</em> designation indicates this model <strong>prioritizes value over bleeding-edge specs</strong>, and positions it as the sweet spot in Samsung’s tablet lineup where you get flagship features without paying flagship premiums. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5676/">At $359, down from $499, this 128GB/WiFi model has hit a record-low price</a> on Amazon for Black Friday that undercuts not just the standard iPad but also Samsung’s own higher-tier Tab S10 models.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5676/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Display Quality That Rivals iPads</h2>
<p>The <strong>10.9-inch LCD display at 2304 x 1440 resolution</strong> contributes to sharp visuals above the standard iPad resolution while matching the pixel density of more expensive tablets. You get an <strong>on-screen refresh rate of 90Hz</strong> that results in notably smoother scrolling, animations, and gaming compared to the 60Hz screens still common on tablets from rivals in this price range. This higher refresh rate makes daily interactions feel more responsive and fluid and reduces the subtle lag that plagues lower-refresh screens when you scroll rapidly through long documents or social media feeds.</p>



<p>The<strong> included S Pen stylus is a significant added value</strong> and allows handwriting, drawing, and precise input sans separate purchases like the Apple Pencil, which adds $129 to iPad prices. The pressure-sensitive tip and low latency make writing experiences that truly feel like pen on paper, rather than plastic on glass and encourages actual note-taking and sketching rather than awkward finger drawing</p>
<p><strong>Powered by the Exynos 1580 processor</strong>, it delivers ample performance for all multitasking, gaming and media consumption needs without thermal throttling and battery draining, issues that plagued mid-range tablet chips from yesteryear. It’s <strong>optimized by Samsung for smooth performance</strong> across productivity apps such as Microsoft Office, creative tools such as Adobe apps, and entertainment platforms such as Netflix, YouTube, and mobile games.</p>



<p>The<strong> IP68 rating for water resistance speaks to the exceptional durability</strong> for tablets that are normally kept away from water exposure. It certifies submersion up to 1.5 meters in water for up to 30 minutes, covers everything from kitchen spills to poolside use to bathroom entertainment without anxiety. Protection extends the tablet’s life by surviving accidents that would destroy unprotected devices.</p>
<p>It features a large-capacity cell and efficient power management<strong> for a battery life of up to 20 hours of mixed-use</strong>&nbsp;and covers several days of normal use between charges. Super Fast Charging reduces downtime when recharging becomes necessary, providing hours of use from brief charging sessions. The starting storage configuration is 128GB, <strong>with microSD expansion supporting up to 1TB additional capacity</strong> to ensure ample room for apps and documents.</p>
<p>At $359, the Galaxy Tab S10 FE gives you a 10.9-inch 90Hz display, Exynos 1580 processor, included S Pen with AI features, IP68 water resistance, a 20-hour battery, and expandable storage at 28% below retail this Black Friday. Fan Edition positioning delivers the optimal balance of features and pricing that makes premium tablet capabilities accessible without iPad premiums or flagship Galaxy pricing.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5676/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-tab-s10-fe-drops-to-record-low-for-pennies-might-be-time-to-offload-that-ipad-now-2000647199]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Quietly Clears 32″ 165Hz Gaming Monitor, Odyssey Curved Display Now Goes 40% Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-quietly-clears-32-165hz-gaming-monitor-odyssey-curved-display-now-goes-40-off-2000647195</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-quietly-clears-32%E2%80%B3-165hz-gaming-monitor-odyssey-curved-display-now-goes-40-off.1364053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The 57-inch Odyssey G9 ultrawide monitor commands attention and premium pricing,<a href="https://kotaku.com/samsung-57-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-240hz-1ms-is-800-off-hardcore-gamings-holy-grail-at-a-record-low-2000646508"> even when sales roll around</a>, but not everyone wants or can accommodate a display that dominates entire desks and requires dedicated space planning.</p>
<p>Standard-sized desks deserve premium gaming monitors too, and the <strong>32-inch Odyssey G55C delivers flagship features</strong> in dimensions that fit normal workspaces without sacrificing immersion or performance. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5925/">At $199, down from $329, this QHD curved gaming monitor has hit a record-low price</a> on Amazon for Black Friday and became the <strong>best-selling model across Samsung’s entire Odyssey lineup</strong>. That combination of 1000R curvature, 165Hz refresh rate, and genuine HDR10 support at this aggressive discount explains why it’s so popular.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5925/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>1000R Curvature That Matches Human Vision</h2>
<p>This <strong>2560 x 1440 QHD resolution packs 1.7 times more pixel density than standard 1080p displays</strong>&nbsp;and makes for noticeably sharper visuals where text stays crisp and game details remain clear during fast motion. As it is a sweet spot in resolution, it offers meaningful visual improvement over Full HD without the extreme GPU horsepower that 4K displays require to maintain high frame rates in demanding games.</p>
<p>Modern mid-range graphics cards handle QHD gaming comfortably at high settings, something that often forces compromise between visual quality and smooth performance if using 4K. Its wider aspect provides more horizontal screen real estate, which benefits both gaming and productivity by allowing the display of more content simultaneously, whether tracking enemies in competitive shooters or managing multiple windows during work sessions.</p>



<p>The <strong>aggressive 1000R curve radius comes closer to the natural curvature of human peripheral vision</strong> than, say, gentler curves at 1800R or even flat panels, making for immersive viewing that wraps content around your field of view. That tight curvature puts every part of the screen an equal distance from your eyes when properly positioned, minimising eye movement required to scan across the display while maintaining consistency in focus between centre and edges.</p>
<p>Racing games are dramatically better-the curved display creates peripheral awareness of oncoming corners and competitors. First-person shooters pick up situational awareness with better peripheral enemy detection. The effect of immersion proves most pronounced during longer gaming sessions, where the curved display pulls you into game worlds more effectively than flat monitors do, which maintain psychological distance between viewer and content.</p>



<p>The <strong>165Hz refresh rate ensures smooth motion rendering</strong> that eliminates the choppiness plaguing 60Hz displays when the game’s camera pans fast or the character is moving at incredible speeds. In competitive games, high refresh enables reduced motion blur and better target tracking to give you clear views of enemies in movement and quicker reaction capability when events catch you by surprise.</p>
<p>The <strong>response time of 1ms MPRT complements</strong> the high refresh by making sure pixel transitions are done fast enough to prevent ghost trails behind moving objects. FreeSync from AMD Radeon synchronizes display refresh with your GPU’s frame output and removes screen tearing for fluid visuals without the stutter that occurs when refresh and frame rates desync.</p>
<p><strong>HDR10 support extends the color range</strong> and contrast ratio beyond what standard dynamic range displays are capable of showing, revealing details in both shadows and highlights that SDR crushes into solid blacks or blown-out whites. Game scenes gain dramatic impact through deeper blacks, brighter highlights, and more saturated colors, making virtual worlds feel more alive and realistic.</p>
<p>At $199, the Samsung Odyssey hits that perfect sweet spot between immersion and practicality for standard desks, while the feature set compares well to premium monitors available for as much as twice the price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5925/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-quietly-clears-32-165hz-gaming-monitor-odyssey-curved-display-now-goes-40-off-2000647195]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The M4 MacBook Air Hits a Margin-Free Black Friday Price, but Apple Only Offers a Small Batch for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/an-early-black-friday-shocker-apple-drops-a-749-deal-on-the-m4-macbook-air-at-amazon-2000646931</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-m4-macbook-air-hits-a-margin-free-black-friday-price-but-apple-only-offers-a-small-batch-for-black-friday.1364047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Well, here’s one we were not expecting on the Monday of Black Friday Week — a massive unannounced deal from Apple, of all companies. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5916/">The 2025 M4 MacBook Air is the shocking subject of a huge 25% off deal at Amazon, bringing it to an all-time low price of just $749</a>. With Apple’s laptop fleet of brand-new M5 models soaking up most of the attention, they’ve decided to sneak in a killer deal on a killer laptop.</p>
<p>Make no mistake, the M4 chip makes this MacBook Air a beast for productivity, streaming, multitasking, or pretty much anything else you ask of it. The M4 was built specifically to run Apple Intelligence, and the MacBook Air has all of Apple’s industry-best features like the brilliant 13.6-inch Liquid Retina display and 18 hours of battery life. It’s a perfect match for an iPhone, with the real-time mirroring feature that lets you answer calls and texts without having to break stride to reach for your phone, and it’s a seamless pairing with any of the AirPods models.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5916/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Not New, But Definitely Not Old</h2>
<p>The M4 chip that drives the impeccable performance of the MacBook Air was Apple’s state-of-the-art processor and possibly the best anywhere in the tech world until the M5 dropped just this past October. So you don’t exactly need a time machine to hearken back to the days when the M4 ruled the roost, and the debut of the M5 does not detract one bit from its performance.</p>
<p>The M4 chip is twice as fast as the M1, and a mind-blowing 23 times faster than the last of Apple’s Intel processors. The Neural Engine that’s built into the M4 not only makes Apple Intelligence possible, it makes it run with blazing speed. There’s sufficient processing power for the Air to power up to two external displays with the same fast, fluid performance even for demanding tasks like video editing.</p>



<h2>Multimedia Superstar</h2>
<p>The MacBooks have long been among the very best laptops for connecting remotely for work or pleasure, and the M4 MacBook Air is a great example. The 12MP Center Stage camera ensures you’ll show up on the other end of a video call looking your best, and the MacBook Air’s three built-in mics and four speakers with Spatial Audio bolster a pro-level connection. Having Wi-Fi 6E and Bluetooth 5.3 connections eliminates any online glitch-outs to keep the conversation rolling without interruption.</p>
<p>The MacBook Air isn’t one of those laptops with a million ports and jacks for external devices, but what it has — two Thunderbolt 4 ports in addition to its MagSafe charging port and a headphone jack — are top-notch for connecting external monitors or external storage or charging devices.</p>
<p>For a Monday deal during Black Friday Week, this one’s a shocker. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5916/">Apple’s 13-inch M4 MacBook Air shedding $250 from its price at Amazon and landing at a record-low $749 was most definitely not on our Bingo card</a>, but it’s real, and it’s potentially one that could cause a supply-draining stampede. We would not recommend sleeping on this one too long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5916/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/an-early-black-friday-shocker-apple-drops-a-749-deal-on-the-m4-macbook-air-at-amazon-2000646931]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marshall Home Speaker Drops to All-Time Low at 40% Off, Now Far Cheaper Than Sonos and Bose Rivals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marshall-home-speaker-drops-to-all-time-low-at-40-off-now-far-cheaper-than-sonos-and-bose-rivals-2000647189</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marshall-home-speaker-drops-to-all-time-low-at-40-off-now-far-cheaper-than-sonos-and-bose-rivals.1363996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The market for home speakers is full of great options from Sonos, Bose and Samsung – all of them offering solid audio quality and smart features to merit their pricing. However, if you need a high-end speaker that doubles as a conversation piece through distinctive retro aesthetics inspired by classic guitar amplifiers, nobody pulls this vision off better than Marshall.</p>
<p>The iconic brand has successfully translated their <strong>legendary amplifier design language into Bluetooth speakers</strong> that look like miniature versions of the amps that powered rock history.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4526/"> At $179, down from $299, the Acton III has reached an all-time low price</a> on Amazon for Black Friday and delivers on that signature Marshall sound that made them legends in professional audio.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4526/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Re-Engineered Soundstage</h2>
<p>The third-generation design expands the <strong>stereo soundstage beyond earlier Acton models</strong> through revised driver placement and acoustic tuning that creates wider sound dispersion throughout your listening space. This engineering delivers immersive audio where instruments and vocals occupy distinct positions across the sound field rather than collapsing into a narrow center channel.</p>
<p>The Marshall signature sound <strong>emphasizes clarity across all frequencies while maintaining the punchy, dynamic character</strong> that made their amplifiers famous among musicians who demanded both power and precision. Rock, jazz, classical, and electronic music all benefit from the balanced frequency response that doesn’t sacrifice detail for overwhelming bass or harsh treble.</p>



<p>Futureproofing is in-built into the speaker <strong>with the next-generation Bluetooth 5.2 implementation</strong>&nbsp;which supports emerging features and codecs the moment they become widely available instead of requiring hardware replacement to access new standards. This forward compatibility matters because Bluetooth audio technology continues evolving with improved codecs, lower latency protocols, and enhanced multi-device handling that will roll out over the useful life of this speaker.</p>
<p>Compared to older versions of Bluetooth, the improved connection stability reduces dropouts and interference from competing wireless signals in crowded home environments full of Wi-Fi routers, smart home devices, and neighboring networks. Traditional <strong>wired connection fallback via 3.5mm auxiliary input is available</strong> for devices without Bluetooth and for situations where you prefer avoiding wireless compression altogether.</p>



<p>It’s a pretty straightforward pairing process that eliminates complicated app requirements or multi-step configuration sequences which frustrate users who want to play music quickly: Press the Bluetooth button, select it from your phone’s Bluetooth menu, and y<strong>ou’re playing audio within seconds of taking it out of the box</strong>. This extends into daily use, where the speaker remembers previously paired devices and automatically reconnects when they come in range, rather than having to repeat the pairing every time you want to listen to something. <strong>The speaker has tactile, analog controls</strong> at the top that allow very satisfying physical interaction when adjusting the volume, bass, and treble-a feeling more engaging than simply tapping on glass touchscreens or issuing voice commands.</p>
<p>The Marshall Acton III brings re-engineered stereo soundstage at $179, a discount of 40% off retail this Black Friday. The competitive home speaker market offers many excellent audio options, but Marshall’s distinctive design and rock heritage create an emotional appeal that technical specifications just can’t provide.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4526/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marshall-home-speaker-drops-to-all-time-low-at-40-off-now-far-cheaper-than-sonos-and-bose-rivals-2000647189]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Expands Its Black Friday Deals From Star Wars to Marvel, Spider-Man Subway Scene Drops to Nearly Free]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/spider-man-2s-iconic-train-sequence-in-lego-form-drops-20-for-black-friday-2000647064</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-expands-its-black-friday-deals-from-star-wars-to-marvel-spider-man-subway-scene-drops-to-nearly-free.1363990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="0" data-end="519">LEGO is a timeless toy that continues to capture the hearts of people of all ages. It’s not just for kids. Anyone with a sense of nostalgia or creativity can dive into the fun. LEGO has a vast array of collaborations with different fandoms, and perhaps one of its most popular partnerships is with Marvel. Among the many sets inspired by the Marvel universe is one based on the most iconic scene from the second film in Sam Raimi’s Spider-Man trilogy, and its now available at a discounted price. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5197/">This particular LEGO set of the Spider-Man vs. Doc Ock subway train showdown typically sells for $55, but it’s currently on sale for 20% off, bringing the price down to $44</a>. This price drop makes it a great deal for any LEGO fan or Spider-Man enthusiast looking to recreate one of the most memorable moments from the early 2000s Spider-Man films.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5197/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="0" data-end="519">Most Iconic&nbsp;Spider-Man Moment</h2>
<p data-start="867" data-end="1630">If you were a teenager during the mid-2000s, you probably fondly remember <em data-start="941" data-end="955">Spider-Man 2</em>, the sequel to the 2002 blockbuster. The movie remains a fan favorite and is often cited as the best of the trilogy and even all the Spider-Man film adaptations. Spoilers for <em>Spider-Man 2</em> I guess&nbsp; but, for many, the standout scene from this movie is the subway sequence, where Tobey Maguire’s Spider-Man must save a runaway train from crashing. In this scene, Spider-Man, after losing his mask, uses his webs to slow down the train, and in the end, the New York City passengers agree to keep his identity a secret.</p>
<p data-start="1632" data-end="2357">The LEGO set that pays tribute to this unforgettable scene contains 393 pieces and includes not only a detailed train model but also four minifigures: Spider-Man, Doc Ock, J. Jonah Jameson, and Aunt May. Spider-Man comes with two interchangeable heads—one masked and one unmasked—so you can replicate the scene exactly as it happened. The set also features Doc Ock with his four mechanical arms, which are adjustable and can be posed in a variety of ways. Two of the arms are equipped with laser beams, while the other two can attach to the train to create that intense showdown. Though not actually present during this scene in the movie, J. Jonah Jameson and Aunt May are included just to fill out the set. I guess they’re more recognizable than the kid who returns Peter’s mask.</p>


<p data-start="2359" data-end="2692">The completed set measures over 3 inches high, 9 inches long, and 2 inches wide, making it a perfect size to display once you’ve finished building it. The roof of the train is removable, allowing you to take a closer look at the interior details, which is a nice touch.</p>
<p data-start="3194" data-end="3606" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">Whether you’re a Spider-Man fan or simply someone who love to collect LEGO, this set offers a great way to relive a classic moment from the <em data-start="3324" data-end="3338">Spider-Man 2</em> movie. And with the current discount, you can save $11 when bringing home this piece of cinematic history.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5197/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/spider-man-2s-iconic-train-sequence-in-lego-form-drops-20-for-black-friday-2000647064]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>