<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:19:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mewgenics Has Its Own Resetti Who Will Destroy Your Run If You Save Scum]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mewgenics-reset-save-scum-cheat-easter-egg-steven-resetti-binding-of-isaac-2000668196</link>
            <guid>1433545</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span>, the cat-breeding tactical roguelike developed by Tyler Glaeil and </span><i><span>The Binding of Isaac’s</span></i><span> Edmund McMillen, is still enjoying its moment in the sun. After earning its entire development budget back in its first three hours of release on February 10, </span><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span> smashed its 24-hour-old record of 65,962 concurrent players on Steam yesterday, drawing in 83,956 players on February 11. It will almost undoubtedly do the same again today.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>However, even though </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/mewgenics-completionist-secrets-hours-binding-isaac-roguelike-2000667343"><span>Glaeil stated</span></a><span> that it will likely take “months or years” for players to find everything hidden away in </span><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span>, at least one person took less than 24 hours to discover a character named Steven. The self-proclaimed “Mr. Resetti” of </span><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span>, Steven will punish those attempting to save scum their way through the game by wresting control away from players.</span></p>

 <p><span>Steven was </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/mewgenics/comments/1r1cr3e/mr_resetti_showing_up_after_exiting_to_desktop/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>first spotted</span></a><span> over on r/mewgenics by a player who had to leave “in the middle of combat.” </span><i><span>The Binding of Isaac</span></i><span> fans will likely recognise Steven as one of the game’s bosses, but he actually originated in McMillen’s Newgrounds game </span><i><span>Time Fcuk. </span></i><span>Steven will appear in </span><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span> if you quit a run without saving, something which players might be tempted to do if a fight isn’t going their way. Or, as Steven puts it, he’ll only pop up if he spots you “fcuking with the game save.”</span></p> <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W8DUz82I-B0"><span>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W8DUz82I-B0</span></a></p> <p><span>The first time that he appears, Steven will simply admonish you for your save-scumming attempts, but warns you that the “gloves are off” if you attempt to save scum further. From here, he’ll start messing with your </span><i><span>Mewgenics</span></i><span> run. The second time you quit and reload during a run, Steven will inflict one of your cats with the “Deja Vu” disorder, which gives them a 10 percent chance to miss their turn.</span></p>

 <p><span>However, the fourth attempt at save scumming is the true run killer, as Steven will take over your current </span><i><span>Mewgenics </span></i><span>playthrough and attempt to finish it for you. According to everyone who has purposefully let Steven take over, he’s absolutely terrible. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4XN4jYLAyaA&amp;t=281s">As you can see here</a>, <em>Binding of Isaac </em>YouTuber </span><span>SlayXc2 managed to observe</span><span> the AI-controlled Steven making it through the first two fights, although he was already down to only one cat by the end of the second one.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mewgenics-reset-save-scum-cheat-easter-egg-steven-resetti-binding-of-isaac-2000668196]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch Players Are Selling Out The Cause For Lootboxes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-talon-sides-event-allegiance-rewards-lootbox-2000668184</link>
            <guid>1433515</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Overwatch</span></i><span>’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-new-heroes-story-sigma-dialogue-sombra-talon-2000667771"><span>soft reboot</span></a><span> began earlier this week, and part of the new lore-driven seasonal rollout is a Splatfest-style mechanic that has fans siding with either the titular peace-keeping group or the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-cinematic-doomfist-vendetta-death-reign-talon-2000665013"><span>terrorist organization Talon</span></a><span>. Yes, a lot of players have been playing heroes from both sides of this conflict over the past decade and might have some allegiances based on characters they main, but still, the number of fans making the heel turn to side with Talon is crazy.</span></p> <p><span>Siding with either faction gets you in-game rewards tied to different characters from both factions and you get lootboxes the further you progress, so there’s plenty of reason to pick one or the other in terms of in-game benefits. But what about the principle? What about seeing the world not as it is, but as it could be? When you were at your lowest and putting hundreds of hours into </span><i><span>Overwatch </span></i><span>in an unhealthy marathon, was it Vendetta who hyped you up? No, it was Winston, the soft-spoken gorilla scientist who put out the recall message a decade ago and has been fighting on the frontlines ever since. But one Emre voice line shows up and y’all switch up on him? You find Watchpoint Gibraltar in shambles and you stick your tail between your legs and join the bad guys? Crazy.</span></p>

 <p><span>While Talon’s support sits around 55-60 percent depending on when you look at it, the Overwatch backers aren’t quietly giving up, and are putting these disloyal payload pushers on blast.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Y'ALL FAKE AF<br>THEY SET GIBRALTAR ON FIRE AND YOU JUMP SHIP??? <a href="https://t.co/Ygstt6I8Wf">pic.twitter.com/Ygstt6I8Wf</a></p> <p>— uguubear 🧈🐻 AniYEG B08 (@uguubear) <a href="https://twitter.com/uguubear/status/2021777015742050393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">you mfs are actual traitors bro, winston stood by your side in ow1 every single day since overwatch 1s death and yall STILL CHOSE TALON <a href="https://t.co/g8s3KZQA6O">pic.twitter.com/g8s3KZQA6O</a></p> <p>— hatori🗯️ (@kornyflake) <a href="https://twitter.com/kornyflake/status/2021678776728662473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 11, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Y'all niggas fake as fuck for real <a href="https://t.co/GHCbhoyfEF">pic.twitter.com/GHCbhoyfEF</a></p> <p>— ensee (@enseecan) <a href="https://twitter.com/enseecan/status/2021716165870112950?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 11, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">overwatch vs talon event <a href="https://t.co/JepwsXSWgM">pic.twitter.com/JepwsXSWgM</a></p> <p>— VizFint (@VFlince) <a href="https://twitter.com/VFlince/status/2021861631152832856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">GUYS PLEASE DO SOMETHING I DON'T WANT TO LET WINSTON DOWN GUYS PLEASE <a href="https://t.co/0f9PbcKmfm">pic.twitter.com/0f9PbcKmfm</a></p> <p>— Spider-Brian (@SpiderBrian_) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpiderBrian_/status/2021807881625186472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="es" dir="ltr">Deshonra<br>Deshonra en esta familia<br>Talon son terroristas, el mundo necesita a overwatch, el mundo necesita a HÉROES<br>PIENSA EN WINSTON, EL ESTUVO AHÍ PARA TÍ 🫵 <a href="https://t.co/BoIDn5nFqE">pic.twitter.com/BoIDn5nFqE</a></p> <p>— Ori🍯💛🤍💜🖤 (@Ori_two_point_3) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ori_two_point_3/status/2021849244341006500?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Talon vs Overwatch event is giving me the same anxiety as the presidential race</p> <p>— Valeria Talon Agent 😈 (@ElvisBadger) <a href="https://twitter.com/ElvisBadger/status/2021875193350893783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>You’re able to switch between the two periodically, so there’s still time for those who have sided with Talon to lock in. It’s unclear if a Talon victory will have any effect on the ongoing story Blizzard is rolling out over the course of the year, but Echo, one of Overwatch’s Omnic heroes, will get a skin based on whichever faction wins. So there’s speculation that Echo’s fate and allegiance might change depending on if Talon or Overwatch wins out. For now, fans are yelling at each other to join their respective side. Vendetta voice actor Chiara Preziosi is also campaigning, and very effectively, I might add.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">BITCHES AND HOES ARE MORE THAN WELCOME IN TALON! 🫶 <a href="https://t.co/k796B5gJ88">https://t.co/k796B5gJ88</a></p> <p>— Chiara Preziosi (@Ruby_Rust) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ruby_Rust/status/2021331929354862737?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 10, 2026</a></p></blockquote> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-talon-sides-event-allegiance-rewards-lootbox-2000668184]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crisol: Theater of Idols Is A Tremendously Spanish Affair, and A Halfway Decent Survival Horror Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/crisol-theater-idols-review-steam-horror-shooter-spanish-2000667876</link>
            <guid>1433419</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Crisol: Theater of Idols</span></i><span>‘ richly illustrated world</span> <span>is deeply familiar to me. Maybe there’s a certain segment of players who’ll play it and note the same parallels I couldn’t help but draw. Though it bears a lot in common with a number of legendary games, like </span><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Bioshock</span></i><span>, this survival-horror title, which takes just as many cues from Spanish culture and folklore as it does from those legendary games, feels most in conversation with something entirely different: it reminds me a lot of the telenovelas I grew up watching on Univision.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Latine households have a few common staples. Adobo seasoning in our pantries. Daily variants of </span><i><span>arroz con habichuelas</span></i><span> with your protein of choice. A Bible of some sort, a crucifix, or related Christian imagery on the walls. Maybe a sticker that reads, “</span><i><span>Dios es amor.”</span></i><span> And, of course, a constant rotation of </span><i><span>novellas </span></i><span>in the evenings.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Novellas </span></i><span>are the height of drama and camp. There is a twist around every corner, and you’ll never miss it because these cheaply produced series will reuse the same loud sound effect to denote every dramatic development in the story. Think the </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oc7Cin_87H4"><span>Vine “boom,”</span></a><span> but every 15 minutes (charitably). Like any good soap opera, they’re often packed with too many characters to count, let alone recall at the drop of a hat. Depending on the genre–</span><i><span>novellas</span></i><span> can follow teenagers who </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vVagT0B3cos&amp;list=RDvVagT0B3cos&amp;start_radio=1"><span>break into songs</span></a><span>, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZc97aIDTUE&amp;list=PLlpTGFsKPu1k2_4mKo6Ou9iP9H6eNjRL-"><span>drug lords rising through the ranks</span></a><span>, and everything in between–these characters are usually tried-and-true archetypes, like the stumbling nerd or the doggedly loyal cadet/soldier/cop. And if there’s one thing these </span><i><span>novella </span></i><span>actors are gonna do, it’s ham things up.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>These programs, which have often enraptured the elders of my life, promised big performances, and it seemed like every other show my mother watched during these primetime slots featured booming voices, grand gestures, and </span><a href="http://www.cosmopolitan.com/entertainment/tv/news/a31651/10-best-novelas-of-all-time/"><span>more lies and betrayals</span></a><span> than one should be able to feasibly fit into a half-hour block. These shows and performances often oscillated between scintillating and corny, never anywhere in between.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>I need you all to understand this, because I couldn’t shake the feeling while playing </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>that I was caught in a fever dream of a </span><i><span>novella</span></i><span>. </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>is a halfway decent survival horror title with some great creature design, but what it really is underneath all that is a good ol’ Spanish soap. One with plenty of dramatic twists, a few too many characters, and some of the most hammed-up performances a game has ever shipped with. I love its deeply Spanish, deeply flawed heart.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>, from the Madrid-based developer Vermila Studio,</span> <span>is a tragedy told in a handful of chapters. Each of them takes Gabriel, the game’s zealous protagonist and aforementioned loyal soldier archetype, to a corner of Tormentosa, an island and colony caught in a torrential downpour. It is also caught in a religious civil war by the time that Gabriel washes up on its shores. It’s a conflict that calls for Gabriel to battle the forces of the sea god with weapons blessed (maybe even cursed, actually) by the sun god and which use his own blood as ammunition.&nbsp;</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000667878" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000667878"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000667878">Vermila Studios</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I enjoyed this aspect of </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>, though I wouldn’t call it my favorite part of the equation. I dig the metaphor, which calls into question the sacrifices that organized religion typically demands, especially of its most ardent followers. How much is Gabriel willing to bleed to see his god back in power? What actions is he willing to take, regardless of his own moral standing, to see his will done? These are questions that are blunted by the kind of game </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>is–you can’t opt out of combat here–and the answer to both proves to be: </span><i><span>a lot</span></i><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>Each of Gabriel’s weapons is, both literally and metaphorically, blood-starved, and he is plenty happy to give them everything for his cause. It is always just a smidge spine-chilling to hear or see the spikes that pierce Gabriel and drain him, as well as literally just see his blood in the cartridge of his weaponry. His opponents are similarly visually arresting. Wooden statues derived from Catholic imagery (the religion is never name-dropped but sure is heavily alluded to) lumber through the streets waiting to be carefully dismembered by precise shots of your pistol or rifle, but I could often fall back on a shotgun to blast these things to splinters and assure they’d stay down. Eventually, these enemies grow to encompass other bits of religious imagery and architecture as you encounter towering golems lined with stone faces and monstrosities born from stained glass.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Regrettably, though, </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s combat is just fine. Shots land with a satisfying heft and it’s awesome to occasionally take out a leg or a knife-wielding arm and buy yourself a few seconds to consider your next move. Beyond this, though, enemies require very little thought, especially after you’ve netted a few upgrades, and the overwhelming amount of healing afforded to you on a normal playthrough chafes against and neuters the sacrificial effect of the central blood mechanic. I quickly became numb to the notion of refilling my weapons and depleting my HP because I was either flush with syringes, or knew that the game was hiding some form of healing right around the corner.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>Here, the game dovetails back into the campy territory of those previously mentioned </span><i><span>novellas. </span></i><span>Remember that Vine boom I referenced earlier, and the repeated deployment of a dramatic audio cue? </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>has its own “haunting” series of sounds it will frequently play, only these sounds are triggered by the act of draining dead carcasses, often of animals, for blood/ammo. Tormentosa’s streets are littered with the cadavers of chickens that can be drained of their blood…only </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>takes this opportunity to then play a hilariously faint cuckoo, which happens </span><i><span>every time </span></i><span>you drain the blood from the poor birds. A dead pig will squeal. A horse-like beast might bray. Though I can’t speak to the intention, it definitely comes across as a comic beat rather than a dramatic one.</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>occasionally blurs this line between corny melodrama and unintentional comedy to mixed results. While Gabriel is straight-laced and bottoned-up, he eventually gains an ally, called Mediodia, who provides exposition and comic relief in equal measure. The performance here (especially in the native Castellano Spanish, which </span><i><span>should </span></i><span>be the default voice track of the game) and her back-and-forth with Gabriel makes her come across as a goblin-like, torturous little sister. It’s disarming hearing them banter moments after a new development in the story or tense encounter against </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s enemies, but such is the dramatic range of a typical </span><i><span>novella </span></i><span>chapter, which might follow up a subplot about infidelity or grief with a recurring sight gag or a detour into a humorous B-plotline. It is about as novel as it is jarring.</span></p> <p><span>Consider, then, how it comes across when these moments of camp and levity, intended or not, smash up against </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s main plotline, in which one religious sect has violently persecuted another and you are attempting to overthrow a god with a blood-tinged armory, all the while unraveling the conflict that has plagued Tormentosa, recounted through flashbacks–which play out as vignettes with faceless, sanguine red silhouettes– illustrating the island’s violent and dramatic implosion.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000667877" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000667877"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000667877">Vermila Studios</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Lest you think I find all of its </span><i><span>novella </span></i><span>qualities grating or otherwise dubious, I do think that </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s penchant for drama brings out the best in its performers. It is rare to hear an entire cast of Spanish speakers in a game where that audio track is not just a haphazardly produced dub. Here are performances built upon the strength of our language, given by actors with the ability to properly enrich the words on the page with texture and specificity. It is even more thrilling to have them unreservedly go for it. The voice actress for Dolores, a particularly menacing foe who stalks Gabriel throughout the game, is a standout “big” performance, but many others fare pretty well here too, including the protagonist’s VA. Arroyo, one of the game’s more obvious baddies, and even the sun god have incredible presences, even if they are heard more than they are seen.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Not every performance is as stunning though, and quite a number of them get lost in the shuffle. </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s acts are dense with their own ensembles, and characters within them are usually working against one another. In the seemingly unending deluge of conflicts on Tormentosa, some more complex than others, it can be a little harder than usual to nail down motivations and characters worth rooting for, or even simply tracking throughout the narrative. I typically felt adrift in </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s smaller stories, only to be reeled back in when the narrative shined a light on one of its grander performers and more dramatic material.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>In a word, </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>is uneven, and that’s the most </span><i><span>novella</span></i><span>-ass thing about it. See, the thing about </span><i><span>novellas </span></i><span>is that though they attempt it all–comedy, melodrama, camp, action, steamy romance, and thrills of all sorts–they also kind of fizzle out by their end. The balancing act is tough to maintain so consistently. </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s ambitions seem to lie all over the place, but despite that, it still brings out top-notch performances. I was hooked on its drama plenty enough to blast through Tormentosa’s clubs, caverns, and cathedrals. And it is a competent enough survival-horror title to thrill and occasionally provide a good scare along the way, even if it feels at times like its action and horror is pulling its punches. But for all its missteps, I couldn’t help but love </span><i><span>Crisol</span></i><span>‘s authentically Spanish heart, and I can’t help but desire more of it. From </span><i><span>Crisol </span></i><span>and from games at large.&nbsp;</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/crisol-theater-idols-review-steam-horror-shooter-spanish-2000667876]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>