<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:16:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Season 2 Review: Give Us More Episodes Or Stop Adding Subplots]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-two-review-amazon-more-episodes-bethesda-new-vegas-2000665533</link>
            <guid>1425532</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-2-finale-teases-new-location-and-something-big-liberty-prime-colorado-2000665525"><em>Fallout’</em>s second season</a> on Amazon was bigger, that’s for sure. But was it better? Well, I’m not as sure about that. It depends on how you define “better.” At the very least, there was a lot happening.</p> <p>The <a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-1-free-to-watch-youtube-prime-2000664098">first season of Amazon’s live-action adaptation</a> of Bethesda’s <em>Fallout</em> franchise had plenty of moving parts, too, but for the most part, it was focused on our three main characters—The Ghoul, Lucy, and Maximus—venturing out into the wasteland in search of answers. Their stories intersected as we learned more about the Ghoul’s connections to the past. By the end of that season, our characters had grown, learned some things, and it felt like the show had reached a satisfying and logical stopping point for this chapter of the story while still teasing what was to come next. In other words, a good season of a TV show. <a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-2-finale-margot-enclave-cooper-janey-2000665411"><em>Fallout’s</em> second season</a> was a lot more complicated and a lot less satisfying. In other words, not a great season of TV.</p> <h2><em>Fallout</em> Season Two Is Overstuffed With Subplots</h2> <p>Many, many, <em>many</em> different plot points and ideas were tossed at the wall this season, and while some of them got an ample amount of screen time, like the Ghoul’s past encounters with Mr. House and the Cold Fusion capsule, plenty of other storylines didn’t. Here’s a Super Mutant. He knows stuff about the Encalve. That’s cool, right? Okay, well, that’s all you get, and it won’t factor into any part of the rest of the season. Worse, some ideas did get decent screen time, but I’m not sure why. We spent a lot of time tracking the growth of a snack group in Lucy’s old vault, and I thought it was building up to some big clash or change. Nope. Or if that did happen, we’ll have to wait until season three to see it.</p>

 <p>Maybe the worst example of <em>Fallout</em> season two wasting time is the subplot involving Lucy’s brother, Norm. At the end of the first season, he was stuck in a vault filled with frozen Vault-Tec employees who were supposed to be woken up every so often to help lead. He ends up freeing them all and pretending to be part of the company. They help him escape, and he manipulates them and lies to lead them outside in search of his sister and answers about what Vault-Tec’s grander plans are for his home. And then…they all discover he’s lying, he gets knocked out twice, and eventually rad roaches kill all of them except Norm and one woman from the group who was sympathetic to him.</p> <p>Okay. Um…what was that all about? I was excited to see Norm using manipulation and deceit to survive in the wasteland, unlike his sister, who stayed (mostly) nice and honest. And the idea of Norm leading a group of people on the surface sounded like a great way to give his character more to do. Instead, the group is killed, and now he’s heading back to the Vault with a woman he liked. He did learn about the Forced Evolutionary Virus (FEV), which will likely play a role in season three, but beyond that, this whole side quest didn’t work for me.</p>

  <p>Mr. House, a character from <em>Fallout: New Vegas,</em> plays a major role in this season. This live-action version of him is fantastic and shows that the series can bring in game characters and do them justice.&nbsp; Yet by the end, his status is left up in the air, and I’m not even sure what happened to him. It’s very strange to spend so much of the season fleshing out Mr. House, only for the finale to seemingly leave his fate unknown and not even explain why.</p>

 <p>Some will argue that the show is setting up events and plot points for season three and will suggest that’s just how TV works. The thing is, a good season of TV should feel somewhat self-contained. A chapter of the story with its own ideas and endings. I don’t need or want every plot thread tied up. However, a TV season should wrap up in a way that feels like a natural stopping point while also providing enough closure and answers that you don’t feel like you wasted your time watching most of it. <em>Fallout</em> season two doesn’t do this, and I think it either needed to gut some plotlines or extend the episode count beyond eight.</p> <h2><em>Fallout</em>‘s Main Characters Are The Best Part Of Season Two</h2> <p>Thankfully, while the show did a poor job of balancing all its plots this season, it was able to deliver some great moments for Maximus, Lucy, and the Ghoul.</p>

 <p>In particular, the Ghoul’s storyline bounced wonderfully between his time before and after the bombs, revealing a lot more about his connections to House, The Enclave, and Vault Tec. For fans of <em>Fallout</em> lore, this is where the show shines the brightest, though for non-<em>Fallout</em> fans, some of this stuff is poorly explained. I had to answer a lot of questions after each episode when talking to people who like the show, yet have never played the games.</p> <p>Maximus escaping the Brotherhood and becoming a beacon of hope for the people of New Vegas after standing up against invading Deathclaws is a great evolution of the character. The moment when he walks by a young boy while wearing the NCR power armor is a perfect way to visually show his growth. The young boy who was saved by a power-armor-wearing soldier is now the one in armor saving the day.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000665730" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665730"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665730">© Amazon</figcaption></figure> <p>And Lucy’s relationship with her father and his plans to use control chips to save the wasteland were also a highlight of the season. It’s clear that Lucy would love for the wasteland to not be so violent and dangerous, but she won’t let her dad turn people into robot-like slaves to achieve that goal. As she tells him late in the season, after handcuffing him to an oven and before running off to destroy his work, “Thanks to you, I’m not a fudging idiot.” She still loves her dad, still respects that he raised her right, which makes his betrayal and eventual choice to wipe his own mind in the end all the more heartbreaking for her.</p>

 <p>At least seconds later, she’s reunited with Maximus and can begin the next chapter of her life in the wasteland. I mean, as she points out, the return of Caesar’s Legion and the NCR means New Vegas is likely going to be involved in a big war, one which she could have prevented with her dad’s tech. That’s the thing about war, though, it uh…never changes.</p> <p>As for the Ghoul, he’s off to Colorado to find his family. So it does seem like once again our main characters won’t all be hanging out together, as Lucy and Maximus are staying back in New Vegas. The change of scenery could help the show a lot. One can only spend so many hours in desert-y wastelands before getting bored.</p>

 <p>Still, I’m very nervous that season three of <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-way-to-play-fallout-new-vegas-in-2026-pc-mods-steam-deck-xbox-ps5-2000664195"><em>Fallout</em></a> is going to try to balance even more storylines and ideas across two different locations. If the showrunners can pull that off, season three could be amazing. If not, season three could end up being even more complicated, unsatisfying, and messy than season two.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-two-review-amazon-more-episodes-bethesda-new-vegas-2000665533]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prince Of Persia Creator Reacts To The Canceled Sands Of Time Remake: ‘Having A Project Killed Is A Brutal Experience’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-cancelled-mechner-2000665726</link>
            <guid>1425529</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>It’s been a couple of weeks since Ubisoft </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-cancels-long-delayed-prince-of-persia-remake-black-flag-remake-delay-2000661866"><span>canceled its </span><i><span>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time </span></i><span>remake</span></a><span>, and fans, the developers, and actors on the project are all still reeling from the news. One person who is also reacting to it is Jordan Mechner, the creator of the original </span><i><span>Prince of Persia</span></i><span>, who also acted as a designer on </span><i><span>Sands of Time </span></i><span>back in 2003. </span></p> <p><span>Mechner hasn’t been with Ubisoft in decades, and has largely left the video game industry in favor of writing books, but he still posted about the cancellation </span><a href="https://www.jordanmechner.com/en/latest-news/#winter-days"><span>on his personal website</span></a><span>, offering his condolences to the team.</span></p> <blockquote><p><span>I’d hoped my first post of the new year would celebrate </span><i><span>The Sands of Time</span></i><span>‘s release, but alas, that’s not in the cards. The remake’s cancellation as part of Ubisoft’s restructuring was disappointing news to all fans who’d been eagerly awaiting it, myself included.</span></p> <p><span>My sympathy goes to the development team in Montreal; I can only imagine how they must feel. Having a project killed is a brutal experience. It’s an aspect of the game industry that the public doesn’t often see, but developers are all too familiar with.</span></p> <p><span>A cancellation so close to release can be particularly devastating for younger team members who don’t have decades of past shipped titles on their resumé. It’s tough to suddenly absorb that the past four years of hard work you were proud of, and looking forward to seeing out in the world as your new calling card, will now never see daylight. Words like loss and grieving might seem exaggerated, but artists put their hearts into their work. Memories of nights and weekends spent in studio crunch instead of at home with loved ones, sacrifices that felt worth it at the time, only add to the pain retrospectively once their object ceases to exist.</span></p> <p><span>I love games — playing them, making them — but news like this makes me feel especially grateful that for the past five years, I’ve been focused on making books and art. The production budget of a graphic novel is minuscule; the creative freedom of trusting that what I write and draw will reach readers directly is priceless.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>Honestly, good for him for getting out and finding something less soul-crushing than game development right now. He touches on something significant here in that people who are still early on in their game dev career will be especially affected by this, as they likely spent years working on something they can’t include in their portfolio, and Ubisoft </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-art-leak-canceled-remake-2000663501"><span>seems dead set on making sure no one sees what the team was working on</span></a><span> by scrubbing leaked art and screenshots from the internet. Eman Ayaz, an actor who is believed to have played a role in the remake, recently released a video lamenting how her work on the project was one of her best performances, but now it will never see the light of day.</span></p>

 <p><span>The </span><i><span>Sands of Time </span></i><span>remake cancellation came as part of a </span><a href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/59b4Z0RNls45UDTVV6gBNR/801a91a599b337779106af51cf08e539/Ubisoft_Jan_PR_draft_vF.pdf"><span>larger restructuring at Ubisoft</span></a><span>, which resulted in the shelving of six games and the delaying of seven others.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-cancelled-mechner-2000665726]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Pokémon 30th Anniversary Commercial Is Forcing Me To Care About The Super Bowl]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-30-commercial-super-bowl-lx-ad-2000665640</link>
            <guid>1425526</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Look, I get it: there’s absolutely nothing interesting or special about not being interested in football. People who are performatively uninterested in watching sports are deeply tiresome. But I have a special excuse: I’m British. To me the Super Bowl is like a broadcast from an alien planet, recognizable in some respects, but completely indecipherable in others. Although I hear it has commercials and a nice bit of live music in the middle. One of those commercials, however, has piqued my interest: <em>Pokémon</em> is making some noise about having bought one of those impossibly expensive spots as the launch of its 30th anniversary promotions.</p> <p>Admittedly, my Britishness is not a&nbsp;<em>very</em> good excuse. Not least because I have friends who’ll be staying up literally all night to watch the event, and even some who already know the names of the teams involved. But they are oddities on our isle, those willing to start watching an hours-long live sporting event that begins at 11.30 p.m. And despite my reading that a game of your American Football only lasts 60 minutes but for all the stopping and starting, apparently the entire Super Bowl event goes on for more than four hours. (Also my excuse becomes tattered nonsense when I also admit to having lost many a night’s sleep to stay up watching a U.S. baseball game, because that is the only good sport, and go Phillies.)</p>

 <p>I’ve tried to come to terms with the rules of football. I’ve spent a lot of time in the States (when it felt safe to visit), and I spent a lot of that time watching baseball either in stadia or on ESPN, and fell deeply in love. And I know from that experience that my issue with football is that I don’t understand how to understand it, rather than there being anything inherently wrong with the sport itself. Like that moment when it clicked that baseball wasn’t about the batting but the pitching, I’m sure if I dedicated the time, the true nature of NFL games would slot into place for me, I’d understand its chess-like elements, and see more than what appears to be rugby with every last element of fun removed.</p> <p>But what I am far less likely to ever come around to is the crassness of celebrating the Super Bowl for its commercials. The most expensive spots on U.S. TV are spoken about each year as if they represent a cultural moment, with the ads rated for their entertainment value and artistic merit, as if these constant interruptions are benefiting the viewer in any way. I detest advertising, I do all I can to avoid it in all its forms, and god I’m such a bloody hypocrite because I really want to see what <em>Pokémon</em> has lined up.</p>

 <h2>The Pokémon 30th anniversary begins at the Super Bowl</h2> <p>2026 is <em>Pokémon</em>‘s 30th anniversary, and The Pokémon Company International (TPCi) has announced it will begin a year-long “campaign” to mark this beginning with a commercial during February 8’s Super Bowl LX. As a teaser for this, it has released a peculiar 21-second promo featuring Jigglypuff goofing around in what looks like a recording studio’s editing suite.</p>

  <p>It had been expected that TPCi would be waiting until February 27 to begin the anniversary noise, given that’s what’s become known as Pokémon Day, to match the date on which the original <em>Pokémon Red</em> and&nbsp;<em>Green</em> launched in Japan in 1996. While there has been no official announcement, it’s inevitable that on that date we’ll receive a Pokémon Direct that will—and here I’m very confidently speculating—give us the first details about <em>Pokémon</em>‘s Gen X starters, and likely an announcement for a new mainline entry in the game series due to launch before Christmas 2026. It’s been four years since <em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> and&nbsp;<em>Violet</em> released, the longest gap between main games in 15 years, and it’d be a new level of crazy, even for Nintendo, not to see the tenth generation of pocket monsters arrive for the 30th birthday.</p> <p>As for the Super Bowl spot itself, it’s probably best not to get hopes&nbsp;<em>too</em> high. Recent teases like the Jigglypuff clip above have resulted in deep anticlimaxes, like all the excitement over a Pikachu-led music game resulting in, instead, <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-legend-z-a-youtube-dj-pikachu-1851786626">an hour-long “DJ set” ahead of last July’s Direct</a>. TPCi describes the forthcoming commercial spot as something that will” illustrate the brand’s mission to bring people together through a shared love of Pokémon and honor its growing audience of diverse, global and multigenerational fans across three decades,” and indeed where fans will “see themselves and their fandom reflected in unexpected ways.” Which to me sounds like a super-long montage of <em>Pokémon</em> nostalgia amounting to reminding you that you loved it at some point in the past.</p>

 <p>Alongside this, the various international versions of the online Pokémon Center stores are selling 30th anniversary gubbins, but there’s no point even linking them as at the time of writing they’ve all inevitably gone down under the weight of scalpers scooping it all up.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000665715" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665715"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665715">© Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>And yet, for all my cynicism, I really want to see what is being put together. TPCi&nbsp;<em>are</em> capable of some <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-horror-trailer-creepy-2000619530">truly extraordinary advertising campaigns</a> that play out more like VHS horror than commercials, and while it’s too much to hope it’d lean that weird during the big football game, it at least creates the possibility of something that’s not wholly generic. Yes, it’s much more likely to be a cloying play on your childhood memories, but let me be the optimist. Not quite optimistic enough that I’ll stay up until 2 a.m. to watch whatever comes of it, let alone sit through the interminable stop-starting of men in suits of armor crying because someone trod on their toe. (Dear God, America, watch some rugby union and get a grip.) But I’ll likely seek it out the following morning, not least because of a naive hope for a glimpse of Gen X starters hiding somewhere in there.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-30-commercial-super-bowl-lx-ad-2000665640]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPad (A16 Chip) All-Time Low Deal Quietly Makes a Comeback, No Need to Look for Budget Tablets]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-ipad-a16-chip-all-time-low-deal-quietly-makes-a-comeback-no-need-to-look-for-budget-tablets-2000659253</link>
            <guid>1425499</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Apple iPad 11-inch (A16) is a portable tablet made for watching videos, browsing the web, and some light creativity, and it also has a powerful A16 chip inside to make everything run smoothly. It has 128 GB of storage for downloading apps and content, Wi-Fi 6 connectivity to quickly connect to compatible wireless networks, and one USB-C port for charging your device and attaching accessories. The tablet also includes a 12 MP front camera with Center Stage technology to keep you well-framed during video calls, a 12 MP rear camera with flash for better photos, and 4K video recording. It also has Touch ID on the top button and a long-lasting battery, so it’s always ready when you need to use it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/">You can purchase the Apple iPad 11-inch (A16) at Amazon right now for only $300, instead of the regular price of $349; that is a savings of $49 and 14% off.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>One of Apple’s best tablets in an affordable size and form factor</h2>
<p>This iPad has an A16 processor, designed to give users a fast app-opening experience, whether they are moving between programs like Safari, Messages, or games and creative apps. iPadOS allows users to run multiple apps simultaneously in a layout of their choice, for example, playing a video while keeping notes and a browser open. Because this iPad comes with 128 GB of internal storage, the user can download and store a variety of apps and files without needing to delete any items.</p>
<p>The 11-inch Liquid Retina display is large and very sharp, making it great for viewing movies, photos, and text clearly at arm’s length. Its brightness adapts automatically to ambient light, helping you see what you are doing more clearly. This screen is large enough to support split-screen work, but small enough to hold comfortably when you’re just scrolling through the internet or checking out your favorite TV show.</p>



<p>The front-facing 12 MP landscape Center Stage camera on the iPad will keep you centered on the screen during video calls, even as you move around. The back of the iPad features a 12 MP wide-angle lens camera and a flash, letting you shoot both 4K video and photographs, including scanning receipts, taking pictures of homework assignments, and capturing clear images of important documents. It also has two built-in microphones and dual speakers for voice clarity.</p>
<p>For those who would like to turn their iPad into a digital notebook or sketch pad, they can use the Apple Pencil to create handwritten notes, draw ideas, and edit PDFs on the iPad’s glass surface. Then, with just a couple of taps, you can send the documents you’ve created to others via email or messaging apps. You can also add a Magic Keyboard Folio to your iPad, which converts it into a lightweight laptop when you need to do some extended typing.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/">This iPad offers a lot of capabilities at an affordable $300, $49 less than the original retail price of $349.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-ipad-a16-chip-all-time-low-deal-quietly-makes-a-comeback-no-need-to-look-for-budget-tablets-2000659253]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Epic Games Store Can’t Beat Steam But It Might Become The Next Discord]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/epic-games-store-free-fortnite-discord-steam-2000665313</link>
            <guid>1425496</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p>The Epic Games Store might still feel to some like just a glorified <em>Fortnite</em> launcher. It was until recently the only way to play Epic’s hit battle royale on PC and that’s certainly what many of the people downloading the client use it for. But there’s a growing contingent of players that use it for playing other PC games as well. In fact, while total gameplay hours spent on the store fell a whopping 14 percent last year, total hours spent on non-Epic games was actually up 4 percent. This is one of the details Epic VP Steve Allison is focused on when I talk to him about the company’s new 2025 year-in-review report published this week.</p> <p>“Sixty percent of our audience are dual users,” he tells me. “They use Steam and the Epic Games Store. Forty percent don’t. But not all the 40 percent are <em>Fortnite</em> players. A lot of them are coming off of games like Riot’s games or <em>Minecraft</em> or <em>Roblox</em> or things like that. I’m actually always pretty surprised at how big that incremental group is. But for those dual players, there’s an interesting thing. In the totality of the story, what I can tell you is of the average monthly active users of 67 million, only about 26 percent of those players are <em>Fortnite</em> players. The rest are third-party.”</p>

 <p>It’s the end of the day. Allison, a 30-year industry veteran with stints at Atari, Midway, and Telltale, is clearly exhausted from briefing journalists all day about the pitch to make more people actually want to use the Epic Games Store. “The launcher sucks. Let’s call it what it is,” he <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-launcher-sucks-lets-call-it-what-it-is-epic-game-store-boss-says-promising-a-year-of-big-improvements-to-speed-new-forum-type-social-features-more">told <em>Eurogamer</em></a>. “We’re ripping the guts out” and replacing it with something better, he <a href="https://www.polygon.com/epic-games-store-egs-update-avatars-voice-chat/">told <em>Polygon</em></a>. “Our goal isn’t to dance on Steam’s grave,” he <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/our-goal-isnt-to-dance-on-top-of-steams-grave-how-epic-plans-to-convince-pc-gamers-to-buy-their-games-from-the-epic-games-store-instead-of-steam">told <em>IGN</em></a>. So what is the goal, exactly? And why is it taking so long to get there?</p> <h2>If Steam is Google, Epic feels like PC gaming’s Bing</h2> <p>Released back in 2018 with an announcement at the Game Awards, there was a brief groundswell of hype around how the<em> Fortnite</em> maker might offer a meaningful competitor to Steam’s dominance in the PC gaming marketplace. Valve’s storefront is an incredibly powerful engine for game discovery that can also be a cesspool <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-14/white-supremacist-nazi-content-spread-on-steam-gaming-platform">attracting some of the worst people on the internet</a>. Maybe Epic could curate the best of PC gaming without toxic dregs? But many years later it’s still missing key features and feels a bit like a massive but empty mall. There’s tons of vendors hawking their wares but no real sense of a community.</p>

 <p>2026 is supposed to be the year that changes, or at least starts to. Epic is promising sweeping overhauls to the underlying infrastructure of the store to make it load faster and run better. More ambitious are the “community spaces” it claims will spring up when it ships voice chat and parties that exist at the platform layer outside of within any particular game you’re playing. Other incoming features include avatars, player profiles, and private messaging. Yes, it’s taken Epic eight years to unlock these 2000s-era online gaming features.</p>

 <p>I asked Allison why. He blamed, in so many words, Epic’s five-year-long crusade to get Apple and Google’s mobile storefronts to allow competing storefronts and third-party payment processing. “The litigation gave us the opportunity to bring the mobile stores,” he said. “That was a part of the vision from jump, but we just couldn’t get to it. The minute we could get to it, we pivoted to it really hard. That’s the kind of company Epic is, it pivots hard and fast, and that came at the expense of getting some of those [features].”</p> <p>Mobile versions of the Epic Game Store came to iOS devices in the EU and Android devices everywhere last year, and the company’s long-term strategy is to make the launcher part of a connected network that exists beyond any single platform. A unified text chat system rolled out last year and a shared library of cross-platform games people can play on both mobile and PC is coming in the future. “It’s taken a while,” Allison, who’s been along for the entire ride, admitted. “It’s going to be on us to earn those players back by hopefully doing cool shit, and we’ll, we’ll get there, but I think we’re finally doing the work that’s expected of us, and hopefully we can make some of those players come around again.”</p>

 <h2>Staying exclusive while others go multiplatform</h2> <p>But even if the Epic Games Store can hypothetically match Steam feature-for-feature, or even exceed it, there’s still no guarantee it will be enough to overcome the entrenched networking effects and decades of player investment that give Valve’s storefront an advantage. Early on, Epic tried to coerce players to switch with a series of controversial timed exclusives, like <em>Borderlands 3</em>, that mostly just pissed people off and hurt sales. Allison confirmed that strategy is in the past and exclusives aren’t a priority moving forward.</p> <p>“There’s 20,000 releases a year on PC, we could pick wrong 1,000 times and end up with $0 so we needed to focus no matter,” he said. “I understand how people felt about it, but that was a purposeful strategy that really worked for the beginning of the store, but it has really moved on from that.” It doesn’t sound like that means Epic-published games like <em>Alan Wake 2</em> will ever be coming to Steam, however. Epic-funded games “will always be on the Epic Games Store as long as we have a publishing deal in place with our partners,” he said when I asked.</p> <p>Epic now relies mostly on carrots instead of sticks to lure over PC gamers. Its monthly free games <a href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-steam-epic-games-publishing-deal-tim-sweeney-2000662259">were recently dunked on</a> for reportedly helping to fuel sales for the Steam versions, but Epic isn’t shying away from that attention. Its year-in-review report openly boasts about the lift games get across multiple platforms when they are given away for free on the Epic Games Store. In 2025, the company gave away 100 different games that were claimed a total of 662 million times. It estimates the total value per player in claimed games was $2,316.</p>

 <p>It doesn’t sound like Epic plans to turn that money spigot off anytime soon. The free drinks, even for people who continue to spend most of their time on Steam, will continue. But is it having any effect? Allison <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/epic-says-only-16-to-18-percent-of-people-claiming-free-games-on-the-epic-games-store-buy-games-there-afterwards-but-for-cost-per-new-user-its-hard-to-beat/">told <em>Gamesradar</em></a> that less than 20 percent of users who collect the free games then go on to spend money buying others afterwards. That’s an expensive user acquisition strategy, though it certainly earns you a lot more positive PR than <a href="https://kotaku.com/monopoly-go-ad-budget-bigger-than-spider-man-last-of-us-1851350182">spending hundreds of millions to market clicker games on mobile</a>.</p> <h2>A CEO who tweets too much</h2> <p>One thing Epic isn’t rushing to copy from Valve, however, is its AI disclosure policy. Developers on Valve’s storefront are required to tell players when a game includes assets made with generative AI (LLMs for coding and other work doesn’t count). Epic CEO Tim Sweeney <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/epics-sweeney-says-platforms-should-stop-tagging-games-made-with-ai">recently made fun of these rules</a>, saying they “make no sense” when, he contends, all games will eventually use genAI in their production. “I don’t disagree with that,” Allison said. I understand how the discourse and conversation are going, but it’s it. I don’t want to say it’s a fool’s errand, but it’s a very, very difficult thing to accurately police.”</p>

 <p>He continued, “If they’re using it to fire people and all those kinds of things that people are worried about, that’s a terrible thing that we don’t endorse. But we don’t think that that’s how AI is going to be used in game development. We think that it’s going to help a lot of these smaller teams make awesome shit, like, like we haven’t seen from a six- or 10-man team, and we’re in a period of time where we’re starting to see the impact of the current situation in the industry on large teams. So we’re not going to require people to disclose it. It’s really up to the developer what they want to disclose.”</p> <p>Sweeney also took a swing at Steam after a class-action lawsuit in the UK over regional pricing <a href="https://kotaku.com/valve-class-action-lawsuit-steam-uk-ruling-2000663481">was allowed to move forward</a>. He called Steam’s 30-percent commission on game sales “<a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2017028895875195171">junk fees</a>,” likening them to the monopoly rent-seeking on iOS and Android that he spent years fighting Apple and Google over in court. But no PC gamer would liken Steam’s robust game discovery mechanisms to Apple’s poor stewardship of the App Store, and unlike on mobile, Steam is kicking the Epic Games Store’s ass without locking players out of competing stores on PC. If Valve is a business built on junk fees, it’s because players and developers have thus far been all too eager to pay them.</p> <p>It’s sometimes hard to know how much to distinguish Epic’s grand strategy from Sweeney’s own ideological crusades. Earlier this month, the CEO came to Elon Musk’s defense against, of all things, regulatory attempts to restrict <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/epic-games-ceo-tim-sweeney-argues-banning-twitter-over-its-ability-to-ai-generate-pornographic-images-of-minors-is-just-gatekeepers-attempting-to-censor-all-of-their-political-opponents/">AI-generated CSAM material from spreading on X</a>. He likened the creation of sexualized images of kids to AI “<a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2009753835456156088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2009753835456156088%7Ctwgr%5E314650d7dadff0c1aa9d6234049569646ffe2c5d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.pcgamer.com%2Fgaming-industry%2Fepic-games-ceo-tim-sweeney-argues-banning-twitter-over-its-ability-to-ai-generate-pornographic-images-of-minors-is-just-gatekeepers-attempting-to-censor-all-of-their-political-opponents%2F">going off the rails</a>” and noted that no AI tools are “perfect” while arguing against calls for the app’s removal from storefronts. He then <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/2010497254495342610?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2010497254495342610%7Ctwgr%5E623d893e2f1f48f01e6c25eb1e028e6a67d652f4%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thegamer.com%2Ftim-sweeney-grok-controversy%2F">got angry at websites for quoting him</a>. In a follow-up email after our interview, I asked whether Allison agreed with that reasoning and whether it’s hard having a boss who tweets so much. He declined to comment.</p>

 <h2>A bigger slice of a growing PC gaming pie</h2> <p>The Epic Games Store’s ambitions for 2026 gesture at something much bigger than it’s ever been. One new pitch to developers is to compliment free game giveaways with more free in-game rewards for <em>Fortnite</em>. Buying <em>Crimson Desert</em>, the upcoming open-world action-adventure game, will get players exclusive cosmetics in the battle royale. The goal is to find new ways to leverage the success of the one to build up the latter. Those giveaways, the messaging integration, and the upcoming voice-chat parties feature <a href="https://kotaku.com/discord-sdk-nitro-ads-ipo-profitable-splitgate-2-1851770484">remind me a lot of Discord</a>. Epic’s goal might not be to topple Steam after all. It might be to leapfrog it by becoming the next gaming social media platform that also happens to sell some games.</p> <p>Allison says the company’s not thinking in zero-sum terms. PC and mobile gaming is growing while consoles plateau. His view is that these platforms can all grow together. “Our goal was to compete with Steam and if things worked out that PC gaming would grow as a result of having real competition.” He said he’s proud of how far the store has come since launch, when <em>Fortnite</em> had 8 million monthly active users and the store was at zero. Now the Epic Games Store’s 67 million users a month averages about half of where Steam is as at while each keeps growing.</p> <p>“They’re like 140 million, not sure exactly, because of how much bot traffic they have, but it’s still significant. It’s close to double, and we’re at that level,” Allison said. “So PC gaming has grown substantially since we’ve entered the market. We believe it’s because we’re competing. And, you know, we would be thrilled to be in a bigger pool of PC gaming that is much bigger than it was in 2018, which is where I think that’s going to continue to go. We’re starting to see console consumption behavior shift to PC and mobile. And so look, if Steam keeps growing and we keep growing, we’ll be super stoked, I will be happy. And our goals are really to get to be about 25, 30 percent of all PC gaming on the PC side of the business. And if we do, if you push past that, that’s awesome, but it’s like that will still be a multi-billion-dollar business in third party, and I think PC gaming will be better for it.”</p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/epic-games-store-free-fortnite-discord-steam-2000665313]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>