<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:21:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These 11 Super Bowl LIX Commercials Should Just Be TV Shows]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/harrison-ford-super-bowl-commerical-tv-shows-1851759100</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/these-11-super-bowl-lix-commercials-should-just-be-tv-shows.1104972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/harrison-ford-super-bowl-commerical-tv-shows-1851759100<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="439aaa6cf0b71909820439a0c976f917" data-recommend-id="image://439aaa6cf0b71909820439a0c976f917" data-format="jpg" data-width="1733" data-height="975" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Bad Bunny (left), Aubrey Plaza (center), and Michael Shannon (right) enjoying RITZ crackers" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Bad Bunny (left), Aubrey Plaza (center), and Michael Shannon (right) enjoying RITZ crackers" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->RITZ</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="439aaa6cf0b71909820439a0c976f917" data-recommend-id="image://439aaa6cf0b71909820439a0c976f917" data-format="jpg" data-width="1733" data-height="975" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Bad Bunny (left), Aubrey Plaza (center), and Michael Shannon (right) enjoying RITZ crackers" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Super Bowl airtime doesn’t come cheap. In fact, this year companies <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/news/8-million-for-30-seconds-tracking-the-staggering-rise-of-super-bowl-ad-costs-110054057.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAJDGy5Po2CvrHcKG_LVkdLjYNrbNBx3gPbnfYiNpHmlNL1i3JbNHAqLgABhftWHcVkwCw7s-XJY-f_37FARIsgx9ug1NDSbtWWHdViIsh6-KFMtseaznIwZisqWy0_mZWJQdY6gduQ7_q6MekdQ0mlBXgXFUfHZej-ut0ZT_fp0G&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/8-million-for-30-seconds-tracking-the-staggering-rise-of-super-bowl-ad-costs-110054057.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAJDGy5Po2CvrHcKG_LVkdLjYNrbNBx3gPbnfYiNpHmlNL1i3JbNHAqLgABhftWHcVkwCw7s-XJY-f_37FARIsgx9ug1NDSbtWWHdViIsh6-KFMtseaznIwZisqWy0_mZWJQdY6gduQ7_q6MekdQ0mlBXgXFUfHZej-ut0ZT_fp0G" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spent $8 million</a></span> for 30 seconds of screen time at a Super Bowl most people will only remember for Kendrick Lamar’s unprecedented rap beef victory lap. There were commercials about Meg Ryan having orgasms at a restaurant with Billy Crystal (a la <em>When Harry Met Sally</em>), Gordon Ramsay and Pete Davidson hanging with alien cookware, and Post Malone drinking beer while acting like...Post Malone. My argument is: If brands are willing to spend an NFL player’s salary on a blink-and-you’ll-miss-it commercial, then why not fork over $40 million more and produce some high quality TV?</p><p>From Matthew McConaughey spouting “foodball”-related conspiracy theories to Michael Shannon and Aubrey Plaza being unimpressed by everything in life, here are the 11 Super Bowl LIX commercials that need to become TV shows.</p></div></div><div><p>You could put Glen Powell in a jet (<em>Top Gun: Maverick</em>), the path of a tornado (<em>Twisters</em>), or a lethal relationship (<em>Hit Man</em>), and he’s going to make you want to watch all of it. So, him donning a blonde wig as the most adrenaline-fueled version of Goldilocks ever in the Ram Trucks Super Bowl commercial was a thrill ride I didn’t want to end. What if he had a lighthearted but high-stakes anthology series where he’s a dad trying to connect with the children he has in the commercial by retelling classic children’s stories with him as the action hero? If he’s dodging dragons and riding over volcanoes as Goldilocks, you could easily fill 15 episodes of him saving Hansel and Gretel from that cannibalistic old witch with an AK-47, or dressing up as one of the three little pigs to interrogate the captured wolf in order to find out the location of his fellow wolves so they can exact revenge. CBS, put this show on after <em>Tracker</em>. </p></div><div><p>Michael Shannon and Aubrey Plaza are a match made in sarcastic heaven as they try to stop delicious RITZ crackers from breaking their veneer of perpetual dissatisfaction. While the concept gets a couple of chuckles for the ad’s 31 seconds, I’d love to see Plaza and Shannon in a TV series where they realize life is too short to hate everything, so they employ Bad Bunny to try to introduce them to things to make them happy, and despite his best efforts, he fails more often than he succeeds. Imagine Shannon and Plaza’s stone-faced reactions to skydiving, an ayahuasca retreat, and front row seats at a Bad Bunny concert. Cut the check, RITZ.</p></div><div><p>When Harrison Ford talks, I listen. This Jeep Super Bowl commercial was simply 120 seconds of Ford exuding enough captivating cool to be able to speak to America about understanding the cost of freedom like he’s our father. Honestly, that’s the show. Ford living on a farm, riding trucks, and looking directly into our souls every episode as he explains life lessons about the benefits of taking the road less traveled, why we pay taxes, and how to cook eggs when you only have a chicken and sunlight in the woods. Think of it like <em>Mr. Rogers’ Neighborhood</em> if it was in the <em>Yellowstone </em>universe.</p></div><div><p>Nostalgia is always in style, especially when it involves a sequel to one of the greatest romantic comedies of all time. This Super Bowl LIX commercial revisited <em>When Harry Met Sally</em>’s iconic scene in which Sally (Meg Ryan) proves to Harry (Billy Crystal) that men can’t tell when women are faking orgasms by imitating an orgasm so convincingly in a restaurant full of people that someone famously says, “I’ll have what she’s having.” The only difference is this time, it appears Hellmann’s mayonnaise is <em>actually </em>that pleasurable. The 1989 classic ends with the pair getting married. If, 36 years later, they’ve gotten to the point where some store-bought mayonnaise is the highlight of their night, there could be comedic gold in uncovering the ways this longtime couple tries to keep things spicy, even if it’s just arguing over condiments. </p></div><div><p>People often wonder what they would say or do if they ever met aliens. This HexClad commercial proposes the idea that Gordon Ramsay would be introduced to out-of-this-world cookware, some of which he’s already used. This could be a really limited series (I’m talking four episodes, tops) of Ramsay berating alien chefs who cook intergalactic meals he’s never heard of but can nevertheless judge because his taste is the best in the universe. Unfortunately, with Pete Davidson as the alien ambassador, something is surely going to blow up in Ramsay’s face. </p></div><div><p>A good mockumentary will always make for good TV. The Uber Eats commercial stars Matthew McConaughey as an executive revealing all the ways in which football is a “conspiracy to make us hungry.” Only, plot twist: it’s actually about McConaughey playing himself and pitching Greta Gerwig on a movie about this conspiracy. A movie with McConaughey acting as a zany version of himself, pursuing the making of this passion project and going to great lengths to break down this NFL conspiracy, could be a comedy hit. As ridiculous as some of the claims are (Football being played on Sundays because of ice cream sundaes?), it would be interesting to see what new and wacky coincidences they can come up with while using McConaughey’s hypnotic charm to make them seem somewhat real. Honestly, why else would the Green Bay Packers’ fanbase be known as Cheese Heads?</p></div><div><p> Post Malone and irreverent comedian Shane Gillis being drunk and disorderly troublemakers in a cul-de-sac is a funny enough premise for a Bud Light Super Bowl commerical and a <em>Workaholics</em>-style raunchy comedy. Can you imagine Post Malone day-drinking and playing acoustic versions of Kendrick Lamar’s “Not Like Us” while Peyton Manning, living next door, is trying to enjoy the silence of retirement? Add in Shane Gills teaching the neighborhood kids how to safely do a keg stand, and you’ve got three seasons of an HBO series. <br></p></div><div><p>I wouldn’t say Booking.com’s Muppet-filled Super Bowl LIX commercial was the best of the night, but it’s probably the most TV-series-ready of them all. The Muppets bouncing around the world trying to find the right vacation spot is cool for a 30-second commercial, but it really makes me want a <em>White Lotus</em>-style comedy. Kermit and Miss Piggy convincing the rest of the gang to spend their summer at an all-inclusive resort, only to find out there’s some shady activities happening right under their noses, is must-see TV. If <em>Bert and Ernie’s Great Adventures </em>can get 52 episodes, <em>The Muppets: White Lotus</em> can get at least enough for a summer. </p></div><div><p>Sure, Instacart gathered the mascots of some of the most popular consumer brands in the world to entice people watching the Super Bowl to get their groceries from them. What they unintentionally did was show us what a cross between <em>Toy Story</em> and <em>Night at the Museum</em> could look like. The same excitement you get from seeing how characters from disparate video game franchises might interact in a <em>Super Smash Bros.</em>-style duel can be achieved by seeing what happens when the Kool-Aid Man bursts through a wall and messes up a floor that Mr. Clean spent all day polishing. But, honestly, I just want to see people’s reactions when their groceries go on strike and move away. </p></div><div><p>Let’s be clear: Dunkin’s Super Bowl commerical is very stupid (borderline insultingly stupid). But then, that’s what makes the sight of Ben and Casey Affleck and Jeremy Strong doing battle with other coffee brands a car wreck of a commercial you don’t want to look away from. As a TV show, the Affleck brothers running multiple Dunkin’ locations while trying to ward off competitors has the same absurdist foundation that made <em>Eastbound and Down </em>irresistible. With guest appearances from Super Bowl-winning coach Bill Belichick, Druski, possibly Matt Damon, and a bunch of others joining the fight, this could be a great late-night binge for the stoner crowd. </p></div><div><p>Anything Walton Goggins does deserves to be on TV, even if it’s just him breaking the fourth wall for a GoDaddy commerical. But, while the man who made a relatable antihero out of a human mutated by radiation in <em>Fallout </em>spends the ad joking about how actors rarely know anything about the professions they pretend to do, I wouldn’t mind a TV show that puts him in an alternate reality where there’s no difference between who you are on TV and who you are in your normal life. People would run up to him to help them stop bank robbers because he played a cop on <em>The Shield</em>, only for those same bank robbers to ask him for help since he also played a thief in <em>Justified</em>. There could be some sentimental overarching message about him having the potential to be anything, or some societal critique on our obsession with stars. Either way, I need Apple TV and the <em>Severance</em> creators to get the scripts going for this one.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Gives Out Free PS Plus Days But Fails To Explain Mysterious PlayStation Network Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/psn-down-outage-why-free-ps-plus-gift-sony-ps5-1851759274</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-gives-out-free-ps-plus-days-but-fails-to-explain-mysterious-playstation-network-outage.1104945/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/psn-down-outage-why-free-ps-plus-gift-sony-ps5-1851759274<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-recommend-id="image://5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arrowhead Game Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-recommend-id="image://5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The PlayStation Network <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psn-playstation-network-login-servers-error-login-ps5-1851758731&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psn-playstation-network-login-servers-error-login-ps5-1851758731">has been back up and running</a></span> for a bit now, after a major outage took PlayStation 5 and PS4's online features offline for roughly 24 hours at the end of last week. To make up for the extended downtime, Sony is  offering every  paying PS Plus member a small but free extension of their existing subscription.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“We apologize for the inconvenience and thank the community for their patience,” Sony <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a></span> on X on February 9, the morning after PSN came back online. “All PlayStation Plus members will automatically receive an additional 5 days of service.” It appears this make-good should be added  directly to players’ accounts and push back their renewal dates by nearly a week. </p><p>It’s a nice little gesture but it still doesn’t address why PSN suffered one of the longest outages in the service’s history over the weekend. The pervasiveness of the problems, across multiple continents and PSN features like accounts and the PlayStation Store, seemed to point to some sort of significant malfunction.</p><h2 id="h320"><a id=""></a>Why was PSN down for 24 hours?</h2><p>Sony’s explanation for what happened is strangely brief and vague. “Network services have fully recovered from an operational issue,” the company <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a></span> on February 9. There was no further detail about what that operational issue was or whether it might pop back up at some point.</p><p>Sony’s description of the issues prior to solving them was similarly limited. “We are aware some users might be currently experiencing issues with PSN,” is all the company wrote for the 24 hours that PSN was down, as thousands of players <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psn-down-playstation-network-outage-reactions-ps5-1851758856&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psn-down-playstation-network-outage-reactions-ps5-1851758856">aired their frustrations and demanded more information</a></span> across social media and Reddit. Imagine Netflix being down for an entire day with an explanation that basically amounted to, “Well that was weird, but hey we’re back!”</p><p>Because the duration of the interrupted service recalled the infamous PSN outage of 2011 which arose from a malicious hack, some fans were worried that something similar might have happened this time as well, even taking the step of preemptively changing their PSN login information in case their accounts had been compromised. Fortunately, that doesn’t appear to have been the case this time around. Hopefully, the outage remains a blip and PlayStation Network service continues without future problems. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Bans Forced In-Game Ads From All Steam Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-adverts-ads-ban-free-to-play-1851759164</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-bans-forced-in-game-ads-from-all-steam-titles.1104816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-adverts-ads-ban-free-to-play-1851759164<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you, like most people on Earth, are a frequent mobile gamer, you’ll be all too aware of the bane of in-game ads. Because the freemium model proves by far the most successful way to release games on telephones, you pay by sitting through agonizing ads with fake countdown timers, “X” buttons that don’t close anything, and faux interactivity designed to trick you into tapping through to the store. Valve has now made it abundantly clear that anything like this on its PC store means an instant ban.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194341" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: March 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="219" data-playlist="194341,194651,196447" data-current="194341"><div><p>The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: March 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19799.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>As <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spotted by <em>GamingOnLinux</em></a></span>, Valve’s encyclopedic Steamworks Documentation has been updated to make it much more clear that it refuses to sell any game that relies on in-game advertising for its business model. That means no games can require players to watch ads to be able to play, nor hide any elements of a game behind a commercial. And it goes further, banning the use of viewing ads to gain in-game advantages, rewards, or time.</p><p>“Developers should not utilize paid advertising as a business model in their game,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">say Valve’s instructions</a></span>, “such as requiring players to watch or otherwise engage with advertising in order to play, or gating gameplay behind advertising. If your game’s business model relies on advertising on other platforms, you will need to remove those elements before shipping on Steam.” The company suggests switching to an up-front payment, or keeping the game “free” but keeping upgrades as paid DLC. The rules then say,</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>Developers should not use advertising as a way to provide value to players, such as giving players a reward for watching or engaging with advertising in their game.</p></blockquote><p>For people who never play games on mobile, these might seem quite bizarre things to need to rule out: while video games have, for decades, included in-game ads (or even <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qy8iuOFtHdI&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qy8iuOFtHdI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">existed to <em>be </em>advertising</a></span>), gatekeeping actual play behind commercials has only been a very occasional, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nba-2k-just-keeps-putting-unskippable-ads-in-a-60-vide-1845443416&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nba-2k-just-keeps-putting-unskippable-ads-in-a-60-vide-1845443416">very egregious matter</a></span>. On mobile, it’s the norm.</p><p>If you’ve played a match-3, or a merger game, or any number of mock-RTS games, you’ll be very familiar with the requirement to sit through 30 seconds of a puzzle game being played infuriatingly badly, or a flashing icon begging you to tap on an army unit, or the most extraordinarily high-quality CG animation promoting a game that plays like it was made on a VIC-20. A tiny circle counts down from 30 seconds, after which the advert doesn’t end, and then it cuts to a new screen with a new timer, replaced by an X so tiny that if you don’t tap it with a tungsten needle it’ll take you to the store page. After all that, you’ve now got enough imaginary energy to take two more turns at the game you wish you were allowed to enjoy.</p><p>While maddening, this is extraordinarily profitable, and though you and I might scream into the void that we just want to pay $5 to own the game outright, the moment you put a price on an unknown mobile game, it’s doomed to obscurity. And while Steam may not have been plagued by the same issues, it makes a lot of sense for Valve to make these rules clear for those hoping to just port their game and business model over to PC, wholesale.</p><p>If anything, it’s very surprising that this isn’t already a fire that needs putting out, rather than something that can be addressed through some preventative measures like these. The mobile market proves that are squillions of people who are content to sit through countless ads to play games, so you’d think there would have already been a bigger push to see if the same could happen with PC’s free-to-play audiences. Small mercies, I guess.</p><p>Valve makes clear companies <em>can</em> still advertise in games. Those awkward billboards and real-world brand cosmetics are still fine to include, although Steam does stipulate that these must not be “disruptive” and that they be “appropriate within the context of the game.”</p><p>It’s worth noting this does also block previous gross behavior we’ve seen from the biggest names, the likes of 2K, filling basketball games with unskippable ads and so on.</p><p><strong>Updated: 10/02/2025, 10:13 a.m. ET:</strong> The wording of the post has been slightly adjusted to make clear this was already a rule, but made much more prominent in a new update.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>