<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:23:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gorillaz Just Revived Their 26-Year-Old Flash Game Site And It’s Wonderful]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gorillaz-revive-26-year-old-flash-game-site-kong-studios-2000624770</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gorillaz-just-revived-their-26-year-old-flash-game-site-and-it%E2%80%99s-wonderful.1294071/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Well, here’s something unexpected: Kong Studios is back. The OG <a href="https://kotaku.com/gorillaz-fornite-festival-leaks-forza-horizon-japan-xbox-sony-evo-analogue-2000619149">Gorillaz</a> Flash-powered site from the late ’90s was a popular destination for fans and features mini-games, music, and more. And now you can return to an updated and modern version of Kong Studios.</p> <p>Kong Studios first launched in 1998 and was the coolest place for fans of the fictional animated band. I should know, I used to visit it many, many years ago and struggled to use it on my dial-up connection. <a href="https://kotaku.com/over-36-000-flash-games-have-been-saved-and-are-now-pla-1841389493">The site was powered by Flash (RIP</a>), and over the years following its launch, it grew bigger and bigger, adding more content to find, virtual rooms to explore, songs to jam out to, and lots of fun Easter eggs for fans. Then in 2008, after a decade of support, the site was closed and forgotten. However, that all changed today as Kong Studios is operational once more.</p>  <p>On September 10, <a href="https://kongstudios.gorillaz.com/">Gorillaz released a new updated version of Kong Studios</a> that features a <em>Doom</em>-like first-person shooter experience where players have to fight off the zombie apes as seen in the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1V_xRb0x9aw">band’s video for “Clint Eastwood.”</a> You can skip that and just enter Kong Studios directly, and if you do, you’ll find a much higher-res version of the nostalgic site. There’s plenty to click on and explore in the lobby of the place, and Gorillaz promise that more rooms and content will be added to Kong Studios in the future.</p>

 <p>“Kong Studios is the home of Gorillaz and a gamified fan experience where you can explore the rooms and spaces of 2D, Murdoc, Noodle and Russel,” explained Gorillaz on the site’s <a href="https://gorillaz.com/Kongstudiosfaqs/">FAQ page</a>. “It’s also a place to go to find out everything you want to know about Gorillaz, first.”</p> <p>I’m very happy to see Kong Studios return, and not just because I’m a big Gorillaz fan. Over the last decade or so, we’ve seen more and more of the internet and the culture around it move from distinct places to large social media networks and apps. <a href="https://kotaku.com/please-stop-closing-forums-and-moving-people-to-discord-1847684851">Forums are closing. Fan sites are dying</a>. Instead, everyone and every brand is just using Facebook, Instagram, Discord, and TikTok to interact with fans and other people. And while that’s fine, it isn’t as cool as the old internet, where every band and person had their own site. Or where forums were controlled directly by the companies or groups themselves.</p>

 <p>The old internet was a weirder, wackier, and often more interesting era that I miss. While Kong Studios won’t bring that back by itself, it’s great to see a band as popular as Gorillaz realize that having your own place on the web might be valuable in 2025 as apps and networks get stuffed more and more with AI and bots.</p> <p>Anyway, here’s a walkthrough of the old Kong Studios so you can see what they took from us.</p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gorillaz-revive-26-year-old-flash-game-site-kong-studios-2000624770]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s The Perfect Time To Play Assassin’s Creed Shadows]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/its-the-perfect-time-to-play-assassins-creed-shadows-2000624758</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-the-perfect-time-to-play-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows.1294032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-rpg-1851770647"><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a> launched back in May to positive reviews from fans and critics. But like with most Ubisoft games, <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-free-updates-assassins-creed-shadows-road-map-1851778558"><em>Shadows</em> has continued to be updated over time</a>. And tomorrow’s big 1.1.1 update is its biggest yet, making it the best time to return to the game’s gorgeous digital recreation of Japan.</p> <p><a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/62imkAfEdpZSadOqfktQHv">On September 10, Ubisoft released the full patch notes for <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> update 1.1.1</a>, which is arriving on all platforms on Thursday. This is a massive update. The big star of this new patch is that it adds support for the game’s first major DLC expansion: <em>Claws of Awaji</em>. This DLC is launching on September 16 and will be available to anyone who pre-ordered <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-graphics-seasons-screenshots-1851770252">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a></em> ahead of its launch earlier this year. It will also be sold separately. The upcoming expansion adds a whole new region to the already massive in-game world of <em>Shadows</em>, as well as around 10 hours of story content, missions, and activities.</p> <p><em>Claws of Awaji</em> adds a new weapon type for Naoe, one of the game’s two playable characters, to use: The fast and hard-hitting bo staff. But you don’t need to buy the DLC to get this new weapon. Ubisoft has changed plans and announced on Wednesday that all players will get access to a bo staff after completing a new free quest being added in update 1.1.1.</p>

 <p>“Originally developed exclusively for the <em>Claws of Awaji</em> expansion, we thought this weapon was way too cool not to share with everyone… for FREE,” explained Ubisoft in the patch notes post for 1.1.1. “You get a Bo! And you! And you at the back! Everyone gets a Bo, coming September 16<sup>th</sup>.”</p> <p>Meanwhile, update 1.1.1 also adds a ton of free stuff that will be available on September 11. For starters, Ubisoft is increasing the level cap (again) and now you’ll be able to level up to 100, letting players get even more powerful. <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-shadows-no-animal-killing-zoo-1851781328">Your in-game hideout is also getting some new features and upgrades</a>. Here’s what Ubisoft had to say about the new hideout changes:</p> <blockquote><p>With the new update, each unique building now includes 2 additional upgrade levels, bringing a total of 20 new enhancements, alongside 3 new Hideout levels. These upgrades introduce valuable bonuses that accelerate Hideout growth, improve crafting capability by making Gold more accessible, and directly enhance Naoe, Yasuke, and their allies, making them more effective in both combat and exploration.</p></blockquote> <p><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> will also get two new gear levels: Mythic and Artifact. Ubisoft makes it sound like upgrading weapons and armor to these new levels will take some time, and that it’s mainly an option for players who are playing on new game+ and need extra help against the tougher enemies. Here are the full patch notes from Ubisoft, which are very long but include details on a lot of other neat changes, fixes, upgrades, and tweaks.</p>  <h2 id="QURESVRJT05BTCBISUdI">ADDITIONAL HIGHLIGHTS</h2> <h3 id="VW5jYXBwZWQgQ3V0c2Nl">Uncapped Cutscenes</h3> <p>Cutscenes are no longer limited to 30 FPS (PC Only).</p> <h2 id="TElTVCBPRiBCVUcgRklY">LIST OF BUG FIXES</h2> <h3 id="R2VuZXJhbMKg">General</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue where the game crashed during the cutscene of the “Chained” rift.</li> <li>Fixed various localization issues.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the vertical sliding sound effect continued if you switched characters during a slide.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where some tutorials repeated themselves after unlocking Yasuke.</li> </ul> <h3 id="R2FtZXBsYXnCoMKg">Gameplay</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue where the Naginata Ronin were not vulnerable after using the Vault ability.</li> <li>Addressed an issue where the Scale of the Koi and Soaring Tatsu trinkets were not functioning as expected.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the aiming reticle option “Only While Aiming” was missing from the settings.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a persistent “New Item” notification appeared after looting weapons from scout supply chests.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where players were unable to start horse archery in Iga because the quest giver had moved locations.</li> <li>Fixed an issue Ikko Ikki Kamon banner was missing after completing the “Collection of Crests” quest.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the Mount Nukai contract targeted a chest that was already opened.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where multiple waypoints were not synchronizing.</li> </ul> <h3 id="RGlmZmljdWx0eSBPcHRp">Difficulty Options</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue on Nightmare difficulty where Teppo enemies appeared broken.</li> <li>Fixed an issue on Nightmare difficulty where the Samurai Spear Guard had a combat glitch.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where Canon Mode disabled itself on the second launch of the game.</li> </ul> <h3 id="SGlkZW91dMKg">Hideout</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue in the Hideout when selecting the option to duel with Naoe or Yasuke did nothing.</li> <li>Fixed an issue in the Hideout where certain buildings or set pieces could not be rotated.</li> <li>Fixed an issue in the Hideout that prevented players from moving the horse stables after changing their original location.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where Rufino remained stuck in the Hideout after being recruited.</li> </ul> <h3 id="U2tpbGxzLCBBYmlsaXRp">Skills, Abilities &amp; Upgrades</h3> <ul> <li>Addressed an issue where the Shadow Piercer ability was not functioning correctly.</li> <li>Addressed an issue where the 33% health recovery on posture attack perk was not functioning as expected.</li> </ul> <h3 id="VmlzdWFscyAmIEdyYXBo">Visuals &amp; Graphics</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed various visual issues.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue with the architect’s lip sync in the “Seta-Killers” quest.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue affecting Yasuke’s aim with the Teppo when wearing variations of the Samurai Hat.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue with the Ronin Kasa Hat.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue with the Blush of the Earth bow quiver.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue with Oni’s Flesh Armour.</li> <li>Fixed a visual issue where Gashadokuro’s mask did not have red eyes on the Memories screen.</li> </ul> <h2 id="U1BPSUxFUlMgV0FSTklO"><em>—SPOILERS WARNING! —</em></h2> <h3 id="UXVlc3RzwqDCoA==">Quests</h3> <ul> <li><strong>“A Critical Encounter”</strong>: Fixed an issue where players could not interact with Rufino to trigger the quest.</li> <li><strong>“Broken Horn”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where players could not progress due to being stuck by the Animus wall.</li> <li><strong>“Face the Oshiroi Baba”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where Yokai objective member rewards were not being granted correctly.</li> <li><strong>“Feast For Thought”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where requirements were automatically completed for the quest.</li> <li><strong>“Man Behind the Curtain”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where after Ermigo died, Gaspar was incorrectly shown as dead.</li> <li><strong>“My Name Is Yasuke”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where players could not progress due to being stuck outside the Animus wall.</li> <li><strong>“Of My Enemy”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where Hiromichi’s man stopped moving if the player entered combat while following him.</li> <li><strong>“Out of the Shadows”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where the game crashed after the cutscene.</li> <li><strong>“Silver Smugglers”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where Yoshisada could be assassinated early before the quest.</li> <li><strong>“Tea Bowls for Rikyu”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue in the Hideout where tea bowls could no longer be placed after completing the quest.</li> <li><strong>“The Tournament”:</strong>&nbsp;Fixed an issue where players could not interact with Gyoji despite a blue marker being shown.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where players were unable to talk to Katsuhime in the crop field when she was sitting on the ground.</li> </ul> <h2 id="UExBVEZPUk0tU1BFQ0lG">PLATFORM-SPECIFIC FIXES</h2> <h3 id="UEPCoA==">PC</h3> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue where the heavy attack (LMB+Shift) was not functioning correctly on keyboard and mouse.</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/its-the-perfect-time-to-play-assassins-creed-shadows-2000624758]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>