<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:53:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic Fans Waited Over A Year For This Crummy Shadow Generations Collector’s Edition, And They Want Their Money Back]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-shadow-generations-limited-run-games-edition-2000655411</link>
            <guid>1391137</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>fans had to wait over a year for their Limited Run Games special edition of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-review-levels-powers-1851676560"><i><span>Sonic X Shadow Generations</span></i></a><span>. The remaster/excellent pack-in game launched in October of 2024, but with multiple shipment delays, it took 14 months between launch day and the special edition’s arrival on fans’ doorsteps. Was it worth the wait? Absolutely not.</span></p> <p><span>Several fans are reporting that the package’s Sonic and Shadow statues are showing up with various defects. Some have scratches, others have misprinted eyes, and one poor soul’s Shadow arrived with his nose broken off. The special edition cost $249.99 before taxes and shipping, and after a year-long wait, I would also be livid if this is what showed up in the mail.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I’m never ordering from limited run games ever again…. Almost 2 years for this?? Where is bro’s nose?!?!? 😭😭😭<a href="https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@LimitedRunGames</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicXShadowGenerations?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SonicXShadowGenerations</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicTheHedgehog?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SonicTheHedgehog</a> <a href="https://t.co/Z9yxMBbht7">pic.twitter.com/Z9yxMBbht7</a></p> <p>— Austin (@Atolan_805) <a href="https://twitter.com/Atolan_805/status/2002640145514967054?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 21, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">finally got my SXSG shipment from <a href="https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@LimitedRunGames</a>  … $200… yall 🫩<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicXShadowGenerations?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SonicXShadowGenerations</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicTheHedgehog?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SonicTheHedgehog</a> <a href="https://t.co/H0TNuegWH5">pic.twitter.com/H0TNuegWH5</a></p> <p>— nikki ☆ (@ottisopse) <a href="https://twitter.com/ottisopse/status/2002076010209292729?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Got my Sonic &amp; Shadow Statue from <a href="https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@LimitedRunGames</a> 🫠<br>Shadow in the next post 😐<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicXShadowGenerations?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SonicXShadowGenerations</a> <a href="https://t.co/dOaw0XALyL">pic.twitter.com/dOaw0XALyL</a></p> <p>— Xion_KingdomHearts (@XionKingdomHea1) <a href="https://twitter.com/XionKingdomHea1/status/2003222871351656747?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Shadows nose is literally melting off his face, im crying 😂😭 <a href="https://t.co/53k45Edhk2">https://t.co/53k45Edhk2</a></p> <p>— F-Sonic (@fsonic3) <a href="https://twitter.com/fsonic3/status/2003232402030887321?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">TWO HUNDRED DOLLARS… <a href="https://t.co/55le3QTBfc">https://t.co/55le3QTBfc</a> <a href="https://t.co/wuHQL4Ik8f">pic.twitter.com/wuHQL4Ik8f</a></p> <p>— Jam – Queen of Goop~ 👑 ENVtuber (@JLDrawz) <a href="https://twitter.com/JLDrawz/status/2001773474008711672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>At the moment, Limited Run Games hasn’t responded to fans’ requests for answers about how these damaged and defective statues came to be, and some are even claiming the company has </span><a href="https://x.com/ottisopse/status/2002129958567882815?s=20"><span>untagged itself from posts</span></a><span> about the issue. We’ve reached out to Limited Run for comment on the situation and will update the story if we hear back.</span></p>

 <p><span>At any rate, I hope those of you who got shitty collector’s editions at least enjoyed the game. </span><i><span>Shadow Generations </span></i><span>is probably the best </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>game in years, and it deserved a better statue. Thankfully, there were other editions that were of much higher quality that are </span><a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/267040143965"><span>selling for cheaper than Limited Run’s</span></a><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>Limited Run is in hot water with </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>fans, but the company probably has bigger problems right now, given it is now the </span><a href="https://www.limitedrungamessettlement.com/"><span>subject of a lawsuit</span></a><span> for allegedly violating the Video Privacy Protection Act and selling user data to Facebook owner Meta.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonic-shadow-generations-limited-run-games-edition-2000655411]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Washed-Up Pro Gamer Goes Viral For Griefing In Arc Raiders: ‘You Want Optional PvP Go Play WoW‘]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvp-griefing-twitch-thump-2000655362</link>
            <guid>1391098</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A player looks out at two enormous spiderbots in the sea.</span> © Embark Studios / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The PvP nature of multiplayer extraction shooter <em>Arc Raiders</em> has been contentious since the game’s launch. There are many who see the ability to kill and be killed by other players are vital for the game’s tension and enjoyment. There are others who argue it’s antithetical to the conventions of a game in which a scant, brave few are trying to bring back resources to those living underground. Either way, <em>Arc Raiders</em> players have reached a fascinating and fragile understanding in which most people, most of the time, don’t kill. So when a retired pro gamer shows up and just starts slaughtering everything, it’s…well, it’s just rude!</p> <p>As&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-just-started-i-have-nothing-retired-pro-gamer-goes-viral-for-relentlessly-killing-casual-arc-raiders-players-but-is-it-griefing-or-just-fair-pvp"><em>IGN</em> reports</a>, Taylor “THump” Humphries—a former pro at games like&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends</em>,&nbsp;<em>Rocket Arena</em>, and&nbsp;<em>H1Z1</em>—has decided to spend his spare time taking out as many “casual” players as he can in Embark’s breakout hit game. On recent Twitch streams, THump has been broadcasting himself <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thump/clip/ThoughtfulGracefulRhinocerosPunchTrees-6vUn_UhjhRo_L3KC">griefing in&nbsp;<em>Arc Raiders</em></a> for, seemingly, his lone amusement. His most recent stream, a grueling 13 hours long, is primarily the guy killing other players in a game in which most people opt to be peaceful.</p>

  <div> <p><span>Now, let me stress, he’s doing nothing </span><em>wrong</em><span>.&nbsp;</span><em>Arc Raiders</em><span> has PvP for a really good reason: it makes it a thousand times more tense to play. Were it only PvE (and honestly, all the wrong parts of me dearly wishes it were), then every interaction with another player would become banal, lacking the terrifying hope for uneasy, fleeting alliances that make it so exciting. Every time a player deliberately kills you, it feels like wanton betrayal, though it’s clearly well within the rules.</span></p> </div> <p>The issue with THump’s murderstreams is that the entire exercise is the video game equivalent of shitposting. His commentary is incessant irony, with him laughing as he makes other people sad. And, I dunno, I’m too old and tired to find that shit funny. Somehow this is proving entertaining enough to the streamer that he’s doing it night after night of late, most recently delighting in lobbing grenades.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Logging in with a full inventory of trigger nades and killing everyone trying to get re-looted after the expedition is a joy. Trigger nades do NOT need a nerf! Live<a href="https://t.co/hiY3uPb3e7">https://t.co/hiY3uPb3e7</a> <a href="https://t.co/DuaFRCGlUi">pic.twitter.com/DuaFRCGlUi</a></p> <p>— THUMP (@THump) <a href="https://twitter.com/THump/status/2003213487397568807?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>A few days back, it was <a href="https://x.com/THump/status/2001729907760730180">this post on X</a> that really riled people up, as THump dropped a clip of his killing a party of four at the very start of a run, when they didn’t even have any loot to steal. “We just started, I have nothing,” said the first person he killed. “What scum man,” they added after the second kill.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I love killing grown men that have jobs and children as they are trying to get 5 million credits for the expedition. Killing all teamers in solos, live now.<a href="https://t.co/hiY3uPb3e7">https://t.co/hiY3uPb3e7</a> <a href="https://t.co/ncHTgNMT1x">pic.twitter.com/ncHTgNMT1x</a></p> <p>— THUMP (@THump) <a href="https://twitter.com/THump/status/2001729907760730180?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Given THump’s a troll, his responses to those objecting—<a href="https://x.com/THump/status/2002365789475660245">such as</a> “I come from a place where PvP is not optional…<span>it’s a way of life. You want optional PvP go play <em>WoW</em></span>“—are obviously insincere. When one person calls him “another toxic streamer,” and suggests he’d have a better time helping other players rather than killing them, <a href="https://x.com/THump/status/2001832306106159267">he replies</a>, “Id rather ruin others time than have fun myself.”</p>

 <p>But, again, he’s not doing anything wrong. While THump’s repeated claims of innocence, that he’s just killing other players “in a PvP game,” are clearly disingenuous, there’s no arguing that <em>Arc Raiders</em> isn’t designed to facilitate it. Honestly, as much as seeing someone do this for clout is embarrassing to watch, I take huge solace in knowing that his actions are something that stands out among players. I really rather love that this ostensibly PvP game has somehow engendered a player base that, 90 percent of the time, opts not to kill, even when there’s personal gain in doing so. In 2025, that feels like a beacon of hope, and a douche like THump exploiting it only highlights how valuable it is.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvp-griefing-twitch-thump-2000655362]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The People Yearn For Gay Hockey Romance As Heated Rivalry Ties Top-Rated Episode Of All Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/heated-rivalry-show-episodes-book-gq-ratings-2000655368</link>
            <guid>1391062</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I have already spread the gospel of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/heated-rivalry-show-book-watch-cast-hockey-2000649249"><i><span>Heated Rivalry</span></i><span>,</span></a><span> the gay hockey romance TV series bestowed upon us by our yaoi-loving neighbors in the north (Canada). But now, weeks later, many more worshippers have heard the word of our gay Lord.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>According to </span><a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/heated-rivalry-hbo-biggest-tv-show-surprise-hit-1236614905/"><i><span>Variety</span></i></a><span>, </span><i><span>Heated Rivalry</span></i><span> is the most-watched original series ever on Canada’s Bell Media Crave streaming service. In the United States, it’s the top-rated non-animated series HBO Max has acquired since its launch in 2020, and amongst the top five of all scripted debuts on the streaming service this year.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>The breakout TV series is spreading like flash frost across the nation. There’s an </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/search?q=heated%20rivalry&amp;t=1766503148249"><span>entire TikTok cottage industry</span></a><span> dedicated to the show (I bought my sister a shirt through it). The gay bar I occasionally work at won’t stop playing </span><a href="https://www.billboard.com/culture/tv-film/heated-rivalry-episode-four-music-all-things-she-said-tatu-1236141882/"><span>“All The Things She Said”</span></a><span> over the speakers. They’re playing</span> <a href="https://x.com/MTLHeartsHabs/status/2000368255580492236/photo/1"><span>scenes on the Jumbotron at hockey games</span></a><span>, they’re doing </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QMCkwlxjon4"><span>flirty Teen Vogue videos</span></a><span>, they’ve got </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@francisdominiic/video/7585807672772021517?q=francisdominiic&amp;t=1766502213450"><span>packed WeHo sports bars screaming</span></a><span> over the most recent episode.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>That episode, titled “I’ll Believe in Anything,” is currently rated as the second-best episode of television ever by </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/search/title/?title_type=tv_episode&amp;num_votes=1000,&amp;sort=user_rating,desc"><span>IMDB users</span></a><span>, topped (teehee) only by </span><i><span>Breaking Bad</span></i><span>’s “Ozymandias.” Both episodes have a perfect 10-star score, but&nbsp;<em>Heated Rivalry</em>‘s up there with just 31,000 votes compared to <em>Breaking Bad</em>‘s 273,000.<br> </span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="tl" dir="ltr">Consent king Ilya <a href="https://t.co/Id5o8egZJ3">pic.twitter.com/Id5o8egZJ3</a></p> <p>— Empty Netters (@EmptyNettersPod) <a href="https://twitter.com/EmptyNettersPod/status/2002540741638169030?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 21, 2025</a></p></blockquote>   <p><span>Though both showrunner Jacob Tierney (</span><i><span>Letterkenny</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Shoresy</span></i><span>) and newcomer stars Connor Storrie and Hudson Williams are shocked by </span><i><span>Heated Rivalry</span></i><span> becoming one of the year’s biggest shows, there is something especially stunning about how the world of hockey has welcomed it. There are </span><a href="https://x.com/EmptyNettersPod/status/2002540741638169030"><span>straight dudes with hockey podcasts watching a gay show with earnestness and excitement</span></a><span>—not judgment.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The NHL, a league infamous for its players <a href="https://www.outsports.com/2025/6/4/24112574/nhl-gay-slur-suspensions-playoffs-fine/">hurling homophobic slurs</a> and <a href="https://www.espn.com/nhl/story/_/id/35927172/brothers-eric-marc-staal-decline-wear-panthers-pride-night-jerseys">refusing to take part in Pride nights</a>, is embracing the newfound attention the sport has gotten thanks to </span><i><span>Heated Rivalry</span></i><span> (hockey has struggled to gain a consistent viewership foothold in the States). </span><span>“There are so many ways to get hooked on hockey and, in the NHL’s 108-year history, this might be the most unique driver for creating new fans. See you all at the rink,” a league spokesperson told </span><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-features/heated-rivalry-hbo-max-gay-drama-hockey-players-hit-women-1236456083/?taid=69496b144a2c5800015805d3&amp;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter"><i><span>The Hollywood Reporter</span></i></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>If you have a young woman or a gay man in your family, expect to hear about this show during Christmas if you haven’t already. Especially because the season finale of </span><i><span>Heated Rivalry</span></i><span> airs on HBO Max at 12 a.m. ET on December 26.&nbsp;</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/heated-rivalry-show-episodes-book-gq-ratings-2000655368]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Video Game Industry Pays Tribute To Vince Zampella: ‘The Embodiment Of A Legend’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vince-zampella-death-car-crash-tributes-reactions-2000655379</link>
            <guid>1391059</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Yesterday, it was confirmed that Vince Zampella, the head of Respawn also known for his work as a lead developer on </span><i><span>Call of Duty </span></i><span>and</span><i><span> Battlefield</span></i><span>, was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/report-vince-zampella-battlefield-boss-and-call-of-duty-co-creator-killed-in-car-crash-2000655216"><span>killed in a car accident</span></a><span> on Sunday, December 21. Zampella had a storied career, co-founding Infinity Ward in 2002, which would go on to spend the next two decades creating </span><i><span>Call of Duty </span></i><span>games. After a messy breakup with Activision, he went on to found </span><i><span>Titanfall </span></i><span>developer Respawn Entertainment and was eventually made the lead of the </span><i><span>Battlefield </span></i><span>franchise in 2021.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">We are heartbroken by the loss of Vince Zampella, a creative leader whose work shaped generations of players and helped define what modern shooters and action games could be.</p> <p>Across a remarkable career, Vince played a foundational role in franchises including Call of Duty,… <a href="https://t.co/M2NgyJRWu2">pic.twitter.com/M2NgyJRWu2</a></p> <p>— Battlefield (@Battlefield) <a href="https://twitter.com/Battlefield/status/2003237892227789293?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>When you have a career that spans decades and helped launch some of the most influential shooters in the genre, you’re bound to touch the lives of many people in the video game industry. After news of Zampella’s death began to spread, fans and colleagues began flooding social media with tributes.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I cannot believe I am writing this.</p> <p>Vince Zampella, a titan of the video game industry, the co-creator of Call of Duty and co-founder of Respawn Entertainment, not to mention a dear friend, died in a car crash yesterday in Los Angeles. <a href="https://t.co/jW3bT88gsE">pic.twitter.com/jW3bT88gsE</a></p> <p>— Geoff Keighley (@geoffkeighley) <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffkeighley/status/2003192911765340568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I can’t believe this. It’s so tragic. I just saw him at TGA’s. I’ve known Vince for years, and traveled the world with him at Activision. He’s truly brilliant and such a nice person. This loss will be felt in our industry for years. <a href="https://t.co/77CPKAuCA0">pic.twitter.com/77CPKAuCA0</a></p> <p>— Tim Willits (@TimWillits) <a href="https://twitter.com/TimWillits/status/2003204652792443255?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:jye22xkea3jqsabskhfec347/app.bsky.feed.post/3mam6j4jhfc2i" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreigipdf6rn4wotiz2zq6r3mzeebnvaialutufv3o4pfau32ssrih2i"> <p lang="en">No matter where and what he was up to, Vince would always find half an hour to catch up on life &amp; work at every event. It never seemed to matter to him that I make arcade games &amp; help indies out, while he was in charge of some of the most impactful games ever. Giving a shit was what mattered to him.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:jye22xkea3jqsabskhfec347?ref_src=embed">Rami Ismail (رامي) (@ramiismail.com)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:jye22xkea3jqsabskhfec347/post/3mam6j4jhfc2i?ref_src=embed">2025-12-22T21:29:10.386Z</a></p></blockquote></div>    <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:un3uyqbcgtthozfmqhrzmjrs/app.bsky.feed.post/3mamc2wjpfs2t" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreihlvypxux6depke7qky7qqdlpsreda7bojtplbxtba7blcn6kmvii"> <p lang="en">I first got to know Vince in 2013/2014 when he was on the road showing off titanfall and we were showing Dance Central or Fantasia or something. Had no reason to be kind or pay me any attention but was always thoughtful and kind despite shouldering a(mother) huge franchise.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:un3uyqbcgtthozfmqhrzmjrs?ref_src=embed">John Drake (@johndrake.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:un3uyqbcgtthozfmqhrzmjrs/post/3mamc2wjpfs2t?ref_src=embed">2025-12-22T22:32:49.305Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Vince was awesome. A real one – chill, but with a strong will and powerful heart. We have been friends for a long time and he and my wife Kristy were very close – confidants and allies. He leaves behind great children and many who love and respect him. When we were respectful…</p> <p>— Randy Pitchford (@DuvalMagic) <a href="https://twitter.com/DuvalMagic/status/2003194764586598408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Vince Zampella was not just an amazing game creator. He was also a friend. </p> <p>In absolute shock right now. Rest in peace to an absolute legend and giant of our industry. <a href="https://t.co/acqJxlD1u1">pic.twitter.com/acqJxlD1u1</a></p> <p>— JP Kellams (@synaesthesiajp) <a href="https://twitter.com/synaesthesiajp/status/2003191500679893207?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sometimes people throw around terms like "industry legend" to describe famous game developers, but Vince Zampella was genuinely legendary. </p> <p>Most people have no idea how influential the man was. Director on Medal of Honor: Allied Assault. Co-creator of Call of Duty. Then he… <a href="https://t.co/9UACRlcWre">https://t.co/9UACRlcWre</a></p> <p>— Ryan K. Rigney (@RKRigney) <a href="https://twitter.com/RKRigney/status/2003200822532841737?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Devastating and beyond heartbroken for the family of Vince Zampella. His path and impact on the industry are how I got my start and I will deeply mourn his loss. <a href="https://t.co/p6sKhQyH6E">https://t.co/p6sKhQyH6E</a></p> <p>— rebb ford (@rebbford) <a href="https://twitter.com/rebbford/status/2003202751522832416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I'm deeply saddened by the loss of Vince Zampella, a friend and a force in our industry. Vince helped shape modern gaming and inspired so many of us along the way. </p> <p>My thoughts are with his family, friends, and everyone who had the privilege of knowing him.</p> <p>-Patrick Söderlund</p> <p>— Embark Studios (@EmbarkStudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/EmbarkStudios/status/2003473809538687221?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Absolutely heartbroken.</p> <p>Vince Zampella created and lead so much incredible entertainment and innovation in games over his legendary life.</p> <p>My tears and condolences to his dear family, his friends, and his colleagues.</p> <p>So grateful I got to see him last week. So grateful for the…</p> <p>— Donald Mustard (@DonaldMustard) <a href="https://twitter.com/DonaldMustard/status/2003205841495720024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>    <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fuck, where to even begin when it comes to Vince Zampella. </p> <p>While most knew him as the co-creator of Call of Duty and head of Respawn, I had the great fortune of also witnessing his particular brand of leadership, which often included standing up for what he believed in over… <a href="https://t.co/7C3dnPG2pq">https://t.co/7C3dnPG2pq</a></p> <p>— Alex Frostwolf🌙 (@alex_frostwolf) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex_frostwolf/status/2003222453066039663?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Utterly devastating news. Vince shaped the industry we all play in today. We simply would not have the games &amp; genres we have without Vince’s work. He &amp; his creations truly inspired and challenged me &amp; I’m a better creator thx to Vince. My condolences to his family &amp; friends. 🙏</p> <p>— Bruce Straley (@bruce_straley) <a href="https://twitter.com/bruce_straley/status/2003232742214078528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Still processing this. Can't believe we lost another legend in gaming. Don't know if its possible to overstate the impact Vince Zampella has made on games. Co-creator of Call of Duty (biggest game franchise of all?)  Co-founded <a href="https://twitter.com/InfinityWard?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@InfinityWard</a>  &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/Respawn?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Respawn</a>. </p> <p>Unbelievable loss.… <a href="https://t.co/YEJcjcxyXe">pic.twitter.com/YEJcjcxyXe</a></p> <p>— Ed Boon (@noobde) <a href="https://twitter.com/noobde/status/2003228766076580119?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Two Vince memories I’ll never forget… I remember going to the first Respawn office right after the E3 unveil to play Titanfall. It was the one of the first times anyone outside Respawn had gone hands on. I’ll never forget how excited and nervous he looked as we played. I was in…</p> <p>— JP Kellams (@synaesthesiajp) <a href="https://twitter.com/synaesthesiajp/status/2003234449853423798?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I just saw that Vince Zampella passed away yesterday in a car crash. I had to read it multiple times to believe it. He was an amazing mentor and friend. He will be sorely missed. My heart goes out to his family. RIP my friend!</p> <p>— Mark Rubin (@PixelsofMark) <a href="https://twitter.com/PixelsofMark/status/2003201831527391383?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I heard the tragic news that Vince has passed away. I still can’t believe it.<br>I first met Vince during his time at Infinity Ward, when he and Jason were creating “COD: MW2.” After they were forced out of Infinity Ward, Vince went on to found Respawn. When I was preparing to go… <a href="https://t.co/qLuy6sSC9w">pic.twitter.com/qLuy6sSC9w</a></p> <p>— HIDEO_KOJIMA (@HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN/status/2003400118868046169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The industry lost a legend.</p> <p>I lost a friend. </p> <p>RIP Vince. Gonna miss you. <a href="https://t.co/ekl2dtgh6d">pic.twitter.com/ekl2dtgh6d</a></p> <p>— Andy McNamara (@TheRealAndyMc) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheRealAndyMc/status/2003216010221101402?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Following the news, Respawn parent company and </span><i><span>Battlefield </span></i><span>publisher Electronic Arts released its own statement to </span><i><span>Kotaku </span></i><span>and other outlets:</span></p> <blockquote><p><span>This is an unimaginable loss, and our hearts are with Vince’s family, his loved ones, and all those touched by his work. Vince’s influence on the video game industry was profound and far-reaching. A friend, colleague, leader and visionary creator, his work helped shape modern interactive entertainment and inspired millions of players and developers around the world. His legacy will continue to shape how games are made and how players connect for generations to come.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>Zampella was 55, and is survived by three children.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vince-zampella-death-car-crash-tributes-reactions-2000655379]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shokz OpenRun Pro 2 Price Drop Makes It a Budget Bone Conduction Headphone, Gear Up for Your 2026 Fitness Goals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/shokz-openrun-pro-2-price-drop-makes-it-a-budget-bone-conduction-headphone-gear-up-for-your-2026-fitness-goals-2000655250</link>
            <guid>1391044</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As we approach the new year, you might find yourself thinking a lot about your goals for 2026. Lots of folks go into January big ambitions to get in shape and keep to a regular fitness routine, but the reality many also drop any health changes they’re trying to make by February. It’s a motivation and discipline issue, but you can help yourself look forward to your time in the gym or time running outdoors with the right tools. I’m talking about a good pair of headphones. I like to use my time running to catch up on podcasts that I otherwise, wouldn’t get a chance during the day to listen to. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5756/">My Shokz OpenRun Pro headphones are my perfect companion for this. Right now, their replacement model are on sale for 22% off on Amazon,</a> bringing the price down from $180 to just $140, saving you $40.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5756/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Bone Conduction Technology</h2>
<p>These headphones stand out from regular earbuds because they don’t go in your ears. Instead, they rest around your ears and use bone conduction to deliver sound. This means that sound vibrations are transmitted through your cheekbones, not through your ear canals. It’s a concept many of us might recall from those <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g3ca4tfXefk">quirky lollipop toys in the 90s</a> that played music when you bit into them, though the Shokz headphones offer a much higher-quality listening experience.</p>
<p>The main benefit of this design is that it keeps your ears open to the sounds around you, which can be crucial, especially when running outdoors. Being aware of your environment is a safety issue. Whether it’s listening for approaching cars or simply staying aware of other runners or pedestrians, bone conduction allows you to enjoy your music or podcasts without losing situational awareness.</p>



<h2>Comfort and Fit</h2>
<p>The Shokz OpenRun Pro 2 headphones have a design that comfortably sits on your ears, resembling a pair of sunglasses worn backward. They feature a lightweight, flexible titanium frame that wraps around your head, ensuring the headphones stay securely in place even during intense workouts. This design is especially great if you’ve ever been worried about earbuds falling out while running or exercising.</p>
<p>When it comes to battery performance, the Shokz OpenRun Pro 2 doesn’t disappoint. You can enjoy up to 12 hours of continuous listening on a single charge. And if you need a quick recharge, just five minutes of charging provides you with around 1.5 hours of playtime, which is incredibly convenient when you’re about to head out for a run and realize you forgot to charge them beforehand.</p>



<p>Shokz also offers a mini version of the OpenRun Pro 2 for those who need a more snug fit. The mini model has a shorter connecting band, making it more suitable for smaller heads. The standard version measures 20.7 cm across, while the mini is 18.6 cm. If you’re unsure which model would be the best fit, Shokz provides guidance on their website to help you decide.</p>
<p>Both the standard and mini versions are currently available at the same discount, and the colors you can choose from include black, silver, orange, and blue. Each of them are on sale for the same discount so you can choose based on your personal preference, and not which will save you more money.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5756/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/shokz-openrun-pro-2-price-drop-makes-it-a-budget-bone-conduction-headphone-gear-up-for-your-2026-fitness-goals-2000655250]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maybe The Weirdest Thing Anyone’s Ever Said In A Video Game Lawsuit]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-lawsuit-kotor-2-switch-divinity-2000655351</link>
            <guid>1391014</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Lil Wayne makes an unexpected appearance in a very unusual legal fight. <em>Call of Duty</em> is coming to Switch as soon as a few months from now. And one of Ubisoft’s Canadian studios just unionized. It’s the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture. I’m finalizing my personal game of the year list and I think I’ve almost nailed it. What games do you wish more people had paid attention to this year?</p> <h2>“Okay, you’re a goon, but what’s a goon to a Goblin?? Nothin’. Nothin’. You ain’t scaring nothing.”</h2> <p>That’s how attorney Ray Kim described Aspyr, the company behind a Switch port of <em>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic II</em> that ended up at the center of a very bizarre lawsuit, <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/star-wars-kotor-ii-lawsuit-saga"><em>Game File</em> reports</a>. Those are lyrics from Lil Wayne on the track “We Be Steady Mobbin.” Aspyr were the “goons,” per the legal filing in an actual court of law, while the players suing over missing DLC were “the goblins, and they will not be deterred.” The group reached a settlement earlier this month but the long, messy paper trail revealed plenty of other interesting nuggets, including the <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-kotor-old-republic-2-remake-kotor-kotor2-lucasfilm-leak-court-docs-2000651434">existence of an apparent <em>KOTOR 2</em> remake</a>.</p>

 <h2><em>Divinity</em>‘s director suggests you might not want to bother with the old games</h2> <p>“If you play [the two <em>Divinity: Original Sin</em> games], you will see things <a href="https://kotaku.com/divinity-turn-based-rpg-larian-studios-early-access-date-2000653845">in [the upcoming] <em>Divinity</em></a> that reference those two,” Swen Vincke <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/rpg/theyre-a-bit-outdated-larian-boss-swen-vincke-doesnt-believe-you-should-play-the-older-divinity-games-before-the-new-one-unless-you-want-the-lore/">told <em>GamesRadar</em></a>. “If you played the first <em>Divinity</em>, you will see it referenced properly inside of this <em>Divinity</em>. Ego Draconis, same story, or The Dragon Knight Saga, all of it is being referenced, but it’s just part of the history of what happened in this world, and it helped shape the world to the point where it is now.”</p>

 <p>But if you just want a taste of the lore and came to Larian through the cinematic feel of <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, just play <em>Original Sin 2</em>. “If you played because you really enjoy tactical combat or co-op multiplayer or really having lots of freedom, you should definitely play <em>Original Sin 2</em>, because that’s a game that was a blueprint for<em> BG3</em>,” he said.</p>

 <h2><em>Call of Duty</em> will reportedly come to Switch soon</h2> <p>Years after signing an agreement to bring the franchise back to Nintendo’s platforms, the shooter is still MIA. “The first <em>CoD</em> Switch version is nearly done,” <a href="https://x.com/JezCorden/status/2003171421879460027">claims</a> <em>Windows Central</em>‘s Jez Corden. He said it’s currently scheduled for a 2026 release, though it’s not entirely clear which form the game will take: a port of an existing sequel or a completely different experience. “We’re committed to getting the franchise on Switch,” a spokesperson for Activision confirmed earlier this year.</p>

 <h2>We almost got <em>Grand Theft Auto: Tokyo</em></h2> <p>Ex-Rockstar North tech director Obbe Vermei, who worked on the franchise’s PS2-era games, said the studio had once looked at setting the open-world formula in cities all across the world, <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>-style. An entry based in Japan was the closest to getting off the ground. “We had ideas about<em> GTA</em> games in Rio de Janeiro, Moscow and Istanbul,” he told <a href="https://www.gameshub.com/news/article/obbe-vermeij-interview-2849146/"><em>Games Hub</em> in a recent interview</a>. “Tokyo almost actually happened. Another studio in Japan were going to do it, take our code and do<em> GTA: Tokyo</em>. But then that didn’t happen in the end.”</p>

 <p>He continued, “People love having these wild ideas but then when you’ve got billions of dollars riding on it, it’s too easy to go ‘let’s do what we know again,’ and also America is basically the epicenter of Western culture, so everybody knows the cities, even people who haven’t been there. They have a mental image of the cities.”</p>

 <h2>A Ubisoft studio in North America just unionized for the first time</h2> <p>Ubisoft Halifax is located in Nova Scotia and works on mobile projects, including <em>Rainbow Six Siege Mobile</em>. The group announced its plan to unionize earlier this year and had a majority vote ratified last week after Ubisoft dropped its initial challenges. “It has started a conversation,” programmer Jon Huffman <a href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/atlantic/nova-scotia/article/halifax-workers-form-first-ubisoft-union-in-north-america/">told CTV News</a>. “Colleagues have reached out to say it’s a huge surprise. Whether or not they choose to follow, that’s up to them. We’ve shown the way forward, hopefully.”</p> <h2>Bloober Team’s next project name-checks some of the best horror games</h2> <p><strong>“</strong>You have no idea how hard it is for me not to reveal what Project M truly is—but for now, it’s still too early to talk about it. We’re confident that we’ll be able to share the first details very soon,” CEO Piotr Babieno told <em>Nintendo Insider</em>. <strong>“</strong>What I can say is this: fans of&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil</em>,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill</em>,&nbsp;<em>Limbo</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Eternal Darkness</em> will immediately feel at home. That said, Project M introduces a bold twist—one that no horror game has ever explored before. This is a vision that could only exist on Nintendo hardware.”</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33s-loses-indie-game-awards-after-being-accused-of-lying-about-ai-use-2000655119"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> was stripped of some Indie Game Awards over its use of AI</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-the-old-country-rare-big-game-you-can-finish-weekend-short-aaa-2k-2000655148">More games like <em>Mafia: The Old Country</em>, please</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-switch-2s-most-impressive-port-is-75-percent-off-right-now-2000655205"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>‘s super Switch 2 discount was too good to be true</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" src="about:blank" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://player.twitch.tv/?video=2647155999&amp;parent=Kotaku.com"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start"></span></iframe></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-lawsuit-kotor-2-switch-divinity-2000655351]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roku Streaming Stick Plus (2025) Crashes 52%, a Discount You’ll Never See on Amazon Fire TV Stick]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roku-streaming-stick-plus-2025-crashes-52-a-discount-youll-never-see-on-amazon-fire-tv-stick-2000655260</link>
            <guid>1391011</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>This Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 lets you turn your TV into a smart entertainment center using a very compact and powerful streaming device. Using the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 allows you to access your favorite streaming apps and channels through a very intuitive menu system that makes finding your favorite TV shows and movies fast and easy. If you want to enhance your TV viewing experience at a low cost, the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 is a great option.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/">On Amazon, you can buy the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 for as little as $19 (down from the normal price of $40).</a> This represents a discount of $21 and 52% off the original price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A quick and easy streaming solution</h2>
<p>All you need to do is insert the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 directly into your TV’s HDMI port and suddenly you will have an easily accessible menu system of streaming options. Many popular streaming services such as Netflix, Hulu, Disney+, Prime Video, and many others are included in the streaming stick plus 2025. There is no longer a need to constantly switch between multiple apps on your TV. Setting up the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 is relatively fast and easy. All you need to do is insert the streaming stick into the HDMI port of your TV, connect to your wireless network, and then follow the on-screen instructions. Before long you will be enjoying your favorite TV shows and movies without wasting a lot of time and effort.</p>
<p>You can also use the streaming stick to find a variety of different types of shows and movies fast. You can browse by type of show, enter a title in the search bar, or view trending shows right now. Additionally, there are many free channels provided with the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025, so if you are looking to find some new TV shows to watch without having to pay for a subscription, the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 is still a good option.</p>



<p>Casting from your mobile or tablet is another useful feature of the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025. With the ability to cast from your mobile or tablet, you can send video, photo, or music from your mobile or tablet to the large screen on your TV without needing to use any cords. This makes it easy to share videos you took on a recent trip with friends and family, play music for a party, or simply see content in a larger format. The Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 continues to respond well during the entire period of your viewing or listening session.</p>
<p>Overall, the Roku Streaming Stick Plus 2025 offers a great combination of streaming channels, ease of use, and fast performance, making it a good choice for anyone looking for an easy way to stream. And it’s on sale for a great price, too.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roku-streaming-stick-plus-2025-crashes-52-a-discount-youll-never-see-on-amazon-fire-tv-stick-2000655260]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>