<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 03:44:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Saw At Today's Big PlayStation State Of Play]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-playstation-state-play-2025-everything-we-saw-sop-1851761893</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-we-saw-at-todays-big-playstation-state-of-play.1107783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sony-playstation-state-play-2025-everything-we-saw-sop-1851761893<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="e954c1af7760971f3c3025a7fa2d681a" data-recommend-id="image://e954c1af7760971f3c3025a7fa2d681a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends race forward in fast cars. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends race forward in fast cars. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sega</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e954c1af7760971f3c3025a7fa2d681a" data-recommend-id="image://e954c1af7760971f3c3025a7fa2d681a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends race forward in fast cars. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Today, February 12, 2025, Sony held its first State of Play showcase of 2025. There weren’t any massive surprises, but there were a ton of really neat-looking games that just might snag your attention. In particular, there was a good chunk of third-person melee action, typically featuring swords slashing up some monstrosity. </p><p>Enough preamble, let’s get into everything we saw at today’s State of Play!</p></div></div><div><p>Sony kicked off their show with a nice little look at <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, in all its open-world, monster-bashing glory. If you haven’t been following this game, it’s worth checking out the trailer as it showcases a wide variety of beasts and environments. <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>ships on February 28, 2025.</p></div><div><p>With some slick-looking art and 2D platforming hack-n-slash action, <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance </em>sees<em>&nbsp;</em>the folks behind <em>Streets of Rage 4 </em>take a shot at resurrecting Sega’s classic ninja series. Let’s hope it plays as good as it looks. I mean, some of those landscapes are just too gorgeous. I could die there and be okay with it.</p></div><div><p><em>Crossworlds</em>, as the name suggests, seems like it’s putting a world-hopping spin on the <em>Sonic Racing </em>series, with mid-race portals you can drive through to take you to other realms. It has a closed beta on February 21, which you can sign up for now.</p></div><div><p>Oh hell yeah, it’s a <em>Digimon</em> game! When was the last time you played one of those? Time to stop playing <em>Palworld</em>!</p></div><div><p>With an ethereal presentation that promises a sword-swinging hero’s journey through some pretty spectacular-looking environments, <em>Lost Soul Aside</em> looks promising for fans of speedy and flashy third-person melee action. Hopefully it will be stylish enough for the more discerning fans of the genre among us. <em>Lost Soul Aside</em> launches on March 30, 2025. <br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e84214561e6f53b9312b45ecde7fa4b9" data-recommend-id="image://e84214561e6f53b9312b45ecde7fa4b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1440" data-height="810" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Goro Majima looks at someone off camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Goro Majima looks at someone off camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e84214561e6f53b9312b45ecde7fa4b9" data-recommend-id="image://e84214561e6f53b9312b45ecde7fa4b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1440" data-height="810" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Goro Majima looks at someone off camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>A demo for the new <em>Yakuza</em> title arrives this week!</p></div><div><p>Here’s a mashup you probably didn’t expect. Ichiban Kasuga from <em>Like A Dragon</em> brings his cheerful disposition and thrilling heroics to the world of <em>Dave the Diver</em>.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e466cb88e0d30f16532dd7f0baf69804" data-recommend-id="image://e466cb88e0d30f16532dd7f0baf69804" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A soldier opens fire on enemies at a distance in a science fiction setting." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A soldier opens fire on enemies at a distance in a science fiction setting." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->1047 Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e466cb88e0d30f16532dd7f0baf69804" data-recommend-id="image://e466cb88e0d30f16532dd7f0baf69804" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A soldier opens fire on enemies at a distance in a science fiction setting." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This <em>Portal</em>-meets-<em>Halo</em>-like sequel is rolling out an alpha demo later this month, on February 27. <br></p></div><div><p>Hey, if you always wanted to roam around a virtual hub dedicated to everything <em>WWE </em>(akin to the City in <em>NBA 2K25 </em>but for wrestling), check out the video above as Paul Heyman shows off The Island.</p></div><div><p>Oh, hi Randy. And other Randy. The Randys (Randies?) showed up to give us a quick look at the latest game in the cartoony-yet-always-gory <em>Borderlands</em> universe. I’ll have to wait till I get the game in my hands for sure, but from the looks of the trailer at least, the gunplay looks more solid and substantial than ever. The Randys also announced a special State of Play later this year that will go all in on <em>BL4</em>. </p><p><em>Bordelrands 4</em> launches on September 23, 2025. <br></p></div><div><p>Today’s SoP showed off even more of the upcoming <em>Split Fiction</em>, the science fiction meets fantasy fusion co-op adventure from the makers of <em>It Takes Two</em>. <br></p></div><div><p>I always sit up straight when a domineering masculine voice demands a status report. Maybe that’s something I need to work out with my therapist. Either way, <em>Directive 8020</em> is a flashy-looking science fiction horror romp that gives me some serious <em>Alien</em> vibes. Dead bodies on space stations, the creepiness of “substances” in space? Heck yeah. <em>Directive 8020</em> arrives on October 2nd.</p></div><div><p><em>Five Nights At Freddy</em>’s is getting yet another game, likely filled with even more animatronic creeps just waiting to scare the heck out of you.</p></div><div><p>With a lush, dark, and creepy aesthetic that’s giving some gentle Tim Burton vibes, <em>The Midnight Walk </em>is a fresh-looking first-person shooter with some clear stealth and puzzle elements. It arrives on May 8, 2025. It’ll also be playable on PS VR2!</p></div><div><p>I keep telling people that Octopodes are super smart. And <em>Darwin’s Paradox!</em> is all about that. This cute-looking platformer from Konami arrives later this year.</p><h2 id="h458622"><a id=""></a><em>SLIDE #16<strong>Warrior’s Abyss</strong></em></h2><p>A roguelike <em>Dynasty Warriors</em> just might be the twist to this legendary series you never thought you needed. It’s available on PS5 and PS4 today if you’re interested in giving it a shot.</p></div><div><p>These days I continue to suspect that the PS2 era was peak gaming. It’s all been downhill since then. Is that true? I don’t really know. But what I do know is that an ambitious remaster of <em>Onimusha 2</em> is arriving on May 23 if you want to get a taste of that PS2 magic.</p></div><div><p>If <em>Onimusha 2</em> wasn’t enough, today’s SoP followed it up with more <em>Onimusha</em> (nuts, right?). This one isn’t a remaster, however. Rather, with a stylish modern presentation and some great-looking physics interactions, new series entry <em>Onimusha:</em> <em>Way of the Sword </em>is definitely worth putting on your radar with an expected release window of 2026. <br></p></div><div><p>Okay, for those of you who enjoy <em>MGS3</em>, I’m happy for you. The game is fine. This remake doesn’t inspire me to put up with it again, but hey, if you want to hear David Hayter play Snake again (who wouldn’t?) It’ll probably be worth it for that alone.</p><p><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em> arrives on August 28, 2025—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://d&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://d/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">but you knew that already, didn’t you</a></span>? <br></p></div><div><p>Give me Adam Jensen—err, I mean his voice actor, Elias Toufexis—and a moody trailer for a pretty intense-looking sci-fi game and I’ve almost  forgotten what <em>Deus Ex</em> even is. With a release date of September 4, 2025, <em>Hell Is Us</em> looks like it could be a gripping adventure.</p><h2 id="h458623"><a id=""></a><em>SLIDE #21<strong>Lies of P: Overture</strong></em></h2><p>If you were fan of 2023’s soulslike <em>Lies of P</em>, you’ll be happy to check out a trailer for its upcoming expansion, arriving this summer. </p></div><div><p>Where to begin with this one? Somehow, I imagine this is what Hideo Kojima’s dreams look like—glimpses of play with violent interuptions. Kojima isn’t involved in this game, but it still looks worth checking out as it seems quite imaginative. <br></p></div><div><p><em>Days Gone</em> might be mid at best for some folks, but I quite enjoyed it and with a permadeath mode and other features, I might be willing to give it a spin again. This remaster launches on April 25.</p></div><div><p>If you’re up for looking pretty and slashing weird monsters, <em>Stellar Blade</em> is getting a PC release <em>and</em> an expansion this June. <br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f37780dadd2b80700e0751465420222f" data-recommend-id="image://f37780dadd2b80700e0751465420222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Four teens walk across a fallen tree trunk in a forest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Four teens walk across a fallen tree trunk in a forest." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Don’t Nod / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f37780dadd2b80700e0751465420222f" data-recommend-id="image://f37780dadd2b80700e0751465420222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Four teens walk across a fallen tree trunk in a forest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage Tape 1</em> sees the folks at Don’t Nod take on the story of a fateful summer in the lives of a group of young friends, and how they’re dealing with its ramifications as adults.</p></div><div><p><em>Blue Prince</em> is a puzzle game billing itself as an “atmospheric architectural adventure” set inside a cryptic house that’s hopefully filled with  worthwhile secrets for those of us who like to snoop around where we probably don’t belong. <br></p></div><div><p><em>Abiotic Factor</em>, already a huge hit on Steam, is a co-op survival game that gives me some <em>Half-Life</em> vibes, with strange creatures and scientific endeavors that hopefully won’t doom us all.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f38ce624da495309169a18051da2acd3" data-recommend-id="image://f38ce624da495309169a18051da2acd3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows title art for several Armored Core games and Patapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows title art for several Armored Core games and Patapon." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / FromSoftware / Pyramid / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f38ce624da495309169a18051da2acd3" data-recommend-id="image://f38ce624da495309169a18051da2acd3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows title art for several Armored Core games and Patapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The original <em>Armored Core, Armored Core Project Phantasma, Armored Core Master of Arena, </em>and <em>Patapon 3</em> are coming to PlayStation Plus for subscribers with access to the Classics Catalog.</p></div><div><p>There sure were a lot of swords at today’s event. And while <em>Hell Is Us</em> maybe looks most appealing to me, I’d be lying if I said <em>Tides of Annihilation </em>wasn’t a close second.</p></div><div><p>Blood-pumping music and stylish action complete with wall-running and first-person shooting are at the heart of <em>Metal Eden</em>. It’s expected on May 6, 2025.</p></div><div><p><em>Mindseye</em> is an action adventure game about “AI and human greed” destroying society. It’s directed by Leslie Benzies, the former president of Rockstar North, so don’t be surprised if it gives off some serious <em>Grand Theft Auto </em>vibes.</p></div><div><p><em>Saros </em>is the latest game from Housemarque, makers of such elegant games as <em>Returnal </em>and <em>Resogun. </em>It stars Rahul Kohli and while the trailer has no gameplay, it hints pretty strongly at this game building on what the studio achieved in <em>Returnal</em>, which, it seems, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/saros-release-date-trailer-gameplay-roguelike-1851762075&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/saros-release-date-trailer-gameplay-roguelike-1851762075">is exactly what they’re aiming to do</a></span>. <em>Saros</em> arrives in 2026. They closed the show with this one, so maybe it’s worth keeping on your radar? <br></p><hr><p>And that wraps up our rundown of Sony’s February 12, 2025 event! Nope, there was no <em>Bloodborne </em>or <em>God of War</em>. Sorry!</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>