<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:03:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom’s Upcoming Blockbusters Feel Old In The Best Way]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom%E2%80%99s-upcoming-blockbusters-feel-old-in-the-best-way.1275654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><span>These days, most AAA video game companies are struggling to gain and maintain momentum in a fickle marketplace when games are taking longer than ever to make. Capcom, meanwhile, is on a hot streak. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-review-world-tour-story-mode-roster-1850481281"><i><span>Street Fighter 6</span></i></a><span>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragons-dogma-2-review-ps5-1851349573"><i><span>Dragon’s Dogma 2</span></i></a><span>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113"><i><span>Monster Hunter Wilds</span></i></a><span>, and the continued renaissance of the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-4-re4-remaster-remake-review-capcom-ps5-1850278891"><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i></a> <span>series are just a few examples of the developer being in a no-skips, all-hits era. I recently got a chance to play three of the company’s upcoming games: </span><i><span>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i><span>, and my limited time with each spoke both to the variety in the company’s line-up, but also indicated a refreshing “back to basics” mentality that a lot of AAA companies can’t seem to fathom in 2025. These games feel like they’re from a different era, and that’s for the better.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Onimusha: Way of the Sword - 3rd Trailer: The Genma Experiments | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bf1cAQIKpWA?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><i><span>Onimusha: Way of the Sword </span></i><span>was the first game I played during my preview session, and after 20 years away, the latest </span><i><span>Onimusha </span></i><span>feels surprisingly untouched by the RPG trappings that have latched onto many modern action games. The section I played was the same one I saw at Summer Game Fest, which showed samurai warrior Musashi Miyamoto slicing his way through a mostly derelict village overrun by underworldly monsters. At first blush, </span><i><span>Way of the Sword </span></i><span>might feel a bit simple to the modern action game fan who has become so used to skill trees and Soulslike difficulty. But there was a time in the PlayStation 2 era when a good parry and dodge mechanic was enough to satisfy you for about 10 to 15 hours.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>When I played </span><i><span>Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, I was caught off guard by how “of its time” it felt. It’s as if it picks up where the series left off 20 years ago, but with a bit of modern flair and finesse. The boss fight at the end of the demo against Ganryu Sasaki, a fellow Oni Gauntlet-wearing swordsman, was challenging enough to prove that skillful swordplay is enough to carry an action game in 2025, even as the genre more frequently de-emphasizes those core fundamentals.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Pragmata - First Contact Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdDVyBtYrUI?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>That same streamlined focus was evident when I played </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>. I already </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pragmata-capcom-preview-summer-game-fest-impressions-1851784342"><span>wrote up impressions of the demo</span></a><span> I played at Summer Game Fest, and this appointment was mostly focused on the same early section of the game, just with a boss fight at the end. Like </span><i><span>Way of the Sword</span></i><span>, the sci-fi puzzle shooter feels like something plucked out of a previous generation. Its over-the-shoulder shooting, brutalist sci-fi aesthetic, and dad game setup make it feel exactly like something you would’ve seen on a GameStop shelf during the PS360 generation. As I said back in June, it keeps from feeling like a rote retread of old tropes by combining its shooting with a real-time puzzle-solving element that has you breaking down enemy defenses and opens a window for your bullets to actually do real damage. Separately, these mechanics are simple and perhaps unremarkable; together, they create a big-budget shooter that would have been the kind of fun, one-off experiment a company like Capcom would have released between big sequels. Even as Capcom has put out hit after hit, the company has become pretty reliant on sequels in the same way pretty much every other AAA developer has. It’s refreshing to see that it still has the chops to put out something like </span><i><span>Pragmata</span></i><span>, a non-sequel which may pull from old motifs, but also feels novel as games like it have gone out of style in recent years.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Resident Evil Requiem - Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/POz1-EmLsTY?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>That brings us to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-9-grace-trailer-gamescom-mother-2000618547"><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i></a><span>, the latest entry in a series that has spent the better part of a decade reinventing itself. What I played of the ninth mainline game in the long-running survival horror series felt more evocative of </span><i><span>Haunting Ground</span></i><span>, a cult classic hide-and-seek horror game Capcom put out in 2005, than the misadventures of Chris Redfield and Leon Kennedy. As we see more of it, </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>may eventually adopt the more action-oriented flow of 2021’s </span><i><span>Resident Evil Village </span></i><span>or stay in the escape room-esque hide-and-seek loop of the segment I played, but in the demo&nbsp; section, at least, it felt like the game had been stripped down to its core elements to leave you with a terrifying helplessness. All I had to defend myself from a horrifying monstrosity that followed me back and forth through a dimly lit hallway was my wits, glass bottles, and whatever light sources I could find to scare it away. </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>has been experimenting with what it means to carry that name for a while, and so perhaps it’s fitting that what I played of </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>didn’t make me think of </span><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i><span> much at all, but rather of a </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/survival-horror/after-20-years-capcom-removes-its-website-for-controversial-usd500-ps2-horror-game-and-i-know-the-bad-ending-might-get-you-pregnant-but-im-prepared-to-stage-a-funeral-if-there-isnt-a-remake/"><span>long-lost gem that Capcom has mostly forgotten</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>All three of these games are coming out in 2026, and by then, we’ll be another trip around the sun removed from the games that seemingly inspired each of them, and they could feel even more out of time. Even so, Capcom’s dedication to the old ways of doing things, when it feels like every other month we’re hearing about a beloved franchise or </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-bioware-layoffs-mass-effect-1851784416"><span>company</span></a><span> being handcuffed to&nbsp; modern practices solely meant to make every game a time suck, is a big part of the reason it’s put out mostly bangers for the past few years. I’m not usually one to say “things were better back in my day,” but it is nice to have reminders that not every developer has learned the wrong lessons. At least one major player is willing to go back to the well, find what worked before, and meaningfully iterate on it instead of breaking it apart to turn it into something we no longer recognize.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 Brings Back Horrors Of Paid Day-One DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-day-1-dlc-clans-2000618832</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-the-masquerade-%E2%80%93-bloodlines-2-brings-back-horrors-of-paid-day-one-dlc.1275549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A vampire stares into camera.</span> © Paradox
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p><em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</em> has been through a hell of a journey to reach us. At <a href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-onl-2025-resident-evil-silent-hill-silksong-2000618460">last night’s Opening Night Live from Gamescom</a>, Paradox revealed the long-delayed game finally has a release date, October 21. What the publisher didn’t boast about was is that it is locking two out of the six playable clans behind paid day-one DLC, and it’ll cost you an extra $30 to unlock them. A third of the ways to play the game.</p> <p>Expensive day-one DLC was once the most loathed concept in gaming. Back in 2012 <a href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-3-dlc-triggers-fan-outrage-bioware-respons-5887626">it was the talk of the industry</a>, as companies deliberately developed a chunk of the launched game with the intention of hiding it behind a further paywall, and people understandably <em>hated it</em>. Times moved on, and now we’re screwed over in all manner of different ways, most usually seeing significant portions of games sectioned off behind so-called “battle passes,” where we’re expected to not just pay once but to buy new ones multiple times throughout the year! Yay video games! But Paradox is kicking us old-school with <em>Bloodlines 2 </em>by deciding that a full third of how you can play the game will require you to fork out 50 percent of the original asking price again. The cheapest version of the game will cost you $60 on PC, but if you want to buy everything they developed for launch, it’ll cost you an extraordinary $90. Not even the $70 “Deluxe Edition” will secure you either of the missing clans. (Thanks <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-sticks-two-bloodsucker-clans-including-the-sexy-one-behind-paid-day-one-dlc"><em>RPS</em></a>.)</p> <p>A huge part of how the original&nbsp;<em>Bloodlines</em> played was based on the clan you chose at the start. It affected not just more common features like stats, but entirely changed how you approached the game. Different clans within the world treated you accordingly, missions were experienced differently as a result, and the means by which you could approach the RPG quests were all affected by who you were. Play as Brujah and you were a mighty warrior but very vulnerable to “frenzy,” where you’d fully lose control of your bloodlust. But pick a Toreador and you were a schmoozer, expert in socializing, but weakened by your inability to turn away from the truly beautiful. Clearly these made for very different experiences of the game. But now, in&nbsp;<em>Bloodlines 2</em>, if you want to be a Toreador and play that way, it’s going to cost you an awful lot more.</p>

 <p>As <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2/bloodlines-faq">the game’s own FAQ</a> makes clear, these choices are not cosmetic.</p> <p>“How will the dialogue options differ in each playthrough?” asks one of the questions. The answer:</p> <blockquote> <p>The dialogue options differ depending on which clan you’ve chosen and what choices you’ve made throughout the story. When hunting for Blood Resonance, specific disciplines and outfit choices can also affect NPCs on the street.</p> </blockquote> <p>It also notes that “each clan offers new, unique abilities, playstyles, and distinct outfits.” Play style seems a hell of a thing to lock to day-one DLC.</p> <p>For a while, Bloodlines<em> 2</em> did look to have become vaporware, after its original development under Hardsuit Labs fell apart in 2021 following its former leads being fired. Then in 2023 it re-emerged, <a href="https://kotaku.com/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-new-release-date-1850804491">now being developed by The Chinese Room</a>, the studio best known for their walking sims, which has had its own turbulent few years. Given The Chinese Room only released their most recent game, <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em>, in June of last year, it seemed unlikely that <em>Bloodlines 2</em> could be imminent. But here we are! It’s out in just a couple of months.</p> <p>We’ve reached out to Paradox to ask what has motivated the decision to lock away such a significant chunk of the core game behind day-one DLC. (Although we can guess it’s at least in part, “We desperately need to recoup some of the costs of the last six years of development across two different studios under multiple different leaderships for the sequel to a game that came out in 2004.”) We’ll report back if they respond.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-day-1-dlc-clans-2000618832]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>