<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:23:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Fire Max 11 Tablet Hits Lowest Price Yet Ahead of Prime Big Deal Days, Hundreds Cheaper Than an iPad]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-fire-max-11-tablet-hits-lowest-price-yet-ahead-of-prime-big-deal-days-hundreds-cheaper-than-an-ipad-2000627185</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-fire-max-11-tablet-hits-lowest-price-yet-ahead-of-prime-big-deal-days-hundreds-cheaper-than-an-ipad.1311784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’d be telling you that this limited-time deal on the Amazon Fire Max 11 tablet is hot, or that it’s fire, or that it’s a scorcher, but honestly, would you still respect us in the morning? So we’ll dispense with the terrible puns and cut straight to the deal, because it’s one of the better ones we’ve seen in a while on this great, affordable tablet. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4376/">It’s 32% off for a limited time, turning a very good $280 price into a great one at just $190.</a></p>
<p>To put things in perspective, the Amazon Fire Max 11 is an 11-inch tablet with an octa-core processor, 14-hour battery life, expandable storage of up to 1TB via microSD card, and 2.4 million pixel resolution. As an Amazon product it blends seamlessly with the rest of the Amazon ecosystem, including Prime Video, Kindle, Audible, and Luna, along with your smart home devices via either Alexa or the Device Dashboard. And here’s the kicker — at this sale price it’s over $700 less than the 11-inch M4 iPad Pro, and $375 less than the 11-inch M3 iPad Air.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4376/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Premium Features, Not Price</h2>
<p>There are probably metrics and benchmark tests that put those pricier iPads ahead of the Fire Max 11, but not nearly enough to quantify the price difference. The octa-core processor at the heard of the Fire Max 11 is certainly no slouch when it comes to streaming, multitasking, and gaming on Luna. The 128GB of storage is small, but so easily and inexpensively expandable thanks to the microSD card slot that the Apple tablets lack.</p>
<p>Wi-Fi 6 speeds, a robust 14-hour battery life, 8MP camera, and options to expand into a more laptop-like experience with the sold-separately Fire Max 11 Keyboard Case — which also happens to be&nbsp;<em>way</em> more affordable than Apple’s Magic Keyboard — all make the Fire Max 11 highly competitive even before you do a price comparison. Once you check out those numbers, this isn’t even a fair contest.</p>



<h2>Beautifully Basic</h2>
<p>When you look at the Fire Max 11 — and this is the latest, most updated iteration of the Fire Max — in the context of being a fully integrated part of the massive Amazon ecosystem, it’s a brilliant tablet, especially for just $190. It’s not going to compete with a laptop as a productivity machine, although this deal does come with a free 3-month Microsoft 365 trial, but as an e-reader, streaming device, smart-home control panel, and light gaming device, it’s an exceptional tablet.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-powerful-octa-core-processor-lockscreen/dp/B0B2SFTGQ6?tag=kotaku01-20">This model of the Amazon Fire Max currently on sale for just $190</a> has the max 128GB storage and also comes with lockscreen ads deactivated. The $90 savings on this deal are great, and even greater when you tack them onto the hundreds you save by avoiding the super-bougie competitor tablets.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4376/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-fire-max-11-tablet-hits-lowest-price-yet-ahead-of-prime-big-deal-days-hundreds-cheaper-than-an-ipad-2000627185]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameStop Giveaway Unlocks Shiny Legendary Pokémon For The First Time And It Goes Very Poorly]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-koraidon-miraidon-gamestop-codes-scalper-2000629926</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamestop-giveaway-unlocks-shiny-legendary-pok%C3%A9mon-for-the-first-time-and-it-goes-very-poorly.1311781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>You would think that The Pokémon Company and GameStop would know that turning something that could easily have been distributed digitally into a physical item, only obtainable in stores, would attract the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scalper-reseller-trading-card-van-gogh-pikachu-1850925900"><span>Mandibuzz-like vultures who circle the franchise</span></a><span> looking for a way to scalp its merch to make a quick buck. That’s exactly what’s happened with a partnership to give out free codes for rare </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457"><span>Shiny Pokémon</span></a><span> in </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-dlc-teal-mask-indigo-disk-gen-9-1851109325"><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i></a><span>, as scalpers have found a way to ruin something else for everyone.</span></p> <p><span>Here’s what was supposed to happen: from September 26 to October 15, fans who visit GameStops or EB Games locations would be able to get a code to receive either a Shiny Koraidon or Miraidon, the legendary Pokémon that grace </span><i><span>Scarlet</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span>‘s covers. These alternate-colored variants have never been available before, so if you’re the kind of collector who wants every Shiny, this is a pretty big deal. No purchase was required to get one of these codes; all you had to do was show up at participating locations. However, many fans are reporting that their local stores are running out of codes weeks before the promotion ends next month, and some locations say they won’t be getting more. Some customers report that stores still have codes but have been </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonScarletViolet/comments/1nqg2ay/local_gamestop_shiny_koraidon_and_miraidon/"><span>giving them out only as a promotional item</span></a><span> alongside other purchases, despite the official word on </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s website </span><a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/get-shiny-koraidon-or-shiny-miraidon-at-gamestop-and-eb-games"><span>saying no purchase is necessary</span></a><span>.</span></p>   <p><span>Sometimes these events are digital, meaning that you could download an event Pokémon in a store or through the game itself and go on your merry way. But when they involve a physical card with a code on it, supplies actually </span><i><span>are</span></i><span> limited, and when something is limited, a scalper is waiting just around the corner to swoop in. This also happened the same day as a new </span><i><span>Trading Card Game</span></i><span> set drop, so these people smelled blood in the water, and not only got the codes, but have started listing them for sale on places like </span><a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=shiny+koraidon+and+miraidon&amp;_sacat=0&amp;_from=R40&amp;_trksid=p4624852.m570.l1311"><span>eBay</span></a><span>. Some of the prices are fairly cheap at less than $10, while other sellers are getting bold and asking for much more. Even if the price is cheap, these codes are supposed to be free, so even a dollar is a profit for scalpers.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>As some <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EFl1XUEqcls">commentators have pointed out</a>, <em>Pokémon </em></span><span>loves brand synergy, which is why every facet of its business releases new products around the same time. The games come out, new TCG sets come out alongside it, and more plushes of new critters show up on the Pokémon Center website, so it makes sense that it would offer these rare Pokémon on the same day people are showing up to game shops to buy the new TCG sets. That said, adding scarcity to a digital good just emboldens some of the worst people to keep taking advantage of other fans. Hopefully, these stores get more codes between now and when the promotion ends in October, because only sending enough for one weekend sounds like poor planning on everyone’s part.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-koraidon-miraidon-gamestop-codes-scalper-2000629926]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Battlefield 6 Trailer Is A Direct Attack Against Call Of Duty]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-battlefield-6-trailer-direct-attack-against-call-of-duty-celeb-trailer-skins-ea-2000629910</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-battlefield-6-trailer-is-a-direct-attack-against-call-of-duty.1311775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A new live-action trailer for <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-have-a-button-that-blows-up-everything-in-a-map-and-its-fun-to-press-it-2000626898">Electronic Arts’ upcoming<em> Battlefield 6</em> </a>features a group of celebrities, including Zac Efron, getting swiftly blown up by a missile in what seems to be a dig at <em>Call of Duty</em>‘s many commercials featuring actors, musicians, and other famous people. It’s the latest example of the two military shooter franchises reacting to one another in a way we’ve not seen in years.</p> <p>On September 28, EA released the “<em>Battlefield 6</em>: Official Launch Live-Action Trailer.” And like many live-action<em> Call of Duty</em> ads from the last decade, the <em>BF6</em> commercial starts off with a group of celebs cosplaying as soldiers and getting ready to fight. But just 24 seconds into the new trailer, a missile flies into frame and blows up all four stars in a large, fiery explosion. A group of soldiers then walks through the area, with one asking, “Who was that?” and the other bluntly replying that it “doesn’t matter” before telling everyone to move out.</p>  <p>While the new ad doesn’t directly mention <em>Call of Duty</em>, it’s obvious what EA is doing here. For many, many years, <em>Call of Duty</em> games have used celebrities like Will Arnett, Jonah Hill, Michael B. Jordan, Cara Delevingne, and many others in various live-action trailers. <a href="https://youtu.be/yXzMOUCYGBs">As recently as 2021,<em> Call of Duty</em> featured numerous celebs in a <em>Warzone</em> ad</a> that was heavily criticized by fans for going too far and feeling too silly. This new <em>BF6</em> trailer feels like a direct nod to those <a href="https://youtu.be/IhPyNuqewZU">celeb-heavy launch ads</a> and a commitment from EA that it won’t follow in <em>CoD’s</em> footsteps, a move that fans in the comments of the trailer seem to greatly appreciate.</p>

 <p>Over the years<a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-bad-bf6-battlefield-6-hype-trailer-2000618912">, longtime <em>CoD</em> players have lamented</a> the franchise’s shift away from grounded combat and realism as bizarre crossover skins and over-the-top future tech have become more prevalent in recent entries. This has all come to a head in 2025 as <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-struggled-xbox-series-s-60-fps-switch-2-2000625487"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a>, which had a massively popular open beta earlier this year, has gone the opposite direction and doubled down on being a gritty, grounded, and realistic military shooter. Activision has responded by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-changes-black-ops-7-pre-order-operator-skins/">making changes to skins</a>, rolling back plans to let all <em>Black Ops 6</em> skins move forward into <em>Black Ops 7,</em> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-blops7-skins-goofy-crossover-turned-down-deals-bf6-grounded-2000628200">even letting devs talk publicly about the series turning down some collaboration cosmetic deals</a>.</p>

 <p>It’s very, very unlikely that <em>Battlefield 6</em> will outsell <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> this year. But it seems like EA’s FPS might take a bigger bite out of the rival shooter series than it has in previous years, and Activision is definitely paying attention. <a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-sale-saudi-arabia-madden-pif-jared-kushner-2000629829">The news that EA is being bought up by Saudi Arabia’s PIF</a> as well as other investors, including Jared Kushner’s investment firm, has certainly added <a href="https://kotaku.com/electronic-arts-acquisition-saudi-arabia-jared-kushner-2000629849">an awkwardness to <em>BF6</em>‘s rollout</a>, though.</p> <p><em>Battlefield 6</em> will launch on October 10 for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. EA won’t talk about a Switch 2 port. <em>Black Ops 7</em> launches on consoles and PC in November. <a href="https://kotaku.com/will-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-come-to-switch-2-1851784023">It also isn’t going to be available on Switch 2.</a></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-battlefield-6-trailer-direct-attack-against-call-of-duty-celeb-trailer-skins-ea-2000629910]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MrBeast Responds To Concerns Over Trapping Guy In Burning House For $500,000]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mrbeast-house-fire-trapped-prize-stunt-viral-youtube-backlash-safety-2000629861</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mrbeast-responds-to-concerns-over-trapping-guy-in-burning-house-for-500-000.1311739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The latest YouTube video stunt by one <a href="https://kotaku.com/mrbeast-lawsuit-beast-games-amazon-hidden-cameras-1851775284">James “MrBeast” Donaldson</a> has already wracked up over 46 million views in just one day and it’s not hard to imagine why. Titled “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zo7i8VTpfNM&amp;t=28s">Would You Risk Dying For $500,000?</a>” it shows a series of challenges in which people brave flame-engulfed obstacles in exchange for money. It’s kind of like David Blaine if, instead of doing absurd and wild stuff himself, he paid other people to do it while also explaining how it was all incredibly fake and just for grim lulz.</p> <p>The infernal trap that’s been drawing the most attention is one in which a stuntman is tied to a chair inside a “burning house” and has to escape and save as much money as he can from inside the house in order to earn the highest cash prize possible. Donaldson bounces back and forth between urgent warnings about how real the flames are and mugging the camera with jokes about MrBeast product placement. The entertainment concept is more grotesquely mundane than anything Phillip K. Dick could have imagined and also, clearly, highly entertaining to millions of people.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">This blew up, if you’re curious obviously we had ventilation for the smoke and a kill switch to cut off the fires. We had professionals test this extensively and the guy in the video as stated is a professional stunt man. I take safety more serious than you could ever imagine.</p> <p>— MrBeast (@MrBeast) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrBeast/status/1972507399413260366?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Donaldson defended his uniquely gifted intuition for creating the debased content people crave by promising the whole stunt was tested with professionals multiple times, responding to viral posts about the stunt with additional context. The last thing Donaldson needs after lawsuits last year over <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/mrbeast-internal-investigation-findings-sexual-misconduct-1235150941/">alleged safety violations on his Amazon Prime</a> show is people thinking he doesn’t take the premise of potentially roasting another human being alive for less than the median home price after taxes seriously.</p>

 <p>“We had professionals test this extensively and the guy in the video as stated is a professional stunt man,” he wrote on X over the weekend. “I take safety more serious than you could ever imagine.” He expanded on the setup in a comment on the YouTube video as well.</p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:on5oeywiqx32fh2zau473wz6/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzy22r723k2w" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiglqdgk2xfrl3d2mts5fqecakrqwbllpidp6sbsybsdamtbhqirve"> <p lang="en">Content creators tend to think any spectacle is defensible if they can say health and safety concerns have been attended to behind the scenes, but that’s not really it imho. Mr. Beast’s whole thing is that his subjects’ desperation for cash allows him—a wealthier person—to indulge his sadism.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:on5oeywiqx32fh2zau473wz6?ref_src=embed">southpaw (@nycsouthpaw.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:on5oeywiqx32fh2zau473wz6/post/3lzy22r723k2w?ref_src=embed">2025-09-29T12:45:09.235Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p>“In case there’s any concern about the safety of the stuntman contestant, I just wanted to mention that we take safety extremely seriously,” he added. “Every challenge was tested by multiple stuntmen, we have a full rescue team on standby with firefighters, EMTs and divers equipped with an ambulance and fire truck. We also had a pyro team controlling the fires and multiple fire suppression methods on every challenge to ensure we could essentially turn off the fire if there was ever an issue. But our stunt coordinator did an amazing job as always, and none of these systems were ever needed. Just wanted to be transparent with you all since I saw some concern!”</p> <p>This is the Catch-22 at the heart of this entire genre of extremely watchable algorithm-bait. Either the entire thing is so real and authentic that it’s an absolutely monstrous thing for everyone involved to be associated with and signals the utter depravity of modern capitalism, or the stunt is all so fake and performative that none of it matters and you’ve been conned out of 25 minutes of your week just so some guy can hock candy bars.</p> <p>Either way, it kinda sucks!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mrbeast-house-fire-trapped-prize-stunt-viral-youtube-backlash-safety-2000629861]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scalpers Are Already Trying To Flip The Xbox Ally X For Twice The Price And It’s Not Even Sold Out Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-price-ebay-asus-microsoft-2000629892</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scalpers-are-already-trying-to-flip-the-xbox-ally-x-for-twice-the-price-and-it%E2%80%99s-not-even-sold-out-yet.1311691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Microsoft and Asus’ collaborative handheld Xbox device is arriving on October 16, 2025, with pre-orders available at various outlets right now. And as things go on the internet, eBay listings promising confirmed pre-orders are now <a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=rog+ally+xbox+x&amp;_sacat=0&amp;_from=R40&amp;_trksid=p2334524.m570.l1313&amp;LH_TitleDesc=0&amp;_odkw=rog+ally+xbox&amp;_osacat=0">going for two to three times the retail price</a> –which is pretty ridiculous when the top-tier model of this handheld is already a thousand bucks.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-handheld-rog-ally-x-price-preorder-2000629161">Xbox’s Handheld Finally Has A Price, And It Costs More Than An Xbox</a></p> <p>The ROG Xbox Ally X is an Xbox-skinned portable PC much like the Steam Deck or Asus’ own non-Xbox-branded “Ally.” These devices have become quite popular in recent years because, well, they’re usually pretty awesome. With the ability to carry around massive storefronts like Steam on the go, and enough horsepower to run graphical powerhouses like <i>Cyberpunk 2077</i>, it’s no wonder Microsoft wanted to get in on the action with a more Xbox-themed offering. The only problem is that the hardware manufacturer and game publisher is asking folks to spend $600 on the basic model, and a full four-digit $1,000 for the top-tier model featuring a more powerful processor. And yet, some eBayers think folks will spend even more than that even though it hasn’t sold out elsewhere. Wild.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000629896" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000629896"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000629896">© Screenshot: eBay / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <h2>Who’s buying this thing anyway?</h2> <p>The ROG Xbox Ally X (which is the more powerful of the two models) is <i>technically</i> more powerful than some of its competitors. It features a new AMD Z2E AI Chip. Is it a generational leap? Certainly not enough to prompt Valve to base a Steam Deck successor on it.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-series-x-s-price-hike-raise-trump-tariff-microsoft-2000627228">Microsoft Reveals The First $800 Xbox With Another Round Of Price Hikes</a></p> <p>Still, the <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/hardware/handheld-gaming-pcs/the-rog-xbox-ally-x-priced-at-usd1-000-and-available-to-pre-order-in-october-making-it-officially-the-most-expensive-xbox-ever/">improved performance of the Z2E</a> <i>is</i> worth noting, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Handhelds/comments/1m8ujhf/at_low_tdps_the_z2_extreme_is_a_generational_leap/">around a 10 to 20-percent performance improvement</a> over TKTK, and sometimes a bit more, under certain circumstances. That improvement, however, comes at a cost, namely about $500 more than what you’d pay for a Steam Deck, and $100 more than Asus’ excellent ROG Ally X, which is not the Xbox-branded one. (No, you’re not dumb, this naming convention is.)</p>

 <p>So, that really just leaves the controller-based Xbox user interface, which reduces the overall processing power Windows takes up and is more gamepad-friendly, and the unique controller grips. And even then, <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-windows-handheld-app-leak-2000626934">folks have found a way to get the new Xbox game launcher working</a> on regular, non-Xbox-branded Ally portable PCs, and, to be honest, while I haven’t held a ROG Xbox Ally, it’s gonna be hard to compete with the Steam Deck’s excellent ergonomics.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-windows-handheld-app-leak-2000626934">The Biggest Reason To Buy The Xbox Ally Handheld Just Leaked</a></p> <p>At $1,000 for the top-tier Xbox handheld, it’s hard to see a compelling reason to upgrade if you already have a Steam Deck, and certainly not if you have a more powerful handheld than that. Who, then, is gonna get suckered into spending twice that for an eBay pre-order? Hopefully not you!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-price-ebay-asus-microsoft-2000629892]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New PS5 Model Ditches The Shiny Black Plastic Fans Hated]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/leaked-ps5-model-shiny-black-plastic-fingerprints-borderlands-4-silent-hill-2000629868</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-ps5-model-ditches-the-shiny-black-plastic-fans-hated.1311688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good morning. Welcome to a new week. Will it be better than last week? I really hope so! Anyway, today’s Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku’s</em> daily round-up of interesting news and stuff you might care about, features a new and less shiny PS5, <em>Silent Hill f</em> sales data,<em> Borderlands 4</em> DLC news, a content creator retiring, and a cool Daft Punk video.</p> <h2><strong>New PS5 Model Ditches All That Shiny Black Plastic</strong></h2> <p>A new model of the PlayStation 5 has leaked online ahead of an official announcement from Sony, and while it’s not a massive update to the current iteration of the console, it does include one tweak that seems to be making a lot of people happy: The new PS5 doesn’t include shiny black plastic.<a href="https://x.com/Zuby_Tech/status/1972613838953476238"> As reported by Zuby_Tech</a>, new photos and information about the refreshed PS5 show that it features matte black plastic, saving you from having to cover your PS5 in nasty fingerprints every time you dare to move or touch it.</p> <p>Other changes found in this new, updated PS5 console include different-colored USB ports, a smaller SSD, and a new heatsink. The console is also overall a bit lighter now, likely thanks to more stamped metal parts inside. No word on when to expect this new console to hit shelves, but I’d bet it won’t be long, as we are getting close to the holiday season.</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Silent Hill f</em> Outselling <em>Silent Hill 2</em> remake</strong></h2> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="ja" dir="ltr">『SILENT HILL f』</p> <p>全世界累計出荷本数※が100万本を突破しました。<br>プレイいただいた皆さまありがとうございます。</p> <p>■ゲームはこちら: <a href="https://t.co/msZNoMHzVg">https://t.co/msZNoMHzVg</a></p> <p>※2025年9月26日時点 当社調べ<br>※パッケージ版出荷数とダウンロード版販売数の合計<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SILENTHILL?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SILENTHILL</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%82%B5%E3%82%A4%E3%83%AC%E3%83%B3%E3%83%88%E3%83%92%E3%83%AB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#サイレントヒル</a> <a href="https://t.co/P6jl93zhGW">pic.twitter.com/P6jl93zhGW</a></p> <p>— SILENT HILL (@silenthill_jp) <a href="https://twitter.com/silenthill_jp/status/1972577585558433936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>People really like <em>Silent Hill f</em>, Konami’s first original mainline entry in the long-running horror series in over a decade. So I’m not shocked to see it selling so well. According to Konami, <em>Silent Hill f</em> sold a million copies in around 24 hours. <a href="https://www.konami.com/games/corporate/ja/news/topics/20250929/">In a press release announcing the news</a>, the publisher also confirmed that <em>Silent Hill f</em> was selling faster than last year’s <em>Silent Hill 2</em> remake. This is good news for <em>Silent Hill</em> fans who have spent the past decade putting up with a lot of bad news, garbage, and disappointment. Hopefully, this new era of <em>Silent Hill</em> isn’t short-lived.</p>

 <h2><strong>GOG Adds More Classic Games To Its Preservation Program&nbsp;</strong></h2> <p>Classic PC gaming store Good Old Games, aka <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/gog-preservation-program?cjdata=MXxOfDB8WX">GOG, announced recently</a> that over half a dozen more titles were being added to its ongoing preservation program. <a href="https://kotaku.com/gog-games-preservation-program-drm-1851696363">Launched in 2024</a>, the GOG Preservation Program is the store’s long-term plan to keep certain classic PC games playable, updated, and accessible. It’s a great idea and one which, if GOG sticks to it, could be extremely helpful for games that no longer have official publisher or developer support.</p>

 <p>Here’s the latest list of games added to the program, many of which are currently on sale to celebrate the news:</p> <p><em>– Gothic 1</em><br> <em>– Gothic 2</em><br> <em>– Necronomicon: The Dawning of Darkness</em><br> <em>– Mortal Kombat Trilogy</em><br> <em>– Freespace 2</em><br> <em>– XIII Century Gold Edition</em><br> <em>– Stranglehold</em></p>

 <h2><strong>Gearbox Reveals <em>Borderlands</em> <em>4</em>‘s First DLC Character&nbsp;</strong></h2>  <p>Over the weekend during Tokyo Game Show, Gearbox and 2K Games revealed the first playable DLC character coming to<em> Borderlands 4:</em> C4SH, a gambling robot cowboy built around luck and chance. <a href="https://x.com/borderlandshub/status/1972264469280559301">Fan account Borderlands 4 Bulletin shared more information</a> about the new Vault Hunter on social media directly from the Gearbox TGS panel. The studio says that C4SH will have 3 action skills just like the other playable characters and that the character’s skills are “distinctly unpredictable, as they all involve an element of chance.”</p>

 <p>C4SH will be available in Q1 2026 for all players on all platforms who own the Super Deluxe Edition of <em>Borderlands 4,</em> buy the Vault Hunter Pack DLC, or who purchase the game’s first Story Pack when it’s available.</p> <p><strong><em>Skyrim</em> Grandma Shirley Curry Retiring (Again)&nbsp;</strong></p> <p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/the-elder-scrolls/almost-90-years-old-skyrim-grandma-shirley-curry-says-shes-retiring-from-the-adventuring-life-im-tired-im-not-having-fun-anymore/">As reported by<em> PC Gamer</em>,</a> Shirley Curry, better known online as the famous <em>Skyrim</em> Grandma, is retiring from content creation. The nearly 90-year-old gamer, who will appear in <em>Elder Scrolls 6</em> when that finally launches, <a href="https://youtu.be/89L4oV-ZKqM">confirmed the news in a new VLOG uploaded to her YouTube channel.</a> She explained that she’s just “bored” with playing <em>Skyrim</em> again and isn’t having a great experience on YouTube anymore, as many of the comments she got were just, according to her, younger kids shouting about how much they loved their video game grandma. She says she wanted more feedback and interesting conversations.</p> <p>“That’s why I’m just going to stop uploading anything to do with <em>Skyrim</em>,” said Curry. “I’m tired, I’m not having fun anymore, probably because of all the little kids on there. I think that’s about all I have to say.”</p> <p>Curry will keep making VLOGS and blogging, but her days with <em>Skyrim</em> are over. Probably. It was just a year ago that Curry actually announced similar plans to retire from <em>Elder Scrolls</em> content, but then came back and even made a video of herself playing the <em>Oblivion Remaster</em>. But based on how she sounds in this new VLOG, I get the feeling she really is done with <em>Skyrim</em>.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/magic-gathering-mtg-star-trek-marvel-avengers-2026-sets-2000629313"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em> is turning into a giant <em>Fortnite</em>-like mess</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-free-to-play-game-tech-debt-ceo-discord-ps5-pc-fps-performance-2000629256"><em>Helldivers 2</em> was, at one point, planned to be a free-to-play game</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-america-3ds-satoru-shibata-2000629269">Nintendo of America’s New CEO Seems Fun</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch This:</h2>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/leaked-ps5-model-shiny-black-plastic-fingerprints-borderlands-4-silent-hill-2000629868]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>