<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:32:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Looks Like Another Impressive Switch 2 Port From Ubisoft]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-impressive-switch-2-port-ubisoft-december-2000638603</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-looks-like-another-impressive-switch-2-port-from-ubisoft.1333027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>One of the worst-kept secrets of 2025 has finally been officially announced by Ubisoft.<a href="https://kotaku.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows"><em> Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a>, the latest entry in the publisher’s sneaky-stabby series of open-world games, is getting a Switch 2 port later this year.</p> <p>On October 23, <a href="https://youtu.be/OzyD_EFZzgc">Ubisoft officially revealed</a> that <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> is coming to the Nintendo Switch 2 on December 2. This version of the game will support full cross progression across all platforms and will also feature touchscreen support for all in-game menus, though you’ll be able to use a controller, too. The recently released expansion for <em>AC Shadows</em>, <em>Claws of Awaji</em>, won’t be available for Switch 2 players until “early next year.”</p>

 <p>Here’s the first trailer for the Switch 2 port of <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows,</em> which appears to show a seemingly impressive-looking port of the massive and <a href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-graphics-seasons-screenshots-1851770252">gorgeous open-world game</a> set in feudal Japan.</p>  <p>“We are delighted to bring <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> to Nintendo players,” said <em>AC Shadows</em> director Charles Benoit in a press release announcing the port. “Whether slipping through the shadows as Naoe or facing foes head-on as Yasuke, players will be able to roam the streets and rooftops of feudal Japan at home or anywhere their journey takes them on Nintendo Switch 2.”</p>

 <p>Ubisoft’s incredible-looking and playing <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-patch-is-it-good-2000624465">Switch 2 port of<em> Star Wars Outlaws</em> earlier this year</a> showed that the company can bring its high-end blockbusters to Nintendo’s less-powerful hardware while still making sure the games look great. And this first trailer for <em>Shadows</em> running on Switch 2 looks equally impressive, with lots of detail and realistic lighting. Sure, it’s not as sharp as <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> running on a PS5 Pro connected to a 4K TV, but I bet it will look fine on the Switch 2’s smaller screen.</p> <p>Of course, <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> arriving on Switch 2 isn’t exactly a surprise. <a href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-switch-2-preorder-release-date-2000634141">The game was leaked earlier this month</a> following months of rumors. Still, it’s nice to have it officially announced, and it’s great that more people will have a chance to check out what I think is one of Ubisoft’s best games in a long time.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-impressive-switch-2-port-ubisoft-december-2000638603]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker’s Soundcore Select 4 Go Speaker Is Practically a Steal After Dropping to an All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/listen-to-music-anywhere-even-your-shower-with-the-soundcore-select-4-go-for-31-off-2000638281</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anker%E2%80%99s-soundcore-select-4-go-speaker-is-practically-a-steal-after-dropping-to-an-all-time-low.1333024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s a little early for holiday shopping, but honestly, that’s what makes it the best time for holiday shopping. Get all your gifts picked out ahead of time so you can enjoy the season building up to the special day. You won’t have to rush around trying to find something for everyone or paying a bunch of extra money on expedited shipping because you waited until the last minute. Plus, you can find some great stuff on sale right now. For instance, check out this Bluetooth speaker by Soundcore, a brand from Anker.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4954/"> The Soundcore Select 4 Go normally sells for $35, but right now Amazon has it for 31% off. That shaves $11 off the price so you can get it for just $24.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4954/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Take It in the Shower</h2>
<p>This Soundcore Bluetooth speaker is a speaker you can take anywhere. It’s IP67 waterproof and dustproof, meaning it can withstand harsh outdoor conditions. It’s designed to able to handle being immersed in water up to 3.3 feet deep for up to a half hour. Strap it to a paddle board or kayak without fear of it falling in and getting damaged. Heck, you can even hang it up in your shower so you can listen and sing along to your favorite music. We all know the acoustics sound best in there, maybe you can even hit the high notes of “Golden” by Huntr/x from <em>K-Pop Demon Hunters</em>.</p>
<p>This speaker has a solid battery life. You can enjoy a listening time of up to 20 hours non-stop on a single charge. Great for taking on a camping trip where you won’t be able to recharge it again after each use.</p>



<p>Each Soundcore Select 4 Go has a little strap on the end of it so you can easily adhere it to you bag, back of your beach chair. or really anything you can imagine. Get the speaker up off the ground or table so everyone can enjoy it better.</p>
<p>If you have more than one Soundcore Bluetooth speaker, you can enable true wireless stereo. Your Soundcore Select 4 Go can be paired with a second Soundcore speaker so you can have each serve as either the left or right output. Pair them using the Soundcore smartphone app.</p>
<p>The Soundcore Select 4 Go is available in several different choices of colors.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4954/"> All of which happen to be on sale, going for between $24 and $26 for a limited time</a>. Get the blue, purple with yellow, or white with red speaker for just $24, the black for just $25, or the green or white for just $26.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4954/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/listen-to-music-anywhere-even-your-shower-with-the-soundcore-select-4-go-for-31-off-2000638281]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders Gunning For The Best Racer Of 2025: ‘I’ve Thrown Everything I Have Into This Game’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-gunning-for-the-best-racer-of-2025-ive-thrown-everything-i-have-into-this-game-2000638593</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-air-riders-gunning-for-the-best-racer-of-2025-%E2%80%98i%E2%80%99ve-thrown-everything-i-have-into-this-game%E2%80%99.1333021/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Even in a packed year for kart racers, <a href="https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-switch-2-release-date-nintendo-direct-trailer-2000618410"><em>Kirby Air Riders</em></a> is playing for keeps. Will it earn a place alongside <a href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-free-roam-open-world-burnout-paradise-1851776569"><em>Mario Kart World</em></a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-crossover-review-hatsune-miku-2000626583"><em>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds</em></a>? Director Masahiro Sakurai hopes so. The legendary developer said he doesn’t plan on continuing the series; the upcoming Switch 2 exclusive is a one-and-done. “I’ve thrown everything I have into this game,” he said during its latest livestream preview. He certainly has. Just when you thought you knew everything<em> Kirby Air Riders</em> has to offer, Sakurai announces even more modes, characters, and features, including a roguelike adventure called Road Trip.</p> <p>In a second hour-long <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_ZHYjYHHiBM">Direct-style presentation for <em>Kirby Air Riders</em></a> that went live on Thursday, the famed<em> Smash Bros. Ultimate</em> director reminded fans why he’s the king of content maximalism. If you thought Nintendo’s latest racing game, out November 20, would be just a racing game with a sandbox mode, you would be sorely mistaken, my pink, puffy friend. Some are already calling it the “<a href="https://x.com/TAHK0/status/1981361888173969671">Kirby game of all Kirby games</a>.”</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sorry to break the order of my reporting of the Kirby Air Riders Direct, but I needed to share Sakurai's closing speech because what a guy! He is a masterclass in game development. <a href="https://t.co/ngXoBgcj4X">pic.twitter.com/ngXoBgcj4X</a></p> <p>— Kābī (@KirPinkFury) <a href="https://twitter.com/KirPinkFury/status/1981362564576551304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>This is far from the full list of newly revealed features players will get to mess around with:</p> <ul> <li>Top-down camera view race mode called Top Ride</li> <li>Roguelike mode with random challenges from other modes and unique story beats called Road Trip</li> <li>Match lobby called Paddock where you can interact and move between different online races</li> <li>Variant of Air Ride called Swap Relay where you change machines every lap</li> <li>Machine that can switch configurations called Transform Star</li> <li>Set of achievements called Checklist that lets you chase unlockables throughout the game</li> <li>Global Win Power shows how many times you’ve won in addition to your online class ranking</li> <li>Custom licenses to show off your personality online</li> <li>Boss battles</li> <li>Expanded roster including the spider Taranza, wily duo Lololo &amp; Lalala, the bug-eyed Marx, and others</li> </ul> <h2><em>Kirby Air Riders</em> feels like a direct attack on <em>Mario Kart World</em></h2> <p>Like I said, this is an incomplete and abridged rundown of all of the gameplay elements Sakurai dove into during the latest and likely final preview of <em>Kirby Air Riders</em> ahead of release. He also mentioned how players will earn miles by playing that are spent to unlock more parts of the Machine Market to outfit your ride. Plus there are new collectibles called Gummies. They sound a bit like the stickers from <em>Smash Bros. Ultimate</em>. “Who knows, maybe you’ll become a Gummillionaire!” Nintendo’s words, not mine.</p>

 <p>But wait, there’s still more! <em>Kibry Air Riders</em> is also getting dedicated amiibo figures. There are three, all launching next year starting on March 5 with Meta Knight &amp; Shadow Star, followed later on by King Dedede &amp; Tank Star and Chef Kawasaki &amp; Hop Star. Like the new amiibo Nintendo’s been rolling out, these are bigger, more complex, and will likely have those bigger $30 price tags to match. Has Nintendo given Sakurai a blank check to do whatever he wants with <em>Kirby Air Riders</em> before he makes the next <em>Smash Bros.</em>? Probably.</p> <p>We’ll see how it all adds up in practice, but on paper at least, the game is certainly shaping up to satiate even the most ravenous fans’ demands in a way the somewhat content-lite <em>Mario Kart World</em> maybe didn’t when it debuted back over the summer. “Just so you know, we’re not planning DLC, everything is here,” Sakurai said of <em>Kirby Air Riders</em>. Ouch! Switch Online subscribers can try the game for free during Global Test Ride events on Nov. 8-9 and Nov. 15-16.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kirby-air-riders-gunning-for-the-best-racer-of-2025-ive-thrown-everything-i-have-into-this-game-2000638593]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s 50″ Fire TV With Soundbar Combo Hits Record Low, It’s Cheaper Than Buying the TV Alone]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-50-fire-tv-comes-with-a-soundbar-and-is-160-off-2000637805</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon%E2%80%99s-50%E2%80%B3-fire-tv-with-soundbar-combo-hits-record-low-it%E2%80%99s-cheaper-than-buying-the-tv-alone.1332967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If you’re kicking yourself still for not jumping on any of the deals from a couple weeks ago over at Amazon for Prime Big Deals Day, something wonderful just dropped into your lap. Right now, Amazon has one of its Fire TVs on sale for 31% off. And this isn’t a Fire TV Stick, this is a full 50-inch TV with a Fire TV interface.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4953/"> That discount brings the price down from $520 to just $360, saving you a whole $160</a>. <strong>If that’s not enough to get you excited, it also includes a free Fire TV Soundbar.</strong> Those start around at least $100 and it’s bundled here for no extra charge.</p>
<p>The Amazon smart TV measures across at 50-inches making for a pretty sizable display for a living room, den, or any shared space really. This is the 4-series model from 2024. It supports vivid 4K entertainment withy HDR10, HLG, and Dolby Digital Plus which all work together to make an impressive picture for your enjoyment with clear clarity and bright colors.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4953/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>As an Amazon smart TV, this comes with an Alexa-enabled remote. The Alexa remote is a complete gamechanger when it comes to browsing for content. Those on-screen keypads can be so cumbersome to type on. Every app lays them out differently, with some being in alphabetical order and others following the popularized QWERTY layout. And all you have in the little directional pad to hop over one letter at a time. That can take forever to type out a long title like “<em>Only Murders in the Building</em>.” Sweat not, because with the Alexa remote, you can just hold the button and speak the title aloud, then be brought right to it.</p>



<h2>Fire TV Soundbar Included</h2>
<p>TV speakers have gotten better and better over the years, but they’re still no comparison to a dedicated surround sound system or sound bar. What a treat it is that this TV comes with its own soundbar free of charge. This can be set right in front of your TV on top of your media center so you can enjoy rich, three-dimensional virtual surround sound. It supports DTS Virtual:X and even more detail with Dolby Audio. It’s easy to set up too. Just plug it into the TV with the included HDMI cable to the HDMI eARC/ARC on the TV. Presto, now the soundbar will work just like that.</p>
<p>The TV has three additional HDMI ports along with that HDMI eARC/ARC port so you can connect to a cable box or multiple gaming consoles if you wish.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4953/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-50-fire-tv-comes-with-a-soundbar-and-is-160-off-2000637805]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govee LED Wall Light Bars (6-Pack) Drop to Lowest Price Yet, Each One Costs Less Than $10]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bring-some-light-into-your-space-with-these-gove-led-wall-lights-for-29-off-2000637778</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/govee-led-wall-light-bars-6-pack-drop-to-lowest-price-yet-each-one-costs-less-than-10.1332916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>An easy way to breathe new life into a space is with lighting. You don’t need to swap out any furniture or rugs or anything like that. Simply adjusting where the light is coming from, how intense it is, and even the color can completely change how it feels to be in a room. A nice bright cool white for when doing chores like vacuuming or sweeping, a warmer soft white for when relaxing with a book, or vibrant colors that change on dime when jamming to some music or games — this is what’s possible with a set of Govee LED wall lights. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4952/">These RGBIC wall lights from Govee happen to be on sale at the moment.</a></p>
<p>Get a six-pack for 29% off. That brings the price down from $70 to just $50 for a limited time, saving you a whole $20. Additionally, in case you want to go all out with your lighting setup, you can snag the 14-pack on sale too. That one is normally $180, but the discounts brings the pack down by $40 to just $140. The six-piece set contains two panels which are constructed of three light sections each while the 14-piece set contains seven panels which are constructed of two light sections each. Each piece just plugs into the next and then the last can be connected to an outlet to power.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4952/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Each wall LED light measures 16 inches long and can display 16 million different colors. The color combinations are practically endless. Each light bar can be mounted to your wall easily. Get creative, choosing to hang the light bars at varied angles or heights.</p>
<p>You control your Govee wall lights using the smart app available for iPhone and Android. From there, you can select between over 64 dynamic scene modes with multi-color effects. The app can be connected with Google Home or Alexa so you can control it with your voice or as part of other routines you have set up with different smart devices.</p>



<h2>Music Mode</h2>
<p>The real show here is what you can do with music. These LED wall lights are able to synchronize to your music using the Govee Home App. It includes 11 versatile music modes that pair with the audio playing through to make for a more immersive listening experience.</p>
<p>For a limited time, you can save quite a bit on these Govee LED wall lights. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4952/">Get the two-panels set for just $50 or the seven panel set for just $140 before the prices go back up.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4952/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bring-some-light-into-your-space-with-these-gove-led-wall-lights-for-29-off-2000637778]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>