<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 18:48:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In This Stunning Metroidvania, You’re Only Held Back By Your Own Imagination]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ooo-review-metroidvania-puzzle-platformer-nama-takahashi-2000616880</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-this-stunning-metroidvania-you%E2%80%99re-only-held-back-by-your-own-imagination.1267341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A piece of art for Ooo.</span> © Nama Takahashi / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p>The traditional Metroidvania format works something like this: As you gain new abilities, you gain access to new areas. That platform up there that’s completely unreachable? Come back when you’ve gained double-jump. That sort of thing. <em>Öoo</em> follows the same formula, except when you return to those previously explored levels, you realize that it was only your own imagination holding you back. The magic was in your heart all along.</p> <p><em>Öoo</em> is a puzzle-platformer in which you play a little Kawaii caterpillar whose body segments are made of bombs. At the start of the game you’re just the head, able to move left and right, and that’s it. To jump, Öoo (I’m assuming that’s its name) needs to plop down a bomb and sit on top when it explodes. To jump a gap to the right, put down a bomb and stand on its right side when you explode it. That reasonably simple concept is how you begin exploring an ever-growing map, occasionally picking up yellow fly-like creatures and delivering them to large frogs that are blocking your way so you can proceed. And this all works tremendously well! It’s a novel concept for a platform game, one in which jumping is all about explosions, and you figure out new, inventive ways to use this technique as the puzzles demand it from you. It then gets even more interesting when it adds a second bomb. As is often the case with games like this, if that sounds like your jam, I strongly suggest you stop reading now and go buy it. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2721890/oo/">It’s only $8</a>, and it’s one of my favorite games of the year. The rest of this piece is to convince everyone else of its genius, but also gives the reader a <em>bit</em> more information than I had when I started playing, after completing its stunning demo earlier in the year.</p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Öooo - Official Short Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jXQmJBsrciI?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>So, you place a bomb with A (and by default are left sitting on top of it) and explode it with X. Place two bombs and then X will explode each in the order you placed them. Put two on top of each other with you sitting at the top and you’ve got a sort of double-jump. Sit on one while the other blows you sideways…well, this is the sort of stuff you need to figure out.</p>

 <p>When the <a href="https://buried-treasure.org/2025/06/next-fest-june-2025s-buried-treasures/"><em>Öoo </em>demo came out earlier this year</a>, it suggested that a second bomb was something you got very early on in the game, which may have led some to suspect that a third and a fourth would be arriving soon after. I’m rather pleased to report that’s not actually the case, or I suspect what has proven to be one of the most meticulously crafted puzzle-platformers I’ve ever played might have become too woefully complicated. While there’s great appeal in sandbox experimentation with four different bombs exploding in order, to discern the one desired combination for a puzzle solution would have been deeply demoralizing. Sticking to two, but having so much imagination for how they can be used in ever-more interesting ways, demonstrates an awful lot of smarts. In fact, you have just two until the very end of the game, but you’ll never stop learning new ways to use them.</p> <p>And this is the key. If this were a game about getting more and more bomb segments, or even being given fresh new abilities with which they interact, then you’d have something like a traditional Metroidvania. But it isn’t and you aren’t. You get that second bomb about half an hour into the game, and then that’s your lot. So why is it that <em>Öoo</em> still plays like a Metroidvania? Because it’s just so utterly, brilliantly designed.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000616906" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000616906"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000616906">©Nama Takahashi / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Almost from the start, you’ll encounter areas you can’t yet reach. You then play on in another direction, with the gradual introduction of increasingly complex puzzles causing you to think more inventively about your tools and how you can use them. At a certain point, rather than being able to carry on any further, you’ll reach a dead end in one of the game’s occasional teleport rooms, and you’re just left with the option to jump back to a part of the map where you can see an incomplete path. It’ll be one of those areas you couldn’t reach yet. Except, well, now you can. Not because you have a new skill, but because now you can think differently about how to approach the puzzle. And I’ve never experienced anything like this before. It’s quite extraordinary!</p>

 <p>Gosh, that was a long and necessary route to make that one point, so let’s move on to what else makes <em>Öoo</em> such a great game. This is a follow-up to developer Nama Takahashi’s&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/elechead-switch-steam-good-bad-ending-collectibles-1849158240"><em>ElecHead</em></a>, itself a wonderful platform-puzzler, and shares its retro aesthetic, albeit now with a more vibrant color palette. Gorgeous looping animations mean the levels feel buoyant, and Öoo itself is bursting with character, complete with falling asleep and snoring when left idle. And let’s not put aside that the game is called <em>Öoo</em> because that’s exactly what the character looks like.</p> <p>Another hugely important aspect of <em>Öoo</em> is that it has no interest in wasting your time. To solve puzzles you need to experiment, and to do that, you need to take risks. There are a bunch of ways to die, but there’s no significant penalty. Checkpoint flags are everywhere, meaning you’re never forced to mindlessly retrace your steps. The only times you might be more than a screen away are when there’d otherwise not be a means to backtrack–which is to say, everything’s been thought of, and you won’t be infuriatingly trapped. Should you become completely flummoxed by a puzzle, however, Takahashi has recorded <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8PA3w0GnpAo">a video of his completing the entire game</a>, which you can easily scrub to find where you’re currently stuck. At which point you will put your head in your hands and lament your folly for not having figured it out for yourself. Because, as I’ve said, this game gives you everything you need right from the start.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000616907" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000616907"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000616907">©Nama Takahashi / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Worry not when you see that walkthrough video is only 45 minutes long. This is the creator of the game, and in real life you’ll be easily spending at least three or four hours before you’ll reach the end credits. And what a splendid few hours it is! This is such a delightful game, and so wonderfully intelligent in its creation.</p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2721890/oo/"><em>Öoo</em> is out now on PC for $8</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ooo-review-metroidvania-puzzle-platformer-nama-takahashi-2000616880]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can’t Swim In Mafia: The Old Country And That’s Fine]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-old-country-swimming-open-world-baldurs-gate-2000616867</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can%E2%80%99t-swim-in-mafia-the-old-country-and-that%E2%80%99s-fine.1267320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-old-country-reviews-metacritic-roundup-ps5-2000616275"><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> </a>is set on the island of Sicily. Despite your proximity to the Mediterranean, however, there’s no swimming in the latest, not-quite-open-world gangster game. A clip showing the new blockbuster’s lack of “swimming physics” quickly blew up on social media, spurring a debate about whether <em>The Old Country</em> cuts corners. In actuality, I wish more games were fine with cutting junk that doesn’t matter.</p> <p>Swimming is one of the ways an open-world game proves just how premium and expensive it is. Falling in water meant instant death in <em>Infamous 1</em> and <em>2</em>, while in <em>Second Son</em> it merely returned you to the last hard surface you were standing on. But in <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em>, light swimming mechanics became part of exploring the world. You couldn’t swim in <em>Grand Theft Auto</em> until <em>San Andreas</em>. One of the more controversial aspects of <em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em> and <em>Tears of the Kingdom</em> games is that, while you can swim on the surface of the water, you can’t dive underneath like in previous games.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">In case you were wondering, Mafia: The Old Country doesn't have swimming physics just like previous Mafia Games <a href="https://t.co/oUA13X64Q1">pic.twitter.com/oUA13X64Q1</a></p> <p>— NikTek (@NikTekOfficial) <a href="https://twitter.com/NikTekOfficial/status/1953894404588179783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Swimming was never a thing in the <em>Mafia</em> games <a href="https://kotaku.com/how-the-makers-of-mafia-iii-lost-their-way-1825242177">until <em>Mafia 3</em></a>, which took place in a canal- and swamp-filled version of New Orleans called New Bordeaux. So it might have made sense to expect that to remain part of the feature set in <em>The Old Country</em>. But the new game is also more streamlined, focusing on its characters, missions, and world rather than on the kind of sandbox bloat that can be fun to mess around with but ultimately doesn’t add a ton to the overall experience. <em>The Old Country</em> is $50 and only 12 hours long. To some that’s a raw deal. But for advocates of quicker, cheaper, more sustainable game development, it seems like the perfect antidote to <a href="https://kotaku.com/former-sony-exec-calls-for-shorter-games-that-are-cheap-1844150846">a lot of the big-budget excess</a> that weighs down so many other projects. So, instead of letting you spear fish or dive for treasure, <em>The Old Country</em> warps you back to land anytime you fall in deep water.</p>

 <p>“This reminds me of when we showed <em>BG3</em> to someone (exec or whatever)–a wealth of mechanics–and with zero emotion he just goes ‘can you swim in the game?’ Like bro this isn’t mechanical whack-a-mole, endlessly layering on mechanics maketh a good game not,” Larian Studios publishing director Michael “Cromwelp” Douse <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/1954131668215693599">wrote on X</a> in response to the debate over <em>Old Country</em>‘s old-school swimming band-aid. “The realities of game design are such that each feature has a cost. Manpower-&gt; time-&gt; budget. ‘Why not just[…]’ can set a producer on fire. Try it, its funny. Better to not swim if you’re not going to do anything with it, than to add it simply to have it.”</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Engagement baiters show invisible walls and "no swimming" but conveniently they forgot to show areas where the need to swim was thought of, and very obviously decided against. Many other games teleport you back to the shore and no one is complaining. <a href="https://t.co/HRfJiU5ARE">pic.twitter.com/HRfJiU5ARE</a></p> <p>— Silent (@__silent_) <a href="https://twitter.com/__silent_/status/1954547676625641537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Douse pointed to day-and-night cycles as another example. While occasionally pretty and immersive, most games don’t actually do much with them, like change how characters act at night or what enemies you might face. It’s one of those back-of-the-box bullet points that can get wheeled out in pitch meetings to impress a publisher but can end up leading to more headaches and a less focused game in the long run.</p> <p>“I feel like I’m aging out of the gaming sphere because I see this and ask myself ‘Does this game even need a swimming? Should dev time be devoted to it’ and people in the comments are saying ‘This is unacceptable for a 2025 game’ Idk I just don’t think games need every mechanic,” read <a href="https://x.com/Actually_Tina/status/1954232748044112165">one viral response</a> to the swimming debate from X user ActuallyTina. “I would much rather devs spend time on mechanics that actually engagement the player a lot then a big empty world with nothing in it or swimming that is just there because idk its 2025 and you need swimming.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mafia-4-old-country-swimming-open-world-baldurs-gate-2000616867]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warner Bros. Is On A Box Office Hot Streak Unlike Anything We’ve Seen Before]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wb-warner-bros-streak-weapons-box-office-record-opening-weekend-minecraft-2000616900</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warner-bros-is-on-a-box-office-hot-streak-unlike-anything-we%E2%80%99ve-seen-before.1267275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>Over the weekend, <em>Weapons</em> made a killing at the box office, opening with an impressive $42 million and in the process helping movie studio <a href="https://kotaku.com/wb-warner-bros-discovery-split-hbo-max-ceo-david-zaslav-1851784086">Warner Bros.</a> do something no other studio or distributor has done before in history.</p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/video-game-cases-loose-discs-bf6-resident-evil-persona-spider-man-news-2000616874#:~:text=Weapons%20Director%20Says%20His%20Resident%20Evil%20Movie%20Will%20Be%20Weird">Zach Cregger’s latest horror film, <em>Weapons</em></a>, tells the story of a group of kids who all left their homes in the middle of the night and never returned. The strange and creepy movie has received high praise from critics, with a 95% on Rotten Tomatoes. And that certainly helped <em>Weapons</em>, with a budget of only $38 million, draw in a ton of people over the August 8th weekend, beating out<em> Fantastic Four</em> and <em>Freakier Friday</em>, two Disney-produced flicks. This is now the sixth film in a row from WB to pull off a $40-million-or-more opening weekend at the box office.</p> <p><a href="https://editorial.rottentomatoes.com/article/weekend-box-office-weapons-racks-up-another-big-win-for-warner-bros/">As reported by Rotten Tomatoes</a>, this is apparently the first time a movie studio has ever been on such a hot streak. It all started with <a href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345"><em>A Minecraft Movie</em></a> in April. Since then, WB has been on an impressive and historic box office run. Here’s the full breakdown of each movie the studio has released and how much it made during opening weekend:</p> <ul> <li><em>A Minecraft Movie</em> – April – $162 million</li> <li><em>Sinners – April</em> – $48 million</li> <li><em>Final Destination: Bloodlines</em> – $51 million</li> <li><em>F1</em> – $51 million</li> <li><em>Superman</em> – $125 million</li> <li><em>Weapons</em> – $42 million</li> </ul> <p>Making this streak all the more impressive is that half of these are original movies, not sequels, reboots, or spin-offs. This seems to fly in the face of how Hollywood has operated over the last decade, where at times it’s felt as if nearly every movie is some kind of continuation of an existing franchise. Warner Bros., on the other hand, seems to be spreading out its budget across new ideas as well as making IP plays, like <em>Minecraft</em> and its <em>Final Destination </em>reboot.&nbsp; It’s a strategy that’s working. Oh, and <em>Weapons</em> also marks the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/boxoffice/comments/1mmlqv4/wb_is_having_quite_the_year_weapons_is_the/">seventh film in 2025 from Warner Bros. to open at number one</a> at the domestic box office, which is also a first for a movie studio as far as I can tell. (<a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/release/rl2465301249/?ref_=bo_wey_table_28"><em>Mickey 17</em></a> wasn’t a huge hit for WB, but it did open at number one during the first weekend of March.)</p> <p>Will this streak continue? Maybe. WB’s next big movie to hit theaters is <em>The Conjuring: Last Rites</em> on September 5. This likely won’t win over critics like <em>Sinners</em> and <em>Weapons </em>did, but the franchise has been a consistent moneymaker for the studio, and horror flicks are hotter than ever right now. So it’s possible that both of WB’s historic streaks at the box office continue. Meanwhile, you have to imagine execs at Disney, MGM, and Sony are watching closely and looking at their upcoming projects to see if they need to inject a bit more originality into their future film slates.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wb-warner-bros-streak-weapons-box-office-record-opening-weekend-minecraft-2000616900]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Umamusume Fans Tried To Pay Tribute To Recently Deceased Racehorse, But It Didn’t Go As Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/umamusume-pretty-derby-grass-wonder-death-tribute-art-2000616912</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/umamusume-fans-tried-to-pay-tribute-to-recently-deceased-racehorse-but-it-didn%E2%80%99t-go-as-planned.1267245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><span>On August 8, Grass Wonder, a real-world racehorse which gacha game </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/umamusume-pretty-derby-horse-girl-gacha-game-ludwig-1851785849"><i><span>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</span></i></a> <span>based one of its anime horse girls on, died at the age of 30. According to </span><a href="https://www.bigredfarm.jp/post/%E3%82%B0%E3%83%A9%E3%82%B9%E3%83%AF%E3%83%B3%E3%83%80%E3%83%BC-%E6%AD%BB%E5%8E%BB"><span>the official obituary</span></a><span>, the horse (who is male in real life) passed due to multiple organ failure. The official </span><i><span>Umamusume</span></i><span> social media accounts </span><a href="https://x.com/uma_musu/status/1953773211667009804"><span>paid tribute to Grass Wonder</span></a><span> upon news of his death, and fans decided to pay tribute to the horse through </span><a href="https://x.com/Neshaa_3450/status/1954207604743254457"><span>a piece of pixel art</span></a><span> on </span><a href="https://wplace.live/"><span>Wplace</span></a><span>, a world map that users can paint and collaborate on. However, things nearly went awry when fans realized the art they were attempting to recreate was AI-generated, until the community rallied to change things up and pay a more honest tribute to Grass Wonder.</span></p> <p><span>If you’ve never heard of Wplace, it’s an interactive world map that lets you paint over any location, and people use it to create some pretty incredible digital art. It’s a living canvas that anyone can draw on, and that includes making a tribute to race horses who are no longer with us. A group of Umamusume fans started creating a piece on the map around Dolores, Quezon in the Philippines, where many of the organizing fans are based. The artwork depicts Grass Wonder walking through a field with a bouquet of sunflowers in hand. The text “Farewell, Grass Wonder” is shown above her in a blue sky. While it’s a lovely gesture, the group project got a bit more complicated when it was discovered that the original reference art </span><a href="https://x.com/scalizo_art/status/1954353052322058262"><span>was AI-generated</span></a><span>.</span></p> <p><span>The project began on a </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/kabayongbabaepilipinas"><span>Philippine</span></a> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/kabayongbabaepilipinas"><span>Facebook fan page</span></a><span>, and once people realized the original artwork was AI slop, the group’s admin </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/kabayongbabaepilipinas/posts/1427845951603157/"><span>put out an apology statement</span></a><span>.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Message of the admin from the group of where the collaboration idea started! </p> <p>Truly, I apologize on behalf of the group alongside the admins. </p> <p>This wasn't meant to trick people, we genuinely wanted a community that works together. </p> <p>Again,I apologize. I hope everyone gets along <a href="https://t.co/wmSdYQA2sY">https://t.co/wmSdYQA2sY</a> <a href="https://t.co/mnVAZebZ1g">pic.twitter.com/mnVAZebZ1g</a></p> <p>— Neeshaaaaaa~ (@Neshaa_3450) <a href="https://twitter.com/Neshaa_3450/status/1954497350204113250?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Following this, the group consulted artists to help finish the project, and added more recognizable features to the final piece to pay a better tribute to Grass Wonder, including her armband, hair tie, and patterns on her skirt.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The initial group responsible for the startup of the project has contacted an actual artist regarding adding details, and here's he finished version! <a href="https://t.co/E0l95o9iMp">pic.twitter.com/E0l95o9iMp</a></p> <p>— Neeshaaaaaa~ (@Neshaa_3450) <a href="https://twitter.com/Neshaa_3450/status/1954525295782035773?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>While I’m sure everyone would rather that the final image not have AI-generated origins, at the very least, fans were able to give it a human touch. Grass Wonder is one of 114 playable horse girls in</span><i><span> Umamusume</span></i><span>, each of which you train to race in a run-based, almost rogue-like fashion. The game originally launched in Japan in 2021 before rolling out in other Asian territories over the following years. </span><i><span>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</span></i><span> finally launched worldwide back in June, and has </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/umamusume-pretty-derby-horse-girl-stable-guidelines-1851786102"><span>become a viral sensation</span></a><span> after big streamers like Ludwig and Northern Lion played it on their channels.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/umamusume-pretty-derby-grass-wonder-death-tribute-art-2000616912]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything You Need To Know About Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/puyo-puyo-tetris-2s-switch-2-mouse-mode-game-key-card-2000616902</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-you-need-to-know-about-puyo-puyo-tetris-2s.1267224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <div id="ez-toc-container">

<nav><ul><li><a href="#how-long-does-it-take-to-beat-puyo-puyo-tetris-2s%e2%80%98s-adventure-mode" title="How long does it take to beat Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S‘s Adventure Mode?">How long does it take to beat Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S‘s Adventure Mode?</a></li><li><a href="#how-well-does-mouse-mode-work-on-puyo-puyo-tertris-2s" title="How well does mouse mode work on Puyo Puyo Tertris 2S?">How well does mouse mode work on Puyo Puyo Tertris 2S?</a></li><li><a href="#puyo-puyo-tetris-2s%e2%80%99-physical-version-comes-on-a-gamekey-card" title="Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S’ physical version comes on a Game-Key Card">Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S’ physical version comes on a Game-Key Card</a></li></ul></nav></div>
<p>The<i> Puyo Puyo Tetris</i> series combines two classic puzzle franchises into a single fun and vibrant experience, and it tends to be a pretty damn good time. With the Nintendo Switch 2 now out in the wild, fans of the series can get their hands on <i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i>, an enhanced version of 2020’s <i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2</i>. You can tell it’s enhanced because of the “S”, which is the universal way to know something is extra cool, I think.</p> <p>Anyway, this new version of the game brings a variety of upgrades and new features, such as the new 2v2 Doubles Mode, a bunch of additional characters, and even mouse controls. But if you’re a diehard fan, you’ll probably be checking out the Adventure Mode, which sends you off on a journey across an overworld map to compete against foes for some puzzle mayhem. How long will you spend seeing things through? How does its mouse mode work? And what should you consider before grabbing a physical version? Let’s take a look.</p> <h2><span id="how-long-does-it-take-to-beat-puyo-puyo-tetris-2s%e2%80%98s-adventure-mode"></span>How long does it take to beat <i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i>‘s Adventure Mode?<span></span></h2> <p>So, let’s get something out of the way: <i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i> is a puzzle game with endless replayability, so how many hours of fun you get out of it will be based on how much you enjoy <i>Puyo Puyo</i> and <i>Tetris</i>. However, the Adventure Mode tells a story with missions to tackle, speaking more to folks who like a campaign to tackle. And that campaign is finite, naturally.</p>

 <p><b>Simply reaching the end of </b><b><i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i></b><b>‘s Adventure Mode can take 10-15 hours</b>, depending on your skill level. But you can stretch things out much further by trying to tackle every optional mission and side story the game has to offer. Additionally, completionists will want to aim to get a full four-star rating on every mission to show they know their shit. Not me, though, because I’m equally dreadful at <i>Puyo Puyo</i> and <i>Tetris</i>.</p> <p>Speaking of being bad at puzzle games, you can mess with the difficulty to help set you up for success if you’re not making any headway in the campaign. I don’t feel much shame admitting that I’m just not very fast or good at stacking all this colorful stuff, and neither should you.</p> <h2><span id="how-well-does-mouse-mode-work-on-puyo-puyo-tertris-2s"></span>How well does mouse mode work on <i>Puyo Puyo Tertris 2S</i>?<span></span></h2> <p>Not only does the <i>2S</i> version of this game toss in the 2v2 Doubles Mode, it also allows you to use the Switch’s “mouse mode” to move your blocks around. In this mode you’ll use your shoulder button to rotate the block, while pulling down with the mouse will accelerate how fast the block falls. While this adds a level of physicality you might otherwise not expect in <i>Tetris</i>, it can be a challenge to pull the mouse down in a perfectly straight line, so don’t be surprised if the blocks land a little to the left or right when using this mode.</p>

 <h2><span id="puyo-puyo-tetris-2s%e2%80%99-physical-version-comes-on-a-gamekey-card"></span><i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i>’ physical version comes on a Game-Key Card<span></span></h2> <p>If you were hoping to grab a physical copy of this game, you should know that you’ll still need to download the full game with an internet connection. The card that ships in the case is only a key for a license to download the game and doesn’t have the full data available for you to play.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-survey-game-key-carts-2000614465">Switch 2 Owners Are Leaping On A Survey To Express Fury Over Game Key Cards</a></p> <p>On the flip side, you can still share or resell this Game-Key card, which you can’t do with a “digital” version. <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-survey-game-key-carts-2000614465">Game-Key cards are an ongoing frustration</a> for Switch 2 fans, and <i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S </i>is no exception.</p> <hr> <p><i>Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</i> is available now on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/puyo-puyo-tetris-2s-switch-2-mouse-mode-game-key-card-2000616902]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World: What Are The Best Karts And Tracks For Donkey Kong?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-switch-2-donkey-kong-karts-2000616894</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-what-are-the-best-karts-and-tracks-for-donkey-kong.1267221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <div id="ez-toc-container">

<nav><ul><li><a href="#how-to-unlock-donkey-kong-in-mario-kart-world" title="How to Unlock Donkey Kong in Mario Kart World">How to Unlock Donkey Kong in Mario Kart World</a></li><li><a href="#which-karts-are-best-for-donkey-kong" title="Which karts are best for Donkey Kong?">Which karts are best for Donkey Kong?</a></li><li><a href="#donkey-kong-unlockable-costumes" title="Donkey Kong Unlockable Costumes">Donkey Kong Unlockable Costumes</a></li><li><a href="#what-tracks-favor-donkey-kong" title="What tracks favor Donkey Kong?">What tracks favor Donkey Kong?</a></li></ul></nav></div>
<p>He’s the leader of the bunch, you know him well, but where is Donkey Kong in the roster of <i>Mario Kart World</i>? When you load up the game and try to find the newly-redesigned DK, you may be disappointed to not be able to find him. Luckily, you can find him without too much trouble! Here’s what you need to know to unlock Donkey Kong in <i>Mario Kart World</i>, which tracks he’s best on, and what karts you should use when playing as him.</p> <h2><span id="how-to-unlock-donkey-kong-in-mario-kart-world"></span>How to Unlock Donkey Kong in Mario Kart World<span></span></h2> <p>To unlock Donkey Kong, you only need to complete the Mushroom Cup in the Grand Prix mode. It might seem like a massive oversight to not have Donkey Kong unlock for completing the Banana Cup, but considering the Mushroom Cup culminates in the track DK Spaceport, it’s a good place to find him.</p> <p>Placement is irrelevant here; you only need to complete the grand prix to qualify. Whether you end up in first place or 24th, you’ll be able to add DK to your playable roster. You might want to try playing the cup again if you ended up in 24th, though.</p>

 <h2><span id="which-karts-are-best-for-donkey-kong"></span>Which karts are best for Donkey Kong?<span></span></h2> <p>There are at least four karts that will serve Donkey Kong well against other racers. Chagrin’ Truck is easily one of the fastest, but the Baby Blooper sacrifices top speed for some increased handling you may find useful. Following these two karts, the Reel Racer and Stellar Sled offer a nice combination of speed and handling.</p> <h2><span id="donkey-kong-unlockable-costumes"></span>Donkey Kong Unlockable Costumes<span></span></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000616899" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000616899"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000616899">© Screenshot: Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Unfortunately, as if making him unlockable wasn’t enough, the DK disrespect continues with his unlockable costumes. He has one costume for players to find out in the open world. This puts him barely above minor drivers like Cow and Snowman, and below the main cast of characters. I don’t know how it happened that costumes for King Boo somehow rank above the ape that started it all, but here we are.</p> <p>Donkey Kong’s only unlockable costume is All-Terrain. You can find it by eating quite a few different foods from around the map; try out a variety and you’re bound to find it before long. It’s a great looking costume. Just try to block out any memories it surfaces of 2022’s disappointing Mario Strikers: Battle League.</p> <h2><span id="what-tracks-favor-donkey-kong"></span>What tracks favor Donkey Kong?<span></span></h2> <p>For the most part, other heavy-class characters like Bowser might be the pick to hit the best times. But tracks like Crown City, Desert Hills, Wario Shipyard, Koopa Troopa Beach, Dandelion Depths, Choco Mountain all typically favor the heavy class, so Donkey Kong should perform well here.</p> <hr> <p><i>Mario Kart World </i>is available now on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-switch-2-donkey-kong-karts-2000616894]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>