<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:15:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of The Biggest YouTubers In The World Asks Fans To Stop Paying Him]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/streamer-cr1tikal-youtube-twitch-superchat-charity-2000634079</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-biggest-youtubers-in-the-world-asks-fans-to-stop-paying-him.1322254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Popular streamer Charles White Jr., aka Cr1TiKal/MoistCr1TiKaL, that long-haired dude who seems to be a pretty good person, has taken the unusual step of shutting off his YouTube memberships and Super Chats. Instead of prompting his viewers to throw money at the screen, he’s instead urging folks to donate to charity. “There are so many better options for your money,” he said.</p> <p>As <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/there-are-so-many-better-options-for-your-money-popular-streamer-turns-off-all-donation-tells-fans-to-give-to-charity/">first reported by <i>VGC</i></a>, White has posted a video announcing that he’s shut off user-donated monetization on his YouTube channel, and saying that he’d shut off Twitch subs as well if he could. “I would say toodle-oo, give it a strong slap on the ass, tell it good game and goodbye.” But apparently it’s harder than that. Still, he stressed that money spent on his stream could be put to better use:</p> <p>There are so many good charities doing extremely good work that could be benefited greatly from your contribution. Like maybe you’d want to donate to a charity that’s doing extremely important work in Gaza. That would be a significantly better use of that money than donating it to me.</p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/streamer-cr1tikal-youtube-twitch-superchat-charity-2000634079]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finally, A Gaming Chair I Don’t Have To Be Embarrassed By]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gaming-chair-elgato-herman-miller-embrace-elgato-2000634072</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/finally-a-gaming-chair-i-don%E2%80%99t-have-to-be-embarrassed-by.1322218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Stuff for gamers tends to look…ridiculous. You’ve got all these sharp angles, and don’t get me started on the constant need to shove RBG LEDs into friggin’ everything. Well, in stark contrast to that trend,&nbsp; Elgato, makers of the Stream Deck, various capture cards, and other kit for streaming setups, has a new chair that looks almost too normal. And for a decent chair that’ll last you? It ain’t sitting at too terrible of a price.</p> <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/798127/elgato-embrace-gaming-chair">As spotted by <i>The Verge</i></a>, Elgato’s new chair, the “Embrace,” comes in at $500 bucks and will be shipping this holiday season. It comes with all the design elements that make gaming chairs decent to sit in. For hours. Without moving. Staring at the screen with little urge to get up beyond necessary biological impulses.</p>

 <p>As Tom Warren at <i>The Verge </i>states, the Embrace seems to be going up against Herman Miller’s “<a href="https://store.hermanmiller.com/gaming-chairs/embody-gaming-chair/100160889.html?lang=en_US&amp;sku=100160889">Embody</a>” chair which, I’ll be honest, has a touch more personality with its color options. I’m really into the white and purple theme. Elegant, not overbearing. But wow, that thing costs almost $2,000. I’m sure it’ll save me back problems down the line, but if I’m spending that kinda money and it’s not for rent, it’s almost certainly for something completely irresponsible. Plus, do I want to be that girl who spent two grand on a chair?</p>

 <p>I’ve had the same rando-brand chair I bought on Amazon for like five years now. It cost $300, and has held up through my many fits of punching the arm rests while listening to Gojira or some other crazy shit. If I do decide upon the Embrace as my next gaming chair, I’ll be sure to let you know if you can beat the hell out of it. And how comfy it is.</p> <p>But seriously! Like even just a two-tone color option would have added at least some personality without making me feel like I need to hide it if I bring a guy over or something.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gaming-chair-elgato-herman-miller-embrace-elgato-2000634072]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh No, Someone Added Jack Black’s Minecraft Steve To Sonic Racing: Crossworlds]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mod-jack-black-steve-minecraft-2000634068</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-no-someone-added-jack-black%E2%80%99s-minecraft-steve-to-sonic-racing-crossworlds.1322185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Warner Bros.
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p><span>The crossover characters and tracks are my least favorite thing about </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-crossover-review-hatsune-miku-2000626583"><i><span>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds</span></i></a><span>, an otherwise excellent kart racer that didn’t need a bunch of licensed partnerships to stand out. That said, it doesn’t surprise me that the modding community has taken that concept and run with it. I do wish someone would add more </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>characters, such as </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-movies-eggman-robotnik-agent-stone-stobotnik-gay-1851738189"><span>Agent Stone</span></a><span> from the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-review-shadow-keanu-reeves-jim-carrey-1851726797"><span>live-action</span> <span>movies</span></a><span>, but it seems like modders have other ideas, like Jack Black’s Steve from </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/a-second-minecraft-movie-is-hitting-theaters-in-just-two-years-2000634000"><span>the </span><i><span>Minecraft </span></i><span>movie</span></a><span>. This is basically my worst nightmare.</span></p> <p><span>Steve, as he exists in the </span><i><span>Minecraft </span></i><span>games, is already in </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>as DLC, but now you can play as his obnoxious film counterpart. The “Jack Black Steve Collection” mod on </span><a href="https://gamebanana.com/mods/625763"><span>GameBanana</span></a><span> comes courtesy of user BROCHONKY, who has added two skins for Jack Black’s character to </span><i><span>Crossworlds</span></i><span>. One is a photoscanned action figure that looks just like the actor, while the other is a stylized version of the character that uses </span><i><span>Minecraft</span></i><span>‘s signature blocky style. As a bonus, the mod also includes the infamous Chicken Jockey as it appears in the original game.</span></p>

 <p><span>The mod doesn’t just include skins, it also has voice lines and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-lava-chicken-jockey-easter-egg-game-1851786345"><span>music from the movie</span></a><span>. Black’s trademark hammed-up delivery followed him into Overworld, so the movie has several soundbites that became memes, such as when he announces the Chicken Jockey’s arrival and says “flint and steel” while teaching the other characters to craft. All of this seems like the making of a troll character, but I also feel like hearing these voice lines repeatedly during races would rot your own brain, so you reap what you sow.&nbsp;</span></p>  <p><span>Sega is apparently cool with character mods, so Steve will live to Chicken Jockey another day. The company recently </span><a href="https://x.com/RaceCrossWorlds/status/1976175976720867553"><span>banned cheaters who used mods to win races</span></a><span>, but the company’s </span><a href="https://games.sega.com/eula/?lang=en"><span>End User License Agreement</span></a><span> explicitly encourages creative work like adding new characters to their games. If I see Jack Black Steve on the racetrack, I will be running him off a cliff expeditiously. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mod-jack-black-steve-minecraft-2000634068]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Shatters Over 700,000 Concurrents On Steam As Fans Fight Errors And Login Queues]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-steam-record-login-queue-multiplayer-download-issue-2000634042</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-shatters-over-700-000-concurrents-on-steam-as-fans-fight-errors-and-login-queues.1322116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-review-steam-ps5-campaign-multiplayer-2000633379"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a> is out today and it’s already blowing up on Steam. The multiplayer military shooter is already well on its way to a million concurrents on Steam alone as fans race to witness the franchise’s revival after years of <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-bad-bf6-battlefield-6-hype-trailer-2000618912">stumbles and collective disappointment</a>. The record-breaking influx initially meant long queues but now some players are facing others issues, including a weird bug that tells them they need to buy and download a multiplayer mode they already own to start playing.</p> <p>Currently in the top-five most played games on Steam, <em>Battlefield</em> is the only game in the top four that’s paid. A $70 price tag hasn’t stopped it from overtaking Valve’s<em> Dota 2</em> and <em>Counter-Strike 2</em>, or the perennial chart-topping battle royale<em> PUBG</em>. Players logging on when the game went live around 11:00 a.m. ET on Friday were immediately greeted by absurd queue positions featuring hundreds of thousands of other players trying to get into the always-online game.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">350,000 in the queue for Battlefield 6 already 🤯 <a href="https://t.co/O6tPcS7e7R">pic.twitter.com/O6tPcS7e7R</a></p> <p>— Tyler James (@FreakyMusic_) <a href="https://twitter.com/FreakyMusic_/status/1976666403723006090?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><em>Battlefield</em> lead producer David Sirland <a href="https://twitter.com/tiggr_/status/1974844687484641683?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1974844687484641683%7Ctwgr%5Ebe0e9b592c93c25f20d70e73f251027fe236f8e8%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamesradar.com%2Fgames%2Fbattlefield%2Fbattlefield-6-lead-tempts-fate-says-servers-should-be-ready-for-launch-after-numerous-betas-across-pc-and-consoles%2F">previously</a> seemed confident that the sequel would be prepared to welcome in the flood of day-one players following months of beta hype and promising feedback. DICE was quick to point out that login queues are part of trying to keep the ramp-up process “smooth and stable for everyone.” That didn’t stop fans from jabbing each other with screenshots of their positions on social media and the Battlefield subreddit. Long before anyone has a KDA to brag about in <em>Battlefield 6</em>, fans are turning to queue positions as high-score markers of elite status. Can anyone <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1o340g7/i_think_people_are_trying_to_play_bf6_idk_maybe/">beat 458,400</a>?</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bro….<br>how doe i play the game now? <a href="https://t.co/wMwXmmHGWm">pic.twitter.com/wMwXmmHGWm</a></p> <p>— DjKr4m3r Gaming (@djkr4m3r) <a href="https://twitter.com/djkr4m3r/status/1976671821476073568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>But other players have been facing a strange issue in which, even after getting into the game, they would be asked to install it. “Running into an error with <em>Battlefield 6</em> that states I need to install multiplayer, and it shows me all the files I need to install,” one wrote on X. “Does anyone have any fixes? I’m afraid I’m going to have to queue again.” <a href="https://x.com/NachoCapart/status/1976678451252953251">Someone else</a> even tried deleting the game, reinstalling everything, and queuing again to try and get in. “If it works, please tell me,” another player wrote back.</p>

 <p>So far, EA has said it’s aware of the problem but hasn’t shared advice on how to address it. “We’re aware of an issue preventing players from accessing the game with some receiving an error stating they need to purchase DLC or similar,” it announced around noon on Friday. “Stay tuned for further updates as the team investigates this issue.”</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000634048" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000634048"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000634048">Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>In the meantime, <em>Battlefield 6</em> seems well on its way to living up to to the initial blitz of player interest some had been predicting. Data firm Ampere Analysis <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/about-that-ea-deal">told <em>The Game Business</em></a> it was forecasting 1.7 million copies pre-ordered on Steam alone. If all of them login within the first 24 hours, the fall blockbuster will be well on its way to being Steam’s most-played game so far this month.</p>

 <p>To break into the top 10 of all-time highest concurrent player counts, it’ll need to beat <em>Banana</em>‘s 917,000 record. The top spot is still held by <em>PUBG</em> at over 3.2 million players simultaneously. EA will probably be content with having already edged out its own free-to-play giant <em>Apex Legends</em>, though. No wonder Activision seems so worried <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-free-battlefield-6-call-of-duty-rivalry-2000633176">about <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> this year</a>. It’s the first time in six years it’s had to go head-to-head with a <em>Battlefield</em> that had a single-player campaign, even if this one has <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-review-steam-ps5-campaign-multiplayer-2000633379">left many critics overwhelmed</a>.</p> <p><strong>Update 10/10/2025 3:04 p.m. ET:</strong> EA says it thinks it’s discovered the cause of the installation error some players are getting and will have a fix ready soon.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Update: Installation of Content</p> <p>We believe we have found a possible cause for this issue. We are in the process of validating a potential fix and will provide an update when we have it. <a href="https://t.co/bqfubq6Szz">https://t.co/bqfubq6Szz</a></p> <p>— Battlefield Comms (@BattlefieldComm) <a href="https://twitter.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1976711820640457139?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-steam-record-login-queue-multiplayer-download-issue-2000634042]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>