<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:23:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Ryzen 7 Laptop Bundle Crashes to 64% Off, Loaded With Freebies and Likely Gone Before October Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dell-ryzen-7-laptop-bundle-crashes-to-64-off-loaded-with-freebies-and-likely-gone-before-october-prime-day-2000629976</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dell-ryzen-7-laptop-bundle-crashes-to-64-off-loaded-with-freebies-and-likely-gone-before-october-prime-day.1312537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If you happen to be on the hunt for a new laptop, whether that’s because you’re a student in need of something to complete assignments, a small business owner looking to handle your business needs, or just some guy looking to watch YouTube and draw pictures, come check out the Dell Inspiron 15. This laptop has a touchscreen and is bundled with some bonus accessories. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4388/">The Amazon listing has the full price set at $2,200, but the limited time deal indicates its been marked down by 64% to just $800</a>. Some quick napkin math will tell you that’s a $1,400 discount.</p>
<p>You might be thinking that’s absolutely ridiculous. How can this laptop be on sale for that much off? Well, you’re right to be suspicious. When we look at this bundle’s price history, we can see it has only existed on Amazon for about a month. After first being listed, it immediately dropped in price and it’s mostly been at that $800 amount since.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4388/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Lots of sellers on Amazon will artificially inflate the list price so that when they mark it down, the sale looks enormous. Even if we go to Dell’s website, we’ll find versions of this model laptop going for about the same as you find it here. All that said, this is a pretty good value.</p>
<p>What you’re getting is a 15.6-inch touchscreen laptop that’s powered by the AMD Ryzen 7 7730U. With that we also have an integrated graphics card, 32GB of memory, and a full 1TB of internal storage on its SSD. This laptop is designed to be able to take on school, work, entertainment, and any other sort of everyday task an average user might encounter — and it’s got the specs to support that.</p>
<p>The screen’s touch controls allow you to operate the laptop as if it’s a tablet, choosing to use pinch, zoom, and swipe gestures like you would on a mobile device. It has a resolution of 1080p and uses an anti-glare coating to help minimize reflections, making for more comfortable viewing in bright settings.</p>



<h2>Bonus Gifts Included</h2>
<p>Along with the laptop, you also get a number of free accessories. This Dell Inspiron 15 comes with a stylus pen to be used on the touchscreen, a cleaning clothe, a laptop sleeve for traveling, a USB flash drive with 128GB on it, as well as some port covers and webcam covers. Plus, the laptop comes pre-installed with Windows 11 Pro.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4388/">Right now, you can get the Dell Inspiron 15 and all these goodies for just $800.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4388/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dell-ryzen-7-laptop-bundle-crashes-to-64-off-loaded-with-freebies-and-likely-gone-before-october-prime-day-2000629976]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just Cause Devs Announce UK Studio Closure And Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/just-cause-devs-announce-uk-studio-closing-and-layoffs-contraband-xbox-2000630245</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-cause-devs-announce-uk-studio-closure-and-layoffs.1312459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/just-cause-3-the-kotaku-review-1745359451"><em>Just Cause</em></a> and <em>Mad Max</em> developer Avalanche Studios is closing up a studio in the United Kingdom and is laying off an undisclosed number of employees due to “current challenges to our business and the industry.”</p> <p>On September 30, <a href="https://avalanchestudios.com/stories/studio-update">Avalanche Studios Group posted a short update</a> on the company’s official site announcing that its UK development studio in Liverpool is being closed and that all employees will be “impacted.” Avalanche also confirmed in the same statement that layoffs are planned for its Swedish studios located in Malmö and Stockholm. The news of layoffs and a studio closure comes about two months after Avalanche and Xbox announced that the upcoming game <em>Contraband</em> was canceled.</p> <p>Here’s Avalanche’s full statement as posted online:</p> <blockquote><p>In light of current challenges to our business and the industry, we have thoroughly reviewed how to best ensure Avalanche Studios Group’s long-term success. This review has led us to the difficult conclusion that we must make changes to our staffing and locations. As a result, we are proposing to close our Liverpool studio, and to initiate a collective consultation process, as required by UK law. This will impact all Avalanchers in Liverpool. The changes will also impact our other studio locations in Malmö and Stockholm, where we will reduce our workforce and restructure the teams to address our games’ needs.</p> <p>Our immediate focus is to offer full support to all Avalanchers during this challenging time. Despite these changes, we remain deeply committed to providing amazing games to our passionate player communities.</p></blockquote> <p><em>Contraband</em> was first announced back in 2021 and was going to be published by Xbox and developed primarily by Avalanche’s studio in Liverpool. However, four years later, we had heard very little about the game and its status. <a href="https://kotaku.com/just-cause-makers-xbox-exclusive-contraband-canceled-amid-recent-cuts-2000616371">In August 2025</a>, Xbox and Avalanche announced what most people expected: Development on <em>Contraband</em> was being halted as the studio “evaluated” the future of the game and its plans moving forward. And while the game isn’t mentioned directly in the statement above, it appears those involved with the evaluation have settled on layoffs.</p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/candy-crush-ai-king-microsoft-layoffs-xbox-farm-saga-1851786283">This is just one</a> of <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-industry-layoffs-how-many-2024-unity-twitch-1851155818">many, many, many layoffs</a> to <a href="https://kotaku.com/latest-round-of-mass-layoffs-at-xbox-begin-with-200-job-1851785492">happen in the video game industry</a> over the last few years as it becomes more expensive to develop bigger games and harder than ever to get people to play them, as titles like <a href="https://kotaku.com/old-games-2023-playtime-data-fortnite-roblox-minecraft-1851382474"><em>Fortnite, GTA Online, Call of Duty, </em>and <em>Roblox</em></a> dominate the charts. <a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-netease-game-director-layoffs-season-2-1851765290">And even if your game is a big hit</a>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-virtuos-layoffs-cyberpunk-patch-1851786435">that doesn’t mean you’re safe.</a></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/just-cause-devs-announce-uk-studio-closing-and-layoffs-contraband-xbox-2000630245]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Might Finally Add Replaceable Batteries To PlayStation Controllers]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-dualsense-controller-gamepad-battery-life-2000630240</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-might-finally-add-replaceable-batteries-to-playstation-controllers.1312408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When first-party video game controllers finally cut the cord to embrace their wireless future in the PS3/Xbox 360 era, Sony chose the path of built-in rechargeable lithium batteries over Xbox’s AA-battery solution. While rechargeable battery kits would become available for 360 controllers and beyond, Sony stuck to its built-in solution. It looks like that may be changing soon, however, if some leaks are to be believed.</p> <p>According to <a href="https://www.ppe.pl/news/384532/nowe-ps5-pro-i-kontrolery-dualsense-z-pozadana-funkcja-zdradzamy-szczegoly.html">Polish-language site <i>PPE</i></a>, credentialed leaker Graczdari has spilled the beans on an upcoming update to the DualSense controllers Sony plans to ship with <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/a-new-ps5-pro-model-has-been-leaked-and-its-releasing-soon/">a new, more energy-efficient PS5 Pro that seems to be on the horizon</a>. Grains of salt and all, this same leaker accurately called <i>Flight Simulator</i>’s arrival on Sony hardware and the physical release of <i>Oblivion Remastered</i>.</p>

 <h2>What kinds of batteries will this thing take?</h2> <p>According to the leak, this revised DualSense controller is referred to internally as “V3.” What isn’t as clear is whether or not you’ll be able to shove some Duracells in here and call it a day. Our <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sony-is-reportedly-set-to-release-an-updated-ps5-dualsense-controller-with-a-removable-battery/">comrades over at <i>VGC</i></a> don’t seem to think so, as the language in the original report seems to suggest the batteries might be a separate product category of their own, perhaps not too dissimilar from Xbox’s rechargeable battery solution.</p> <p>PlayStation controller battery life has been a bit of a rollercoaster over the years. Veterans of the PS3 era will likely remember the DualShock 3 as being quite generous when it came to playtime. The DualShock 4, however? That battery would evaporate faster than water on Mars. The DualSense hasn’t been much of an improvement, especially with its more sophisticated rumble feature and triggers. Hopefully V3 of this otherwise very comfy controller will lengthen your time spent cordless.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-dualsense-controller-gamepad-battery-life-2000630240]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UGREEN Mac Mini M4 Dock Has Never Been This Cheap, Featuring 11 Ports and 8TB Expansion at Giveaway Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-mac-mini-m4-dock-has-never-been-this-cheap-featuring-11-ports-and-8tb-expansion-at-giveaway-pricing-2000629601</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ugreen-mac-mini-m4-dock-has-never-been-this-cheap-featuring-11-ports-and-8tb-expansion-at-giveaway-pricing.1312405/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As great as Apple’s products are in the performance department, a huge part of their appeal has always been, well, they’re&nbsp;<em>cool looking</em>. The latest models of the longtime favorite Mac Mini – the M4 Mac Mini and M4 Mac Mini Pro — are no exception. But it’s a third-party accessory — the amazing UGREEN dock and stand — that is the best fit possible for the M4 Mac Mini for performance and expanded capability, and it passes the good-looks test. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4387/">It’s also at an all-time low price of $61 (32% off) ahead of Amazon Prime Big Deal Days.&nbsp;</a></p>
<p>The UGREEN dock and stand blends in with the M4 Mac Mini so seamlessly it looks like it’s part of the Mini itself, or at least an accessory built by Apple. But as a UGREEN product, it gives you that elegant look and outstanding performance at a fraction of the price Apple would likely charge.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4387/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Looks Aren’t Everything</h2>
<p>We’ve gone on long enough about the aesthetic superiority of the UGREEN Mac Mini Dock and Stand. Where it truly shines and massively overperforms its price is in what it brings to your Mini. Three additional USB-A ports at 10Gbps, two more at 5Gbps, two USB-C ports at 10Gbps, a SD and MicroSD card reader that reads and writes at a sizzling 170MB/s are instantly added to your M4 Mac Mini, all via just one unobtrusive USB-C connection to the Mini itself.</p>
<p>Then there’s the expansion opportunity — the UGREEN Mac Mini Dock and Stand has a “hidden” enclosure at the bottom of the unit that can hold an M2 NVMe SSD drive. The drive itself isn’t included (hello — $61!) but this gives you the option of adding as much as 8TB of storage to your Mini. PCI Express, NVM Express, and NVM3 M.2 drives are all compatible via an easy plug-and-play installation, and once it’s plugged in, the UGREEN dock moves data back and forth with the Mini at a staggeringly fast 10Gbps.</p>



<h2>Stand That Delivers</h2>
<p>The UGREEN covers details you wouldn’t normally consider, including conductive paint shielding for 5G avoidance and reducing Wi-Fi interference. There’s also a bottom groove in the stand for access to the power button, eliminating the only design flaw of the Mini itself — having to lift it up just to turn it on.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4387/">M4 Mac Mini users are getting a pre-Prime Day bonanza with this hot 32% off deal on the UGREEN dock and stand.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4387/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-mac-mini-m4-dock-has-never-been-this-cheap-featuring-11-ports-and-8tb-expansion-at-giveaway-pricing-2000629601]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>