<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 02:12:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s Massive Fall Sale Is Live And Here Are The Best Deals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-fall-autumn-sale-2025-best-biggest-cheapest-deals-games-pc-steamdeck-2000629959</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam%E2%80%99s-massive-fall-sale-is-live-and-here-are-the-best-deals.1311988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The leaves are turning orange and brown. Pumpkins and scarecrows are appearing on porches all around your town. It’s fall, the best season of the year. And as with every seasonal shift, fall brings with it a big ol’ limited-time Steam sale featuring hundreds and hundreds of discounted PC games.</p> <p>On September 29<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/specials/">,</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/specials/">Valve kicked off the big Steam Fall Sale</a>. There is precisely a metric shit-ton of games on sale on Steam from now through October 6, so you have a week to dig through everything and hopefully find a good deal on big games like<em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-the-kotaku-review-1845946628">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, Doom Eternal, Diablo IV,</em> and many, many more. To help you out, I’ve dug around for a bit and pulled out some of the biggest and best deals currently available on Steam.</p> <p>Also, as a heads up: The <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-deck-valve-best-games-to-play-verified-pc-gaming-1849371052/21">LCD Steam Deck</a> is currently <a href="https://kotaku.com/autumn-2025-steam-deck-sale-cheap-pc-gaming-handheld-2000627631">20 percent off on Steam, too</a>. If you’ve been wanting to jump into PC gaming, this is a great way to do that, and many of the games listed below will run great on a Steam Deck.</p> <p>Anyway, here’s my list of highlights, arranged alphabetically. And yay, the comments are back, so we can all help each other find good deals. If you spot anything not on this list that you think is worth buying or checking out that’s on sale right now, leave it in the comments below.</p> <hr> <ul> <li><em>Assassin’s Creed Mirage</em> – $15 ($50)</li> <li><em>Assassin’s Creed Origins</em> – $6 ($60)</li> <li><em>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</em> – $18 ($70)</li> <li><em>Control Ultimate Edition</em> – $4 ($40)</li> <li><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> – $21 ($60)</li> <li><em>Dead Island 2</em> – $15 ($50)</li> <li><em>Death Stranding</em> – $20 ($40)</li> <li><em>Desperados III</em> – $4 ($40)</li> <li><em>Diablo IV</em> – $23 ($50)</li> <li><em>Doom Eternal</em> – $4 ($40)</li> <li><em>Dying Light</em> – $5 ($25)</li> <li><em>Far Cry Primal</em> – $4 ($30)</li> <li><em>Forza Horizon 5</em> – $30 ($60)</li> <li><em>Greedfall</em> – $3 ($35)</li> <li><em>High on Life</em> – $10 ($40)</li> <li><em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> – $12 ($60)</li> <li><em>Horizon Forbidden West</em> – $36 ($60)</li> <li><em>Left 4 Dead –</em> $2 ($10)</li> <li><em>Monster Train</em> – $2 ($25)</li> <li><em>Monster Train 2</em> – $20 ($25)</li> <li><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> – $49 ($70)</li> <li><em>Persona 5 Royal</em> – $21 ($60)</li> <li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</em> – $30 ($60)</li> <li><em>Ready or Not</em> – $25 ($50)</li> <li><em>Red Dead Redemption II</em> – $15 ($60)</li> <li><em>Resident Evil 4 remake</em> – $20 ($40)</li> <li><em>Resident Evil 7</em> – $8 ($20)</li> <li><em>Resident Evil Village</em> – $10 ($40)</li> <li><em>Rise of the Tomb Raider</em> – $3 ($30)</li> <li><em>Rome: Total War Remastered</em> – $8 ($30)</li> <li><em>Sea of Thieves</em> – $20 ($40)</li> <li><em>Sniper Elite 5</em> – $5 ($50)</li> <li><em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em> – $8 ($40)</li> <li><em>Two Point Campus</em> – $3 ($30)</li> <li><em>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine II</em> – $30 ($60)</li> </ul> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steam-fall-autumn-sale-2025-best-biggest-cheapest-deals-games-pc-steamdeck-2000629959]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Goes Private, Then What?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ea-saudi-arabia-battlefield-6-mass-effect-bioware-private-equity-2000629947</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-goes-private-then-what.1311985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Why does Saudi Arabia want to make games? What will the largest leveraged buyout in history mean for EA and its employees? How will the consequences of the <a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-sale-saudi-arabia-madden-pif-jared-kushner-2000629829">new $55 billion deal</a> ripple out across the rest of the video game industry? I reached out to some analysts to get their take on the sale and what it tells us about the state of gaming now, and where it’s headed. Here’s what they said.</p> <h2>A “soft-power” play</h2> <p>“This is the second-largest deal in games history—$50 billion for a mature publisher whose growth engine has stalled,” Joost van Dreunen, a professor at NYU’s Stern School of Business and author of <a href="https://superjoost.substack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-cy="styled-link"><u>SuperJoost Playlist</u></a>, wrote in an email to <em>Kotaku</em>. “It shows how sovereign capital, not just Big Tech, is now dictating who controls cultural IP. It also highlights how public-market fatigue with slow-growth publishers is pushing them toward privatization.”</p> <p>Saudi Arabia’s Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman has mandated $38 billion be invested in turning the country into a gaming powerhouse, with sizable chunks of that already being spent on buying up <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-go-scopely-niantic-saudi-arabia-monster-hunter-1851769360">mobile game makers</a>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/evo-saudi-arabia-street-fighter-6-sony-esports-2000622367">taking over esports</a>, and acquiring equity in <a href="https://kotaku.com/snk-saudi-arabia-mohammed-bin-salman-mbs-king-of-fighte-1848754233">major gaming companies</a> (it already owns 10 percent of EA going into the sale). While other private equity partners are part of the sale, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-29/saudi-plans-for-video-game-hub-grow-with-55-billion-ea-deal?srnd=undefined"><em>Bloomberg</em> reports</a> that the majority of the funding comes from Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund.</p>

 <p>In the <a href="https://superjoost.substack.com/p/electronic-arts-55b-buyout-doesnt">latest edition of his newsletter,</a> van Dreunen points to the illogic of the the deal’s financial math, which values EA much more highly than its current cash flow would suggest it should be for a leveraged buyout in which $20 billion is financed through debt. He argues the deal underpins Saudi Arabia’s willingness to overpay for U.S. cultural IP, as well as Wall Street’s loss of interest in legacy gaming businesses whose growth potential has stalled out in recent years. “At the center sits the irrational financial logic that tells you it’s about power, prestige, and staking Saudi Arabia’s claim in American entertainment,” he writes.</p>

 <h2>Gaming continues to consolidate in search of growth</h2> <p>The conventional wisdom was that amid the post-pandemic flurry of market consolidation, EA would merge with someone sooner or later. <a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-acquisition-apex-legends-star-wars-fifa-nbcuniversal-1848957274">It reportedly engaged in acquisition talks</a> with Apple and others back in 2022, with a potential deal to to merge with NBCUniversal eventually falling apart over price. Pundits have called on Disney to buy the publisher of <em>Madden</em> and <em>FIFA</em> (now <em>EA Sports FC</em>) <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190223172654/https://kotaku.com/wall-street-journal-to-disney-buy-ea-5075163">for decades</a>. “We couldn’t be in a stronger position as a standalone company,” EA CEO Andrew Wilson said back in 2022.</p>

 <p>What’s changed since then? EA hasn’t has a new runaway success story since <em>Apex Legends</em>, which shadow-dropped back in 2019 and stumbled last year amid declining interest.<em> EA Sports FC</em>, <em>Madden</em>, and now <em>College Football</em> are the core games sustaining the publisher, but it’s unclear where they go from here. <em>Battlefield </em>is taking on <em>Call of Duty</em> again for the first time in years, but it’s an expensive live-service gambit at a time when few new multiplayer games seem to be able to stick for any length of time.</p>

 <p>“EA’s mobile games business has traditionally underperformed and should be a much larger part of its overall business,” Piers Harding-Roll, Games Research Director at Ampere Analysis, told <em>Kotaku</em> in an email. “This alignment could help transform EA’s mobile business. EA’s revenue growth in recent years has been benign, so the opportunity to drive growth and build out a long-term strategy by bringing together a cross-section of expertise is attractive to both parties.”</p>

 <p>The publishers attempts to adapt its hit franchises into mobile games have either been canceled (<a href="https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-mobile-shutdown-ea-respawn-battlefield-1850056170"><em>Battlefield</em></a>), quickly closed down (<a href="https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-mobile-shutdown-ea-respawn-battlefield-1850056170"><em>Apex Legends</em></a>), or struggled to bring in boatloads of money (<a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/ea-sports-mobile-revenue-1-billion"><em>Madden</em></a>). “The deal creates opportunities for Saudi Arabia to strengthen its console &amp; PC presence, and provides EA with an opportunity for synergy with [Saudi-owned mobile developer] Scopely for ongoing mobile expansion, now that both are under the PIF,” Daniel Ahmad, Director of Research and Insights at Niko Partners, told <em>Kotaku</em> in an email.</p> <h2>Leveraged buyouts are a recipe for pain</h2> <p>Big private-equity deals involving lots of debt often <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/1/6/21024740/private-equity-taylor-swift-toys-r-us-elizabeth-warren">bring with them sharp cuts</a>. Business analysts will call this “right-sizing” or “rationalizing the business,” but what it means is people paid a fraction of their CEO’s salary get fired. EA currently has roughly 15,000 employees, a number many industry watchers expect to decline. “Leveraged buyouts deposit a large amount of long-term debt on the company being acquired and an additional $20 billion of debt will need to be serviced through cutting costs and building more margin from existing businesses to generate more free cash flow,” Harding-Roll said.</p> <p>There’s been a lot of debate on whether going private will free the company up to invest in franchises long-term rather than invest almost exclusively in games that deliver predictable quarterly returns. Could a lack of shareholder pressure yield more single-player blockbusters, or provide EA with enough runway to give the next <em>Mass Effect</em> as much time in development as it needs? Or will the debt crunch incentivize EA to lop off anything that’s not generating revenue and retreat even further into annualized sequels?</p>

 <p>“EA’s empire is heavy on sports and sprawling studios, so some ‘right-sizing’ is inevitable—expect a sharper split between the sports division and everything else, some studio consolidation, and likely relocation of certain functions to Saudi Arabia,” van Dreunen told&nbsp;<em>Kotaku</em>. “Being private could also tilt its content strategy back toward longer-cycle franchises rather than quarter-to-quarter live-ops churn. <em>Battlefield</em> gets a cushion, but there will be trims and a sports-versus-everything-else carve-out.”</p> <h2>Unconventional players in uncharted waters</h2> <p>Video games are a notoriously chaotic business, mergers are inherently unpredictable, and a sovereign wealth fund has never owned one of the biggest gaming publishers in the world before (following Activision’s sale to Microsoft, EA is the biggest non-platform, non-Chinese company in gaming by revenue). While it’s reasonable to explain the deal by pointing to Saudi Arabia’s global PR blitz and synergies in sports and mobile gaming, it’s also reasonable to think it’s way too early to tell how this will shake out, especially when you throw a $20 billion loan into the mix.</p>

 <p>“I can’t say I know what it all means yet, or what this deal will result in when it comes to EA’s games and studios,” Mat Piscatella, Circana’s Director of Gaming Research, told&nbsp;<em>Kotaku</em>. “I’d hazard to even attempt to speculate at this point. Of course, leveraged buyouts have a certain history that generally hasn’t been great for the acquired companies, but I do not know if that will be the case here given the parties involved.”</p> <p>“It’s very much about aligning gaming and esports alongside entertainment and sports as key diversification pillars for the Saudi economy,” Ahmad added. “The deal also begs the question of what will come in the future regarding mergers and acquisitions for the global games industry, given the ongoing consolidation trend, and the ability for smaller companies to break through to walk among the giants.”</p> <p>While more layoffs may be a grim inevitability, the analysts <em>Kotaku</em> spoke with didn’t predict any seismic shifts in the immediate aftermath of the deal, set to close next summer. “I don’t expect any significant changes to the upcoming slate of games over the next couple of years,” Harding-Roll said. “The biggest opportunities remain growth of the <em>Battlefield</em> franchise, growth of the <em>EA Sports FC</em> franchise during the World Cup 2026 and bigger exposure to mobile gaming.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ea-saudi-arabia-battlefield-6-mass-effect-bioware-private-equity-2000629947]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[18 Years Later, Disney Announces A New Simpsons Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/18-years-later-disney-announces-the-simpsons-movie-2-sequel-fox-teaser-homer-2000629950</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/18-years-later-disney-announces-a-new-simpsons-movie.1311898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Disney’s 20th Century has announced that a new movie based on the <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-simpsons-best-episodes-characters-top-to-watch-list-1850309544">long-running animated TV sitcom<em> The Simpsons</em></a> is in the works. The newly announced sequel will arrive in 2027, 20 years after the release of the first <em>Simpsons</em> flick.</p> <p>On September 29,<a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DPMgc7Yj0PE/#"> Disney and 20th Century announced on social media</a> that a new <em>Simpsons</em> film was officially in development. No plot details were shared about the movie, but Disney did post a teaser poster for the upcoming sequel. The poster features Homer Simpson grabbing a pink doughnut covered in sprinkles shaped like the number 2, likely hinting that the movie will be titled <em>The Simpsons Movie 2</em>.&nbsp; The tagline “Homer’s combing back for seconds” is included on the poster. So, good news, Homer is back. Shocking, I know, but there you go.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Woohoo! The Simpsons are coming to theaters with an all-new movie on July 23, 2027! <a href="https://t.co/wVqxwn8rLc">pic.twitter.com/wVqxwn8rLc</a></p> <p>— 20th Century Studios (@20thcentury) <a href="https://twitter.com/20thcentury/status/1972723057396690948?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>   <p><span>Created by Matt Groening and premiering in 1989,&nbsp;<em>The Simpsons</em> is the longest-running sitcom on TV. While many have criticized the show’s quality since the late ’90, the series has remained extremely popular on TV and is considered an anchor of Fox’s Sunday block of animated TV shows. The original <em>Simpsons</em> movie premiered in July 2007 and was a huge box office hit, earning over $536 million at the global box office. That movie featured a story about a giant dome being put over the town of Springfield due to pollution. It also brought back old former writers, took years to make, and featured a more detailed art style.</span></p> <p><span>We’ve heard rumors for years of a second <em>Simpsons</em> movie, <a href="https://simpsons.fandom.com/wiki/The_Man_Who_Came_to_Be_Dinner#:~:text=However%2C%20according%20to,a%20regular%20episode.">including a proposed follow-up featuring the franchise’s alien characters</a> Kang and </span><span>Kodos</span><span>. That movie didn’t move forward as the writing staff couldn’t stretch the plot out to a full-length movie. But now it seems the writers and producers behind the show have finally nailed the plot for the next flick. Now we just have to wait until 2027.</span></p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/18-years-later-disney-announces-the-simpsons-movie-2-sequel-fox-teaser-homer-2000629950]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>