<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:49:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Internet Reacts To The Death Of Catherine O’Hara]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/catherine-ohara-death-died-reaction-tmz-pedro-pascal-2000664620</link>
            <guid>1421389</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Catherine O’Hara, the legendary actor known for her roles in television and film like </span><i><span>Schitt’s Creek</span></i><span>, the </span><i><span>Home Alone </span></i><span>films, the second season of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661"><i><span>The Last of Us</span></i></a><span>, and much, much more, has passed away at the age of 71. </span><a href="https://www.tmz.com/2026/01/30/catherine-ohara-dead/"><i><span>TMZ</span></i></a><span> reports that she died earlier today, January 30, though the cause of death is currently unconfirmed.</span></p> <p><span>O’Hara’s death came as a bit of a shock, as she had been keeping busy in recent years, appearing in the second season of </span><i><span>The Last of Us </span></i><span>as Gail, an original character for the live-action series. Pedro Pascal, who plays Joel in the show, was one of the first of her co-stars to publicly pay tribute after O’Hara’s passing, sharing a lovely photo and calling the comic star a “genius” who he was grateful to be near.</span></p>   <p><span>Since her storied career spanned decades, O’Hara’s fans have many touchstones to think back on, whether that be her presence on the beloved Canadian sketch comedy show </span><i><span>SCTV </span></i><span>early in her career or some of her voice acting roles, such as Sally from </span><i><span>The Nightmare Before Christmas</span></i><span>. When news broke, fans immediately started flooding the internet with tributes, condolences, and jokes about how the wrong </span><i><span>Home Alone 2 </span></i><span>star died.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">RIP to the most iconic on-screen Mom of all time, Christmas won’t be the same knowing Catherine O’Hara isn’t out looking for Kevin. <a href="https://t.co/eTqw5CBJOX">pic.twitter.com/eTqw5CBJOX</a></p> <p>— Joe Russo (@joerussotweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/joerussotweets/status/2017302103195324510?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">some people should not be able to die!!!!!! <a href="https://t.co/z1Lo5UOjPv">https://t.co/z1Lo5UOjPv</a></p> <p>— kelsey weekman (@kelsaywhat) <a href="https://twitter.com/kelsaywhat/status/2017302858761109902?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">One of the best actors of her generation. Easily one of the best comedians of all time. As much Catherine O’Hara as we got, it was nowhere near enough. <a href="https://t.co/tU7XI7lBDE">https://t.co/tU7XI7lBDE</a></p> <p>— Mike Drucker (@MikeDrucker) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikeDrucker/status/2017305719788245385?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">the day-o scene from beetlejuice is probably one of the most iconic scenes in cinematic history thanks to catherine o'hara’s incredible comedic timing and physical comedy. what a huge loss it is to hear of her passing, rip to an icon ❤️ <a href="https://t.co/VoSxPgofF8">pic.twitter.com/VoSxPgofF8</a></p> <p>— ⟡mich⟡ (@classiccinemich) <a href="https://twitter.com/classiccinemich/status/2017306447588049204?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>   <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Catherine O’Hara turned in easily one of the greatest comedic television performances as Moira Rose in Schitt’s Creek. Television is a better art form for her having appeared on it. We are better for having witnessed her craft. <a href="https://t.co/J4jnuova5K">pic.twitter.com/J4jnuova5K</a></p> <p>— bobbi loves vampires ❤️ (@hiimbobbi) <a href="https://twitter.com/hiimbobbi/status/2017303561583931712?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Catherine O’Hara died today and people are still talking about Donald Trump. That’s what’s wrong with our world! <a href="https://t.co/rgbBFgyzEK">pic.twitter.com/rgbBFgyzEK</a></p> <p>— DOGSRULE (@Jeffreyaasen5) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jeffreyaasen5/status/2017300332435661126?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">catherine o’hara is dead at 71 and yet that man still fucking lives <a href="https://t.co/ZQKjyws7PI">pic.twitter.com/ZQKjyws7PI</a></p> <p>— titlor swift (@GAYLANDTOO) <a href="https://twitter.com/GAYLANDTOO/status/2017306266134065400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">catherine o’hara please say sike right now <a href="https://t.co/LabEfzJcVh">pic.twitter.com/LabEfzJcVh</a></p> <p>— sammy (@biglittlerivera) <a href="https://twitter.com/biglittlerivera/status/2017300825853268360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2026</a></p></blockquote>          <p><span>O’Hara is survived by two children and her husband, director Bo Welch. I leave you with a roundup of some of her best moments as Moira Rose in </span><i><span>Schitt’s Creek</span></i><span>.</span></p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/catherine-ohara-death-died-reaction-tmz-pedro-pascal-2000664620]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Bunch Of Big Video Game Company Stocks Just Tanked For A Very Dumb Reason]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/video-game-stocks-down-take-two-gta-nintendo-roblox-unity-google-ai-game-maker-2000664594</link>
            <guid>1421239</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Yesterday, Google revealed its Project Genie AI-generation tool, allowing people to make “interactive environments” in seconds using just prompts. Today, in response to this, a bunch of investors seem to think this is the future of game development and are bailing on big game companies. This has led to stocks tanking for companies like Take-Two and <a href="https://kotaku.com/roblox-new-york-times-interview-baszucki-2000646174">Roblox</a>.</p> <p>On January 29, Google started rolling out early access to a new “experimental research prototype” AI tool named Project Genie. It is powered by Genie 3 and Gemini and allows users to create 3D worlds you can move around in simply by inputting a text prompt, like “Cartoonish 3D racing game with toy cars.” <a href="https://kotaku.com/google-ai-genai-nintendo-zelda-breath-wild-mario-64-project-genie-2000664227">As reported by <em>The Verge</em> on Thursday</a>, the tool can also be used to create “games” that look a lot like <em>Mario</em> and <em>Zelda</em>, something I imagine Nintendo won’t be happy about.</p>

 <p>While Genie’s creations aren’t games at all, just 3D environments that you can explore for a short amount of time, it seems many investors believe that tools like Genie will soon magically be making entire games. There’s been a bunch of sudden stock sell-offs across the gaming industry on Friday as a result.</p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ijzk33hik37peth6s45vndeb/app.bsky.feed.post/3mdnsxei4lk2w" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiaijody4fvos6knzduiwmseo2dgu7b5imtxilea5fnkgaiara4uny"> <p lang="en">Video game stocks are suddenly crashing today with the launch of Google's Project Genie as investors think games will start magically getting made with AI</p> <p>➡️ ca.investing.com/news/stock-m… </p> <p>#GoogleGemini #TakeTwo #CDProjektRED #Roblox #videogames</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ijzk33hik37peth6s45vndeb?ref_src=embed">Shinobi602 (@shinobi602.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ijzk33hik37peth6s45vndeb/post/3mdnsxei4lk2w?ref_src=embed">2026-01-30T17:23:17.949Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p><a href="https://ca.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/unity-stock-falls-alongside-taketwo--roblox-after-googles-project-genie-launch-4429665">As reported by <em>Investing.com</em>,</a> the stock price for numerous publishers and console manufacturers is tanking today after Genie’s reveal. As of 1:05 p.m. EST, <em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em> publisher Take-Two Interactive was down over nine percent. Roblox’s stock price had slid nearly 12 percent. Video game engine company Unity’s stock is down a whopping 20 percent. <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/NTDOY/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAG7DeRlALEalto-xnKvXTp7KQFjICvRwxzk5IiImf36NuZ2544k6LSSE4RRCuiQ4hR08ut2AtuKtmdnAuNNNmMmyD8VAc89FQQzP8_97U5BPHLDgp7uWBsLjJqa7C3K-DeXSsmw3cVeevxwUJ0Knf4DrbMbSdGoTxdyOfUhcNN1p">And even Nintendo stock is down</a> nearly five percent. These tumbles all happened today, which seems to directly connect the slides to the reveal of Google’s new Genie tool.</p>

 <p>At the moment, the interactive experiences Google’s tool can produce last only one minute, run at 24 frames per second, and cap out at 720p. They also lack stability, with one demo featuring a race track changing mid-gameplay. The tool can also be used to create replicas of games like <em>Mario 64</em>, though Google seems nervous about this ability, with the AI tool eventually stopping a <em>Verge</em> reporter from making more Mario “games” over concern for “the interests of third-party content providers.” Meanwhile, other people are already using the tool to make ugly, horrible versions of <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/genie-3-ai-video-games-gta-6-dark-souls/"><em>GTA 6 </em>and<em> Dark Souls.&nbsp;</em></a></p>

 <p>But for the people with all the money, none of this matters. They see a future where game devs and companies aren’t needed, and this magic AI tool can save money and quickly produce the next <em>Call of Duty </em>or <em>GTA.</em> Good luck with that.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/video-game-stocks-down-take-two-gta-nintendo-roblox-unity-google-ai-game-maker-2000664594]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Amazing Games To Play On Your Phone Instead Of Doomscrolling]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/10-best-mobile-games-balatro-slay-the-spire-android-ios-2000664549</link>
            <guid>1421236</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Five slices of mobile games.</span> © grapefrukt / Devolver / Red Blue Games / LocalThunk / Mega Crit / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>You were just checking the time. That’s all. But there was a notification, and it could have been important, but it turned out to be a link to a funny post on BlueSky. And now it’s 47 minutes later and you’ve doomscrolled through page after page of news and reaction to the seemingly unending torrent of horror being visited upon the country and world, and you feel helpless, wound up, and sad. Oh, and what time is it? Stop! Stop this madness! Your phone is a whole gaming console in one tiny slab! So next time you pick it up, click onto one of these fabulous games instead.</p> <p>All the following games are selected because they’re such incredibly good ways to spend those spare moments of time when you’d otherwise be tempted to look at the algorithm’s horror. These are the games that’ll fit in on the train ride, during coffee, or as you’re sitting outside waiting for your kid to emerge from the school, and they’re also a great way to while away the last hour before you fall asleep at night. As such, I’m not selecting games like <em>Honkai Star Rail</em> or&nbsp;<em>Warframe</em> because firstly they’re just better on a bigger screen, and secondly because that sort of game is an entire second job in itself. This is all about the perfect way to distract your brain and fingers in a fulfilling, non-terrifying manner.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Slay the Spire</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/slay-the-spire/id1491530147">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.humble.SlayTheSpire&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>Mega Crit’s legendary <em>Slay the Spire</em> might be more immediately associated with PC and console, but in the years after its 2019 release it was brought to iOS and Android in an absolutely perfect port. The pioneering roguelite deckbuilder remains as all-consuming today as it did seven years back, and the shorter battles and ability to quit out and pick back up where you left off make it ideal for quick plays on your phone. Or indeed entire evenings consumed with mastering a deck to defeat everything in your path. It’s one of the few properly priced mobile games at $10, but remember you’re buying one of the best games ever made, with a minimum play time of infinity hours.</p> <hr> <h2>Balatro</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/balatro/id6502453075">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playstack.balatro.android&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>2024’s smash hit took its time coming to mobile, but arrived in glorious style. The poker-ish game took the world by storm on PC and console in February 2024, and then became the entire planet’s meta when it reached iOS and Android that September. It remains one of the finest ways you can occupy your spare time, each run a unique experience as you shape your deck and Jokers to win your way through the rounds and challenges. Like <em>Slay the Spire</em>, it’s $10, and worth every cent.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Polimines Deluxe</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/polimines-deluxe/id6473717385">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.penguinpopgames.poliminesdeluxe&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>Spanish indie developer Molter Games might not be a household name, but puzzle game&nbsp;<em>Polimines&nbsp;</em>deserves to be. This combination of puzzles like&nbsp;<em>Picross</em>,&nbsp;<em>Hexcells</em> and&nbsp;<em>Minesweeper</em> creates a unique and enormously clever challenge. This mobile version combines both the PC’s <em>Polimines 1&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>2</em>, which works out perfectly since the sequel pretty much picks up where the difficulty for the first game left off. Every solved puzzle in the second half will make you feel like a complete genius. And the whole thing is only $5.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Sparklite</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/sparklite/id1553922886">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playdigious.sparklite&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>RPG&nbsp;<em>Sparklite</em> was generally liked when it came out in 2019, without blowing anyone away. It’s a gorgeous roguelite in which you play as Ada, on her broken airship, making trips to the world of Geodia below to gather items and “patches” and battle mighty Titans. Each failure is an opportunity for a new attempt, with the progression of creating new stores and crafting stations on her floating island, and applying the patches into machines that create a unique set of skills and attacks to shape how you play. It got a bit lost on console, even the great version on Switch, but it just works so incredibly well as a mobile game. A good run can fill a commute, and there’s a constant sense of progression that makes you want to pick it back up for another try on the way home.</p> <hr> <h2>The New York Times Games</h2> <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/nyt-games-wordle-crossword/id307569751">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nytimes.crossword&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>No, not technically a game, but by far one of the very best ways to spend time on your phone. <em>Wordle</em> and others are free, but if you pay the sub (and you can get it incredibly cheap—I’m paying around $3 a month), you get access to the daily <em>NYT</em> crossword alongside <em>Connections</em>, <em>Strands</em>, <em>The Mini</em> (crossword), <em>Pips</em> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ALGL4Hm5g8">Spelling Bee</a>, as well as access to their archives. There are now bots for a bunch of these that’ll analyze your play, and it just added two-player Crossplay, the most blatant, bare-faced Scrabble rip-off since <em>Worlds With Friends</em>. I start each day with <em>Wordle</em> and <em>The Mini</em>, end each day with the crossword and <em>Spelling Bee</em>, and the others sneak in for coffee breaks. (Bonus game: check out the amazing <a href="https://squaredle.app/"><em>Squardle</em></a> which also has an app.)</p>

 <hr> <h2>Stuffo the Puzzle Bot</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/stuffo-the-puzzle-bot/id6444358789">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Hapatus.Stuffo&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>There’s a good chance you’re familiar with the extraordinary old-school dungeon crawler&nbsp;<em>Legend of Grimrock</em>. But the next game from one of its two main developers deserves to be equally lauded. <em>Stuff the Puzzle Bot</em> is one of the most brilliantly clever puzzle games you’ll ever play, one of those where discovering the solution makes you feel like you’ve made a momentous breakthrough and simultaneously want to buy flowers for the creator. The component parts look familiar—using a little robo to pick up and rearrange blocks of various types such that he can reach a level’s exit—but rarely has this been so exquisitely executed. The mobile version is perhaps even better than the PC build, with fingertip controls making so much sense.</p> <hr> <h2>Shattered Pixel Dungeon</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/shattered-pixel-dungeon/id1563121109">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.shatteredpixel.shatteredpixeldungeon&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p><em>Pixel Dungeon</em> by Watabou (Oleg Dolya) was originally released for mobile in 2012, and was a delightful micro-dungeon crawler. But best of all, it was released as free software, with anyone else welcome to lift its entire code and create their own versions, even for sale. The result has been a huge range of splendid variants, and it’s generally agreed the best of these is <em>Shattered Pixel Dungeon</em> by Evan Debenham—it’s certainly my favorite. A project that was meant to last a few months has eventually led to 12 years of work so far, with new content added roughly every three months, and yet the game feels uncomplicated and welcoming to play. It’s $5, and will occupy you for the rest of time.</p> <hr> <h2>Loop Hero</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/loop-hero/id6464048549">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playdigious.loophero&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>Another PC roguelite that found its way to mobile three years later, <em>Loop Hero</em> feels so very at home on your phone. This is a game that’s essentially about walking around in a circle, but what a circle it is. Instead of controlling your character, you play “cards” that lay obstacles, enemies and advantages, as well as mountains and marshes, around the circuit of road on which the character walks. He or she then battles the path’s foes, with each loop more dangerous than the last, and you left deciding if you’ll risk another go-around or chicken out and bring your hero back to base with the loot to develop farms and structures and their resulting advantages. Making its game a literal loop creates a perfect one-more-go mobile game. It’s free to download, and then $7 to unlock the full game.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Holedown</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/holedown/id1297270249">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.grapefrukt.games.bore&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>The brilliant minds at Grapefrukt Games have brought us some all-time classic mobile games, like&nbsp;<em>Rymdkapsel</em> and&nbsp;<em>Twofold Inc</em>, and most recently&nbsp;<em>Subpar Pool</em>. But it’s&nbsp;<em>Holedown</em> that permanently lives on my phone. This brilliantly clever variant on the&nbsp;<em>Breakout</em> format has you bouncing squillions of balls around the screen, trying to destroy strangely shaped blocks by hitting them until their number is reduced to zero. And really interestingly, the core game is designed to be finished, a series of levels you will progress through, rather than presenting you with a <em>Tetris</em>-like increase in difficulty that increases until you inevitably game over. But it has that too, via an infinite mode with bragging rights for how far you can reach. It’s a sublimely satisfying game to play, and a very reasonable $4.</p> <hr> <h2>Crying Suns</h2>  <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/crying-suns/id1511788295">iOS</a> / <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.altshift.cryingsuns&amp;hl=en_us">Android</a></p> <p>If you’re after something a bit more strategic to stop those doomscrolling fingers, then it’s worth remembering 2019’s&nbsp;<em>Crying Suns.</em> Inspired by&nbsp;<em>FTL</em>, but putting you in charge of a far larger, far more involved ship, with several hundred crew members to worry about. With multiple sectors to explore, and deep tactics required for combat, this is perhaps one of the more involved games in the list, and yet as a roguelite it’s still intended to be played in more controlled bursts. It’s generally far better to be distracted by the peril of your fictional crew than anything going on outside the window just now. $9 for all that.</p>

 <hr> <h2>And now you…</h2> <p>This is a list that could continue on until it reaches the bottom of the internet; mobile gaming is a wonderful source of fantastic entertainment, and in between all the more involved and longer-term <em>Diablo Immortal</em>s<em>, </em>revamped Square Enix RPGs,&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Genshin Impact</em>s are a billion options that’ll provide the perfect shorter-term alternative to a doomscroll. I picked these 10 because I thought of them first, but another day it could easily have been any number of other collections. So please, drop suggestions to any games you’d recommend into the comments!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/10-best-mobile-games-balatro-slay-the-spire-android-ios-2000664549]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>