<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 10:34:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Sonic Racing: Crossworlds, Sega Does What Nintendon’t]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mario-kart-preview-shadow-2000620065</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-sonic-racing-crossworlds-sega-does-what-nintendon%E2%80%99t.1280412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I’ve played </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-previews-sonic-resident-evil-play-days-1851784271"><i><span>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds</span></i></a> <span>twice now, and both times, I had the same fleeting thought: “What if </span><i><span>Sonic</span></i><span> outruns </span><i><span>Mario Kart </span></i><span>and has the better kart racer this year?” </span><i><span>Mario Kart World </span></i><span>is pretty good. It is a really solid One of Those, and it will no doubt be a mainstay in the Switch 2’s long lifetime–but it plays things safe, has several frustrating things going on under the hood, and by God, 24 players is too damn many.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>After playing about a dozen hours of </span><i><span>World </span></i><span>with friends since the Switch 2 launched in June, playing </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>for even an hour was refreshing, as it feels like Sega is not only taking some cool risks to shake up the formula, but also making calculated choices that rein in chaos and allow for more strategic racing.</span></p> <p><i><span>Crossworlds</span></i><span>’ biggest shake-up is the introduction of the Gadget Panel, which is essentially an overhaul of </span><i><span>Team Sonic Racing</span></i><span>’s Bonus Box system. Before each race, you can use your panel to create a loadout of upgrades, usable items, and stat boosts to fit your playstyle. Some upgrades take up more space than others on your panel. My typical arsenal included the option to start each race with a monster truck transformation item that gives you a significant speed boost and also lets you trample over enemies in your path. Having something like that takes up multiple slots on your panel, but it’s an excellent way to get a head start at the beginning of a race.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>While that’s a one-and-done boost, a lot of the upgrades help you throughout a race, such as performing speed boosting air tricks faster, making your drift a little smoother, or offensive-based upgrades like giving yourself a boost every time you collide with an enemy kart. You can race in cars or the Extreme Gear hoverboards, which will define your playstyle, but your Gadget Panel lets you fine-tune it into something unique and personalized. I use the monster truck at the beginning of the race, but after I’ve gotten my head start, I want to make sure I have a smooth ride as I pass the rest of these slowpokes, so I use the rest of my panel to make my drifts faster and get a speed boost when I bump into others.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds | Competition Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1nIhfo2X0oI?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>Having all those spinning plates on screen at once would overwhelm </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>if it had taken </span><i><span>Mario Kart World</span></i><span>’s 24-player races as a challenge. However, </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>maintains a 12-player limit on its races, and after all the </span><i><span>World </span></i><span>I’d been playing, it’s become pretty clear to me that this is the sweet spot.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Yeah, having 24 players on a track at once is a good technical showcase for the Switch 2 and feeds into the usual “bigger = better” mentality that permeates through most video games, but it has also turned out to be one of </span><i><span>World</span></i><span>’s biggest frustrations. By design, if there are more racers on a track, the slightest setback will inherently give more players a chance to pass by you. One well-timed blue shell can send a first-place winner back a dozen placements with not enough time or resources to regain the lead. So much of </span><i><span>Mario Kart </span></i><span>is determined by the luck of the draw. If you get the right item, you can Bullet Bill your way to the front of the pack, but you might get something less useful. </span><i><span>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds </span></i><span>has the same item-based play, but its Gadget loadouts leave your playstyle less to chance, and its 12-player races mean that the slightest misstep isn’t punished by being tossed down the rankings into an oblivion you can’t drive out of. It adds fun complexities without becoming chaotic and convoluted to the point where only the sweatiest among us can reach first place.</span></p> <p><i><span>Crossworlds</span></i><span> is doing a lot of things right, and in light of a relatively lukewarm reception for its biggest competitor, </span><i><span>Mario </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>are potentially on an even playing field, and the blue blur could come out on top for the first time in a while. I may not be thrilled with the crossover slop this time around, but I’m eager to get on my board as Shadow when </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>launches on September 25.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mario-kart-preview-shadow-2000620065]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Awesome-Looking Games That Went Under The Radar At Gamescom 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gamescom-2025-trailers-cozy-sim-jrpg-soulslike-roguelite-2000620078</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/6-awesome-looking-games-that-went-under-the-radar-at-gamescom-2025.1280223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-onl-2025-resident-evil-silent-hill-silksong-2000618460">Gamescom 2025</a> was the biggest on record. Maybe your eyes began to glaze over from the multi-day barrage of new game announcements, trailers, and interviews. Now that the dust has begun to settle, we can finally reflect on a few of the fresh looks at cool, upcoming projects that may have gone under the radar. The following games didn’t catch the Gamescom spotlight, but they did catch my eye. Here are six neat trailers you probably missed.</p> <h2><em>Katanaut</em> is a cosmic horror slash ’em up</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Katanaut - Release Date Reveal - FGS Live From gamescom" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bCRCTGSTaBQ?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032830/Katanaut/"><em>Katanaut</em></a> is a 2D pixel art roguelite about killing tons of abominations in a post-apocalyptic urban hellscape. You run, slash, dodge, and find lots of power-ups along the way. Will survival be rewarded with some cooler sci-fi story reveals than your average roguelike? I hope so. It comes to PC on September 10.</p> <h2><em>Wild Blue</em> brings back classic Star Fox vibes</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Wild Blue | Gameplay Trailer | PC &amp; Xbox Series X|S" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mFzYMGiSrfw?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1921490/Wild_Blue/"><em>Wild Blue</em></a> is an on-rails shooter starring anthropomorphic animals trying to save the world one blown-up enemy ship at a time. It’s being developed by Chuhai Labs, founded by Giles Goddard, one of the original programmers of <em>Star Fox</em> on the SNES. While we’ve gotten a few other spiritual successors like <em>Whisker Squadron: Survivor</em>, a new Star Fox doesn’t seem in the cards anytime soon, so the more the merrier. There’s no release date yet.</p>

 <h2><em>Kaidan</em> is a samurai extraction game</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="KAIDAN - World Premiere Trailer - FGS Live From gamescom" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h7fpiG0gzqs?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3744040/Kaidan/"><em>Kaidan</em></a>‘s trailer might be giving some people Soulslike flashbacks, but it actually seems like it might have more in common with the quick, arcade action of a 3D <em>Ninja Gaiden</em>. You play as a samurai in feudal Japan fighting Cthulhu-infused horrors, but the real twist is that it’s an extraction-lite. You’ll prepare for missions, select from multiple characters, and head into them solo or with an online group to fight mythical Yokai and try to come out the other side alive. It’s confirmed for a release on PC, but there’s no timeframe yet.</p> <h2><em>Project Bloomwalker</em> is a Studio Ghibli-looking cozy sim with a twist</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Project Bloomwalker - Official Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZsmRAs0GJEo?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/21/project-bloomwalker-gamescom-hands-on-preview/"><em>Project Bloomwalker</em></a> is about removing blight from the world with a magical house that’s moved around by robotic legs. Once you settle down somewhere, you forage for materials, craft crystals, and try to get everything you need to restore the area to its natural splendor before moving on again. There are more than a few hints of <em>Howl’s Moving Castle</em> in the air, and the best part is that you get to recruit cute little creatures called Oddlings to help you with your survival crafting chores.</p> <h2><em>Lost Hellden</em> has the PS2-era JRPG charm</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Lost Hellden - Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ouvf7HwjuD0?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2355020/Lost_Hellden/"><em>Lost Hellden</em></a> is an old-school Japanese RPG with shades of PS2 classics like <em>Rogue Galaxy</em> and <em>Dragon Quest</em> 8. There’s a job system, skill tree, and painterly backdrops to the areas you’re exploring. <em>Final Fantasy</em> veteran Hitoshi Sakimoto is helping with the music, and <em>Gravity Rush</em> artist Takeshi Oga is involved with the character art. Combat blends turn-based decision-making with real-time mechanics. There’s even a card-based mini-game. It’s all there on paper, though I’ve seen enough of these kinds of games fail to stick the landing to keep me cautiously optimistic.</p> <h2><em>Morsels</em> is a <em>Pokémon</em>-like collectathon in the sewers</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="MORSELS | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fy4A0vHr6GU?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1719040/Morsels/"><em>Morsels</em></a> has you play as a mouse who transforms into strange creatures mutated by sewer life and has access to unique abilities. Structured as a roguelite, you can swap between the creatures you encounter on demand in order to fight your way back up to the surface and defeat the ruling regime of cats. Some are calling it a cross between<em> The Binding of Isaac</em> and <em>Atomicorps</em>. It looks really pretty and is mixing together enough different ideas to have a shot at distinguishing itself in a crowded genre. It’s set to launch on console and PC on November 18.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gamescom-2025-trailers-cozy-sim-jrpg-soulslike-roguelite-2000620078]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>