<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:08:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Island 3 Is In Development, Seeking Our Brains In 2028]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dead-island-3-dambuster-studios-zombie-action-rpg-2000653827</link>
            <guid>1384516</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A zombie jumps while swinging its fist.</span> © Deep Silver
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>It looks like the wait for&nbsp;<em>Dead Island 3</em> won’t be&nbsp;<em>quite</em> as long as that between&nbsp;<em>Dead Island</em>s <em>1</em> and <em>2</em>. Dambuster Studios, the team that took over development of the second mainline entry in the sprawling zombie series, remains at the helm for the follow-up, aiming for a 2028 release.</p> <p>As detailed <a href="https://x.com/bogorad222/status/2000827597106896907">by Timur222 on X</a>, Dambuster’s latest financial statements state that the UK-based subsidiary of Deep Silver (and thus Embracer) has moved straight on from 2024’s release of&nbsp;<em>Dead Island 2: Ultimate Edition</em> to working on the direct follow-up as its “primary focus.” Right now all developers are working on the game, while those in QA will be moving over too, once Luna and Mac versions of <em>DI2U&nbsp;</em>are out the door. The details state that “feature, character, world and story design” are all “moving at pace,” all with a view to releasing in the first half of 2028.</p>

 <p>The original&nbsp;<em>Dead Island</em> appeared in 2011, developed by Polish team Techland, and despite being a solid zombie first-person action-RPG, arrived in a mess of mistakes and controversies. Chief among them was the <a href="https://kotaku.com/this-games-special-edition-comes-with-a-statue-of-a-bik-5976075">severed torso statue of a bikini-clad woman</a> included in the game’s special edition, but <a href="https://kotaku.com/whoops-you-might-be-playing-an-unfinished-version-of-d-5837480">releasing the internal development build onto Steam</a> instead of the final game on launch didn’t really help. Still, once fixed, it was fun—nothing exceptional, but fun.</p>

 <p>Techland followed it up two years later with a standalone expansion (remember when we called those “expandalones” for a minute?),&nbsp;<em>Dead Island: Riptide</em>, but had a cooler reception given it repeated so many of the things that held the first game back from being great. There then came a crappy spin-off called&nbsp;<em>Escape Dead Island</em>, a rapidly abandoned MOBA called <em>Dead Island: Epidemic</em>, a remastering of the original, and a canned mobile spin-off that never saw a release. At the same time, Techland opted out of making&nbsp;<em>Dead Island 2</em>, instead moving on to much greater success with&nbsp;<em>Dying Light</em>, meaning Deep Silver had to find a new studio. That was German team Yager Development, best known for <em>Spec Ops: The Line</em>, with an expected 2015 release. It didn’t go well.</p>

 <p>By July 2015, Deep Silver announced they’d taken the game back off Yager and handed it to UK studio Sumo Digital (<em>Crackdown 3</em>,&nbsp;<em>Team Sonic Racing</em>), issuing annual proof-of-life statements for the project until 2019 when it was declared that it had changed developers yet again. That time it went to another UK team, Dambuster (formed from the ashes of the collapse of Crytek UK), and in 2023 it was <em>finally</em> released, some eight years later than originally intended. It was fine!</p> <p>It also sold well enough to justify continuing on, and we now know that Dambuster has been working on the third mainline entry since it shipped the remaster of the sequel. For what it’s worth, the financial report <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/09140280/filing-history">filed in the UK</a> also shows that the 194-person-strong company made a profit in 2024, and is sitting on assets of over £2 million. Dambuster is owned by Deep Silver, which is owned by Plaion, which is owned by Embracer, which is owned by Cthulhu.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dead-island-3-dambuster-studios-zombie-action-rpg-2000653827]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forget Apple Watch, Samsung Quietly Clears Out the Galaxy Watch Ultra (2025) Cheaper Than Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/forget-apple-watch-samsung-quietly-clears-out-the-galaxy-watch-ultra-2025-cheaper-than-black-friday-2000653577</link>
            <guid>1384513</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For those who love to stay active in the great outdoors—whether running, swimming, cycling, hiking, or really any workout you can do outside of four walls and a ceiling—the Galaxy Watch Ultra is the ultimate companion for your wrist. Designed with fitness enthusiasts in mind, it offers a rugged build and supports a wide range of activities to help you track your fitness progress. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6412/">This outdoor-ready smartwatch is currently available at a 23% discount, dropping from its original price of $650 to a more affordable $500 during this holiday season.</a></p>
<p>When we’ve written about this watch previously, it’s discount has usually come with the caveat of needing to trade-in an old watch. Not this time though. You can just save $150 without departing with any of your current tech.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6412/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Rugged Titanium Build</h2>
<p>The Galaxy Watch Ultra boasts a durable 47mm titanium face that can withstand impacts, bumps, and the rigors of outdoor activities. This tough design ensures it stands up to the elements while maintaining a sleek appearance. The titanium comes in a few color options—titanium gray, titanium white, titanium blue, and titanium silver—so you can choose one that best suits your style. The watch also offers several band choices, including a synthetic Peakform band, and a fabric-based trail band, a more robust marine band. Though, all options for this listing come exclusively with the marine band. I’m personally a big fan of the titanium gray variant as that one’s included band is a sleek orange.</p>
<p>Along with tracking your workouts, the Galaxy Watch Ultra is able to monitor your overall health. the watch tracks your sleep and daily energy levels, providing a “physical readiness” score based on factors like the quality of your sleep, heart rate, and step count.</p>
<p>The heart rate tracking is exceptionally accurate. Powered by Galaxy AI, the watch can filter out unnecessary physical movements, allowing it to deliver more precise heart rate data to help you fine-tune your workouts for better results.</p>



<p>For an added bonus, the watch gives personalized wellness tips, offering insights based on your daily activities, sleep patterns, and heart health that can help you optimize your well-being.</p>
<p>The Galaxy Watch Ultra’s battery can go for up to 60 hours on a single charge, meaning you won’t have to worry about running out of juice before your next workout. This extended battery life is particularly useful for sleep tracking. While many other smartwatches struggle to last&nbsp; a full day, night time becomes when you might want to charge it. With those, you never end up getting to utilize the sleep features. The Galaxy Watch Ultra only needs to charge every few days you can still use it to track your sleep throughout the night. The watch can even detect potential sleep apnea.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6412/">Normally priced at $650, the Galaxy Watch Ultra is now available at a significant 23% discount.</a> Save yourself $150 as you bring the price down to $500. Whether you’re a seasoned athlete or just looking for a tough and reliable fitness watch, the Galaxy Watch Ultra is a perfect choice. Makes for a great gift for the fitness freaks in your life this holiday season.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6412/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/forget-apple-watch-samsung-quietly-clears-out-the-galaxy-watch-ultra-2025-cheaper-than-black-friday-2000653577]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Drops Its microSD Card Below $0.13 per GB for Holidays, the Cheapest Nintendo Switch Storage Upgrade]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-its-microsd-card-below-0-13-per-gb-for-holidays-the-cheapest-nintendo-switch-storage-upgrade-2000653790</link>
            <guid>1384483</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Storage issues are common, but also avoidable. If you’re running out of storage on your Nintendo Switch 2 and often find yourself deleting some titles to make room for new ones, investing in an SD card can be a smart move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6411/">Right now, Amazon is offering the 256GB Samsung P9 Express microSD card for just $33, after taking 40% off its usual $55 retail price</a>. Prime members get to enjoy free delivery, so they’re saving a few extra dollars on that front too. This is also the lowest we have seen this memory card drop to since its release, but as you’d expect, the deal is selling out fast. We suggest getting your orders in as soon as you can before the price shoots back up – which could be any moment now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6411/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Spacious Capacity With Impressive Speeds</h2>
<p>Starting with the storage; you’re getting a nice 256GB of additional storage with this card, which translates into more space for the latest releases, updates, DLC, and even screenshots. You will be able to have all the titles you like installed and ready to go; no need to choose what to delete to make room for something new every few weeks. The capacity this version gets you should be enough for casual gamers who mostly play smaller indie titles. However, if you’re looking to download a bunch of large AAA games, you might want to consider grabbing the 512GB version, which is sitting at $100 at the time of writing. This will help you avoid the same old loop where you find yourself with limited storage every few weeks.</p>
<p>As for the performance, you’re looking at sequential read speeds up to 800 MB/s, which helps load games considerably faster than the brand’s standard microSD cards. That means spending less time on loading or updating, and quicker game launches. Despite the impressive capabilities, the card maintains an ideal temperature as it works, even during intense matches. That’s thanks to its Dynamic Thermal Guards, which work tirelessly to keep the card from overheating while ensuring smooth performance.</p>



<p>Best of all, the card is made to work with Nintendo Switch 2, plus it plays nicely with a range of microSD UHS-I devices, including computers, handheld consoles, tablets, and even cameras. When using it with a camera, you can expect it to capture stunning 4K video and photos like a pro!</p>
<p>You’re also getting a 6-proof protection with a 3-year limited warranty with your purchase. It’s basically temperature, drop, magnet, water, X-ray, and wearout proof, which means you’ll enjoy consistent performance 24/7. Samsung Magician software helps you keep an eye on the health of the card and monitor performance with ease.</p>
<p>All in all, if you’re looking for an easy way of boosting the overall storage of your console while still enjoying good performance, this P9 Express microSD card can be a good addition to your setup.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6411/"> It normally goes for $55, which is already quite affordable considering all that you’re getting, but the current 40% discount makes it even more approachable.</a> And since it works with a range of devices, now is a great time to pick a couple of these for your cameras, tablet, or even laptop – without blowing your budget!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6411/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-its-microsd-card-below-0-13-per-gb-for-holidays-the-cheapest-nintendo-switch-storage-upgrade-2000653790]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State Of PlayStation In 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-2025-ghost-yotei-sales-plus-price-hike-2000653527</link>
            <guid>1384450</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>If you were to ask Sony executives about PlayStation’s 2025, they’d probably tell you it was great. According to the company, the PS5 is already its </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-sales-sony-borderlands-4-patch-performance-mgs4-2000629168"><span>“most successful” console generation</span></a><span> after only five years. Thanks to all the money Sony’s made through microtransactions and subscription services like PlayStation Plus, the system the internet claims has </span><a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/ps5-has-no-games"><span>“no games”</span></a><span> is eclipsing its predecessors (as long as you don’t adjust for inflation), and it presumably still has a few years left in it. But does Sony actually have anything to show for it in year five?</span></p> <p><span>While it’s beating out previous PlayStations in terms of revenue and the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-sold-over-80-million-ps5-in-five-years-2000616264"><span>hardware sales have been staggering</span></a><span>, the PlayStation 5’s lifespan has also been defined by </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-sony-biggest-flop-failure-box-office-1851676475"><span>live-service flops</span></a><span>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-playstation-layoffs-london-studio-closure-1851289547"><span>studio closures</span></a><span>, and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-part-ii-2-remastered-ps5-ps4-remake-too-soon-1851042718"><span>time-biding remasters</span></a><span>. Throughout the PS5 era, Sony has been devouring money, but hasn’t been offering the kinds of big (and small) exclusives defined by identifiable characters, experiences, and stories that were once synonymous with the brand.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>By 2024, the PS5 seemed like a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/astro-bot-playstation-ps5-references-characters-1851640150"><span>cultural black hole</span></a><span> despite its success. Did 2025 get things back on the right track? Or was it just another year of Sony’s misguided pivots away from what made PlayStation more than just the box on which you play the games that don’t run well on Switch?</span></p>

 <h2><b>The hardware</b></h2> <p><span>While the PlayStation 5 is still a raging success for Sony, it, like most other video game hardware, was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-console-price-increase-sony-america-august-21-2000618873"><span>hit with a price hike</span></a><span>. This followed the Trump administration’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-ps5-pro-game-console-prices-tariffs-report-1851779765"><span>new tariffs</span></a><span> (though the device’s price was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-digital-edition-price-increase-uk-europe-tariffs-1851776054"><span>raised in other territories</span></a><span> outside of America, as well), which also caused Xbox to raise its prices and seemingly affected the Switch 2’s debut MSRP in June. Now the system will run you an extra $50, regardless of which SKU you buy. The standard edition costs $549.99, while the digital edition without a disc drive now costs as much as the disc-drive version did in 2020 at $499.99. The PlayStation 5 Pro, meanwhile, has been raised to a whopping $749.99, which is a hefty asking price for something that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-review-one-year-later-worth-it-price-4k-games-2000642988"><span>hasn’t made much of an impact</span></a><span>.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000648497" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000648497"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000648497">© Sony</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Historically, console prices are supposed to go down as a generation goes on. Sony has already said that the PS5 is </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-playstation-5-life-cycle-generation-sony-1851257227"><span>entering the “later stages of its life,</span></a><span>” and the PS6 is </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps6-next-gen-xbox-price-specs-leak-release-date-2000635303"><span>supposedly on the way</span></a><span>. But even as the PS5 enters its twilight years, it’s more expensive than ever. The only time you probably would’ve paid more for the thing is when it was scarce and scalpers were reselling it. (A cheaper model was also </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-announces-cheaper-ps5-thats-only-for-japan-2000643085"><span>released in Japan earlier this year</span></a><span>, but it’s region-locked.)</span></p>

 <p><span>The PS5 may have gone up in price, but one of its peripherals went down and stayed there. The PlayStation VR2’s $550 price tag </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/psvr2-price-discount-cheap-hitman-playstation-ps5-1851766790"><span>nosedived to $400 in February</span></a><span> following reports that Sony had </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-vr2-headsets-production-sales-halt-sony-1851344240"><span>halted manufacturing</span></a><span> the headset as it struggled to meet its original projections. This makes it not unsurprising that Sony itself didn’t do much to support the PSVR2 in 2025. A few notable third-party projects like </span><i><span>Lumines Arise</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Hitman World of Assassination</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Alien Rogue Incursion</span></i><span> kept the VR sickos fed, but Sony didn’t do much of note with the thing in 2025.</span></p>

 <p><span>Also on the hardware side, Sony is finally making the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-portal-the-kotaku-review-1851015770"><span>PlayStation Portal</span></a><span> what it always should have been. The streaming handheld was previously a Remote Play machine that let you stream your PS5 to it, but now the device </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-portal-cloud-streaming-update-ps5-patch-2000641330"><span>can stream games</span></a><span> directly from the cloud, rather than bouncing them off another system.</span></p>

 <h2><b>The software</b></h2> <p><span>Broadly speaking, booting up a PS5 hasn’t changed much in 2025. Yeah, Sony brought back a few </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-update-new-april-24-retro-ps2-ps3-theme-sound-focus-1851777579"><span>dynamic themes</span></a><span> after previously making them a limited-time flourish, but beyond that, </span><a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/"><span>scrolling through the system’s 2025 system software patch notes</span></a><span> shows a lot of small quality-of-life changes, a few accessibility updates like the addition of an audio focus option to make soft sounds come through on headphones more clearly, and more customization options for the main menu UI. There’s a lot for audiophiles to chew on, but overall, the PS5 user experience is in a pretty alright place. Don’t fix what ain’t broke.</span></p> <h2><b>The services</b></h2> <p><span>The PS5’s price wasn’t the only one Sony raised this year. The cost of PlayStation Plus, the subscription service that lets users play online, add free monthly games to their collection, and stream a huge library of older titles at higher tiers, was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-price-increase-ps-plus-canada-mexico-ps5-tariffs-1851776655"><span>also hiked in April in multiple countries</span></a><span>, and Sony is </span><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sony-says-it-will-continue-to-adjust-ps-plus-pricing-as-more-players-choose-higher-tiers/"><span>open to doing it again</span></a><span>. This </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-ps-plus-ps5-game-pass-price-spider-man-2-starfield-1850787462"><span>wasn’t the first time Sony’s done this in the PS5 era</span></a><span>, either. It feels like as more people are putting time into free-to-play games, Sony is looking for different ways to squeeze some juice out of them through subscriptions and microtransactions.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000645472" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000645472"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000645472">© Sucker Punch</figcaption></figure> <h2><b>The games</b></h2> <p><span>But none of the above matters if the games aren’t there. The PlayStation 5 has ingrained itself so completely into the public consciousness as the de facto video game console on your TV that Xbox won’t tell us its sales numbers anymore. As a result of its market domination, the success of any PS5 game can be considered a PS5 win by association. Huge breakthrough games like </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 </span></i><span>don’t even have to be Sony games for the PS5 maker to benefit. </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>can continue to scrape in </span><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/fortnites-hold-on-revenue-and-maus-remains-in-july-2025-newzoo-charts"><span>billions in revenue</span></a><span> and if those microtransactions happen through the PlayStation Store, Sony’s getting a cut. So what is Sony actually doing with the hypothetical freedom you get from being top dog? In 2025, not a lot.</span></p>

 <p><span>Continuing a grim trend from recent years, Sony studios in 2025 were repeatedly hit by layoffs </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/days-gone-sony-bend-canceled-shooter-layoffs-1851784264"><span>after live-service projects failed to take off</span></a><span>. And yet, PlayStation higher-ups continue to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-live-service-concord-marathon-smoothly-2000616270"><span>insist that this is the way forward</span></a><span> for the company that was once defined by more than a desperate need to hook someone into dailies and microtransactions. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-bungie-marathon-destiny-2-acquisition-fiscal-2000642935"><i><span>Marathon </span></i><span>was delayed even as </span><i><span>Destiny 2 </span></i><span>is struggling</span></a><span>, so the major PlayStation pillars this year were </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/death-stranding-2-review-is-it-good-ps5-playstation-5-1851784852"><i><span>Death Stranding 2</span></i></a><span>, which will eventually go to other platforms, and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-september-2025-sales-borderlands-4-final-fantasy-tactics-2000638319"><i><span>Ghost of Yotei</span></i></a><span>, which, despite </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sucker-punch-charlie-kirk-ghost-yotei-boycott-2000646987"><span>manufactured controversy</span></a><span>, has sold millions of copies and is a GOTY season darling.</span></p> <p><span>So yeah, the PlayStation 5 has had a good year on paper, but how much of that is actually the result of Sony’s own legwork? When all is said and done, I’m sure the company will have a wonderful earnings report after the fiscal year is over, and it will have no reason to learn anything from its failed projects and fired workers.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The problem with Sony’s nearly monopolistic hold on the AAA console market this generation is that PlayStation, as a brand, has become so ubiquitous that it doesn’t need an identity anymore. Incredible games make their way to the PlayStation 5 more than any other console, whether that be because the Switch 2 can’t run them well or because developers </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cm24PAjAbBc"><span>decide that releasing on Xbox, with its smaller attachment rate, isn’t worth the risky investment</span></a><span>. So yeah, PlayStation has “won” the imagined console war, and now its internal line-up doesn’t have to stand out the way it once did. The company can just release a big AAA-ass video game every once in a while and get major awards buzz. Most of PlayStation’s output in recent years has felt influenced by prestige television, with cinematic games like </span><i><span>The Last of Us</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>God of War</span></i><span> becoming the video game equivalent of Oscar bait, lapping up praise and acclaim every year. Those games are, perhaps, the final echoes of the time when PlayStation was moving artistic mountains, but nowadays, they feel like they exist largely to prop up an assembly line of failed live-service efforts, and none of the smaller, quirkier, or more low-stakes experiences that once made PlayStation’s catalog the most diverse of all the console makers’ are anywhere to be found.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000283254" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000283254"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000283254">© HBO</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Last year </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/astro-bot-kotaku-review-playstation-5-1851640280"><i><span>Astro Bot</span></i></a> <span>was released, a celebration of PlayStation history that was conspicuously lacking in characters and references to PlayStation 5 games. If that game had launched in 2025 instead, I don’t think that would have changed. The PS5 has been a huge financial success for Sony, so it doesn’t really have to be anything else in the eyes of those who are making the big decisions. PlayStation has always been a business, but now the people who used to come out on stage at events like E3 and pitch people on a specific, defined experience that PlayStation could offer </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-shawn-layden-live-service-sony-last-us-online-1851772581"><span>have mostly left the company</span></a><span> as it has abandoned passion projects like </span><i><span>Gravity Rush</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Dreams</span></i><span>,</span> <span>and </span><i><span>Sly Cooper </span></i><span>to try (and repeatedly fail) to enter the live-service rat race. Even the games that were once some of the brand’s strongest artistic statements </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661"><span>will be bled dry</span></a><span> until whatever integrity those works once had is just a distant memory.</span></p> <p><span>We’re five years into the PS5 generation, and despite it being the “most successful” console ever in Sony’s line-up, the company has remarkably little cultural cache to show for it beyond the PS5’s name becoming the video game equivalent of everyone calling a bandage a “Band-Aid.” And hey, it looks like you can iron out all those wrinkles, quirks, and charms and still make it to the top of the video game food chain. In two generations on top, PlayStation has achieved the kind of ubiquity the Sony higher-ups probably wanted, and all it cost the brand was its soul.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-2025-ghost-yotei-sales-plus-price-hike-2000653527]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s Final PlayStation VR2 Clearance for Holidays, Last Units Are Hitting Their Lowest Price Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonys-final-playstation-vr2-clearance-for-holidays-last-units-are-hitting-their-lowest-price-ever-2000653520</link>
            <guid>1384447</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Still looking for the right gaming-oriented gift this holiday season? While we’re start off the final weeks of December, some retailers are reinitiating Black Friday-level discounts to aid with your holiday shopping. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6410/">One of the standout deals at Amazon is for the PlayStation VR2, which is now priced at just $299, down from its usual $400.</a> This discount of $101 makes it an excellent holiday gift option.</p>
<p data-start="382" data-end="692">For many, the price of virtual reality headsets like the PlayStation VR2 can prove quite the barrier to entry. However, with the PSVR2 now at its lowest price ever, it’s an ideal time to jump in. This deal slashes the cost a full quarter of its retail price, making it a lot more tempting.</p>
<p data-start="694" data-end="1154">The PSVR2 packs some impressive features, borrowing from the PlayStation 5’s DualSense controller with its haptic feedback and adaptive triggers. It also includes finger touch detection, eye tracking, 3D audio, and headset feedback for a fully immersive experience. The headset boasts aa 110° field of view on its 4K HDR display that runs at 120fps, thanks to two OLED screens with 2000 x 2040 resolution each—four times the resolution of the original PlayStation VR.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6410/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p data-start="1156" data-end="1477">One of the standout features of the PSVR2 is the 3D audio, which enhances the feeling of being inside the game. You’ll be able to hear every whisper in your ear, pinpoint the location of enemies or allies by the sound of their footsteps or gunshots, and experience a soundscape that adapts to your movements and position.</p>
<p data-start="1479" data-end="1696">To use the PSVR2, you simply connect it to your PlayStation 5 console, making setup easy. It’s not limited to VR games either; you can also enjoy non-VR content in Cinematic Mode, adding even more value to the device.</p>


<h2 data-start="1479" data-end="1696">What to Play</h2>
<p>If you’re a fan of the Horizon series with&nbsp;<em>Horizon: Zero Dawn&nbsp;</em>and <em>Horizon: Forbidden West</em>, then you’ll want to experience the complete saga as its stands now with&nbsp;<em>Horizon: Call of the Mountain</em>—a title exclusive to PSVR2. Take on a first person perspective as you explore the stunning vistas of this world through the eyes of a new character, Ryas. Scale large cliffs with your pickaxes and take down large enemies by really drawing back a bow.</p>
<p>There are also some awesome multiplatform VR titles that have found another home on PSVR2. The rhythm game Beat Saber is the must-own titles for anyone with a virtual reality headset, and&nbsp;<em>Superhot</em> is still an unbeatable experience that uses the medium at its full capacity.</p>
<p data-start="1698" data-end="1990" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">If you’ve been waiting for the perfect time to grab a PlayStation VR2, now’s your chance. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6410/">The $299 price tag at Amazon means you’re saving $101, but keep in mind that you’ll need a PS5 to use it.</a> It’s a great deal for anyone looking to dive into the world of VR gaming this holiday season.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6410/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonys-final-playstation-vr2-clearance-for-holidays-last-units-are-hitting-their-lowest-price-ever-2000653520]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong‘s Sea Of Sorrows DLC Announced, Plus A Free Switch 2 Upgrade For The Original Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-dlc-sea-of-sorrows-switch-2-2000653816</link>
            <guid>1384432</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Hornet stands in a splashy puddle.</span> © Team Cherry / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>It still feels odd to live in a post-<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> reality. The game was ephemeral for so many years that it feels almost crass for it to have been released three months ago. It probably helps that it’s been <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/hollow-knight-silksong/critic-reviews/?platform=pc">rapturously received</a>—among <a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-review-hornet-team-cherry-2000639568">more nuanced criticism</a>—and there’s now more good news: somehow, improbably, Team Cherry is well on its way to releasing a <em>free </em>expansion due in 2026. That accompanies the excellent news that those who bought the original <em>Hollow Knight</em>&nbsp;for Switch will soon be entitled to a free upgrade to a refreshed version for Switch 2.</p> <p>The enigmatically quiet Team Cherry has <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/holiday2025">posted an update to its hilariously infrequently updated blog</a>, detailing the news, but also making clear the small team’s delight at the success of the game’s release. Stating that <strong>over seven million people</strong> have bought the game so far (does quick math, takes off 30 percent for store tithes…that’s $98 million!), Team Cherry says “your continued enthusiasm remains a massive motivator as we work towards expanding the game even further.”</p>   <p>This leads us to the freshly announced expansion,&nbsp;<em>Sea of Sorrow</em>. There’s a teaser trailer, but don’t expect to get anything from it.</p>

  <p>Well that could have been a text message. <em>Sea of Sorrow</em> will have new areas (seemingly wetter than most), bosses and tools, in an expansion that will be completely free when it releases—Team Cherry claims—next year. But seriously? Anyone believe that? Come on. 2027 at the earliest, <em>for sure</em>. Actual information about the DLC, beyond that it has a nautical setting, will be held until “shortly before” the expansion is out, so expect more self-imposed silence from the developers, and then presumably a reply on the Discord when it slips.</p>

 <p>It’s all good, though! Of course they should take their time. It’s a passion project, no one’s entitled to it by a certain date, and it’s being given away for free. Plus they just made $100,000,000—why is any of them even acknowledging the existence of game development right now?</p>

 <p>Yet, still Team Cherry works, leading to even more generous news that there’s to be a Switch 2 refresh of the original&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight</em>, and that too will be given to owners of the original Switch version for free! This will add improved framerates, a higher resolution, and a bunch of graphical effects that appeared in&nbsp;<em>Silksong</em>. If you want a sneak peak of that updated goodness, you can jump into the beta branches on Steam or GOG, which include 21:9 support for ultrawide sickos.</p> <p>There are claims that there are even more plans for 2026, which are currently secret, but also word that Team Cherry’s games will be on sale across various stores over the holiday season. Given&nbsp;<em>Silksong</em> was already only $20, that could mean some proper bargains.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-dlc-sea-of-sorrows-switch-2-2000653816]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP Doesn’t Care About Profit With This 72% Off 15.6″ Laptop Bundle (16GB RAM, 1TB SSD), Even a MacBook Can’t Compete]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hp-doesnt-care-about-profit-with-this-72-off-15-6-laptop-bundle-16gb-ram-1tb-ssd-even-a-macbook-cant-compete-2000653800</link>
            <guid>1384429</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s not every day Amazon lets you pick a highly-rated laptop for less. If you’ve been looking to upgrade your everyday office/study machine but the scary price tags have been holding you back, the retailer is making it incredibly easy to grab one without shelling out big bucks.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6417/">We’re spotting plenty of solid deals across a range of models like HP, Dell, Asus, Lenovo, and more, but one of our favorite offers is the 72% discount on the HP 15.6-inch touchscreen business lapto</a>p. You’re saving a whopping $1,720 on this highly-rated model and getting some useful computer accessories for free, but the deal is only around for today. It wraps up at midnight, so it’s best to bag the drop as soon as you can. Once it’s gone, we don’t expect it to be back before New Year’s.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6417/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Vibrant Visuals on the Touchscreen</h2>
<p>In a portable build, you’re getting an impressive 15.6-inch FHD IPS touchscreen that delivers brilliant, sharp visuals. You’ll enjoy vibrant colors and sharp details for all your favorite TV shows and movies, plus be able to read text better. The 178-degree wide viewing angle offers consistent visuals from all sides, while the micro-edge design offers larger screen real estate to work on. Touch support takes the experience a bit further by letting you use your fingers directly on the screen to perform a bunch of tasks. You’d be able to scroll through long documents without relying on the trackpad, swipe through images, browse, sketch, and even type. Note that the screen does not fold all the way back like a 2-in-1, so this thing won’t convert into a tablet for an only-screen experience, but the touch support still comes in handy, especially when you don’t want to bother with the mouse or the keys.</p>



<p>There’s an HD camera right above the display, which is paired with AI noise reduction. Both of these come together to make your video calls better; you will look good, and sound just as great. The battery life is another strong selling point. A single charge gets you up to 9 hours of usage, which means you can go an entire workday without plugging it in. Even better, recharging is just as quick. HP Fast Charge juices your laptop from 0 to 50% in just 45 minutes. You can plug it in during lunch break and come back to a machine that’s ready to go.</p>
<p>Power-wise, the laptop features an 8-core Intel Core i3-N305 processor. It works with 16GB of RAM to deliver the performance you need for your everyday tasks, plus some demanding projects. There’s a built-in 1TB SSD that offers plenty of space to store all your important files and documents without feeling limited, plus delivers fast boot/load times.</p>
<p>Windows 11 Pro also comes pre-installed. Other freebies include a Redragon patented wireless mouse, an external optical drive, and a screen wipe. Together, these cost around $200, but you’re getting the kit here for absolutely nothing. That said, the discount is only around for a few more hours, and the stock could sell out before the offer ends. Grab it before that happens!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6417/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hp-doesnt-care-about-profit-with-this-72-off-15-6-laptop-bundle-16gb-ram-1tb-ssd-even-a-macbook-cant-compete-2000653800]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>