<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:12:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Is Scrambling To Address AI Accusations Over Double-Barreled Gun]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-ai-stickers-cosmetics-bundle-2000655167</link>
            <guid>1390612</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The player backlash against generative AI in gaming <a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33s-loses-indie-game-awards-after-being-accused-of-lying-about-ai-use-2000655119">has hit a fever pitch as we close out the year</a>, and <em>Battlefield 6</em> is the latest target of fans’ ire.<em> Kotaku</em> understands that EA is currently investigating accusations of AI slop in season 1’s recent <span dir="auto">winter cosmetics and trying to determine just exactly how the controversial technology may or may not have been used in their production.&nbsp;</span></p> <p>The accusations started over the weekend when fans circulated one of <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-review-steam-ps5-campaign-multiplayer-2000633379"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a>‘s new stickers from the Windchill bundle, which is currently being sold for just under $10. The cosmetic shows a character aiming down the scope of a double-barreled rifle. “Two barrels on the M4A1, sure,” read one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1prq9x9/remove_this_ai_shit_from_the_store/">angry viral post</a> on the game’s subreddit. “I would literally prefer to have no sticker than some low quality AI generated garbage. You can look at <em>BO7</em> and see how many favors AI generated rewards won with them.”</p>

 <p>This led some fans to start doing an AI “vibe check” on other cosmetics in the game. While nothing as glaring as <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em>‘s six-fingered <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-generative-ai-call-duty-gamescom-2025-slop-2000618833">Santa Zombie loading screen</a> has been found, it’s raised questions about how widespread the issue might be. For example, there’s an in-game sticker of a bear who appears to have more than <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1ps4ze4/there_are_a_lot_of_things_that_dont_really_pass/">10 claws on its paws</a>. Is this just sloppy quality control or evidence that <em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s post-launch development has been outsourcing designs to generative AI tools?</p>

   <p>An AI-generated double-barreled rifle would fun afoul of a promise made earlier this year by EA VP Rebecka Coutaz, who oversees DICE and the other teams making <em>Battlefield</em>. In an <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8xrkxdkkrno">interview with the BBC</a>, she promised fans they wouldn’t see any AI-generated imagery in the final game, but admitted that the technology is used in the earlier phases of production “to allow more time and more space to be creative.”</p>

 <p>There are a couple of increasingly common ways AI slop like this might make it into a big-budget blockbuster that’s on its way to being the best-selling game of 2025. The first is that concept artists might use generative AI to create references for a design before digitally painting over those by hand. The second is that an outsourcing team EA subcontracts with ends up submitting designs for cosmetics that then slip through a rushed review process.</p>

 <p>EA has been uniquely bullish on the potential for AI to transform game development. “We view AI as a powerful accelerator of creativity, innovation, and player connection,” CEO Andrew Wilson told investors during the company’s earnings report last May. Staff across various departments, from art and QA to marketing and customer service, have been strongly encouraged to find ways to experiment with AI tools in their daily workflows. <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/inside-ai-divide-roiling-video-game-giant-electronic-arts-2025-10"><em>Kotaku</em> reported just last month</a> that the tools were used to create an entire cover for the Deluxe Edition of <em>NHL 26</em>.</p>

 <p>But while a double-barreled rifle might be a dead giveaway that AI was involved, other errors might simply be a result of quality control going down as teams rush to flood <em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s post-launch window with new content and microtransactions. According to a source familiar with the game’s production, the scope of its current roadmap has stretched resources thin when it comes to reviewing it all for any potentially embarrassing mistakes.</p> <p>EA did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-ai-stickers-cosmetics-bundle-2000655167]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Switch 2’s Most Impressive Port Is 75 Percent Off Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-switch-2s-most-impressive-port-is-75-percent-off-right-now-2000655205</link>
            <guid>1390549</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-side-quests-panam-dream-on-sinnerman-1850875179"><em>Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition</em></a> is one of the best-looking and most impressive Switch 2 ports around. And for the rest of the month, this open-world RPG is being sold for less than $20 on the Nintendo eShop alongside a bunch of other great deals on other titles.</p> <p>Today is the start of <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/sales-and-deals/#show=0&amp;p=1&amp;sort=dd&amp;f=corePlatforms&amp;corePlatforms=Nintendo+Switch+2">Nintendo’s Holiday Sale</a>, and the big star of all the deals is definitely<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em> on Switch 2, which has been marked down from $70 to $17.50. Yes, that’s the price. That’s not a typo. It’s a discount so big that deals guru <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wario64.bsky.social/post/3malqko57bb2b">Wario64 was seemingly worried</a> it might be a glitch until a press release confirmed it to be accurate. But yup, from now until January 5, you can buy <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-switch-2/?srsltid=AfmBOorZAHCtVMvYtP0x1w2bNxy9TXgL0E9uLYngGDW_ZzHT7Lwh-SE0"><em>Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition,</em> which includes the game’s <em>Phantom Liberty </em>expansion, for less than $18</a>. Wild stuff.</p>

 <p>For those who already own the port or don’t want to play it, there are other big deals and games included in Nintendo’s end-of-the-year holiday sale, including discounts on <em>RPG Divinity: Original Sin 2</em>, <em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII, Silksong,</em> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-patch-is-it-good-2000624465"><em>Star Wars: Outlaws,</em> which is another impressive Switch 2 port</a> that even supports cross-saves across all platforms.</p>

 <p>Here’s a list of some of the biggest and best deals we spotted in the ongoing sale. And just a heads-up that there are a few other sales events happening, so some of these deals might go away sooner than January 5. In other words, don’t wait too long to snag any of these games.</p> <ul> <li><em>Cyberpunk 2077: Ult. Edition – $17.50 ($70)</em></li> <li><em>Star Wars: Outlaws – $40 ($60)</em></li> <li><em>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Splintered Fate – $13 ($33)</em></li> <li><em>Survival Kids – $33 ($50)</em></li> <li><em>Street Fighter 6 – $20 ($40)</em></li> <li><em>Cronos: The New Dawn – $45 ($60)</em></li> <li><em>Shadow Labyrinth – $20 ($30)</em></li> <li><em>SpongeBob SquarePants Titans of the Tide – $30 ($40)</em></li> <li><em>Dave The Diver – $12 ($20)</em></li> <li><em>Fast Fusion – $11 ($15)</em></li> <li><em>Hollow Knight Silksong – $16 ($20)</em></li> <li><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization VII – $46 ($70)</em></li> <li><em>Ball x Pitt – $12 ($15)</em></li> <li><em>No Man’s Sky – $24 ($60)</em></li> <li><em>NBA 2K26 – $28 ($70)</em></li> <li><em>On Piece Pirate Warriors 4 – $10 ($40)</em></li> <li><em>Sonic X Shadow Generations – $25 ($50)</em></li> <li><em>Daemon X Machina: Titanic Scion – $49 ($70)</em></li> <li><em>Light Nightmares III – $28 ($40)</em></li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/the-switch-2s-most-impressive-port-is-75-percent-off-right-now-2000655205]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Vince Zampella, Battlefield Boss And Call Of Duty Co-Creator, Killed In Car Crash]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/report-vince-zampella-battlefield-boss-and-call-of-duty-co-creator-killed-in-car-crash-2000655216</link>
            <guid>1390474</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>On Sunday, Vince Zampella, executive vice president at EA, head of Respawn, and one of the devs who helped create <em>Call of Duty</em>, was killed in a car crash in Southern California.</p> <p>On Monday, <a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/video-game-developer-vince-zampella-crash-call-of-duty/3819576/"><em>NBC4</em> reported that Zampella</a> was killed in a single-car crash involving a 2026 Ferrari 296 GTS that happened on December 21 at 12:45 pm local time on a road north of Los Angeles in the San Gabriel Mountains. California Highway Patrol told the outlet that the car veered off the road and collided with a concrete barrier. The car’s passenger was ejected from the vehicle. The driver was reportedly trapped in the ensuing car fire and died at the scene. The passenger reportedly died later at a nearby hospital.</p> <p>No details have been released as to why the car crashed, nor did <em>NBC</em> specify if Zampella was the one driving.</p> <p>“It’s hard to process this right now. He was such a force in the industry and for him to be just gone I still can’t believe,” <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/witdarkstar.bsky.social/post/3mam2erg6bk2s">shared</a> Respawn developer Patrick Wren on social media.</p>

 <p>“I was fortunate enough to work with Vince a few times, and it was always a pleasure. This sucks,” <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/thevowel.bsky.social/post/3mam2borh622r">posted</a> former Xbox operations manager Eric Neustadter.</p> <p>The 55-year-old game developer was one of the key people behind the creation of <em>Call of Duty.</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/when-call-of-dutys-creators-left-they-took-a-lot-of-pe-5817329">He later left that franchise</a> and helped co-found Respawn in 2010 with fellow <em>CoD</em> developer Jason West. The studio’s first game was the critically acclaimed Xbox-only, EA-published <em>Titanfall</em>. It would later produce a sequel, a popular battle royale spin-off, and two highly successful <em>Star Wars</em> action games, <em>Jedi: Fallen Order</em> and <em>Jedi: Survivor.</em> In 2017, Respawn was acquired by EA and became a key part of the publisher’s roster of studios. In 2021, Zampella was put in charge of <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-modern-day-specialists-classes-release-da-1851649399"><em>Battlefield</em> and helped the series rebound</a> with this year’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-sales-black-ops-7-charts-2000645794">massively successful <em>Battlefield 6</em>,</a> which is one of 2025’s biggest games. Meanwhile, the franchise he helped create, <em>Call of Duty</em>, continues to be one of the biggest game franchises in the world.</p> <p><strong>Update 12/22/2025 4:10 p.m. ET:&nbsp;</strong>EA sent over this statement to <em>Kotaku</em>:</p> <blockquote><p>This is an unimaginable loss, and our hearts are with Vince’s family, his loved ones, and all those touched by his work. Vince’s influence on the video game industry was profound and far-reaching. A friend, colleague, leader and visionary creator, his work helped shape modern interactive entertainment and inspired millions of players and developers around the world. His legacy will continue to shape how games are made and how players connect for generations to come.</p></blockquote>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/report-vince-zampella-battlefield-boss-and-call-of-duty-co-creator-killed-in-car-crash-2000655216]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>