<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:02:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Elder Scrolls Online Boss Breaks Silence On Game Cancelation That Drove Him From Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-online-project-blackbird-shooter-rpg-canceled-microsoft-2000656493</link>
            <guid>1396174</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Matt Firor founded Zenimax Online in 2007 and helped Bethesda shepherd<em> The Elder Scrolls Online</em> into one of the premier MMORPGs out there. He left abruptly last summer when Microsoft laid off dozens at the studio amid a wider bloodbath at the company and canceled the upcoming online multiplayer game he and others were working on, <a href="https://kotaku.com/blackbird-mmorpg-leaks-gta-dan-houser-eso-free-2000615981">Project Blackbird</a>. He recently broke his silence on the reason for his departure, confirming what fans had long suspected.</p> <p>“Project Blackbird was the game I had waited my entire career to create, and having it canceled led to my resignation,” Firor wrote in a January 1 post on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7412202293737046016/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-id="inline-link" data-url="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7412202293737046016/" data-hl-processed="none" data-mrf-recirculation="inline-link" data-hawk-tracked="hawklinks" data-mrf-link="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7412202293737046016/">LinkedIn</a>&nbsp;which he later <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:sdsbjnwwyzxwz3b4lqtbtwd5/post/3mbeicw5hgw2f?ref_src=embed&amp;ref_url=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.pcgamer.com%252Fgames%252Fmmo%252Fformer-elder-scrolls-online-chief-confirms-microsofts-2025-bloodbath-drove-his-departure-from-zenimax-project-blackbird-was-the-game-i-had-waited-my-entire-career-to-create%252F">shared on Bluesky</a>. “My heart and thoughts are always with the impacted team members, many of whom I had worked 20+ years with, and all of whom were the most dedicated, amazingly talented group of developers in the industry.”</p>   <p>The post never mentions Microsoft directly and doesn’t take aim at the decision makers at Xbox, which acquired Zenimax Online in 2021, but the move clearly left a very bad taste in many veteran developers’ mouths. Some of Firor’s former colleagues went on to form Sackbird Studios to work on their own multiplayer game. “With internal funding and full creative control, the studio is focused on crafting bold, character-driven experiences free from corporate compromises,” they <a href="https://kotaku.com/halo-studios-gta-6-price-fortnite-simpsons-2000633663">wrote last year</a>.</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-layoffs-zenimax-online-blackbird-elder-scrolls-1851785629"><em>Bloomberg</em> reported</a> that Blackbird was an ambitious loot shooter that mixed elements of <em>Destiny</em> and <em>Blade Runner</em> with the structure and questlines of an MMORPG. Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer reportedly played a build of the game last March and loved what he saw, making its eventual cancelation even more perplexing. The layoffs and cuts came as Xbox game studios were <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-price-hike-game-pass-layoffs-new-console-2000638546">reportedly tasked</a> with achieving a controversial 30-percent profit margin despite being forced to make all of their games playable for free on Game Pass.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-online-project-blackbird-shooter-rpg-canceled-microsoft-2000656493]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Subscribers Are Back To Just Three Free Games This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-jan-2026-free-monthly-games-core-keeper-2000656495</link>
            <guid>1396156</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The first free monthly <a href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-december-2025-extra-assassins-creed-jrpg-2000652236">PlayStation Plus games</a> for paying subscribers in 2026 have been revealed and it’s a sleepy month for PS5 and PS4 players. There are also only three additions for this month, compared to last month’s five.</p> <p>On December 31, Sony revealed the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/31/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-january-need-for-speed-unbound-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-core-keeper/">first batch of PS Plus Essential games</a> coming this year and while they’re decent games, none of the picks make a big splash. These games will be available to add to your PlayStation library permanently beginning on January 6. Once added, you can install them and play them whenever you want as long as you are an active PS Plus Essential, Extra, or Premium subscriber. Here’s the list of games and what platforms they are available on:</p> <ul> <li> <p><em>Need For Speed Unbound</em> | PS5</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</em> | PS4, PS5</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Core Keeper</em> | PS4, PS5</p> </li> </ul> <p><em>Rebrushed</em> is the 2024 remaster of the 2010 platformer from <em>Deus Ex</em> director Warren Spector. Nice for anyone who didn’t play the original or wants an important lesson in game development history. <em>Unbound</em>, meanwhile, is the 25th installment in the&nbsp;<em>Need for Speed</em> series and features a neat cel-shaded art style. The 2022 release is a fun racer but far from the most memorable in the franchise.</p>

 <p><em>Core Keeper</em> is arguably the best pick-up this month. It’s a top-down pixel art crafting sim that marries <em>Minecraft</em> and <em>Stardew Valley</em>. Like those games it continues to receive meaty free updates, with one coming later this month called Void &amp; Voltage. Not the worst month overall, though not as generous as last month’s <a href="http://PlayStation Plus games">pre-holiday haul</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-jan-2026-free-monthly-games-core-keeper-2000656495]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[31 Games We Can’t Wait To Play In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/2026-game-releases-most-anticipated-batman-gta-6-wolverine-2000656197</link>
            <guid>1396138</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>2026 is shaping up to be another big year for video games. The next 12 months are set to bring massive sequels like <em>Forza Horizon 6, Resident Evil Requiem,</em> and <em>Gears of War: E-Day.</em> There are also some smaller games we’re excited to get our hands on, like <em>Bubsy 4D, Mouse: P.I. for Hire,</em> and <em>Slay The Spire 2.</em> And of course, there’s<em> Grand Theft Auto 6,</em> which, assuming it doesn’t get delayed again, will close out 2026 with a big, industry-shaking bang.</p> <p>There are so many games to be excited about in 2026 that you might have forgotten about some of them. So we here at <em>Kotaku</em> have created this handy list of 31 games we’re excited to play in the new year. Now, place your bets for how many will actually launch in 2026 and how many will instead be delayed to 2027 or beyond.</p>

 <h2><b><i>Resident Evil Requiem</i></b><b> – Feb. 27</b></h2>  <p><span>I was already excited for a new mainline </span><i><span>Resident Evil</span></i><span> game arriving in early 2026; you didn’t need to add Leon Kennedy. But I’m very grateful. -Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight </i></b><b>– 2026&nbsp;</b></h2>  <p><span>We ain’t getting a new </span><i><span>Arkham </span></i><span>game anytime soon, so this Lego spin on the formula will have to do. Luckily, it looks rad as heck. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><b><i>Forza Horizon 6 </i></b><b>– 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>The follow-up to one of the best Xbox games ever made, and it’s set in a gorgeously dense open-world recreation of Japan. Yup. That’s going to be goooood. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Control Resonant </i></b><b>– 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>Remedy’s 2019 </span><i><span>Control </span></i><span>was a wonderful and creepy paranormal shooter. I’ve desperately wanted a sequel, and that’s finally arriving next year. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Mouse: P.I. for Hire </i></b><b>– March 19</b></h2>  <p><span>Mixing a boomer shooter with classic black-and-white cartoons is an odd choice, but the final product seems awesome, and we don’t have to wait long to play. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>007 First Light –</i></b><b> March 26</b></h2>  <p><span>IOI, the people behind </span><i><span>Hitman</span></i><span>, seem like the perfect studio to make a James Bond game. Hopefully, it all comes together in the spring. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><b><i>Bubsy 4D</i></b><b> – 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>I didn’t have “Excited for a new <em>Bubsy</em> game” on my bingo card for 2026, but here we are. What can I say? <em>Bubsy 4D</em> looks good. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>The Duskbloods</i></b><b> – 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>FromSoftware’s upcoming eight-player online action RPG sounds like a great idea </span><i><span>now</span></i><span>, after </span><i><span>Nightreign </span></i><span>proved to be a huge hit and a great game. Hopefully, the Switch 2 is able to handle it. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><b><i>Gears of War: E-Day </i></b><b>– 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>I’m sad that <em>Gears 5</em>’s story isn’t moving forward. Still, it should be fun seeing Marcus and Dom back together in this upcoming prequel to the OG Xbox 360 trilogy. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><b><i>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</i></b><b> – 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>So many <em>Star Wars</em> games are RPGs, shooters, or action-adventure experiences. That’s fine, but I’m happy to see someone making a racing game set in my favorite sci-fi universe. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><strong><em>Marathon</em> – March 2026</strong></h2>  <p>The it’s over/we’re so back graph has been all over the place on this one, but with a series of post-alpha test tweaks, including the addition of proximity chat, I’m once again looking forward to seeing Bungie’s take on the extraction shooter, especially if they can weave as much of the background sci-fi lore into a <em>Destiny</em>-style aspirational end-game as I’m hoping they can. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><b><i>Grand Theft Auto 6</i></b><b> – November 19&nbsp;</b></h2>  <p><span>At this point, I feel like I’ve written so many words about the upcoming</span><i><span> GTA 6 </span></i><span>that I’m not sure what else to say. You know what this game is. You are probably excited for it. Let’s hope Rockstar lands this sucker. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Marvel’s Wolverine</i></b><span> –<strong> 2026</strong></span></h2>  <p><span>Insomniac’s </span><i><span>Spider-Man</span></i><span> games have been joyous open-world treats that feel great to play. So people are understandably excited for the studio’s upcoming </span><i><span>Wolverine </span></i><span>game that looks fun and very, very bloody. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><strong><em>Saros</em> – April 30</strong></h2>  <p><em>Returnal</em> will always have a special place in my heart, but I’m looking forward to seeing Housemarque branch off into a more forgiving roguelike arcade shooter structure with a robust metagame progression that gives more players more footholds, which will hopefully see more of them hang on and stick it out for the whole ride. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><strong><em>Mina the Hollower</em> – 2026</strong></h2>  <p>Following a brief delay, I can’t wait to see the <em>Shovel Knight</em> team’s take on <em>Castlevania</em> meets <em>The Legend of Zelda: Link’s Awakening</em>. I’m looking forward to a retro homage that pushes the genres it’s playing with to new heights. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p>

 <h2><strong><em>Replaced</em> – March 12</strong></h2>   <p>This game looks incredible. Looking at it will be enough. Playing it will hopefully feel extra special. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><em>Forbidden Solitaire&nbsp;</em>– Q1 2026</h2>  <p><i><span>Forbidden Solitaire </span></i><span>is ostensibly about you finding and playing a spooky ‘90s CD-ROM solitaire game—think </span><i><span>The 7th Guest </span></i><span>but, y’know, solitaire—and getting way more than you bargained for. I have no idea what that means in gameplay terms, but I can’t wait to find out. – Carolyn Petit</span></p> <h2><strong><em>The Blood of Dawnwalker</em>&nbsp; – 2026</strong></h2>  <p>Ex-<em>Witcher 3</em> devs make a vampire immersive-sim RPG. Enough said. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><strong><em>Danganronpa 2×2</em> – 2026</strong></h2>  <p><em>Danganronpa 2: Goodbye Despair</em> is getting a fancy remake, but it’s also getting a new “what if” scenario in which different victims and killers manifest in its murder mystery. So hey, even if the new storyline isn’t great, we’ll get to play <em>Danganronpa 2&nbsp;</em>again. – Kenneth Shepard</p>

 <h2><strong><em><i>Pokémon</i> Champions</em> – 2026</strong></h2>  <p><i data-stringify-type="italic">Pokémon Champions&nbsp;</i>is the new competitive platform for the series moving forward, and it’s going to integrate several mechanics, such as Mega Evolution and Z-Moves, into one place, meaning it has the potential to completely transform the competitive space, and free up the main games to no longer be beholden to a particular way of doing things. – Kenneth Shepard</p> <h2><b><i>Mario Tennis Fever</i></b><b> – February 12</b></h2>  <p><span>The world needs more fun tennis games. Thank you, Mario and company, for hearing these calls and showing up so early in 2026 to deliver a game that looks like it’ll be exactly what folks want. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>

 <h2><b><i>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</i></b><b> – 2026</b></h2>  <p><span>Sure, another remake of the first </span><i><span>Tomb Raider game </span></i><span>seems a bit silly. But, hey, it looks great and will hold fans over until 2027’s </span><i><span>Tomb Raider: Catalyst.</span></i><span> – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><strong><em><i>Pokémon</i> Pokopia</em> – March 5</strong></h2>  <p><em><i>Pokémon</i> Pokopia </em>appears to be Pikachu and friends’ take on an <em>Animal Crossing</em>-style life sim, but it also seems to have a dark, post-apocalyptic setting that might keep it from being as cozy as other games in the genre. Intriguing! – Kenneth Shepard</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Pragmata</em> – April 24</strong></h2>  <p>New AAA franchises are so few and far between, it’s a special treat whenever we get one, especially out of Japan. It’s not 3D <em>Mega Man</em> but it might be the next best thing. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><strong><em>Marvel Tokon Fighting Souls</em> – 2026</strong></h2>  <p>When it comes to anime fighters, you don’t bet against Arc System Works.&nbsp;<em>Marvel Tokon Fighting Souls&nbsp;</em>is a 4v4 fighting game with Earth’s Mightiest Heroes on the roster, and it looks pretty rad. – Kenneth Shepard</p> <h2><strong><em>Scott Pilgrim EX</em> – 2026</strong></h2>  <p>It’s about time we got a new&nbsp;<em>Scott Pilgrim&nbsp;</em>beat em up, and this time, it’s coming with a brand new story by series’ creator Bryan Lee O’Malley set after the events of the <em>Scott Pilgrim Takes Off&nbsp;</em>anime. – Kenneth Shepard</p> <h2><strong><em>Demon Tides</em> – February 19</strong></h2>  <p><em>Demon Tides&nbsp;</em>is a modern-day PS2-style mascot platformer that manages to nail the middle ground between pinpoint precision and free-flowing, fast-paced action that so many others in the genre can’t quite inhabit. – Kenneth Shepard</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Nocturne</em> – June 30</strong></h2>  <p>I had to get at least one rhythm game on this list, and <em>Nocturne</em>, a rhythm RPG inspired by science fantasy games of the ’90s, is basically&nbsp;<em>Guitar Hero</em> meets&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy</em>. – Kenneth Shepard</p> <h2><strong><em>Slay the Spire 2</em>– March 2026</strong></h2>  <p>I slept on the first <em>Slay the Spire</em> when it initially launched. I will not make that mistake again. With most sequels I want a little bit more than just “bigger and better,” but with <em>Slay the Spire 2</em> that will be more than enough. <span>– Ethan Gach</span></p> <h2><b><i>Halo: Campaign Evolved</i></b><b> –</b><strong> 2026</strong></h2>  <p><span>Like </span><i><span>Tomb Raider</span></i><span>, it’s a bit silly that we are getting yet another remake of the first </span><i><span>Halo</span></i><span>, but this one is coming to PlayStation 5, and I wish I could go back in time and tell 12-year-old Zack that fact. It would blow his dumb pre-teen mind. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p> <h2><b><i>Yoshi and the Mysterious Book –</i></b><strong> 2026</strong></h2>  <p><span>This ain’t the Nintendo platformer I was hoping for in 2026, but it looks cute, and for folks who love the </span><i><span>Yoshi </span></i><span>games, well, here’s another one for you. – Zack Zwiezen</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/2026-game-releases-most-anticipated-batman-gta-6-wolverine-2000656197]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>