<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:49:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s Budget Wireless Headphones Just Got Even Cheaper With a Nearly 50%, Priced Like No-Brand Wired Earbuds]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonys-budget-wireless-headphones-just-got-even-cheaper-with-a-nearly-50-priced-like-no-brand-wired-earbuds-2000652308</link>
            <guid>1379911</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The market is overflowing with headphones, but does that mean every other option out there is worth your money? Not at all. Those on a budget looking to grab a solid pair – we come bearing good news.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4594/">Amazon just slashed the Sony WH-CH520 wireless headphones by 46%, bringing the price down to just $38</a>. You’re saving $32 on a pair that not only gets you premium, high-quality sound but also offers an incredible battery life. All color options are discounted, so there’s plenty to choose from. Prefer your audio gear minimal? Go for the stunning blue version. Those who want their headphones to have a bit of a personality can consider the pink or yellow options! The retailer is also throwing in a two-month trial to Audible with your purchase to sweeten the deal even more.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4594/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Custom Sound Experience</h2>
<p>There’s nothing too crazy going on looks-wise, which is a good thing. The lightweight build features an adjustable headband, paired with swivel earcups that slip on and off gently. The ear pads are soft, plus they come with an additional head cushion and silent joints, making it easy to wear these headphones for an extended period of time. You’ll be able to survive those never-ending commutes, plus boring tasks that otherwise feel unbearable.</p>
<p>Everyone has different sound preferences, and this pair takes care of that. It pushes high-quality, rich audio, but you can further customize the listening experience by tailoring it according to your taste using the EQ Custom feature on the Sony Headphones Connect app. The platform lets you pick from a wide range of presets to match the quality of the sound to what’s playing. Go for a deeper bass for energy-filled tracks, and tone it down when something a bit calmer plays. DSEE support makes it easy to enhance the quality of compressed music files just as well. There’s even a built-in microphone for easy hands-free calling on the go, without having to pull your phone out; great for catching up with friends while travelling, and hopping onto work meetings while sitting in a cafe.</p>



<p>Pairing these Bluetooth headphones with up to two devices at the same time is made possible with Multipoint connection. For instance, if you have them connected to your phone and laptop, you can stream music on the former and quickly switch to the latter when it’s time for a Zoom session. Those losing track of their essentials often will appreciate how you can check the last known location of the headphones in Google’s Find My Device app on your smartphone.</p>
<p>Battery life is significantly better than most other options in this range. You’re looking at around 50 hours of continuous listening on a single charge. That’s more than enough to get through at least a few days without worrying about running out. Running low but don’t have the time to juice them up fully? No sweat. A quick 3-minute top-up gets you an additional 90 minutes of playback!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4594/">There’s a lot more to like about these headphones, especially now at their current price.</a> These offer exceptional battery life and impressive sound, plus let you customize your listening experience according to your preferences. All six colors are discounted, so you can pick the one that fits your aesthetics the best.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4594/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonys-budget-wireless-headphones-just-got-even-cheaper-with-a-nearly-50-priced-like-no-brand-wired-earbuds-2000652308]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker Is Offloading Warehouse Stock Including Its 14-in-1 Docking Station, Like a Second Black Friday for the Holidays]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anker-is-offloading-warehouse-stock-including-its-14-in-1-docking-station-like-a-second-black-friday-for-the-holidays-2000652283</link>
            <guid>1379854</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="98" data-end="638">Many laptop users rely solely on the hardware built into their machines, and while modern laptops are impressively capable, doing everything on the laptop alone can actually hold you back. Even a 17-inch notebook—considered fairly large by portable-PC standards—still feels small compared to the displays most people use today. External monitors commonly start around 27 inches, offering significantly more screen real estate, and some setups go far beyond that with ultra-wide or even 4K panels that dramatically expand your field of view.</p>
<p data-start="640" data-end="1240">If you spend a lot of time typing at your desk, you might prefer the feel and responsiveness of a mechanical keyboard over your laptop’s built-in keys. Maybe your laptop’s speakers don’t produce the volume or clarity you want, leading you to plug in external ones. Add in a separate microphone for calls, a pair of headphones for focus, or even a drawing tablet if you’re an artist, and suddenly you have an entire desk ecosystem of peripherals that your laptop needs to connect to. The problem? Many modern laptops come with only one or two USB ports—nowhere near enough for all these accessories.</p>
<p data-start="1242" data-end="1579">That’s where a reliable USB hub becomes essential. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5667/">The Anker USB-C docking station fits this role perfectly, and even better, it’s currently available at a significant discount. Right now you can save 38%,</a> which knocks $27 off the original price. Instead of paying $70, you’ll only spend $43—a great deal for the functionality it offers.</p>
<p data-start="1242" data-end="1579">In need of more than one? The two-pack is also on sale for… exactly the same price as buying two individually… How about that?</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5667/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="1242" data-end="1579">Extended View with Triple Display</h2>
<p data-start="1581" data-end="2206">This docking station serves as a simple, single-cable solution that helps eliminate desk clutter and keep your workspace tidy. Plug one USB-C cable into your laptop, and suddenly all your accessories—monitors, storage devices, audio gear, and more—are connected at once. The dock supports 4K video output at up to 60Hz through its HDMI port, making it ideal for watching high-resolution content or expanding your desktop across multiple screens. While the USB-C data port doesn’t support video output, the hub includes two HDMI ports plus a VGA port, allowing you to connect as many as three external displays simultaneously.</p>


<p data-start="2208" data-end="2532">Charging is handled impressively well too. The same USB-C connection used for data and displays can also power your laptop. The dock supports up to 80W of passthrough charging, meaning you can leave your original power adapter in your bag. With the hub powering your device, you free up ports and simplify your entire setup.</p>
<p data-start="2534" data-end="2712">File transfers are fast and efficient, thanks to both USB-C and USB-A ports capable of speeds up to 5Gbps. Moving large documents, photos, or videos becomes quick and convenient.</p>
<p data-start="2714" data-end="2937" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">With its current 38% price drop, the Anker USB-C hub is an excellent value. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5667/">For just $43, you get powerful connectivity, cleaner desk organization, and a smoother overall workflow—all while saving $27 off the regular price.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5667/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anker-is-offloading-warehouse-stock-including-its-14-in-1-docking-station-like-a-second-black-friday-for-the-holidays-2000652283]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Faces Fresh Criticism Over PC Roadmap And Paid Weapon Skins]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mhw-tu4-title-update-4-pc-fixed-2000652579</link>
            <guid>1379848</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s been a rough year for <a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113"><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></a>, a fun, very streamlined action-RPG bogged down by bad performance on PC and a lackluster cadence of post-launch content. Now Capcom has revealed Title Update 4, the latest free patch aimed at getting the multiplayer grind back on its feet. While it includes the game’s first Elder Dragon, it’s also getting flack for a PC optimization roadmap that drip-feeds fixes and new paid weapon skins that monetize part of the end-game loot chase. Nine months after launch, the latest <em>Monster Hunter</em> sequel still can’t seem to catch a break.</p> <p>Arriving December 16, the <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-us/update/ver_01_4/">latest free content drop</a> is headlined by the Elder Dragon Gogmazios, which fans are already preparing to get demolished by. A trailer for Title Update 4 shows the ability for four players to team up with support NPCs to fight Gogma as a party of eight. In addition to new Gogma Artian Weapons, <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>‘ end-game grind will also expand with Armor Transcendence upgrades, Arch-Tempered Jin Dahaad strikes, additional support hunters Nadia and Griifin, and new optional quests.</p>

  <p>So far so good! But Capcom’s recent <em>Monster Hunter</em> showcase also revealed the game’s next set of microtransactions, the Cosmetic DLC Pack 4. This one, which isn’t part of the existing $50 Cosmetic DLC Pass, includes, among other things, new Layered Weapon designs for each weapon type. These don’t impact gameplay per se, but they do look, depending on your preference, cooler than what you earn in the game without paying. Fans aren’t stoked. “DLC like this should not exist,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1pjsfwl/cosmetic_dlc_pack_4_layered_armor_and_weapons/">wrote</a> on the subreddit.</p>

 <p>These kinds of ornaments, now increasingly common in other live-service games, are still relatively new to the <em>Monster Hunter</em> series. There was already a big stink in the community when Layered Weapon skins arrived in <em>Monster Hunter Rise</em>. Capcom <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/yxq2t4/capcom_have_removed_english_plushie_weapons_video/">even removed a trailer</a> for a paid DLC pack that made weapons look like plushies because it got downvoted so much. As one fan <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1pjt0dt/its_just_stickers_its_just_poses_its_just_stuff/">recently laid</a> out, the microtransaction creep has been unrelenting. “”It’s just stickers…it’s just poses…it’s just stuff for the camp…”</p>

 <h2>Don’t expect <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> on PC to get fixed all at once</h2> <p>There’s also the new PC optimization roadmap that Capcom revealed during the showcase. The fixes are good, but long overdue and will be spread across multiple months rather than coming in one fell swoop. The latest performance boost begins with CPU/GPU optimization in December as part of Title Update 4. Then January will add more “PC-specific” improvements to high-resolution texture packs and VRAM usage, as well as new graphics and CPU settings. Further optimization will follow in February with a patch targeting graphical detail to reduce GPU processing loads.</p>

 <p>Does that mean the PC version will finally be in tip-top shape by the one-year anniversary? Some players are skeptical that the December update will make a huge difference and are wondering why Capcom <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1pjshc0/tu4_optimization_roadmap/">seems to have prioritized</a> other things up to this point. “One whole entire year to get optimizations, this is why all of my hunting buddies have already quit the game,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1pjs6o5/details_and_timeline_regarding_the_promised/">wrote</a> one player on the subreddit.</p> <p>In the meantime, Steam ratings for <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> have improved from a <a href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-title-2-patch-notes-steam-reviews-1851785248">true low point over the summer</a>, but only just barely. It still hasn’t broken 70 percent positive. “I waited a long time before putting out a review of this game,” <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/#app_reviews_hash">reads</a> one recent Steam review from a player with nearly 300 hours logged. “Please understand that I’ve been with this series since 2007, so I have an attachment to it unlike any other game series I’ve immersed myself in. To get to the point; Capcom is ridiculous for putting this game out the way they did.”</p> <p>The long road to redemption for the PC release continues.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mhw-tu4-title-update-4-pc-fixed-2000652579]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Are Modding Ugly Sonic Back Into The Original Movie]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-2019-cut-ugly-redesign-fan-movie-remake-2000652606</link>
            <guid>1379812</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>It was a good thing that the internet bullied Paramount into fixing </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-sonic-the-hedgehog-movie-looks-uh-1834411263"><span>Sonic’s horrifying human-like form</span></a><span> in the first live-action </span><i><span>Sonic the Hedgehog</span></i><span> movie. If that hadn’t happened, we likely wouldn’t have gotten the great follow-ups and Keanu Reeves playing Shadow in </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-review-shadow-keanu-reeves-jim-carrey-1851726797"><i><span>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</span></i></a><span>. But even five years later, who wouldn’t be morbidly curious to know what the movie would have looked like if Paramount hadn’t gone back to the drawing board? That’s what a fan group is giving us the chance to find out with </span><i><span>Sonic the Hedgehog: The 2019 Cut</span></i><span>.</span></p> <p><span>The fan remake of the 2020 film aims to recreate every shot of the movie, but with the ugly-ass hedgehog that Paramount nearly unleashed into theaters. Originally, the team of fans was going to release a trailer this week, but it has been delayed until December 24 because they weren’t “completely happy” with the final result.</span></p>

 <p><span>“We wanted Sonic’s animation to feel as fluid as possible, and to be honest, it would have gotten some negative reviews if we’d released it today,” the announcement reads.&nbsp;</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/vYuGKoGXDr">pic.twitter.com/vYuGKoGXDr</a></p> <p>— A26 (@A26Pics) <a href="https://twitter.com/A26Pics/status/1998924804326621228?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>To make up for the delay, the </span><i><span>2019 Cut </span></i><span>team released a brief first look showing ugly Sonic running on the inside of a washing machine, and yep, that really does look like that monstrosity in a scene from the final movie. Gross!</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">A short clip for you all 🫣<br>Hope you like It<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GottaFixFast?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GottaFixFast</a><br>🌀🦔 <a href="https://t.co/2ET7vPsZSV">pic.twitter.com/2ET7vPsZSV</a></p> <p>— Sonic The Hedgehog: The 2019 Cut (@SonicCut2026) <a href="https://twitter.com/SonicCut2026/status/1998911190316232755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><i><span>The 2019 Cut </span></i><span>is projected to premiere online sometime in 2026. So hey, if you’re jonesing for </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-4-film-sequel-confirmed-march-spring-2027-sega-1851744323"><i><span>Sonic 4</span></i></a> <span>or the upcoming </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-live-action-movie-spin-off-shadow-4-5-2000649220"><span>untitled spin-off movie</span></a><span>, you have something to look forward to before those are out in 2027 and 2028. It might just make for slightly more unpleasant viewing.</span></p> <p><span>While Sonic got a much-needed makeover, the original ugly design did still get to be in a movie, it just wasn’t a </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>movie. The character </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ugly-sonic-hedgehog-cameo-chip-dale-rescue-rangers-disn-1848955965"><span>appeared in a </span><i><span>Chip ‘n Dale </span></i><span>movie</span></a><span>, voiced by </span><i><span>I Think You Should Leave </span></i><span>star Tim Robinson.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-2019-cut-ugly-redesign-fan-movie-remake-2000652606]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>