<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:25:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft CEO Blames Outlaws' Struggles On 'Choppy' Star Wars Universe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft-ceo-shareholders-choppy-1851786615</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-ceo-blames-outlaws-struggles-on-choppy-star-wars-universe.1248662/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot’s has made some comments on the sales issues of <em>Star Wars Outlaws. </em>The big boss claims that <em>Outlaws</em>’ middling performance last year was, in large part, because the whole <em>Star Wars</em> franchise was in “choppy waters.”</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196842" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Star Wars Outlaws Lost Me With Its Story Trailer" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="138" data-playlist="196842,196406,196566" data-current="196842"><div><p>Star Wars Outlaws Lost Me With Its Story Trailer</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22392.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Guillemot was at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/zzxygofu/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/zzxygofu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a recent shareholders Q&amp;A</a></span>, addressing complaints that last August’s open-worlds action-adventure didn’t hit the exceedingly high sales milestones that had been hoped for. The game—where you play as space criminal Kay Vess rushing around the galaxy committing acts of malfeasance—had “softer than expected” sales on release, which caused a huge drop in Ubisoft’s share value to the lowest it had been in ten years.</p><p>The causes of this were, of course, multi-factorial. The enormous game was buggy, had crappy stealth, and lackluster space-based sections, and these significant shortfalls immediately hurt word-of-mouth. It also released into the worst of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-microsoft-obsidian-anti-woke-dei-twitter-1851714901&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-microsoft-obsidian-anti-woke-dei-twitter-1851714901">2024's tiresome campaigning by the wannabe-Nazis of the alt-right</a></span>, the game committing the twin crimes of featuring a central character who was both a woman <em>and</em> a person of color. Also, people were noticeably getting tired of Ubisoft’s repetitive formula across all its games, and <em>Outlaws</em> took the brunt of this. It was a whole bunch of stuff, but the game’s own failings were a significant part of it. What no one at all was saying was, “It’s because <em>Book of Boba Fett</em> wasn’t that great of a movie.”</p><p>During the shareholder meeting, someone in the audience stood up to ask an interminable barrage of questions, during which he asked&nbsp;of <em>Outlaws</em>, “What have you learned from the failure in terms of sales? Have you learned anything in terms of pricing, in terms of marketing?”</p><p> Guillemot replied, “We didn’t reach our sales targets. The game suffered from a number of items.” The first of these he listed was that “the brand that it belonged to was in a bit of choppy waters,” stopping before explaining exactly what he meant by that. He then added that “the game still had a few items that needed to be polished,” rapidly adding that they received polish in the early weeks of release, but saying that it “did affect sales volumes.” Guillemot then described the upcoming Switch 2 port as “a new version of the game.”</p><p>His underplaying of the bugginess of the game, dropped in as an afterthought after attempting to throw the entirety of <em>Star Wars</em> under the bus, is just odd! Was this an attempt to lump the game in with Disney+ TV series <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217"><em>The Acolyte</em></a></span>, that was also the target of a hate campaign from the organized bigots? While the movies had gone quiet since 2021, the TV series were otherwise flying high, with <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em>, <em>Ahsoka</em>, and of course the beloved <em>Andor</em> proving critical successes. And if the entire franchise is to blame, then why didn’t this affect EA’s 2023 title&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</em>? EA CEO Andrew Wilson described that game’s sales as “strongly” beating expectations, saying that EA was “overjoyed” with its performance. </p><p>Anyway, shareholders and stock values are the antithesis of creative pursuits, and <em>Outlaws</em> was a fine game released into a broken industry where only astonishing success is acceptable.</p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft-ceo-shareholders-choppy-1851786615]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>