<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:46:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Reese’s Oreo Cup Is Tasty, But Only If Luck Is On Your Side]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-reeses-oreo-cup-review-tasty-cookie-snack-candy-2000623453</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-reese%E2%80%99s-oreo-cup-is-tasty-but-only-if-luck-is-on-your-side.1290105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Over the last few years, it feels like there has been a large increase in the <a href="https://kotaku.com/reeses-peanut-butter-cups-now-with-hard-bits-1776649563">number of limited-time Reese’s Cup variations</a> and gimmicks. Many of these have been bad. But the newest crossover featuring Oreo cookies is the first time I’ve tried one of these oddball concoctions and enjoyed it. But only when RNG was on my side.</p> <p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/reeses/posts/you-asked-we-crushed-it-reeses-oreo-cups-are-coming-this-september/1218885443616524/">Released this month, the new Reese’s Oreo cup</a> isn’t simply a <a href="https://kotaku.com/halloween-candy-ranking-worst-best-list-chocolate-bar-1851679251/38">Reese’s cup</a> with some Oreo bits shoved inside. Well, okay, sure, it is mostly that, but the Reese’s cup itself is half milk chocolate and half white chocolate. As someone who is a big fan of the white chocolate Reese’s Cup, I was very happy about this choice. It also makes sense as the Oreo cookie bits, in theory at least, should blend with the white chocolate to create something similar in taste to an actual Oreo cookie.</p> <p>And then you have the classic Reese’s peanut butter filling, which is fine by me as I love that stuff more than real peanut butter. So does this all come together into a winning creation? Well, you know the answer already, I said it in the first paragraph. But yes, it’s pretty dang good!</p>

 <p>The cookie bits add a nice and crunchy texture to each cup, and the darker, more bitter flavor of the Oreo cookie cuts through the peanut butter, so they complement each other in a way that a lot of other gimmicky flavors have been lacking. But that Oreo-ness also doesn’t overpower the entire cup, something that can also happen. (Looking at you, fudge-filled Reese’s Cups.) Instead, the cookie bits and the rest of the cup blend together perfectly. The white chocolate top of the cup also helps add a bit of sweetness and creaminess to the candy, which does sort of recreate the taste of an Oreo that has been dipped in peanut butter. I would know how that tastes, as I’ve done that many times before.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000623478" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000623478"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000623478">©Reese’s / Oreo</figcaption></figure> <p>There is an asterisk, though, next to my “Pretty Dang Good!” appraisal of the new Oreo Reese’s abomination. It all depends on how much Oreo is in your Reese’s Cups. I bought four of the King Size version and three of them had a lot of cookie bits and were fantastic. But one had barely any inside the peanut butter, so you were left with a cup that was just half white chocolate and half milk chocolate. Not a horrible fate, but disappointing if you were expecting some Oreo goodness.</p>

 <p>For those of you out there who miss the <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=crunchy+cookie+cup&amp;rlz=1C1ONGR_enUS955US955&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8#imgrc=D8sfDROw0w3ReM&amp;imgdii=EKOEBjAnc7XWNM">Crunchy Cookie Reese’s Cup from the ’90s</a>, this might be your best bet for re-experiencing that fan-favorite flavor that is no longer sold by Reese’s. From my memory, it’s not quite the same thing, but it’s awfully close. And in the absence of Reese’s bringing it back, this will do just fine for all of you longing for the sweet return of the Crunchy Cookie cup.</p> <p>One last note: If you do buy some of these, stick ’em in the fridge. The one I stuck in the fridge and tasted a few hours later was even better. I mean, Reese’s Cups in general are better cold, but these in particular taste wonderful. The cold stiffens up the chocolate more and adds even more crunch. It’s nice. I can’t buy any more or I’ll eat them all.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-reeses-oreo-cup-review-tasty-cookie-snack-candy-2000623453]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This UGREEN USB-C Charger Drops to a Practically Free, Stock Up for Samsung and Apple’s New Devices]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-ugreen-usb-c-charger-drops-to-a-practically-free-stock-up-for-samsung-and-apples-new-devices-2000623225</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-ugreen-usb-c-charger-drops-to-a-practically-free-stock-up-for-samsung-and-apple%E2%80%99s-new-devices.1290042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There are too many devices and not enough outlets in my life. My phone, tablet, headphones, and everything else are in a constant battle to get plugged into my nearest USB-C port. If this is your life too, you need to upgrade from the cube that came with your phone to something much more useful. This UGREEN 65W USB-C charger has multiple ports to plug your stuff into so you can recharge all your devices at once. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3935/">The charger normally goes for $50, but for a limited time, you can scoop one up for 40% off.</a> That discount brings the price down by $20, so you’re only paying $30.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3935/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Ultra-Fast Charging</h2>
<p>This UGREEN charger is pretty powerful despite its small size. It’s got two separate USB-C charging ports as well as a USB-a charging port, and can hit a max fast-charging output of 65W. To put some numbers on that, a MacBook Air M2 can go from zero to over 50% in just 30 minutes. The charging block supports Samsung Super Fast Charging 2.0. The S24 Ultra can be brought up to 50% in just 19 minutes. An iPhone 15 Pro will go up to 60% in only 30 minutes.</p>
<p>The charger is about 55% smaller than a MacBook charger, measuring in at only 2.08 inches by 1.57 inches by 1.25 inches. And because it’s so small, it will only take up a single outlet on a power strip. Huge pet peeve whenever manufacturers make their bricks so big they take up two or sometimes even three of them. Not and issue here.</p>



<p>Designed for portability, the prongs of the plug can be folded back into the brick. This let’s you toss it into your bag or pocket without risk of those little bits getting caught on anything or breaking.</p>
<p>USB-C and USB-A are pretty universally compatible at this point. So that means this UGREEN charger can be used with your phone whether it’s an iPhone or an Android from Google, Samsung, and more. It’ll work on a pair of JBL earbuds. It can even charge your Steam Deck or Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>UGREEN designs its charges with safety in mind. The upgraded Thermal Guard protection system can safeguard your devices from overheating or short circuiting. No worry with leaving them plugged in.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3935/">For a limited time, you can grab yourself one of these UGREEN 3-in-1 USB-C and USB-A universal chargers on sale</a>. Amazon’s limited-time discount has shaved 40% off the price, bringing what you pay down to just $30.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3935/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-ugreen-usb-c-charger-drops-to-a-practically-free-stock-up-for-samsung-and-apples-new-devices-2000623225]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Fan Just Painstakingly Recreated The Office Inside No Man’s Sky]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-the-office-base-building-settlement-nbc-2000623462</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-fan-just-painstakingly-recreated-the-office-inside-no-man%E2%80%99s-sky.1290039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The grounded, relatable setting of a certain paper distributor in Scranton, Pennsylvania might be the furthest thing one could imagine from the endless, procedurally generated galaxy of <i>No Man’s Sky</i>, but one virtual space explorer has put some serious digital elbow grease into recreating <i>The Office</i>’s iconic setting. It’s a delight to check out for fans of the show or for those who appreciate some solid base building in Hello Games’ massive space sim.</p> <p>The replica’s creator, user Ok_Misterpiece_9363, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoMansSkyTheGame/comments/1n8efk3/welcome_to_the_office/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">showed it off on Reddit</a> where it’s amassed more than 14,000 upvotes and tons of excited comments filled with <i>Office</i> memes from fans impressed by how faithfully the Scranton-based office space and warehouse has been reproduced.</p>   <p>What’s really neat about this office recreation is how much of the building and the experience of traveling through this space it captures. Having visited many Dunder Mifflin recreations in games like <i>VRchat</i> myself, I’m typically used to just seeing the main floor where most of the show’s action takes place. But this <i>NMS</i> version lets you walk in from the ground floor and, with a quick teleport jump, you can then explore the main office suite, the “annex” area, and even take a quick trip down to the warehouse.</p>

 <p>Those who know the fictional office well might be able to spot a few omissions and quirks, however. Intern-turned-fraudster-turned-hipster Ryan is missing his closet office from the later seasons; the conference room leads directly to the warehouse (there’s a corridor behind it instead on the actual set of the show); and speaking of the warehouse, it doesn’t look much like what we’d seen in nine seasons of the celebrated comedy.</p>   <p>These deviations aside, this is an undeniably cute homage to a beloved comedy, filled with references to various memorable moments such as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoMansSkyTheGame/comments/1n8efk3/comment/ncfue0a/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">Pam and Jim’s rooftop date</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoMansSkyTheGame/comments/1n8efk3/comment/ncftytq/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">the speedometer race scene</a> from an episode in season five, and more.</p> <p>If you want to visit galactic Dunder Mifflin yourself, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoMansSkyTheGame/comments/1n8efk3/comment/ncea34o/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">Ok_Misterpiece_9363 has provided the coordinates here</a>.</p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/no-mans-sky-the-office-base-building-settlement-nbc-2000623462]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PC Gaming Handhelds Are Getting Ridiculously Expensive]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/legion-go-2-price-specs-madden-curse-eagles-2000623447</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pc-gaming-handhelds-are-getting-ridiculously-expensive.1290000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Big <em>Cult of the Lamb</em> DLC and even bigger PC gaming handhelds. Welcome to the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture. I am still recovering from the Philadelphia Eagles’ narrow escape from the Dallas Cowboys last night. It only took six seconds for star defensive tackle Jalen Carter to get ejected from the game for spitting at opposing quarterback Dak Prescott, only for a second angle to reveal Prescott actually spit first.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">DAK SPAT FIRST?!?! <a href="https://t.co/J2xrMlJRLj">pic.twitter.com/J2xrMlJRLj</a></p> <p>— Bussin' With The Boys (@BussinWTB) <a href="https://twitter.com/BussinWTB/status/1963806763418829238?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Carter apparently then asked him if he just spat at him (Prescott’s loogie had little hang-time before going straight to the ground) and Prescott said something to the effect of “why the hell would I do that?” and then Carter decided the time for words had ended and fired back with his own salvo of saliva aimed squarely at Prescott’s chest. <a href="https://nypost.com/2025/09/05/sports/dak-prescott-explains-his-version-after-new-video-emerges-in-eagles-spit-gate/">The curse of <em>Madden</em> continues</a>? I can’t wait to suffer through another season of the 2024 Super Bowl champions looking like utter frauds.</p> <h2>The Legion Go 2 is almost twice as expensive as the original</h2> <p>Lenovo revealed its newest PC gaming handheld and its impressive specs are overshadowed only by its price tag. It starts at $1,100 or about the price of a 15-inch MacBook Air. For that you get an 8.8 inch OLED display, an AMD Z2 processor, 16GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/769776/legion-go-2-official-lenovo-new-flagship-handheld-cost"><em>The Verge</em> reports</a> it won’t launch with SteamOS, and it won’t have Microsoft’s new Windows gaming UI that’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/rog-xbox-ally-price-pc-gaming-handheld-asus-pre-order-2000622751">releasing with the Xbox ROG Ally</a> either. That option won’t arrive until <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/772853/the-lenovo-legion-go-2-will-get-xbox-flavored-windows-in-spring-2026">sometime in spring 2026</a>.</p>

 <p>None of this is doing much for my enthusiasm for an otherwise cool upgrade. It’ll be the beefiest portable PC gaming competitor to the Switch 2 when it arrives on October 31, complete with detachable controller grips, a kickstand, and optical mouse controls. But with the best Legion Go 2 model coming in at almost $1,500, I’m not sure any number of new bells and whistles will get prospective buyers over the sticker shock.</p> <h2><em>Cult of the Lamb</em>‘s <em>Woolhaven</em> DLC will be almost as long as the base game</h2>   <p>The action roguelike base-builder has an expansion coming in early 2026 and developer Massive Monster claims it will <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@cultofthelamb/video/7546404300310859026?_t=ZN-8zTCaEzxTMM&amp;_r=1">effectively feel like a second game</a>. The wintery DLC adds new settlement mechanics, levels to explore, and brutal weather to survive. It looks neat but unlike all of the free updates generously showered on players, <em>Woodhaven</em> will be paid. No price has been revealed yet.</p>

 <p>“We tend to go all out, be at weddings, to raves, to three free massive content updates,” the devs said in a TikTok. “This DLC is not free, but I promise you’ll love it.”</p> <h2><em>Schedule 1</em> fans are voting on whether to finally bring shrooms to the hit Steam game</h2> <p>The drug-selling <a href="https://newsletter.gamediscover.co/p/schedule-is-solo-smash-hit-and-the">crewlike</a>‘s <em>Rival Cartels</em> update is live and the next <a href="http://Hireable Drivers, Fishing, and Shrooms.">community poll</a> is available for players to vote on. The three options are between Hireable Drivers, Fishing, and Shrooms, a psychedelic not currently available in the game. While drivers would be the most practical, fans of funky fungi have been waiting for their moment in the spotlight. Some players are chanting “Shrooms, baby!” Others say “Fishing EZ.” The weirdos howl “I want police raids so bad.”</p>

 <h2><em>MindsEye</em> devs surprise remaining players by actually continuing to fix the game</h2> <p>“I can’t wait for the next statement from the studio (it’s so fucking over),” wrote Electrical_Sugar_742 a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/comments/1n73bx6/i_cant_wait_for_the_next_statement_from_the/">couple of days ago</a>. But Build A Rocket Boy responded with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEyeGame/comments/1n90pgy/update_4_pc_console/">update 4,</a> which is full of changes to the beleaguered action shooter. It addresses PC performance issues and adds quality-of-life improvements, including the ability to finally skip cutscenes. How are players responding?</p> <p>“I’ve deleted it for now,” wrote one. “Maybe by 2040 the game will reach 1.0,” wrote another. The most controversial patch note is “Removed EVERYWHERE vehicles from Build.MindsEye – those vehicles were made accessible unofficially, and we will bring them to MindsEye when they are ready.” User RazorLined wrote, “You guys really thought this was the time to make that change. Really guys. REALLY!?!” Tough crowd.</p>

 <h2>Repair support for every old Nintendo console before the Switch has officially ended</h2> <p>The <em>Mario</em> maker ran out of replacement parts for the New 2DS XL this week. “Due to the depletion of parts inventory required for repairs, we have terminated the repair service for the New Nintendo 2DS XL console as of September 4, 2025,” a&nbsp; <a href="https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1838479151034175962">post on X</a> reads, per X’s built-in translate function. “Repair services for all other Nintendo 3DS series have also been terminated.”</p> <p>The company ended <a href="https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1808707230377914724">repair support</a> for the Wii U last year. With both platforms’ eShops also set down and no online functionality left, the sun has finally set on Nintendo’s pre-Switch years.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/firaxis-lays-off-dozens-devs-civilization-vii-struggles-cuts-2k-2000623187"><em>Civ 7</em> studio Firaxis is laying off a bunch of developers as the game struggles</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/puzzle-quest-immortal-edition-match-3-remaster-2000623170">Another one of the best puzzle games ever is getting a remaster</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-aaaaa-silksong-next-gen-pc-devolver-digital-2000623190">GTA 6 will only truly be an “AAAAA” level blockbuster if it can save console gaming</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/legion-go-2-price-specs-madden-curse-eagles-2000623447]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marshall Major V On-Ear Headphones Crash to Lowest Price Ever, Over 5x Cheaper Than AirPods Max]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marshall-major-v-on-ear-headphones-crash-to-lowest-price-ever-over-5x-cheaper-than-airpods-max-2000623230</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marshall-major-v-on-ear-headphones-crash-to-lowest-price-ever-over-5x-cheaper-than-airpods-max.1289964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Looking for the right pair of headphones? The three most important factors are do they look good do they sound good, and will they not empty my bank account? Well, you can go right ahead and check off all three boxes with <strong>the Marshall Major V on-ear wireless headphones</strong>. These Bluetooth headphones are stylish as heck, produce great sound, and pretty dang affordable. They’re normally listed at $160. However, Amazon has them as part of a limited time deal at the moment. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3934/">They’re going now for as low as 38% off which drops the price by a solid $61. You’ll only be paying $99.</a></p>
<p>With the Marshall Major V headphones, you can expect to hear the signature sound Marshall is known for. You get a thunderous bass, smooth mids, and a crisp treble. Marshall is not like Samsung or Apple. They are exclusively in the audio business — a business they’ve been in for over 60 years, mind you. The brand has developed so many iconic product from huge amplifiers to headphones such as these. They’re priority is meeting the needs and expectations of musicians and anyone else who deeply cares about sound quality.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3934/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Long Listening Time</h2>
<p>A pair of Bluetooth headphones won’t really be worth that much to you if they can’t hold a charge, so how doe the Marshall Major V hold up? Well, these on-ear headphones are capable of lasting over 100 hours on one charge. You can listen to your music non-stop for over four days before you need to plug them in again. And when they do finally die on your, you can even choose to charge them wirelessly. You’ll get from zero percent back up to full is just about three hours.</p>
<p>The Marshall Major V are engineered knowing you’ll be schlepping them around with you wherever you go. That’s why they’re ruggedly durable. They can handle getting roughed up a tad. When they’re not in use, they fold up easily to nice, portable size so you can toss them in a bag without taking up much room.</p>



<p>These headphones even features a side button which you can customize to trigger a number of different actions. By default, this button will launch Spotify on the connected device.</p>
<p>Right now, Amazon has the Marshall Major V wireless Bluetooth headphones marked down by a solid $61. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3934/">That 38% discount is bringing the price down from $160 to just $99 for a limited time.</a> Pick between black, brown, cream, and midnight blue. Currently all are on sale, but the black and cream are sitting at the lowest price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3934/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marshall-major-v-on-ear-headphones-crash-to-lowest-price-ever-over-5x-cheaper-than-airpods-max-2000623230]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>