<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:54:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[For Wolfenstein 3 To Be Good, It Needs To Punch Nazis Even Harder]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-sequel-nazis-trump-ice-machinegames-2000658228</link>
            <guid>1400974</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The news that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-in-development-machinegames-bethesda-2000657758"><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i></a><span> is in the works is music to my ears. I’ve long been a fan of Sweden-based MachineGames’ take on </span><i><span>Wolfenstein</span></i><span>, which transforms B.J. Blazkowicz’s one-man war on occult-powered Nazis into a grisly and moving narrative about the strength of family and communities while finding oneself amidst endless conflict. </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 2</span></i><span> showed the importance of resisting the narrative that fascism can and will win. If I have one concrete hope for a potential sequel, it’s that it doesn’t ease up on the gas.</span></p> <p><span>The first of these games, </span><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Order</span></i><span> is</span><span> really good, as is its prequel, <em>The Old Blood</em>. Their shooting chops have always been up to snuff and their unflinching narratives were a breath of fresh air at a time when FPS fare was beginning to feel a little same-y. They had a stylish verve that was becoming all-too uncommon and paired B.J. with the likes of alt-history takes on Jimi Hendrix and Nikola Tesla. Besides that, it was also refreshingly novel to play an FPS about Nazis at a time where it seemed like most of the genre was ditching the past in favor of modern and future conflicts. It was 2014, and we couldn’t have known what was to come.</span></p> <p><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Colossu</span></i><span>s was an entirely different story. Arriving in the fall of 2017, </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span> struck like lightning. Its unveiling and marketing beats reveled in the joy of ripping fascists to shreds, while </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fps/8-years-after-wolfenstein-2-vowed-to-make-america-nazi-free-again-multiple-reports-suggest-wolfenstein-3-is-finally-in-development/"><span>leaning into the dystopic headlines</span></a><span> Americans increasingly became inundated with. It adopted the “punch Nazis now, ask questions later” ideology that emerged amid Donald Trump’s first presidency and the rise of the alt-right. More specifically, it leaned into that time that Richard Spencer–a Neo-Nazi and early figurehead of the alt-right movement–got </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aFh08JEKDYk"><span>decked</span></a><span> by an unknown assailant on camera.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>At the time, many criticized publisher Bethesda’s decision to appropriate some of this language and rhetoric throughout </span><i><span>The New Colossus’</span></i><span> marketing cycle. Fans of the games and companies involved openly protested against the game on social media, and even threatened to boycott it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>During an interview with </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Wolfenstein/comments/7ap3n8/hey_bethseda_youre_game_is_making_people_mad/"><i><span>Vice News</span></i></a><span> which centered on this outrage, Bethesda’s then-director of PR, Pete Hines, told the outlet, “Unless you’re a Nazi, there should be nobody who’s opposed to the idea of being against Nazis.” When told that the game’s aggressive marketing tone might be poking the hornet’s nest, Hines even doubled down, saying, “Maybe a little bit, but the hornet’s nest is full of Nazis so…fuck those guys. I’ll poke a Nazi hornet’s nest.”</span></p>  <p><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span>‘ narrative was as brazen as its marketing campaign and bold in a way few games have managed since, focusing on a Nazi-occupied America and how B.J. and his allies, the Kreisau Circle, begin fomenting rebellion at home. It is filled with sights that are still hard to shake, like KKK members in full Klan garb chumming it up with Nazi shocktroopers on the streets of Roswell, New Mexico. And it is filled with characters and pulse-pounding dialogue exchanges that interrogate whether America has ever really been the virtuous home of freedom its most patriotic defendants claim it to be. After all, America under Nazi rule in <em>The New Colossus </em>looks a lot like America always has</span><span>.</span></p> <p><span>Maybe the root of evil wasn’t abroad all along. Maybe it’s been in us the whole time. And maybe we never really stamped it out because the blood and cruelty which it produces has always greased the wheels of this </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/no-games-for-genocide-xbox-microsoft-boycott-palestine-2000650175"><span>damnable, infernal machine</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet B.J. and his allies fight like hell to dismantle it. They take on impossible odds, which manifest in </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span>‘ difficulty spikes and often brutal gauntlets and level design. B.J. himself even takes a detour into his past and confronts the earliest source of evil in his life: his racist, abusive father, Rip. And you know what he does? He exorcizes his demons. It is cathartic to be in B.J.’s shoes at that crucial moment when he takes back his life from Rip, who dies at the hands of his own son in defense of an America that, in his own words, has become “a white man’s world now.” And it is cathartic to take that rage and rip into Nazis for several more hours afterwards.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Colossus</span></i><span> could not have more perfectly matched the moment it emerged into. Its European developers definitely seem like they were tuned into the national conversation overseas and the growing political divide in America, but I don’t believe any of them would go so far as to say they predicted the exact descent into fascism which the game’s development and release would parallel. </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i><span>, however, could be an entirely different story.</span></p> <p><span>Even if </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i><span> is only in the earliest stages of production right now, it could still arrive near the end of Trump’s second presidency. And lord knows the material that MachineGames has to work with nowadays. That loser notion that Rip died defending? Well, that seems like the primary ambition of the current U.S. administration, which continues to stoke fires both abroad and at home in pursuit of this goal. Look no further than the way that the administration has continually sicced ICE–the </span><a href="https://www.404media.co/inside-ices-tool-to-monitor-phones-in-entire-neighborhoods/"><span>president’s own secret police</span></a><span> at this point–on American citizens in a manufactured war on immigrants, rounded people up into camps, and even claimed the lives of innocents, as many saw with the </span><a href="https://defector.com/ice-agent-kills-woman-dhs-tells-obvious-insane-lies-about-it"><span>murder of Renee Nicole Good</span></a><span> in Minneapolis on January 7.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>If </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span> felt like a heightened, yet prescient take on the politics of the 2010s, what might a follow-up in the wake of the declining American empire under a second Trump administration look like? Neither you nor I can really say, but if it’s anything like its predecessors, it will be abrasive, unhinged, and rightfully angry at the rot we’ve observed in the time since </span><i><span>Wolfenstein </span></i><span>was last in the limelight. At the naked abuses of power which dominate our timelines and drive our seemingly routine descents into madness. At the normalization of Nazi shit and cruelty. I could use a place to vent all that frustration. Maybe, just maybe, </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3 </span></i><span>will fill that role perfectly whenever it arrives.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-sequel-nazis-trump-ice-machinegames-2000658228]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FF7 Rebirth Director Explains The Mini-Game Bloat]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-minigames-remake-trilogy-3-game-2000658234</link>
            <guid>1400953</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Remake</span></i><span>’s third and final entry is still years away, but Square Enix is actively developing whatever comes after 2024’s </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>. The sequel was notoriously </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-mini-games-best-worst-ranked-1851340606"><span>minigame heavy</span></a><span>, and while the </span><i><span>Remake </span></i><span>trilogy already felt like it was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-remake-mini-games-third-game-1851272221"><span>straining to make three games out of one</span></a><span>, </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s reliance on minigames to pad the length really pushed things past the limit. Other than </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-ending-cloud-aerith-sephiroth-1851374178"><span>its divisive ending</span></a><span>, it’s probably the most widely derided part of the game, but it doesn’t sound like this criticism has deterred Square from this approach.</span></p> <p><span>In </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbrBjFZabUE"><span>an interview with </span><i><span>GamerBraves</span></i></a><span>, </span><i><span>Rebirth </span></i><span>director Naoki Hamaguchi was asked about </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s inclusion of heaps of minigames, with interviewer Sean Lim noting that some players felt the onslaught interrupted the game’s pacing. Hamaguchi said that the team’s intention was to not only shake up what the player was doing throughout </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s lengthy runtime, but also pay homage to the original </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span>, which had its fair share of minigames as well.</span></p>

  <blockquote><p><span>So, that’s not a unique problem for </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</span></i><span> only. A lot of games, aside from the main theme and main story progression, also have the side games and the minigames built into them. So, we don’t think we’re unique in that aspect. So when you’re playing the game and you’re going through the main story progression, as well as the intended game design, you tend to fall into this trap of having the same tempo. So, you tend to get bored playing it. To sort of combat this and keep that fresh feeling of going through the game, that’s why we introduced these minigames, to sort of add a diversity of experience as you’re playing the game, to keep up the good rhythm, so to say. So we understand when you introduce these different facets, some people would play it and really enjoy it, but some people would rather just get on with the main story. So it’s sort of a calculated move on our part to include all these different facets of the game. Whether it’s the amount of minigames or the pacing [with which] we introduce them, so on the creator side, it’s sort of something we have taken into account when we do the game design.</span></p> <p><span>So the original </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span> also had lots of minigames, and it was very famous for that. So, when [we] were entrusted with doing the remake, [we] sort of wanted to keep that spirit of the diversity of play within the title, so that people can have lots of different experiences the same way they did with </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span>.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>I can appreciate wanting to be true to the original RPG’s minigames, but </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s obvious use of it as filler goes far beyond reimagining. It would be helpful if each diversion was good, but they varied from the good as hell </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ff7-rebirth-queens-blood-naoki-hamaguchi-interview-1851312733"><span>Queen’s Blood card game</span></a><span> to the infamous </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-cait-sith-box-throw-mod-remove-1851744876"><span>Cait Sith box throwing segment</span></a><span>. Walking through </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s open world was like trying to cross a minefield where the most obnoxious, unskippable landmines were waiting for you if you stepped in the wrong direction. </span></p>

 <p><span>Hamaguchi doesn’t say if this will persist into the next </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Remake</span></i><span> game, but he has said elsewhere that the third game will </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-part-3-remake-length-how-long-2000637274"><span>be more concise</span></a><span>, so hopefully that means&nbsp; the minigames get dialed down a bit in the final chapter. Or let Sephiroth strike me down.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-minigames-remake-trilogy-3-game-2000658234]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why A 2025 Prediction For More Witcher 3 DLC Keeps Gaining Momentum]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-zerrikania-expansion-rumor-2000658222</link>
            <guid>1400881</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-the-kotaku-review-1703766283"><i><span>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</span></i></a><span> turns 11 years old in May. Its last big update was a next-gen version released in 2022. But that hasn’t stopped speculation from mounting about a surprise expansion dropping sometime soon for the beloved open-world RPG.</span></p>

 <p><span>Rumors first began to swirl last summer, when prominent Polish leaker Borys Nieśpielak said he</span> <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-ciri-geralt-sequel-cdpr-2000655922"><span>suspected</span></a><span> developer CD Projekt Red might reveal new content for </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> at the Game Awards. And while this</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/everything-we-saw-at-the-2025-game-awards-2000652719"> <span>obviously didn’t come to pass</span></a><span>, rumors of the expansion’s possible existence have only continued to pile up in the months since:</span></p>

 <ul> <li aria-level="1"><span>During a November 2025 investor call, CD Projekt CFO Piotr Nielubowicz</span> <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/11/transcript-q3-2025-earnings-3.pdf"><span>implied</span></a><span> the existence of an unannounced product (via</span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-there-really-going-to-be-a-2026-witcher-3-expansion"> <i><span>Eurogamer</span></i></a><span>), saying, “Given our current progress, there is a chance that new content hinted upon in recent calls and reports may see release in the coming year.”</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>CEO Michał Nowakowski also chimed in about a mystery project in a Q&amp;A session following the presentation, telling investors that a majority of the workforce at support studio Fool’s Theory is working on it (via</span><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-secret-expansion-rumors-swirl-after-cd-projekt-hints-at-new-content"> <i><span>IGN</span></i></a><span>), later noting this amounted to over 100 developers.</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>Polish Noble Securities analyst Mateusz Chrzanowski last month</span> <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/analizy/noblesecurities-cdprojekt-wiedzmin-dlc-orion-cyberpunk"><span>forecasted</span></a><span> a “paid add-on” with a budget of 52 million PLN (or around $14 million USD), scheduled for release in May 2026 (via</span><a href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/new-witcher-3-dlc-expected-in-early-2026-to-set-up-the-witcher-4-3297731"> <i><span>Dexerto</span></i></a><span>). “The release should kick off the actual marketing campaign for </span><i><span>The Witcher 4</span></i><span>,” Chrzanowski added, according to a rough machine translation.</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>The heart of Chzanowski’s prediction has to do with CD Projekt Red’s corporate incentive program for the studio, </span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-expansion-rumours-analyst-100-percent-certain-cd-projekt-red-will-release-significant-new-content-this-year"><i><span>Eurogamer </span></i><span>reports</span></a><span>. “Currently, PLN 700 million [£144m] is needed to meet the first threshold, with only five quarters remaining,” Chrzanowski explained. “This implies the need for something significantly larger than just another update or a version for a niche platform.”</span></li> </ul> <h2>Why <em>Witcher</em> fans are talking about Zerrikania</h2> <p><span>Fast-forward to January 8. </span><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-expansion-reports-continue-now-with-discussion-of-a-possible-dune-style-location"><i><span>IGN Poland</span></i></a><span> reports local sources had previously known about a potential expansion to </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> for years. Furthermore, early rumors indicated the developers were at some point possibly interested in using an isolated, desert region known as Zerrikania as the add-on’s setting. Zerrikania is located to the east of the Northern Kingdoms (i.e. where most of </span><i><span>The Witcher</span></i><span> video game series takes place) and, according to</span> <a href="https://witcher.fandom.com/wiki/The_Wonders_of_Zerrikania"><span>an in-game book</span></a><span>, is home to dragon worship, tattooed “warriors maids,” and man-killing flies. Scary.</span></p>

 <p><span>With </span><i><span>The Witcher 4</span></i><span> planned to release</span> <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-2027-release-window-investor-call-ps6-cdpr-1851772310"><span>no sooner than January 2027</span></a><span>, it wouldn’t be shocking if CD Projekt wanted to fill the gap with something to tide fans over, especially if the long-awaited sequel slips into the next console generation. Of course, this is all still speculation, but the evidence is certainly building up to </span><i><span>something</span></i><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>One thing we do know for sure is that sometime this year, </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> is getting </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-mod-support-ps5-xbox-final-patch-1851783100"><span>mod support on consoles</span></a><span>. The update was supposed to arrive last year but slipped to 2026. Hopefully that’s not all CDPR has planned. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-zerrikania-expansion-rumor-2000658222]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Game Publisher Is Pushing Back Against AI Art With Contracts That Ban It: ‘It’s Cancerous’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hooded-horse-gen-ai-art-ban-4x-strategy-steam-2000658179</link>
            <guid>1400812</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Companies pumping hundreds of billions in investment into new generative AI tools and LLM models promote it as a sea change technology that will be as revolutionary as the introduction of the desktop computer. Even some game industry figures believe it will usher in a new era in which games are made better, quicker, and more cheaply, democratizing development for creatives without hundred-person teams behind them. For indie publisher Tim Bender, the recent explosion in AI slop has been nothing but a headache. “If I sound frustrated, it’s because, like, honestly, all this thing has done is made our lives more difficult.”</p> <p>The label he helps run as CEO, Hooded Horse, struck gold after signing the medieval base-builder mega hit <em>Manor Lords</em>, but its library of published games has grown far beyond it in the past two years with releases like the Lego-like tower-defense game<em>&nbsp;Cataclismo</em>, the economic management sim <em>Workers &amp; Resources: Soviet Republic</em>, and the 4X sequel <em>Endless Legend 2</em>. Being strategy games isn’t the only thing they all have in common. They also all adhere to a strict ban on generative AI art.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Battlefield 6 is getting accused of using Gen AI. <a href="https://t.co/fa2E79X8as">pic.twitter.com/fa2E79X8as</a></p> <p>— Shooter Intel (@ShooterIntel) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShooterIntel/status/2003067393141346461?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>“I fucking hate gen AI art and it has made my life more difficult in many ways…suddenly it infests shit in a way it shouldn’t,” Bender told me in a recent interview. “It is now written into our contracts if we’re publishing the game, ‘no fucking AI assets.'”</p>

 <p>It turns out that just saying no to gen AI is the easy part. Actually trying to enforce a ban is where things can get tricky. There’s no magical machine you can put a game through to detect if it has generative AI content in it. Platforms like Steam, which require disclosures for the use of such content, basically operate on good faith that developers will be honest about what’s in their games. <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> briefly had AI placeholder art in one part of the game at launch before it was eventually pulled, but that box on the Steam page was never checked.</p>

 <p>Production can be messy enough even within small studios. Development teams working with freelancers or outsource companies, as many indies do, will have an even harder time maintaining checks throughout the production pipeline to weed out any gen AI art usage.</p>

 <h2>“[Gen AI art] is cancerous”</h2> <p>“We’ve gotten to the point where we also talk to developers and we recommend they don’t use any gen AI anywhere in the process because some of them might otherwise think, ‘Okay, well, maybe what I’ll do is for this place, I’ll put it as a placeholder,’ right?” Bender told me. “Like some, people will have this thought, like they would never want to let it in the game, but they’ll think, ‘It can be a placeholder in this prototype build.’ But if that gets done, of course, there’s a chance that that slips through, because it only takes one of those slipping through in some build and not getting replaced or something.”</p>

 <p>He continued, “because of that, we’re constantly having to watch and deal with it and try to prevent it from slipping in, because it’s cancerous.”</p> <p>Hooded Horse, which already this year helped usher the grand strategy sci-fi game <em>Terra Invicta</em> out of Early Access and into its 1.0 release, employs two full-time artists who help with all of the publisher’s marketing art, which can include appearances in showcases and announcements for things like Xbox Game Pass launches. “It would be a betrayal of them to work with anything that is using gen-AI art, like, I wouldn’t be able to face them if we had that right. And we’re absolutely committed ethically, for all the reasons you know, against this,” Bender said.</p>

   <p>His point of view isn’t one you hear a whole lot among the video game industry’s giants. EA is all in on the potential for AI to make its loot-box-driven sports franchises even more lucrative. Embark Studios, maker of last year’s mega-hit <em>Arc Raiders</em>, continues to shrug off complaints about the game’s use of generative-AI voice performances.</p> <p>“We don’t use AI to not have to hire people or replace people or job groups or voice actors,” CEO Patrick Söderlund recently told <em><a href="https://gamesbeat.com/inside-arc-raiders-a-candid-interview-with-game-leaders-patrick-soderlund-and-owen-mahoney-while-playing-live/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow" data-target="true">GamesBeat</a></em>. “People have to take a step back and understand what it is and how it can be a big help to developers and be a tremendous benefit to players. I realize it is an intricate subject and discussion.”</p> <h2>It’s about good ethics, not bad PR</h2> <p>There’s also a sense among some developers that everyone else is rushing to embrace the AI revolution, and anyone who doesn’t will find themselves left behind in a landscape that’s increasingly competitive and hostile to new game releases. “Korea is reportedly one of the countries where ChatGPT is used most actively,” Sean Kim, the co-CEO of <em>Lies of P</em> publisher Neowiz, told <a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2026/01/05/ceo-of-lies-of-p-publisher-neowiz-talks-2025-overture-expansion"><em>Game Informer</em></a>. “It’s hard to find a game company here today that isn’t using AI in some way. At the very least, companies are using either ChatGPT or Gemini.”</p>

 <p>Even some acclaimed GOTY winners have been captured by this mindset. “Our successes come from empowering people to work in their own way and bring the best out of their skill &amp; craft, so that we can make the best RPGs we can possibly make,” <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> director Swen Vincke posted <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2001704942562660649">on X last month</a>. “In that context, it would be irresponsible for us not to evaluate new technologies. However, our processes are always evolving, and where they are not efficient or fail to align with who we are, we will make changes.”</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Holy fuck guys we’re not "pushing hard" for or replacing concept artists with AI.</p> <p>We have a team of 72 artists of which 23 are concept artists and we are hiring more. The art they create is original and I’m very proud of what they do.</p> <p>I was asked explicitly about concept art…</p> <p>— Swen Vincke @where? (@LarAtLarian) <a href="https://twitter.com/LarAtLarian/status/2001011042642505833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 16, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The Larian Studios cofounder was responding to controversy that had erupted over previous remarks that suggested gen-AI would be used in the making of the studio’s next RPG, <em>Divinity</em>. Vincke promised no gen-AI assets in the finished game but suggested artists might experiment with it during the exploratory phase of development. For Hooded Horse, the issue with gen AI isn’t just about skepticism over its usefulness or potential backlash from players, it’s about the moral issues surrounding tools trained on plagiarizing other people’s work.</p>

 <p>“When it comes to gen-AI, it’s not a PR issue, it’s an ethics issue,” Bender said. “The reality is, there’s so much of it going on that the commitment just has to be that you won’t allow it in the game, and if it’s ever discovered, because this artist that was hired by this outside person slipped something in, you get it out and you replace it. That has to be the commitment. It’s a shame that it’s even necessary and it’s a very frustrating thing to have to worry about.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hooded-horse-gen-ai-art-ban-4x-strategy-steam-2000658179]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Starfighter Movie Includes A Lightsaber Scene Shot By Tom Cruise]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-starfighter-lightsaber-jedi-tom-cruise-shot-scene-levy-deadpool-2000658194</link>
            <guid>1400809</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>This year, after half a decade away, <em>Star Wars</em> returns to theaters with <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-mandalorian-grogu-trailer-reactions-2000627675">The Mandalorian and Grogu.</a>&nbsp;</em>But after that movie, 2027 will see another <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-starfighter-mia-goth-ryan-gosling-shawn-levy-1851783918"><em>Star Wars</em> entry hit theaters: <em>Starfighter</em></a>. According to the film’s director, <em>Deadpool Vs Wolverin</em>e’s Shawn Levy, one scene in the upcoming sci-fi sequel was filmed by superstar Tom Cruise. Really.</p> <p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/08/movies/shawn-levy-star-wars-stranger-things.html">In a new interview with </a><em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/08/movies/shawn-levy-star-wars-stranger-things.html">The New York Times</a>,</em> Levy talked about the pressure he’s under making <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DOtlyDdDxnw/">a new <em>Star Wars</em> movie starring Ryan Gosling,</a> as well as the excitement of getting to work on the sci-fi mega-franchise. He also told the newspaper that various big names have visited the <em>Starfighter</em> set, including Steven Spielberg and Tom Cruise. The most surprising bit? Cruise actually ended up filming a bit of the movie after Levy made a joke about the mayor of Hollywood grabbing a camera.</p>

 <p>As Levy tells it, Cruise arrived on set in November and after getting welcomed by the cast with the <a href="https://kotaku.com/mission-impossible-games-ps2-n64-mobile-final-reckoning-1851781905"><em>Mission Impossible</em></a> theme song, started watching as Levy set up a lightsaber duel in a muddy lake. Levy joked to Cruise to get in and help with the cameras, and apparently, the superstar takes everything at face value. So he reportedly grabbed a camera and hopped into the water, ruining his shoes in the process, in order to get the perfect shot.</p>

 <p>“Now, when you see the movie,” Levy told the <em>NYT</em>,&nbsp; “you’ll know that part of it was shot by Tom. I mean, how cool is that?”</p>  <p>It’s wild, for sure, but the more interesting information is Levy confirming a lightsaber duel in <em>Starfighter</em>. Many had wondered if the Jedi would appear in this film, which is set a few years after <em>Rise of Skywalker.</em> And while a lightsaber duel doesn’t confirm Jedi are involved, it does make it seem far more likely that some Force-wielding folk will be showing up in <em>Starfighter</em>.</p>

 <p>The question now is who will be swinging those laserswords and why? Is <em>Starfighter</em> actually (secretly)<em> Star Wars Episode 10</em>, as some fans have wildly speculated? Or will two people who have no history with a lightsaber be fighting in a swamp? Is Rey showing up in this movie? We’ll have to wait until next year to find out. Let’s hope Tom Cruise is a good cameraman.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-starfighter-lightsaber-jedi-tom-cruise-shot-scene-levy-deadpool-2000658194]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>