<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:42:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This 10,000 Pa Robot Vacuum and Mop with 70-Day Self-Emptying Is Selling for Peanuts, Roborock Demolishes the Competition]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-10000-pa-robot-vacuum-and-mop-with-70-day-self-emptying-is-selling-for-peanuts-roborock-demolishes-the-competition-2000639314</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-10-000-pa-robot-vacuum-and-mop-with-70-day-self-emptying-is-selling-for-peanuts-roborock-demolishes-the-competition.1336408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Nobody enjoys spending weekends pushing a vacuum around, especially with pets dropping fur everywhere and kids tracking dirt through the house. Robot vacuums solve this daily headache by cleaning while you work, relax or run errands. Roborock has built a reputation as the premium choice in robotic cleaning, but <strong>their newest Q10 S5+ breaks that luxury barrier</strong>.</p>
<p>Launched in June 2025, this latest-generation model combines both vacuuming and mopping in one machine, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4512/">Amazon just slashed the price to an all-time low of $299 instead of $549, beating even Prime Day pricing</a>. This is the most affordable entry point into Roborock’s advanced cleaning technology and it delivers flagship features at a price that makes sense for everyday households.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4512/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>HyperForce Suction That Lives Up to the Hype</h2>
<p>The 10,000 Pa HyperForce suction system is an enormous breakthrough in cleaning capabilities: This unit of measurement expresses the level of suction pressure produced by the vacuum cleaner and by registering 10,000 Pa, the Q10 S5+ has one of the highest suction forces ever recorded by professionally reviewed robot vacuum cleaners.</p>
<p>The pet hair pickup rate climbed to 96 percent in tests, beating the category average of 75.4 percent when comparing it to similar robot vacuum cleaners. The anti-tangle feature requires recognition for its outstanding performance. The regular brush comes equipped with <em>JawScrapers</em> <em>Comb</em>, featuring teeth that remove tangles on rotation. This feature avoids the hair from winding around the brush, found in regular robot vacuum cleaners.</p>



<p>The <em>VibraRise 2.0</em> mop system also introduces actual floor scrubbing action unlike dragging a soaking wet cloth behind the robot vacuum cleaner. The sonic vibrations enable <strong>the mop pad to pulse up to 3,000 times per minute</strong> to ensure sufficient vibrations for removing sticky spills and tough stains on the floor. The two-zone vibrations allow for greater coverage during each pass as opposed to traditional single-zone vibrations. The <strong>mop will automatically raise by 8mm when it detects that it is standing on a carpeted floor</strong> so that it does not saturate the rugs.</p>
<p>The <strong>RockDock Plus comes with a self-emptying feature</strong>&nbsp;along with a huge 2.7-liter dust bag that can collect debris for a mind-boggling <strong>70 days without having to change it.</strong> This increases the forgetting period for vacuum cleaning by so much, for you will not think about it for several months. With each docking, the system will automatically extract the trash from the dustbin through a closed system that will see no dust escapes back to the air inside your house.</p>



<p>The PreciSense LiDAR navigation system has laser distance scanning technology to create a comprehensive map of your home. The sensor on top of the robot spins <strong>360 degrees and calculates distances to walls, furniture, and objects up to 8 meters away</strong>. This allows it to generate a comprehensive floor plan that it memorizes for future cleaning routines, learning the optimal paths through each room. Multi-level mapping comes in handy for homes that feature several floors, memorizing different maps for upstairs and downstairs without any confusion.</p>
<p>The obstacle avoidance feature in <em>ReactiveTech</em> depends on structured light technology whereby the robot emits invisible lights that are distorted by any object along its path, using which the system calculates the size and distance. This <strong>enables the robot to avoid shoes, wires, pet toys</strong>&nbsp;and other items that may lie on the floor, instead of becoming stuck or sending an alert to the human for assistance.</p>
<p>The value for money is absolutely great, make sure you don’t miss that deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4512/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-10000-pa-robot-vacuum-and-mop-with-70-day-self-emptying-is-selling-for-peanuts-roborock-demolishes-the-competition-2000639314]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Windows 11 Mini PC Sells for Pennies on Amazon, Now 3x Cheaper Than Mac Mini]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-windows-11-mini-pc-sells-for-pennies-on-amazon-now-3x-cheaper-than-mac-mini-2000639301</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-windows-11-mini-pc-sells-for-pennies-on-amazon-now-3x-cheaper-than-mac-mini.1336390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Desktop towers eat up precious desk space, generate noise and cost more than they should. Mini PCs solve all three problems by delivering full Windows performance in a package smaller than a hardcover book. The GMKtec G10 with Windows 11 Pro pre-installed offers a compelling alternative to Apple’s Mac Mini if you need Windows instead of macOS: Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5036/">just dropped this 512GB mini PC to an all-time low of $189 instead of $299</a>, and gives you real desktop power for less than a basic Chromebook.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5036/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Real Desktop Power in a Compact AMD Package</h2>
<p>The AMD Ryzen 5 3500U is driving the G10 and it is a 64-bit processor that <strong>features four cores and comes from AMD’s Zen+ architecture</strong>. This quad-core processor has a processing speed of 2.1 GHz and requires only a 15W thermal design power so that it is energy-friendly for use every day. This processor can further scale up to speeds of 3.7 GHz when it comes to single-threaded activity for smooth performance for users when it comes to web browsing, document processing, and video streaming.</p>



<p>The integrated Radeon Vega 8 has a processing speed of up to 1.2 GHz and uses the system memory along with the CPU. The unified memory allows for faster processing by avoiding the lag that comes when the CPU has to access different memories which makes it efficient for graphics processing. The Vega 8 processor has around 35 percent better graphics processing compared to Intel N-series, such as N100 or N150, used in entry-level mini-computers.</p>
<p>The GMKtec G10 is shipped with <strong>16GB of DDR4 SDRAM running in dual-channel mode</strong>, and it has two 8GB SO-DIMMs installed. The use of dual-channel mode increases the bandwidth from the CPU to the Ram by two times that of the single-channel mode setup. Users can upgrade the RAM to a maximum of 64GB by replacing the two installed SO-DIMMs, although 16GB will suit any user. The<strong> computer comes preinstalled with a 512GB SSD drive and has a PCIe 3.0 connection</strong> for faster access.</p>



<p>This small enclosure is turned into a productivity powerhouse by its triple display support: The <strong>Radeon Vega 8 Graphics can handle a total of three 4K displays simultaneously using its HDMI 2.1 display port, display port, and USB-C display port</strong>. The maximum recommended resolution for each display support is 4K, and the refresh rate is 60Hz, ensuring that there are no motion or text artifacts. This feature is particularly beneficial for stock market professionals requiring simultaneous access to different market feeds, designers requiring access to images, and any user requiring maximum display space.</p>
<p>The<strong> 2.5 Gigabit Ethernet port provides speeds that reach up to 2500 Mbps</strong>, well over double that supported by 1 Gigabit, the average standard found on computer ports. This will provide faster access times for larger file transfers through your home network which makes it easier to stream video without buffering. The added boost offered by the faster connection will also shine when accessing NAS storage, servers or using home networking software tools like pfSense or Untangle.</p>
<p><strong>Windows 11 Pro is installed and activated</strong>&nbsp;so there’s no waiting around for activation codes. The Windows 11 Pro comes with various features, such as <em>Remote Desktop</em>, allowing connection to the mini PC from another computer, <em>BitLocker</em>, used for encryption to protect your files, and <em>Hyper-V</em>, used for creating virtual machines.</p>
<p>Make sure you don’t miss that deal, it’s one of the most affordable ways to get a decent Windows computer.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5036/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-windows-11-mini-pc-sells-for-pennies-on-amazon-now-3x-cheaper-than-mac-mini-2000639301]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govee’s Floor Lamp Is Selling for Pocket Change, Amazon Has Zero Profit Margin Left on It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/govees-floor-lamp-is-selling-for-pocket-change-amazon-has-zero-profit-margin-left-on-it-2000639420</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/govee%E2%80%99s-floor-lamp-is-selling-for-pocket-change-amazon-has-zero-profit-margin-left-on-it.1336387/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Looking to transform a dull corner into something that actually catches the eye? Smart lighting has become the go-to solution for people who want to add personality to their space without committing to a full room makeover. Several <em>Govee</em> lamp models are currently on sale on Amazon but the real star of the show is their <em>RGBIC Floor Lamp Basic</em>, the platform’s number one best-seller in floor lamps. Right now, you can grab this <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4546/">game-changing lighting solution for just $69, down from its usual $99 price tag</a>. That’s a <strong>record low for this fantastic lamp</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4546/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why This Lamp Changes Everything About Room Lighting</h2>
<p>See what’s different about this floor lamp from your regular standing lamp: The RGBIC tech allows for <strong>different colors to be displayed on different parts of the LED strip</strong> <strong>lighting</strong> at the same time. When it comes to regular RGB lighting, it can only display one color at a time for the whole lamp itself: This RGBIC lamp can display actual color gradients and light displays that are more suited for your activity or desired mood. You can display red transitioning through orange, through yellow, then through blue, all simultaneously,<strong> along the lamp’s 136-cm standing height</strong>.</p>



<p>The lamp emits 1000 lumens and that’s incredibly bright for any use, whether it’s reading, working or any other activity. The warm white LEDs, too, are not merely a gimmick. This way, the lamp will provide decent lighting when needed, and then it’s free to display its outrageous colors when desired. The lamp’s design is also quite clever. Four poles made from aluminum can be assembled and rest upon another piece made from the same metal so that it doesn’t topple. The silicone that coats the light strip around the poles does more than add to the aesthetic. Instead, it helps diffuse the lighting from the LED lights, eradicating spots to ensure that lighting transitions smoothly from one color to the other.</p>



<p>Getting this lamp set up and running takes minimal effort: The Govee Home app (available for iOS and Android) connects <strong>via your home’s 2.4GHz WiFi network and unlocks the full potential of those 16 million color options</strong>. Inside the app, you’ll find <strong>58 dynamic scene modes</strong> with names like Cheerful and Romantic that do exactly what they promise. But the real power comes from creating your own custom scenes: Want specific colors at specific brightness levels for different times of day? Set it up once and let automation handle the rest. Voice control through Alexa or Google Assistant means you can adjust everything without touching your phone. Simple commands like asking Alexa to turn the lamp blue or dim it to 30% work exactly as you’d expect.</p>
<p>The sync feature for music makes way for something special to happen for entertainment purposes: Connect it to your sound system or simply play your music around the lamp, and see how it lights up in sync with the sounds. Gaming sessions become more interesting when the lights around you shine in sync with what’s happening in the action. Movie time sessions become more enjoyable when the environment lights around it change in sync with the sounds from the movie.</p>
<p>Considering the price, you are basically having access to technology that previously sold for so much more. Other rival intelligent lighting systems will require additional hub setups, so many elements, and so much hassle when it comes to putting them together. This lamp requires only that it’s plugged in and that the app is downloaded, and it will start functioning by itself.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4546/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/govees-floor-lamp-is-selling-for-pocket-change-amazon-has-zero-profit-margin-left-on-it-2000639420]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beats Pill Selling for Pennies, Amazon Liquidates the Iconic Bluetooth Speaker]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/beats-pill-selling-for-pennies-amazon-liquidates-the-iconic-bluetooth-speaker-2000639295</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beats-pill-selling-for-pennies-amazon-liquidates-the-iconic-bluetooth-speaker.1336372/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good sound matters most during the moments when music becomes the backdrop to your life. Game day gatherings with friends, cooking marathons in the kitchen, cozy living room hangouts during these cold months or even impromptu dance sessions when your favorite track comes on. You need a speaker that can keep up with your energy without constantly dying or worrying about spills.</p>
<p>The Beats Pill has been a favorite for years, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5035/">Amazon just dropped it to an all-time low of $99 instead of the original $149</a>. This iconic capsule-shaped speaker is being cleared out at a price that makes sense for what you get.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5035/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Redesigned Acoustics Deliver Seriously Loud Performance</h2>
<p>The 2024 Beats Pill went through a complete internal redesign focused on one goal: <strong>bigger, cleaner sound</strong>. At the core sits a reengineered racetrack woofer that uses stronger neodymium magnets to drive 28 percent more motor force compared to the previous Beats Pill Plus. This increased power lets the woofer displace 90 percent more air volume, which translates directly into deeper bass that you can actually feel. The woofer’s innovative structure includes ridges and contours designed to minimize low-end distortion even when you crank the volume to maximum.</p>
<p>The tweeter is encased in its own secure compartment to provide additional support that helps prevent unwanted vibrations. The tweeter’s compartment allows it to produce <strong>clear highs and full-bodied middle tones without disruption from the motion of the woofer</strong>. The speaker unit itself is tilted at an angle of 20°, ensuring that sound waves reach your ears instead of the floor or any piece of furniture in front that could absorb them. This feature allows Pill to perform better than its 8.6-inch size by sounding larger.</p>



<p>Bluetooth 5.3 increases connectivity functionality when compared to the previous version and offers quicker pairing, greater range and more stable connectivity. The Beats Pill comes equipped with Class 1 Bluetooth and offers the range advantage that standard Bluetooth speakers lack. This allows you to move from room to room or outside without having to worry about the sound suddenly cutting off. The <strong>speaker has quick pairing capabilities for both iOS and Android</strong>&nbsp;so it will automatically recall your device for easy reconnecting. The<em> Find My</em> and <em>Find My Device</em> integration feature for both iOS and Android also assists in tracking the location of the speaker using your smartphone.</p>



<p>Battery life has also improved to reach an <strong>impressive 24 hours of playback at 50 percent volume</strong> which is double what the previous model offered. With the improved battery life, the speaker can last through an entire day without requiring a recharge. Fast fuel charging has also improved functionality and offers up to two hours of playback time when charged for only 10 minutes if you need to leave for an important engagement.</p>
<p>The <strong>IP67 rating</strong> is also a serious level of protection for resisting the elements: This level of certification allows the speaker to withstand immersion beyond 1m for 30 minutes without any issue, while still blocking ingression from dust. The added sealing helps resist ingress from sand, dirt, and water. The silicone grips securely on smooth surfaces, making it resistant to slipping, and the lanyard cord allows for effortless carrying.</p>
<p>At this price point, the Beats Pill are among the best portable Bluetooth speakers on the market.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5035/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/beats-pill-selling-for-pennies-amazon-liquidates-the-iconic-bluetooth-speaker-2000639295]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Drops MacBook Air M4 Price Yet Again, Now Cheaper Than Basic Windows Laptops]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-drops-macbook-air-m4-price-yet-again-now-cheaper-than-basic-windows-laptops-2000639289</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-drops-macbook-air-m4-price-yet-again-now-cheaper-than-basic-windows-laptops.1336360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The perfect laptop needs to do three things well: <strong>handle your daily workload</strong> without hiccups, <strong>last through a full day</strong> without hunting for outlets, and <strong>stay portable</strong> enough to carry anywhere. Since its launch in March, Apple’s 2025 MacBook Air with the M4 chip with 256GB storage has been doing a pricing dance on Amazon that’s been frustrating to watch. It started at $999, dropped to $849, climbed back up to $899, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/">and now it’s finally hit rock bottom at $799 instead of $999</a>. This marks a new all-time low for what’s already Apple’s most popular laptop.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The M4 Chip Brings Desktop Power to Ultraportable Design</h2>
<p>The Apple M4 chip is the central processing unit in that laptop and it <strong>has a speed rate of 4.4 GHz, along with a 10-core CPU</strong> (four performance cores and six efficiency cores). This will allow the performance cores to undertake difficult tasks such as video production and processing complex documents, while the efficiency cores will perform everyday tasks without affecting the battery life.</p>
<p>The 8-core GPU that comes standard in the model supports ray tracing, mesh shading and other advanced features that were only found in the company’s M3 chip. Ray tracing allows light to trace its paths through 3D settings. The GPU also allows for faster editing times in Final Cut Pro and Adobe Photoshop, increasing photo-editing performance by up to 3.6 times faster than Intel models and movie editing by eight times faster in the movie-editing software iMovie.</p>
<p>Apple has incorporated <strong>a 16-core Neural Engine in the M4</strong> which executes a mind-boggling 38 trillion operations every second and nearly double that of the previous M3 chip. This Neural Engine enables <strong>Apple Intelligence functionality in the latest macOS version</strong>, including the functionality to remove background noise from videos automatically, improve images in a single click and provide system-wide AI support for keeping your data completely private.</p>



<p>The display is a <strong>13.6-inch Liquid Retina which offers a resolution of 2560×1664 pixels</strong> at 224 pixels per inch and features support for more than one billion colors. The display has a brightness level of 500 nits for clarity when used in bright conditions, such as outdoor lighting. The display can display colors accurately as it features the P3 wide color standard and offers support for more than a billion colors, <strong>along with True Tone technology</strong>.</p>
<p>The battery life can last for a <strong>maximum of 18 hours when used normally</strong> thanks to Apple’s optimized architecture using the ARM chip. The Macbook Air 2025 will provide its users with similar performance when using the battery and when it’s plugged into power, unlike Windows-based laptops whose performance will decline when using the battery for energy conservation reasons.</p>



<p>The improved 12MP Center Stage camera has an ultra-wide sensor and crops intelligently so that the user is always in frame during video calls. The <em>Center Stage</em> feature automatically tracks the user’s movement, zooms and pans to frame them regardless of where they happen to be in the room. The camera also has a feature that allows it to flip to <em>Desk View</em> mode which allows it to shoot from directly above, using the ultra-wide angle, highlighting the user’s desk.</p>
<p>Connectivity options include t<strong>wo Thunderbolt 4 ports that provide a data transfer rate of 40 Gbps</strong>, which makes it possible to connect high-resolution monitors and storage drives. The computer can support a maximum of 2 exterior monitors without affecting its internal display unlike its previous versions. The Wi-Fi 6E technology supports the use of the less crowded 6 GHz bandwidth and offers users faster internet connectivity. The computer also has a Bluetooth connection technology that allows it to connect to wireless devices. The <strong>computer has a 3.5 mm headphone jack</strong> that can support high-impedance headphones.</p>
<p>With a weight that’s only 2.7 pounds and thickness of 0.44 inches, the MacBook Air still leads the way when it comes to portability in Apple’s range. If you’re looking for a solid ultraportable laptop, this is a great choice – especially at this price point.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-drops-macbook-air-m4-price-yet-again-now-cheaper-than-basic-windows-laptops-2000639289]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Is Reportedly Making A Crash Bandicoot Series And He Better Not Talk]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/netflix-making-crash-bandicoot-animated-series-talking-report-cartoon-2000639396</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-is-reportedly-making-a-crash-bandicoot-series-and-he-better-not-talk.1336339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A new report claims that Netflix is developing an animated <a href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873"><em>Crash Bandicoot</em></a> series. And that could be cool, Crash seems perfectly suited to a cartoon, but I do have one request: He better not talk.</p> <p>On October 27, <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/news/crash-bandicoot-animated-series-in-the-works-at-netflix/"><em>What’s On Netflix</em> reported</a> that it had heard from sources that Netflix has been quietly working on a <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> animated TV show. Plot details are being kept under wraps, but the outlet claims that WildBrain Studios is the animation team behind the yet-to-be-announced <em>Crash</em> series. This is the same studio that worked on<em> Sonic Prime</em> from 2022 to 2024. The studio has also worked on <em>Johnny Test, The Snoopy Show, </em>and <em>Carmen Sandiego.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>Crash Bandicoot first appeared in the PlayStation 1 OG 3D platformer <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> in 1996. That title was developed by Naughty Dog, long before the studio would go on to make <em>Uncharted</em> and <em>The Last of Us</em>. It then developed two more sequels and a kart racer spin-off before moving on to other projects. Meanwhile, other studios continued to make <em>Crash</em> games well into the Xbox 360 era. In 2017, Activision put out the <a href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-naughty-dog-vicarious-visions-jump-1851786482"><em>N. Sane Trilogy</em>,</a> which contained remakes of the first three PS1 games. That was followed by 2021’s <em>Crash 4: It’s About Time</em>. Following Xbox’s purchase of Activision, Crash is now owned by Xbox. Weird.</p>

  <p>Assuming this TV show happens<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->and considering <a href="https://kotaku.com/video-game-tv-show-netflix-amazon-prime-fallout-last-of-1848707788">every streaming studio is desperately spending millions of dollars</a> on making their own <a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-show-amazon-review-1851400505"><em>Fallout</em></a> or <em>Last of Us</em>-sized hit, it’s very likely<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->it will be Crash’s first original show. It won’t, however, be his first appearance on Netflix. Controversially, the platforming legend appeared in Netflix’s <em>Skylanders</em> series, sporting an Australian accent. I hate it. And a lot of Crash fans did, too. The character has normally not spoken in the games or, at most, only uttered a handful of words, like “Whoa!” or “Uh-Oh!” And that’s all he needs. Let the others do the talking. Crash should be a force of nature that causes chaos in each episode.</p> <p>Talking or no talking, this reported <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> show is likely still a ways off from being announced and released. While we wait, we can watch some footage from <a href="https://youtu.be/LVFJ49X11ck">a different animated <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> show</a> that Amazon was rumored to be working on a few years ago, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/01/rumour_looks_like_crash_bandicoots_cartoon_series_has_been_cancelled">but which was reportedly canned in 2021</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/netflix-making-crash-bandicoot-animated-series-talking-report-cartoon-2000639396]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matrix Creators Wanted Kojima To Make A Game Based On The Movie, But Konami Said No]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-wachowskis-matrix-game-movie-mgs-konami-ps2-2000-2000639384</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/matrix-creators-wanted-kojima-to-make-a-game-based-on-the-movie-but-konami-said-no.1336321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Hideo Kojima / Warner Bros. / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>25 years ago,<em>&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/what-the-matrix-resurrections-really-says-about-video-g-1848276051">Matrix</a></em> creators and directors the <a href="https://kotaku.com/i-m-sorry-to-say-laurence-fishburne-died-in-the-2005-ma-1844803953">Wachowskis</a>&nbsp;met up with <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> creator <a href="https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-metal-gear-solid-death-stranding-ai-2000636622">Hideo Kojima</a> to ask him and his team to create a video game based on the blockbuster sci-fi action film starring Keanu Reeves. Apparently, Kojima was very interested in doing it, but higher-ups at Konami passed.</p> <p><a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/10/they-were-big-fans-of-kojima-the-wachowskis-once-asked-the-metal-gear-creator-to-make-a-matrix-video-game">In a recent interview with <em>Time Extension,</em></a> former Konami Digital Entertainment vice president of licensing Christopher Bergstresser talked about the long-rumored tale that Kojima was asked to make a <em>Matrix</em> game in 2000. It seemed like it was probably true, and details about it were floating around online, but the specifics were always a mystery. But not anymore, as Bergstresser talked openly about the meeting with <em>Time Extension.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p>“The Wachowskis were big fans of Kojima,” Bergstresser told the outlet. “So (Konami producer) Kazumi Kitaue, [Hideo] Kojima, Aki Saito (who still works with Kojima), and I were at the Konami HQ, and we got a call from the Wachowskis, who wanted to come in and meet with Kojima. So they did! The two of them came in with their concept artist, and effectively they said to Kojima, ‘We really want you to do the <em>Matrix</em> game. Can you do that?’”</p>

 <p>According to Bergstresser, this question was translated for Kitaue, and his response was a blunt “No.” This was likely because Konami wanted Kojima to focus on making <em>Metal Gear Solid 2</em>, which was in the early stages of production. While this might have been disappointing for the Wachowskis, they didn’t have any hard feelings and still invited the group to <em>The</em> <em>Matrix’s</em> launch party in Japan.</p> <p>Before this interview, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hideo-kojima-speaks-about-the-matrix/1100-2448486/">there was evidence of this meeting</a>, as <em>Time Extension</em> points out. But this is the first time we’ve really heard anything about it directly from someone who was there. The outlet does claim, however, that a different Konami employee told them that this story isn’t entirely accurate. Reportedly, Kojima still showed a “strong interest” in making a <em>Matrix</em> game even after Kitaue shut it down, and many members of the <em>MGS</em> creator’s team were filled with “immense disappointment” after missing out on such an opportunity.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-wachowskis-matrix-game-movie-mgs-konami-ps2-2000-2000639384]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>