<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:22:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Moves Odyssey Curved Gaming Monitor Into Clearance, 49″ G93SC Series Hits an All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-moves-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-into-clearance-49-g93sc-series-hits-an-all-time-low-2000664187</link>
            <guid>1420828</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Calling the Samsung Odyssey OLED G9 “ultra-wide” barely scratches the surface. This thing is enormous. At 49 inches across, it can dominate an entire desk. It’s the kind of monitor that makes dual-screen setups look quaint, delivering a single, seamless canvas that stretches far into your peripheral vision. Right now, it’s also far more affordable than usual. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/">The Odyssey OLED G9 normally sells for $1,249, but Amazon has dropped the price to $900, knocking a hefty $349 off the total for a limited time.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Lose Yourself in Super Wide Worlds</h2>
<p>That massive panel isn’t just about size for the sake of spectacle. The display runs at a resolution of 5120 by 1440, effectively matching two 27-inch QHD monitors fused together. Games and apps have room to breathe, and multitasking feels natural instead of cramped. The 1800R curve gently wraps around your field of view, making long gaming sessions feel immersive rather than overwhelming. It mirrors the way our eyes naturally take in our surroundings, pulling you deeper into sprawling open worlds or competitive arenas.</p>
<p>Speed is another major highlight. With a 240Hz refresh rate, the Odyssey OLED G9 is built for fluid motion and fast reactions. Paired with an ultra-low 0.03ms response time, on-screen action stays immediate and razor sharp even during frantic firefights or high-speed racing. NVIDIA G-Sync and AMD FreeSync Premium Pro support keep frames smooth and synchronized with your GPU, minimizing screen tearing and stutter so gameplay stays consistent and responsive.</p>



<p>The OLED panel itself elevates everything you put on screen. Blacks are truly black, whites are strikingly bright, and colors have a depth that standard LCDs struggle to match. Contrast is intense and precise, with light and dark areas kept tightly controlled. There’s no distracting glow or bleed around bright objects, which helps scenes look cleaner and more realistic. Games, movies, and even everyday desktop use benefit from the added clarity and vibrancy.</p>
<p>Connectivity is refreshingly flexible. The monitor includes HDMI 2.1, DisplayPort, and a built-in USB hub, making it easy to juggle multiple devices. You can keep a gaming PC, work laptop, and another device connected at the same time and switch between them effortlessly. The Odyssey OLED G9 can even detect active sources and automatically jump to the right input. For power users, picture-in-picture and split-screen options allow two different systems to share the display side by side.</p>
<p>Deals like this don’t come around often for flagship OLED gaming monitors. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/">Dropping from $1,249 to $900, the Samsung Odyssey OLED G9 becomes far more compelling for anyone ready to go all-in on a truly immersive setup.</a> For players who want size, speed, and image quality in one unapologetically massive package, this is a rare chance to save big.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-moves-odyssey-curved-gaming-monitor-into-clearance-49-g93sc-series-hits-an-all-time-low-2000664187]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Clears Out 45W Nintendo Switch Charger at Record Low, Compatible With Switch Lite and Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-45w-nintendo-switch-charger-at-record-low-compatible-with-switch-lite-and-steam-deck-2000664238</link>
            <guid>1420798</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Powering your Switch doesn’t have to be complicated. While you technically can power your console with any third-party USB charger or a power bank, you’ll get the best performance with only a few. The 45W Nintendo charger by Marsdock is one of the most reliable options around.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/">It typically sits at an already affordable price of $17, but you can now grab it for only $14 at Amazon – thanks to a 15% discount.</a> This offer applies to the option that includes a 5-foot cable. If you’re looking for something that’s a bit longer, the 10-foot is available for $17, down from $19. Grabbing two of these will knock another 6% off your total. Prime members can enjoy free delivery with their purchase, which brings the overall cost down even further.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Speedy and Reliable</h2>
<p>For under $15, you’ll enjoy high-speed charging. It gets your consoles from 0 to 50% in just an hour, offering significantly greater charging stability and higher efficiency than the standard 39W options. The adapter supports input from 100-240V and output up to 15V/2.6A, which makes it great for everyday gaming and travel. Compatibility is just as impressive, as the charger plays nicely with most devices that can be charged under 45W via USB-C. These include Switch, Switch OLED, Switch Lite, Switch TV dock, Steam Deck, and Switch Pro Controller.</p>



<p>Marsdock takes durability seriously with this one, too. The premium cord is rated for over 2000 bends, which ensures longevity, while the solid, well-fitting plug maintains safety and offers efficient power transfer. Additionally, there are built-in multi-safeguards and a cooling system that intelligently monitors temperature, offering protection against overcharging, short circuiting, overheating, and sparking. Basically, you can use the charger anywhere, anytime, without worry.</p>
<p>Included in the box are the 45W AC power adapter, with a 5ft AC extension cord. On a regular day, you’d pay around $17 to enjoy the convenience and fast speeds this charger offers, which is already quite affordable. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/">The current 15% discount, however, drops it to just $14.</a> Amazon has listed the discount as a limited-time offer, so it’s best to grab it without wasting much time. Now is also a great time to stock up on other gaming accessories and essentials, as we’re spotting quite a lot going for less at the retailer. We’re covering the best offers that are worth your hard-earned money, so be sure to check back for the latest drops!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-45w-nintendo-switch-charger-at-record-low-compatible-with-switch-lite-and-steam-deck-2000664238]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s The Last Chance To Buy The Nintendo Switch’s Best Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers-last-day-save-money-2000664520</link>
            <guid>1420795</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Switch vouchers over a Mario Party background.</span> © Nintendo / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The Nintendo Switch Game Voucher is <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-voucher-mario-kart-fire-emblem-discount-1850062170">one of those straight-up good deals</a>. If you’re a subscriber to Nintendo Switch Online, you can buy two coupons for $100, which can then be used to buy two full-price digital games more usually priced at $60 each. Boom, $20 saved, two new games to enjoy. And today, January 30, 2026, marks the very last day you can buy the vouchers. Boo.</p> <p>Back in July of last year, <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-vouchers-pokemon-za-metroid-prime-4-preorder-1851785969">Nintendo announced its intention to kill off the voucher scheme</a> alongside the launch of the Switch 2. With newer game prices nudging up to $70 and $80, it was made immediately clear the vouchers would not be valid for Switch 2 games, but that it <em>would</em> still be possible to take advantage of the scheme for another six months, and that all vouchers bought would remain valid for a full year after the point of purchase. Well, that day has come, and if you want to be sure of a way to pick up a couple of full-price Switch games between now and 2027, this is your last chance. A huge thanks to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/reminder-todays-your-last-day-to-buy-switch-game-vouchers"><em>Nintendo Life</em></a> for reminding us of the deadline.</p>

 <p>It’s still a great offer! Nintendo very notably still hasn’t moved on to focusing its new titles on the Switch 2, and the vouchers will save you a chunk off the just-released <em>Metroid Prime 4</em>, and indeed on April 16’s&nbsp;<em>Tomodachi Life: Living the</em> Dream<a href="https://kotaku.com/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-direct-nintendo-2000664120">,</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-direct-nintendo-2000664120">which we learned new details about yesterday</a>. The vouchers are also valid on a really decent range of games including <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em>,&nbsp;<em>Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em>,&nbsp;<em>Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</em>, and even the $70&nbsp;<em>Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>. These are all first-party Nintendo titles which are&nbsp;very rarely put on sale.&nbsp;You can see the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/games/game-voucher-eligible/#sort=df&amp;p=0">lengthy full list of eligible titles here</a>.</p> <p>It’s a double-bummer that this isn’t being extended to the Switch 2, given Nintendo also killed off its <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendos-rewards-program-is-actually-pretty-good-1823654369">splendid gold coins</a>. These were accrued by buying new games, and every dollar spent got you 5c worth of coins. At its best, this meant spending the $100 needed to get two vouchers also got you another $5 off a purchase. Quite why Nintendo’s removed all these advantages and offered no new incentives on Switch 2 is unknown, and a massive disappointment.</p>

 <p>However, if you <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers/">buy a pair of vouchers today</a>, they will remain valid until Jan 30, 2027. That <em>Tomodachi Life</em> was added to the scheme so close to its demise is a sign that&nbsp;maybeNintendo might even put other new Switch 1 releases into the offer even after it can no longer be purchased. No guarantees, though.</p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-game-vouchers-last-day-save-money-2000664520]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AirPods 4 With ANC Carry the Biggest Discount in Apple’s Earbuds Lineup, Now at Its Lowest Price of the Year]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/airpods-4-with-anc-carry-the-biggest-discount-in-apples-earbuds-lineup-now-at-an-all-time-low-2000664296</link>
            <guid>1420765</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple AirPods 4 are wireless earbuds with Active Noise Cancellation in a compact form that is convenient to carry and use throughout the day. To enhance comfort and stability, Apple redesigned the AirPods 4 earbuds with a more defined shape and a shorter stem with easy-to-use press controls for playing music and answering calls. For a quieter experience, the Active Noise Cancellation feature helps reduce external sounds as they reach your ears. If you prefer to stay aware of your surroundings, Transparency Mode lets you listen to what is happening around you while continuing to listen to your music.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/">You can purchase the Apple AirPods 4 at Amazon for $119. This is a savings of $60 and 34% off of their original price of $179.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Some of Apple’s best earbuds for calls, music, podcasts, and more</h2>
<p>AirPods 4 have an optical in-ear sensor that ensures they play audio only when the earbuds are worn and pause when they are removed. They feature a vent system designed for pressure-balanced sound, which can make extended listening feel much more comfortable. Plus, there are physical controls that let you perform common actions, such as controlling music playback and managing calls, without having to access your phone.</p>
<p>With Active Noise Cancellation, the Adaptive Audio feature combines noise cancellation with Transparency Mode to adapt to your surroundings. Conversation Awareness can automatically lower the volume of what you are listening to when you begin talking with someone nearby, and then raise it back up after you stop speaking. Voice Isolation uses computational audio to minimize ambient noise and improve clarity in noisy environments.</p>



<p>For music, TV programs, movies, and video games, Personalized Spatial Audio features dynamic head tracking to place sound around you. The high-excursion driver, high-dynamic-range amplifier, and Adaptive EQ work together to deliver a consistent, balanced sound that adapts to how well each AirPod fits your ears. The H2 headphone chip supports the processing required for spatial effects and noise reduction.</p>
<p>The USB-C charging case provides additional battery life, extending how long you can listen. With Active Noise Cancellation, you can expect up to 4 hours of listening time and up to 20 hours with the charging case. Five minutes of charging can provide approximately one hour of listening time.</p>
<p>Hands-free Siri can be activated with either “Siri” or “Hey Siri.” Also, with Siri Interactions, you can respond with a nod yes or a gentle shake no. Audio Sharing lets you share audio with two AirPods. Find My lets you locate your AirPods 4 and the charging case<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/">. The AirPods 4 and the charging case are both rated IP54 for dust, sweat, and water resistance. Now’s a great time to buy the AirPods 4, as they’re currently $119, down from $179.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6034/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/airpods-4-with-anc-carry-the-biggest-discount-in-apples-earbuds-lineup-now-at-an-all-time-low-2000664296]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenovo’s 24″ All-in-One Desktop Now Costs About as Much as a Budget Tablet on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lenovos-24-all-in-one-desktop-now-costs-about-as-much-as-a-budget-tablet-on-amazon-2000664269</link>
            <guid>1420747</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Workstation upgrades aren’t cheap. If your desk is in need of a refresh, but you don’t want to shell out big bucks, we’ve got good news.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6959/">Right now, the 24-inch Lenovo all-in-one desktop computer is down to just $400 at Amazon, after a whopping $199 discount</a>. This bundle comes with everything you need to get started right away, including a pre-installed copy of Windows 11 Home, a wired keyboard, and a wired mouse. However, as you’d expect, the offer is only available for a short time. It’s best to snap it up sooner rather than later, if you want to avoid paying the full $599 price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6959/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">Ver en Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Ideal for Students and Work Professionals</h2>
<p>You’re getting a stunning 23.8-inch, spacious Full HD display that pushes 1920 x 1080 resolution. You’ll enjoy crisp, vibrant picture quality for all types of content, whether you’re streaming your favorite show or creating an important work presentation. Plus, the anti-glare coating keeps the screen easy on the eyes, which is great for long work sessions or never-ending meetings. Speaking of video calls, you’ll find a high-quality 720p HD camera right above the screen. This camera is paired with Mono microphones that isolate your voice from the background noise and deliver it clearly on the other end.</p>
<p>Performance is impressive for day-to-day use. The system runs on a modest Intel N100 processor that features four cores and four threads with a max Turbo frequency of 3.40 GHz. It’s not a powerhouse, but it’s still perfectly capable of supporting your everyday needs – like office work, streaming, browsing, checking emails, handling light creative projects – without slowing down. There’s an 8GB DDR4 RAM to keep things running smoothly as you work and play. Again, it’s not massive, so you won’t exactly be able to multitask comfortably. But as long as you’re not trying to work on a bunch of resource-heavy tasks at once, you will enjoy minimal lag and decent performance.</p>



<p>Storage is taken care of by a roomy 512GB PCIe NVMe M.2 SSD, which is plenty for important work files, media content, research documents, and even some games. Note that the system is not expandable, so you won’t be able to increase the capacity as your needs grow, but you can always add external storage solutions to manage space better.</p>
<p>Wireless connectivity options include Intel Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth 5.2. On the wired side, you’re covered with an array of ports, including two USB-A (Hi-Speed USB / USB 2.0), two USB-A (USB 10Gbps / USB 3.2 Gen 2), one HDMI-out 1.4b, one Ethernet (RJ-45), and one headphone or microphone combo jack (3.5mm) – that’s all you need to create a fuller, more productive setup. Getting the wired keyboard and wired mouse in the bundle means you’ve already got all you need to get started with work and entertainment right away.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6959/">The bundle now costs $400, after Amazon took 33% off its usual price.</a> Just note that we’re not expecting the offer to last long. If you’ve been looking to upgrade your workstation without spending a ton, now is your chance to pick a solid, highly-rated option for less. Delivery is free, too, so $400 is all you’ve got to pay today.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6959/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">Ver en Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lenovos-24-all-in-one-desktop-now-costs-about-as-much-as-a-budget-tablet-on-amazon-2000664269]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WD 8TB External Hard Drive Drops Back to $0.02 per GB, Now Cheaper Than 6TB Storage Capacity]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wd-8tb-external-hard-drive-drops-back-to-0-02-per-gb-now-cheaper-than-6tb-storage-capacity-2000664299</link>
            <guid>1420720</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>You can add a lot of extra storage to your computer without opening the case with the Western Digital 8TB Elements Desktop External Hard Drive. Photos, 4K video, game installs, and old project archives all take up valuable space on computers. This desktop-style external drive provides a spot to stash them. The WD Elements Desktop has a black enclosure designed to sit next to your computer tower or monitor, and its 8TB capacity will give you enough space to create several large backup systems and many large media folders. To begin moving files to the external drive, simply plug in the power and the included USB cable, and you’re done.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6958/">The Western Digital 8TB Elements Desktop External Hard Drive is available now at Amazon for $171, a $54 savings or 24% off the original price of $225.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6958/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>An 8TB hard drive perfect for adding extra storage to your PC</h2>
<p>The Western Digital 8TB Elements Desktop External Hard Drive is a USB hard drive that provides additional storage capacity for larger media collections and bigger project folders. WD claims that this version of the Elements Desktop offers faster data transfer speeds than previous models, so transferring large numbers of photos, 4K videos, or large game files should be easier and quicker. The Elements Desktop comes pre-formatted to work immediately with a Windows-based PC, but Mac users will have to format it before use.</p>
<p>Setting up the WD Elements Desktop model is easy and does not require much technical knowledge. Once connected to a Windows machine, the Elements Desktop is recognized immediately and can be used to store files after connecting the power and USB cables.</p>



<p>A compact desktop enclosure houses the internal mechanical hard drive in the WD Elements Desktop, and it does not take up much space, especially considering the amount of storage capacity it contains. The WD Elements Desktop is compact, which makes it easy to place beside a computer tower or monitor. The simple black design will blend in well with most computing environments, and the quiet passive operation makes it suitable for long-duration file transfers and scheduled backups.</p>
<p>If you are running out of internal storage space, then this 8TB Elements Desktop model is one of the easiest ways to add capacity to your computer. This hard drive can be used to store full system backups, serve as an archive for older projects, or store large media collections, such as videos and photos, that are taking up too much space on your internal drive. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6958/">Now’s a great time to buy the WD Elements Desktop model, which is currently selling on Amazon for $171, a $54 savings from the $225 list price.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6958/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wd-8tb-external-hard-drive-drops-back-to-0-02-per-gb-now-cheaper-than-6tb-storage-capacity-2000664299]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>