<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:13:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Is Coming To Game Pass, Alongside Gears Of War: Reloaded]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-gears-of-war-reloaded-game-pass-2000618432</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-is-coming-to-game-pass-alongside-gears-of-war-reloaded.1273881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Half Gears of War, half Dragon Age.</span> © Xbox Games Studios / EA
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p>Xbox has just announced the new games arriving on Game Pass in the second half of August, and it contains a couple of enormous names. We already knew that&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> was going to be a day-one release on Microsoft’s subscription service, but we’ve now learned that <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> will be joining it two days later. Along with a bunch of others.</p> <p>Added today for PC is <em>Balatro</em> publisher Playstack’s <em>Void/Breaker</em>, developed by Stubby Games. Another game launching directly onto Game Pass, this is from the same team that created 2022’s extremely good FPS puzzler <em>The Entropy Center</em>.&nbsp;<em>Void/Breaker</em> is a roguelite FPS in which you’re trapped in endless loops by an evil AI, and is all about lightning-fast action.</p> <p>Also arriving on PC is an early access build of <em>Blacksmith Master</em>, a game that’s proven to be well-liked on Steam in which you…well, you already guessed from the title. It’s a blacksmith management sim.</p>

 <p>Arriving tomorrow, August 20, on consoles and PC is <em>Goat Simulator Remastered</em>, the recent remake of the original&nbsp;<em>GTA</em>-like spoof, and <em>Persona 4 Golden</em>, the 2012 update to one of the most beloved entries in the murderous coming-of-age series. Then on August 21 there’s <em>Herdling</em>, the big-beast herding adventure <a href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-trailers-announcements-1851627031/36#content">first announced at Gamescom last year</a>.</p> <p>Come August 26, the big hitter arrives. Stretch your crouching muscles because it’s <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em>, the anticipated remastering of the original <em>Gears of War</em> from 2006. Being published by Xbox Games Studios, it’s coming straight to Game Pass Ultimate, but in our new, strange future, it’s also being released for sale on PlayStation as well.</p> <p>Then there’s the big surprise for this month, <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em>. While the game has developed some manner of infamy for allegedly being poorly treated by both <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-anthem-mark-darrah-youtube-bioware-1851779569">BioWare</a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-mass-effect-5-bioware-live-service-1851756169">EA</a>, and was then caught in the tiresome culture wars, it remains a solid RPG and a great piece of storytelling in a well-loved universe. It already faced the ignominy of being <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-playstation-plus-march-sonic-tmnt-1851766608">free on PS Plus just a month after it was released</a>, but perhaps makes more sense to arrive on Game Pass now that it’s six months old.</p>

 <p>Here’s the full list of releases for August, and the various tiers of Game Pass on which they appear:</p> <p>Aug 19: <em><strong>Blacksmith Master </strong></em>– PC (Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass)</p> <p>Aug 19: <em><strong>Void/Breaker</strong></em><em> –&nbsp;</em>PC&nbsp;(Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass)</p> <p>Aug 20:&nbsp;<em><strong>Goat Simulator Remastered</strong>&nbsp;</em>– Xbox Series X|S (Game Pass Standard)</p>

 <p>Aug 20:&nbsp;<strong><em>Persona 4 Golden</em></strong> – Cloud, Console, PC (Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard)</p> <p>Aug 21:&nbsp;<strong><em>Herdling</em></strong> – Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S (Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass)</p> <p>Aug 26:&nbsp;<strong><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em></strong> – Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S (Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass)</p> <p>Aug 28:&nbsp;<strong><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em></strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong>– Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S (Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass)</p>

 <p>Then, because the universe must be balanced, a bunch of games are leaving. On August 31 you’ll no longer have:</p> <ul> <li><em>Ben 10 Power Trip&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, and PC)</li> <li><em>Borderlands 3&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, and PC)</li> <li><em>Paw Patrol Mighty Pups Save Adventure Bay&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, and PC)</li> <li><em>Sea of Stars&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, and PC)</li> <li><em>This War of Mine: Final Cut&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, and PC)</li> </ul> <p>Presumably&nbsp;<em>Borderlands 3</em> is being removed to entice you to pay for&nbsp;<em>Borderlands 4</em> when it comes out in September.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-gears-of-war-reloaded-game-pass-2000618432]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brainrot Slop Is Taking Over Fortnite (And Everything Else, Too)]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/brainrot-meme-fortnite-roblox-playstation-plus-odst-helldivers-2-news-2000618411</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brainrot-slop-is-taking-over-fortnite-and-everything-else-too.1273818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>And, just like that, we’re back. Welcome once again to Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku’s</em> daily round-up of news, interesting stuff, stories you might have missed, and more. This morning, we have bad news about PlayStation Plus, good news about<em> Helldivers 2,</em> strange news about that PlayDate console, and sad news about the state of video games as brainrot meme games continue to take over everything. But hey, at least that new <em>Conjuring</em> movie looks like it might be pretty good?</p> <h2><strong>A <em>Fortnite</em> clone of <em>Roblox’s</em> <em>Steal The Brainrot</em> is super popular</strong></h2> <p><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/steal-a-brainrot-roblox-empire-review-popular-memes-1851787027">Steal A Brainrot</a></em> has become one of the most popular games on <em>Roblox</em>, leading to kids throwing tantrums when someone…well, steals their brainrot. And now, someone has created a clone that’s become one of the most popular games on <em>Fortnite</em>. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-brainrotted-roblox-clone-is-dominating-the-fortnite-charts/1100-6534047/">At one point, as reported by <em>GameSpot</em></a>, the <a href="https://fortnite.gg/island?code=3225-0366-8885"><em>Fortnite</em> knock-off had over 180,000 active players.</a> That would put it in the top five on the Steam charts.</p> <p>And all this popularity has led to a flood of brain-rotting slop. There are clones filling up <em>Fortnite’s</em> creative mode. And if you look around other storefronts and games with user-generated content, <a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-psn-playstation-store-ai-slop-brainrot-junk-spam-1851786494">you’ll see that knockoff brain-rotting games are truly everywhere</a>. It’s totally awesome and not at all horrible that so much of the video game industry is now entirely based around random users chasing the algorithm and exploiting kids playing stuff on their iPad.</p>

 <h2><strong>Eight games are leaving PlayStation Plus in a few weeks</strong></h2> <p>Sony has announced that eight games are leaving PlayStation Plus Extra’s library on September 16. Sadly, one of the games going away is <em>Plucky Squir</em>e, a solid adventure with some impressive visual flair. Here’s the full list:</p> <ul> <li><em>UFC 5&nbsp;</em></li> <li><em>The Plucky Squire</em></li> <li><em>Night in the Woods&nbsp;</em></li> <li><em>Road 96&nbsp;</em></li> <li><em>Pistol Whip&nbsp;</em></li> <li><em>Odin Sphere: Leifthrasir</em></li> <li><em>FIST: Forged In Shadow Torch&nbsp;</em></li> <li><em>Dragon’s Crown Pro</em></li> </ul> <h2><strong>Game Boy emulation is now possible on the PlayDate</strong></h2>   <p>The PlayDate might not be the best-selling console around, but it is one of the coolest. And now the black-and-white handheld with a huge library of exclusive games (and a crank!) can do something very cool: Play original Game Boy games. Of course, not officially. Neither Nintendo nor the people behind the PlayDate are involved.&nbsp; But instead, a small group has created “<a href="https://github.com/CrankBoyHQ/crankboy-app">CrankBoy,” a free, fast, and high-performance Game Boy emulator</a> that works perfectly on the PlayDate and its sharp black-and-white screen.</p> <h2><strong>Some of <em>Halo’s</em> best guns will soon be available in <em>Helldivers 2</em></strong></h2> <p>We knew <em>Halo 3: ODST</em> content was coming to <em>Helldivers 2</em> as part of the game’s leap from PS5 to Xbox later this month. But now,<a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/19/helldivers-2-halo-odst-crossover-warbond-xbox-launch/"> Xbox has revealed more details about the crossover DLC</a>, and while I’m happy to see the iconic ODST armor arriving in<em> Helldivers 2</em>, the bigger news is that four guns from <em>Halo</em> are coming to the co-op sci-fi shooter, too. This includes the franchise’s famous assault rifle, but more importantly, it includes <em>ODST’s </em>wonderful&nbsp;SOCOM pistol, aka that cool silenced pistol that goes “pip pip pip” and drops Grunts cleanly. I’m hopping back into <em>Helldivers 2</em>, baby.</p> <h2>Valve is adding six new characters to its hero shooter thing known as <em>Deadlock</em></h2> <p>Remember <a href="https://kotaku.com/deadlock-valve-steam-hero-shooter-moba-release-date-1851631341"><em>Deadlock</em></a>? It was that secret hero-based MOBA-shooter Valve sort of released, but in a weird way. Well, <em>Deadlock</em> continues to grow, and the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1422450/view/669466707009471267?l=english">game’s latest update is one of its biggest</a>. It adds a whole new lobby area for players to explore between matches and a new character, a deadly but stylish vampire. Plus, Valve plans to add five new characters to the game over the next few days. Perhaps it’s time I play some more <em>Deadlock</em>?</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-netease-original-heroes-new-characters-2000618254">The devs behind <em>Marvel Rivals</em> might start adding original characters</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-sony-santa-monica-cory-barlog-2000618215">No,<em> God of War</em>‘s director didn’t tease a new game; it was all a hoax</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/skate-4-reboot-ea-servers-150-players-100-songs-seasons-summer-2000618257"><em>Skate 4</em> will support 150 players all skating at once</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch This:</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Incredible Demo Scene - Making Art with Code" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vIQ74_DRWEM?feature=oembed"></iframe></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/brainrot-meme-fortnite-roblox-playstation-plus-odst-helldivers-2-news-2000618411]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hollow Knight: Silksong Drought Is Finally Over As Devs Tease ‘Special Announcement’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-announcement-gamescom-stream-2000618437</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-hollow-knight-silksong-drought-is-finally-over-as-devs-tease-%E2%80%98special-announcement%E2%80%99.1273815/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-the-kotaku-review-1827367425"><i><span>Hollow Knight</span></i></a> <span>fans, this is not a drill. We’re actually getting an update on </span><i><span>Hollow Knight: Silksong</span></i><span>, the long-awaited sequel that has gone so long without an update that the act of anticipating it </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/silksong-hollow-knight-switch-2-screenshots-date-1851775219"><span>has become a meme</span></a><span> almost as common as making </span><i><span>Half-Life 3 </span></i><span>jokes in the chat section of every industry livestream. </span><i><span>Silksong </span></i><span>may appear at today’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/silksong-gamescom-2025-livestream-what-time-fallout-black-ops-7-2000618270"><span>Gamescom showcase</span></a><span>, but it looks like developer Team Cherry also has something else to share on Thursday.</span></p> <p><span>The studio has scheduled a YouTube video to go up on Thursday, August 21, at 10:30 a.m. Eastern Time titled “Special Announcement.” There’s really nothing else to go on here beyond a logo and a chat log of people already excitedly waiting for whatever the video is. However, given that the game is </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-xbox-rog-ally-gamescom-demo-1851787121"><span>playable at Gamescom</span></a><span>, there’s enough reason to be cautiously optimistic that </span><i><span>Silksong </span></i><span>is finally, after all this time, imminent, and coming to a console near you. Here’s the scheduled video if you want to save it for Thursday, or just hang out with the rest of the sickos waiting in the chat.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Special Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XGeJwsUP9c?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><i><span>Hollow Knight: Silksong </span></i><span>was first announced in 2019, just two years after the original game launched in 2017. Since then, the game’s absence from any and every video game showcase has been felt so deeply that hoping and praying for its arrival has become an ongoing joke for the series’ fans, as well as passersby who loved to clown on fans every time the game didn’t show up. Now, it seems, the drought is finally over. Hopefully, </span><i><span>Silksong </span></i><span>is coming soon. If it is, you’ll be able to play it just about anywhere, as the game is coming to both current and last-gen consoles, as well as PC, Mac, and Linux devices. Strap in, folks. After six years of waiting, the ride is about to begin.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-announcement-gamescom-stream-2000618437]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening Dev Blames Crappy Endgame Communication On Enforced Vacations]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-endgame-update-funcom-2000618401</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-dev-blames-crappy-endgame-communication-on-enforced-vacations.1273761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A man kicks someone in the face.</span> © Funcom
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p>The latest update for&nbsp;<em>Dune: Awakening</em> begins with an apology. Recognizing that communication with players hasn’t been Funcom’s strong suit of late, the developer explains that it’s in part because of “state mandated” vacations.</p> <p>“I apologize if people feel the communication around issues with the game has been lacking,” says <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1172710/view/515218419125060312">the latest update posted to Steam</a> (thanks,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/dune-awakening-promises-an-endgame-overhaul-and-says-communication-has-been-bad-because-developers-had-state-mandated-vacations/"><em>PC Gamer</em></a>). “We are focused on improving this. With a percentage of the team having their well-earned (and state mandated) vacations, customer service and the community team have not always had access to developers who can answer their every question.”</p> <p>If you’ve ever been on a trip to Norway (and Sweden) during July, you’ll have learned the hard way (I speak from experience) that <em>everything is closed</em>. This is a result of <em>fellesferie</em>, the annual summer “common holidays” where just about everyone takes their vacation at the same time. Which is quite mad, but for Norwegians, entirely ordinary. It’s normal for offices to just close down in July, and people who do persist in working during the month will struggle if they rely on suoport from their colleagues. It appears to be <em>fellesferie</em><em>&nbsp;</em>that’s affected&nbsp;<em>Dune: Awakening</em>.</p>

 <p>Regarding the enforced nature of these vacations, Norway has something called the The Holiday Act, that mandates all employees receive 25 days of vacation a year, meaning it’s even more tricky to prevent an entire team all disappearing off at once.</p> <p>“We’ve been playing whack-a-mole with bugs, cheats and exploits during the July month of summer,” says Funcom. “We’ve banned thousands of cheaters, fixed a bunch of duplication and exploit bugs and continued working on the stability of the game. We’ve been working to achieve a cadence of patches that allows us time to make stable and consistent fixes, while being fast enough to address issues like exploits before they get too far out of control. Live Game development is a blend of reactivity and long term planning.”</p> <figure id="attachment_2000618409" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000618409"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000618409">© Funcom</figcaption></figure> <p>While players have loved <em>Awakening</em>, there’s been a lot of dissatisfaction around what there is to do once the main content is finished. Funcom explains that its Gamescom news is going to be focused on the Chapter 2 Free Update and The Lost Harvest DLC, neither of which will affect the endgame, saying, “this is because Chapter 2 and the DLC were planned and began development before launch.” But, it goes on to list what’s happening in the later stages.</p>

 <p>It seems the big problem facing Funcom, other than an empty office, is that&nbsp;<em>Dune: Awakening</em> has drawn in what it describes as “very different demographics,” who all want something different from the MMO’s endgame. However, the issues are boiled down to “loss of items/vehicles, players feeling that they are forced into PvP, exploits and cheats, and lack of endgame content/grind.” Arriving soon are the following changes:</p> <ul> <li> <p><b>Improved Player Logging</b>&nbsp;– One of the key frustrations we see is the lack of information and clarity around why certain items/objects/vehicles are gone. We will increase the information in your logs so that you have a better idea of what is going on. For example, listing the names of people who take things from chests in your base.&nbsp;<wbr></p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p><b>Vehicle Salvaging System</b>&nbsp;– We’re working on a vehicle salvaging system that will allow you to recover lost vehicles.&nbsp;<wbr></p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p><b>Cobalt Paste/Vehicle Inventory&nbsp;</b>– We’re adjusting the volume of the infamous cobalt paste and adding more slots to the Assault Ornithopter vehicle inventory. We will be adding a cargo container that can be carried by the Carrier Ornithopter.&nbsp;<wbr></p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p><b>Instanced Deep Desert Loot</b>&nbsp;– The constant camping and queuing of the Deep Desert Testing Stations leads to a frustrating experience where people arrive at an empty Testing Station. We’re going to change these to be more in line with the rest of the game.&nbsp;<wbr></p> </li> </ul> <ul> <li> <p><b>Offline Notifications about important events&nbsp;</b>– We understand that not everybody can or wants to log in to check power/taxes constantly in the game. We would like to create a notification service that sends you the status of your base via email. This one is squarely aimed at you, Ben.</p> </li> </ul> <p>The post then continues with longer-term plans for endgame content:</p> <blockquote> <p>As we’ve mentioned previously, the Landsraad is supposed to be the endgame activity driver. Currently it does not have the breadth or depth of content or progression to serve that function. As we work towards Chapter 3, we will begin to tie the faction progression of the game to the Landsraad, while also systematically building out the Landsraad with a greater variety of activities across the world.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>As a player this means that you can increase your faction rank by completing Landsraad tasks, checking in with your Duke or Baron occasionally to perform special missions and visit faction vendors.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>Landsraad activities will become contract based, rather than delivery based, which will allow us to effectively remove the issue of stockpiling that is currently endemic in the game.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>This ensures that people are rewarded for solo play (as well as making contributions easier for them to track) and will give you many choices in how you progress over time.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>As for the planned activities, we have plenty in mind in addition to the current testing stations and shipwrecks. The following list contains examples, and not promises, as these will take work and time to deliver. But currently we are thinking of things like: Assassinations, Treasure Maps, Races, Construction Challenges, Duels, Faction vs Faction maps, Improved control points, Scavenger Hunts, Temporary Crafting Challenges etc.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>These activities will make use of the Overland Map, spawning in new maps as required. We have always wanted to flesh out the Overland Map over time, and this will boost that along.</p> <p>Of course, we are open to your suggestions so please share with us on social media the kinds of activities you would like to see in the Landsraad.&nbsp;<wbr></p> <p>As the Landsraad activities become more fleshed out, we will then transition the Deep Desert back towards the original intention – a sandbox area where players can compete for control of the spice. We will continue to iterate on the Deep Desert – adding no-fly zones to enforce ground combat, adding more layouts with more variety and challenge, and ensuring that there is clear progression. In addition, we are experimenting with the tech behind the Deep Desert and if things go well, you will experience the Deep Desert in a much more stable environment.</p> </blockquote> <p>This will apparently be the focus for the rest of 2025, now everyone’s back in the office. Before they all take off again for Christmas.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dune-awakening-endgame-update-funcom-2000618401]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Recreated KPop Demon Hunters In Animal Crossing And It’s Amazing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-songs-animal-crossing-youtube-stream-2000618416</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/someone-recreated-kpop-demon-hunters-in-animal-crossing-and-it%E2%80%99s-amazing.1273758/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><span>I never really think of </span><i><span>Animal Crossing: New Horizons </span></i><span>as a great game for recreating other movies and music videos until I see the lengths some creators go to use Nintendo’s life sim as their movie studio. I’ve been obsessed with Netflix’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-best-worst-songs-soundtrack-ranking-2000616633"><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i></a><span> for the past month, and several nights a week I’ll find myself scrolling through my feeds looking for reaction videos, covers, and other indulgences to feed my ongoing brainrot. Now, I’ve found an </span><i><span>Animal Crossing </span></i><span>channel that is recreating all the movie’s musical numbers in </span><i><span>New Horizons</span></i><span>, and I’m mostly just surprised at the creative solutions they came up with to make up for the game’s lack of fantasy weaponry and demons.</span></p> <p><span>Anyone who’s played </span><i><span>Animal Crossing: New Horizons </span></i><span>knows that it has some pretty robust creative options in terms of outfit design, character customization, and even set creation. Where the challenge lies in recreating something like a </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters </span></i><span>music video is in finding animations, items, and characters that can at least somewhat emulate things that don’t exist in the game. YouTuber Magic Studios, who has recreated almost every musical moment in the film, has managed to use the tools in </span><i><span>New Horizons </span></i><span>to creatively represent actions like demon fighting and skydiving from a busted plane, and, to the best of their ability, tried to capture the film’s choreography.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="✨K-Pop Demon Hunters: What It Sounds Like (An ACNH Music Video)✨" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fKk9WeRNXxg?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>Some of the most clever details will likely hit hardest for people who have both seen the movie and put an exorbitant amount of time into perfecting their </span><i><span>New Horizons </span></i><span>island, such as the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-tom-nook-is-misunderstood-506751609"><span>money-loving tanuki Tom Nook</span></a><span> representing Gwi-ma, the demon king final boss that the Kpop girl group Huntr/x faces in the finale. My favorite part of these videos, however, is seeing how Magic Studios recreated different costumes for both the main cast and side characters using </span><i><span>New Horizons</span></i><span>’ Custom Designs feature. Some videos are more elaborate than others, like the “Golden” music video which faithfully recreates the movie’s pre-performance hype cycle as the girls are promoting the upcoming single.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="✨K-Pop Demon Hunters: GOLDEN (An ACNH Music Video)✨" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/arDp3X_5lyg?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>You can check out all of Magic Studios’ </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i><span> videos </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@magicstudios7112"><span>on their channel</span></a><span>. The film is streaming on Netflix and is now the </span><a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/top10/most-popular"><span>second-most-popular movie ever on the platform</span></a><span>. If you can still grab tickets, Netflix is putting the movie in theaters this weekend for a limited-time sing-along event.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-songs-animal-crossing-youtube-stream-2000618416]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>