<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:09:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of The Most Underrated Roguelikes Of The Past 6 Years Is Just $3 On Switch Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-cheap-indie-game-sale-roguelike-metroidvania-2000641389</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-most-underrated-roguelikes-of-the-past-6-years-is-just-3-on-switch-right-now.1344853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Dicey Dungeons</em> came out <a href="https://kotaku.com/dicey-dungeons-is-a-good-entry-point-for-deck-builders-1837283279">way back in 2019</a>, a fact that blew my mind when I went to go double-check it today. That feels like a lifetime ago, but the deckbuilding roguelike itself still feels surprisingly fresh. Developed by Terry Cavanagh (<em>Super Hexagon</em>, <em>VVVVVV</em>), it combines two of my favorite things, turn-based combat and getting burned on RNG re-rolls, into a great dice battling game that too often goes overlooked. Somehow it’s currently just $3 on Switch.</p> <p>The premise is basically “what if you took a traditional turn-based dungeon game and ran every action through a jumble of chaos?” You collect equipment in the form of cards which dictate what actions you can take, and dice which are used to activate the cards. Some cards can only work with certain dice, and certain abilities will be stronger or weaker depending on the rolls you link them with. It’s a multi-layered math problem that sounds like homework in theory but is actually quite straightforward to navigate and slickly implemented in practice.</p>

 <p>There’s a bit of <em>Slay the Spire</em>, a bit of <em>Balatro</em>, and a whole lot of Cavanagh’s own clever design work going on. It’s not the only great Switch indie game on sale right now, though. A whole bunch of them are super cheap for the next week or so:</p> <ul> <li><em>Sifu</em> – $10 (75 percent off)</li> <li><em>What Remains of Edith Finch</em> – $4 (80 percent off)</li> <li><em>The Pathless</em> – $10 (75 percent off)</li> <li><em>Haiku, the Robot</em> – $4 (80 percent off)</li> <li><em>Ashen</em> – $10 (75 percent off)</li> <li><em>Dredge</em> – $10 (60 percent off)</li> <li><em>Gorogoa</em> – $4.50 (70 percent off)</li> <li><em>Citizen Sleeper</em> – $6 (70 percent off)</li> <li><em>Blasphemous</em> – $6.25 (75 percent off)</li> <li><em>Dicey Dungeons</em> – $3 (80 percent off)</li> <li><em>Darkest Dungeon</em> – $7.50 (70 percent off)</li> <li><em>Kentucky Route Zero: TV Edition</em> – $10 (60 percent off)</li> <li><em>Risk of Rain 2</em> – $6.25 (75 percent off)</li> </ul> <p>I’ve already sung <em>Dicey Dungeons</em>‘ praises, but I want to give another special shoutout to <a href="https://kotaku.com/haiku-the-robot-hollow-knight-silksong-review-metroidva-1848910676"><em>Haiku, the Robot</em></a>. This is another one that was easy to miss when it came out a few years back. It’s a retro-styled Metroidvania that has some neat ideas but doesn’t overstay it’s welcome. There’s fun combat, some light platforming, and a great soundtrack. Plus a grappling hook. But it’s not an overwhelming maze or a gauntlet of brutal boss fights. It’s inspired by <em>Hollow Knight</em> but a much friendlier version of that formula, while still feeling authentic and charming. At just $4, it’s also a steal.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-cheap-indie-game-sale-roguelike-metroidvania-2000641389]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wow, There Are Way Too Many Nintendo Apps]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-store-app-music-too-many-switch-2-iphone-phone-2000641401</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-there-are-way-too-many-nintendo-apps.1344850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Today, <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-store-app-play-time-session-switch-3ds-wii-u-2000641372">Nintendo launched a new Store app</a> for mobile phones that lets you wishlist, search for, and buy Switch and Switch 2 games on your phone. And that’s neat, but uh, why is this a separate app? Why does Nintendo keep insisting that you need one app to listen to music, another one to handle parental controls, and yet a few more to buy games, get news, and manage your Switch 2 console? It’s getting ridiculous.</p> <p>On November 5, the Nintendo Store App was released on mobile phones, letting users check out the Switch and Switch 2 eShop and even dig into some really interesting playtime data that the Mario maker has been collecting for years. Yet, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/developer/nintendo-co-ltd/id1062496488">it also means Nintendo now has five separate non-gaming apps</a>.</p>

 <ul> <li>Nintendo Switch App</li> <li>Nintendo Music App</li> <li>Nintendo Today!</li> <li>Nintendo Switch Parental Controls</li> <li>Nintendo Store App</li> </ul> <p>Want to see which of your friends are online or manage your screenshots? <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-app-update-screenshots-upload-qr-code-1851782946">Use the Switch mobile app</a>. Want to buy a Switch 2 game on your phone? Well, download the newly released store app and use that. Also, the store app just opens a browser when you try to buy a game, so it’s not even that useful. Want to manage your console’s parental controls? Guess what, buddy? Go download another app. Curious about any new Nintendo news or announcements today? Fuck you, go download yet another app. Perhaps you wish to enjoy some music from your favorite Switch game, <em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons.</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-music-app-update-nes-games-donkey-kong-1851786691">Oh, you already know what I’m going to tell you: Download another app</a>.</p>

 <p>It’s all so strange and unnecessary. All of these apps feel barebones and not very useful because individually, each one only offers a few options and features. I’d much rather have a single Nintendo Switch app on my phone that contains a store, a little news section, and a way to manage my console and friends list. Breaking that out across three apps is silly. I’d even shove the parental controls into the main Switch app, too. This is mostly how Steam, Xbox, and PlayStation handle it, though Sony and Microsoft <em>also</em> break out parental controls into separate apps like Nintendo.</p> <p>Anyway, I’m excited for Nintendo to announce another new app next year that lets me change the visual settings on my Switch 2 and then another app that lets me manage my saves. I want 18 different Nintendo apps that I bounce between by 2030!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-store-app-music-too-many-switch-2-iphone-phone-2000641401]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Regret To Report ‘Grand Theft Cthulhu’ On Game Pass Just Ain’t Good]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/grand-theft-cthulhu-gta-dead-static-drive-xbox-game-pass-review-is-it-good-2000641388</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-regret-to-report-%E2%80%98grand-theft-cthulhu%E2%80%99-on-game-pass-just-ain%E2%80%99t-good.1344775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I often have to play a game for a few hours before I feel confident in saying I liked it or didn’t like it. Before I can say this is good or this is bad. Sometimes you play a game that, within 20 minutes or less, makes it clear that it ain’t very good. Sadly, <a href="https://kotaku.com/grand-theft-cthulu-sure-lets-do-it-1841477897"><em>Dead Static Drive</em></a> was one of those games.</p> <p><em>Dead Static Drive </em>has been in some form of development for <a href="https://www.killscreen.com/dead-static-drive-road-trip-horror-vintage-americana-style/">nearly a decade</a> and has repeatedly gone viral online thanks to its eye-catching art style. And now the isometric survival horror game is out on Xbox, PC, and Game Pass. Often marketed as “<a href="https://www.deadstaticdrive.com/">Grand Theft Cthulu</a>,” <em>Dead Static Drive </em>has you stealing cars, completing missions, and exploring a monster-infested world that provides a lot of freedom to go where you want to go while trying to gather the supplies you need to stay alive. It’s a cool idea, for sure, but it never comes together. Most of this game doesn’t really work, and with the exception of <em>Dead Static Drive</em>‘s wonderful low-poly art style, there’s little about this game that I enjoyed.</p>

  <p>The biggest issue I encountered is how horrible it feels to drive cars in the newly released game. In something describing itself as Grand Theft Chthulu, I expected the cars to handle well and feel fun to drive around desolate cities and highways. Nope! No matter what camera or controller settings I changed, driving in <em>Dead Static Drive</em> is a mess. I never felt in control of any vehicle I entered, and getting around corners without crashing proved to be the biggest challenge. I’m also baffled by the decision not to include any engine noises. The first time I got into a car and drove off, I assumed the game had bugged out and the car should be making noise. Restarted, tried a different car, and nope. Nothing. Silence. I looked at other people’s gameplay and it turns out that this isn’t a bug, but a design choice. And it’s odd! This robs the different cars you encounter of a lot of the personality and makes the game feel unfinished.</p>

 <p>A lot of this game feels unfinished, though, so that’s probably why I assumed the missing audio was a bug at first. Combat is a slog, animations are clunky, quests break all the time, and NPCs get stuck on geometry. The inventory screen seems half-finished, missing features like “Quick Move” which makes managing all the gubbins you find annoying as heck on a controller. Characters also don’t have voice lines, which could have been fine, but in a game where cars make no noise beyond tire squeals and the world around you is empty, it just leads to <em>Dead Static Driv</em>e being a boring experience.</p> <p>After about three hours of playing <em>Dead Static Drive</em>, I pulled over and got out. It’s a shame because the world looks amazing, and I like the premise a lot, but what’s here just isn’t worth any more time.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/grand-theft-cthulhu-gta-dead-static-drive-xbox-game-pass-review-is-it-good-2000641388]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If You’ve Finally Run Out Of Stuff To Do In Baldur’s Gate 3, How About A New Campaign?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-campaign-fan-mod-path-to-menzoberranzan-2000641395</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-you%E2%80%99ve-finally-run-out-of-stuff-to-do-in-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-how-about-a-new-campaign.1344772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491"><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i></a> <span>is an incredibly dense RPG, and I’m sure there are still players who have yet to see everything in Larian Studio’s </span><i><span>Dungeons &amp; Dragons </span></i><span>adventure. However, for the sickos who have been combing through the game for two years and wish they had a reason to go back to it, a group of dedicated fan modders is working on what is essentially the expansion Larian chose not to make.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>“Path to Menzoberranzan” is an entirely fan-made campaign separate from the story and characters of </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i><span>. Around 130 modders are working on this original tale. Though the full campaign is still far off, the alpha is projected to launch in the “first half of 2026,” and will include the mod’s prologue chapter. As the name suggests, the mod’s campaign will take players to Menzoberranzan, a prominent Drow city in the fantastical world of Faerûn. Even if you’re a casual Forgotten Realms fan, you might have heard about the city from </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3 </span></i><span>companion Minthara, who originated from the city before becoming a pawn of the Absolute.&nbsp;</span></p>

  <p><span>Though it remains to be seen if the campaign will have any overt references to the main game’s crew, “Path to Menzoberranzan” will feature an entirely new cast of characters, each with an original backstory and voice acting. While development is ongoing, the team is still actively recruiting team members, auditioning voice actors, and providing semi-regular updates on </span><a href="https://discord.com/invite/ptm"><span>its Discord server</span></a><span>. So if you’re looking for something to do while you wait for whatever Larian is working on next, here’s another </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3 </span></i><span>project to distract you.</span></p> <p><span>Despite </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i><span>’s resounding success, Larian seems to be done with the series and is instead </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-director-teases-next-crazy-thing-sequel-2000614546"><span>working on two new </span></a><a href="http://projects.we/"><span>projects</span></a><span>. We don’t know what either of them is yet, but the team is likely much further along than the ideation phase it was in when Larian </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-larian-studios-next-game-excalibur-1851509450"><span>first started discussing these games last year</span></a><span>. Despite moving on from the game, Larian put out some massive patches and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-notes-crossplay-photo-mode-1851776211"><span>free updates for </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i></a><span>, so if you haven’t played it since launch, there’s plenty new to see.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-campaign-fan-mod-path-to-menzoberranzan-2000641395]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>