<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:16:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All-Time Great Luigi’s Mansion Is Heading To Nintendo Classics In Time For Halloween]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/all-time-great-luigis-mansion-is-heading-to-nintendo-classics-in-time-for-halloween-2000638167</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-time-great-luigi%E2%80%99s-mansion-is-heading-to-nintendo-classics-in-time-for-halloween.1331272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Luigi attempts to vacuum a ghostie.</span> © Nintendo / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p><em>Luigi’s Mansion</em>, the original game in the glorious ghost-hunting series, was a launch title released for the GameCube in 2001. However, beyond a remake on the much underloved 3DS in 2018, the 24-year-old classic has long been tough to play without using emulation. And it’s worth playing, because it’s completely brilliant! So it’s tremendous news that on October 30, the game is being added to the GameCube collection on what’s now called Nintendo Classics, available to anyone with a Switch 2 and the expanded subscription.</p> <p>OK, admittedly I’m struggling with the fact that I remember playing this game on release like it was a decade ago, not two and a half of them, but my own battle with linear time aside, this is all good news. It’s wild to me that <em>Luigi’s Mansion</em> hasn’t been ported to every Nintendo console since, given just what a stone-cold classic the third-person ghost-vacuuming game truly is.</p>

 <p>Poor Luigi, ever trembling in the shadow of his brave brother, is notified that luck is finally going his way, and he’s won a mansion! Except, he never entered the contest, and it turns out the place is a haunted wreck. Thankfully, Professor Elvin Gadd has made a base in the place (presumably squatting?), although he explains the building only popped into existence a few days earlier. Oh, and Mario’s trapped inside. So Luigi, using E. Gadd’s Poltergust 3000 vacuum cleaner, sets about clearing the mansion of its ghostly inhabitants.</p>

  <p>The game received a fairly frosty reception from some on its release in 2001 (<em>GameSpot</em> called it the most disappointing game of the year!), partly based on its relatively short length (it comes in under 10 hours), and partly because it wasn’t a&nbsp;<em>Mario</em> game. Much like the Switch 2 launching with a <em>Donkey Kong</em> title and not the expected new&nbsp;<em>Super Mario</em> extravaganza, the GameCube similarly confused the masses with a Luigi-led project that was an entirely new type of game from Nintendo. It wouldn’t be until almost a year later that <em>Super Mario Sunshine</em> came out to fill that gap, and <em>GameSpot</em> called that the most disappointing game of the year, too!</p>

 <p>Anyway, all those moaners were wrong, and judged not as a substitute for a <em>Super Mario</em> game but as something very different in its own right, <em>Luigi’s Mansion</em> shines. It’s quite easy (apart from the stupidly hard final boss), it’s relatively short, and it’s very, very funny, and that’s what it was setting out to be.</p>

 <p>It is, however, worth noting that this addition is the original game, and not the much prettier 2018 3DS remake, which itself now wallows in the sad misery of abandonware.</p> <p>If you have the Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscription (oh <em>please</em> can Nintendo give that a new name too?), you’ll find that <em>Luigi’s Mansion</em> will appear in the GameCube section of Nintendo Classics this October 30, just in time for spooky season.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/all-time-great-luigis-mansion-is-heading-to-nintendo-classics-in-time-for-halloween-2000638167]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus Offloads Its RTX 5070 and 5080, Now Priced Like the Old Gen]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-offloads-its-rtx-5070-and-5080-now-priced-like-the-old-gen-2000638139</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-offloads-its-rtx-5070-and-5080-now-priced-like-the-old-gen.1331254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Gaming at high frame rates with maxed-out settings doesn’t have to drain your bank account anymore. Asus just dropped a deal on two of its latest powerhouses: the TUF Gaming GeForce <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4923/">RTX 5070 is now down to $584 on Amazon (from $739)</a>, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4922/">the RTX 5080 sits at $1,349 (originally $1,599)</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4922/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See RTX 5080 at Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4923/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See RTX 5070 at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why Should You Pay Attention to These Cards?</h2>
<p>The RTX 5070 comes equipped with 12GB of GDDR7 memory whih is the most recent generation of graphics memory technology. GDDR7 brings much higher data transfer rates than the older cards’ GDDR6, so textures load sooner, stuttering is reduced, and you enjoy smoother action in memory-hungry titles like Cyberpunk 2077 or Microsoft Flight Simulator. 12GB capacity means you’ll have no VRAM bottlenecks at 1440p or even 4K resolutions in most titles, and provides you with headroom through the next couple of years as titles increasingly require increasing amounts of resources.</p>
<p>The RTX 5070 uses a 3.125-slot design which means it’s slightly thicker than traditional two-slot cards but not quite as massive as some three-slot monsters. This extra space allows for a more robust cooling solution without turning your case into an oven. Asus equips it with axial-tech fans that spin in alternating directions to reduce turbulence and increase airflow efficiency.</p>



<p>Upgrading to the RTX 5080, you’ll be getting 16GB of GDDR7 memory and the more substantial 3.6-slot build. This card aims directly at gamers who won’t compromise, running 4K resolution with ray tracing and still demanding triple-digit frame rates. That extra 4GB of VRAM over the 5070 makes all the difference when you’re gaming at higher resolutions and ultra textures or you’re doing content creation like video editing or 3D rendering on the side. Vapor chamber cooling on the RTX 5080 is an evolution of the older heat pipe technology. Instead of using the latter’s hollow tubes to conduct the heat, the vapor chamber distributes the thermal energy on a wider surface area, keeping the hotspot under control and delivering steady results even through long gaming marathons.</p>



<p>Both boards are PCIe 5.0 capable, doubling the bandwidth of PCIe 4.0. Now, you won’t be seeing huge real-world improvements to gaming these days, but future software and applications are going to be increasingly making use of that extra bandwidth. DisplayPort 2.1 and HDMI connectivity adds future-proof readiness of the next generation of monitors, including those scaling well beyond 4K resolution and higher refresh rates. If you have come to consider one of those new 240Hz 4K monitors, these cards actually have the ability to properly feed themIt manufactures these TUF Gaming cards using military-grade components and provides protective PCB coating.</p>
<p>At $584, the RTX 5070 undercuts what many people paid for last generation’s mid-range cards while delivering current-gen performance and features. The RTX 5080 at $1,349 brings flagship-tier gaming within reach of enthusiasts who don’t want to take out a loan for their hobby. Given that both cards have strong review scores on Amazon (4.7 stars for the 5070 across over 2,000 reviews, and 4.6 stars for the 5080), stock my sell out quickly.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4922/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See RTX 5080 at Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4923/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See RTX 5070 at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-offloads-its-rtx-5070-and-5080-now-priced-like-the-old-gen-2000638139]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>