<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:03:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MTV Simulator Features 25,000+ Music Videos And Is Very Cool]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mtv-simulator-features-25000-music-videos-and-is-very-cool-2000657223</link>
            <guid>1398793</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Today, MTV is a zombie network that primarily <a href="https://x.com/MTVSchedule/status/1465685976509030404/photo/1">airs episodes of </a><em><a href="https://x.com/MTVSchedule/status/1465685976509030404/photo/1">Ridiculousness</a>&nbsp;</em>and random Paramount-owned comedy films. It’s depressing. But before all that, before <em>The Real World</em> and <em>Road Rules</em>, MTV was a channel that mostly played music videos, and it was cool. So I was happy to hear that someone has created a free MTV simulator website, complete with retro ads.</p> <p>MTV Rewind is a website that tries to recreate the experience of watching the original music channel back in the day. When you first visit the site, it starts playing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_first_music_videos_aired_on_MTV">original MTV broadcast</a>, complete with VJ introductions and the original music videos that were aired on that faithful day back in August 1981. I wasn’t alive back then, but it’s still fun to relive that launch from the comfort of my PC in 2025.</p>

  <p>Beyond recreating the first day, MTV Rewind features different decades you can swap between, built up of playlists featuring thousands of videos, as well as random, old TV ads from back in the day. And I have to admit, there is something special and comforting about returning to an era in which music was delivered to me without me having to create playlists, seek out artists, or hear the stuff that some algorithm decides I want to listen to next. Just a hose of old music videos streamed directly into my ears. Cool shit.</p>

 <p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OldSchoolCool/comments/1q5e7n1/comment/nxzbdgn/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">The creator of MTV Rewind says</a> they built this project, which uses YouTube for all the videos, over the course of a week as a “passion project.” They shared on Reddit that they have “a deep nostalgia” for MTV and miss the 24/7 music videos. I’m happy they took the time to make this site. Now, if you’ll excuse me, I have a lot of 1990s music to jam out to while I work.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mtv-simulator-features-25000-music-videos-and-is-very-cool-2000657223]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stranger Things’ Big Finale Fight Was Inspired By Baldur’s Gate 3]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-big-finale-fight-vecna-mind-flayer-eleven-baldurs-gate-3-2000657205</link>
            <guid>1398736</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The <a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-season-5-finale-matt-duffer-interview-2000656663"><em>Stranger Things</em> season five finale</a> ends with a big fight involving the major players of the series, and according to the creators behind the hit Netflix show, how this large fight played out was inspired by <em>Baldur’s Gate 3.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>Last week, on New Year’s Eve,<em> Stranger Things</em> wrapped up after nearly a decade with an epic two-hour finale. While some fans weren’t happy with the conclusion and are <a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-secret-finale-conformity-gate-explained-2000656704">even theorizing that a special bonus episode will be released soon,</a> the last episode of<em> Stranger Things</em> did deliver a big battle featuring Vecna, the Mind Flayer, and many of the characters people have grown to love over the last few years.</p> <p><a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/stranger-things-finale-is-eleven-alive-vecna-killed-rock-spinoff-1236621528/">In a new interview with <em>Variety</em></a>, the Duffer brothers, the duo behind the show and its finale, revealed that the big boss fight was inspired by playing<em> Baldur’s Gate 3.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>“We were thinking about <em>D&amp;D,</em> and I was playing <a href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491"><em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em></a> [while creating the finale], and we felt it was very important that the only way for them to defeat it was for the entire party to work together,” said Matt Duffer. “Everyone had fully realized—either through self-acceptance or they’ve resolved all their various issues—moving into that final battle, they’re absolutely primed. They’re the ultimate team, and it’s the party working all together to defeat this thing. And they each have their own individual skills, right? And that’s where I go back to<em> Dungeons &amp; Dragons,</em> and something like <em>Baldur’s Gate</em>. Because that’s how you take down these monsters that seem otherwise unstoppable.”</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/larian-gen-ai-divinity-baldurs-gate-3-rpg-2000653912">Swen Vincke,</a> the head of the studio behind<em> Baldur’s Gate 3,</em> seemed pleased with this information, <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2008573846526529945">resharing it on Twitter</a> and saying, “That’s pretty cool.”</p> <p>While speaking to <em>Variety</em>, Matt Duffer also added that “lots of video game references were applied to that final battle,” but didn’t confirm anything specific. Also, it sounds like the Duffers are aware of your wild theories that the “true” finale is yet to be revealed and simply replied, “Obviously, that’s not a real thing.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-big-finale-fight-vecna-mind-flayer-eleven-baldurs-gate-3-2000657205]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape From Tarkov Dev Trolls Players By Making Its Impossible Ending Even More Brutal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-boat-choice-terminal-2000657207</link>
            <guid>1398700</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app">
      <p><a href="#main">
  Skip to content
</a></p>

<nav>
    
    
        
  </nav>

  


<section>
    
      <main id="main">
              <nav aria-label="Breadcrumb">
    <a href="https://kotaku.com/culture/news">
        <span>News</span>
    </a>
  </nav>
  
  
  <article>
          <header>
    <h2>
        <i>Escape From Tarkov</i> Dev Trolls Players By Making Its Impossible Ending Even More Brutal
    </h2>
          <p>
        After player feedback said that the ending was too ruthless, developer Battlestate Games made it even more so
      </p>
    </header>
    
    <div>
                                    <p>
                <a href="https://kotaku.com/tag/escape-from-tarkov" rel="tag">Escape From Tarkov</a>              </p>
            
            

                          
                      
          <p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Battlestate Games
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p>
          
          
          <div>
            
            <p><span>After a long, eight-year wait, players can finally escape from Tarkov in </span><i><span>Escape from Tarkov</span></i><span>. However, reaching the new end-game location, Terminal, is no easy feat, and neither is battling your way through to its conclusion. And now, following complaints from some in the</span><i><span> Escape from Tarkov</span></i><span> community who found escaping too difficult, developer Battlestate Games has decided to make things even harder.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>As part of the long-awaited 1.0.0.2 update on December 1st of last year, Battlestate Games added four unique endings to </span><i><span>Escape from Tarkov’s</span></i><span> gruelling 200-ish hour-long campaign. </span><span>Battling through the chaotic wave of AI-controlled enemies is no simple task, especially since you’ve just been stripped of all your gear, </span><span>but things become all the more punishing once you reach Terminal’s final hurdle. And according to </span><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/escape-from-tarkov/terminal-ending-change"><i><span>PCGamesN</span></i></a><span>, after some players said they found it too challenging, the devs decided that it actually still sounded a bit too easy.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>If you’ve yet to complete Terminal for yourself, be warned that we’re about to get into heavy spoiler territory here.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>When </span><i><span>Escape from Tarkov’s</span></i><span> full release update dropped, it added a brutal decision that players had to make: a boat had to be taken to reach the titular escape, but it only fit three. The game’s standard player formation is squads of five. Thus, two people had to stay behind, becoming engulfed in a nuclear blast while others sail away to safety (and earning themselves one of </span><i><span>Escape from Tarkov’s</span></i><span> “bad” endings).</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Naturally, considering all the work it takes to get to that point, a sizable chunk of the community complained online. </span><a href="https://x.com/Velion/status/2007488455002206273"><span>This included</span></a> <i><span>Escape from Tarkov</span></i><span> streamer Velion, who wrote, “</span><span>I would really like to see this changed where everyone can escape together. Imagine being able to go into terminal and meeting 2 other players who you work together on a hard map and you survive and make it out.” </span><span>Directing his feedback squarely at Battlestate Games, he tagged studio head Nikita Buyanov in his Twitter post.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Buyanov immediately replied by simply stating “its changed already,” which would reasonably lead you to assume that leaving Tarkov with all your buddies is now an option.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Turns out that Buyanov considers himself a comedian, as he actually meant that things have “changed” for the worse. As </span><a href="https://x.com/Pestily/status/2008264876163228137?s=20"><span>other players</span></a><span> online have already pointed out, the number of players who can now escape at the end of Terminal has been whittled down to one.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Of course, you could just play through Terminal by yourself and not have to bother with the hassle of deciding which of you gets to live once it ends, but that feels like it defeats the point. </span><i><span>Escape from Tarkov</span></i><span> has always been a game about forging bonds and making friends, and watching them all get consumed by a nuclear blast while you sail off into the sunset, </span><i><span>Titanic-</span></i><span>style, just seems fitting.</span></p>

            
          </div>

          <div>
                                          
                          
            
            
  
                          <div>
                <h2>🕹️ Level up your inbox</h2>
<div>
  <p>Don’t miss the latest reviews, news and tips. Sign up for our free newsletter.</p>
  <!-- Mailchimp for WordPress v4.9.13 - https://wordpress.org/plugins/mailchimp-for-wp/ --><!-- / Mailchimp for WordPress Plugin -->
</div>
              </div>
            
            <h2>You May Also Like</h2>
    
    
            
          </div>

          
        </div>
  </article>
      </main>

      
      </section>

      
  





    </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/escape-from-tarkov-ending-boat-choice-terminal-2000657207]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logan Paul’s Pitch For A Pokémon Game Is Nostalgia Brain Poison]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-red-blue-remake-logan-paul-firered-leafgreen-2000657176</link>
            <guid>1398673</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I don’t pay much attention to Logan Paul, the content creator turned wrestler with side hustles that involve turning </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>cards </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/logan-paul-most-valuable-pokemon-card-auction-2000656107"><span>into heartless cash grabs</span></a><span> and a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/youtube-logan-paul-cryptozoo-nft-game-refund-lawsuit-1851143787"><span>failed NFT game</span></a><span>. But the social media persona entered my field of view last night after making </span><a href="https://x.com/LoganPaul/status/2008546103965479046"><span>a now viral post</span></a><span> pitching his idea for a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><span>new </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>game</span></a><span>. Well, “new” is a stretch, considering what he’s asking for is essentially another fucking remake of the original </span><i><span>Pokémon Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span> games. But having been in the series’ vicinity for almost 30 years, I know that this is the type of artless pitch lapsed and casual </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>fans would happily gobble down like Moomoo Milk.</span></p> <p><span>Pushing aside with all our might that this reads like a pitch to Game Freak that was probably written by ChatGPT (“nostalgic equity” is a phrase no human has ever said), let’s look at what Paul is actually asking for.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea for The Pokémon Company:</p> <p>I think there is a MASSIVE opportunity to capitalize on the decades of nostalgic equity that fans have with the franchise</p> <p>The same frenzy that originally propelled Pokémon into mainstream culture lives within millions of adults that yearn for the…</p> <p>— Logan Paul (@LoganPaul) <a href="https://twitter.com/LoganPaul/status/2008279181080109173?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>He says that The Pokémon Company has a “massive opportunity” to bank on nostalgia, as if Pikachu and friends have ever not taken the opportunity to shove the original Kanto starters into something over the past 30 years. He also mentions how, every few years, he’ll boot up the original games on a Game Boy to find “just as much joy” playing back through them as he had as a child.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>He then admits he doesn’t have “much of a connection” to newer Pokémon, which is where he begins to give the game away. He does like Annihilape and Baxcalibur, suggesting he’s not completely out of the loop. But since he doesn’t really seem to care about anything Pokémon has done in the last 27 years, he argues it would be cool for Game Freak to create “remastered” versions of the Generation I Game Boy games, with “adaptive NPCs that evolve alongside the player.”</span></p>

 <p><span>He says they could even use modern technology to let players connect to the internet for trading and battling, something Pokémon has literally been doing for 20 years, ever since </span><i><span>Diamond</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Pearl </span></i><span>on the DS. He goes on:</span></p> <blockquote><p><span>This will do three things</span></p> <p><span>1.) Give older fans a chance to relive their childhood thus awakening a massive, dormant demographic&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>2.) Give newer, younger fans a taste of what originally made the franchise so special</span></p> <p><span>3.) Bridge the gap for older fans who don’t connect with newer Pokémon in a way that’s familiar to them</span></p> <p><span>If we believe that video game cycles are like a pendulum, the near-future of gaming may birth a desire for more simplified, block-based aesthetics. We already see it happening with games like Minecraft &amp; Roblox. As technology continues to advance at an alarmingly rapid pace, I personally believe the future will lean towards “retro”</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>This LinkedIn-ass post tries to intellectualize what is obvious nostalgia-pining as some kind of market inevitability; that it would just be good business sense for </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>to go back to Kanto for the people who only played those original games decades ago, outgrew them, and now think the problem is that the all-ages franchise has fallen “behind the times.” Also, crucially, Game Freak already remade those original games twice with </span><i><span>FireRed</span></i><span>/</span><i><span>LeafGreen </span></i><span>and the </span><i><span>Let’s Go </span></i><span>games on Switch, the latter of which are only seven years old.</span></p>

 <p><span>Yes, the original </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>are still the best-selling games in the franchise, and maybe some people are too young to realize that the level of Pokémania back then was far beyond the still massive success </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>enjoys right now. To insinuate that </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>is in danger of getting away from its base of ‘90s kids, though, is like saying the sun isn’t shining because you’re inside and can’t feel its warmth. But this is the sentiment of a lot of retired Pokémon trainers who stopped playing in elementary school and mistake their own lack of interest for the series no longer having the sauce.</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s the same mentality that makes people mad that </span><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet </span></i><span>have “regular animals” in them like Flamigo when </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>had Seel, or who didn’t like that Gen V and VI had Pokémon made of “objects” when Grimer and Voltorb were literal sludge and a living Poké Ball. </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>made me feel something specific as a child, and now that I’m an adult and my brain has developed differently, I don’t feel that way anymore. Instead of the realities of adulthood crushing my spirit, it must be because the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games don’t have Professor Oak and Misty in them all the time.</span></p>

 <p><span>If all you’re looking at is video game sales numbers, you probably could foolishly think </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>is “struggling” in the market compared to what it hit in the ‘90s, despite the absolute trashfire that was </span><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i><span> still readily selling around 27 million copies, a number any other company would kill to hit. But </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>is a lifestyle brand that makes most of its money from </span><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pokemon-has-become-the-highest-grossing-media-franchise-of-all-time/"><span>merchandise sales</span></a><span>, and you would think someone who played a major role in inflating the value of the trading cards would know that.</span></p>

 <p><span>Honestly, if people like Paul want something that feels just like the old games did when they were five, try a ROM hack. Fans have been making retro-style </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games for decades. They’re not only great, they’ll probably also make you feel cozy-wozy with their pixelated graphics that look like what you played on your Game Boy. And hey, you can probably find plenty that don’t include all the hundreds of new Pokémon you don’t like, but which millions of younger players grew up on and hold as dear as old-timers do Pikachu or Charmander.</span></p> <p><span>This yearning for the mines of Kanto exists around the periphery of </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>every day, and it’s only going to ratchet up more this year with the series’ 30th anniversary celebrations <a href="https://x.com/pokemon_cojp/status/2006379822012911872?s=46&amp;t=ELmQU9gVKk7kgACkfTFs1Q">already paying tribute to those old games</a>. ROM hacks, mock-ups from people who don’t even like the games anymore, and even fan art are constantly gesturing at the series’ old aesthetics. I still have my original copy of </span><i><span>Pokémon Yellow </span></i><span>sitting on my shelf to this day, and maybe if Game Freak releases those old games on Switch this year, I’ll play it again.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>But I don’t need The Pokémon Company to keep looking back. And the company certainly doesn’t need to tap into a “massive,” untapped well of fair-weather fans who will come back to the franchise for good if they remake </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>again. I think it’ll live.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-red-blue-remake-logan-paul-firered-leafgreen-2000657176]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>