<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:19:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Wario Going To Be In The Super Mario Galaxy Movie?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/is-wario-going-to-be-in-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-sequel-leak-trailer-2000672772</link>
            <guid>1443760</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-rob-robot-trailer-2000669425"><em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie </em></a>arrives in theaters in April. We know <a href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-galaxy-movie-direct-yoshi-birdo-baby-2000662854">Yoshi, Bowser Jr., and Rosalina</a> will be joining the sequel alongside the main returning characters, Mario, Luigi, Bowser, and Peach. But according to a new leak courtesy of a theater chain’s website, another new face is set to show up in the animated sequel.</p> <p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-description-appears-to-spoil-a-major-unannounced-character">As spotted by <em>IGN</em></a>, United Kingdom-based fancy movie theater chain Everyman recently posted a new text description for the upcoming blockbuster that just straight up lists Wario. The totally new, not-yet-announced-to-be-in-this-movie villain who is seemingly going to be a part of <em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em> hasn’t shown up in any of Nintendo’s past marketing beats or trailers. <a href="https://www.everymancinema.com/film-listing/327878-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie/#coming-soon:~:text=After%20defeating%20Bowser%20and%20saving%20Brooklyn%2C%20Mario%20faces%20Wario%20and%20Bowser%20Jr.%27s%20evil%20alliance.%20Now%2C%20alongside%20his%20friends%20and%20Yoshi%2C%20he%20must%20stop%20their%20plans%20for%20world%20domination.">Here’s the description</a>:</p>

 <blockquote><p>“After defeating Bowser and saving Brooklyn, Mario faces <strong>Wario</strong> and Bowser Jr.’s evil alliance. Now, alongside his friends and Yoshi, he must stop their plans for world domination.”</p></blockquote> <p>Well, that sure sounds like Wario is going to be in this movie! Of course, calling this a spoiler is probably inaccurate as it’s likely to be revealed in Nintendo and Universal’s own pre-release marketing rollout via a new teaser or something before the movie’s April 1 debut. But at least for now, Wario’s inclusion in the <em>Mario</em> movie sequel has yet to be announced. We do know that Chris Pratt, who voices Mario, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/chris-pratt-supposedly-hints-at-a-couple-more-character-surprises-in-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie">has hinted that there are more unannounced characters left to be revealed</a>. So he’s likely referencing Wario, assuming this leaked description is accurate. And if it is, it sounds like Wario will play a big role in the film alongside Bowser Jr.</p> <p>Now, what I’m really excited about is that if Wario is in this movie, that means I can raise the chance of <a href="https://kotaku.com/waluigi-debuted-20-years-ago-today-and-i-respect-him-a-1844460557">Nintendo’s horrible affront to nature, Waluigi,</a> showing up in this flick from 1 percent to a solid 10 percent. Maybe more! How exciting.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/is-wario-going-to-be-in-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-sequel-leak-trailer-2000672772]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The New Head Of Xbox Is Worried About Birthrates, But Says AI Will Save Us]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-asha-sharma-birthrates-ai-fertility-2000672756</link>
            <guid>1443757</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Asha Sharma.</span> © Lenny's Podcast / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>After <a href="https://kotaku.com/phil-spencer-goodbye-email-memo-xbox-microsoft-2000672084">the shock resignation of Phil Spencer and Sarah Bond from Xbox last week</a>, the gaming world is attempting to piece together exactly <a href="https://kotaku.com/thats-it-im-calling-it-xbox-is-dead-time-of-death-february-20-2000672114">what will happen next to Microsoft’s gaming brand</a>, especially under the auspices of new leader Asha Sharma. Why has someone with a background in AI and not gaming been put at the helm? And wait, she said <em>what</em> about birthrates and AI?</p> <p>Big tech’s obsession with birthrate figures is something that should certainly make you feel uncomfortable, given it’s usually about half a step removed from <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/why-are-elon-musk-and-marc-andreesen-obsessed-with-birth-rates/">matters far more sinister</a>. Which is why it’s so disappointing to hear Asha Sharma, in an interview on a podcast from five months ago, saying that the thing she thinks about the most—other than GPUs—is whether her son “will have classmates in the future.” (Thanks <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/samred.com/post/3mfdstcvges2c">Sam Machkovech</a>.) This is because, she says, “fertility rates are declining, the average birthrate in the ’90s when we were growing up was, like, 3, and now it’s 2.3, and in 2050 it’s estimated to be below replacement.” This is strange on its own, and also completely wrong, but her next words make it far weirder. “I think that AI can have such a big effect on it, and already is.”</p>

 <p>Sharma goes on to give examples of this, like how she’s heard about a hospital in London that’s using AI to improve the fertility success rate of IVF, the “amazing story” of how ChatGPT 5 is “helping in healthcare,” and how Stanford was a big customer of hers, using AI for “tumor reviews.”</p>  <p>Of course, the reason for the declining birthrate in the U.S. is multifactorial, but almost certainly primarily about income. In the affluent ’90s, people felt confident about being able to afford two or three children, but in the 2020s that’s a far more costly prospect. If people in big tech were genuinely concerned about the number of children being born, their attention would be wholly focused on <a href="https://publichealth.jhu.edu/2026/is-the-us-birth-rate-declining">making American lives more affordable, providing better benefits and support, and increasing wages</a>. And not, say, on replacing workers with ineffectual AI while driving industries that rely on paying low incomes.</p>

 <p>Sharma’s numbers are <em>way</em> off, as it happens. The fertility rate wavered between 1.9 and 2.0 in the 1990s, and hasn’t been close to her claimed 3 since the mid-60s. It dipped as low as 1.6 after steady decline following the financial crash of 2008, but in recent years has begun to recover: it was back up to 1.8 in 2025. So in fact a difference of 0.1 since Sharma’s heyday of baby births.</p>

 <p>But to put everyone’s minds at rest regarding those empty classrooms: As it turns out, we don’t just distribute however many children are around into the current number of classrooms. That would be a weird system. So even if birthrates were to suddenly halve, we’d just have…fewer schools. Am I really explaining this to the head of Xbox?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-asha-sharma-birthrates-ai-fertility-2000672756]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Releases New Art Of All 1000+ Monsters For Its 30th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-30-anniversary-art-logos-every-pokedex-serebii-2000672767</link>
            <guid>1443664</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>It’s officially Pokémon week. On Friday, the monster-taming series will celebrate its 30th anniversary </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-where-when-to-watch-generation-10-switch-2000671968"><span>with a livestream discussing new projects</span></a><span> and likely revealing the next games. As part of the marketing campaign, The Pokémon Company has been leaning into the idea that every Pokémon is someone’s favorite, and as such, it’s releasing commemorative 30th anniversary logos for every single one of these little guys.</span></p> <p><span>Fan site and database </span><a href="https://serebii.net/pokemon30/#artwork"><i><span>Serebii</span></i></a> <span>has archived every piece, which includes at least one for every Pokémon, though several have multiple depicting things like alternate forms and regional variants. I’m a little bummed they didn’t do any for Mega Evolutions, but I can’t complain too much when every monster is represented here. There’s over 1000 images here, so if you want to find your favorites, it’s probably easiest to do a ctrl+f or command+f and search their names. I found my team on my phone this morning and that was a pain in the ass. But look at my boy:</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000672770" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000672770"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000672770">© The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I always appreciate when The Pokémon Company does stuff like this and the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-sitting-cuties-alola-generation-7-center-order-2000624487"><span>Sitting Cuties plush line</span></a><span> that give every critter some love, as it means everyone, no matter how obscure your favorite Pokémon is, will feel included. It’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-original-stitch-sitting-cuties-merch-center-1850507835"><span>tough out there if your favorite isn’t one of the pseudo mascots</span></a><span>, and some of these initiatives, like the Original Stitch shirts, haven’t lasted long enough for everyone to get something representing their favorite. But now, everyone got commemorative art on the same day so nobody’s missing out.</span></p> <p><span>Friday, February 27, will mark 30 years since the original </span><i><span>Pokémon Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Green </span></i><span>launched in Japan, and will also be the beginning of several events both online and off celebrating the anniversary. It’s also highly likely that come Friday we’ll see the next mainline RPGs, which have been </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-gen-10-wind-wave-map-leak-pikachu-professor-2000655613"><span>leaking over the past year and a half</span></a><span> following the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-leak-generation-10-wind-wave-galar-legends-mmo-2000635337"><span>Game Freak teraleak</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-30-anniversary-art-logos-every-pokedex-serebii-2000672767]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The PS5 Is Still Outselling The Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps5-switch-2-sales-price-jan-2026-2000672749</link>
            <guid>1443628</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Let’s get this out of the way up front: the PlayStation 5 and Switch 2 are both selling really well right now. But one of those consoles is five years old and the other has only been out for nine months after years of waiting. So why is <a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-sales-switch-2-earnings-ghost-yotei-memory-shortage-2000665998">Sony’s machine continuing</a> to outsell Nintendo’s latest portable device in the U.S.?</p> <p>Circana Senior Director <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3mfcbfovqnc2r">Mat Piscatella reports</a> that PS5 still led January 2026 in hardware sales in the U.S. despite people buying fewer PS5s than they did a year ago. Switch 2 was in second place, followed by Xbox Series X/S and PC gaming handhelds. Overall, hardware spending jumped 16 percent compared to January 2025, even as last-gen hardware declined. PS5 was down 17 percent year-over-year and Xbox Series X/S was down 27 percent. Unsurprisingly, the original Switch fell off a cliff with a 79 percent drop.</p>

 <p>Is this indicative of the ongoing strength of the PS5 platform, or does it mean unusual softness in Switch 2 launch year sales? Recent earnings reports showed that Nintendo lost the holiday period worldwide to Sony as well. Despite Switch 2 surpassing Switch 1 sales on a time-aligned basis, it was beaten by five-year-old hardware. Maybe some of that was the big Black Friday price cuts that made a PS5 cheaper than a Switch 2. Maybe it was people gearing up for the launch of <em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em> this year.</p> <p>And maybe part of it had to do with the Switch 2 missing a big exclusive to get people off the fence. Neither a 3D <em>Mario</em> nor a new<em> Zelda</em> have been announced yet and 2025’s big seller, Pokémon<em> Legends: Z-A</em>, was available on the existing Switch. Things might only get tougher if and when Nintendo is <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-tariff-ai-ram-stock-price-2000661382">forced to increase the price</a> of the Switch 2 due to the ongoing RAM shortage, something new reporting and many analysts suggest is a forgone conclusion for 2026.</p>

 <p>Then again, President Trump’s tariffs <a href="https://kotaku.com/supreme-court-strikes-down-trump-tariffs-that-hiked-prices-on-switch-xbox-and-ps5-2000671987">were just struck down as unconstitutional</a>. I’m not sure how the government is planning on refunding consumers or companies for those import taxes, but maybe it will give Nintendo the wiggle room it needs to hold the Switch 2’s current $450 price for a bit longer.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps5-switch-2-sales-price-jan-2026-2000672749]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Evangelion Series Is Coming, And It’s Written By Nier’s Director]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/evangelion-new-series-yoko-taro-nier-neon-genesis-anime-2000672745</link>
            <guid>1443625</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>We probably don’t need any more </span><i><span>Neon Genesis Evangelion</span></i><span>, but </span><a href="https://www.evangelion.jp/news/260223-1/"><span>a new series was announced</span></a><span> during the legendary anime’s 30th anniversary celebration, and it will have Yoko Taro, the director of the </span><i><span>Nier </span></i><span>series, on board as a writer.</span></p> <p><span>We know nothing about the series at the moment, including whether it takes place before, after, or during the original series. The </span><i><span>Rebuild</span></i><span> films confirm the existence of multiple timelines, so this could be a retelling of the original </span><i><span>Evangelion</span></i><span> story but in one of these alternate universes. It may also take place after one of the series’ multiple endings across the original show, the </span><i><span>End of Evangelion</span></i><span> film, and the </span><i><span>Rebuilds</span></i><span>. I’m skeptical, but Taro’s involvement is enough to at least make me curious.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="ja" dir="ltr">発表されました。がんばります……！ <a href="https://t.co/exqNLJV9Pt">https://t.co/exqNLJV9Pt</a></p> <p>— yokotaro (@yokotaro) <a href="https://twitter.com/yokotaro/status/2025882968355651791?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 23, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Taro will be writing the script, but the new series will be directed by Kazuya Tsurumaki and Toru Yatabe, who have both worked on the series before. Tsurumaki is also known for series like </span><i><span>FLCL</span></i><span> and the current </span><i><span>Gundam </span></i><span>series </span><i><span>Mobile Suit Gundam GQuuuuuuX</span></i><span>, while Yatabe has done work on </span><i><span>Chainsaw Man</span></i><span> and also collaborated with Tsurumaki on </span><i><span>GQuuuuuuX</span></i><span>. It sounds like original </span><i><span>Evangelion </span></i><span>creator Hideaki Anno isn’t involved at a top level beyond his studio Khara producing the show, which, given the way </span><i><span>Thrice Upon a Time </span></i><span>ended, that’s probably a good thing. It seems like he’s said what he wanted to with this series and if it has to come back, maybe handing the keys to someone else is for the best.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The announcement was the culmination of the Evangelion:30+; 30th Anniversary of </span><i><span>Evangelion </span></i><span>festival in Japan, which also included a 13-minute short starring Asuka, which has reignited the spark of a decades-long shipping war by showing a vision of her married to main character Shinji and having a kid. Which is loaded considering </span><a href="https://x.com/GayBamboozler/status/2025294426944520519?s=20"><span>the way the series typically frames their relationship</span></a>, but she does end up <a href="https://x.com/MrJalenSan/status/2025478953079586946?s=20">rejecting him in the end</a>.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="es" dir="ltr">En el corto de Asuka que se está proyectando en el Eva Fest ella tiene una visión de un universo alterno donde se casa con Shinji y hasta tienen una hija.</p> <p>Anno me arruinó la vida por enésima vez. <a href="https://t.co/vrQWOceqEj">pic.twitter.com/vrQWOceqEj</a></p> <p>— DasTier (@DasTier92) <a href="https://twitter.com/DasTier92/status/2025250796313391485?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 21, 2026</a></p></blockquote> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/evangelion-new-series-yoko-taro-nier-neon-genesis-anime-2000672745]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>