<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:03:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An AI ‘Ghost’ That Plays Games For You Is The Inevitable Endpoint Of Where This Is All Headed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-patent-ai-ghost-ps5-megabonk-2000657230</link>
            <guid>1398931</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Whenever my kids get stuck playing a game, they run around the house yelling for me to help them. Doesn’t matter where I am or what I’m doing. Making dinner, taking out the trash, going to the bathroom, nowhere is safe. I patiently try to explain to them that back in my day, there was no grownup to help me beat Snake Man in <em>Mega Man 3</em> or find Excalibur in <em>Final Fantasy IV</em>. I just had to bash my head against the wall until I figured it out or give up until I got older.</p> <p>They never find this paternal wisdom satisfactory, so there I am finding them Zonai devices in <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> or turning off damage in the <em>Minecraft</em> settings menu like a personal accessibility assistant. Will they do the same for their children? They might not have to. New AI “ghosts” might be able to do everything in the game for them. The games will, on command, be able to play themselves. Perfect for grinding crypto-currency in the Roblox mines while the oceans rise. RIP my future grandchildren.</p>

 <p>A Sony patent for these AI ghosts has been making the rounds online today. As <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sony-ai-patent-will-see-playstation-games-play-themselves-when-players-are-stuck/">reported by <em>VG</em>C</a>, the September 2024 registration documents which were publicized earlier this week reveal a technology that would allow people to get AI to help them beat games. These AI “ghost players” would be trained on existing game footage and either demonstrate the solution to an obstacle (“Guide Mode”) or beat it entirely (“Complete Mode”).</p>

 <p>It’s not clear from the patent whether Sony actually plans to move forward with this new AI help tool now or in the future. People have <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ramiismail.com/post/3mbr3vakjwk2p">made jokes online</a> about how bad current AI is at hallucinating gameplay, showing you something that looks normal enough before shifting into surreal nightmare fuel just moments later. There are also concerns about how the AI “helper” would be trained, which would <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/moomanibe.bsky.social/post/3mbrpdt63tk2f">seemingly include</a> footage shared on social media and YouTube.</p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:7zpntsbraj7cbishj4haru2v/app.bsky.feed.post/3mbr7p6eg3c2k" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreigfbv6ihj3s732hiqdpwh2lfogthvvzvuz7ldy26pot2thmypli3a"> <p lang="en">the point of a movie is not to be done watching it. the point of a song is not to be done listening to it. the gamers' obsession with completion as the only motivator to play a game has directly led to the medium's worst traits. "AI gaming ghost" is a reflection of the lack of willingness to engage</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:7zpntsbraj7cbishj4haru2v?ref_src=embed">funbil (@funbil.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:7zpntsbraj7cbishj4haru2v/post/3mbr7p6eg3c2k?ref_src=embed">2026-01-06T14:58:57.706Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p>Gaming has a long history of companies trying to help players overcome the difficulty that they themselves designed into their games. In the past there were hotlines and strategy manuals. More recently, companies have tried to embed guides directly into the games. <a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-ps5-community-game-help-1851366566">Game Help on PlayStation 5</a> shows you videos of how other players have completed a particular section of a game. It’s a neat idea whose implementation is messy and incomplete. Microsoft is trying to go a step further and embed <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-ai-copilot-minecraft-overwatch-insider-microsoft-1851769746">its Copilot AI</a> into games to offer chatbot-style assistance as an overlay like a new version of <a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-life-death-microsoft-clippy-paper-clip-loved-hate">Clippy</a>.</p>

 <p>Tools like this could be a boon for helping more people enjoy games or at least “unstuck” themselves before bouncing off in a fit of boredom or frustration. But there’s also a <em>Black Mirror</em> version where all of the friction of actually playing a game is offloaded to AI agents entirely. How many games would be improved by adding a skip button that lets you fast-forward your progression by 20 seconds or 20 minutes? How many games would you stop playing entirely if you could offload the drudgery entirely?</p>

 <h2>AI ghosts grinding AI optimized battle passes</h2> <p>Players love to optimize strategies and get one over on the games they’re playing. Sometimes that means doing a lot of work to grind as effectively as possible or craft the most broken build. Other times it means wrapping a rubber-band around an analog stick and going to sleep while the game does all the work for you. What would it be like to play <em>Diablo 4</em> if those builds you had to look up online were automatically recommended inside the skill tree menu?</p>

 <p>What would be the point if at any time you could put the mouse and keyboard down and let an AI agent, trained on YouTube or even your own play history, take the wheel and grind until all of that hyper-rare loot finally drops? Not everyone would go for it. Maybe some would. We already know <a href="https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-poe2-diablo-4-paid-boosting-fake-controversy-1851743670">what choice Elon Musk would make</a>.</p>

 <p>Experience-based games would probably be safe. The ones where you’re there for player choice or the story, though even fans of things like <em>Dispatch</em> might be tempted to have someone else handle all of the less engaging mini-games. Multiplayer games have faced an ongoing arms race with cheaters for years. Who wouldn’t be tempted to take credit for a duos Battle Royale win pulled off by their AI counterpart? None of this is in the Sony patent for AI help, but it’s all in the same Pandora’s box.</p> <p>In fact, some of the most popular games of the past few years play with automating the player’s role to some degree until they are irrelevant to the outcome. That’s what made people obsessed with <em>Vampire Survivors</em>. It’s what helped <em>Ball X Pit</em> sell over a million copies. It’s what made <em>Megabonk</em> so popular, it ended up being nominated for an award at the Game Awards that the developer had to recuse himself from. Some games call upon us to embrace the moment-to-moment drudgery of simulated work. Others lure us with the siren’s call of participating in a high-score chase where the big reward <a href="https://kotaku.com/ball-x-pit-vampire-survivors-balatro-roguelike-2000642155">is seeing our own participation incrementally diminished</a>.</p> <p>In 20 years, even that concept might sound as alien to my grandkids as calling something a “button masher.” By then, the computers will no doubt be able to read the inputs directly from their minds. What the AI chooses to do with those, well, that’s anybody’s guess.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-patent-ai-ghost-ps5-megabonk-2000657230]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s Very Good 4K UHD Blu-Ray Deal Is Back And Better]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazons-4k-uhd-blu-ray-deal-33-3-movies-sale-best-movies-list-2000657244</link>
            <guid>1398928</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good news! Amazon is doing its 3 for $33 4K UHD Blu-Ray sale <a href="https://kotaku.com/amazon-4k-uhd-bluray-sale-godzilla-joker-3-for-33-deal-1851777167">again</a>. If you’ve been wanting to build up a physical collection of your favorite movies (or grow your current collection), you should take advantage of this deal before stuff starts selling out.</p> <p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wario64.bsky.social/post/3mbr2skj6dk2h">As spotted by deals guru Wario64,</a> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/promotion/psp/A118PVMFHMZXZ1?tag=kotaku01-20">Amazon is once again offering up 4K UHD movies for just $11 each</a>. The catch? You have to buy at least three for the deal to kick in. But, once you have three in your cart, you can just keep adding movies, and they each only cost $11. Want 7 4K UHD movies? That will be $77. That’s a heck of a deal considering a new 4K UHD movie can cost upwards of $20 or $30 normally.</p>

 <p>Before you start buying these movies, remember you’ll need a UHD player to watch any of these 4K UHD films. Your PS5 and Xbox Series X are solid UHD players, assuming they have disc slots and you are using the correct HDMI cable. You’ll also want a 4K TV, too. With that all out of the way, here are some of the newer UHD movies currently on sale on Amazon, as well as some classics.</p>

 <h2>New Movies On Sale</h2> <ul> <li><em>F1 The Movie</em></li> <li><em>Jurassic World Rebirth</em></li> <li><em>Superman</em></li> <li><em>Wicked</em></li> <li><em>1917</em></li> <li><em>Megan 2.0</em></li> <li><em>Nobody 2</em></li> <li><em>Fall Guy</em></li> <li><em>How To Train Your Dragon (2025)</em></li> <li><em>Godzilla x Kong: The New Empire</em></li> <li><em>A Minecraft Movie</em></li> <li><em>Nope</em></li> </ul> <h2>Older Movies</h2> <ul> <li><em>The Maltese Falcon</em></li> <li><em>American Pie</em></li> <li><em>Twister</em></li> <li><em>The Lost Boys</em></li> <li><em>Purple Rain</em></li> <li><em>The Blues Brothers</em></li> <li><em>Van Helsing</em></li> <li><em>Schindler’s List</em></li> <li><em>Vertigo</em></li> <li><em>Scarface</em></li> <li><em>Harvey</em></li> <li><em>The Matrix</em></li> <li><em>The Shining</em></li> <li><em>Animal House</em></li> </ul> <p>Who’s bothering with movie discs in 2026? Well, for starters, anyone who wants to actually have control over their media library and not be subject to the curatorial whims and constant price increases of streaming platforms. Also, solving the question of what to watch by walking over and staring at a shelf is so much more satisfying than scrolling an endless list of bad algorithmic recommendations.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazons-4k-uhd-blu-ray-deal-33-3-movies-sale-best-movies-list-2000657244]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cut Fallout: New Vegas Ending Shows Yes Man Was Even More Sinister Than He Appeared]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-ending-cut-content-yes-man-2000657243</link>
            <guid>1398913</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>We’ve known for </span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/chris-avellone-explains-what-happened-to-fallout-new-vegass-post-game"><span>some time now</span></a><span> that developer Obsidian Entertainment was forced to cut </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas’</span></i><span> post-game content during its development. But now, thanks to the data found on a recently unearthed Xbox 360 dev kit, we can finally take a look at what some of that scrapped content would have entailed. It turns out that a more sinister conclusion to Yes Man’s story once existed after the credits rolled.</span></p> <p><span>Regardless of who you side with during the Second Battle of Hoover Dam, there’s no squeaky-clean, morally sound conclusion to </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas</span></i><span>. Going with Caesar’s Legion is the objectively cruel choice, yes, but the NCR aren’t exactly saints either. Another option is siding with Yes Man. It’s the closest thing </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas</span></i><span> has to a good ending. Choosing Yes Man, the overtly amenable Securitron that has been forcibly modified by antagonist Benny, is akin to siding with no one, as the peppy robot will gladly carry out whatever orders you give it.</span></p>

 <p><span>Exactly whose side Yes Man is ultimately on has been a topic of debate for </span><i><span>New Vegas</span></i><span> fans since the game was released, and discussion surrounding his allegiances (or lack thereof) has </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fallout/comments/1q0vcia/new_vegas_canon_ending_theory_yes_mans/"><span>once again intensified</span></a><span> following the reappearance of Mr House’s Securitron, Victor, in the second season of the </span><i><span>Fallout </span></i><span>TV series.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Following the New Vegas tease at the end of the first season, fans have been theorizing about which of the game’s endings is now the “canon” ending. Comments made by project director Josh Sawyer and the aforementioned cut content have led some to believe that siding with Yes Man may indeed be </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas’</span></i><span> true ending.</span></p>

 <p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fallout/fallout-new-vegas-lead-writer-loved-writing-yes-man-but-thinks-his-questline-may-have-been-a-mistake-it-lets-you-get-through-the-game-without-getting-your-hands-dirty/"><i><span>PC Gamer</span></i></a><span> recently interviewed </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas’</span></i><span> lead writer John Gonzalez, who stated that he believes offering players a “rebellious, individualistic” path with Yes Man, </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fotv/comments/1munso2/reminder_the_yes_man_ending_to_fnv_only_exists_so/"><span>one in which they don’t have to pick a faction to ally with</span></a><span>, might have actually been a misstep on Obsidian’s part. “I think that questline may have been a mistake, because it lets you get through the game without getting your hands dirty,” Gonzalez said.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Despite Gonzalez’s comments, however, the ending to Yes Man’s path does imply that you may have still gotten your hands at least a little dirty. After you dispatch Legate Lanius, who serves as the second-in-command of Caesar’s Legion and is one of two potential boss fights during your fight to retake Hoover Dam, there are implications that the robot takes quite a heel turn. Yes Man informs the player that they’ll be “going off-line” to “reprogram” their personality, and their comment about becoming more “assertive” in the process may imply that Yes Man no longer wishes to take commands from the player; a scary thought, considering they now control an army of machine gun-wielding robots. Still, considering how jovial the exchange is, you’re left with enough wiggle room in your interpretation to read the choice as fairly neutral from a moral standpoint, and there’s ultimately no way to know the true outcome, considering the end credits roll immediately after this conversation ends.</span></p>

 <p><span>But based on recently discovered cut dialogue ripped from a Beta build of </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas</span></i><span>, it seems that Yes Man may have played a much darker role in the originally planned post-game.</span></p> <p><span>On November 26th of last year, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yfp9pfxnqz4"><span>Games’ Past</span></a><span> uploaded a video detailing the discovery of two prototype builds of </span><i><span>Fallout: New Vegas</span></i><span>, found on an Xbox 360 dev kit in a store in Utah. Games’ Past also uploaded the contents of the dev kits online, and modders managed to uncover and restore a wealth of previously unseen cut content from the builds.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>As detailed in a separate video by </span><a href="https://discord.com/channels/@me/1458090158170570805/1458139450071847004"><span>Alternative Gaming Channel</span></a><span>, dozens of post-game lines of dialogue were hidden in these prototype builds. The cut Yes Man dialogue is particularly interesting, with him outright telling the player character to “fuck off” if you choose to respond negatively to an announcement he makes about his new “assertive” personality.</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>Another cut Yes Man line is even more chilling, with the generally chipper robot talking about slaughtering </span><i><span>New Vegas</span></i><span>’ civilians and “using their blood and their skins” to “decorate the Securitrons.”. He does shout “Exterminate!” afterwards, though, so hopefully it was just a goofy little </span><i><span>Doctor Who</span></i><span> reference that could only be triggered with the Wild Wasteland perk. In any case, it seems that helping Yes Man might be just as morally damning as the rest of New Vegas’ endings, which may explain why the Mojave’s future isn’t looking too bright in the TV series.&nbsp;</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-ending-cut-content-yes-man-2000657243]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fantasy FPS Where You Shoot Skeletons To Stop The Game From Crashing Looks Incredible]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fantasy-fps-where-you-shoot-skeletons-to-stop-the-game-from-crashing-looks-incredible-2000657233</link>
            <guid>1398895</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For many people, <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-metroid-prime-4-mario-120fps-perfomance-mode-2000650994">a steady level of performance</a>–no framerate dips or slowdown–is an important part of any video game. But what if it was <em>the most</em> important part of a game, such that if your performance tanked, you’d die? That’s the elevator pitch for <em>FPS Quest</em>, an upcoming first-person shooter that looks wild.</p> <p><a href="https://youtu.be/yxewel3xAOQ"><em>FPS Quest</em></a> starts off as a fantasy RPG with skeletons and knights in armor. But after getting their ass kicked one too many times, the game’s protagonist installs some mods that them decidedly non-fantasy weapons like a pistol, an assault rifle, and a shotgun. The game within the game wasn’t built to handle these mods, however, so from there, things start to break, and<em> FPS Quest</em> becomes all about playing through a game that is falling apart while also trying to avoid a crash, which will kill you.</p>

  <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3989240/FPS_Quest/">The game’s Steam store page</a> describes what sounds like a roguelike shooter in which you go on different runs through “prebuilt but recombined levels” that get more corrupted and glitchy as you progress. To keep the game from crashing, you can do things like lower the in-game graphics, use in-game mods to remove geometry, and escape out of bounds into unfinished or leftover bits of the game world. It’s a trippy but cool idea for a game that has me very intrigued.</p> <p>One thing the game’s developers make clear on Steam is that <em>FPS Quest</em> doesn’t actually run at a lower framerate, which can cause problems and make people feel sick. Instead, it simulates playing a game at a low FPS. That’s good to know. <em>FPS Quest</em> doesn’t have a release date yet, but I’ve already added it to my wishlist and can’t wait to play.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fantasy-fps-where-you-shoot-skeletons-to-stop-the-game-from-crashing-looks-incredible-2000657233]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>