<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:45:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything We Saw At The 2025 Game Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/everything-we-saw-at-the-2025-game-awards-2000652719</link>
            <guid>1381297</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Warner Bros.
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Tonight the 2025 Game Awards took place, and like every year, millions of people tuned in for a glimpse into the next few years of games. The Los Angeles event may have “Awards” in the name, but for most people, it’s an extended E3-style press conference hosted by Geoff Keighley. If you weren’t able to catch the live show and want to know all the World Premieres you missed, we’ve got you covered. Here’s everything we saw at the 2025 ceremony.</p> <h2><em>Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic</em></h2>  <p>After some awards and a&nbsp;<em>Clair Obscur</em> musical performance, we got the first trailer for <em>Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic </em>by Arcanaut Studios. The game is a single-player action RPG, and ex-BioWare director Casey Hudson, who is known for his work on the original&nbsp;<em>KOTOR&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;the&nbsp;<em>Mass Effect&nbsp;</em>trilogy, is returning to&nbsp;<em>Star&nbsp;</em><em>Wars</em> for the project.</p>

 <h2><em>Divinity</em></h2>  <p>After lifting a bunch of people off the ground,&nbsp;<em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> developer Larian revealed what the mysterious statue Keighley had been teasing all week was for: a new entry in the <em>Divinity </em>series. All we saw was a pretty brutal cinematic trailer of a man being burned alive in front of a crowd of cheering cultists, but that didn’t go very well for them. See for yourself by watching the full trailer. Damn. Pretty gnarly for this early in the show, huh? The game will apparently be even bigger than&nbsp;<em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, and that’s pretty daunting.</p>

 <h2><em>4:LOOP</em></h2>  <p>After a lovely speech from Best Performance winner Jennifer English, we saw a new shooter/roguelike from Sony and Bad Robot called <em>4:LOOP</em>.</p> <h2><em>Coven of the Chicken Foot</em></h2>  <p>Next up is the debut game from Wildflower Interactive, led by ex-Naughty Dog director Bruce Straley. The narrative adventure game stars an older woman and a strange plant monster as they work together to survive. However, it looks like their relationship might not be entirely smooth sailing, as the monster appears to turn on the woman at the end of the trailer.</p>

 <h2><em>Ontos</em></h2>  <p>Fractional Games and Kepler Interactive were up next with a new look at <em>ONTOS</em>, a new first-person horror game that’s got some fucked up body horror shit happening. But this is the same team that made <em>Soma</em>, so that’s not surprising. It’s coming out in 2026.</p>

 <h2><em>Zenless Zone Zero</em></h2>  <p>For the Hoyoverse sickos, a new character for&nbsp;<em>Zenless Zone Zero </em>was revealed.</p> <h2><em>2XKO</em></h2>  <p><em>2XKO</em>, the&nbsp;<em>League of Legends&nbsp;</em>fighting game, is coming to consoles in January, and Riot showed off a quick glimpse of Caitlyn as she’ll appear when she joins the roster.</p>

 <h2><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em></h2>  <p>Next we got a new look at&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil Requiem</em>, and my husband Old Leon Kennedy was in this one. I didn’t hear a word anyone else said over the wedding bells. But you can watch it yourself. Game looks sick.</p>

 <h2><em>Order of the Sinking Star</em></h2>  <p><em>Order of the Sinking Star</em> is a fantasy puzzle game from <em>Witness </em>and <em>Braid </em>developer Jonathan Blow. It has over 1400 puzzles and is coming in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Exodus</em></h2>  <p>Oh right, Matthew McConaughey is in this one.&nbsp;<em>Exodus&nbsp;</em>is an upcoming sci-fi action RPG shooter that looks like it’s trying to fill the <em>Mass Effect</em>-shaped hole in your heart. It’s from&nbsp;<em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons&nbsp;</em>company Wizards of the Coast, so it’s got a pretty notable legacy behind it. We’ll see if it lives up to it when it launches in early 2027.</p> <h2><em>Warlock: Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></h2>  <p>Wizards of the Coast isn’t done, though, as&nbsp;<em>Battlestar Galactica&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Mass Effect&nbsp;</em>star Trisha Helfer took the stage to introduce&nbsp;<em>Warlock: Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>. The cinematic trailer confirmed the game will launch in 2027, with a proper gameplay reveal to come in 2026.</p>

 <h2><em>Control Resonant</em></h2>  <p>Remedy showed up to announce the sequel to 2019’s <em>Control</em>. After an elaborate stage show that was probably a seizure hazard, we saw a cinematic trailer that I’m sure was comprehensible to those who finished the first game. It’s coming in 2026, and you can read <a href="https://kotaku.com/control-2-is-a-trippy-character-action-game-set-in-a-twisted-nyc-2000650168">more details about this bold, unusual sequel that Remedy shared with us here</a>.</p> <h2><em>Gang of Dragon</em></h2>  <p>Next, the trend of bloody trailers continued with <em>Gang of Dragon, </em>the first game from Nagoshi Studio, led by Toshihiro Nagoshi, one of the former leads behind the <em>Yakuza&nbsp;</em>series. It definitely feels in line with his previous work on Japanese crime dramas, so&nbsp;<em>Yakuza&nbsp;</em>fans will probably feel right at home.</p>

 <h2><em>Street Fighter&nbsp;</em>movie</h2>  <p>We’re taking a break from games for a moment with the first look at upcoming the <em>Street Fighter </em>live-action movie. There wasn’t a whole lot to glean about the story, but there’s plenty of punching, kicking, and other mayhem. Several members of the cast were present, and I am a total mark, because this totally got me. I’m ready to boot up&nbsp;<em>Street Fighter 6 </em>right now&nbsp;but there’s still like, two hours of this show left. Jesus.</p> <h2><em>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</em></h2>  <p>Geoff had an extended conversation with a Batman minifig before showing off a new look at <em>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</em>. That game is basically a new&nbsp;<em>Arkham</em>, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-preview-arkham-2000633994">what I played of it earlier this year was pretty dope</a>.</p> <h2><em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>hour</h2>  <p>After an hour of teases, we finally got to see the next&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>game. The announcement began with a cinematic trailer in which Lara shoots up some scavengers, and it sounds like Alix Wilton Regan, known for her work as the Inquisitor in <em>Dragon Age</em>, is voicing her this time around. Good for her. The game is coming in 2027.</p>

  <p>After this, we saw footage of <em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em>,&nbsp; a remake of the original game from the ’90s. We got to see a little bit of Lara doing cool acrobatics and shooting up a dinosaurs, so she’s still doing what she does best. This one is coming in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Forest 3</em></h2>  <p>Next, we saw a moody trailer for&nbsp;<em>Forest 3 </em>which&nbsp;for a second I thought might be <em>Half-Life 3</em> because the logo started with the “3.” That one’s on me. My bad.</p> <h2><em>Invincible VS</em></h2>  <p>The&nbsp;<em>Invincible </em>fighting game is coming in 2026, and we have our first look at new fighter Ella Mental.</p> <h2><em>Orbitals</em></h2>  <p>Next we saw a short trailer for co-op game <em>Orbitals</em>, which&nbsp;<em>Kotaku&nbsp;</em>managing editor Carolyn Petit described as “anime&nbsp;<em>Split Fiction</em>,” and that’s a pretty apt comparison.</p>

 <h2><em>Diablo IV</em></h2>  <p>After Mephisto, a big ol’ demon, roasted the audience on stage, Blizzard revealed <em>Diablo IV</em>‘s next expansion called <em>Lord of Hatred </em>with a grody cinematic trailer. It’s coming on April 28 and bringing <a href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4s-second-expansion-adds-new-classes-and-big-changes-2000652722">some new classes and big changes to the game</a>.</p> <h2><em>Marvel Rivals</em></h2>  <p>After a long-ass wait, Deadpool is finally coming to&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>. The merc with a mouth debuted with a stylish animated trailer, but unfortunately NetEase didn’t bring any gameplay with them to show us how he’ll play in-game. He’ll join the game next season in January, with Elsa Bloodstone to follow after.</p>

 <h2><em>007: First Light</em></h2>  <p>In a new trailer we see that Lenny Kravitz is playing the villain in the upcoming&nbsp;<em>James Bond&nbsp;</em>game&nbsp;<em>007: First Light</em>. This will be the musician’s first video game role.</p> <h2><em>Lords of the Fallen II</em></h2>  <p>Next up is the first gameplay trailer for fantasy-soulslike sequel <em>Lords of the Fallen II</em>. The original game also has a new update out today.</p> <h2><em>Saros</em></h2>  <p>Housemarque and actor Rahul Kohli showed up with a new trailer for the upcoming roguelike shooter <em>Saros.</em> The trailer focuses on the game’s story and characters, and the game is coming to PS5 on March 20.</p>

 <h2><em>No Law</em></h2>  <p><em>No Law&nbsp;</em>looks like&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>‘s baby brother. Literally can’t think of another way to describe it.</p> <h2><em>Total War: Warhammer 40k</em></h2>  <p>David Harbour of&nbsp;<em>Stranger Things&nbsp;</em>fame showed up to announce&nbsp;<em>Total War: Warhammer 40k</em>, because he’ll be in the game. The beloved strategy series is crossing over with <em>Warhammer 40k</em>, which means the Venn diagram of some of the sickest of sickos is converging when the game launches.</p> <h2><em>Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve</em></h2>  <p>Bandai Namco was up next with&nbsp;<em>Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve</em>, the next entry in its flight combat series. It’s launching in 2026.</p> <h2><em>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</em></h2>  <p><em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>fans are eating tonight, as they’re soon getting not only an RPG, but also a racer. <em>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</em> will let you live out your podracing dreams in 2026.</p>

 <h2><em>Out of Words</em></h2>  <p>If a stop-motion co-op platformer that’s probably gonna make you cry sounds like something you’d jive with, <em>Out of Words&nbsp;</em>is probably for you. It’s coming next year.</p> <h2><em>Phantom Blade 0</em></h2>  <p>Next, we got a lengthy look at&nbsp;<em>Phantom Blade 0</em>, S-GAME’s upcoming wuxia action game. It looks like the kind of challenging, twitchy hack-and-slash you want from something like the modern day <em>Ninja Gaiden</em> games. It’s coming to PS5 and PC on September 9.</p> <h2><em>Mega Man Dual Overdrive</em></h2>  <p>As we start to wind down, Capcom announced a new&nbsp;<em>Mega Man&nbsp;</em>game called <em>Dual Overdrive</em>. After a brief gameplay clip, the company announced it will launch in 2027.</p> <h2><em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em></h2>  <p>We got a short clip of the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em> in which Mario and Luigi face off against Bowser Jr. Luigi does get a pretty good knee to the kid’s face.</p> <h2><em>Highguard</em></h2>  <p>Closing the show was&nbsp;<em>Highguard</em>, a new fantasy shooter by Wildlight Entertainment, a studio led by ex-Respawn folks who worked on&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Titanfall</em>. You can see some of that DNA in here with its focus on traversal and quick movement, which its mixing with its fusion of modern and fantasy weaponry. The game will launch on January 26, and is free to play.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/everything-we-saw-at-the-2025-game-awards-2000652719]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>