<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:07:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 7 Best Scary RPGs To Play During Halloween]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halloween-horror-rpgs-bloodborne-witcher-pathologic-1851682650</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-7-best-scary-rpgs-to-play-during-halloween.1021086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/halloween-horror-rpgs-bloodborne-witcher-pathologic-1851682650<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="a1c240588f907fc67b94b0fc6c15d050" data-recommend-id="image://a1c240588f907fc67b94b0fc6c15d050" data-format="jpg" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A hunter clothed in black sits on a chair inside of a clocktower" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A hunter clothed in black sits on a chair inside of a clocktower" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a1c240588f907fc67b94b0fc6c15d050" data-recommend-id="image://a1c240588f907fc67b94b0fc6c15d050" data-format="jpg" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A hunter clothed in black sits on a chair inside of a clocktower" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>There are plenty of amazing horror games out there, we even made a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/best-horror-games-ps5-xbox-steam-pc-silent-hill-2-1851671021&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/best-horror-games-ps5-xbox-steam-pc-silent-hill-2-1851671021">whole list</a></span> about it! However, one genre that you might not immediately think of as a hotbed of good scares is role-playing games. You’d be wrong, though. RPGs of all types have some of the best horror stories in the medium, thanks to the focus on expansive worlds and player freedom that can easily be twisted into a scary situation of your own making. If you’re a fan of thrills as well as lengthy games you can really sink your teeth into, then these seven terrifying RPGs are the perfect treat for Halloween.</p></div><div><p>We all saw this coming. The 2004 vampire RPG basically has the market cornered on horror RPGs even two decades after its release. But there’s good reason for that! <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/wit-and-charm-are-powerful-weapons-in-vampire-the-masq-1835701842&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/wit-and-charm-are-powerful-weapons-in-vampire-the-masq-1835701842"><em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines</em></a></span> drops you into an incredibly realized world of vampire politics that you get to involve yourself in and change through a slew of wonderful combat and dialogue systems. It’s a great RPG but it’s also deeply rooted in the compelling vampire world it’s set in, so you really can’t do better than this.</p></div><div><p>While <em>The Witcher 3</em> is already a gritty and dark fairytale RPG full of monsters, its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-witcher-3-blood-and-wine-the-kotaku-review-1779646150&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-witcher-3-blood-and-wine-the-kotaku-review-1779646150"><em>Blood and Wine</em></a></span> expansion might be an even better pick for Halloween. Sure, the brown and gray color palette gets a Technicolor update, but that’s just to make all the blood look even more vibrant. <em>Blood and Wine</em> is a vampire story that builds on the solid systems and characters of the base game. You don’t even have to play <em>The Witcher 3</em> first, as you can start <em>Blood and Wine</em> right from the menu.</p></div><div><p>The best parts of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/deciding-whether-to-restart-a-video-game-is-my-latest-d-1835134928&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/deciding-whether-to-restart-a-video-game-is-my-latest-d-1835134928"><em>Pathologic 2</em></a></span> only show themselves once you die. The horror RPG is all about managing your resources to stay alive. You need to eat, drink, rest, and heal constantly, on top of managing your reputation across the game’s many towns. But once you do die, a weird meta encounter informs you that the world has gotten worse and so have you. What was already a strange and dangerous world becomes exponentially so through debuffs like less health or more unconventional things such as losing the ability to hug characters. The more you die, the more things change, and there is always a little bit of a pull on your curiosity to find out how bad things can really get.</p></div><div><p>Square Enix’s cult classic answer to <em>Resident Evil </em>will always deserve more attention than it gets. As you’d expect from the makers of <em>Final Fantasy</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/parasite-eve-had-more-in-common-with-final-fantasy-than-1788134625&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/parasite-eve-had-more-in-common-with-final-fantasy-than-1788134625"><em>Parasite Eve</em></a></span> added RPG elements to the survival horror genre to great success. You play as Aya Brea, a rookie NYPD cop who, over the course of a lonely week in late December, works to save the city from a mitochondrial outbreak that threatens to destroy the world. It’s pulpy, it’s scary, it’s fun, and it’s worth playing if only for seeing the jaw-dropping opening cinematic.</p></div><div><p>For my money, no game has done gothic horror better than <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-the-kotaku-review-1695227854&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-the-kotaku-review-1695227854"><em>Bloodborne</em></a></span>. The city of Yharnam, with its constant sense of dread that bears down on you as you explore its cobblestone streets and gothic structures, has one of the most imposing atmospheres in any game ever. Sure, there’s still the tough-as-nails combat and constant retreading of territory we know from the <em>Souls </em>games—this is still FromSoftware—but rather than dark fantasy, <em>Bloodborne </em>evokes true horror. That happens both in the grotesque monster designs you encounter during its difficult fights but also in its story of cosmic dread and humanity’s overambition.</p></div><div><p>Cosmic horror will—for better and worse—always be synonymous with H.P. Lovecraft. One of the author’s most famous creations, Cthulhu, has even spawned a fantastic tabletop RPG, on which the video game <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> is based. That video game is a great translation of Lovecraftian cosmic horror thanks to its emphasis on sanity. As you progress, you’ll slowly lose your mind, but before you do that you’ll be out to work as a detective. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-the-kotaku-review-1695227854&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-the-kotaku-review-1695227854"><em>Call of Cthulhu</em></a></span> lets you choose your background, which then opens up different dialogue options during investigations. This makes each playthrough feel unique, and cultivates the sense that perhaps you aren’t getting the full picture.</p></div><div><p>The secret to horror roguelike <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/darkest-dungeon-the-kotaku-review-1755308882&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/darkest-dungeon-the-kotaku-review-1755308882"><em>Darkest Dungeon</em></a></span>’s success is stressing you the fuck out. Each member of your party, with whom you attempt to navigate the titular dungeons, has a stress level. If they get too stressed they will literally have a heart attack. This will stress you out and that’s great! The system makes you keenly aware of the risk vs reward of every action. If your party members explore without light, don’t eat proper food, or witness deaths, they’ll become increasinglystressed. But what if you can just make it through? It might be worth it! That’s the eternal conundrum of every run of <em>Darkest Dungeon</em>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp Is Getting Replaced By A Poorer Version For A Huge Fee]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-pocket-camp-complete-mobile-nintendo-1851682569</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/animal-crossing-pocket-camp-is-getting-replaced-by-a-poorer-version-for-a-huge-fee.1021017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-pocket-camp-complete-mobile-nintendo-1851682569<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In August 2024, Nintendo’s free-to-play mobile incarnation of <em>Animal Crossing</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Pocket_Camp/status/1826502311830860094&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Pocket_Camp/status/1826502311830860094" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">was announced</a></span> to be coming to an end this  November. It’s now been revealed that its replacement, <em>Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp Complete</em>, will appear December 3, and ditch all of the 2017 game’s microtransactions for a one-off sum. Except, the sum is huge, the game’s losing features, and there’s no exception for long-time players of the original <em>Pocket Camp</em>.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196626" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="271" data-playlist="196626,195027,196884" data-current="196626"><div><p>Who Is The Best Hang In Unicorn Overlord? A Scientific Ranking</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196626/196626_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22184.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Nintendo’s experiments with mobile gaming have often been at odds with the ethos the company usually tries to express. At one point the now defunct <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-tour-gacha-pipe-rubies-spotlight-shop-items-1849492461&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-tour-gacha-pipe-rubies-spotlight-shop-items-1849492461"><em>Mario Kart Tour</em> sported deeply controversial gacha mechanics</a></span>. The company has also been quick to shut down games that aren’t performing as wanted, to the disappointment of long-term players, with a bunch of different mobile titles—including <em>Dragalia Lost</em> and <em>Dr. Mario World</em>—canned since the mobile ventures began in 2016.</p><p><em>Pocket Camp</em>’s situation isn’t <em>quite </em>as final as others, like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-tour-new-content-end-mobile-racer-spinoff-1850825190&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-tour-new-content-end-mobile-racer-spinoff-1850825190"><em>Mario Kart Tour</em>’s no longer receiving updates</a></span> since the end of 2023. Instead, people who’ve been playing the <em>Animal Crossing </em>game since its 2017 release will be able to transfer across their progress to the new game. But only after paying a whopping $20 entry fee. And it will only be updated for another year. And it’s losing features. And oh boy this doesn’t look great.</p><figure id="" data-id="8cb4892420c49631ee69eef927da437d" data-recommend-id="image://8cb4892420c49631ee69eef927da437d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An Animal Crossing character, very happy at a picnic." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An Animal Crossing character, very happy at a picnic." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8cb4892420c49631ee69eef927da437d" data-recommend-id="image://8cb4892420c49631ee69eef927da437d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An Animal Crossing character, very happy at a picnic." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>There’s something of a concession toward just how <em>enormous </em>a price this is for a mobile game people may have already spent vast sums on previously—for the first two months, Nintendo will be charging half that much, ending on January 31, 2025. Still, another $10 is a kick in the eye for those who’ve invested over the last seven years.<br></p><p><em>Pocket Camp Complete</em> doesn’t mark a  step forward for the game, but rather will see it continuing with a slightly reduced set of features, and the promise of one more year of updates. If you’ve got an established village, it’ll all transfer over, along with all your Friendship Levels, but not your leaf tickets, which are <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/36088777921945-What-happens-to-my-Leaf-Tickets&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/36088777921945-What-happens-to-my-Leaf-Tickets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">being removed entirely</a></span>. But in a really surprising move, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/36353725150489-What-is-Animal-Crossing-Pocket-Camp-Complete&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/36353725150489-What-is-Animal-Crossing-Pocket-Camp-Complete" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nintendo makes clear on its update page</a></span> that “There is no discount specifically for <em>Animal Crossing: Pocket Camp</em> users.”</p><p>Why not?! What a deeply peculiar move, to not reward those who’ve been subscribing for $3 to $8 a month since 2019, when subs began! The game costs the same for me, who has never played, as for the person who’s put in $480 in subscription fees.</p><p>Various online features are getting ditched, such as sharing gifts and the Market Box, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/38847775801625-About-Friends-in-Pocket-Camp-Complete&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/38847775801625-About-Friends-in-Pocket-Camp-Complete" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interacting with other islands is becoming a whole weird ordeal</a></span>. Most of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/39072047740057-Things-No-Longer-Available-in-Pocket-Camp-Complete&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://faq.ac-pocketcamp.com/hc/en-us/articles/39072047740057-Things-No-Longer-Available-in-Pocket-Camp-Complete" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bonuses that came with subscriptions</a></span> are going too.</p><p>It also looks like Nintendo intends to stop updating the game as frequently come October 2025, after which point there are no plans to add new cookies or new events, suggesting the $20 entry fee is buying you access to the last proper year for the game. Who knows? This may be timed to overlap with the release of a new <em>Animal Crossing </em>game for the Switch 2, given the normal release schedule of the series suggests one should be due.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTube Rejects Dr Disrespect's Request To Profit Off His Channel Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-monetization-black-ops-6-ban-1851682643</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youtube-rejects-dr-disrespects-request-to-profit-off-his-channel-again.1021011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-monetization-black-ops-6-ban-1851682643<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="43c7e7a40844af3c5ef71f56ea63197e" data-recommend-id="image://43c7e7a40844af3c5ef71f56ea63197e" data-format="png" data-width="1135" data-height="637" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Guy Beahm plays COD: Blops 6 on YouTube" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Guy Beahm plays COD: Blops 6 on YouTube" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Dr Disrespect / YouTube / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="43c7e7a40844af3c5ef71f56ea63197e" data-recommend-id="image://43c7e7a40844af3c5ef71f56ea63197e" data-format="png" data-width="1135" data-height="637" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Guy Beahm plays COD: Blops 6 on YouTube" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>It’s been a few months since Guy “Dr Disrespect” Beahm <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-turtle-beach-twitch-ban-sext-minor-1851559715&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-turtle-beach-twitch-ban-sext-minor-1851559715">lost sponsors</a></span> and had his YouTube channel demonetized after he admitted to “inappropriate” contact with a minor on Twitch. The  controversial online personality is still playing and streaming games on the Google-owned platform, however, even though his request to have monetization of his 4.5 million follower channel reinstated was recently denied.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“Actually, champs, unfortunately, they pushed back the [appeal review] another 60 days,” he told viewers of his <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em> stream <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYzmO3OCaj0&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYzmO3OCaj0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over the weekend</a></span>. “Believe it or not, they waited until the very last second last night to tell us, ‘uh, we’re going to extend just for another 60 days, and then you’ll be eligible to reapply, and we’ll review the application.’ But you know what, champs, okay then, let’s wait another 60 days.”</p><p>YouTube announced it was demonetizing Beahm’s channel <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-sexting-allegation-minor-1851565750&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-sexting-allegation-minor-1851565750">back in June</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-sexting-twitch-ban-youtube-elden-ring-1851556854&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-sexting-twitch-ban-youtube-elden-ring-1851556854">following public allegations and multiple news reports</a></span> that the streamer had originally been banned from Twitch back in 2020 over misconduct related to messages exchanged with an underage user. Beahm later admitted to speaking to a minor on the platform but denied ever doing anything that was illegal before going on an indefinite vacation from streaming amid a loss of sponsors and business partnerships. </p><p>But Beahm returned to the world of YouTube gaming in September with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-livestream-twitch-ban-sexting-1851642418&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-disrespect-youtube-livestream-twitch-ban-sexting-1851642418">a rant about how he had been defamed</a></span> and accusing his detractors of conspiring to bring him down. He also reapplied for YouTube partnership status on September 25 in order to begin once again making money off of his massive audience on the platform. Following a 30 day review, it now appears that YouTube has punted on a final decision until the very end of the year.<br></p><p>In the meantime, Beahm has been hawking new Donald Trump-inspired merchandise that says “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DrDisrespect/status/1849888659237109821&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DrDisrespect/status/1849888659237109821" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Make Gaming Great Again</a></span>” and teasing something “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.thegamer.com/dr-disrespect-guy-beahm-twitch-youtube-streamer-appeal-request-video-monetisation-denied/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.thegamer.com/dr-disrespect-guy-beahm-twitch-youtube-streamer-appeal-request-video-monetisation-denied/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">much bigger</a></span>” than his YouTube return to his remaining fans. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>