<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 08:30:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Sonic Racing: Crossworlds, Sega Does What Nintendon’t]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mario-kart-preview-shadow-2000620065</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-sonic-racing-crossworlds-sega-does-what-nintendon%E2%80%99t.1280412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I’ve played </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-previews-sonic-resident-evil-play-days-1851784271"><i><span>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds</span></i></a> <span>twice now, and both times, I had the same fleeting thought: “What if </span><i><span>Sonic</span></i><span> outruns </span><i><span>Mario Kart </span></i><span>and has the better kart racer this year?” </span><i><span>Mario Kart World </span></i><span>is pretty good. It is a really solid One of Those, and it will no doubt be a mainstay in the Switch 2’s long lifetime–but it plays things safe, has several frustrating things going on under the hood, and by God, 24 players is too damn many.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>After playing about a dozen hours of </span><i><span>World </span></i><span>with friends since the Switch 2 launched in June, playing </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>for even an hour was refreshing, as it feels like Sega is not only taking some cool risks to shake up the formula, but also making calculated choices that rein in chaos and allow for more strategic racing.</span></p> <p><i><span>Crossworlds</span></i><span>’ biggest shake-up is the introduction of the Gadget Panel, which is essentially an overhaul of </span><i><span>Team Sonic Racing</span></i><span>’s Bonus Box system. Before each race, you can use your panel to create a loadout of upgrades, usable items, and stat boosts to fit your playstyle. Some upgrades take up more space than others on your panel. My typical arsenal included the option to start each race with a monster truck transformation item that gives you a significant speed boost and also lets you trample over enemies in your path. Having something like that takes up multiple slots on your panel, but it’s an excellent way to get a head start at the beginning of a race.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>While that’s a one-and-done boost, a lot of the upgrades help you throughout a race, such as performing speed boosting air tricks faster, making your drift a little smoother, or offensive-based upgrades like giving yourself a boost every time you collide with an enemy kart. You can race in cars or the Extreme Gear hoverboards, which will define your playstyle, but your Gadget Panel lets you fine-tune it into something unique and personalized. I use the monster truck at the beginning of the race, but after I’ve gotten my head start, I want to make sure I have a smooth ride as I pass the rest of these slowpokes, so I use the rest of my panel to make my drifts faster and get a speed boost when I bump into others.</span></p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds | Competition Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1nIhfo2X0oI?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p><span>Having all those spinning plates on screen at once would overwhelm </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>if it had taken </span><i><span>Mario Kart World</span></i><span>’s 24-player races as a challenge. However, </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>maintains a 12-player limit on its races, and after all the </span><i><span>World </span></i><span>I’d been playing, it’s become pretty clear to me that this is the sweet spot.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Yeah, having 24 players on a track at once is a good technical showcase for the Switch 2 and feeds into the usual “bigger = better” mentality that permeates through most video games, but it has also turned out to be one of </span><i><span>World</span></i><span>’s biggest frustrations. By design, if there are more racers on a track, the slightest setback will inherently give more players a chance to pass by you. One well-timed blue shell can send a first-place winner back a dozen placements with not enough time or resources to regain the lead. So much of </span><i><span>Mario Kart </span></i><span>is determined by the luck of the draw. If you get the right item, you can Bullet Bill your way to the front of the pack, but you might get something less useful. </span><i><span>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds </span></i><span>has the same item-based play, but its Gadget loadouts leave your playstyle less to chance, and its 12-player races mean that the slightest misstep isn’t punished by being tossed down the rankings into an oblivion you can’t drive out of. It adds fun complexities without becoming chaotic and convoluted to the point where only the sweatiest among us can reach first place.</span></p> <p><i><span>Crossworlds</span></i><span> is doing a lot of things right, and in light of a relatively lukewarm reception for its biggest competitor, </span><i><span>Mario </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Sonic </span></i><span>are potentially on an even playing field, and the blue blur could come out on top for the first time in a while. I may not be thrilled with the crossover slop this time around, but I’m eager to get on my board as Shadow when </span><i><span>Crossworlds </span></i><span>launches on September 25.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-mario-kart-preview-shadow-2000620065]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Recreated All Of Robocop As The Cracker Barrel Logo]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/someone-recreated-all-of-robocop-as-the-cracker-barrel-logo-2000620081</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/someone-recreated-all-of-robocop-as-the-cracker-barrel-logo.1280220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>After nearly 50 years, <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-cracker-barrel-logo-woke-trump-cooperate-greed-2000619204">Cracker Barrel</a> changed its logo last week. You probably heard or read something about it, as news of the change and the reaction to it became one of the biggest topics on the internet. And so, somehow, that leads us to a person online replacing the Cracker Barrel logo with the entirety of <em>Robocop</em> from 1987.</p> <p>On August 23, a few days after the Cracker Barrel news had swept the internet and sparked countless blogs and articles (<a href="https://kotaku.com/new-cracker-barrel-logo-woke-trump-cooperate-greed-2000619204">even we wrote about it</a>), Twitter user Kodiak posted to the dying social media site the “full 1987 film <em>RoboCop</em> rendered as the Cracker Barrel logo.” You might be wondering a few things, namely: Why? Well, don’t worry, Kodiak doesn’t want to leave you with a mystery. Why did they re-render <em>RoboCop</em> as the Cracker Barrel logo?&nbsp; “Because nothing matters,” <a href="https://x.com/thisiskodiak/status/1959402871939862841">posted Kodiak</a>.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The full 1987 film RoboCop rendered as the Cracker Barrel logo. Because nothing matters. <a href="https://t.co/0e1UjAezJY">pic.twitter.com/0e1UjAezJY</a></p> <p>— Kodiak (@ThisIsKodiak) <a href="https://twitter.com/ThisIsKodiak/status/1959402871939862841?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Is this the ideal way to watch <em>RoboCop</em>? Some might say yes. <a href="https://x.com/jenny____r/status/1959668520452862246">At least one person has seemingly watched the film on their big screen TV</a>, which is fun to think about. Another question you might be pondering—between never-ending thoughts about Cracker Barrel’s new, boring logo and what it means in relation to modern-day society—is a simple one: Is this legal? I’m not a lawyer. I’d probably say no, but these days it really does seem like law and order is out the window, and the rich and powerful can do whatever they want. Ohhh….wait, now I get why they picked <em>RoboCop</em> for this joke. Funny! (Shout out to <em><a href="https://www.garbageday.email/p/a-b-testing-your-anti-woke-meltdown-e1a04224ffbb38b6">Garbage Day</a></em> for spotting this.)</p> <p>Anyway, go ahead and watch <em>RoboCop</em> until Twitter kills the video. At the moment, it has over 550k views, so it seems like Elon Musk and whoever still works at Twitter don’t care. Or they forgot the password to the account that lets them delete stuff. Either way, enjoy <em>RoboCop</em>. Or you can go buy and play that <a href="https://kotaku.com/robocop-rogue-city-new-game-2023-review-shooter-rpg-pc-1851000568">awesome <em>RoboCop</em> game from a few years back</a>. Do both at the same time? What do I care? I’m not your dad.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/someone-recreated-all-of-robocop-as-the-cracker-barrel-logo-2000620081]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Minecraft Mod Turns It Into Portal 2, Complete With A Level Editor]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/portal-2-minecraft-java-edition-mod-valve-pc-remake-2000620054</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-minecraft-mod-turns-it-into-portal-2-complete-with-a-level-editor.1280175/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It’s&nbsp;<span>highly unlikely that we’ll see <a href="https://kotaku.com/portal-valve-erik-wolpaw-half-life-alyx-steam-counter-s-1848807049">a new&nbsp;<em>Portal</em> game</a> anytime soon from series creators </span>Valve. But now you can create your own<em> Portal 3</em> in a place I didn’t expect: <em>Minecraft</em>. Or you can play through 50 pre-made <a href="https://kotaku.com/portal-2-is-the-better-portal-but-you-better-bring-a-f-5793326"><em>Portal</em> <em>2</em></a> puzzles via a newly released <em>Minecraft</em> mod.</p> <p>On August 22, <a href="https://portaljavaedition.net/about">a group of 20+ modders and fan devs released <em>Portal: Java Edition</em></a>, a free remake of Valve’s 2011 first-person puzzler built entirely in vanilla Minecraft using resource and data packs. That <em>technically</em> means the project, which is free to download now on PC, doesn’t use any “mods,” though the creators do include extra third-party mods that help with optimization. And you’ll likely want to install those if you plan to play. This rebuilt version of<em> Portal 2</em> in <em>Minecraft</em> is pushing the Java version of the popular crafting game hard, and it can chug on even beefy PCs without the extra mods.</p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Portal: Java Edition | Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8v7ZfuKZNis?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>According to the team behind it<em>, Portal: Java Edition</em> started development in 2020 and has taken roughly five years to complete. The mod includes all the mechanics and features from <em>Portal 2</em>, including portals (of course), lasers, light bridges, and mobility gels. The project is shipping with 50 levels spread across eight map packs. And if you burn through all of those, well, don’t worry, you can make some more, thanks to the included level editor. The level editor should be pretty easy to use for <em>Minecraft</em> vets, as it seems to function just like building anything else in Mojang’s crafting game, just with more big red buttons and companion cubes.</p> <p>To play <em>Portal: Java Edition</em>, you’ll need to own <em>Minecraft: Java Edition</em> on PC and then download the project’s files from GitHub. I had to download an older version of <em>Minecraft</em> to get <em>Portal</em> working in the game, but that’s not too hard and is fully supported by the official <em>Minecraft</em> launcher. Once more people are playing this and building levels in it, I expect to replay <em>Doom’s</em>&nbsp;E1M1 and the first level of<em> Super Mario Bros</em>. in the near future.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/portal-2-minecraft-java-edition-mod-valve-pc-remake-2000620054]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>