<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:19:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yu-Gi-Oh Could Be Lego’s Next Big Anime Crossover]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/yugioh-lego-contest-rules-yugi-kaiba-characters-cards-2000665381</link>
            <guid>1424284</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Lego is asking </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/death-battle-ash-ketchum-pokemon-yugi-moto-yugioh-video-2000651417"><i><span>Yu-Gi-Oh</span></i></a> <span>fans to design its first potential set based on the card game anime, meaning 30 years after the manga originally launched, </span><i><span>Yu-Gi</span></i><span>-pilled millennials might finally be get to duel in Lego form. Anime could end up being the next lucrative frontier for the company’s licensed brick empire.</span></p> <p><span>The toy company has </span><a href="https://beta.ideas.lego.com/blog/b40e8dea-5622-4e9b-90bc-7aa254e58a6f"><span>announced a contest</span></a><span> for </span><i><span>Yu-Gi-Oh </span></i><span>fans to submit ideas for a buildable set, but it has a few rules and regulations that will narrow down the eligible designs. The examples Lego gives include models of characters and their trademark monsters, such as Yugi and the Dark Magician or Kaiba and his Blue-Eyes White Dragon. Dioramas of iconic duels from the anime, or a standalone monster, are also allowed.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Lego is specifically looking for ideas based on the Battle City and Duelist Kingdom tournament arcs from the original anime, so if you were thinking of an idea for a character in one of the more recent anime series, think again. Each idea must have between 400 and 2000 pieces to be considered. Lego is not looking for chump sets here.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>That’s all well and good, but I’m surprised Lego isn’t taking an obvious route and releasing a Millennium Puzzle Lego set when Yugi literally builds his signature pyramid pendant that he wears around his neck like an actual Lego. Maybe if this contest takes off Lego will consider other </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/konami-ai-yu-gi-oh-world-championship-commentary-2000624978"><i><span>Yu-Gi-Oh</span></i></a><span> models. That one seems like a no-brainer.</span></p>

 <p><span>Still, the focus on the original anime series does make it sound like Lego is targeting older fans who grew up with the classic cards and characters, which is in line with the marketing of other collaborations like the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-lego-sets-release-date-price-pikachu-charizard-2000658895"><i><span>Pokémon</span></i></a> <span>sets that specifically called out people who have back pain and bills to pay.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>But hey, these things are expensive, require a lot of patience to assemble, and are much more elaborate than the smaller sets you see marketed to kids. Submissions are open until March 10.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/yugioh-lego-contest-rules-yugi-kaiba-characters-cards-2000665381]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Things We Just Learned From Nintendo About How The Switch 2 Is Doing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-earnings-switch-2-sales-nintendo-metroid-prime-4-2000665326</link>
            <guid>1424203</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The first half of the Switch 2’s first year is in the books. <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-review-metroid-prime-4-pokemon-2000656188">Here’s how we graded it back in December</a>. But now Nintendo’s latest earnings report is here to offer some hard numbers on how the Mario maker’s current next-gen platform shift is going. TL;DR: Incredibly strongly, though it’s still searching for that <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-launch-lineup-single-player-mario-3d-mkw-1851784352">runaway hit no one can shut up about</a>.</p> <p>This week <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-sk="tooltip_parent">the company announced</a> it had sold 7 million Switch 2 consoles during the 2025 holiday period, bringing the lifetime sales up to 17 million for the first six months. Meanwhile the original Switch sold an additional 1.36 million units, with another 750,000 expected to sell through the end of the current fiscal year on March 31, 2026.</p>

 <p>The original Switch has now cleared the lifetime total of 154 million set by the DS, officially making it the company’s most popular console ever. At the same time, it now seems unlikely to actually eclipse the PlayStation 2 as the most popular console ever. At 155 current lifetime sales, the OG Switch would need to find another 5 million sales in the couch cushions somewhere <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-limited-edition-zelda-echoes-sales-1851611733">to beat the PS2’s 160 million</a>.&nbsp;Here are the other interesting takeaways from Nintendo’s latest earnings:</p> <h2>&nbsp;Digital is king on Switch 2</h2> <p>While digital sales remain increasingly dominant, physical game sales usually tick up during the holiday as people gift each other games. Well, for the Switch 2’s first holiday, digital sales did way better than expected. Nintendo reported a 14.7 percent increase year-over-year. It attributed that “mainly due to an increase in sales of downloadable versions of packaged software and add-on content.” And this excludes people buying the digital version of <em>Mario Kart World</em> via the Switch 2 bundle. The proportion of packaged software that was sold in downloadable versions in holiday 2024 was 56 percent. In 2025 it was 58.7 percent.</p>

 <h2>Switch 2 is still wildly outperforming the Switch</h2> <p>While Nintendo reports a slower holiday than expected for the console in the U.S., demand in Japan has been exceeding Nintendo’s expectations and the Switch 2 continues to outpace its predecessor by a healthy margin. It’s outsold the original Switch during the six-month launch window by nearly two to one. Of course, the Switch 2 has the benefit of the holiday season being in that launch period, while the original Switch launched in the spring as opposed to the summer. Still, it shows people are hungry for the upgrade.</p>

 <h2>Annual playing users are actually down though</h2> <p>Weirdly, despite launching a long-awaited, highly anticipated new console in 2025, Nintendo actually ended the year with fewer annual players than it had in 2024. That number, which includes anyone with an account who played a game at some point in the past 12 months, peaked at 130 million in 2024 and ticked back down to 129 million in December. That suggests that while Switch 2 is converting existing players to the new hardware, the push hasn’t necessarily helped expand the platform’s overall footprint.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000665377" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665377"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665377">Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <h2><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em> didn’t chart</h2> <p>Despite <a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-kotaku-review-is-it-good-120-fps-switch-2-2000651400"><em>Metroid Prime 4 </em></a>launching in December, Nintendo didn’t release any sales data for the game, a very bad sign. That suggests the game hasn’t yet cracked 1 million sales on either Switch 1 or Switch 2, even if it may have cumulative sales across both platforms may have passed that benchmark. On the one hand, that’s not shocking. <em>Metroid</em> has never been a big seller for Nintendo. On the other hand, it suggests that we might not get a new <em>Metroid Prime</em> anytime soon, and that players weren’t rushing to make it their big Switch 2 blockbuster for the holiday. Total software sold is up compared to the Switch 1, but the overall attach rate is lower, likely because Switch 2 owners already have a huge backwards-compatible Switch 1 library to pull from.</p>

 <h2>The Switch 2 is missing a big new hit</h2> <p>Nintendo has sold <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/finance/software/index.html">14 million copies</a> of <em>Mario Kart World</em> but that includes the Switch 2 console bundles. <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> is doing great for a Switch 2 exclusive at 4.25 million sales but hasn’t yet proven if it can do<em> Super Mario Odyssey</em> numbers.<em> Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> has sold over 11 million copies, including nearly 4 million on Switch 2. And even <em>Kirby Air Riders</em> broke 1 million sales. That’s about where the Switch 1’s launch lineup was at <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AmiiboCanada/comments/79o6oa/summary_of_switch_sales_from_nintendo_q22017/">after its first six months</a>, but that didn’t include Christmas or <em>Mario Odyssey</em>. The Switch 1 finished its first year with multiple first-party games breaking the 5 million sales mark, and so far the Switch 2 doesn’t seem likely to match that without a big surprise announcement or two in the next six months.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-earnings-switch-2-sales-nintendo-metroid-prime-4-2000665326]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>