<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:12:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Quietly Offloads Its 1TB  Laptops via Amazon (74% off), but Displays No Direct Deals on Its Website]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dell-quietly-offloads-its-1tb-laptops-via-amazon-74-off-but-displays-no-direct-deals-on-its-website-2000642475</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dell-quietly-offloads-its-1tb-laptops-via-amazon-74-off-but-displays-no-direct-deals-on-its-website.1349404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Budget laptops typically force compromises on storage, RAM, or processor power to hit accessible price points, and leave buyers frustrated with sluggish performance. Dell quietly sidesteps this problem by offloading fully-loaded Inspiron 15-inch laptops through Amazon rather than advertising aggressive discounts on its own website to protect brand perception while clearing inventory.</p>
<p>The Inspiron 3530 with <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5432/">Intel i7 processor, 32GB RAM, and 1TB SSD currently sells for just $939 on Amazon, slashed from its typical $3,599 price tag</a>. Dell’s own site shows no comparable promotion which makes <strong>Amazon the exclusive channel for this 74% discount</strong> that brings professional-grade specs down to consumer pricing.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5432/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>



<h2>Dell Loaded This Laptop With Premium Components</h2>
<p>Fantastic performance without the thermal throttling that makes cheaper laptops struggle with demanding workflows comes <strong>with the 13th generation Intel Core i7-1355U processor</strong>. This 10-core chip with 12MB cache revs up as high as 5.0 GHz when needed for responsive computing. Moreover, the integrated graphics in the Intel Iris Xe really push beyond what most mainstream integrated options can provide: This means you’re getting a laptop that will not become obsolete the moment you need to do something more resource-intensive than just basic web browsing and document editing.</p>



<p>Adding 32GB of DDR4 RAM to this machine takes it from merely adequate to truly capable for professional work. Such ample memory allows seamless multitasking among creative applications so you could edit photos in one window, render video in another and monitor your email in a third. For anyone who works with virtual machines, large datasets or memory-intensive development environments, the extra 32GB gives you the headroom that spares you constant application switching and waiting.</p>



<p>This 1TB SSD gives plenty of storage for operating system and personal files without imposing constant cleaning or cloud dependence. Solid-state storage delivers boot times measured in seconds rather than minutes, and applications launch almost instantaneously compared to mechanical hard drives. A PCIe connection provides the drive with the bandwidth needed to operate at maximum speed, meaning large files transfer quickly and the whole system feels responsive.</p>
<p>The anti-glare coating on this 15.6-inch Full HD touchscreen provides excellent visual quality that, during extended work sessions and increases comfort. A 1920×1080 resolution enables one to have sharp rendering of text, which reduces eye strain when working with documents. WVA panel technology assures the viewer of accurate color representation and wide viewing angles.</p>
<p>The options include older legacy USB 2.0 ports for older peripherals, modern USB 3.2 Gen 1 Type-A and Type-C ports to enable fast data transfer, HDMI 1.4 for external displays, an SD card reader in service of photographers, and a standard headphone jack. WiFi 6 support provides the fastest wireless connectivity currently available, and Bluetooth 5.3 ensures reliable connections to wireless mice, keyboards, and headphones.</p>
<p><strong>Windows 11 Pro includes</strong> additional security features and the ability to join a domain that’s not offered in the home versions, while the<strong> Copilot AI assistant</strong> offers contextual help to make productivity tasks easier.</p>
<p>For $939, this laptop is cheaper than many mid-range machines with half the RAM and storage: <strong>it’s a spectacular value that Dell can’t promote too loudly without undermining its premium brand position</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5432/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dell-quietly-offloads-its-1tb-laptops-via-amazon-74-off-but-displays-no-direct-deals-on-its-website-2000642475]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>