<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 08:48:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Shift Codes And Gold Keys Work In Borderlands 4]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/how-shift-codes-gold-keys-work-borderlands-4-help-get-more-2000626107</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-shift-codes-and-gold-keys-work-in-borderlands-4.1299771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-11-best-changes-borderlands-4-junk-loot-menus-legendary-guns-2000624953"><em>Borderlands 4</em></a> is out now! Yay, that’s exciting. <a href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-pc-performance-dlss-frame-gen-pitchford-gearbox-steam-2000625765">However, on PC, it has some performance problems</a> that might dampen your enjoyment. But hey, whatever, you’re here because you want to figure out how Shift Codes work and how to get Gold Keys in <em>Borderlands 4.</em> It’s a weird and some might say unnecessary system, but I’ll help walk you through it. And by the end you’ll be good to go.</p> <p>First, before we go any further, you need to create a free Shift account. Shift is Gearbox’s very own video game network… thing. It has been around since <em>Borderlands 2</em>, and the website for Shift has basically not changed since then, so it looks old, but it is pretty easy to use. Just hop over to the <a href="https://shift.gearboxsoftware.com/home">Shift site and make a free account.</a> Next, you’ll want to link whatever platform you play on, like Xbox, to your new Shift account. To do that, look to the top left of the website and click “Gaming Platforms.” Then select your platform and follow the steps to log in and get everything all synced up. Okay, now, you can start redeeming Shift codes. But first…</p> <h3>What Are Shift Codes?</h3> <p>That’s a great question! Here’s a sticker. Shift codes are alphanumeric codes that are handed out by official Gearbox and <em>Borderlands</em>-related accounts, often on social media. These codes will provide an in-game reward when correctly redeemed. Many people can use a single Shift code, but they often have expiration dates, so older codes might not work.</p>

 <p>One of the best and most frequent providers of new Shift codes is Gearbox CEO Randy Pitchford himself, so you might want to follow him on X. Sorry about that. And no, I don’t think Pitchford pushed to create Shift simply to get more followers online, but it’s a funny theory.</p> <p>Technically, Shift codes exist for other Gearbox games, like <em>Aliens: Colonial Marines and Battleborn</em>, but uh… well, these days, 99 percent of Shift codes are connected to <em>Borderlands</em> and <em>Wonderlands</em> because nobody plays Gearbox’s other games. Anyway, once you have a Shift code, either from Pitchford or one of the many fan sites and accounts that catalog them, it’s time to enter that code on the Shift website!</p>

 <h2>How Do I Use A Shift Code?</h2> <p>There are two ways to enter a Shift code and gain its rewards. The first, and worst way, is to boot up the game the Shift code is connected to and enter the code via that title’s Shift screen. This is a cumbersome way to do this and has no benefits and many drawbacks. Do you really want to enter a long string of letters and numbers with an Xbox gamepad and on-screen keyboard? Nah.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000626109" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000626109"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000626109">©Gearbox / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The better way to use your Shift Codes is to do so on your phone or PC. Once you’re logged into your Shift account, you can just copy the code and hop over to the website. Then you just click “Rewards” and pop your Shift code into the empty box.</p>

 <p>Depending on the code, you’ll likely need to specify a platform. So, for example, if you put in a Shift code for a Gold Key in<em> Borderlands 4</em>, the game will ask you what platforms you want to redeem it on and show you every platform you have linked. Fun fact: Most codes can be reused for each connected platform. If you enter it in correctly, you’ll get a prompt letting you know, and the rewards feed below where you entered the code will update to show you what you just earned, in what game, and on which platform.</p> <h2>Wait, I Want Gold Keys, Not Shift Codes!</h2> <p>Calm down. Shift codes are how you get Gold Keys. And while it is true that not all Shift codes provide Gold Keys for various <em>Borderlands</em> games—some provide cosmetics and other bonuses—the vast majority of codes in 2025 will give you Gold Keys.</p>

 <p>Just keep in mind that Gold Keys, once redeemed, can’t be used in any other <em>Borderlands</em> game. I have nearly 80 of the bastards waiting to be used in<em> Borderlands 3</em>, but none of them can make the leap to <em>Borderlands 4.</em> It makes me very sad.</p> <h2>How Do I Use These Gold Keys In <em>Borderlands 4</em>?</h2> <p>All Gold Keys in all <em>Borderlands</em> titles, including<em> Borderlands 4</em>, are used to open big gold chests that can be found in the hub areas of the various games. These chests have a high chance of dropping really good loot, including rare legendary guns and gear. In<em> Borderlands 4,</em> there are actually a few gold chests located at various safehouses and other points of interest, but be aware you can’t open a Gold chest until you unlock the Outbounder’s village near the starting area of the game in the Fadefields.</p>

 <figure><figcaption>©Gearbox / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>To use a key, just go up to the chest and hit the open button. But be warned! You really shouldn’t do this until you are at least level 40, as early on in the game you’ll likely just replace whatever you get with better gear quickly as you level up. Also, if you’re playing with randos or greedy friends, be aware that the gear you get from the chest will fly out of it after 30 seconds or so, and at that point, anyone can grab it. This happened to me. I lost a great revolver. My friends laughed. I grew more bitter.</p> <p>And that’s all you need to know about Shift codes and Gold Keys. If you want lots of Shift Codes for <em>Borderlands 4,</em> <a href="https://x.com/borderlandshub/status/1968030270847922295">I’d recommend this account on Twitter</a> that rounds them all up and posts them with a direct link to the Shift site, making it easy to snag some codes and keys on your phone while you are out and about. Or follow Randy Pitchford on Twitter, I guess?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/how-shift-codes-gold-keys-work-borderlands-4-help-get-more-2000626107]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>