<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:17:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Our First Look At Tomb Raider’s New Lara Croft]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/heres-our-first-look-at-tomb-raiders-new-lara-croft-2000652781</link>
            <guid>1380961</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Tomb Raider</em> is back in a big way. At the 2025 Game Awards, Amazon Game Studios revealed trailers for not one, but two new, upcoming <em>Tomb Raider</em> games starring Lara Croft.</p> <p>The first game shown off during the awards show was <em>Tomb Raider: Catalyst</em>, a new adventure starring a redesigned Lara Croft that seems to have connections to the past <a href="https://kotaku.com/games/tomb-raider-definitive-survivor-trilogy"><em>Survivor Trilogy</em> version</a>.</p> <p>Here’s the trailer for <em>Catalyst</em>, which arrives sometime in 2027:</p>  <p>After revealing the new <em>Tomb Raider</em> sequel, we also got a trailer for <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-tomb-raider-game-details-leak-and-it-looks-like-a-reboot-2000652612">the previously leaked <em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em></a>, a full-on, big-budget remake of the original Tomb Raider game that appears to have connections to the <em>Survivor Trilogy</em> and <em>Catalyst.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p>Here’s the trailer for <em>Legacy of Atlantis</em>:</p>  <p>We don’t know much about Catalyst, but the remake,<em> Legacy of Atlantis,</em> is being developed in Unreal Engine 5. Here’s how Amazon describes it:</p> <blockquote><p><em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em> is a stunning reimagining of the 1996 genre-defining game. As Lara Croft, harness your wits and athleticism to explore exotic locations lost to time—from the jungles of Peru to the ancient ruins of Greece, the deserts of Egypt, and a mysterious Mediterranean island shrouded in myth. Traverse treacherous landscapes, solve deadly contraptions, and face lethal predators as you hunt for the scattered pieces of the Scion, an artifact of immeasurable power.</p></blockquote> <p>In both trailers, it seems like we are getting a more classic Lara, complete with dual pistols, confidence, and that cool move where she lifts herself up slowly while climbing on a ledge. Oh, and dinosaurs are back in <em>Legacy of Atlantis.</em> And now they have feathers. Truly, a modern spin on the classic game.</p> <p><em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em> is out in 2026. <em>Catalyst</em> is out in 2027.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/heres-our-first-look-at-tomb-raiders-new-lara-croft-2000652781]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>