<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 21:39:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s 5 Minutes Of Sony’s Next Exclusive Sci-Fi Death Trap]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/saros-sci-fi-trailer-returnal-housemarque-ps5-state-of-play-2000628274</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-5-minutes-of-sony%E2%80%99s-next-exclusive-sci-fi-death-trap.1307622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Sony opened its September State of Play with our first gameplay look at <em>Saros</em>, the next big PS5 game from <em>Returnal</em> makers Housemarque. It’s set to arrive on March 20, 2026 exclusively on PS5 and will be “enhanced” on PS5 Pro. Like <em>Returnal</em>, it’s a fast-paced third-person roguelike sci-fi shooter built around players dying over and over while getting stronger with permanent upgrades.</p> <p>Here’s the new <em>Saros</em> gameplay trailer that just premiered during State of Play. The upcoming sci-fi game stars Rahul Kohli as Arjun Devraj and looks just as wild and frenetic as <em>Returnal</em>.</p>  <p>And here’s the game’s official description:</p> <blockquote><p>Arjun Devraj, a Soltari enforcer, fights to survive on the lost colony of Carcosa under an ominous eclipse. Shape-shifting biomes and hostile ruins set the stage for a fast-paced, cinematic action experience where every encounter demands precision and adaptability. Combat unfolds as a fluid dance of dodges, shields, and parries, paired with a high-tech arsenal built of human and alien weaponry. Master enemy patterns, evolve your strategy, and face off against spectacular bosses that push every skill to the edge. Death is not the end, with permanent upgrades, evolving equipment, and the “Second Chance” system that allows you to always come back stronger.</p></blockquote> <p>PlayStation 5 owners have been wondering what 2026’s exclusive release calendar will look like, and with <em>Saros</em>, it looks like Sony is starting the year off strong with what appears to be another exciting and likely tough-as-nails third-person roguelike shooter from a team that has been consistently knocking it out of the park for three decades. Will <em>Saros</em> match the success of <em>Helldivers 2</em>, the sci-fi shooter that kicked of Sony’s 2024? Probably not, but either way, I’m excited to get my hands on <em>Saros</em> in March of next year.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/saros-sci-fi-trailer-returnal-housemarque-ps5-state-of-play-2000628274]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty‘s Large Amount Of Last-Gen Players Aren’t Holding Back Black Ops 7]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-last-gen-player-count-ps4-not-holding-black-ops-7-back-2000628253</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty%E2%80%98s-large-amount-of-last-gen-players-aren%E2%80%99t-holding-back-black-ops-7.1307523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-blops7-skins-goofy-crossover-turned-down-deals-bf6-grounded-2000628200"><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em></a> is set to launch this November. And, surprisingly, a decade after the PS4 and Xbox One’s launch, <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-price-release-date-switch-2-dev-kits-call-duty-2000617983"><em>BLOPS 7</em></a> is still arriving day one on the aging machines. According to the devs making the next entry in Activision’s blockbuster franchise, the old consoles don’t force them to hold anything back, and <em>Call of Duty </em>is still played by a “shocking” amount of people on those platforms.</p> <p><a href="https://www.dexerto.com/call-of-duty/treyarch-address-concerns-black-ops-7-was-held-back-by-last-gen-consoles-3256130/">In a new interview with <em>Dexerto</em></a>, Treyarch’s senior director of production Yale Miller and associate design director Lawrence Metten addressed fan concerns that developing<em> Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em>&nbsp;for the now 13-year-old PS4 and Xbox One was holding the game back and limiting what the studio could do on PC and current-gen hardware. According to them, that’s not the case at all.</p> <p>“The way we’ve talked about it always is, you should never be thinking about old-gen for the features that you’re designing,”&nbsp; Miller told the outlet.</p>

 <p>Instead, the team builds the game for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC, and then makes it work on the older machines. This sometimes leads to features not making it onto PS4 and Xbox One, a disappointing decision for last-gen players, but one that the studio is willing to make.</p>

 <p>“[Theater mode in <em>Black Ops 6</em> was] something that we knew we wanted to do,” said Metten. “We can’t support it on old-gen. That’s not a reason not to do the feature. We’re gonna bite the bullet and disable it on old-gen.”</p>

 <h2>Why <em>Call of Duty</em> is still launching on PS4 in 2025</h2> <p>As to why Activision is still developing <em>Call of Duty</em> games for the decade-old machines, the answer is obvious but still surprising: In 2025, there are still a lot of people playing these games on older consoles. Miller didn’t share specific numbers, but told <em>Dexerto</em> there is a “shocking number of people” playing new <em>Call of Duty</em> games on PS4 and Xbox One, and this apparently helps with matchmaking, giving them more players to work with.</p>

 <p>“It made sense for us to [bring<em> Black Ops 7</em> to last gen], and we could,” said Miler. “There are straight-up, like, graphical features and things that you just won’t see, but we feel like that doesn’t necessarily break the experience. And, obviously, there’s performance and other things that are not gonna be as good, but that’s it. It’s just players.”</p> <p>While that makes sense, I can’t help but feel like it might be time to move on, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-struggled-xbox-series-s-60-fps-switch-2-2000625487">especially as EA’s upcoming <em>Battlefield 6</em> is doing that and cutting PS4 and Xbox One loose</a>. However, while both are military shooters, they offer very different experiences and demand different things from the platforms they are available on.</p> <p>Still, if <em>CoD</em> is so scalable and flexible, I do wonder why the team isn’t, as far as we know, working on a Switch 2 port of <em>Black Ops 7.</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-dev-kits-gamescom-digital-foundry-2000620055">Perhaps they also struggled to get dev kits</a> ahead of Nintendo’s console launch earlier this year? Or maybe somewhere deep inside the massive entity that is Activision-owned studios, someone is tinkering with <em>Black Ops 7</em> on Switch 2 right now. I wouldn’t bet on it, but maybe you like to gamble?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-last-gen-player-count-ps4-not-holding-black-ops-7-back-2000628253]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Alan Wake 2 Is The Big PS Plus Game For October]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-free-october-2025-alan-wake-2-2000628251</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-alan-wake-2-is-the-big-ps-plus-game-for-october.1307496/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Sony was probably saving this announcement for the <a href="https://kotaku.com/sonys-september-state-of-play-new-rumors-and-where-to-watch-2000628219">September State of Play</a> but it’s leaked ahead of time. According to <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/cette-pepite-fera-partie-des-jeux-du-mois-doctobre-2025-du-playstation-plus-essential-60568">Dealab’s billbil-kun</a>, October’s big PS Plus game is <em>Alan Wake 2</em>.</p> <p>The survival horror GOTY contender came out two years ago next month and catapulted <em>Alan Wake</em> into the ever-expanding Remedyverse following the success of <em>Control</em> before it. The mind-warping metanarrative will be part of the Essentials tier, meaning everyone who has even the cheapest PS Plus subscription option will be able to download and play it as long as they stay paying members of the service.</p> <p><em>Alan Wake 2 </em>follows FBI agent Saga Anderson as she investigates a cult responsible for a string of murders in Bright Falls. Coming out 13 years after the original, the sequel takes place that long after the original, too, picking up where the prior game’s narrative threads left off and only getting way weirder from there. If you’re planning on giving <em>Alan Wake 2</em> a spin next month, you’ll definitely want to make sure you’ve completed the original game first.</p> <p>The first game is available to revisit via a remaster released a couple years back. The good news is it’s currently on sale <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1477-PPSA01924_00-AWREMASTERED0001">for just $5</a> on PS5 and PS4, but you only have another day to claim it at that price. The sale ends after September 25.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-free-october-2025-alan-wake-2-2000628251]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>