<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:32:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Is Reportedly Making A Crash Bandicoot Series And He Better Not Talk]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/netflix-making-crash-bandicoot-animated-series-talking-report-cartoon-2000639396</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-is-reportedly-making-a-crash-bandicoot-series-and-he-better-not-talk.1336339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A new report claims that Netflix is developing an animated <a href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873"><em>Crash Bandicoot</em></a> series. And that could be cool, Crash seems perfectly suited to a cartoon, but I do have one request: He better not talk.</p> <p>On October 27, <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/news/crash-bandicoot-animated-series-in-the-works-at-netflix/"><em>What’s On Netflix</em> reported</a> that it had heard from sources that Netflix has been quietly working on a <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> animated TV show. Plot details are being kept under wraps, but the outlet claims that WildBrain Studios is the animation team behind the yet-to-be-announced <em>Crash</em> series. This is the same studio that worked on<em> Sonic Prime</em> from 2022 to 2024. The studio has also worked on <em>Johnny Test, The Snoopy Show, </em>and <em>Carmen Sandiego.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>Crash Bandicoot first appeared in the PlayStation 1 OG 3D platformer <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> in 1996. That title was developed by Naughty Dog, long before the studio would go on to make <em>Uncharted</em> and <em>The Last of Us</em>. It then developed two more sequels and a kart racer spin-off before moving on to other projects. Meanwhile, other studios continued to make <em>Crash</em> games well into the Xbox 360 era. In 2017, Activision put out the <a href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-naughty-dog-vicarious-visions-jump-1851786482"><em>N. Sane Trilogy</em>,</a> which contained remakes of the first three PS1 games. That was followed by 2021’s <em>Crash 4: It’s About Time</em>. Following Xbox’s purchase of Activision, Crash is now owned by Xbox. Weird.</p>

  <p>Assuming this TV show happens<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->and considering <a href="https://kotaku.com/video-game-tv-show-netflix-amazon-prime-fallout-last-of-1848707788">every streaming studio is desperately spending millions of dollars</a> on making their own <a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-show-amazon-review-1851400505"><em>Fallout</em></a> or <em>Last of Us</em>-sized hit, it’s very likely<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->it will be Crash’s first original show. It won’t, however, be his first appearance on Netflix. Controversially, the platforming legend appeared in Netflix’s <em>Skylanders</em> series, sporting an Australian accent. I hate it. And a lot of Crash fans did, too. The character has normally not spoken in the games or, at most, only uttered a handful of words, like “Whoa!” or “Uh-Oh!” And that’s all he needs. Let the others do the talking. Crash should be a force of nature that causes chaos in each episode.</p> <p>Talking or no talking, this reported <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> show is likely still a ways off from being announced and released. While we wait, we can watch some footage from <a href="https://youtu.be/LVFJ49X11ck">a different animated <em>Crash Bandicoot</em> show</a> that Amazon was rumored to be working on a few years ago, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/01/rumour_looks_like_crash_bandicoots_cartoon_series_has_been_cancelled">but which was reportedly canned in 2021</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/netflix-making-crash-bandicoot-animated-series-talking-report-cartoon-2000639396]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matrix Creators Wanted Kojima To Make A Game Based On The Movie, But Konami Said No]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-wachowskis-matrix-game-movie-mgs-konami-ps2-2000-2000639384</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/matrix-creators-wanted-kojima-to-make-a-game-based-on-the-movie-but-konami-said-no.1336321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Hideo Kojima / Warner Bros. / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>25 years ago,<em>&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/what-the-matrix-resurrections-really-says-about-video-g-1848276051">Matrix</a></em> creators and directors the <a href="https://kotaku.com/i-m-sorry-to-say-laurence-fishburne-died-in-the-2005-ma-1844803953">Wachowskis</a>&nbsp;met up with <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> creator <a href="https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-metal-gear-solid-death-stranding-ai-2000636622">Hideo Kojima</a> to ask him and his team to create a video game based on the blockbuster sci-fi action film starring Keanu Reeves. Apparently, Kojima was very interested in doing it, but higher-ups at Konami passed.</p> <p><a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/10/they-were-big-fans-of-kojima-the-wachowskis-once-asked-the-metal-gear-creator-to-make-a-matrix-video-game">In a recent interview with <em>Time Extension,</em></a> former Konami Digital Entertainment vice president of licensing Christopher Bergstresser talked about the long-rumored tale that Kojima was asked to make a <em>Matrix</em> game in 2000. It seemed like it was probably true, and details about it were floating around online, but the specifics were always a mystery. But not anymore, as Bergstresser talked openly about the meeting with <em>Time Extension.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p>“The Wachowskis were big fans of Kojima,” Bergstresser told the outlet. “So (Konami producer) Kazumi Kitaue, [Hideo] Kojima, Aki Saito (who still works with Kojima), and I were at the Konami HQ, and we got a call from the Wachowskis, who wanted to come in and meet with Kojima. So they did! The two of them came in with their concept artist, and effectively they said to Kojima, ‘We really want you to do the <em>Matrix</em> game. Can you do that?’”</p>

 <p>According to Bergstresser, this question was translated for Kitaue, and his response was a blunt “No.” This was likely because Konami wanted Kojima to focus on making <em>Metal Gear Solid 2</em>, which was in the early stages of production. While this might have been disappointing for the Wachowskis, they didn’t have any hard feelings and still invited the group to <em>The</em> <em>Matrix’s</em> launch party in Japan.</p> <p>Before this interview, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hideo-kojima-speaks-about-the-matrix/1100-2448486/">there was evidence of this meeting</a>, as <em>Time Extension</em> points out. But this is the first time we’ve really heard anything about it directly from someone who was there. The outlet does claim, however, that a different Konami employee told them that this story isn’t entirely accurate. Reportedly, Kojima still showed a “strong interest” in making a <em>Matrix</em> game even after Kitaue shut it down, and many members of the <em>MGS</em> creator’s team were filled with “immense disappointment” after missing out on such an opportunity.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-wachowskis-matrix-game-movie-mgs-konami-ps2-2000-2000639384]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Card Fan Loses Collection In The Worst Way Possible]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-collection-basement-storage-insurance-2000639383</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-card-fan-loses-collection-in-the-worst-way-possible.1336294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Lost during a big move? Stolen when you’re out of town? Consumed in a tragic fire? What’s the worst way your meticulously grown <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-scalpers-mega-evolution-tiktok-2000638182">Pokémon card collectio</a>n could perish? Water damage from flooding is definitely up there. Water damage from a broken sewer line might be the absolute worst, though. That’s what recently happened to one collector who’s still trying to process what happened. “It hurts that I lost a multiple thousand dollar collection, but it really just hurts from losing all the memories,” he wrote.</p> <p>Pictures shared <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonTCG/comments/1og98du/i_lost_my_entire_collection/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=post_body&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.dexerto.com/pokemon/pokemon-tcg-collector-devastated-after-sewage-flood-destroys-thousands-in-sealed-cards-3275184/">over the weekend</a> in the Pokémon trading card Reddit community tell the grim story (via <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/pokemon/pokemon-tcg-collector-devastated-after-sewage-flood-destroys-thousands-in-sealed-cards-3275184/"><em>Dexerto</em></a>). Unopened packs of <em>Astral Radiance</em>,<em> Surging Sparks</em>, <em>Chilling Reign</em>, <em>Stellar Crown</em>, and more lay on a grey basement floor after having sat in pools of contaminated water from a broken sewer line. Their owner, Reddit user Substantial-Pie-4973, said he also lost his entire collection of opened packs as well. Some of the rarest cards spotted in his binder included a Moonbreon and Tomokazu Komiya Charmeleon,</p>

 <p>“I go to the store and get a phone call from my wife. She tells me the basement is flooding and right when I heard those words my heart dropped,” he wrote. “The sewage line busted in the basement which ruined almost all of our belongings and my entire Pokémon collection. The cards in my binders, all of my sealed/loose packs had been soaking in the sewage water for about 2-3 days from what I’m being told, but since the storage room is closed off, we did not smell or see any of the flooding.”</p>

   <p>Substantial-Pie-4973 went into the circumstances of how the collection ended up in the basement in the first place. He said he took a pay cut to help his father open a new business, and he and his wife were living at his grandparents until they could afford a new place to live. As a result, everything was sitting in cardboard moving boxes in the basement. In addition to not being aware of the leak at first, Substantial-Pie-4973 said he also recently had surgery for a hernia, delaying him from getting everything opened and sorted as soon as the mess was discovered. None of it was insured either. An absolute nightmare scenario.</p>

 <p>“Category 3 water damage can be super harmful and porous items like cards are not safely salvageable, so pretty much everything that was touched had to be thrown out,” Substantial-Pie-4973 wrote. “Getting that hit after opening so many packs, finding that product that everyone is wanting on the shelf at the store, trying to complete certain sets, etc…all gone before I felt like I could blink.”</p>

 <p>While this is as good a moment as any to remind people to 1) not store collections in basements, 2) keep everything in sealed plastic containers, and 3) get the collection added as separate item in your insurance policy, it’s also a reminder that those best practices aren’t always available to everyone all of the time. Sometimes life cuts you a break and sometimes it kicks you when you’re already vulnerable.</p> <p>If there’s one silver lining, it’s that fellow collectors are already encouraging Substantial-Pie-4973 to livestream his pulls for the remaining damaged packs and encourage others to donate to help him start rebuilding his collection. “Open the poop packs! Open the poop packs!” chanted one commenter. “It’s every collectors worst nightmare,” wrote another. “Hard to spin it in any positive way. I’m sorry you’re going through all that.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-collection-basement-storage-insurance-2000639383]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Halloween Candy, Ranked From Worst To Best]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halloween-candy-ranking-worst-best-list-chocolate-bar-1851679251</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-halloween-candy-ranked-from-worst-to-best.1336249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/easy-halloween-costume-party-1851676907">October is a spooky month</a>. It’s that time of year when everyone starts watching horror movies, <a href="https://kotaku.com/best-horror-games-october-2023-rdr2-pc-ps5-1850879972">playing scary games</a>, decorating their houses with giant skeletons, and listening to “Monster Mash” a few too many times. But on <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-not-scary-games-to-play-on-halloween-1844512015">Halloween</a> night, we remember the real reason for the season: Candy. And lots of it.</p> <p>But while any candy is better than no candy, not all of these delicious and sugary sweet treats are equal. In fact, some downright suck while others are heavenly pieces of joy wrapped and packaged in plastic. So fellow <em>Kotaku </em>writer Ethan Gach and I sat down and used a very complicated and scientific process, trust us, to rank 38 different candies to find out what is truly the best (and worst) Halloween treat around.</p> <p><strong>Update 10/27/2025:</strong> This list was originally published on October 23, 2024. We’ve updated this ranking to add even more candy to the list.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/halloween-candy-ranking-worst-best-list-chocolate-bar-1851679251]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo’s Controversial Level ‘The Library’ Is Great The Way It Is]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halo-combat-evolved-remake-the-library-2000639359</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo%E2%80%99s-controversial-level-%E2%80%98the-library%E2%80%99-is-great-the-way-it-is.1336246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>In its last few levels, 2001’s <i>Halo: Combat Evolved</i> virtually turns into a survival horror game as you battle your way through hordes of twisted, undead enemies in dimly lit corridors, pressed to make every shot count and desperate to preserve your health as you press forward. Perhaps no level in <i>Halo</i>’s storied campaign presents such a sudden change of tone and intensity as “The Library,” a long set of spacious corridors in which you first meet the sentient undead lifeform known as the Flood, and must face an almost inexhaustible supply of them while equipped with the game’s most powerful weapons.</p> <p>“The Library” has once again become topical as we look toward the release of the upcoming <i>Halo: Campaign Evolved</i>, a remake of the original Xbox launch title. Unlike the anniversary edition of the game which shipped in 2011, <i>Campaign Evolved</i> sets out to tweak existing level structures, as well as the weapon sandbox. And the level whose potential changes fans are speculating about the most is “<a href="https://kotaku.com/halos-worst-level-is-getting-changed-in-the-new-ps5-remake-2000638963">The Library</a>.”</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/halos-worst-level-is-getting-changed-in-the-new-ps5-remake-2000638963"><i>Halo</i>’s Worst Level Is Getting Changed In The New PS5 Remake</a></p> <p>That’s because “The Library” is a notorious level, widely considered a low point, a blemish on <i>Combat Evolved</i>’s otherwise outstanding campaign. But I disagree with the sentiment that “The Library” is some broken level that desperately needs remixing to fix. After recently replaying the level, I am convinced it remains a tense, brutal section of the game that tests you in everything you’ve learned about <i>Halo</i>’s combat thus far, equipping you with the skills necessary to finish the remaining levels, which only amplify the threat by tossing Covenant back in the mix with the Flood.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000639368" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639368"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639368">© Gif: Halo Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The arrival of the Flood dramatically steps up the difficulty in <i>CE</i>. After several levels spent fighting the Covenant, the introduction of these swarming parasites forces you to learn some new playstyles and find new strengths and weaknesses in each of the game’s weapons. The last few levels could’ve just been more of the same. But the Flood dramatically change the pace and scope of the game. Their introduction is when <i>Halo</i> evolves. And evolution is often painful, and full of surprises.</p>

 <p>The Flood swarm the player in vast numbers wielding <i>both </i>human and Covenant weapons; they can leap incredible distances; their melee attack is brutal; the bulbous carrier form explodes with an AOE attack and spawns in several tiny enemies which can collectively swarm you to death if you’re careless. Oh, and they can basically rise from the dead at least once, usually when you least expect it.</p>

 <p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://youtu.be/Q_nsjC8BItc">25 Years Later, <i>Halo</i> Is Finally Coming To PlayStation</a></p> <p>They’re a challenge to fight. Critically, they’re a challenge to <i>survive</i>. And that’s what makes “The Library” such an engaging level; it’s a test of endurance, knowing which fights are worth engaging in, and which ones are better left in your dust.</p>

 <h2>“The Library” is tough, but it has a logic</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639367" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639367"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639367">© Gif: Halo Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>“The Library” asks three things from you: Equip yourself well, use your enemy against you, and <i>keep moving</i>. While there are a few segments in which you’re asked to stand your ground while 343 Guilty Spark takes his sweet time to open a door, that last challenge—keep moving—is the most important of all. Standing still in “The Library” is guaranteed to lead to death, so mastering circle strafing, bunny hopping, and crouch jumping to get on to the elevated platforms is essential for maintaining distance.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/department-homeland-security-halo-ice-pokemon-video-dhs-2000639308"><i>Halo</i> Gets Sucked Into ICE’s Recruitment Meme War</a></p> <p>The Flood are nasty but they also have critical vulnerabilities, all of which “The Library” asks you to manage. Take the bulbous carrier forms which explode. Not only can their explosion work against them when they’re in a dense crowd of Flood, displacing or destroying their own comrades, but they can also trigger chain effect grenade explosions from any explosives dropped by the standard infantry. Again, the challenge is to spot those opportunities, creating more problems for your enemy than they do for you.</p>  <p>And because virtually every weapon in the game is available in the Library by way of the Flood carrying both human and alien firepower, your challenge is to keep yourself stocked. My preference is for a shotgun and plasma rifle combo, occasionally picking up a rocket launcher or needler if I feel I need to take out larger hordes.</p> <h2>In the darkness, terror</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639364" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639364"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639364">© Screenshot: Halo Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>“The Library” is ominously dark, almost bland, utilitarian. It doesn’t feel like it was made to bedazzle you, the player. It feels purpose-built by some ancient alien intelligence that wasn’t concerned with baroque, sci-fi trappings. It’s a dreary, barren set of massive corridors turned into a hellscape by the swarm of undead after you.</p>

 <p>All the while, as you fight for your life, 343 Guilty Spark’s comments on the inefficiencies of your weapons and his strange fascination with the Flood as a life form are reminiscent of Ash’s speech about the xenomorph in <i>Alien</i> being a “<a href="https://youtu.be/VA8jv1M6Y2g">perfect organism</a>.” It feels absurd, almost hilarious, how 343 is more pre-occupied with miscellaneous facts about the function of the parasitic life form than on your actual struggle as you fend off the terrifying swarm.</p> <p>I’m always reminded of <i>Alien, </i>particularly <a href="https://youtu.be/Q_nsjC8BItc">its opening scenes</a>, when I play “The Library,” with which it shares a haunting austerity and ever-present darkness. Dimly lit corridors seem to stretch on forever, revealing an indecipherable architectural language lit only by a passing flashlight.</p>

 <h2>What’s at risk of getting lost when Halo Studios changes “The Library”?</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639366" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639366"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639366">© Screenshot: Halo Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>I remain skeptical of the need to remake <i>Halo</i> at all. To be honest, I think we’re still living in an era of first-person shooters that, especially on console, was largely shaped by <i>Halo</i> to begin with. Tweaking the original <i>Halo</i> to include sprint, ADS, new weapons, and some new level layouts isn’t going to be as substantial an evolution as we saw in, say, the remake of <i>Resident Evil 2</i> a few years ago.</p> <p>What is to be gained by altering “The Library”? Does it just become a more casual stroll through an amusement park of sci-fi architecture?</p> <p>The difficulty of “The Library” speaks to the unstoppable brutality of the Flood in <i>Halo</i>’s narrative: They are such a threat, we’re told, that a previous civilization had to destroy (almost) all sentient life in the galaxy to stop them. Nothing else would do. And in surviving them, Master Chief’s heroism is equally amplified.</p>

 <p>Is <i>Halo</i> the same story if “The Library” isn’t a trip through hell? Is the Flood truly such a terrifying foe if it isn’t given the spacious emptiness of the Library to swarm around in?</p> <p>“The Library” is a demonstration, both narratively and through its challenging gameplay, of why the Flood are so feared. Pare those elements back, and <i>Halo: Campaign Evolved</i> risks being something more generic than the groundbreaking shooter it’s based on.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/halo-combat-evolved-remake-the-library-2000639359]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s Halloween Sale Is Full Of Hidden Horror Gems And Sleeper Hits]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-sale-horror-plague-tale-evil-within-signalis-2000639346</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam%E2%80%99s-halloween-sale-is-full-of-hidden-horror-gems-and-sleeper-hits.1336228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Steam is currently running its “Steam Scream IV” sale and while it’s a little light on big AAA headliners (don’t expect any <i>Resident Evil</i>s on sale, or the recent <a href="https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-review-horror-konami-hinako-ryukishi07-2000627505"><i>Silent Hill f</i></a>), there’s a solid chunk of older titles you might’ve missed, as well as dozens of cool indie games available for pocket change (actual pocket change, mind you).</p> <p>The criteria for the “Scream” sale is also quite wide, so not all of these are horror games strictly speaking, but hey, a discount’s a discount.</p> <h2>Some recent spooky(ish) games you probably forgot about</h2> <p>Okay, maybe you didn’t forget about these, but then why aren’t they in your library? Hmm? As I was perusing the latest Steam sale, I noticed more than a few recent games from a few years ago that were either a hot topic for about a week, or never hit critical mass.&nbsp;<i></i></p>

 <ul> <li aria-level="1"><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/752590/A_Plague_Tale_Innocence/"><i>A Plague Tale: Innocence</i></a> and its sequel, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1182900/A_Plague_Tale_Requiem/"><i>Requiem</i></a></li> <li aria-level="1">Bloober Team’s solid <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1092660/Blair_Witch/"><i>Blair Witch</i></a> game from 2019</li> <li aria-level="1">Bloober Team’s grim cyberpunk drama, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1386900/Observer_System_Redux/"><i>Observer: System Redux</i></a></li> <li aria-level="1">2022’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/698670/Scorn/"><i>Scorn</i></a></li> <li aria-level="1">The excellent 2023 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/482400/System_Shock/"><i>System Shock</i></a> remake</li> <li aria-level="1">Last year’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/flintlock-game-review-soulslike-ashen-difficult-1851595559">short but sweet</a> soulslike <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1832040/Flintlock_The_Siege_of_Dawn/"><i>Flintlock: The Siege of Dawn</i></a></li> <li aria-level="1">One of <a href="https://kotaku.com/still-wakes-the-deep-review-the-chinese-room-1851544587">my favorite horror games</a> from last year, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1622910/Still_Wakes_the_Deep/"><i>Still Wakes the Deep</i></a></li> </ul> <h2>Sick, unmissable indie titles</h2> <ul> <li>Vintage PSX-style spookiness with 2024’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1996010/Crow_Country/"><i>Crow Country</i></a></li> <li>The alluring, dark depths of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/813230/ANIMAL_WELL/"><i>Animal Well</i></a><i></i></li> <li><i>Heretic</i>-inspired Boomer Shooter <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/519860/DUSK/"><i>Dusk</i></a></li> <li>Strange Scaffold’s excellent, vampire-themed <i>Max Payne</i>-like <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1546310/El_Paso_Elsewhere/"><i>El Paso Elsewhere</i></a></li> <li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2475490/Mouthwashing/"><i>Mouthwashing</i></a> (<a href="https://kotaku.com/mouthwashing-steam-pc-indie-psychological-horror-1851690195">why don’t you own this one already?</a>)</li> <li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1262350/SIGNALIS/"><i>Signalis</i></a> (<a href="https://kotaku.com/signalis-survival-horror-impressions-review-pc-ps4-xbox-1849730503">why don’t you own this one already, too?</a>)</li> </ul> <h2>Dirt cheap titles that you somehow haven’t purchased yet</h2> <p>There are only 24 hours in a day. You can’t possibly play them all, but if for some reason you missed out on 2014’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/268050/The_Evil_Within/"><i>The Evil Within</i></a> or its sequel. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/601430/The_Evil_Within_2/"><i>The Evil Within 2</i></a>, they’re both on sale. The first <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/108710/Alan_Wake/"><i>Alan Wake</i></a> is a mere $1.50 right now, and its spin-off, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/202750/Alan_Wakes_American_Nightmare/"><i>American Nightmare</i>, is even cheaper</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/category/scream?offset=1186">This Steam sale is massive</a>, so there’s much more worth digging through. The sale goes until November 3, 2025.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steam-sale-horror-plague-tale-evil-within-signalis-2000639346]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>