<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:52:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Adds the Looney Tunes Sweetheart Tweety Bird to Its Valentine’s Day Deal at a Record Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-adds-the-looney-tunes-sweetheart-tweety-bird-to-its-valentines-day-deal-at-a-record-low-2000663257</link>
            <guid>1417420</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The LEGO Looney Tunes Sweetheart Tweety Bird Figure is a 412-piece kit that lets you turn the iconic yellow canary into a heart-inspired display you can pose and change up. Once you have completed the figure and used the posable head, wings, tail, and feet, you can choose to either position Tweety on the pedestal, cloud, as a matchmaker, or by removing Tweety from the base, placing the bouquet under his arm, and attaching the heart above his head so he appears to be providing a gift.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6900/">You can go to Amazon and purchase the LEGO Looney Tunes Sweetheart Tweety Bird Figure for $24, which is $11 cheaper than the original retail price of $35, and a 31% discount.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6900/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A LEGO project featuring the Looney Tunes’ most iconic bird</h2>
<p>This Valentine-themed build of Tweety offers a couple of obvious options to style the figure so it continues to interest you after you finish the build. First, you can put Tweety on the pedestal cloud, place the bow and arrow within his wings, and create a fun playfulness by posing Tweety as Cupid to fit in with Valentine’s Day on a nightstand or desk. Second, when you want to tone things down a bit, you can take Tweety off the pedestal, give him the bouquet, and place the heart on top of his head so he looks like the giver.</p>
<p>The use of posable joints allows the LEGO Looney Tunes Sweetheart Tweety Bird Figure to appear more lively than a fixed decoration that never changes position. Additionally, since the model is made from LEGO elements, you can move some pieces around if you would like to slightly change how he looks or stands, without using a specialized tool or additional components.</p>



<p>The design features and functionality of this set also enable it to serve a dual purpose as a decorative item rather than simply a one-time build that you throw in storage. The pedestal is compact, so the space required for this item will be small enough to fit on a dresser corner, a bookshelf, or an office shelf.</p>
<p>The step-by-step instructions for building the model are intended to create a fun, satisfying experience as each part goes into place. The directions start by showing you how to form the body and head of Tweety, and then proceed to the pedestal and accessories so that you see the character develop in stages. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6900/">Once the figure is placed on display, you have a charming Looney Tunes figure that you can re-position as many times as you desire, and given the fact that the item is available for $24 on sale, down from the normal $35</a>, it makes for a simple and affordable little project that’s worth building.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6900/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-adds-the-looney-tunes-sweetheart-tweety-bird-to-its-valentines-day-deal-at-a-record-low-2000663257]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even Animal Crossing Fans Can’t Escape AI Slop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-ai-slop-instagram-2000663468</link>
            <guid>1417417</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Not even the </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> community is safe from AI ensloppification.</span></p> <p><span>With the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/everything-you-need-to-know-animal-crossing-kappn-update-switch-2-2000654252"><i><span>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</span></i><span> 3.0 update</span></a><span> only a few weeks old, players have been hard at work sprucing up their islands and posting pictures of all their hard decorating work. But some have been using generative AI to “enhance” their photos or fabricate them altogether, and fans are getting pissed.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Sharing stylistic edits of </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> screenshots online is a foundational pillar of the game’s community. Photos are typically edited to enhance the game’s lighting and shadows, or put through filters to achieve a certain vibe. Photos with the best vibes are rewarded with likes, upvotes, or whatever the clout currency is for a particular social media website. However, </span><a href="https://www.polygon.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-ai-slop-aesthetic/"><i><span>Polygon </span></i><span>reports</span></a><span> that on X and elsewhere, </span><i><span>AC </span></i><span>screenshots enhanced with AI have started trending, often without disclosure that genAI was used.</span></p>

 <p><span>“I think it’s time we talk about the AI use in </span><i><span>Animal Crossing </span></i><span>aesthetic posts that are trending,” </span><a href="https://x.com/cozyberru/status/2015462841139314792?s=20"><span>wrote user Cozyberru on X</span></a><span>. In a thread, they highlight how a number of recently trending&nbsp;<em>AC</em> screenshots were likely created with genAI, pointing out the usual suspects of funky-looking numbers and warped textures on background items. But their issue isn’t so much with using the tool itself. “All I am asking is to be honest and disclose your use of AI or editing,” they wrote.</span></p>   <p><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> has thousands of little knick-knacks, pieces of furniture, and more. Not sharing that an </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> photo has been enhanced with AI can lead to confusion in players who might want to get their hands on something they don’t know has been wholly made up.</span></p>

 <p><span>In the thread, one commenter </span><a href="https://x.com/salFreeApps/status/2015536285998625106?s=20"><span>thanked Cozyberru for their service</span></a><span>. “I’ve been sitting here thinking, ‘is there a mod or hack or glitch going around that I don’t know?’ Because there’s no way to place that item that close to the furniture as much as I want to.”</span></p>

 <p><span>Cozyberru doesn’t explicitly share their feelings about genAI, but others shared theirs in the thread’s comments and elsewhere online. Though it’s not called out specifically in the rules, it seems the </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> subreddit has a strict “No genAI policy.” In a post regarding fanart, a moderator advised community members not to report anything that wasn’t </span><span>“</span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnimalCrossing/comments/1q4powt/please_stop_reporting_art_posts_as_low_quality/"><span>blatantly NSFW or AI.</span></a><span>”</span><span>&nbsp;In another post, a user reposted a video of their island after the original was </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnimalCrossing/comments/1qaz4ms/nearly_3000_hours_and_35_years_later_my_island_is/"><span>taken down for using text-to-speech AI voiceover</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-ai-slop-instagram-2000663468]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Ryzen 7 Mini PC (32GB RAM, 1TB SSD) Drops to Its Lowest Price and Is Selling Fast as a Mac Mini Alternative]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-ryzen-7-mini-pc-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-drops-to-its-lowest-price-and-is-selling-fast-as-a-mac-mini-alternative-2000663260</link>
            <guid>1417366</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Desk space is a luxury these days, especially for people working from home or studying in smaller apartments. A full-size tower PC can feel excessive when all you really need is reliable performance which you can get from something more compact. Mini PCs solve that problem neatly, and the ACEMAGIC Mini PC is a strong example of how much power can fit into a surprisingly small box. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6899/">Right now, it’s also much cheaper than usual, thanks to Amazon discounts that shave as much as $240 off select configurations.</a></p>
<p>The first thing you notice about the ACEMAGIC Mini PC is its size. It’s compact enough to sit unobtrusively on a desk, tuck onto a shelf, or mount behind a monitor. It works for students, professionals, or really anyone building a clean, minimalist workspace.</p>
<p>ACEMAGIC is offering multiple configurations to suit different needs and budgets.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
<p><strong>The entry-level option comes with 16GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD, powered by an AMD Ryzen 7 6800H processor with integrated graphics</strong>. This setup is more than capable of handling everyday tasks like web browsing, document editing, video streaming, and light creative work. It normally sells for $459, but the current discount drops the price to $329, marking a 28% savings.</p>

<p>Users who need extra power can step up to the higher-end model, which includes 32GB of RAM and a 1TB SSD. This version runs on the AMD Ryzen 7 H 255 processor and is better suited for heavier multitasking, larger and more plentiful files, and more demanding applications. Its usual $759 price tag has been cut to $519, a 32% discount that brings premium specs into a far more approachable range. Storage expansion is also supported, with room to add an additional SSD for up to 4TB total capacity.</p>
<h2>Small Stature, Big Performance</h2>
<p>In daily use, performance feels snappy and responsive. The system handles office software, photo editing, and multitasking without slowing down, particularly in the 32GB configuration. Windows 11 Pro comes preinstalled, so setup is quick and straightforward right out of the box.</p>



<p>Display options are well supported. Using USB4 Type-C or DisplayPort 2.0, it can drive an 8K display at 60Hz. An HDMI port supports 4K at 60Hz. The three together means up to three monitors can be connected at once without any extra adapters.</p>
<p>Wi-Fi 6E and Bluetooth 4.2 keep wireless connections fast and stable, while six USB 3.2 ports provide enough room for wired peripherals. Cooling is handled by dual centrifugal fans, a layered fin design, and a dedicated aluminum heatsink for the SSD, keeping noise and temperatures under control.</p>
<p>For anyone looking to reclaim desk space without giving up performance, the ACEMAGIC Mini PC is worth a look—especially with current discounts pushing the top configuration down to just $519.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-ryzen-7-mini-pc-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-drops-to-its-lowest-price-and-is-selling-fast-as-a-mac-mini-alternative-2000663260]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Goes All-In on Soundbars, HT-S400 With Wireless Subwoofer Is Even Cheaper Than AirPods]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-goes-all-in-on-soundbars-ht-s400-with-wireless-subwoofer-is-even-cheaper-than-airpods-2000663275</link>
            <guid>1417321</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Most TVs don’t come with strong built-in speakers. If your entertainment setup is missing solid sound, and you often find yourself fiddling with the volume settings and rewinding scenes just to hear what was said, it might be time for an upgrade.</p>
<p>A soundbar can be an excellent investment, and you don’t have to break the bank to pick one up today. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6898/">The Sony HT-S400 2.1ch soundbar bundle, which includes a wireless subwoofer, is currently going for $228 at Amazon, after an impressive 24% discount on its usual $300 price</a>. You’re saving $72 on an option that’s going to make movies and TV shows a lot more enjoyable by offering a truly immersive listening experience. This $228 price is also the lowest we have seen the soundbar go for in the last 30 days. Just note that the stock is already running low. We suggest placing your orders without wasting much time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6898/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Superior Sound</h2>
<p>Both the soundbar plus the subwoofer come in a minimal design, and are made to easily blend into any room. The soundbar features a flat back, so you can mount it on a wall for an even cleaner setup.</p>
<p>In terms of performance, it’s got S-Force PRO Front Surround and Dolby Digital that come together to create a 3D, cinematic style surround sound that follows you. Audio won’t be blasted from a single place but instead, fill the room in a natural way. Think whispers coming from across the couch, laughter in the air, footsteps around the room – basically, the kind of immersive sound that makes you feel like a part of whatever’s happening on the screen.</p>



<p>Then there’s the X-Balanced Speaker Unit and Separated Notch Edge, which deliver wide-ranging sound and enhanced vocal clarity for crisp dialogs. You won’t miss a word, whether the characters are mumbling to themselves or whispering a secret out. The included wireless subwoofer takes the experience even further. It has a large 160mm speaker unit to push deeper, richer bass that brings music to life. You’ll enjoy all the highs and lows exceptionally well. What’s more, there are multiple sound modes to choose from, including Sound Field, Voice Mode, and Night Mode. The Voice mode, for instance, offers clearer dialogs, while the night mode reduces the overall volume to avoid disturbing others around the house. So, just to recap – this system gets you better dialogs, richer bass, and an overall surround sound experience for all your favorite movies, TV shows, and tracks. That’s almost like bringing the cinema home!</p>
<p>Setting things up and getting started couldn’t be easier. You can connect the system to your TV with either HDMI ARC or optical connection, or other devices via Bluetooth. The OLED display window on the sound bar keeps you in the loop about information such as input source, volume, and sound settings. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6898/">There’s plenty more to like here, especially now that the soundbar, along with the subwoofer, can be yours for just $228</a>. It’s a rare drop on a highly-rated model, but it won’t last long. It’s best to grab it while the offer is still live to avoid paying full price later.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6898/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-goes-all-in-on-soundbars-ht-s400-with-wireless-subwoofer-is-even-cheaper-than-airpods-2000663275]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Batman: Legacy Of The Dark Knight: Everything We Know About The Arkham-Style Adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-dark-knight-everything-we-know-date-2000663464</link>
            <guid>1417318</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-preview-arkham-2000633994"><i><span>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight</span></i></a> <span>was one of the big surprises during last year’s </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-dark-knight-arkham-new-game-2000618481"><span>Gamescom: Opening Night Live</span></a><span> showcase. Not only is it mechanically a pretty big departure from the usual fare of Traveller’s Tales’ </span><i><span>Lego </span></i><span>games, but it also kind of seems like a follow-up to the </span><i><span>Arkham </span></i><span>games that we’ve been lacking for over a decade. The game’s still a few months away, so let’s break down everything we know so far.</span></p> <h2><b>The obvious </b><b><i>Arkham </i></b><b>influence</b></h2> <p><i><span>Legacy of the Dark Knight </span></i><span>draws heavily from Rocksteady’s </span><i><span>Batman: Arkham </span></i><span>games. Like those games, it takes place in an open-world Gotham with Bruce gliding and grappling around as he finds thugs to beat up and Riddler puzzles to solve. When he’s on the ground, the mini-figure Batman rides around on a motorcycle and in the Batmobile, and in combat, he throws almost rhythmic punches, kicks, and parries like he does in the </span><i><span>Arkham </span></i><span>games. When I played the game in October, my muscle memory for those old games kicked in pretty quick. It’s QTE-driven, which means that if you’re on top of your blocks and dodges, you can pretty much dance your way through a fight without taking a hit.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Arkham </span></i><span>fans will also recognize a few of Batman’s tools, including the explosive gel that he uses to break through walls. Overall, it looks like Traveller’s Tales is stepping up in Rocksteady’s absence.</span></p> <h2><b>Playable characters</b></h2> <p><span>Like most </span><i><span>Lego </span></i><span>games, </span><i><span>Legacy of the Dark Knight </span></i><span>is a co-op game. One player will play as Batman, while the other can play as multiple characters from a rotating roster of partners. The ones we know of include Catwoman, Jim Gordon, Nightwing, Robin, and Talia al Ghul. Each of them will have a special ability, which will sometimes be necessary to progress through a level. Gordon, for example, has a foam gun which can be used to block obstacles in Batman’s way. If you don’t have someone to play with, you can swap between characters on the fly to use these abilities.</span></p>

 <h2><b>An homage to the many Batmen that came before</b></h2> <p><i><span>Legacy of the Dark Knight </span></i><span>seems to pay tribute to multiple versions of Batman from movies, animation, and of course, comic books. Some notable cameos we’ve seen in the trailer include characters from the Christopher Nolan, Tim Burton, and Matt Reeves films, and no matter what version of </span><i><span>Batman</span></i><span> is your favorite, you’ll probably see it celebrated here. The idea is that you’ll be playing through a blocky version of Batman’s life, drawing from different iterations but telling the general story of how he went from sad orphan boy to sad orphan man who beats up people in dark alleyways. We’ll surely see cameos from different characters, such as the rest of the Bat Family, his butler Alfred, and maybe members of the Justice League and League of Assassins. Plus, we know we’ll see plenty of Batman’s iconic villains, such as the Joker, Bane, the Penguin, and Poison Ivy.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Release date and system info</b></h2> <p><i><span>Lego Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight </span></i><span>is coming to PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S on May 29, with a Switch 2 version expected later in the year.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-dark-knight-everything-we-know-date-2000663464]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BLUETTI Mini Portable Power Station Drops Below Black Friday Prices, Now an Affordable Emergency Backup for Outages]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bluetti-mini-portable-power-station-drops-below-black-friday-prices-now-an-affordable-emergency-backup-for-outages-2000663272</link>
            <guid>1417300</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Power stations make it easy to keep your important devices, as well as essential home appliances, running during outages and off-road trips. If you’re concerned about a winter storm affecting the electricity supply in your area, or just want a reliable backup power solution for your outdoor adventures, a power station can come in handy.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6897/">Now is a great time to pick up a portable option, as Amazon is offering the Bluetti Elite 10 mini at a 43% discount today.</a> You can pick it up for just $113, after saving a nice $86 on its retail price. This offer applies to both grey and meadow green versions of the power station. The only thing to note here is that the offer is only around for a limited time. We highly suggest grabbing it sooner rather than later if you want to avoid paying the full price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6897/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Easy to Carry</h2>
<p>This power station is truly portable. It fits in your palm, weighs just 4.0 lbs, and features an ergonomic handle that makes the thing incredibly easy to carry around. In fact, it fits within the size guidelines of most airlines, so you can take it with you on flights, too.</p>
<p>As for the power, the Elite 10 is a 128Wh option that’s equivalent to 4 regular power banks. You’re getting a 200W AC outlet, 100W USB-C fast charging, and multiple DC ports to keep multiple devices charged and running. The capacity is more than enough to charge your smartphone more than 6 times and juice a laptop to full twice. You can even power a mini fridge for around 1.8 times, or keep a projector running for a bit. It plays nicely with a wide range of devices, so whether it’s your tech essentials that need a boost or some emergency lights requiring power, it supports them all.</p>



<p>The Elite 10 mini includes a built-in light with three lighting modes with up to 50 hours of illumination, too. These include warm, cool, and SOS, which is handy in low-light situations and emergencies. You can control the power station right through your phone using the dedicated app. It lets you keep an eye on the charging situation, choose light modes, adjust input, and more.</p>
<p>When it comes to recharging the power station itself, you can power it back up in three ways. The first is 150W AC charging, which helps it hit 100% in just over an hour. The 100W solar charging (best to pair with Bluetti 60W/100W panels), and 100W car charging via cigarette lighter are supported too. What’s even better is that the Elite 10 mini comes with a built-in 10ms UPS and features 350W bypass output, which can keep gadgets running without interruption during outages.</p>
<p>Included in the box are the Bluetti Elite 10 mini power station itself, an AC charging cable, a car charging cable, and a user manual. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6897/">You can pick this portable, easy-to-use, but powerful option for $113 at Amazon.</a> This is nothing considering the ease of mind and convenience this appliance brings. Be sure to get your orders in fast, as the deal can wrap up any moment now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6897/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bluetti-mini-portable-power-station-drops-below-black-friday-prices-now-an-affordable-emergency-backup-for-outages-2000663272]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>