<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:14:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Splinter Cell Show Trailer Seems To Pick A Canon Ending For Chaos Theory]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-splinter-cell-trailer-netflix-deathwatch-chaos-theory-ending-john-wick-2000626077</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-splinter-cell-show-trailer-seems-to-pick-a-canon-ending-for-chaos-theory.1299720/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The official trailer for Netflix and Ubisoft’s upcoming animated series, <a href="https://kotaku.com/splinter-cell-deathwatch-anime-netflix-2000619516"><em>Splinter Cell: Deathwatch</em></a>, gives us a much better look at this new version of Sam Fisher and lets us hear more of Liev Schreiber as the aging operative. And while I was nervous at first, I now feel confident that Schreiber can pull this off. Now let’s just hope the show itself is good, too.</p> <p>On September 16, Ubisoft released the <a href="https://youtu.be/4A9iFjaKeMk">official trailer for <em>Splinter Cell: Deathwatch</em></a>. The new animated show adapts Ubisoft’s popular stealth-action video game franchise into an episodic series that will premiere on Netflix exclusively on October 14. Here’s the trailer, which features Sam Fisher doing what you expect: sneaking around, wearing cool goggles, killing people with wire, and being cranky about stuff.</p>  <p>We get to hear more of Liev Schreiber’s take on Sam Fisher, and while it is different than the version established by Michael Ironside, I appreciate that he still sounds like an old guy who is about to snap at any point, and if he does, God help anyone caught in his way. While I’ll miss Ironside, who voiced the character in the original games, I’m happy that Sam is in good hands. <a href="https://kotaku.com/original-splinter-cell-being-remade-by-far-cry-6-devs-1848221698">And honestly, I’m just excited to get more <em>Splinter Cell</em> in any form</a>.</p>

 <p>In this new trailer, we learn more about what this show is actually about.&nbsp; After a younger agent, Zinnia, gets her hands on some valuable intel, she comes to Sam Fisher for help. This brings Fisher into a mission that involves <a href="https://splintercell.fandom.com/wiki/Douglas_Shetland">Douglas Shetland, a villainous character</a> and former friend from the<em> Splinter Cell: Pandora Tomorrow </em>and <em>Chaos Theory</em> games. His daughter is all grown up and running what appears to be an evil corporation of some kind. Uh oh!</p> <p>Interestingly, in the trailer, <a href="https://youtu.be/8c-Jshz9PVc">we briefly see the ending of <em>Chaos Theory,</em></a> with Sam and Douglas standing with guns pointed at each other. It also seems like this series makes it canon that Sam Fisher shot Shetland. In the game, it was a choice between shooting him and not shooting him. If you didn’t pull the trigger, Shetland would shoot at Sam, forcing him to dodge Shetland’s attack before stabbing and killing him. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/splinter-cell-deathwatch-trailer-poster-derek-kolstad-interview#:~:text=So%20is%20Splinter,fits%20the%20mold.%E2%80%99%E2%80%9D">It’s not 100% clear yet if <em>Deathwatch</em> is canon with the games</a>, but if it is, I wonder what else the show will introduce into the franchise’s (surprisingly) sprawling lore.</p> <p><em>Splinter Cell: Deathwatch </em>is being written and produced by <em>John Wick</em> writer Derek Kolstad. It will be available on Netflix on October 14.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-splinter-cell-trailer-netflix-deathwatch-chaos-theory-ending-john-wick-2000626077]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape From Tarkov On Steam Will Require A Separate Purchase]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/escape-from-tarkov-1-0-arena-steam-epic-unheard-edition-2000626063</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-on-steam-will-require-a-separate-purchase.1299651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i>Escape from Tarkov</i>, arguably one of the most hardcore extraction shooters out there, is finally making its way to Steam. The game has previously lived in perpetual beta status, but now the highly anticipated 1.0 release is expected this November. You can’t buy it on Steam just yet, though the listing is up and you can wishlist it. But, as some are learning, if you have already been a long-time <i>Tarkov</i> player and are hoping to consolidate your game library under Valve’s launcher or make use of Steam’s social features, you won’t just be able to download the game on Steam and connect your Battlestate Games account. You’ll have to pay for the game a second time.</p> <p>Like with many things involving <i>Tarkov</i>, this is all a little confusing, if not intimidating. So let’s break it down.</p> <p>The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3932890/Escape_from_Tarkov/">Steam page for <i>EFT</i></a> went public today, with a release date of “coming soon.” Meanwhile, a FAQ on <i>EFT</i>’s official website lists <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/support/knowledge/542">some potentially disappointing news for some</a>: “To play <i>Escape from Tarkov</i> through Steam, you will need to link a Battlestate Games account to your Steam account.” This is hardly unique to <i>EFT</i>’s arrival on Steam, as other games, such as <i>Final Fantasy XIV</i> and, more recently, <i>Star Wars Outlaws</i>, that have previously launched elsewhere and later come out on Steam typically have not supported a “cross-buy” situation. Still, this news has left a sour taste for many, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EscapefromTarkov/comments/1niiife/comment/nej0yg3/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">fans chiming in</a> <a href="https://x.com/OnlyBeysYT/status/1967968457682817456">on social media</a> to suggest the game is likely to get review bombed upon release and that it just feels silly, greedy even.</p>

 <p>The same FAQ page states that if you previously purchased <a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/purchase">any of the more expensive versions</a> of the game, a newly purchased Steam copy “will automatically use the higher edition of the two when launching the game” once you’ve linked your accounts. So, technically speaking, if playing on Steam is a must, and you’ve purchased a more expensive version of <i>EFT</i> in the past, you should only buy the base edition on Steam when it goes live.</p> <p>The Steam FAQ page also contains some other potentially upsetting information: There are currently no plans for <i>EFT</i> to support the Steam Deck and Family Sharing is a no-go. Plus, the system requirements, as seen on the Steam page, are pretty steep. Recommended specs include 64GB (!!) of RAM and a 4070.</p>

 <p><i>Escape from Tarkov</i>’s main extraction mode will finally emerge from beta status on November 15, 2025, after nearly a decade in development. But it’s not the only mode that <i>EFT</i> has on offer.</p>  <p>As an extraction shooter, <i>Tarkov</i> features PvP elements that see both bots and players on a live multiplayer map, though the main game loop is all about getting in, looting, surviving, and extracting. Two years ago, however, BSG released <i>EFT: Arena</i> as a standalone solution for those who wanted to experience the tactical shooter in a competitive environment. Though <i>Arena</i> uses the same <i>EFT</i> account to share rank and stats, and is available for purchase individually on the Epic Games Store right now, this mode does not have a Steam listing.</p> <p>So while needing to buy the game a second time if you desperately need to play might be a bummer, it’s worth noting that you <i>can</i> just add non-Steam games to the Steam launcher. That said, given that you’ll still need a BSG account and your previous purchases of the more expensive editions will carry over, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EscapefromTarkov/comments/1niiife/discussion_tarkov_has_a_steam_page_now/">some are wondering</a> why BSG can’t just allow the base version to carry over with a download of the launcher through Steam.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/escape-from-tarkov-1-0-arena-steam-epic-unheard-edition-2000626063]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Devs Were Extremely Focused On Optimization And Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-framerate-fps-xbox-series-s-ps5-2000626043</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-devs-were-extremely-focused-on-optimization-and-performance.1299609/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/oh-thank-god-the-battlefield-6-open-beta-is-back-2000617797">After playing <em>Battlefield 6′</em>s open beta last month,</a> I was impressed by how well it performed on console. And footage of the beta running on an <a href="https://youtu.be/gLqxhWuli3Y">Nvidia 1060 GPU</a>, a nearly decade-old card at this point, further impressed me. So when I recently talked to some of the devs about <em>BF6</em>, I was curious how the team made it run so well, and they explained it was about not pushing consoles too hard and always optimizing during development.</p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-controversial-quick-turn-flick-console-why-cheating-2000625445">During my video call with <em>Battlefield 6</em>&nbsp;technical director Christian Buhl</a>, I asked if he felt like the current generation of consoles was tapped out and needed to be replaced or if they still had some performance to squeeze out of them. He told <em>Kotaku</em> that while he always feels like “there’s more room to improve performance,” he doesn’t expect devs to “double frame rates” in future PS5 and Xbox Series X/S games at this point. And with <em>Battlefield 6</em>, the studios working on it weren’t even trying to push these consoles to some theoretical breaking point. Instead, the goal was always to make an online FPS that ran very well.</p> <p><span>“We also were intentionally not trying to push super hard on [PS5/Xbox Series X/S,]” said Buhl. “We didn’t want to push to the edge and fail. We wanted to make sure that we had an experience that we could optimize, that we could get to the point where it was going to run reliably at 60 frames per second, or, you know, over 80, whatever settings you preferred. And that was our focus, right? Like, get stuff in there, get it performant, and then add [more].”&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p>Buhl admitted that in the past, developers working on <em>Battlefield</em> games had a different approach. Often teams would “build a bunch of cool shit and then try to make it work.” This time around, that wasn’t the case, and Buhl told me that during development, <em>Battlefield 6</em> had to “<span>constantly be working; it had to constantly be performant.” </span></p> <p><span>“Obviously, it’s not like we’re 100 percent hitting our targets throughout development. But every time we [dropped] too low, we put performance optimization efforts in place, paused work, [and said], ‘You can’t add stuff until we get this optimized,'” explained Buhl. “</span><span>So that we could kind of make sure that at the end, we weren’t trying to do this giant lift of taking it from 30 frames to 60 frames, or something like that. We were taking it from, like, 55 to 60, right? And that’s a much more feasible effort.”</span></p>

 <h2>The ongoing debate around video game performance</h2> <p><em>Battlefield 6</em> on consoles does still use upscaling tech. Buhl confirmed to <em>Kotaku</em> that on PS5 and PS5 Pro the game uses PSSR. And on all consoles, FSR is available too. But it’s clear the devs were focused intently during development on shipping a game that ran well no matter where you played it, even if that meant cutting back visuals or effects.</p> <p>The topic of video game optimization has become a hot one following the release of <em>Borderlands 4</em> last week. Many claim the highly anticipated looter shooter is poorly optimized on PC and console, with players complaining about having to use low settings and DLSS to run the game on beefy rigs. For a point of comparison, <em>BF6</em> is pretty playable on a 1060. <a href="https://youtu.be/UnTB3AkNkno"><em>Borderlands 4</em> is very much not.</a> That card is below the minimum PC specs for both games.</p>

 <p>In my experience on both PS5 and PC, <em>Borderlands 4′</em>s performance has definitely disappointed me. Especially on PS5, where some others and I have run into an issue where the game’s framerate drops lower and lower as you play longer and longer. Gearbox CEO Randy Pitchford has pushed back on these criticisms, claiming the game is very well optimized for what it is and has suggested some players need to lower settings. And if you aren’t happy, you can just <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/borderlands/borderlands-4-boss-tells-players-please-get-a-refund-from-steam-if-you-arent-happy-as-randy-pitchford-continues-his-very-public-crashout-over-the-fpss-performance-woes/">return the game and get your money back</a>.</p> <p><em>Battlefield 6</em> is out on October 10 on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. EA told me the game will support 60FPS on all platforms, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-struggled-xbox-series-s-60-fps-switch-2-2000625487">even Xbox Series S,</a> and on some machines, like the PS5 Pro, the game can exceed that framerate.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-framerate-fps-xbox-series-s-ps5-2000626043]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>