<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 18:56:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Producer Laughed And Said No When Asked If Pragmata Is A Secret Mega Man Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/capcom-pragmata-mega-man-conspiracy-theory-debunked-2000621414</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-producer-laughed-and-said-no-when-asked-if-pragmata-is-a-secret-mega-man-game.1284348/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For many months now, some fans online have suggested that <a href="https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849">Capcom’s upcoming sci-fi adventure <em>Pragmata</em></a> is actually a secret<em> Mega Man r</em>eboot. However, <em>Pragmata’s</em> producer says it is not, even laughing about the conspiracy theory when recently asked about it.</p> <p>Fans and content creators online have spread this theory around for a while. Many point out that <em>Pragmata’s</em> cybergirl sidekick, Diana, shares a lot of design elements with Mega Man<em>,</em> with her coat lending her the robot’s signature color and her arm expanding during some moments in a way reminiscent of the Blue Bomber’s oversized blaster arm. There’s also the game’s narrative setup, which involves evil robots. <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/capcom-settles-it-no-pragmata-isnt-a-secret-mega-man-game/">But, in a recent interview with&nbsp;<em>VGC</em></a><em>,</em> <em>Pragmata’s</em> producer Naoto Oyama completely denied this theory.</p> <p>“<em>Pragmata</em> is not a <em>Mega Man</em> game,” said Oyama. <em>VGC</em> also reports he was laughing as he answered the question. He then added, “It is a completely new game from Capcom.</p>

 <p>“I was actually one of the producers on the <em>Mega Man Battle Network Legacy Collectio</em>n as well, so I’m happy to see that people who love <em>Mega Man</em> are passionate about <em>Pragmata</em> too,” Oyama told the outlet. “From my standpoint, it’s nice to see people are being so positive about it.”</p> <p>So that seems like a definitive no. However, I expect some fans will claim that Capcom is lying. That, <em>of course</em>, they won’t confirm <em>Pragmata’s</em> connection to <em>Mega Man</em>. It’s supposed to be a big secret, so Capcom will deny it until <em>Pragmata</em> launches sometime in 2026. (<a href="https://kotaku.com/capcom-pragmata-delay-delayed-2023-2024-ps5-xbox-pc-1850531732">Remember when this game was revealed in 2020 and was supposed to be out in 2022?</a>)</p>

 <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="PRAGMATA – Announcement Trailer, Extended Cut | Next Gen (2022)" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZJxXPZGmTzY?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>However, I’d argue that Capcom knows how much people want new<em> Mega Man</em> games, and if they were making one, they’d be shouting about it from the rooftops. Also, keep in mind that Capcom isn’t above referencing and hinting at other games in their new IPs. <a href="https://kotaku.com/exoprimal-dino-crisis-reboot-sequel-dinosaur-shooter-ca-1849066060">We saw this happen with <em>Exoprimal</em></a>, which many fans were convinced was a <em>Dino Crisis</em> game. And to fans’ credit, Capcom did include a woman with red hair in a debut trailer for the game about dinosaurs. So I’m not surprised there’s some <em>Mega Man</em> inspiration in <em>Pragmata</em>. Capcom really needs people to remember this game exists and care about it in 2026. And what better way to do that than by sprinkling a few references to something much more popular and hoping the fans take the bait.</p> <p>Anyway, even if <em>Pragmata</em> isn’t a <em>Mega Man</em> game (and I really don’t think it is), the game sounds like it might be an interesting throwback to the kind of linear action games we got back in the 2010s on Xbox 360 and PS3. <a href="https://kotaku.com/pragmata-capcom-preview-summer-game-fest-impressions-1851784342">Here’s what our own Kenneth Shepard thought about it when he played it earlier this year</a>:</p> <blockquote><p><em>Pragmata&nbsp;</em>feels a bit like a game out of time, as its gruff old man protagonist, slow-moving enemies, and brutalist sci-fi aesthetic are all evocative of the over-the-shoulder shooters from the PS360 era. Given those seemingly bygone qualities, it’d be easy for&nbsp;<em>Pragmata&nbsp;</em>to feel rote and dated, but what I played was just inventive enough to feel novel. I was super impressed with it.</p></blockquote>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/capcom-pragmata-mega-man-conspiracy-theory-debunked-2000621414]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Now Requiring Steam Users Verify Their Age In The UK]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/valve-now-requiring-steam-users-verify-their-age-in-the-uk-2000621392</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-now-requiring-steam-users-verify-their-age-in-the-uk.1284273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Valve’s extremely popular PC gaming store Steam is now requiring users in the United Kingdom to <a href="https://kotaku.com/roblox-child-account-safety-settings-danger-1851680045">verify their age</a> using a credit card. This is a direct result of the UK’s controversial Online Safety Act.</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-steam-users-must-now-verify-age-to-access-store-pages-for-mature-games-thanks-to-online-safety-act">As of August 29, as spotted by <em>Eurogamer</em></a>, it looks like Valve is now requiring that all users in the United Kingdom verify how old they are before they will be able to access mature video games. <a href="https://help.steampowered.com/en/faqs/view/292B-3DA3-CFC8-97F6">Valve has also updated its official Steam Support website</a> with new information about age verification, telling UK users that “in order to access Steam store pages for mature content games,” they’ll need to go through an “opt-in process” that requires age verification via credit card. Going through this process will “trigger a £0 authorization” on the card to check if it’s active and real.</p> <p>Valve says that as long as the credit card stored on the Steam account is valid, the account is considered “age verified.” So you should only have to do this once. Hopefully.</p> <p>According to the updated Steam Support website, Valve “reviewed” all age verification methods and determined that using a credit card preserved “the maximum degree of user privacy” compared to some other sites and services that use AI-powered facial scanning tech.</p> <p>“The data processed in the verification process is identical to that of the millions of other Steam users who make purchases or store their payment details for convenience,” explained Valve on the website. “The verification process therefore provides no information about a user’s content preferences to payment providers or other third parties. Valve handles the verification process using its own internal payment processing system, which is independently certified under the PCI-DSS standard.”</p>

 <p>Also on the site, when explaining why this new verification process is being forced upon users, Valve directly and politely lays the blame on the UK’s new online safety laws and Ofcom, the nation’s independent regulator for online safety.</p> <p>Valve isn’t the first video game company to run into issues with the UK’s Online Safety Act, which has placed large, <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/08/no-uks-online-safety-act-doesnt-make-children-safer-online">controversial restrictions and regulations</a> on how people under 18 can access the internet. In July, <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/07/28/xbox-age-verification-uk/">Xbox began rolling out its own age verification process</a> in the United Kingdom. <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/support/account/age-verification-faq/#:~:text=We%20are%20piloting%20an%20age%20verification%20process%20for%20players%20who%20register%20for%20new%20accounts%20in%20the%20UK%20and%20Ireland.%20If%20you%20are%20setting%20up%20an%20adult%20account%2C%20you%20will%20be%20asked%20to%20provide%20proof%20that%20you%20are%20over%20the%20minimum%20age%20for%20that%20type%20of%20account%20using%20an%20age%20verification%20service.">Sony is “rolling out”</a> an age verification process in the&nbsp; UK, too.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/valve-now-requiring-steam-users-verify-their-age-in-the-uk-2000621392]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>