<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:32:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JBL Is Practically Giving Away the Go 3 Speaker at an All-Time Low, Even Throwing In 90 Days of Amazon Music for Free]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jbl-is-practically-giving-away-the-go-3-speaker-at-an-all-time-low-even-throwing-in-90-days-of-amazon-music-for-free-2000648983</link>
            <guid>1369270</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Sure, you can use your phone and tablet can play music, but can any of these provide an immersive, room-filling listening experience with punchy bass and clear lows? That’s debatable. If you’re looking to enjoy bold sound on the go, grabbing a portable speaker makes sense.</p>
<p>Well, thanks to Cyber Monday, bagging one doesn’t have to cost an arm and a leg. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6131/">Right now, Amazon is offering a 25% discount on the JBL Go 3, a mini Bluetooth speaker, which drops its price down to $30</a>. It’s a modest $10 drop, and you’ll also enjoy three months of Amazon Music for absolutely free with your purchase. Even better, several color options are up for grabs for less, so there’s plenty to choose from. Maybe go with the black version if you’re looking for something basic, or pick the stunning red model up to make a statement.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6131/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Bold, Room-Filling Sound</h2>
<p>It comes in an ultra-portable design. The speaker looks like a tiny power bank and features an integrated loop that makes it easy to carry around. Clip it onto your bag, or just slip a finger through and get going. Durability comes from its IP67 waterproof and dustproof rating, protecting the speaker from the not-so-ideal weather and environmental conditions. Take it to the beach, a picnic, by the pool, or even in the washroom; a few splashes or drops in the dirt won’t hurt it. It keeps the music going, regardless.</p>
<p>Despite the tiny size, the sound it packs is seriously impressive. You’ll enjoy the legendary JBL signature audio that’s deep and rich. It captures both the highs and the lows well, keeping distortions at bay. Punchy bass makes you feel your favorite tunes down to the bones for an even more immersive experience. Whether you’re using it to catch up on your favorite podcast or listening to the latest Imagine Dragons album, vocals come through with clarity, and every beat is heard. This also makes the speaker great for streaming your favorite shows with friends!</p>



<p>Battery-wise, you’re looking at around 5 hours of playtime on a single charge. It’s not that massive, but still decent for on-the-go sessions and at-home gatherings. Recharging is fast, too, so the speaker should be back at it in no time. Compatibility is impressive, as the JBL Go 3 works with just about any Bluetooth-enabled device, from smartphones to laptops, computers, tablets, and more. A three-month free trial of the Amazon Music Unlimited Individual Plan provides instant access to millions of songs and podcasts. You can shuffle play artists or albums, create your own playlists, download All-Access Playlists for offline jamming, and even get one free audiobook per month from Audible. The offer will be applied automatically to your account after you make your purchase successfully. You need to redeem it within 30 days. After the 90-day trial, your subscription will continue at the monthly price of $12, if you choose to keep it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6131/">All in all, now is a great time to grab the JBL Go 3 mini Bluetooth speaker. You won’t just be saving 25% on the speaker, but also get to enjoy Amazon Music for free for 90 days</a>. There are multiple color options to choose from, as well. The discount, like many other Cyber Monday deals, is going to expire tonight. If you’ve been thinking of grabbing a solid audio solution for less for yourself or to gift it to a loved one this holiday season, now is the time to make the move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6131/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/jbl-is-practically-giving-away-the-go-3-speaker-at-an-all-time-low-even-throwing-in-90-days-of-amazon-music-for-free-2000648983]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards Is Hyping A Satanic Statue That Randomly Appeared In The Desert]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/geoff-keighley-desert-statue-tga-diablo-4-2000649133</link>
            <guid>1369198</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I may be born and raised in this fine city of New York, but oh do I love the desert. Strange, unexplainable stuff happens out there, what with the aliens, supernatural beings, drugs, or, in this case, video game promotional material that is sure to have confused some unfortunate soul wandering the dunes at night.</p> <p>Over the weekend, Geoff Keighley posted his most cryptic teaser yet for the upcoming Game Awards show on December 11, 2025. Featuring an image of a creepy-looking stone statue of skeletons in the middle of the desert, folks were quick to realize that the Keighley’s caption, “regal.inspiring.thickness,” was actually an address using the <a href="https://what3words.com/clip.apples.leap">What3words geocode service</a>.</p>

 <p>It uses randomized words to quickly pinpoint virtually any location on the surface of the planet. Those three words took internet sleuths to a&nbsp; location in the Mojave desert where there’s presently a wild-looking statue.</p> <p>Keighley’s initial post only showed part of the wild-lookin’ statue. Those who were in the neighborhood, however, were able to get up close and personal and, well, it’s certainly fuel for some interior decorating that my roommate surely won’t appreciate. Check it out:</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Game Awards Monolith at night <a href="https://twitter.com/thegameawards?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@thegameawards</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffkeighley?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@geoffkeighley</a> <a href="https://t.co/Tcdk9xmUYc">pic.twitter.com/Tcdk9xmUYc</a></p> <p>— 𝑳𝑨𝑽𝑨 (@lava037) <a href="https://twitter.com/lava037/status/1994957660161282393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>That’s it at night, where it lights up like I wish Christmas trees would, all red and devilish, beckoning for you to surrender your soul for the promise of power. Here it is during the day:</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="qme" dir="ltr"> <a href="https://t.co/An38ClGFcY">pic.twitter.com/An38ClGFcY</a></p> <p>— Triodug (@TotallyNOTTrio) <a href="https://twitter.com/TotallyNOTTrio/status/1994843918786335123?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The ominous statue looks like a gateway to hell made out of countless skeletons cobbled together and a spidery-lookin’ eyeball thing right in the center above some small steps. Someone must have paid a lot to have it commissioned and dropped off in the middle of nowhere.</p>

 <p>Keighley has been on a little mini reign of terror lately, sharing all kinds of <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1991907624951136477">cryptic tweets</a> that have tortured the poor denizens of various <i>Half-Life</i> subreddits. Some began wondering if the statue was a tease for the next <i>God of War</i> or some completely new franchise.</p> <p>But, based on reporting <a href="https://x.com/JezCorden/status/1995065300539347395">from <i>Windows Central</i></a>, the Mojave desert stunt might actually be teasing the next big expansion for <i>Diablo 4</i> and not some mysterious death metal spin on the Electric Sun Desert Music Festival. Shucks.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/geoff-keighley-desert-statue-tga-diablo-4-2000649133]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Slashes Its 15.6″ Copilot AI Laptop (32GB RAM, 1TB SSD) by 80% in an Amazon-Exclusive Cyber Monday Blowout]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dell-slashes-its-15-6-copilot-ai-laptop-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-by-80-in-an-amazon-exclusive-cyber-monday-blowout-2000648978</link>
            <guid>1369195</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There’s never been a better time to grab tech essentials that feel a little out of reach the rest of the year. We’re talking PCs, gaming monitors, premium laptops, top-rated tablets, solid headphones, and even external storage solutions. Cyber Monday sales have slashed prices across all these categories and more, making today a great time to finally treat yourself to what you’ve been eyeing for long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6130/">Those looking to grab a new Windows laptop; we’ve got great news. The 15-inch Dell touchscreen laptop just dropped by 80% on Amazon</a>. It typically sits at a not-so-friendly tag of $4,500, but this deal lets you bring one home for just $900, though it’s limited to Prime users. And as if the discount wasn’t enough, the retailer is also throwing in a bunch of freebies worth $100 with your purchase. Of course, as you’d expect, the discount is only around for a short period of time. Since today is technically the last day of this week-long sale that started before Black Friday officially kicked off, you only have a few more hours left to grab it. Be quick to avoid last-minute rush and disappointments.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6130/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Powerful Processor for All Your Tasks</h2>
<p>At just 4.2 lbs and under 0.7 inches thin, it’s a lightweight laptop that slides into any bag without adding bulk and goes with you wherever you do, with ease. There’s nothing too crazy going on with the design, which gives off a professional, premium look that blends into any workspace without drawing too much attention to itself. Open it up, and you’re greeted with a spacious 15.6-inch Full HD (1920×1080) WVA touchscreen. It pushes vibrant, clear visuals consistently, whether you’re sitting in a dimly lit room or out there in the sun. Touch support makes navigation easy, letting you use your fingers to swipe, scroll, draw, and even type when you’re not in the mood to press some buttons.</p>
<p>The screen is paired with a comfortable keyboard, which features a lift-hinge design for better wrist support. There’s a numeric keypad on the side; great for those of you who need to work with numbers on a regular basis. Battery life is just as impressive. On a full charge, you can go up to 8 hours without plugging it in. Recharging doesn’t take forever, either, as the machine hits 80% in just about an hour.</p>



<p>Power-wise, Dell has packed the laptop with the 10-core 13th Gen Intel Core i7-1355U processor, which holds up well during both everyday and resource-intensive tasks. Multitaskers will appreciate the massive 32GB RAM. It keeps slowdowns at bay, even during busy days that require you to do a whole bunch of tasks using different applications at once. For storage, there’s a 1TB SSD built right in. You’ll be able to house all that you own, plus enjoy ultra-fast boot and load times. Ports are plenty, so connecting peripherals won’t be a problem. Speaking of peripherals, the accessory kit comes with a Redragon wireless keyboard and mouse combo, for absolutely free.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6130/">On a regular day, this laptop would run you around $4,500, but Prime members can grab it for just $900 right now</a>. Non-Prime members will still see it at its retail price as of now. It offers a nice blend of performance, portability, and a stable battery, which makes it great for work professionals, creatives, students, and even casual users. It’s a Cyber Monday deal, so it’s only valid for today. Act fast to snap it up before it’s too late.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6130/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dell-slashes-its-15-6-copilot-ai-laptop-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-by-80-in-an-amazon-exclusive-cyber-monday-blowout-2000648978]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Person Is Buying Every 1st Edition Kabuto Pokémon Card And Resellers Are Fighting Back]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-kabuto-first-edition-viral-card-2000649100</link>
            <guid>1369192</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A Kabuto 1st edition card wearing a crown.</span> © The Pokémon Company / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>During these revolting times, what we need are heroes. Step forward one such person, offering a bright light of hope into our murky days: the Kabuto King. This anonymous figure (because all the best superheroes are) appeared from nowhere in August this year, with a single and singular goal: to collect every first edition Kabuto card from the <em>Pokémon</em> <em>TCG</em>‘s Fossil set. He’s currently at 1,748.</p> <p>Why? Because no one else did yet.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">New Kabutos: 30<br>Total Kabuto Count: 1748</p> <p>The show goes on 👑 <a href="https://t.co/saoScQIslC">pic.twitter.com/saoScQIslC</a></p> <p>— Kabuto King (@KabutoKing_) <a href="https://twitter.com/KabutoKing_/status/1994810431442227615?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>It’s not uncommon for&nbsp;<em>Pokémon</em> collectors to try to find one of every card of a favourite pocket monster. I, for instance, have collected one of every English-language Mantine and am working on the Japanese versions now. But most people tend to stick to one of <em>each</em>, rather than every single one of the same card. That is Kabuto King’s goal: gathering the cards in any condition, graded or loose, in their thousands, with the intention of buying up every single one.</p>

 <p>What makes the Kabuto King’s quest quite so excellent is that Kabuto is…look, I’m not setting out to offend anyone, but it’s hardly the most glamorous of Pokémon. Not one of Ken Sugimori’s most inspired designs, the creature first introduced in the original <em>Pokémon</em> games is essentially just a brown horseshoe crab with glowy red eyes at the front. Kabuto first appeared in the <em>Pokémon TCG</em> in 1999’s Fossil set, in the ignominious position of 50/62, tucked between the similarly unimaginative Horsey and Krabby. It received no holo pattern, and until the last few months—even with a 1st Edition badge—was of almost no value. In July of this year, you could have bought yourself one for less than a dollar. Right now, the market price, according to <a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/product/44452/pokemon-fossil-kabuto?page=1&amp;Language=English"><em>TCGPlayer</em></a>, is over $28.</p>

 <p>Catching on as a meme, many people are rooting through binders to see if they’ve a spare card they can send the King’s way (I checked, I don’t, sadface emoji), while the masked figure scoops up every example they can find on eBay and other marketplaces. And as a result, the prices are climbing fast. Kabuto King himself has noticed that eBay sellers are suddenly declaring themselves “sold out,” likely in order to relist the previously worthless cards at their new, higher price.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Wow. Ebay sellers cancelling orders from days ago saying “out of stock”…</p> <p>That is BS. They will 100% re-list later at a much higher price. If you list something and someone buys it for your asking price you need to honor it.</p> <p>— Kabuto King (@KabutoKing_) <a href="https://twitter.com/KabutoKing_/status/1995322305556164690?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 1, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Incredibly, after <a href="https://x.com/KabutoKing_/status/1993684329248043039">a post from the X account on November 26</a> went viral, some are trying to compare King Kabuto’s antics to those of NFT sellers and the farce of artificial scarcity. As observed by <a href="https://x.com/StarPlatinum_/status/1995120664034811969">@StarPlatinum</a>, humorless people began claiming this action is the same as “whale concentration,” presumably because the crypto-brained are really incapable of discerning reality from the imaginary nonsense that drives their every moment. Big news here, but <em>Pokémon</em> cards are actually real objects, tangible and corporeal, and as such, their scarcity is never artificial. This is just one person buying all the real-life cards because they want to, and it’s funny. And, of course, no one cared a jot about the Kabuto cards before they started.</p>

 <p>With daily updates on X, Kabuto King shows a photo of all the new 1st ed Kabuto he’s bought, and then the bulk box in which they’re all being stored. It’s a beautiful sight, and the speed with which it’s all happening is breathtaking. The card had never been worth more than $10 in its 26 years of existence, but now it is the priciest non-holos in the Fossil set! Extraordinarily, <a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/search/pokemon/fossil?productLineName=pokemon&amp;setName=fossil&amp;productTypeName=Cards&amp;page=1&amp;view=grid">it’s currently valued higher</a> than the non-holo Moltres, Articuno, and Zapdos, traditionally the three best regular cards to pull in the set. It’s only $11 behind the cheapest holo, too—Muk, watch out, it’s coming for you!</p> <p>What a splendidly joyful thing to see happening: it’s utterly harmless, deeply charming, and having a bonkers real-world effect on the price of a formerly unloved piece of cardboard. Step aside Gengar, there’s a new card everyone’s hoping to pull from Fossil. Although a sealed 1st Edition Fossil pack will cost you $250 to $370 (people want the Aerodactyl pack art much more), you might want to think twice.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-kabuto-first-edition-viral-card-2000649100]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The War On AI Slop Comes To Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-season-7-gen-ai-tim-sweeney-latata-2000649103</link>
            <guid>1369141</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Fortnite</em>‘s mega-<a href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-simpsons-mini-season-review-changes-new-map-short-2000640868">popular<em> Simpsons</em> event</a> is over and season 7 is now officially live in the battle royale. The victory lap for one of the game’s biggest months in a while has been short-lived, however. No sooner did the new update go live than fans started side-eyeing some of the new sprays, music, and art in the game, wondering if it’s AI-generated. The latest slop witchhunt comes just days after Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney argued against storefront disclaimers for games that use AI.</p> <p>Season 7 features a new battle pass with cameos from The Bride from <em>Kill Bill</em> and Marty McFly from <em>Back to the Future</em>. In keeping with this loose ode to classic cinema, the game also now features new posters and sprays that some players think look suspiciously like they might be at least partly the work of gen AI. “Did <em>Fortnite</em> use AI to make this poster?” is now <a href="https://x.com/Duba_legitleaks/status/1995152082731733329">the question</a> ricocheting <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1pahvnv/is_this_chapter_7_art_ai_generated/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=whitespace&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-fans-are-saying-no-to-ai-slop-after-spotting-what-they-believe-are-ai-generated-images-in-game">around social media</a>.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">it's unfair to criticize those that raise suspicion on this kind of thing. </p> <p>suddenly, there are several images that have that "AI look" to them. Likely touched up and not fully generated, but there's something mildly off about shading and lighting</p> <p>and then the toes on one <a href="https://t.co/cynddbBH56">pic.twitter.com/cynddbBH56</a></p> <p>— WayComet ☄️ (@WayComet) <a href="https://twitter.com/WayComet/status/1995264510098366888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>At the center of the debate is a yeti poster, a <em>Back to the Future</em> spray, a tomatohead talk show billboard, and a new emote song in the battle pass called “<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1paauzo/the_new_icon_emote_latata_is_an_ai_song/">Latata</a>.” Unlike most of the backlashes to AI we’ve seen in gaming, however, this one is based more on vibes than obvious tells. There’s not yet any clear evidence that gen-AI was used, and Epic Games hasn’t officially commented on the controversy yet.</p>

 <p>But the sheer association with the <a href="https://kotaku.com/nhl26-ai-ea-college-football-madden-card-packs-2000646229">slop aesthetic</a> has already blown up into calls to boycott the season. The debate has gotten so messy that r/FortNiteBR, which features over 1 million active users, has already created a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1pasao6/ai_content_in_fortnite_megathread/">dedicated mega thread</a> to stop it from consuming the rest of the subreddit.</p>

 <p>In addition to calls for commenters to stay “civil,” there’s also an informal poll asking for players’ positions on the use of AI in games. Nearly 2,000 respondents said AI has no place in any game. Only 4 percent said they had no issues with generative AI being used in gaming.</p>   <p>At least one of the artists whose work was involved in season 7 has come out rejecting the AI accusations. Sean Dove, a freelancer who goes by andthankyou on Instagram, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/andthankyou/?hl=en">responded after</a> his Marty McFly spray became one of the witchhunt’s targets. “I guess someone on Reddit thinks this is AI,” Dove wrote. “I think the culprit is a clock in the background.” The face clock in question has incorrect numbers. The artist said he grabbed a bunch of clock images from an image search to collage them.</p>

 <p>“It’s entirely possible I grabbed an AI clock and wasn’t paying attention,” he wrote. Dove followed up with a time-lapse image of making the spray.</p> <p>It’s a perfect example of how poisoned the well has become. On the one hand, you have people so suspicious of slop being forced on them that they are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/destiny2/comments/1p7c6cm/no_bungie_did_not_use_ai_for_dredgen_baels/">pointing fingers everywhere without proof</a>. On the other hand, you have an artist potentially unknowingly introducing AI into their work simply by using random online references for household objects.</p>

 <h2>Time Sweeney rails against Steam AI rules</h2> <p>The cloud currently hanging over <em>Fortnite</em> was made darker by recent comments from Epic’s boss. Sweeney recently argued against AI disclosures on Steam and other storefronts. “The AI tag is relevant to art exhibits for authorship disclosure, and to digital content licensing marketplaces where buyers need to understand the rights situation,” <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1993687499621728312?s=20">Sweeney wrote on X</a> last week. “It makes no sense for game stores, where AI will be involved in nearly all future production.”</p>

 <p>When another user on the platform alleged that Epic might already be using gen-AI for coding its Unreal Engine, the executive denied the claim. “I just hate to see Valve confiscate ever more opportunity from small developers by facilitating new categories cancel campaigns and review bombing,” he wrote. “Steam used to just facilitate downloads. Then they foreclosed on payments, then price competition, then crypto, now AI.”</p> <p>Sweeney’s bullishness on generative AI is the spark that’s helping fuel skepticism about <i>Fortnite</i>‘s latest season. After all, if the CEO of a company tells you gen-AI will be involved in “nearly all future production” and thinks that fact shouldn’t have to be disclosed, it’s not a huge leap to consider that’s already happening in his company’s game. No wonder some players just want to be done with the whole thing rather than having to become a part-time <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-spot-generative-ai-art-according-to-artists/">internet forensic</a> whenever their favorite game introduces new art, music, or voices that sound slightly off.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-season-7-gen-ai-tim-sweeney-latata-2000649103]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beats Powerbeats Pro 2 Hits a New Cyber Monday Low While Apple Clears Out Its Black Friday Leftovers]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/beats-powerbeats-pro-2-hits-a-new-cyber-monday-low-while-apple-clears-out-its-black-friday-leftovers-2000648832</link>
            <guid>1369138</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If your first post-Thanksgiving stop is the gym to work off some of that massive feast, you’ll want to make a little Cyber Monday detour to Amazon first to upgrade your wireless earbuds. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6129/">Right now the Beats Powerbeats Pro 2 wireless noise cancelling earbuds are $50 off, making them a great buy at just $200</a>.</p>
<p>These are the latest Powerbeats Pro, having dropped less than a year ago, and they’re packed with features that will earn them a permanent place not just in your gym bag, but anywhere that you’re wanting high-quality sound and pro-level noise cancellation. They work equally well with both Apple and Android devices — which has long been one of the top Beats features — and with the charging case they have up to 45 hours of listening time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6129/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Ready for Sweat</h2>
<p>There really isn’t a situation that’s wrong for the Powerbeats Pro 2, but they truly excel as workout buds. The secure-fit earhooks keep them firmly in place no matter how hard your workout is, with five different sizes of ear tips included to ensure the best possible fit. The earhooks are upgraded from the previous Beats, with nickel titanium reinforcement for flexibility, grip, and overall strength. The Beats app for iOS and Android has a Fit Test feature built in so you can check that you have the best fit and therefore the best sound and best noise cancellation.</p>
<p>The Powerbeats Pro 2 are also IPX4 sweat- and water-resistant to hold fast during your hardest workouts or if rain or snow show up during your outdoor run or bike ride, and this model comes with a heart rate monitoring feature that you can read on the Beats app. The Beats app is also where you’ll be able to find the customizable controls, battery status, and Locate My Beats feature.</p>



<h2>Big Upgrade</h2>
<p>The Powerbeats Pro 2 come with a number of significant upgrades from the previous version, starting with the charging case. It’s significantly smaller, reduced in size by roughly a third to make them more pocket-friendly. The case can now charge wirelessly, and a full charge of both the case and the buds combine to create up to 45 hours of total battery life. If that somehow runs out and you’re in need of a quick boost before you run for the door, the Fast Fuel feature turns a 5-minute charge into 90 minutes of listening time, enough for a workout or a run.</p>
<p>The Powerbeats Pro 2 are all-around great wireless buds, above and beyond working out. They’re armed with stable Bluetooth, built-in voice isolation, and multiple mics for hands-free phone calls. The Active Noise Cancellation is top-notch, and there’s also a Transparency mode that lets you enjoy your music or podcast fully while being aware of your surroundings for safety’s sake. The Powerbeats Pro 2 also fully support spatial audio.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6129/">The $50 Cyber Monday price drop at Amazon pushes the Beats Powerbeats Pro 2 wireless earbuds to the head of the class for great audio deals</a>. Check them out now before this 20%-off deal expires.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6129/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/beats-powerbeats-pro-2-hits-a-new-cyber-monday-low-while-apple-clears-out-its-black-friday-leftovers-2000648832]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>