<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:13:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finally Someone’s Taking ‘Puzzle Platformer’ Literally]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/piece-by-piece-demo-steam-free-puzzle-platformer-2000672798</link>
            <guid>1444126</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Some puzzle pieces for platforming.</span> © Neon Polygons / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>We hear a lot about “puzzle platformers,” but none has ever taken the notion as literally as <em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3249380/Piece_by_Piece/">Piece by Piece</a>.&nbsp;</em>This is a collection of tiny platform games by Neon Polygons, set within the rearrangeable pieces of a jigsaw puzzle, and it’s really ever-so smart.</p> <p><em>Piece by Piece&nbsp;</em>sets its agenda from the very first puzzle. You play as a little king dude trapped inside a single jigsaw puzzle piece. However, when you click in another piece he’s then able to run between the two—so long as there’s not a wall or obstacle blocking his path. So you’d imagine this would start with your just connecting three pieces together and running from left to right to get to grips with the conceit. But no! <em>Piece by Piece</em> wants you on top of things straight away, and you’re going to need to do a slightly more complicated bit of piece juggling to be able to get past a solid wall impeding your path.</p>

  <p>In the full game, due out March 13, you’ll then spend a fair while with this little guy and his challenges, learning the neat tricks the game has to offer like falling vertically from one piece to the next, or snatching pieces away just in time such that he lands on their bottom edge before he can fall through to the next. This is then really drummed into you, and for a moment you wonder if this is it, if this is the extent of the game’s ideas, before it suddenly furls like a fabulous flower and reveals six brand new twists on the format, each with not only their own set of challenges, but then paired up to combine their features for even more. So you might now be an alien trying to move around by creating portals that only work when pieces are connected, or the cutest little drill-guy who burrows through lines of rock, then the two combined into some really brain-pushing challenges.</p> <p>The demo that’s out now is smart enough to not just stick with the opening set of puzzles, but instead jumps about a bit, quickly moving on from the king to the princess lady (who in the full game has to deal with puzzles that require some complicated jiggery-pokery to have flat puzzle pieces align rather than the usual fitting of tabs into sockets), and then to the teleporting alien, the drill guy, and finally those two combined. Said demo includes a total of 13 puzzles, and while they likely won’t have you stumped for long, they certainly give you a great idea of what’s on offer here.</p>

 <p>In the full game you’ll be using magic tiles that can copy pieces, two-sided pieces you can flip, rotating pieces…you get the idea. And it gets&nbsp;<em>much</em> tougher as it goes along, offering some properly juicy head-scratchers. We’ll have a full review when the game is properly out, but for now you should know it’s well worth <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3249380/Piece_by_Piece/">checking out the demo and putting on your wishlist</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/piece-by-piece-demo-steam-free-puzzle-platformer-2000672798]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slay The Spire 2 Is The New Silksong As Indie Games Delay Themselves To Dodge Its Blast Radius]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/slay-spire-2-steam-roguelike-delay-2000672790</link>
            <guid>1444078</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>On February 19, developer Mega Crit finally announced that</span> <a href="https://kotaku.com/slay-the-spire-2-early-access-release-date-steam-trailer-2000671424"><i><span>Slay the Spire 2</span></i><span> has a release date</span></a><span>: March 5. For those of us who would gladly sell a kidney to get our hands on the sequel to the best roguelike deckbuilder ever made (sorry, </span><i><span>Balatro</span></i><span>), this is incredible news. For every indie dev who was inspired to make a roguelike deckbuilder of their own following the original game’s success, however, this is potentially awful news, as </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2’s</span></i><span> early access release date is smack dab in the middle of one of the busiest release periods of the year. <a href="https://kotaku.com/every-game-delayed-silksong-hollowknight-demonschool-baby-steps-cloverpit-2000620407">It’s <em>Silksong</em> all over again</a>, and games that were set to release around that time are now moving out of the way.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>The most well-publicized delay so far is </span><i><span>Handmancers</span></i><span>, a roguelike deckbuilder from developer and publisher 58BLADES. As the devs revealed in a post on </span><a href="https://x.com/Handmancers/status/2025236242204336358"><span>X</span></a><span>, </span><i><span>Handmancers </span></i><span>was supposed to release during the Turn-Based Thursday Fest, a seven-day-long yearly event that’s scheduled to begin </span><a href="https://turnbasedfest.com/"><span>on March 6</span></a><span>. Considering that it starts a day after </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2’s</span></i><span> March 5 release date, this one feels like a smart call. “Yea…we’d get absolutely crushed,” the team wrote.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The developers behind </span><i><span>Mini Tank Mayhem</span></i><span>, a tower defense and deck-building strategy game from Algorocks, have yet to confirm exactly why their game has suddenly been delayed. However, an apparent tester </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1rbg1ps/comment/o6qrfg7/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>on Reddit claimed</span></a><span>&nbsp;that </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2</span></i><span> is indeed to blame. While a random comment on Reddit is obviously not the most reliable source, the timing of </span><i><span>Mini Tank Mayhem’s</span></i><span> sudden delay is awfully suspicious. Its </span><a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2096260/history/?changeid=U:73009738"><span>SteamDB history confirms</span></a><span> that its 3 March, 2026 release date was pushed back to April 30 (and then changed again to April 29) mere hours after </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2’s</span></i><span> latest trailer dropped.</span></p> <p><i><span>Omelet You Cook</span></i><span>, a “cozy chaotic cooking roguelike” published by SchuBox Games, was ahead of the curve. The two-man dev team responsible for the <a href="https://kotaku.com/balatro-meets-luck-be-a-landlord-in-chaotic-cooking-roguelike-that-cant-stop-winning-new-fans-2000668754">excellent <em>Balatro-</em>like food prep game</a> </span><span>decided to move up its 1.0 launch back in January. As confirmed by co-developer Dan Schumacher during an interview with </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/roguelike/slay-the-spire-2-pulls-a-silksong-scares-indie-devs-into-releasing-roguelike-ahead-of-schedule-in-fear-of-losing-players-to-an-absolute-juggernaut-in-our-own-genre/"><i><span>GamesRadar</span></i></a><span>, they pulled it forward out of fear that they’d be overshadowed by </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2’s</span></i><span> yet-to-be confirmed (at the time) March release window. “Every streamer we’d reach out to will be playing it. Every roguelike enjoyer will be checking it out. Even I’ll be playing so much that I won’t have time to finish our game!”</span></p>

 <p><span>While no other devs have yet publicly announced any </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2</span></i><span>-related delays, it’s clearly become a popular topic of discussion among indie studios. Bermrad, the studio behind the hack-and-slash roguelite </span><i><span>Trials of Valor</span></i><span>, noted that their game sharing “some elements with </span><i><span>Slay the Spire</span></i><span>” was less of an issue than the release date itself. Unfortunately, the two games </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/1r9e5vd/were_releasing_the_same_day_as_slay_the_spire_2/"><span>now share</span></a><span> the same release date, as Bermrad announced roughly three weeks ago that </span><i><span>Trials of Valor </span></i><span>will be dropping on March 5.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Other studios have instead chosen to have a little fun with the increased attention on early March’s release lineup. </span><i><span>Grimslair</span></i><span>’s </span><span>developer, ThunderRam Studios, revealed on </span><a href="https://x.com/AWMassMedia/status/2025638786454233168?s=20"><span>X</span></a><span> that there will be “no hiding in the bushes until the hype train passes,” as the studio intends to stick to its previously announced March 6 release date. Fishagon, who are working on the party card game </span><i><span>Vice Versa</span></i><span>, opted to copy and paste 58BLADES’ announcement and swap it out </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IndieGaming/comments/1rbnq5n/handmancers_release_date_announcement_forces_vice/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>with references to their game</span></a><span> instead. </span></p> <p>Games have tried ride the hype wave for a top Steam release before. <span>It’s essentially what the developers behind the decent Metroidvania <i>Adventure of</i><em> Samsara</em> did last year, launching on the same day as<em> Silksong</em>. <a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-atari-adventure-of-samsara-2000624067">It did not go well</a>. Other studios, fortunately, have been spared from making that choice themselves. </span><i>Slumber Realm</i>’s devs, Chugga Chugga LLC, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/videogames/comments/1rb638e/another_slay_the_spire_2_related_announcement/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">announced</a> that their card game roguelike won’t be ready in time to compete with <i>Slay the Spire 2</i> anyway, or, as they put it, “I guess in every sense it has no impact.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/slay-spire-2-steam-roguelike-delay-2000672790]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Director Explains Why Cloud’s Hair Looks Rough On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-director-explains-why-clouds-hair-looks-rough-on-switch-2-2000672823</link>
            <guid>1444075</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Last month, Square Enix released <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-the-kotaku-review-1842697312">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a></em> on Nintendo Switch 2. The port of the 2020 RPG was <a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-switch-2-handheld-performance-2000661851">well-received</a>, with many praising the game’s clarity and performance. But there was one aspect of <em>FF7 Remake</em> that annoyed some players: Cloud’s famous luxurious hair could look fuzzy or pixelated at times. Well, in a new interview, the game’s director has explained <em>thoroughly</em> why this is the case, and said that it might be a problem in future<em> FF7</em> remake trilogy ports on Switch 2 as well.</p>  <p><a href="https://automaton-media.com/articles/interviewsjp/ff7-20260223-423487/">In an interview posted on February 23, <em>Automaton</em></a> talked to <em>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade</em>&nbsp;director Naoki Hamaguchi about the Switch 2 port of the RPG. Specifically, they asked him about Cloud’s pixelated hair. Instead of just saying, “Hey, guys, the Switch 2 isn’t as beefy as a high-end PC or PS5, so we had to make some compromises,” the director behind the remake provided a very detailed response. Here’s some of it via Google Translate:</p>

 <blockquote><p><span dir="auto">“In <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>, we use a process called TAA (Temporal Anti-Aliasing) to prevent the outlines of characters from appearing jagged. TAA is a system that creates smoother images that are closer to high resolution by referencing and overlaying information from past frames in addition to the currently drawn frame. </span><span dir="auto">Hair is a very thin component, so if you draw it as is, it’s easy for each dot to appear or disappear. That’s why in this game, we use a special process that switches between drawing and not drawing hair on a dot-by-dot basis for each frame. By combining this process with TAA, we make it so that the fine hair lines appear to connect smoothly across frames.”</span></p></blockquote> <p>Got all that? Hamaguchi then explained that when the Switch 2 is in portable mode, there are “<span dir="auto">additional restrictions.” This forces the game to lower its internal resolution to ensure solid performance. But doing this makes it harder for TAA to create a stable image, leading to the “graininess and jaggedness” of Cloud’s hair. But because <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/i-adore-final-fantasy-7-remakes-dorky-eco-terrorists-1842843860">FF7 Remake</a></em> on Switch 2 uses a dynamic resolution system, his hair can look worse or better depending on the scene.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2>Cloud’s fuzzy, pixelated hair is likely to return in <em>Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth on Switch 2</em></h2> <p>So hopefully, that explains why Cloud’s hair is a bit pixelated in the Switch 2 port. As for the upcoming Switch 2 port of 2024’s <em>Rebirth</em>, which is set to arrive in June, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/ff7-remake-part-3-unreal-engine-4-ue5-gen-ai-2000663075">the third and final entry in the project releasing sometime in the future</a>, Hamaguchi made it clear that you’ll probably see some fuzzy Cloud hair in those releases, too.</p>

 <p><span dir="auto">“Yes, on the Nintendo Switch 2, in order to stabilize the frame rate, the internal resolution is lowered in scenes with a high load, and DLSS compensates for that,” the director told the outlet. “This is a basic mechanism that is not compatible with current hair rendering technology.”</span></p>

 <p>But Hamaguchi says that being able to play <em>FF7 Remake</em> on the go is worth the trade-off of some elements, like Cloud’s hair, being a bit fuzzy, adding, <span dir="auto">“There are limitations unique to portable devices, but we will continue to do our best to continue optimizing it so that we can improve it even if only a little.”</span></p> <p>I genuinely love that the director didn’t offer up some boring PR quote about the hair, but dug into how it works and why it looks that way. Making games is, like playing games, a series of decisions and trade-offs. Considering how great<em> FF7 Remake</em> runs and plays on Switch 2, I think some fuzzy hair is a fine compromise, even if Cloud might disagree.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-director-explains-why-clouds-hair-looks-rough-on-switch-2-2000672823]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>