<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 07:10:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Take Away Randy Pitchford's Phone]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-real-fan-post-1851782855</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/someone-take-away-randy-pitchfords-phone.1201152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-real-fan-post-1851782855<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sometimes you just gotta walk away. And this might be one of those times. Earlier this month, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1922454876803551555&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1922454876803551555" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gearbox co-founder and CEO Randy Pitchford replied to someone</a></span> on social media about the studio’s next game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-state-of-play-gearbox-round-up-trailer-1851778578&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-state-of-play-gearbox-round-up-trailer-1851778578"><em>Borderlands 4</em></a></span><em>,</em> possibly receiving an $80 price tag. He said it wasn’t his call and then infamously added, “If you’re a real fan, you’ll find a way to make it happen.” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-games-1851781445&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-4-randy-pitchford-gearbox-80-games-1851781445">This didn’t go over well with people online</a></span>. A few days later, on May 22, he said he didn’t intend to sound like an asshole.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197565" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="197565,197567,195670" data-current="197565"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23089.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Now, a week later, he’s posted about the “real fan” comment yet again. However, this time Pitchford basically wrote an article about it,<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1927802548326650365&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DuvalMagic/status/1927802548326650365" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> posting a 573-word tweet</a></span>. In the lengthy response, he apologized for the “misunderstanding” and reiterated that he never intended to suggest people who can’t afford <em>Borderlands 4</em> aren’t real fans. </p><p>Instead, he said his point was that <em>Borderlands 4—</em>a game that I’m still excited to play in September<em>—</em>costing $10 more likely won’t hurt the upcoming looter shooter, as he believes it’s great and still worth the price. And you know what, after reading this 500+ word post, I do believe him. I think Pitchford really didn’t expect his short tweet to set off a firestorm. But it did, and at this point, I’m not sure posting over and over again about it is helping. If anything, it just leads to more people learning about the original comment and, as a result, more discourse happening. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/ouau9SVVrBA&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/ouau9SVVrBA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">He’s like Sideshow Bob stepping on rakes</a></span>. Each post angers more people, making the situation worse. It’s time to put the phone down, walk away, and let the internet move on to something else. So, that’s my advice to you, Randy. Log off, dude. </p><p>Anyway, here’s the full post, lightly formatted so it is easier to read:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>I am sorry there was a misunderstanding. The absolute sincere truth is that I don’t want anyone to pay any more than they should or are comfortable with and I always work with the intent and hope that a customer always feels they got the better end of the deal no matter what they pay. </p><p>The actual context was that a guy replied to a post about Borderlands 4 on the Nintendo Switch 2 was warning me that if the price ends up being $80, the game will fail. What I was trying to do was explain that it wasn’t my call but that if a $10 price increase does happen (since that’s obviously where the industry is going), it will be okay and that Borderlands 4 will be okay because it’s a great game and there are a lot of fans who will see the value and want it. </p><p> I think my trying to short hand that using the phrase “real fans” triggered some people and I saw that it got inflated as if I was making some big statement (I wasn’t - I was just trying to help someone who I thought was sincerely worried about us and looking out for us) and I could see that it was being pressed into the idea that I was taking the audience for granted (which is a super shitty look, but it was not at all my intent and does not reflect at all how I feel). </p><p>The sincere truth is that I’m grateful that anyone likes our games and humbled that so many fans show up to enjoy and support what we do. </p><p>As an artist, I don’t want prices to go up because I want everyone to have access to what we create. I get that business is a thing and that the market and economy are driving prices up and sooner or later we’re going to have to all adapt to that so that the creative engine can make at least as much as it spends to provide us with amazing content. Whatever the case, I’m here to try to entertain people and my priority has always been to try to add some joy and happiness and creativity to the world. To whatever extent I succeed at that, I am grateful and honored and take on every effort with passion and humility. </p></blockquote><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p> May I recommend you consider the people who create entertainment you enjoy are actual, real people who sincerely are working to try to make cool stuff. I have dedicated my life to video games as entertainment and I have made the choice to be accessible on here. I don’t want to let edge cases ruin that for the majority of people who find value in using this medium for a positive connection, but I cannot help that there’s a part of me that doesn’t want to at least try to help those that don’t get it to gain some perspective and some dignity in how they choose to interact. </p><p> I’m not claiming I’m perfect. But I don’t deserve any less latitude than anyone else. I choose to think of others with the most amount of charity and am often surprised to discover some that jump to the worst possible way to consider a thing as doing that is just counter to my nature. </p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything You Need to Know To Get into Magic the Gathering's Final Fantasy Set]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/magic-gatheirng-final-fantasy-cloud-sephiroth-pack-set-1851782830</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-you-need-to-know-to-get-into-magic-the-gatherings-final-fantasy-set.1201110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/magic-gatheirng-final-fantasy-cloud-sephiroth-pack-set-1851782830<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Few game franchises can match the pedigree of <em>Final Fantasy</em>, but one that arguably comes close is the long-running trading card game <em>Magic: the Gathering</em>. Much like <em>FF, </em>Wizards of the Coast’s TCG has been around for decades, bringing in new players regularly and exciting existing ones continualy. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197576" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="PlayStation’s Days of Play Brings Bomb Rush Cyberfunk, NBA 2K25 &amp; More To PS Plus" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="88" data-playlist="197576,197567,197565" data-current="197576"><div><p>PlayStation’s Days of Play Brings Bomb Rush Cyberfunk, NBA 2K25 &amp; More To PS Plus</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197576/197576_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197576/197576_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197576/197576_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23099.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This June, the card game istrying its most ambitious plan yet: collaborating with Square Enix to release a set of cards starring characters, locations and creatures from <em>Final Fantasy </em>history. However, those new to <em>MTG</em>, or trading card games in general, may be overwhelmed by all the different products available. This guide will help you break down all of the offerings to choose what’s right for you. </p><h2 id="h129269"><a id="1"></a>Pre-constructed Commander Decks</h2><figure id="" data-id="7b50ab54d68891e1c32647f238358299" data-recommend-id="image://7b50ab54d68891e1c32647f238358299" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="594" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7b50ab54d68891e1c32647f238358299" data-recommend-id="image://7b50ab54d68891e1c32647f238358299" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="594" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>These are probably the poster child for the collaboration as these are decks created specifically for <em>Magic’s </em>popular commander format. “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-cloud-tidus-1851782536&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-cloud-tidus-1851782536">Commander” is a spin on the rules of <em>MTG</em></a></span><em> </em>where more than two players at a time have a 100-card deck with no duplicates that includes a leader card to offer special abilities when playing. </p><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-cloud-tidus-1851782536&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-commander-cloud-tidus-1851782536">How To Pick The Right Commander Deck For <em>Magic: The Gathering’s Final Fantasy Set</em></a></span></p><p>For the <em>Final Fantasy </em>set, there will be four Commander decks available, each for a different game. There is the <em>FFVI </em>deck starring Terra<em>, FFVII</em> starring Cloud,<em> FFX </em>starring Tidus<em>, </em>and <em>FFXIV</em> starring Y’shtola.<strong> These decks are pretty expensive going for around $70, but you are getting a wide variety of cards and these builds are fairly competitive</strong>. This is a great pickup for those who want to be able to play one of <em>Magic</em>’s most popular game-types, or if you love one of the titles being offered here. There are also Collector’s Editions of these decks that have foils for every card inside at a much higher cost.</p><hr><h2 id="h129270"><a id="2"></a>Play Boosters</h2><figure id="" data-id="bf8d11c38ec6eb023edac283c0be259a" data-recommend-id="image://bf8d11c38ec6eb023edac283c0be259a" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="595" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bf8d11c38ec6eb023edac283c0be259a" data-recommend-id="image://bf8d11c38ec6eb023edac283c0be259a" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="595" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>These are your normal booster packs. They should be around $7 USD each, or you can pick up a box for a little over $200. Each pack will contain 14 cards but all will be <em>Final Fantasy </em>themed. <strong>This is a great option for those who love </strong><em><strong>FF</strong></em><strong> and just want to collect some cards</strong>.</p><hr><h2 id="h129271"><a id="3"></a>Collector Boosters</h2><figure id="" data-id="708ef13e40f418ee62646ad0e968b8ba" data-recommend-id="image://708ef13e40f418ee62646ad0e968b8ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="824" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="708ef13e40f418ee62646ad0e968b8ba" data-recommend-id="image://708ef13e40f418ee62646ad0e968b8ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="824" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Collector’s Boosters are like your standard Play Boosters but have a chance of higher rarity cards. <strong>Collector’s Boosters are for those who want to try to get the coolest looking cards</strong>. These are for those who want to try to get the most valuable cards from the set; however, <strong>Collector’s Boosters will most likely not be reprinted and will be very tough to find</strong>, so if you don’t already have some on order, you may be out of luck.</p><hr><h2 id="h129272"><a id="4"></a><em>Final Fantasy </em>Bundle</h2><figure id="" data-id="e92e1856f160df641e984eb0d14200da" data-recommend-id="image://e92e1856f160df641e984eb0d14200da" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="559" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e92e1856f160df641e984eb0d14200da" data-recommend-id="image://e92e1856f160df641e984eb0d14200da" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="559" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>As the name implies, this is basically a bundle of booster packs with some extras. You get nine play boosters, 32 lands, 16 which are full-art and 16 which are foil, a spindown (which is used to track health in a <em>MTG</em> match) and a deck box. <strong>This retails for $69.99 and is a good option if you are planning on picking up a handful of boosters and want some extras</strong>.</p><hr><h2 id="h129273"><a id="5"></a>Gift Bundle</h2><figure id="" data-id="700f7077dfe27fa9640ef2e8de7bfa3f" data-recommend-id="image://700f7077dfe27fa9640ef2e8de7bfa3f" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="559" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="700f7077dfe27fa9640ef2e8de7bfa3f" data-recommend-id="image://700f7077dfe27fa9640ef2e8de7bfa3f" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="559" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This is basically an improved version of the standard bundle. It includes nine booster packs, a collector booster, 32 full-art lands (16 foil, 16 non-foil), a spindown, and a storage box. This should retail for around $89.99.</p><hr><h2 id="h129274"><a id="6"></a>Pre-Release Pack</h2><p><em>Magic: The Gathering </em>holds special events called “Pre-Releases,” which allow fans the opportunity to get their hands on new cards a week early. Unlike the other products on this list, the Pre-Release Pack is available for purchase at these events. <strong>Each box contains six booster packs, a special rare or mythic rare card, a deck box and </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://diceenvy.com/blogs/news/what-are-spindown-dice-what-makes-them-different-and-why-does-it-matter&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://diceenvy.com/blogs/news/what-are-spindown-dice-what-makes-them-different-and-why-does-it-matter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>spindown die</strong></a></span><strong> </strong>(Editor’s note: No, you <em>can’t </em>use spindowns for <em>D&amp;D</em> even though they have 20 sides). </p><p>Once your packs are opened, you will build a limited, 40-card deck and play in a tournament with other players, with most game shops offering prizes for winners. <strong>This is a great way to get involved in the game and see what it’s like to actually play <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> in a competitive space</strong><em>.</em></p><hr><h2 id="h129275"><a id="7"></a>Starter Decks</h2><figure id="" data-id="95a259753bee3ea7640d1758b8534849" data-recommend-id="image://95a259753bee3ea7640d1758b8534849" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="662" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Wizards of the Coast / Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="95a259753bee3ea7640d1758b8534849" data-recommend-id="image://95a259753bee3ea7640d1758b8534849" data-format="jpg" data-width="679" data-height="662" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Final Fantasy-themed Magic: The Gathering cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Finally, there is a starter deck pack that contains two pre-built decks (Cloud vs Sephiroth). Retailing for $19.99, <strong>this is a good option for those who want to try out <em>MTG</em> in a more casual setting</strong>. </p><hr><p><em>Final Fantasy </em>and <em>Magic: The Gathering </em>fans have a lot to look forward to summer 2025 when this collaboration releases on June 12th. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Make Your Rifle Your Own With Helldivers 2’s Weapon Customization Suite]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-rifle-gun-customziation-update-attachments-1851782818</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/make-your-rifle-your-own-with-helldivers-2%E2%80%99s-weapon-customization-suite.1201080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-rifle-gun-customziation-update-attachments-1851782818<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I spent about twenty hours playing <em>Helldivers 2</em> on launch, and then my wife bought the game; we easily put in another sixty. There was one feature I continuously begged for in the beginning, much to my wife’s annoyance since she couldn’t do anything about it. I wanted weapon customization. Not just skins, but attachments. Thankfully, my wish came true.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,195618,195752" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h810087"><a id=""></a>Exploring weapon customization in <em>Helldivers 2</em></h2><figure id="" data-id="c43e1861495db3d6496f467a28c5d5df" data-recommend-id="image://c43e1861495db3d6496f467a28c5d5df" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon customization menu in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The weapon customization menu in Helldivers 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arrowhead Game Studios / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c43e1861495db3d6496f467a28c5d5df" data-recommend-id="image://c43e1861495db3d6496f467a28c5d5df" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon customization menu in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If this is your first time playing <em>Helldivers 2</em> in quite a while, as it was mine, you’ll receive a notification upon loading into the game and boarding your vessel. It will alert you to the new weapon customization mechanic. To access the new feature, visit the Armory on the left-hand side of the main hallway leading to the command center.</p><p><strong>In the Armory, select the primary weapon you wish to customize, then hit “Customize” or click in the left analog stick on your controller to access the attachments menu.</strong></p><p>Currently, it’s possible to customize most of the game’s primary weapons with a few exceptions. For instance, I couldn’t customize any of the firearms from the <em>Killzone </em>crossover bundle, and you can’t customize sidearms. Hopefully, the developer will change that in the near future so that I could dump an extended magazine on my beloved P-19 Redeemer.</p><p>In any case, you have access to:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Optics</strong></li><li><strong>Underbarrel Attachments</strong></li><li><strong>Muzzle Attachments</strong></li><li><strong>Magazine Attachments</strong></li><li><strong>Weapon Skins</strong></li></ul><p>With the exception of skins, your chosen attachments alter the following stats:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Horizontal Recoil</strong></li><li><strong>Vertical Recoil</strong></li><li><strong>Sway</strong></li><li><strong>Ergonomics</strong></li><li><strong>Capacity</strong></li><li><strong>Magazines</strong></li><li><strong>Reload Time</strong></li></ul><p>For the most part, you want bigger numbers for all, besides Reload Time and Sway, which should be low.</p><h2 id="h810088"><a id=""></a>How to unlock weapon attachments and skins</h2><figure id="" data-id="eda59f65eecc0a2aa7cdb67cb6ca1753" data-recommend-id="image://eda59f65eecc0a2aa7cdb67cb6ca1753" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The inspect animation of a weapon in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The inspect animation of a weapon in Helldivers 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arrowhead Game Studios / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eda59f65eecc0a2aa7cdb67cb6ca1753" data-recommend-id="image://eda59f65eecc0a2aa7cdb67cb6ca1753" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The inspect animation of a weapon in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Weapons in <em>Helldivers 2</em> now have levels. <strong>The more you use a weapon, scoring kills with it, the more XP you earn for said piece of equipment</strong>. As you reach a new level, or a milestone, you’ll unlock additional attachments. </p><p>Of course, if only it were that simple. But this is <em>Helldivers 2</em>, and nothing is meant to be easy for the grunt on the ground!</p><p><strong>Once you earn enough XP to unlock weapon attachments and skins, you must then spend Requisition to further unlock the customization option for use.</strong> Thankfully, earning Requisition isn’t challenging these days, as most people still playing the game know how to farm and which missions to run!</p><hr><p><br><em>Helldivers 2</em> is available now, complete with its brand-new content update, on PS5 and Windows PCs.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds’ Electric Wyvern Is Harder To Beat In Its New Form, But It Can Be Done]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mh-mon-hun-arch-tempered-rey-dau-1851782762</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds%E2%80%99-electric-wyvern-is-harder-to-beat-in-its-new-form-but-it-can-be-done.1201038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mh-mon-hun-arch-tempered-rey-dau-1851782762<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Whether you’re a veteran of the series or are just someone grinding out their first hunts, everyone reaches a point of wanting more batt;es and harder challenges in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>. While the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-blossomdance-event-tickets-1851778319&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-blossomdance-event-tickets-1851778319">Blossomdance Festival</a></span> has provided plenty of the former, the latter is being answered with the addition of Arch-Tempered Rey Dau.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196452,197531" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The latest version of this foe is a fierce opponent with some devastating new tricks. Unprepared hunters are sure to get carted back to their camp quicker than they think. With the right strategies and knowledge, however, this creature will become just another challenge you can farm for exclusive materials. Here’s what you need to know about the game’s first Arch-Tempered monster.</p><h2 id="h125920"><a id="1"></a>How to find Arch-Tempered Rey Dau</h2><figure id="" data-id="778ade1e2ed6f4f97ae0ab8b30dce925" data-recommend-id="image://778ade1e2ed6f4f97ae0ab8b30dce925" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The summary screen for the A Silent Flash event quest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The summary screen for the A Silent Flash event quest." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="778ade1e2ed6f4f97ae0ab8b30dce925" data-recommend-id="image://778ade1e2ed6f4f97ae0ab8b30dce925" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The summary screen for the A Silent Flash event quest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Similar to prior entries, a monster with this classification is restricted to limited-time events. <strong>Arch-Tempered Rey Dau can only be hunted during an Event Quest called <em>A Silent Flash</em> and a Free Challenge Quest called <em>The Shining Storm Rages</em>.</strong> The first instance of these quests ran from April 29th to May 13th and from May 6th to May 20th, respectively. Here’s hoping they come back around often and not just during seasonal events. At the time of publication, the Arch-Tempered Rey Dau is not actively available. We expect strategies against this monster to be very similar, however, should specific Event Quests return.</p><h2 id="h125921"><a id=""></a>Arch-Tempered Rey Dau’s Weaknesses</h2><figure id="" data-id="e78541d525d8b30947acb2ab86e480c1" data-recommend-id="image://e78541d525d8b30947acb2ab86e480c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Suggested Strategy page for Rey Dau." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Suggested Strategy page for Rey Dau." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e78541d525d8b30947acb2ab86e480c1" data-recommend-id="image://e78541d525d8b30947acb2ab86e480c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Suggested Strategy page for Rey Dau." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>While Arch-Tempered Rey Dau is more intense than its weaker variants, the general faults are the same. Come to this hunt ready to take advantage of the following vulnerabilities:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Elemental Weaknesses: Ice</li><li>Weapon Type Weaknesses:Cut, Blunt</li><li>Breakable Parts: Head, Tail (can also be severed), Wings x2</li><li>Susceptible Status Ailments – Blastblight, Exhaust, Paralysis (less effective), Poison, Sleep, Stun (less effective)</li><li>Items and Traps: Flash Pod, Pitfall Trap</li></ul><h2 id="h125922"><a id=""></a>How to Beat Arch-Tempered Rey Dau</h2><figure id="" data-id="916407187ddc29eeae5648c3811933d3" data-recommend-id="image://916407187ddc29eeae5648c3811933d3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two hunters face off against an Arch-Tempered Rey Dau inside its nest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Two hunters face off against an Arch-Tempered Rey Dau inside its nest." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="916407187ddc29eeae5648c3811933d3" data-recommend-id="image://916407187ddc29eeae5648c3811933d3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two hunters face off against an Arch-Tempered Rey Dau inside its nest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Preparing for this fight will be pretty similar to previous Rey Dau hunts. An important distinction is that bringing weapons with an ice element as well as armor with high thunder resistance is more of a requirement than a recommendation this time around. We’ll want to end this as soon as possible, especially with the beast’s abundant health and higher resistance to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-wounds-hunter-mode-solo-co-op-1851771276&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-wounds-hunter-mode-solo-co-op-1851771276">wounds</a></span>.</p><p>Arch-Tempered Rey Dau is also far more aggressive than its Tempered variant, attacking more frequently and stringing together many of its moves. It’s a common occurrence to be hit by one attack and then by another while trying to get up. Remember to call your Seikret for a quick pick-up before you get sent back to camp! Your Seikret is the perfect asset that shouldn’t be overlooked during intense hunts like these. Taking a break from the action to heal up is a lot better than doing so within Rey Dau’s proximity.</p><p>What might be the most notable difference is that many of this monster’s attacks will attract lightning strikes. These increase the likelihood of being stunned and make it more difficult to get some hits in. Hunters who enjoy using weapons with counterattacks will need to keep their guard up a bit longer. A successful <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-offset-attack-monster-weapons-1851775743&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-offset-attack-monster-weapons-1851775743">Offset Attack</a></span> works fine, but other counters will usually be interrupted and leave you defenseless for a more damaging attack. Bringing gear with the Evade Extender skill can be a big help for dodging the lightning as well.</p><p><strong>If you need a break from these aftershocks, destroying the blue Fulgurite crystals along its wings and tail will disable them for around three minutes.</strong> It’s not a permanent solution as the crystals will come back, and you’ll be dealing less damage by not focusing on the head, but this is an ideal tactic if you’re having trouble with these follow-ups.</p><p>Not counting the extra lightning, Arch-Tempered Rey Dau does come with a brand-new move. Standing too close can trigger it to shoot lightning directly beneath it. This is an important attack to be mindful of, since Rey Dau’s underside is a safe spot in previous hunts. Being hit by this will leave you open for a potential follow-up charged beam that can faint you. My advice is to dodge out of the way as soon as you notice it charging up and looking down. You’ll likely have a second at most to react.</p><p>Destroying tempered wounds is still a fantastic way to knock your target down. Coming at odds with this is Arch-Tempered Rey Dau’s high wound resistance. Besides a weak spot that appears after performing its strongest charged beam, there aren’t many opportunities to land a focus strike and some nice damage. Knocking Rey Dau down will mostly require <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-mount-master-mounter-1851775446&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-mount-master-mounter-1851775446">mounting</a></span>, traps (pitfall and vine traps specifically), and the occasional Flash Pod when it’s flying in the air.</p><p>There isn’t much more to the fight than chasing after it to new locations. The electric wyvern is basically enraged the entire fight, so it’s purely a matter of survival. Always prioritize your health to best avoid any one-hit KOs. If you’ve been carted once or twice already, remember that capturing the monster is an option. No shame in finishing this hunt early.</p><h2 id="h125923"><a id=""></a>Arch-Tempered Rey Dau’s Exclusive Rewards</h2><figure id="" data-id="4cfac73c7d909545e759b496c7d4c4f6" data-recommend-id="image://4cfac73c7d909545e759b496c7d4c4f6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The post-hunt rewards screen for A Silent Flash, highlighting a Rey Dau Certificate Y." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The post-hunt rewards screen for A Silent Flash, highlighting a Rey Dau Certificate Y." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Samuel Moreno / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4cfac73c7d909545e759b496c7d4c4f6" data-recommend-id="image://4cfac73c7d909545e759b496c7d4c4f6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The post-hunt rewards screen for A Silent Flash, highlighting a Rey Dau Certificate Y." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Most of the rewards and drops you receive will be the same as the Tempered version. <strong>The biggest difference for Arch-Tempered Rey Dau is that instead of receiving </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mh-hunter-symbols-farm-1851779176&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-mh-hunter-symbols-farm-1851779176"><strong>Hunter Symbol III</strong></a></span><strong>, you’ll receive the new Rey Dau Certificate Y material.</strong> This is needed to forge the new Rey Dau Gamma armor for your hunter and Palico, as well as upgrade to the new Defense Charm V and Power Charm III talismans. That said, with the Arch-Tempered Rey Dau not presently in the game until possibly a future event, the rewards may differ if/when it returns.</p><hr><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> is available now on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Windows PCs. <br></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Panther Game Cancelled As EA Shuts Down Studio By Ex-Monolith Devs]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-panther-ea-cliffhanger-monolith-productions-1851782787</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-panther-game-cancelled-as-ea-shuts-down-studio-by-ex-monolith-devs.1201014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/black-panther-ea-cliffhanger-monolith-productions-1851782787<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d4c4428d525816a9c2690b81822465e5" data-recommend-id="image://d4c4428d525816a9c2690b81822465e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2500" data-height="1250" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Black Panther appears in his suit. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Black Panther appears in his suit. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d4c4428d525816a9c2690b81822465e5" data-recommend-id="image://d4c4428d525816a9c2690b81822465e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="2500" data-height="1250" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Black Panther appears in his suit. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A <em>Black Panther</em> action game that was in development at Electronic Arts has been killed and the studio behind it is no more. The <em>Madden</em> publisher announced it’s shutting down Cliffhanger Games, previously formed by ex-Monolith Productions leadership, according to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cancels-black-panther-game-closes-cliffhanger-games" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new report by<em> IGN</em></a></span>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,196626,195386" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> EA Entertainment president Laura Miele wrote to staff that the cuts were being instituted to “sharpen our focus and put our creative energy behind the most significant growth opportunities,” based on an email viewed by<em> IGN</em>. A <em>Black Panther</em> game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-panther-shadow-mordor-marvel-movie-ea-star-wars-1849518853?_gl=1*i1lccj*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDg0NTc0MDckbzIzNiRnMSR0MTc0ODQ1ODc2NyRqNSRsMCRoMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-panther-shadow-mordor-marvel-movie-ea-star-wars-1849518853?_gl=1*i1lccj*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDg0NTc0MDckbzIzNiRnMSR0MTc0ODQ1ODc2NyRqNSRsMCRoMA..">was previously revealed to be in production at Cliffhanger back in 2023</a></span>, but with no specific details about what kind of gameplay it would include or when it might launch. <br></p><p>The studio was formed by Kevin Stephens, former head of Monolith Productions, which made<em> Middle-Earth:</em>&nbsp;<em>Shadow of Mordor</em>, and other veterans of the studio after work on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tweaktown.com/news/103578/full-backstory-revealed-on-why-wb-games-axed-monolith-productions/index.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/103578/full-backstory-revealed-on-why-wb-games-axed-monolith-productions/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new IP, codenamed Legacy</a></span>, was killed by leadership at Warner Bros. Games in 2021. Monolith subsequently went on to work on a <em>Wonder Woman</em> game before being shut down as well earlier this year. </p><p> “We’re dedicated to delivering fans a definitive and authentic <em>Black Panther</em> experience, giving them more agency and control over their narrative than they have ever experienced in a story-driven video game,” Stephens said last year. “Wakanda is a rich Super Hero sandbox, and our mission is to develop an epic world for players who love Black Panther and want to explore the world of Wakanda as much as we do.”</p><p>These new layoffs at EA come after significant cuts at Respawn Entertainment and in other areas of the publisher while it focuses on its core cash cows like <em>The Sims </em>and <em>EA Sports FC </em>and shifts away from new projects and spin-offs, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/respawn-layoffs-star-wars-jedi-apex-legends-titanfall-1851778330&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/respawn-layoffs-star-wars-jedi-apex-legends-titanfall-1851778330">including a<em> Titanfall </em>project</a></span> that was reportedly in very early development. The publisher recently promised a 2.0-level refresh of <em>Apex Legends</em> to investors, and confirmed that<em> Battlefield 6 </em>will be arriving before the end of March 2026. </p><p>EA also has an <em>Iron Man </em>game in development at EA Motive. Miele reportedly reassured staff in her email that the company remained behind that project as well as the third game in the<em> Star Wars Jedi</em> trilogy. <br></p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>