<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:39:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Struggled Due To Bureaucracy, Says Bethesda Veteran Who Left After 20 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-6-starfield-bethesda-tes-2000660653</link>
            <guid>1408696</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>A veteran designer recently sat down with</span> <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/the-elder-scrolls/bethesdas-former-elder-scrolls-loremaster-on-why-he-left-starfields-communication-breakdowns-and-how-he-wanted-the-elder-scrolls-6-to-be-the-empire-strikes-back"><i><span>PC Gamer</span></i></a><span> to discuss his surprise departure from Bethesda Game Studios in 2023 after two stints and over 20 years at the company. He cited what he saw as detrimental changes in the </span><i><span>Elder Scrolls</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Fallout </span></i><span>maker’s development process due to Bethesda’s continued expansion as the driving impetus behind his decision.</span></p> <p><span>Kurt Kuhlmann, who worked for Bethesda as a junior designer in the late 1990s before rejoining the studio as a senior designer in 2003, made waves in the industry when he decided to step away from the role. By that time, he had worked on every major game in the </span><i><span>Elder Scrolls</span></i><span> series<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->apart from the first, </span><i><span>Arena<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment --></span></i><span>and was responsible for building out much of its setting and lore.</span></p>

 <p><span>“It was almost certainly time for a change,” Kuhlmann told </span><i><span>PC Gamer</span></i><span>. “There were some things that had been going on for a long time that I’d not been super happy with.”<br> </span></p> <h2>Communication breakdowns on<em> Starfield</em></h2> <p><span>Much of this unhappiness, Kuhlmann explained, revolved around Bethesda’s growth from a handful of developers making games in a basement office to hundreds of people across four studios that were managed by Microsoft. No longer could they just pop in on each other to discuss something and get a quick decision from trusted leaders like executive producer Todd Howard.</span></p>

 <p><span>Instead, senior developer responsibilities were becoming more managerial, and everything had to go through several layers of bureaucracy. Kuhlmann described the environment as prone to “communication breakdowns,” attributing some of Bethesda’s recent development struggles to this bloated, hands-off structure. </span><i><span>Starfield</span></i><span> teams, for instance, were often confused about what they were supposed to be doing as discussion filtered through the various studio leads.</span></p>

 <p><span>“The expectation was your job can’t be also making content if you’re actually managing that scope of the project,” Kuhlmann said. “I didn’t want to work that way, because I like making games and being hands-on. It had gotten to a scale beyond where I was really enjoying working in that environment.”</span></p>

 <h2>An <em>Elder Scrolls 6</em> cliffhanger</h2> <p><span>This shift in priorities, combined with Howard retracting a previous promise to make Kuhlmann lead designer on </span><i><span>The Elder Scrolls 6</span></i><span>, signaled to the veteran it was time to leave Bethesda. Kuhlmann, for his part, does acknowledge it was a smart decision to change his potential responsibilities on the still unreleased game, as he probably wouldn’t have liked the job much due to Bethesda’s new development woes.</span></p>

 <p><span>As for what he envisioned for </span><i><span>The Elder Scrolls 6</span></i><span>, Kuhlmann likened his rough ideas to </span><i><span>Star Wars</span></i><span> sequel </span><i><span>The Empire Strikes Back</span></i><span>: The bad guys would have won, setting up the main conflict of </span><i><span>The Elder Scrolls 7</span></i><span>. The protracted AAA release schedule, however, would likely have made a cliffhanger of that magnitude “unfeasible.”</span></p>

 <p><span>“That’s not a good way to end a game and say, yeah, we’ll see you in 10, 15 years,” Kuhlmann said.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-6-starfield-bethesda-tes-2000660653]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Pokopia: Everything We Know About The Animal Crossing-Style Life Sim]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-switch-2-multiplayer-ditto-2000660646</link>
            <guid>1408624</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>It’s the 30th anniversary of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span> this year, and while there are probably big RPG announcements on the way, the first major game we know is coming this year is something a little bit different. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-animal-crossing-switch-2-nintendo-direct-2000625331"><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a> <span>is an </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-tips-guide-2000660180"><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span>-style life sim</span></a><span> in which you help rehabilitate a desolate town into a habitat livable for Pokémon. It seems to be </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s play at the “cozy” genre, but it may have some dark undertones based on what we’ve seen. Here’s everything we know so far.</span></p> <h2><b>The premise</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>stars a Ditto who transforms into a human, whose form you will be able to customize. It is heavily implied that this human form is meant to embody Ditto’s trainer, who is missing as of the beginning of the game.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>They meet a graying Tangrowth called Professor Tangrowth, with whom they decide to help rebuild a desecrated town into a livable space, complete with specialized habitats to attract new Pokémon residents. Along the way, Ditto will learn new abilities that will help it cultivate its growing town, using water attacks to water plants and fire ones to cook and burn objects. Ditto can also transform into other Pokémon for traversal’s sake, turning into a Lapras to swim between areas, for instance, or a Dragonite to fly across great distances.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>As you build your plot of land back up, Pokémon will flock to it and soon you’ll have a little community of critters. They’ll come to you with requests for how to make the town better, and that will attract more Pokémon to your space. The more people that show up, the more you’ll need to build homes and other buildings to fill up the town, such as houses, Pokémon Centers, and other utilities.</span></p>

  <h2><b>New Pokémon</b></h2> <p><span>While there haven’t been any new Pokémon species announced for </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>, a few returning monsters have named variants. Peakychu is a pale-white Pikachu that has an almost ghostly aura about her. Professor Tangrowth has white vines on the top of its head as if it’s an older grass-type Pokémon, and it also wears glasses and a broken Technical Machine on its head to look like a human doctor. Mosslax is a Snorlax that has been asleep for so long it’s been wrapped in vegetation. And lastly, Smearguru is a Smeargle covered in plant splotches. As best as we can tell, these are just named characters and are still considered members of the same existing species. I would be surprised if any of them showed up in the RPGs as usable party members, though.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <h2><b>Is it post-apocalyptic?&nbsp;</b></h2> <p><span>There’s a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400"><span>running theory</span></a><span> that </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>might be set in some kind of dark, post-apocalyptic future version of the Kanto region from </span><i><span>Pokémon Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>. Professor Tangrowth says he hasn’t seen humans in a while, and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-map-kanto-region-post-apocalypse-leak-2000650529"><span>some of the areas</span></a><span> we’ve seen do seem to resemble areas from the original games. Also, each of the “new” Pokémon has some element to them that is giving post-apocalypse. Mosslax has been sleeping so long that nature is reclaiming it, Peakychu is either dead or dying, and Smearguru has seemingly been painting so much that it hasn’t had a proper shower in a while. Will the game actually explore this, or will it just be a haunting truth in the background of an otherwise cozy game? We’re not sure yet.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Multiplayer</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>will include a cooperative multiplayer mode for up to four players, either by connecting online with multiple game owners, or using GameShare to play with a second player who doesn’t own the game. When using GameShare, the second player can play on the original Switch system, but the game will only be natively playable on Switch 2.</span></p>

 <h2><b>It’s a game-key card</b></h2> <p><span>Unfortunately, </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>’s physical copies will include </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-pokemon-pokopia-game-key-card-2000642940"><span>a game-key card</span></a><span>, which means the cartridge you put in your system won’t actually contain the game data. Instead, it will just act as a key to tell your Switch 2 to download the game onto your system through the eShop.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>But when is it coming out?</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia </span></i><span>is coming to Switch 2 on March 5.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-switch-2-multiplayer-ditto-2000660646]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Starts Handing Out Brutal Permanent Bans To Its Worst Cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-permanent-bans-cheaters-stream-sniping-2000660615</link>
            <guid>1408582</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>The word 'BANNED' across an Arc Raiders screenshot.</span> © Embark Studios / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Since the New Year, discussions about <em>Arc Raiders</em> have shifted from near-unadulterated praise (for everything but its use of AI voices) to growing concerns over the game’s cheating problem. Developer Embark has already started making moves to improve this, first removing access to the console in the PC version, and now issuing some quite surprisingly dramatic bans to those it’s catching stream-sniping.</p> <p>Things started getting heated around January 6 <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-cheaters-ninja-shroud-embark-patch-2000657708">when streamer Shroud expressed his frustration</a> during a live broadcast, uttering “What’s the point of fuckin’ playing?” as he encountered so many issues. He was joined by other big names like Ninja and Nadeshot in making it clear that if something didn’t change soon, the high-profile players were likely to move on to other games.</p>

 <p>At the same time, others were complaining that PC players were able to access the Unreal Engine console within the game and switch off various visual settings such that they could see other players with effectively supernatural vision. By January 13, Embark released a new patch that nerfed a couple of elements that were spoiling PvP, while also preventing key card spoof cheats. This followed a hotfix that removed the console from the PC build, with the explanation that it was never supposed to have been available. And this all followed an announcement on the game’s Discord that <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-devs-say-they-have-big-plans-to-stop-the-current-wave-of-cheaters-2000658425">there were longer-term plans in place</a> for addressing the wider cheating concerns.</p>

 <p>Today, it seems, Embark has begun better wielding the banhammer. According to various posts on Reddit and X, streamers have reported that those players engaging in stream sniping are finally receiving retribution, while others have been posting images of ban messages to social media.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">not even 30 minutes later and theyre banned😭 <a href="https://t.co/QxBqjMaGo5">https://t.co/QxBqjMaGo5</a> <a href="https://t.co/aY2AtwALEC">pic.twitter.com/aY2AtwALEC</a></p> <p>— aimkey (@aimkeyx) <a href="https://twitter.com/aimkeyx/status/2012139292001448355?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 16, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>And these aren’t 24-hour slaps on the wrist, either. One image of a ban posted to X by user @aimkeyx begins, “Permanently suspended,” with accompanying text reading:</p>

 <blockquote><p>“Your account has been permanently suspended for behavior that violates our code of conduct. Due to the severity of your violation, access to your account will not be restored.”</p></blockquote> <p>This is a big step up from the 30-day bans that were being issued previously.</p> <p>The few examples we’ve been able to find so far seem to focus on stream snipers. These are people who either deliberately try their luck to get into the same lobby as a streamer, or use external software to ensure they do should the streamer make the mistake of leaving the UUID for their game session visible at the bottom of the screen. While the former might seem unlikely to work often enough for a person to ensure to match up, you have to factor in that should a streamer have tens of thousands of viewers, there could be a couple of hundred people attempting to cheat this way, making the chances of <em>someone</em> managing it a lot higher. And of course once in the same lobby, they can use the livestream footage to gain an advantage over the streamer. But it does seem to suggest that Embark is taking the issue seriously.</p>

 <p>One streamer who claims to have been caught in the crossfire of all this is Tfue, who found he had a 30-day suspension from <em>Arc Raiders</em> a few days ago. Many suggested it could be because Tfue brought up the console on his stream to show how it could be exploited, although he claims he didn’t actually use it. Others made unsupported accusations about the use of various macros, which Tfue strongly denied. Eventually the Twitch streamer with 11.4 million followers had his account restored, seeming to suggest it was an error.</p>

  <p>Who knows! Tfue’s ban was clearly one of the more regular 30-day sin-binnings, rather than these new permanent exclusions. It’ll be interesting to see if things improve for streamers, and then hopefully for the wider PvP audience for the game.</p> <p>Meanwhile, can I suggest a far better way to play? This is my favorite&nbsp;<em>Arc Raiders&nbsp;</em>clip of all time:</p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-permanent-bans-cheaters-stream-sniping-2000660615]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>