<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Is Running Out Of Chances, So I’m Glad It’s Finally Taking Some Real Swings]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-stadium-season-15-spotlight-preview-1851761919</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-is-running-out-of-chances-so-i%E2%80%99m-glad-it%E2%80%99s-finally-taking-some-real-swings.1108596/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-stadium-season-15-spotlight-preview-1851761919<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I never thought I’d become a lapsed <em>Overwatch 2 </em>player, but that’s what I’ve been lately. I barely touched season 14, and that lack of interest was the culmination of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anniversary-pve-story-events-skins-shop-1851665897&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anniversary-pve-story-events-skins-shop-1851665897">years of stagnation</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-skins-characters-reddit-steam-2023-1851119014&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-skins-characters-reddit-steam-2023-1851119014">broken promises</a></span> finally pushing me away. Yeah, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span><em> </em>also showed up and took my time, but even if <em>Overwatch</em>’s most competent competitor in years hadn’t come out, I don’t know that I would have stuck with Blizzard’s hero shooter for much longer. And I don’t think I’ve been alone in feeling that way. For several seasons Blizzard has relied on expensive cosmetics and the occasional <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-avatar-last-airbender-kiriko-venture-genji-1851719903&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-avatar-last-airbender-kiriko-venture-genji-1851719903">high-profile collaborations</a></span> to hold players’ attention. The game is in desperate need of a change, lest the once-megalithic shooter find itself completely irrelevant in the volatile live-service market. After spending a few hours playing the new Stadium mode and messing around with the MOBA-like Perks system, I’m cautiously optimistic that Blizzard is finally getting the game on the right track.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,197298" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In talking with developers about all the changes coming to <em>Overwatch 2</em>, I came away from the Blizzard campus feeling like the team had finally stopped being so precious about what the <em>Overwatch </em>experience is and decided to start experimenting with what it could be. I’ve spent hundreds of hours playing characters like Soldier: 76, Sombra, and Lifeweaver, and their kits are embedded into my muscle memory. Unless a hero has received a major rework, most characters in <em>Overwatch </em>have played pretty much the same way for years. Strategies form based on one defined playstyle, metas with “optimal” team compositions develop, and eventually, players get into a monotonous groove. Blizzard and <em>Overwatch </em>fans have spent so long arguing over things like bringing back the 6v6 format and balancing heroes in a particular way that any thought of what could actually reinvigorate the game had fallen by the wayside.</p><figure id="" data-id="1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-recommend-id="image://1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The UI for picking Orisa's minor perks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The UI for picking Orisa's minor perks." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-recommend-id="image://1f477dfe78e04587c28cdeec1ca53fb4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The UI for picking Orisa's minor perks." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Going back to the 6v6 format was never going to be the shot in the arm a game that has lost this much cultural cache needed. What might work, however, are some of the changes Blizzard is bringing to the core <em>Overwatch </em>game, as well as the introduction of the new Stadium mode, which is unlike anything we’ve ever seen in the shooter before. But before we tackle that monster, let’s start with Perks, the new system being added to the base <em>Overwatch 2 </em>experience you know and love. These are tweaks to existing abilities that can fundamentally change how a hero is played. I was only able to play with a handful of heroes to test out their new kits, but I was pleasantly surprised at how the smallest change can make a hero feel very different.</p><p>Take, for example, Ramattra. The tank thrives in multiple scenarios as he swaps between his more <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://overwatch.fandom.com/wiki/Team_Composition#Poke&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://overwatch.fandom.com/wiki/Team_Composition#Poke" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">poke-driven</a></span> defensive form and his brawler Nemesis form. When I was able to pick between two of his Perks, I was given the option to turn his Ravenous Vortex ability—which has him fire off an orb that typically grounds airborne enemies where it lands and does light damage over time—into something else entirely. This included having the projectile explode if it made direct contact with an enemy, dragging them to the ground with some more precision, or allowing Ramattra to heal himself if he stood inside the vortex. As someone who wants his tank to be capable of sustaining as much damage as possible, the latter was much more appealing to me. But if I’d been facing a pesky flight-based hero like Pharah, I could see myself going the other route. Adapting to the situation in front of you is core to the <em>Overwatch </em>experience, as switching between heroes is a pillar of how you play. But with Perks, those adaptations can finally come from within a hero’s kit.</p><p>Another hero I played with was Orisa, who has undergone significant changes from the more stationary, defense-driven tank she was in the original <em>Overwatch</em>. I have adapted to her brawling, battering-ram-style kit in <em>Overwatch 2</em>, but I miss throwing down a barrier and holding space for my team. Something interesting Blizzard is doing with Perks is bringing back old abilities that have been missing from some heroes’ kits for years. Orisa can swap out her Javelin and get her old shield back. Bastion can self-heal again after losing the ability in his <em>Overwatch 2 </em>rework. The idea that old kits could be reintegrated into <em>Overwatch 2 </em>is one of the most exciting things about Perks because so many of <em>Overwatch</em>’s heroes have lost some of that creative spark that made them appealing in the first place. </p><p>Sombra was once one of my favorite heroes to play, but thanks to some <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-sombra-season-13-patch-notes-ramattra-1851673081&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-sombra-season-13-patch-notes-ramattra-1851673081">frustrating reworks</a></span> that have sanded down what made her stand out in the growing roster I’ve played her less and less. <em>Overwatch 2 </em>has become so fixated on forcing players to carry out team fights the “right” way that the creativity and skill expression of certain heroes have been lost. Perks feel like a correction because not only is it allowing heroes to find new utility, but it’s putting choices in the player’s hands, rather than watering down heroes in pursuit of “balance” and “fairness.”</p><figure id="" data-id="0964db67d55628c964e3aeebf3ac90ae" data-recommend-id="image://0964db67d55628c964e3aeebf3ac90ae" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Kiriko's mod customization screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Kiriko's mod customization screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0964db67d55628c964e3aeebf3ac90ae" data-recommend-id="image://0964db67d55628c964e3aeebf3ac90ae" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Kiriko's mod customization screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If Perks are about giving players a chance to build out their favorite hero’s kit to their liking, Stadium is that philosophy cranked up to 11. Blizzard says the new mode is meant to be the third pillar alongside Quickplay and Competitive, and its retooling of <em>Overwatch</em>’s gameplay loop is one of the most exciting changes Blizzard is implementing. Stadium is a 5v5 mode that takes away one of the cores of <em>Overwatch </em>by locking you into one hero for the duration of a match. Instead of swapping between heroes for its seven rounds, you’ll spend the entire match focusing on creating a custom build for one character. At the beginning of each round, you’ll redeem earned currency to buy Mods that can give your hero of choice buffs, tweak their abilities, and possibly completely redefine how the character functions.</p><p> I was able to play a few matches as both Soldier: 76 and Kiriko. Having played most of my <em>Overwatch </em>matches as the grumpy gay grandpa, I was most curious about what directions Blizzard would let me take him, as the team says the goal of Stadium is to capture the “fantasy” of each hero, dialing their capabilities up to almost absurd levels. The Mods I picked for Soldier leaned into making him a bit more of a brawler. I upped his health and gave him armor, but I also changed his healing station from a placeable tool to one that radiated from him as I pushed forward alongside my team.   </p><p>Kiriko, meanwhile, was the hero with whom I saw the absurd fantasy Blizzard’s going for most clearly. In base <em>Overwatch 2</em>, the support hero is able to teleport next to a teammate to give them some healing, but Stadium allowed me to Mod a different kind of teleport into her kit that didn’t require a target, and could reach much farther away than it would have with that restriction. I could retreat quickly from a tough situation, or pop up next to an unsuspecting enemy to throw a kunai right between their eyes. These are only a few examples of how Stadium lets you alter how a hero plays, and it’s a bit of a bummer that it will only launch with a select 14 heroes because there are so many characters I want to see reach this potential.</p><figure id="" data-id="47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-recommend-id="image://47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-recommend-id="image://47ee7e2891c8620621dc694dfb8db53d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1919" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Soldier: 76 shooting enemies in a third-person view." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Even if I end up becoming a Soldier one-trick again, Stadium allows me to reconsider what I think an <em>Overwatch </em>hero can and should be after years of Blizzard defining that for us. Even things I think are a net positive for the game like the option of Role Queue (I just need to know I’ll have a support hero on my team, sorry) are based on trying to restrict how people play, so Blizzard giving this much freedom and control to players is the most exciting thing about <em>Overwatch 2 </em>right now. </p><p>Blizzard has spent so many years trying to wrangle the game<em> </em>into a polished, pristine competitive product that it almost lost sight of why anyone cared about it in the first place. Stadium and Perks feel like Blizzard <em>finally</em> letting go of the reins and letting players roam free and make their own destiny. Will Perks be enough to put the game back on top? Can Stadium get rid of the bad taste in my mouth left by the company reportedly canceling the story mode we were promised? Only if Blizzard commits to this new direction, rather than falling back into the restrictive mindset that has alienated players over the years.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Just Launched A Discord And It's Already A Mess Of Rabid GTA 6 Fans]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gta-6-rockstar-game-official-discord-server-launched-1851762536</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-just-launched-a-discord-and-its-already-a-mess-of-rabid-gta-6-fans.1108593/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/gta-6-rockstar-game-official-discord-server-launched-1851762536<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-vi-first-trailer-2-a-year-later-1851714995&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-vi-first-trailer-2-a-year-later-1851714995"><em>Grand Theft Auto 6</em></a></span>'s next trailer isn’t here yet, but Rockstar Games does have something <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-release-date-delay-borderlands-4-fall-2025-1851757501&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-release-date-delay-borderlands-4-fall-2025-1851757501"><em>GTA 6</em></a></span>-related to share with you: An official Discord server where you can chat with thousands of other fans who can’t wait for the next entry in the series. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196299" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="385" data-playlist="196299,196424,194341" data-current="196299"><div><p>You Should Play Grand Theft Auto III Before GTA VI | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196299/196299_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21849.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On February 12, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;http://discord.gg/rockstargames&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="http://discord.gg/rockstargames" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rockstar Games quietly launched an official Discord server</a></span> and shared the news with some fan sites and content creators. Earlier today, Rockstar officially confirmed the server was in fact created by the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/4kk8497a128421/celebrate-valentine-s-day-in-gta-online&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/4kk8497a128421/celebrate-valentine-s-day-in-gta-online" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">company, via a newswire post</a></span>. (There had previously been some debate as to whether it was official.) But even before that confirmation, within a few hours of launching the server had thousands of users and the place quickly descended into madness. </p><p>I was around for the official Discord server’s first few hours and poked my head into the channel dedicated to <em>GTA 6</em> to find thousands of messages whizzing by every few seconds. It was  impossible to read unless I scrolled up and paused chat. However, the chat wasn’t worth reading, as most of it was people yelling about wanting the second <em>GTA 6</em> trailer or hurling insults and slurs at each other. </p><p>Some of these messages were deleted, but were quickly replaced by more. People also <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/sigmaandsigma/status/1889776086432563523&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/sigmaandsigma/status/1889776086432563523" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spammed erotic ASCII art</a></span>, flags, and bombarded chat with wild theories about<em> GTA 6</em> leaks, trailers, and release dates. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-6-fans-moon-theory-november-22-new-trailer-rockstar-1851702355&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-fans-moon-theory-november-22-new-trailer-rockstar-1851702355">It was like a concentrated and even more insane version of the <em>GTA </em>community.</a></span></p><p>Perhaps the oddest thing I noticed was the Rockstar Games account in the server replying with obviously AI-generated nonsense whenever people asked it questions about anything.</p><figure id="" data-id="b94c3fae0d60724a1361e0b331cecf72" data-recommend-id="image://b94c3fae0d60724a1361e0b331cecf72" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b94c3fae0d60724a1361e0b331cecf72" data-recommend-id="image://b94c3fae0d60724a1361e0b331cecf72" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This stopped within the first hour of the server launching, but it was strange while it lasted. I’ve reached out to Rockstar Games about the bot and where it went. </p><p>Things have calmed down a lot compared to those first few hours. Some channels, like one dedicated to classic Rockstar Games, isn’t actually filled with spam, and the<em> GTA 6</em> channel has a 10 minute chat cooldown activated which has made it much easier to actually read and use. It’s still filled with people yelling about the next trailer and lying about how they’ve played<em> GTA 6 </em>or seen new gameplay leaks, but at least now you can read each of those posts without having to pause everything. </p><p>Of course, people are assuming that Rockstar Games has launched this new Discord server in preparation for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gta-vi-gta6-first-trailer-gameplay-footage-details-leak-1851005265&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gta-vi-gta6-first-trailer-gameplay-footage-details-leak-1851005265"><em>GTA 6</em>'s next big trailer</a></span>, which is possible. But it also feels like Rockstar wants to have more control over the community and what it posts, and this server would provide that. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>