<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 01:35:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Charging Players To Return To Tutorial Island Despite Promising No Paywalled Locations]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/skate-4-grom-paywall-location-new-map-island-2000671466</link>
            <guid>1441249</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Next month, season three goes live in EA’s free-to-play reboot of <em>Skate</em>. The big new addition in the upcoming season is Grom, an island that players can visit and skate around on. However, the island, which is a slightly updated version of the tutorial island, is essentially locked behind a paywall, which goes against a promise EA made before launch.</p> <p>On February 19, <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/skate/skate/news/dev-update-s3-skatepass-grom-and-the-future">EA and Full Circle posted a blog</a> talking about some of the changes coming in <em>Skate’s</em> third season, which goes live on March 10. In the post, EA revealed that a new island will be available to skaters in the next season. But accessing this island won’t be as simple or free as fast traveling to it once the update is live.</p>

 <p>During the first month of season three, skate.Pass Premium holders will be able to visit Grom as much as they want, whenever they want. For those who haven’t paid for <em>Skate’s</em> battle pass, they’ll be locked out until April. That’s when a “very special multi-week event” will happen, and all players will be invited to Grom’s “grand opening.” After that wraps up, free access to Grom will be restricted once more to Premium pass owners. Non-paying players will be able to spend 500 rip chips, an in-game currency you earn by playing, to buy a day pass to the island.</p> <figure><figcaption>An overhead comparison of Grom during the game’s tutorial and Grom during the event provided by EA.&nbsp; (EA/Kotaku)</figcaption></figure> <p>Did you get all that? A bit confusing, but somewhat understandable for a free-to-play game. However, there’s a problem. Before the launch of <em>Skate</em> in September last year, EA made some promises about the game. <a href="https://youtu.be/FAMgtFyrQLk?t=453">In a video posted in July 2022</a>, the devs said that when they started exploring the free-to-play model, they had to set some “hard ground rules to follow.” One of those rules included “No map areas locked behind paywalls.” Whoops! It also doesn’t help that the new island is just a slightly expanded version of the game’s tutorial island, something that is very clear to see in EA’s own comparison image in the blog.</p>

 <h2>The backlash to <em>Skate</em> paywalling an island</h2> <p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r9a7oh/so_devs/">As you might expect</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r98r3g/ea_did_it_again/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><em>Skate</em> players weren’t happy</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r98r3g/ea_did_it_again/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">about all of this</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r9akiw/what_is_this_full_circle/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">and started flooding social media</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r997il/isle_of_grom/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">and Reddit</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1r98un6/huh_whats_that/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">with posts</a> <a href="https://x.com/nkocharm/status/2024534025692430345">pointing out the promise EA had broken</a>. This eventually led to the official <em>Skate</em> account on <a href="https://x.com/skate/status/2024539083259654345">X posting a statement about Grom</a>.</p>

 <p>“We launched <em>Skate</em> in Early Access so we could build it with players, not behind closed doors,” EA wrote. “Since September, we’ve been updating the world, tweaking characters, and adding features our players have been asking for, and there is lots more coming. Yes, sometimes plans have to change. That’s part of the deal when you’re building in public. We’re here, we’re listening, and we’re going to keep shaping <em>Skate</em> together.”</p> <p><em>Kotaku</em> has reached out to EA for more information.</p> <p>While it is true that game development is messy, going back on this promise has opened up a can of worms. EA also promised that <em>Skate</em> would not contain paid loot boxes or pay-to-win elements. Why should players trust EA to stick to those promises if it is willing to deviate on this issue and toss an island behind a paywall, even one that can be avoided by grinding for currency?</p>

 <p>Regardless, I’m not shocked EA has decided to renege. The company is likely under pressure to make more money across all of its games after announcing its upcoming deal to sell itself to <a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-saudi-bioware-ai-lgbtq-debt-junk-bond-2000630647">Saudi Arabia and private equity goons for $55 billion</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/skate-4-grom-paywall-location-new-map-island-2000671466]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XCOM Designer Shows Off Canceled AI-Fueled Life Sim After Abruptly Shutting Down Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xcom-designer-shows-off-canceled-ai-fueled-life-sim-after-abruptly-shutting-down-studio-2000671432</link>
            <guid>1441216</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/how-a-rabid-xcom-fan-became-the-designer-of-enemy-unkno-5890749">Jake Solomon</a>, who previously served as creative director on <a href="https://kotaku.com/xcom-2-the-kotaku-review-1757343867"><em>XCOM 2</em></a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-midnight-suns-impressions-xcom-firaxis-pc-rpg-1849793171"><em>Marvel’s Midnight Suns</em></a>, announced today that the studio he founded, Midsummer Studios, is closing down. Solomon created Midsummer Studios in 2024 with the goal of “reinvent[ing] the life sim genre,” according to a <a href="https://www.midsummerstudios.com/news/studio-announcement">press release</a> from the time. <a href="https://x.com/SolomonJake/status/2024510423190430181">In a post on X</a> announcing the closure, Solomon wrote, “We built a studio, we made a game, and I’m really proud of both. Before we close the doors at Midsummer Studios I’d like to share a glimpse of <em>Burbank</em>, the game we poured our hearts into. It’s like “Life Sims + <em>The Truman Show</em>,” but it’s more than that. I believe people are storytellers, and I want them to share whatever stories and characters they can dream up. Burbank let’s you do that.”</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">We built a studio, we made a game, and I'm really proud of both. Before we close the doors at Midsummer Studios I'd like to share a glimpse of Burbank, the game we poured our hearts into.</p> <p>It's like "Life Sims + The Truman Show," but it's more than that. I believe people are… <a href="https://t.co/RuYvDhdEZO">pic.twitter.com/RuYvDhdEZO</a></p> <p>— Jake Solomon (@SolomonJake) <a href="https://twitter.com/SolomonJake/status/2024510423190430181?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 19, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Solomon also shared some pre-alpha footage from the game, which showcased an ambitious system in which players could customize their own television shows and write their own stories. In order to do that, <a href="https://x.com/SolomonJake/status/2024511003917009256">Solomon disclosed in a follow-up post</a>, “Our characters use AI for memory, reasoning and speech. That’s what let’s you create anyone you want and drop them in any story you write. But all of our art is created by our talented artists. We had no interest in replacing *any* developers with AI.” Solomon did not provide a reason for the studio’s closure.</p>

 <p>Studio closures and layoffs are arguably the games industry’s biggest crisis right now. Earlier today, <a href="https://kotaku.com/bluepoint-sony-playstation-ps5-god-war-2000671390">Sony announced it would close Bluepoint Games</a>, the studio behind the very well-received <em>Demon’s Souls</em> and <em>Shadow of the Colossus</em> remakes.&nbsp;In a 2024 interview with <em><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/life-sim/xcom-designer-jake-solomon-is-done-with-turn-based-strategy-and-is-now-making-a-life-sim-inspired-by-the-small-town-drama-of-gilmore-girls/">PC Gamer</a></em>, Solomon said that Midsummer Studios had 11 employees, with plans to add two more. At the time of the studio’s creation, those included co-founder and <a href="https://kotaku.com/civilization-beyond-earth-the-kotaku-review-1649058397"><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization: Beyond Earth</em></a> designer Will Miller, and Grant Rodiek, a longtime designer on the<em>&nbsp;Sims</em> franchise. It seems likely that, with Midsummer’s closure and <em>Burbank</em>‘s cancelation, all of those employees will be out of a job.</p> <p>Still, Solomon tried to end the announcement on a positive note. “We have moments playing this game where characters come alive in a way we’ve never experienced. And for an old game developer like me that’s special. What you’re about to see is definitely pre-alpha. But this game was a dream of mine, our team made it come true, so watch and dream with us,” he wrote.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xcom-designer-shows-off-canceled-ai-fueled-life-sim-after-abruptly-shutting-down-studio-2000671432]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta’s Virtual Reality App Ditching VR To Make A Roblox Clone]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/metas-virtual-reality-app-ditching-vr-to-make-a-roblox-clone-2000671434</link>
            <guid>1441189</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>In 2021, Facebook became Meta and the company claimed its <span data-start="12.945" data-end="13.235">focus</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="13.270" data-end="13.398">would</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="13.433" data-end="13.503">be</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="13.537" data-end="13.584">to</span> “<a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/facebook-company-is-now-meta/"><span data-start="13.653" data-end="13.874">bring</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="13.932" data-end="14.002">the</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="14.037" data-end="14.443">metaverse</span>&nbsp;<span data-start="14.478" data-end="14.547">to</span>&nbsp;</a><span data-start="14.629" data-end="15.012"><a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/facebook-company-is-now-meta/">life.</a>” It launched <em>Horizon Worlds,</em> a VR metaverse that people could explore and create worlds in. It looked bad and wasn’t great, but it was supposedly the future. Five years later, Meta’s metaverse is ditching VR and spinning <em>Worlds</em> into a Roblox clone after burning <a href="https://medium.com/analysts-corner/the-100-billion-metaverse-hallucination-6f036155a869">$70+ billion</a> on virtual and augmented reality.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><a href="https://developers.meta.com/horizon/blog/2026-vr-state-of-the-union-horizon-mobile-focus/">On February 19</a>, in a blog post on Meta’s official website, the company announced its plans to split its VR and Reality Labs sector from <a href="https://kotaku.com/facebook-metaverse-horizon-worlds-vr-oculus-quest-2-cha-1848436740"><em>Horizon Worlds</em>, its free-to-play 3D metaverse</a> that supports user-created worlds and games. The company claims that doing this will “create more space for both products to grow.” The plan now is to fully pivot <em>Worlds</em> into a mobile, non-VR software experience that will resemble a Roblox clone more than the virtual metaverse depicted in <em>Ready Player One.&nbsp;</em></p>

 <p>“We started <em>Worlds</em> for VR with a small crew of dedicated creators who set out to build immersive experiences on their own,” said Meta. “Last year, we began to experiment with <em>Worlds</em> as a mobile platform, and we saw positive momentum. Now, to truly change the game and tap into a much larger market, we’re going all-in on mobile.”</p>  <p>And when I say <em>Horizon Worlds</em> is becoming a Roblox clone, I mean that quite literally. In the blog post announcing this big shake-up, Meta name-drops three experiences that have landed on <em>Worlds</em> in recent months and become hugely popular:<em><a href="https://kotaku.com/grow-a-garden-roblox-5-million-active-users-record-pc-1851781824"> Grow A Garden</a>, Steal A Brainrot, </em>and <em>Yeet Yourself</em>. (Though oddly, after posting the blog, Meta removed the last two games. Hmm.)</p>

 <p>These are popular Roblox experiences, and it makes it clear what Meta is really doing with this pivot. Not many people wanted to strap a VR headset to their face to play bad games. But plenty of folks, including kids, are far more likely to hop into <em>Horizon Worlds</em> if it’s just a phone game they can hop into on a device they already own. Early testing proved that. When you consider that <a href="https://kotaku.com/why-the-video-game-industry-is-dying-2000671338">Roblox is one of the few parts of the game industry that is growing rapidly</a> and making tons of money, it makes sense that Meta would decide to take its bad VR Roblox clone, rip out the VR part, and hope to find success as a slop generator for kids.</p>

 <p>As for what this means for the future of virtual reality at Meta, the company claims it isn’t going anywhere. It says it has more VR hardware in development and plans to invest more in third-party VR devs. <a href="https://kotaku.com/meta-game-quest-vr-facebook-deadpool-sanzaru-twisted-pixel-layoffs-2000659376">But after the company sliced up its VR game studios last month</a>, well, it’s clear that if VR sticks around, it won’t be a main focus anymore at Meta. <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/meta/2025/meta-to-invest-600-billion-to-build-ai-data-centers-in-us/">Instead, the company is focused on AI. For now</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/metas-virtual-reality-app-ditching-vr-to-make-a-roblox-clone-2000671434]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Studios Boss Blames Bluepoint Shutdown On ‘Challenging Industry Environment’ Despite Recent Jump In Profits]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-email-bluepoint-hermen-hulst-studio-closing-why-2000671437</link>
            <guid>1441153</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Sony is shutting Bluepoint Games down <a href="https://kotaku.com/bluepoint-sony-playstation-ps5-god-war-2000671390">just five years after buying it</a>. Hermen Hulst said the decision was the result of an “increasingly challenging industry environment” in a note to staff on Thursday. It’s a shocking end for a studio that Hulst himself admits “delivered exceptional experiences for the PlayStation community” and comes despite a recent jump in profits for Sony’s gaming division.</p> <p>“I wanted to share an update from the Studio Business,” the message, a copy of which was viewed by<em> Kotaku</em>, began. “As I mentioned in the December Town Hall, 2025 had some strong highlights within PlayStation Studios. <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> launched to critical and commercial success, <em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em> further showcased our commitment to narrative excellence, and <em>Helldivers 2</em> and <em>MLB The Show</em> continue to drive on-going player engagement and revenue.”</p>

 <p>It continued:</p> <blockquote><p>At the same time, we’re operating in an increasingly challenging industry environment. Rising development costs, slowed industry growth, changing player behavior, and broader economic headwinds are making it harder to build games sustainably.</p> <p>To navigate this reality, we need to continue adapting and evolving. We’ve taken a close look at our business to ensure we’re delivering today while still well-positioned for the future. As a result, we will be closing Bluepoint Games in March.</p> <p>This decision was not made lightly. Bluepoint is an incredibly talented team and their technical expertise has delivered exceptional experiences for the PlayStation community. I want to thank everyone at Bluepoint for their creativity, craftmanship, and commitment to quality. Where possible, we will work to find opportunities for some impacted employees within our global network of studios.</p> <p>While I know this is hard news to hear, I’m confident in the direction we’re headed. Creativity, innovation, and building unforgettable experiences for players remain at the heart of PlayStation Studios. We have a robust roadmap for FY26, with much to look forward to in the months ahead. Thank you for your hard work and continued support.</p></blockquote> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">None of you saw this acquisition coming! 😊</p> <p>— Hermen Hulst (@hermenhulst) <a href="https://twitter.com/hermenhulst/status/1443594280250093569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The message will likely <a href="https://kotaku.com/sonys-ps5-era-studio-acquisition-spree-has-been-a-disaster-2000671404">give some fans a feeling of whiplash</a>. It mentions the need for tough cost-cutting before immediately praising Bluepoint’s work. Its most recent games, a PS5 remake of <em>Demon’s Souls</em> and a PS4 remake of <em>Shadow of the Colossus</em>, were both critically acclaimed. Sony reported in 2021 that <em>Demon’s Souls</em> sold 1.4 million copies in the hardware’s launch year.</p> <p>Instead of continuing to have Bluepoint remaster or remake popular classics, a strategy which has proven very lucrative for Capcom with <em>Resident Evil</em> and Bethesda with <em>The Elder Scrolls: Oblivion</em>, the Texas-based studio was put on a live-service spin-off of <em>God of War</em> which ended up being canned in early 2025. The great irony now is that Sony is finally remaking the original <em>God of War</em> trilogy but is about to close the most obvious candidate for the job. Bluepoint was one of the co-development partners on 2022’s <em>God of War Ragnarök</em>.</p>

 <p>And despite larger industry headwinds, Sony recently posted impressive profits. While overall sales across the gaming division were down year-over-year, profits for PlayStation last quarter <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ghost-of-yotei-outperforms-ghost-of-tsushima-to-bolster-sony-financials">rose 19 percent</a>. It even revised its forecast for the current quarter upwards. Bluepoint is the third recently acquired game studio Sony has shuttered in less than two years.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-email-bluepoint-hermen-hulst-studio-closing-why-2000671437]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher’s Lead Story Designer Says Ending Was A ‘Mistake’ He Had No Control Over]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/witcher-game-ending-cdpr-cd-projekt-red-geralt-2000671408</link>
            <guid>1441102</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Artur Ganszyniec’s 26-episode, 40-hour-long <a href="https://youtu.be/fwRtKBkq0N8?si=7_ARugH5g6fJwuER">playthrough of the first game</a> in </span><i><span>The Witcher</span></i><span> trilogy has finally come to an end, but the game developer, who served as lead story designer on the 2007 game, waited until the final five minutes of his trip down memory lane to drop the juiciest piece of info regarding its development. According to Ganszyniec, the writers at CD Projekt Red were “not really” involved in the creation of its final cutscene, and this “mistake” ultimately forced the team to take </span><i><span>The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings’</span></i><span> story in a completely different direction.</span></p> <p><span>As spotted by </span><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/the-witcher/original-witcher-story-lead-says-the-surprise-twist-at-the-end-was-a-mistake-because-instead-of-focusing-on-geralt-the-sequel-was-forced-into-a-story-about-witchers-who-are-killing-kings-for-some-reason/"><i><span>PC Gamer</span></i></a><span>, Ganszyniec decided to </span><a href="https://youtu.be/fwRtKBkq0N8?si=sMosOYVsDO_lHmR_&amp;t=5417"><span>reveal this information</span></a><span> as the final cutscene in </span><i><span>The Witcher</span></i><span> began to play. Those of you with good memories might remember that the game ends with the attempted assassination of King Foltest. After killing the would-be assassin, Geralt discovers that the culprit was a fellow witcher. This leads directly into the start of the second game, where we find Geralt locked up for his suspected part in the assassination.</span></p>

  <p><span>Turns out, Ganszyniec had no hand in writing the final cutscene. “The script for this…it was created not really involving the story team. So it was sort of, we weren’t really paying attention. And that was a mistake, I think.” As he explains, this is why the “open question” surrounding Geralt’s future that’s presented in the narrated section, which precedes the animated cutscene doesn’t match up with the conclusion. “Someone decided, like the board decided, or [CD Projekt co-founder] Michał Kiciński decided, that we needed an animated outro of the game.”</span></p> <p><span>This does explain why Geralt has suddenly teleported back to Vizima at the end of the game. The disconnect between Dandelion posing the open-ended question, “What then happened to the witcher?” in the closing narration and an ending cutscene that immediately answers said question also now makes sense, as the writers clearly intended for this to provide setup for something else entirely. On the plus side, Ganszyniec doesn’t seem bitter about the change, as he rounded off his playthrough by voicing his excitement for Fool’s Theory’s upcoming remake of </span><i><span>The Witcher</span></i><span>. “Let’s hope that the remake will be a really good game.”</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/witcher-game-ending-cdpr-cd-projekt-red-geralt-2000671408]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slay The Spire 2 Enters Early Access On The Busiest Possible Day]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/slay-the-spire-2-early-access-release-date-steam-trailer-2000671424</link>
            <guid>1441099</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I guess </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-vi-delayed-november-rockstar-games-2000641787"><span>in the year </span><i><span>Grand Theft Auto 6 </span></i><span>is coming out</span></a><span>, there are worse days for </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2</span></i><span>, the long-awaited sequel to the 2019 deckbuilding roguelike, to enter Early Access. But dang, Mega Crit sure picked a packed day to release this early build. The studio announced that </span><i><span>Slay the Spire 2 </span></i><span>will come to Steam on March 5, the same day </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-free-demo-beta-weekend-server-slam-2000668383"><i><span>Marathon</span></i></a> <span>and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-ghost-pikachu-peakychu-cloud-island-2000669710"><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a> <span>are launching. For a lot of folks, those games might not overlap, but if you’re interested in more than one of them, you’ll have to make some choices about how you spend your day.</span></p> <p><span>The announcement comes with a pretty slick animated trailer showing its various class characters kicking ass, but there’s also a bit of gross fantasy violence in there, so viewer discretion is advised if you’re squeamish.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Check out the trailer below:</span></p>   <p><i><span>Slay the Spire 2</span></i><span> was originally supposed to come to Early Access last year before being </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/slay-the-spire-2-is-now-a-2026-release-but-dont-blame-hornet-2000625257"><span>delayed into March late last year</span></a><span>. The team at Mega Crit said this was due to a combination of personal life disruptions and just a desire to add more to the sequel before it got into player’s hands., though they were also clear that it was not part of the spree of delays that came about as a result of </span><i><span>Hollow Knight: Silksong</span></i><span> finally getting a release date.</span></p>

 <p><span>“There’s no single dramatic reason,” the announcement read. “Some personal life stuff hit the team (everyone’s okay!), we kept saying ‘wouldn’t it be cool if…’ one too many times, and honestly, the game just needs more polish to meet our standards.” Thus another six months development before the game reaches players.”</span></p> <p><span>But the wait is nearly over now. The original </span><i><span>Slay the Spire </span></i><span>launched in 2019 </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/slay-the-spire-is-a-roguelike-card-game-and-im-hooked-1822608254"><span>after its own Early Access period</span></a><span>, and is considered one of the progenitors of the deckbuilding roguelike genre and a major player in its popularity in the years that followed. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/slay-the-spire-2-early-access-release-date-steam-trailer-2000671424]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>