<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:04:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox Player Performs Speedrunning Forensics To Uncover Fraud And Win Back World Record]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roblox-fall-guys-speedrun-world-record-fraud-2000657154</link>
            <guid>1398622</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A player who goes by Quinten was on their way to securing a <a href="https://kotaku.com/roblox-new-york-times-interview-baszucki-2000646174">Guinness World Record in Roblox</a> when they were beat out at the last moment by multiple speedruns that were so good, they seemed humanly impossible. A lesser player might have gone back to gambling on the Roblox ponies, but Quinten instead set out to prove that the new records were bogus. It worked.</p> <p>As <em><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/roblox/guiness-world-record-cheat">PCGamesN</a></em><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/roblox/guiness-world-record-cheat"> reports,</a>&nbsp;Quinten was competing for the world record in a Roblox game called <em>Ultimate Easy Obby</em> that has <a href="https://www.roblox.com/games/10760024537/Ultimate-Easy-Obby">over 100,000 reviews</a>. It’s a zany, single-player obstacle course similar to something you might find in <a href="https://kotaku.com/there-s-a-new-type-of-fall-guys-jackass-1846537028"><em>Fall Guys</em></a> and was published by Roblox in partnership with the Guinness World Record company. Last month, Quinten secured a time of 05:48:96 following an “insane back-and-forth battle” with another Roblox speedrunner. It was the result of tons of time spent “optimizing every corner and jump,” the 18-year-old Belgian wrote on Reddit.</p>

 <p>But then something bizarre happened. Quinten’s speedrun record was quickly beaten by three other random Roblox accounts. And not just by a little bit but six whole seconds. “For context: a 6-second gap on a speedrun this optimized is physically impossible,” they wrote. “It was heartbreaking to see a week of grinding ruined by scripts.” Undeterred, Quinten decided to speedrun an investigation into the mysterious rivals to find proof of the suspected cheating.</p>

  <p>This evidence fell into three main buckets. The first was bogus time stamps. <em>Ultimate Easy Obby</em> features a linear obstacle course consisting of 50 stages, but some of the mystery accounts’ timestamps were out of order. The new world record holder was also missing a “digital receipt” of ever having actually completed the race. “This proved he never actually touched the finish line trigger; he likely teleported a coordinate script to the end-game lobby, bypassing the verification check,” Quinten wrote.</p>

 <p>But the real nail in the coffin was painstaking frame-by-frame analysis of Quinten’s own best recorded time to show that shaving six seconds off it would be impossible. “I took my best run and calculated the theoretical maximum time save possible (perfect pixels, zero drag),” they wrote. “Even with a TAS (Tool-Assisted Speedrun) level of perfection, the times the cheaters posted were mathematically impossible within the game’s physics engine.”</p>

 <p>Surprisingly, it all worked. The evidence was submitted to Guinness which then went back, reviewed the records, and re-validated Quinten’s as the true World Record. “It felt amazing to successfully lobby a major organization to reverse verified records based on user-submitted digital forensics,” they wrote. The king of <em>Ultimate Easy Obby&nbsp;</em>can once again rest easy knowing at least one more small sliver of fraud has been carved out of Roblox.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roblox-fall-guys-speedrun-world-record-fraud-2000657154]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Kicks Off 2026 With Two Massive Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-resident-evil-village-star-wars-outlaws-2000657166</link>
            <guid>1398583</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Kay and Lady Dimitrescu.</span> © Ubisoft / Capcom / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>While the first two games added to Xbox Game Pass in January might not knock your socks off, it’s what’s coming later this month that should bring some New Year cheer. By January 13, Game Pass subscribers will have access to Ubisoft’s enormously underrated <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>, and just a week later the stunning&nbsp;<em>Resident Evil Village</em> brings our favorite tall lady to the service.</p> <p>Added today, January 6, are drunken twin-stick shooter <em>Brews &amp; Bastards&nbsp;</em>(no, me neither, but I’ll be installing it this evening) and <em>Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition.&nbsp;</em>Then as soon as tomorrow, last year’s underdog first-person action game <em>Atomfall</em> will be added to the subscription platform, alongside 2025 roguelite sequel <em>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die</em>, online multiplayer soccer sim&nbsp;<em>Rematch</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</em>‘s&nbsp;<em>Master Crafted Edition</em>, hopefully now fixed <a href="https://kotaku.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-master-crafted-refunds-ps5-1851785318">from all its many issues on launch</a>.</p>

 <p>Then, but another day later, we get the original&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy</em> in its 2024 “remodeled” version, seemingly plucked from the&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-pixel-remaster-xbox-tokyo-game-show-1851658451"><em>Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster</em></a><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-pixel-remaster-xbox-tokyo-game-show-1851658451"> bundle</a>.</p> <p>You’ll have to somehow wait another five days, until January 13, before the next update, when <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> arrives, and hopefully a whole new raft of people can discover this fantastic open-galaxy criminal ’em up, after it suffered from both a buggy launch and a concerted anti-woke campaign from the worst people on the internet. Seriously, if you were put off by any of the noise during its 2024 release, this is a great chance to put that right. The stealth is&nbsp;<em>so&nbsp;</em>much better now.</p>

 <p>After&nbsp;<em>My Little Pony: A Zephyr Heights Mystery</em> shows up Jan 15, on the 20th arrives <a href="https://kotaku.com/ikumi-nakamura-sentenced-to-horny-jail-for-lady-dimit-1846919932">Lady Dimitrescu</a> in her size 25s via 2021’s <em>Resident Evil Village</em>, alongside metroidvania platformer <em>MIO: Memories in Orbit</em>, a day-one release.</p> <p>Microsoft giveth, but Microsoft taketh away, so to get all these new games we must sacrifice a bunch too. I don’t imagine too many tears will be shed over the five titles going away on January 15, however, all listed below. Here’s everything in one handy, bullet-pointed list:</p> <h2>January 6</h2> <ul> <li><em>Brews &amp; Bastards</em> (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series)</li> <li><em>Little Nightmares Enhanced Edition</em> (Cloud, Handheld, PC, Xbox Series)</li> </ul> <h2>January 7</h2> <ul> <li><em>Atomfall</em> (Cloud, Console, Handheld, PC)</li> <li><em>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die</em> (Cloud, Xbox Series, Handheld, PC)</li> <li><em>Rematch</em> (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series)</li> <li><em>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine – Master Crafted Edition</em> (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series)</li> </ul> <h2>January 8</h2> <ul> <li><em>Final Fantasy</em> (Cloud, Xbox Series, PC)</li> </ul> <h2>January 15</h2> <ul> <li><em>My Little Pony: A Zephyr Heights Mystery&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, Handheld, PC)</li> </ul> <h2>January 20</h2> <p><em>Resident Evil Village</em> (Cloud, Console, PC)</p> <p><em>MIO: Memories in Orbit</em> (Cloud, Handheld, PC, Xbox Series)</p> <h2>Leaving January 15</h2> <ul> <li><em>Flintlock: The Siege of Dawn </em>(Cloud, Handheld, PC, and Xbox Series X|S)</li> <li><em>Neon White&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, Handheld, and PC)</li> <li><em>Road 96&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, Handheld, and PC)</li> <li><em>The Ascent&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, Handheld, and PC)</li> <li><em>The Grinch Christmas Adventures&nbsp;</em>(Cloud, Console, Handheld, and PC)</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-resident-evil-village-star-wars-outlaws-2000657166]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Office Professional 2021 Hits an All-Time Low at 84% Off, Skip Subscription Fees With This One-Time Purchase]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-office-professional-2021-hits-an-all-time-low-at-84-off-skip-subscription-fees-with-this-one-time-purchase-2000656785</link>
            <guid>1398541</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Looking for a way to finally add the Microsoft Office suite to your computer? It can be pretty pricey usually, but it’s also quite necessary depending on what type of work you do. We’ve got a solution: Microsoft Office Professional 2021 for Windows: Lifetime License, found at StackSocial.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">Check out StackSocial to nab your own copy of Microsoft Office Professional 2021 for Windows: Lifetime License at for $34.97 (down from $219.99)</a>. You save about $185.02, which is a whopping 84% off.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

<h2>A productivity suite without the subscription every year</h2>
<p>The suite has all the applications you need to create documents, spreadsheets, presentations and just about everything else you could want. It has Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, and Publisher, all licensed for lifetime usage on your Windows PC. No more pesky reminders to renew, which should be a huge selling point.</p>
<p>Since this is a lifetime license, you really are covered for as long as you need these programs (or at least until they’re obsolete). Install Office Professional 2021 once and then you own it for life without paying any monthly or annual subscription fees. This is a significant advantage if you’re over subscription-based services, of course, and these are all products you may use on a regular basis. You’ll always have access to the primary apps and functionality you rely upon with Office Professional 2021 this way, even if you’re offline.</p>



<p>If you’ve used Office previously, you should be off to the races as soon as everything is set up and installed. You can save, open and share files created in Office with others. All you need is the product key you’ll get when taking advantage of this deal and instructions for downloading and activating Office on your Windows PC. In addition to the most up-to-date software possible in addition to your download, you’ll be provided with the most recent security features and updates that will continue to support the reliability and performance of your tools.</p>
<p>Installing the productivity apps on your local machine ensures you can utilize them regardless of whether you have an internet connection or not. You have the power of Microsoft Office at your fingertips to assist you with writing reports, analyzing numbers, developing a presentation and managing email.</p>
<p>Really, you can’t go wrong with this price, even if you’re only a casual Office user. You never know when you or one of the kids is going to need it for something. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/">At its discounted sale price of $34.97 on StackSocial, down from $219.99, Microsoft Office Professional 2021 for Windows: Lifetime License is an excellent offer</a>. Say goodbye to subscriptions and open-source software and try something a little different for once.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4845/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at StackSocial</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-office-professional-2021-hits-an-all-time-low-at-84-off-skip-subscription-fees-with-this-one-time-purchase-2000656785]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker Prime Charger (160W, 3-Port) Kicks Off the New Year at a Record Low, Cheaper Than Year-End Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anker-prime-charger-160w-3-port-kicks-off-the-new-year-at-a-record-low-cheaper-than-year-end-pricing-2000656791</link>
            <guid>1398484</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It can be such a pain to run out of battery, whether that’s on your phone, computer, or otherwise. If you find yourself in that predicament more often than is practical, you should have a portable charger to help make sure you’re juiced up whenever you need to be.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5984/">The Anker Prime Charger, 160W is up for grabs at Amazon for a limited time at a discounted price of $105.99 compared to its original retail price of $150.</a> That’s a discount of $44.01, or about 29% off.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5984/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A powerful yet compact portable charger</h2>
<p>This is a powerful and compact portable charger that lets you charge several electronic devices simultaneously. That makes it a great pick for cell phones, tablets, game consoles, and more. It provides up to 160W of power through each of its USB-C ports, so it can safely and rapidly fast-charge a USB-C laptop while charging two additional devices (phone and/or tablet) at the same time.</p>
<p>The USB-C ports are ideal for providing high-power charging to newer laptops, tablets and smartphones, while the USB-A ports are ideal for charging older phones, Bluetooth speakers and/or other smaller electronic devices. Additionally, the Anker Prime Charger has Power Delivery (PD) capability, enabling it to supply power to your electronic devices at the fastest possible rate, allowing you to charge your devices quicker and more efficiently.</p>



<p>Although the Anker Prime Charger has the potential to deliver a significant amount of power, it’s still super small. You can put it on a desktop surface, nightstand, or kitchen counter without taking up too much valuable real estate. It’s also super lightweight and easily storable in a backpack or travel case, making it ideal for use during business trips, vacations, or work-from-home/coworking days, when users would prefer a single charger to replace a tangled mess of individual chargers and cables.</p>
<p>Built-in safety features enable you to feel confident when connecting expensive electronic devices. The Anker Prime Charger constantly monitors temperature and power consumption to ensure that it protects against heat damage (overheating), excessive voltage, and/or electrical shock due to short circuit conditions. Although these protective mechanisms operate transparently, they offer considerable peace-of-mind benefits when you need to charge multiple high-value devices at the same time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5984/">This Anker Prime Charger is absolutely perfect for its size, capacity, and performance.</a> It eliminates clutter, enables fast-charging capabilities for newer devices, and is compatible with both home and travel-based environments. Bottom line? You should get one and keep it in your bag, car, or somewhere else that you use often in case of emergencies. You never know when you might get struck with a charging emergency.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5984/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anker-prime-charger-160w-3-port-kicks-off-the-new-year-at-a-record-low-cheaper-than-year-end-pricing-2000656791]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I’m Begging For A Sequel After Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles Ships 1 Million Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-tactics-ivalice-remaster-sales-sequel-2000657141</link>
            <guid>1398481</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>How many more copies does <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> need to sell before Square Enix greenlights a new grid-based strategy RPG? Almost three years later, physical versions of<em> Hi-Fi Rush</em> are finally up for pre-order. And how long will it take for Netflix to turn <em>Arc Raiders</em> into its next streaming hit?</p> <p>It’s the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture. Depending on what you’re into, January will probably feel like a slow month for big new game releases, at least compared to last year. But I’m getting lowkey hyped for <a href="https://kotaku.com/code-vein-is-the-chillest-dark-souls-clone-1838481190"><em>Code Vein 2</em></a>, the follow-up to the messy 2019 action-RPG anime soulslike. This one <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJLfjZd78hw">has a motorcycle</a>.</p>

 <h2>Even<em> Final Fantasy Tactics</em>‘ original director can’t believe how well the remaster is selling</h2> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I underestimated the sales figures by too much.😂😂😂</p> <p>— 松野泰己🐈‍⬛ (@YasumiMatsuno) <a href="https://twitter.com/YasumiMatsuno/status/2008464271731257715?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Square Enix revealed that<em> Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> has sold over 1 million copies. That might be “below expectations” for the infamously disappointed Japanese publisher, but it was enough to take Yasumi Matsuno by surprise. It also prompted a fresh message to fans from the remaster’s director.</p>

 <p>“The entire development team is not only grateful to you, but, in order to spread the joy, create a better experience, and encourage more people to play, we are looking at updating the game in the future!” Kazutoyo Maehiro wrote, according to a translation <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/strategy/og-final-fantasy-tactics-director-admits-he-underestimated-how-popular-the-ivalice-chronicles-would-be-as-it-passes-1-million-copies-sold-with-the-remakes-lead-teasing-future-updates/">from <em>Gamesradar</em></a>. What does updating the game in the future entail, exactly? Could the missing War of the Lions content be officially restored? Could we get fresh end-game modes?</p>

 <p>“Our first and foremost goal here really was to recreate the original game,” Maehiro&nbsp;<a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-tactics-ivalice-remaster-cloud-wiegraf-cid-sequel-2000622717">told<em>&nbsp;Wired</em></a> last year. “If [<em>The Ivalice Chronicles</em>] were to become a success,” he continued, “I do feel that that would then lead to discussions around potentially bringing out sequels, for example, or newer tactical RPGs.”</p>

 <p>Let the <em>Final Fantasy Tactics 2</em> summoning circle commence.</p> <h2>You can finally pre-order a physical copy of <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em></h2> <p>The 2023 GOTY contender from Tango Gameworks, a studio that Microsoft closed in 2024 but which was later re-opened under Krafton, is finally getting a physical version that you can start pre-ordering <a href="https://x.com/LimitedRunGames/status/2008192175138299918">from Limited Run Games on January 23</a>. That includes a PS5 version. This is one game everyone should have in their collection, even if it could still be a year before it actually starts shipping.</p>

 <h2>We could end up getting an<em> Arc Raiders</em> TV show</h2> <p>Embark studio head Patrick Söderlund <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vY3u7wOmm4w">told <em>GamesBeat</em></a> that Hollywood is interested and so is he. “We [wouldn’t] mind doing that. It would be fun, but it needs to be done in the right way. I hope that we will do that. I think the IP fits quite well with something like that.” Nothing is set in stone yet, however, and Embark doesn’t “have anyone working on a TV or film adaptation yet.” Maybe we’ll see it on Netflix in time for <em>Arc Raiders 2</em>.</p>

 <h2><em>Game of Thrones</em> star Sophie Turner was fine with her ending</h2> <p>She acknowledges that the rest of the cast was disappointed with their characters’ fates. “But I feel that I was very happy with the way Sansa ended her story in <em>Game of Thrones</em>, and no one else was really happy with their ending,” Turner <a href="https://thedirect.com/article/sophie-turner-game-of-thrones-sequel-return">told <em>The Direct</em></a><em>.</em> “I feel like I got a good one, and so I don’t know if I could revisit it.” Would she come back to do more <em>Game of Thrones</em>? “Show me the money,” she joked. She might be <a href="https://kotaku.com/tomb-raider-lara-croft-amazon-sophie-turner-2000623124">too busy with</a>&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider</em> anyway.</p> <h2><em>Final Fantasy 9</em>‘s character artist says goodbye</h2> <p>Toshiyuki Itahana left Square Enix at the end of last year. “Last year marked a major milestone with the 25th anniversary of FINAL FANTASY IX, a truly significant event, and I was deeply grateful to see so many people celebrating FFIX,” he <a href="https://note.com/itahana/n/n277aa9cc7148?sub_rt=share_pb">wrote</a> in a message to fans. He’ll continue to produce art as a freelance illustrator.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/mudang-two-hearts-splinter-cell-layoffs-shut-down-release-date-2000656736">The Korean <em>Splinter Cell</em> revealed at last year’s Xbox summer showcase could be in trouble</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/guy-behind-viral-focus-m-gaming-meme-never-expected-it-to-spread-so-fast-2000656706">The guy behind the viral AAA <em>Mario</em> meme is as surprised as you are</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/stranger-things-secret-finale-conformity-gate-explained-2000656704"><em>Stranger Things</em> fans need to let go</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-tactics-ivalice-remaster-sales-sequel-2000657141]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>