<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:59:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Tower PC Desktop Is Cheaper Than Ever, Probably to Clear Shelves Before Amazon Prime Big Deal Days]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dell-tower-pc-desktop-is-cheaper-than-ever-probably-to-clear-shelves-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2000626589</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dell-tower-pc-desktop-is-cheaper-than-ever-probably-to-clear-shelves-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days.1301718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The advantages of a laptop goes without saying, but lets say it anyway. It’s portable. It’s a portable computer you can take anywhere with you. But I’m here to tell you, “Big whoop.” a lot of us end up just doing our work from the same spot anyway and if you don’t need that portability, you can save some cash by just going with a tower instead. <strong>Take a look at Dell’s Vostro 3030 PC tower.</strong> This is the kind of computer that does what’s expected of it and nothing more. A capital P, capital C <em>PC</em>.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4162/"> It normally goes for $899, but Amazon happens to have it right now for 33% off. Right now, you’ll save $299, bringing the price down to just $600 for a limited time.</a></p>
<p>Diving into the specs, what we have here is a 13-inch by 6-inch by 12inch PC tower powered by a 14th generation Intel Core i3-14100 processor and an integrated Intel UHD 730 graphics card. It’s loaded with 32GB of RAM which while make your performance-intensive apps run fast and react snappy. As far as storage is concerned, the Dell Vostro 3030 is equipped with a PCIe SSD with a capacity of 1TB. You can expect fast load times from anything off this solid state drive.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4162/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Compatibility Options</h2>
<p>One big bonus PC towers have over laptops—the ports. With a newer laptop you might have to suffice with just one, maybe two USB slots along the side. That’s not the case here. This Dell tower comes with three USB-A ports and one USB-C, and that’s just on the front. Turn it around and you’ll be greeted with four more USB Type-A ports. That makes eight USB ports in total.</p>



<p>Other connections you’ll find are an HDMI and DisplayPort so you can set yourself up with two monitors side by side. You also have an Ethernet port on the back and a combination headphone/microphone audio jack conveniently on the front. The Dell tower supports Bluetooth so you can pair wirelessly to headphones or other accessories like your mouse or gaming controller. Wi-Fi 6 support enables you to take advantage of fast download and upload speeds.</p>
<p>The Dell PC tower comes pre-installed with Windows 11 Pro. That comes with support for OneDrive and more.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4162/">For a limited time, Dell’s Vostro 3030 PC tower is heavily discounted at Amazon. Get it right now for $299 off.</a> That brings the price all the way down from $899 to just $600.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4162/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dell-tower-pc-desktop-is-cheaper-than-ever-probably-to-clear-shelves-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2000626589]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>