<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 10:35:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IGN Boss Leaving After Latest Round Of Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ign-john-davison-ziff-davis-layoffs-union-games-media-2000616972</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ign-boss-leaving-after-latest-round-of-layoffs.1267566/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>The head of the biggest gaming site in the world is leaving the company at the end of August, <em>Kotaku</em> has learned. John Davison, who has been <em>IGN</em>‘s publisher since joining back in 2019, told staff on Monday it was time for “the next chapter.” The high-profile departure comes shortly after a big round of layoffs that saw multiple departments across the company impacted.</p> <p>Arriving just months before the start of the 2020 pandemic, Davison’s tenure at <em>IGN</em> saw the site expand into events like <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/xbox-and-sega-among-publishers-appearing-at-ign-live">IGN Live</a> and a market analytics platform called <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ign-launches-gaming-trends-platform-shedding-light-on-how-mobile-roblox-and-more-are-reshaping-the-industry">Gaming Trends</a>. Under parent-company Ziff Davis, <em>IGN</em> also made a massive acquisition last year in the form of the Gamer Network, a suite of European-facing gaming sites like <em>Eurogamer</em>, <em>VG247</em>, and <em>Rock Paper Shotgun</em>. Many of those sites were hit with mass layoffs at the time of the deal, and <em>GamesIndustry.biz</em> was gutted. One of the most valuable parts of that package, <em>Digital Foundry</em>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/digital-foundry-df-direct-ign-patreon-retro-games-media-2000616308">announced just last week</a> that it had purchased all outstanding equity to allow it to leave<em> IGN</em> and go fully independent.</p> <p>Davison, whose 25+ years in games media include stints at <em>EGM</em>, <em>Official PlayStation Magazine</em>, and <em>GameSpot</em>, will be leaving<em> IGN</em> at a time when its future trajectory has never been more uncertain. A reporting, news, and features operation that expanded under previous EIC Tina Amini has suffered cuts in recent years due to multiple rounds of layoffs and buyouts. Amini, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ign-editor-in-chief-tina-amini-steps-down">who left in 2022 and now works at Xbox</a>, was never replaced. Davison reported to Ziff Davis president of gaming and entertainment Yael Prough, and it’s not yet clear if the parent company plans on backfilling his role.</p>

 <p>Davison and <em>IGN</em> did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p> <p><em>IGN</em> laid off over a dozen staff earlier this month, which included approximately 12 percent members in its editorial union. “The company has told us that the reason for this layoff stems from a Ziff Davis mandate to cut costs despite several quarters in a row of year-over-year revenue increases, to which IGN Entertainment responded by coming for our members’ jobs,” <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ignunion.bsky.social/post/3lvm4rhup5k2a">the IGN Creators Guild wrote at the time</a>. “This is perplexing to us, as we are told again and again that IGN Entertainment has had a tremendously successful year thus far thanks to their hard work.”</p> <p>“It’s been an honor to work alongside such talented, passionate people, and I’m deeply proud of what we’ve accomplished together,” Davison wrote in a message to staff today. “I’m excited for what comes next.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ign-john-davison-ziff-davis-layoffs-union-games-media-2000616972]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League Of Legends Dev Sends McDonald’s Jobs Link To Player Who Boosts Accounts For A Living]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/league-of-legends-mcdonalds-job-application-boosting-smurfing-dev-riot-games-2000616955</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/league-of-legends-dev-sends-mcdonald%E2%80%99s-jobs-link-to-player-who-boosts-accounts-for-a-living.1267539/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>A <a href="https://kotaku.com/league-legends-riot-games-worlds-23-interview-1851071665"><em>League of Legends</em></a> player who claimed to have built a career around boosting accounts and selling them replied angrily on social media to a developer at Riot Games. He was worried about how he would make money now. The dev’s response was a link to McDonalds’ careers page.</p> <p>On August 11, <a href="https://www.leagueoflegends.com/en-us/news/dev/dev-banning-bots-boosters-and-more-in-2025/?_gl=1*dgamq1*_gcl_au*MTU3NTAxOTczNy4xNzU0OTQ2Nzkw*_ga*MTM2MDIzODkzMS4xNzU0OTQ2Nzkw*_ga_FXBJE5DEDD*czE3NTQ5NDY3OTAkbzEkZzAkdDE3NTQ5NDY3OTEkajU5JGwwJGgw">Riot Games announced plans</a>&nbsp;to ramp up its efforts to fight back against smurf and alt account misuse in <em>League of Legends,</em> one of the biggest MOBAs on the planet. These new plans include banning and punishing people who grind on accounts owned by other players, boosting their rank in the process, and charging a fee for doing so. These services have <a href="https://insaneboost.gg/">become quite common online.</a> Even <a href="https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-poe2-diablo-4-paid-boosting-fake-controversy-1851743670">Elon Musk admitted to using one such service</a> in <em>Path of Exile II.</em> But Riot is cracking down and banning accounts associated with the practice. These changes will begin in <em>LoL</em> update 25.18 and will likely lead to players being far more cautious about paying others to boost their rank in<em> League of Legends</em>. That will lead to fewer customers for those offering such “services,” and one of these people wasn’t happy about that news.</p> <p>On Monday, <a href="https://x.com/cat1_alex/status/1954924168245358742?">Twitter user SLS replied to Riot’s Director of Product Drew Levin</a>, and explained that their “main income” comes primarily from boosting other players’ accounts in <em>League of Legends</em>. They also coach players in the free-to-play MOBA, but admitted that this only earned them about 15 percent of what they make boosting in a month. They wrapped up their comment with: “What I do after? [sic] Just chill at McDonald’s?” Levin reshared the post and included a link to McDonald’s careers page, seemingly joking that it was time for SLS to find a new job.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/Ku080U0fB4">https://t.co/Ku080U0fB4</a> <a href="https://t.co/7JgyjgOpJF">https://t.co/7JgyjgOpJF</a></p> <p>— Drew Levin (@drewlevin) <a href="https://twitter.com/drewlevin/status/1954931160469114915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>“Bro, you do understand that you have built a business off of ruining other people’s games, right?” <a href="https://x.com/drewlevin/status/1954926308049494207">replied Levin</a>. “[I] have no desire to preserve that at the expense of whatever lobbies you’re boosting accounts through.”</p> <p>When SLS replied to that message with a complaint that the boosting industry wasn’t hurting the game and that boosters take specific orders related to very high ranks, Levin replied again, this time pointing out how absurd it was that SLS was describing breaking how the game ranks players as an “industry.”</p> <p>“‘The industry?’ ‘Taking orders?’ Bro you are paid to trick our skill evaluation systems, and you are talking to the person leading the effort to improve their integrity,” <a href="https://x.com/drewlevin/status/1954930709510168878">said Levin on social media</a>.</p>

 <p><em>Kotaku</em> has reached out to Riot Games about the response.</p> <p>While some players who relied on boosting or liked smurfing–which is when a high-level player creates a new account to use their skills against low-level players–were upset about the changes, the vast majority of the replies to Levin were happy to hear Riot Games was taking alt account abuse seriously in 2025. Of course, it remains to be seen if Riot Games can actually weed out all the boosters and smurf accounts from <em>League of Legends</em> and how quickly people find ways around their new efforts.</p> <p>Also, it should be noted that working at McDonald’s, like any other fast food joint, is a very hard job that requires incredible amounts of patience and stamina. It would be nice if we could all stop acting like people who work at these places are lazy teens working a summer job for beer money or whatever. If that cultural shift were to happen, perhaps they’d have a better shot at getting paid more. And don’t you think the people making your food deserve more money? I do.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/league-of-legends-mcdonalds-job-application-boosting-smurfing-dev-riot-games-2000616955]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>