<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:03:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenovo Goes Full Clearance on Its Laptop at 78% Off, 15.3″ IdeaPad Slim 3 Drops to All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-goes-full-clearance-on-its-laptop-at-78-off-15-3-ideapad-slim-3-drops-to-all-time-low-2000657106</link>
            <guid>1398325</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Shopping for a new laptop today? You’re in luck. Amazon is offering plenty of discounts across a wide range of categories, including laptops. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/">One of our favorite discounts is this 78% drop on the Lenovo IdeaPad Slim 3, which brings its price down to just $440.</a></p>
<p>You’re saving over $1,500 on a machine that is made to handle all your everyday work and entertainment needs like a pro. Even better, if you place your orders today, you will also enjoy free shipping on your purchase, which sweetens the deal even more!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Made for Everyday Use</h2>
<p>IdeaPad Slim 3 is a lightweight laptop with a basic, yet sleek design. You’re getting a nice 15.3-inch WUXGA IPS display that delivers a stunning 1920×1200 resolution to bring all your favorite content to life. Whether you’re catching up on the last episode of Pluribus or creating a work presentation, expect vivid details and vibrant colors. The narrow bezels offer a larger screen real estate to work on, while the anti-glare coating keeps the visuals consistent across all lighting conditions.</p>
<p>Right above the screen is a built-in 720p webcam with a privacy shutter for easier video calls. You will be able to catch up with friends and hop on meetings without needing an external device. Those who need to type long documents and fill spreadsheets often will also appreciate the full-sized keyboard that features a dedicated numeric keypad. It’s comfortable to use, so you won’t have to deal with sore wrists at the end of a productive day.</p>
<p>Speaking of productivity, the laptop runs on a modest 13th Gen Intel Core i5-13420H processor with 8 cores and 12 threads. It’s made to handle regular tasks – think browsing, streaming, light office work, studying – without slowing you down. The processor is paired with an 8GB DDR5 SDRAM memory that keeps things running smoothly as you work or play. That said, it’s not designed for heavy workloads, so you won’t exactly be able to work on demanding tasks. But as long as your needs are fairly standard, it should get the job done just fine.</p>



<p>Storage capacity is better than most options in this range. You’re getting a spacious 512GB SSD that can house your entire multimedia library on your PC, and more easily. SSDs also offer much faster boot and load times than their traditional counterparts, so you’ll also be able to launch programs and move files around more efficiently.</p>
<p>Connectivity options are just as impressive. You’ve got WiFi 6 and Bluetooth 5.2 for wireless connections, plus a wide range of ports including two USB-A (USB 5Gbps / USB 3.2 Gen 1), one USB-C (USB 5Gbps / USB 3.2 Gen 1), with USB PD 3.0 and DisplayPort 1.2, one HDMI 1.4, one headphone/microphone combo jack (3.5mm), one SD card reader, and one power connector. Translation? You can easily connect a bunch of peripherals like a mouse, a portable screen, microphones, etc, without feeling limited.</p>
<p>Windows 11 Home also comes pre-installed, which means you can get started with using the machine right away.</p>
<p>Altogether, in a compact, lightweight build, the IdeaPad Slim 3 packs a wide range of features and impressive power for regular tasks. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/">You’re getting a spacious display, a full-sized keyboard, a modest processor, and a spacious SSD for under $450 here</a>. Keep in mind that the deal is only around for a short time. The discount is likely going to expire soon, so it’s best to lock it in quickly.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-goes-full-clearance-on-its-laptop-at-78-off-15-3-ideapad-slim-3-drops-to-all-time-low-2000657106]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Avengers: Doomsday Teaser Brings The Fantastic Four Into The Mix]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-fantastic-four-wakanda-namor-teaser-2000657142</link>
            <guid>1398271</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I feel like I can’t even keep track of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-teaser-leak-thor-doom-trailer-avatar-2000654848"><span>all the </span><i><span>Avengers: Doomsday </span></i><span>teasers</span></a><span> anymore. Wasn’t one of these supposed to focus on </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-rdj-doctor-doom-avengers-marvel-sdcc-1851607689"><span>Robert Downey Jr. as Doctor Doom</span></a><span>? We’re now at the fourth out of the supposed four theater-exclusive trailers declaring that “so-and-so will return in </span><i><span>Avengers: Doomsday</span></i><span>,” and there’s no sign of the evil doctor yet. This fourth teaser, which is leaking online and also being taken down by Marvel almost immediately after, stars Shuri, the Black Panther, as she prepares the people of Wakanda for what’s to come, and they also meet a hero from another Earth: The Thing.</span></p> <p><span>Though the trailer is getting wiped off social media shortly after it’s been posted, we were able to see it before it got nuked. It opens with Shuri lamenting how she lost her family after the events of </span><i><span>Black Panther: Wakanda Forever</span></i><span>, and we also see Namor and members of the underwater Talokan kingdom looking broodily in the distance at…something. But the real highlight is when Shuri and M’Baku greet none other than the Thing himself, Ben Grimm.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>The Thing and the rest of the Fantastic Four were shown arriving on the MCU’s version of Earth after the events of </span><i><span>Thunderbolts*</span></i><span>, and in </span><i><span>Fantastic Four: First Steps</span></i><span>’ post-credits scene, we saw Doctor Doom taking an interest in Mr. Fantastic and Invisible Woman’s god baby, Franklin. We’re not sure yet how that results in the group hopping multiverses, but it is cool to see even the first glimpse of the First Family teaming up with the rest of the MCU.</span></p>

 <p><span>The first three teasers featured </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-chris-evans-steve-rogers-captain-america-2000653491"><span>Steve Rogers</span></a><span>, the ex-Captain America who “retired” at the end of </span><i><span>Avengers: Endgame</span></i><span> and is now being dragged back into the scrap for probably deeply cynical, nostalgia-baiting reasons; Thor, who prays to his father that he will be able to </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1clWprLC5Ak"><span>return to his daughter Love</span></a><span>; and the X-Men, who are also </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-trailer-xmen-cyclops-charles-magneto-2000655923"><span>getting pulled into all this</span></a><span>. Again, no sign of Doctor Doom yet. Maybe there will be more teasers than initially believed? Or maybe we still have a while to wait for our first glimpse of RDJ as the ruler of Latveria.</span></p> <p><i><span>Avengers: Doomsday </span></i><span>is coming to theaters on December 18.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/avengers-doomsday-fantastic-four-wakanda-namor-teaser-2000657142]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker MagSafe Charger Restocks at Its Lowest Price, 3-in-1 Charging Station for Apple Devices]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anker-magsafe-charger-restocks-at-its-lowest-price-3-in-1-charging-station-for-apple-devices-2000656779</link>
            <guid>1398268</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-start="68" data-end="557">I have far too many devices that need charging at night. Between my iPhone, AirPods, and Apple Watch, the mess of cables around my nightstand is starting to look like some kind of cyberpunk bird nest. It’s really my fault, though—I could easily fix this by getting a charging stand, like this Anker MagSafe charger, which would eliminate the chaos entirely.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6036/"> Normally priced at $230, it’s now available for just $161 due to a limited-time 30% discount</a>. That’s a savings of $69 during the sale.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6036/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="559" data-end="588"><strong data-start="559" data-end="588">Perfect for Apple Devices</strong></h2>
<p data-start="590" data-end="882">This Anker MagSafe charging stand is designed specifically for modern Apple products. It’s made to work with newer iPhones, AirPods, and Apple Watches that support wireless charging. The stand has three built-in wireless chargers, each designed for either your phone, watch, or AirPods case.</p>
<p data-start="884" data-end="1112">Before purchasing, make sure your devices are compatible with wireless charging. iPhones from the iPhone 12 onwards are all set, as are newer AirPods models. Older devices won’t work with this stand’s wireless charging features.</p>
<p data-start="1114" data-end="1587">What’s really impressive about this wireless charger is its speed. The stand can charge an iPhone 17 Pro to 50% in just 22 minutes, which is pretty fast for wireless charging. It provides 25W charging—better than most other wireless chargers in its class. You can leave your devices on the stand overnight, and they’ll be fully charged by morning. Alternatively, you can keep the stand at your desk while you work.</p>


<p data-start="1589" data-end="1817">The stand also features a display that shows the charging status of your devices and even a clock, making it a great addition to your nightstand. This allows you to easily check the time without lifting your head off the pillow.</p>
<p data-start="1819" data-end="2069">As with all Anker products, safety is a top priority. The MagSafe charging stand uses ActiveShield technology, which monitors temperatures over three million times per day to ensure your devices don’t overheat while charging, keeping everything safe.</p>
<p data-start="2071" data-end="2223">With the Anker MagSafe charging stand, you can clean up your nightstand and keep your devices charged without the mess of cables, all for a great price. There are two color options available. Choose either white or phantom gray. Do note that while both are on sale currently, the better deal is on the white version. It is exactly $0.01 cheaper. But then again, pennies are no longer a thing anymore so I guess they are exactly the same. Get it now for $160.99 or $160.98 for a limited time. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6036/">That’s down from a starting price of $230, meaning you end up saving $69—equivalent to 30% off.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6036/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anker-magsafe-charger-restocks-at-its-lowest-price-3-in-1-charging-station-for-apple-devices-2000656779]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPad (11″, A16 Chip) Holds Its Holiday Clearance Price With Extended New Year Deals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-ipad-11-a16-chip-holds-its-holiday-clearance-price-with-extended-new-year-deals-2000657109</link>
            <guid>1398211</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We love tablets for the convenience they bring. You can enjoy your favorite shows on a spacious screen, catch up with work on the go, and even keep kids entertained (for a while, at least) with cartoons or games without handing over your phone. There’s no shortage of options on the market, and if you’re after an iPad, we just found a way to pick one up without paying the full price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/">The 11-inch iPad with the A16 chip is currently sitting at $300 at Amazon, after a sweet $49 discount.</a> We know, it’s not the biggest price drop out there, but considering Apple products rarely go on sale, grabbing a top-rated iPad for less still feels like a win. The discount applies to blue, silver, and pink models, so there are options to choose from. Maybe go for the classic silver version if you like your gadgets minimal, or choose the stunning pink if you’re after something with a bit more personality.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Fast and Efficient</h2>
<p>This iPad flaunts a gorgeous, 11-inch Liquid Retina display. It’s both spacious and bright, plus it features True Tone technology that can automatically adjust according to the color temperature of the room for a comfortable viewing experience. Walk into a dim room, and it will reduce the brightness to reduce eye strain, and similarly, push it back up when you’re using the tablet outdoors. Right above the screen is a 12MP Center Stage front camera, which makes taking selfies and hopping on video calls a breeze. It keeps your center of focus while delivering impressive picture quality that helps you look your best. The front camera is paired with a 12MP Wide back camera with True Tone flash that is just as great for capturing moments, and even taking 4K videos or scanning documents.</p>
<p>The superfast A16 chip keeps things running smoothly, whether you’re trying to work on a creative project or take notes. iPadOS takes the experience even further by letting you navigate with ease. It even comes packed with essential apps like Safari, Messages, and Keynote to help you get started with work or play right away. This version gets you 128GB of storage, which is more than enough to house a ton of photos, all your important programs, and even a few movies, without feeling limited. However, if 128GB feels insufficient, there are 256GB and 512GB versions of the iPad available, too, for $399 and $590, respectively.</p>



<p>If you’re planning to use this iPad for work or creative projects, we highly recommend pairing it with the Apple Pencil (USB-C) and the Magic Keyboard Folio. The former lets you draw, sketch, and take notes with ease. The latter, on the other hand, features a two-piece design with a detachable keyboard and a protective back panel. Both of these attach magnetically to the screen, converting your iPad into a mini laptop. As for connectivity, this version supports Wi-Fi 6 to access the internet.</p>
<p>The battery is designed to last an entire workday on a single charge. You won’t have to worry about plugging it in in the middle of something important.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/">The current 14% discount brings the price down to $300.</a> It’s still a bit of an investment, but if you’re after something that can support all your work and entertainment needs on the go, it’s going to be worth it. Snap it up before the deal expires or the stock runs out!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-ipad-11-a16-chip-holds-its-holiday-clearance-price-with-extended-new-year-deals-2000657109]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>