<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:40:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Years After It Was Announced, Binding Of Isaac Creator Finally Shares A Release Date For His Next Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/12-years-after-it-was-announced-binding-of-isaac-creator-finally-shares-a-release-date-for-his-next-game-2000623148</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/12-years-after-it-was-announced-binding-of-isaac-creator-finally-shares-a-release-date-for-his-next-game.1288908/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good morning! I’m not sure why I’m even writing today’s Morning Checkpoint, as nobody is going to read today’s edition. <a href="https://kotaku.com/silksong-steam-eshop-crashing-twitch-game-pass-hollow-knight-2000623137">Instead, you’ll all be out there playing your fancy new <em>Silksong</em>.</a> Congrats to all of you. For the few of you <em>actually</em> here, today’s Checkpoint includes news about another long-awaited indie game, an update on <em>Wolverine</em>, some info on the development of the Switch 2, and our thoughts on Bloober’s next big horror game.</p> <h2><em>The Binding of Isaac</em> creator’s next game finally gets a release date</h2> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-binding-of-isaac-creators-mewgenics-finally-gets-a-release-date-almost-13-years-after-it-was-announced">After first being announced in 2012, <em>Mewgenics</em> finally has a launch date.</a> And you thought the wait for <em>Silksong</em> was bad! <em>Mewgenics</em>, which is an RPG built around breeding many cats, is being developed by Edmund McMillen, the creator behind<em> The Binding of Isaac</em>, and will launch on February 10, 2026, which is about 13 years after it was first revealed. Not only did McMillen reveal the game’s release date, but he also uploaded <a href="https://youtu.be/cAiIiju7lCo">a 50-minute-long gameplay demo</a> showing off how the game actually plays.</p>  <h2>Insomniac’s <em>Wolverine</em> game is reportedly showing up in a State of Play soon</h2> <p>We’ve not seen much of <em>Wolverine</em>, the next game from<em> Spider-Man</em> makers Insomniac, since it was revealed in 2021. Well, unless you count all the leaked gameplay floating around out there after the studio was hacked. But it seems like the wait for a new official look at the upcoming superhero game might be coming to an end. <em>Insider Gaming </em>reports that sources have told the outlet a trailer for <em>Wolverine</em> is ready, and many expect it to appear in a Sony State of Play later this month. Will he say “Bub?” One can hope.</p>

 <h2>Nintendo delayed the Switch 2 a few times to make sure it had good games ready</h2> <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-repeatedly-delayed-switch-2-at-designers-request-report/1100-6534465/">A new report from <em>Bloomberg</em></a> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2025-nintendo-switch2/">about Nintendo and how it makes games</a> says that the Switch 2’s launch was held back because the people working on launch games requested extra time to “perfect” their titles. Nintendo apparently made this their number one priority and delayed the Switch 2 a few times to make sure the games it launched with were as good as could be.</p> <h2><em>Shinobi: The Art of Vengeance</em> on Switch is getting a resolution boost</h2> <p>People like that new <em>Shinobi</em> game a lot! But on Switch, the 2D action-platformer is a bit fuzzier than it should be. <a href="https://x.com/SEGA_OFFICIAL/status/1963129469373407429?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">Sega knows and is patching the Switch port</a> to “improve” <em>Shinobi</em>‘s resolution. Here’s their full statement:</p>

 <blockquote><p><span>In response to feedback from all players, we are currently developing an update patch to improve the screen resolution in the Nintendo Switch version of this title. Please wait a little longer until the patch is released.</span></p></blockquote> <h2>Someone added a Nintendo Cease and Desist into <em>Smash Bros.</em> as a fighter</h2> <p>Truly the greatest enemy in Nintendo history: A legal cease and desist issued by one of the company’s many lawyers. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-cease-desist-letter-is-now-a-playable-character-in-smash-bros-mod/1100-6534471/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f">Now someone</a> has brought this iconic and terrible creature, which has stopped many a great mod and fan game, into <em>Smash Bros.</em> as a playable character. Good luck to the other fighters. You’re going to need it.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I put my Cease &amp; Desist Letter from Nintendo into Melee!</p> <p>See how much court fines you can stack up against your opponents with this new skin over [COPYRIGHTED CHARACTER]!</p> <p>Get it at your nearest courthouse, linked below! <br>Lawsuit compatible. <a href="https://t.co/QHXyo516z2">pic.twitter.com/QHXyo516z2</a></p> <p>— Moosh (@Mooshies_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mooshies_/status/1962052715649061032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/rog-xbox-ally-price-pc-gaming-handheld-asus-pre-order-2000622751">The new Xbox handheld PC thingy seems cool, but will probably not be worth the price</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/superman-tomorrow-lex-luthor-date-james-gunn-supergirl-batman-2000622739">We’re getting a new Superman movie in 2027</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/cronos-the-new-dawn-review-impressions-horror-bloober-team-silent-hil-2-ps5-2000622488"><em>Cronos: The New Dawn</em> is pretty dang good and scary!</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> <p>Wow, <em>Silksong</em> is out and has a launch trailer. It finally happened. Still a bit weird. Now I go back to waiting for <em>Half-Life 3</em>. Any day now…</p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/12-years-after-it-was-announced-binding-of-isaac-creator-finally-shares-a-release-date-for-his-next-game-2000623148]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Makes Some Big Improvements To Its GBA Emulation]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-online-gba-1080p-remapping-2000623130</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-makes-some-big-improvements-to-its-gba-emulation.1288839/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>The GBA Nintendo Classics screen.</span> © Nintendo
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Nintendo Switch Online, the Switch subscription service with the deeply irritating name, is rearranging the furniture to try to make things make a bit more sense. For one, various libraries of emulated games from older Nintendo systems are now being designated as “Nintendo Classics,” while the Game Boy Advance section receives a couple of significant improvements.</p> <p>First and foremost, on Switch 2 your GBA games—dating from 2001 to 2010—will now apparently run in a far shinier 1080p even when playing in handheld mode. Now, clearly this sets up quite the battle lines between those who believe emulated games should be played at the scale and resolution that was originally intended, ideally on the cloudy-screened technology of its era, and those who like it when things look pretty. Of course, the app also gives you the option to both run the games in a teeny window, and to “reproduce classic feel” by adding a bunch of effects to make it look like it used to. Saying all this, I’ve updated my Switch 2 and I absolutely cannot get the games to run in 1080p, nor find an option for it, so that’s odd.</p> <p>However, what I can confirm as working is control remapping, which is a very welcome inclusion. The option was recently added to the SNES games, and with an exemplary level of precision. For instance, if you’re adjusting controls for <em>Mario Kart Super Circuit</em>, there are options to reassign controls as specific as “Throw Bananas Ahead of You” and “Shoot Shells Behind You,” letting, you move them wherever is most comfortable for you. (Except, of course, to the rear triggers, because annoyingly those are forcibly reserved for reaching the emulator menu.)</p>

 <p>All of the previous consoles’ games are now in their own section on the Nintendo Switch Online app, under Nintendo Classics with the same branding, which makes a lot more sense. NES, SNES, Game Boy, GBA, N64, and GameCube are in a neat row. Of course, rather irritatingly this <em>doesn’t</em> include any games certificated M, like <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-online-forsaken-64-mature-2000622653">today’s addition of&nbsp;<em>Forsaken 64</em></a>, for which you need a separate app—the catchily titled <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/Nintendo-64-Nintendo-Classics-Mature-2592474.html?srsltid=AfmBOoo6In-dwQyKw2KJlbPqUOKk6izShDf_yoce7GWRsGTtNp86uikR">Nintendo 64 – Nintendo Classics: Mature</a>.</p> <p>Let me know if you get 1080p working. Perhaps I’m missing something embarrassingly obvious.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-online-gba-1080p-remapping-2000623130]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>