<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 19:54:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Raised Its Fire TV Prices, but Hisense’s 43″ Smart Fire TV Is Still at a Steal to Clear Out Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-raised-its-fire-tv-prices-but-hisenses-43%e2%80%b3-smart-fire-tv-is-still-at-a-steal-to-clear-out-stock-2000634061</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-raised-its-fire-tv-prices-but-hisense%E2%80%99s-43%E2%80%B3-smart-fire-tv-is-still-at-a-steal-to-clear-out-stock.1323754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’re now a few days past Amazon’s made up holiday of Prime Big Deals Days. They invented it so we would all have a good reason to buy a bunch of stuff in the sales drought the exists between Labor Day and Black Friday. If you had let this October 7 and October 8 sale pass on by having not grabbed anything for yourself, you’re not out of luck just yet. Amazon still has a number of live deals in which you can save boatloads on cool stuff. Take this Hisense TV for example. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4732/">The 43-inch model already starts at an affordable price of $350. However, during this limited time deal, It’s come down by 31%. That means you only have a pay a measly $250.</a></p>
<p>Hisense is one of those brands that is hands down the best option for your depending on your priorities. This isn’t some expensive OLED TV which can go for multiple thousands of dollars. You can still get a picture that big, displays and 4K, and has a wide color gamut without taking out a second mortgage on your house. This 4K 43-inch TV has support for Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos which can enhance your image quality and sound even further.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4732/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>When it comes to video games, the Hisense smart TV employs Game Mode Plus. This allows you to play games with the picture settings prioritizing what matter for gaming. The variable refresh rate and auto low latency mode will reduce input lag so you player character feels snappy and responsive on screen. Otherwise playing on a screen with bad response times can make it feel like you’re moving your guy through mud.</p>
<h2>Fire TV and Alexa-enabled</h2>
<p>This Hisense Smart TV is designed with the Fire TV interface. Download all the streaming apps from Netflix to Disney Plus to Hulu to HBO Max (if that’s what they’re still calling it by the time this gets published).</p>



<p>The remote is built with Alexa voice support. You can just hold the button down and speak into it the title of the movie or TV show you’re looking to watch. It’s much easier to just say “<em>The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford</em>,” than it is to type out all of that one letter at a time on those on-screen keypads.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4732/">For a limited time, you can pick up this Hisense 4K 43-inch television for an all-time low price of just $250.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4732/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-raised-its-fire-tv-prices-but-hisenses-43%e2%80%b3-smart-fire-tv-is-still-at-a-steal-to-clear-out-stock-2000634061]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>