<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:34:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Slashes Its Ryzen 7 Laptop by Nearly 80%, Plus $399 in Free Accessories Thrown In for Early Black Friday Only]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-grab-the-15-inch-dell-inspiron-touchscreen-for-just-800-after-a-2600-drop-2000644679</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dell-slashes-its-ryzen-7-laptop-by-nearly-80-plus-399-in-free-accessories-thrown-in-for-early-black-friday-only.1355722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Dell laptops are some of our favorites out there. They offer a nice blend of performance, portability, solid battery life, and helpful features. But as you’d expect, most options with all this and more sit well over $1,500.</p>
<p>If you’ve been looking to upgrade without shelling out big bucks, we’ve got good news.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5634/"> Amazon has dropped the price of the 15-inch Dell Inspiron touchscreen laptop to $800, which is a straightforward $2,600 off its usual price.</a> There are no complicated coupons or checkout steps to worry about; just add the product to your cart, and the discount will apply automatically. Best of all? It doesn’t end there.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5634/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The retailer is also throwing in a bunch of free accessories with your purchase. These include six useful items, plus pre-installed Windows 11 Pro. The bundle is worth almost $400, but you’re getting it for nothing here. Just be sure to grab your order fast, as the discount might not last long. It might not come back for Black Friday, either!</p>
<h2>High-Performance Processor, Plus Solid Graphics</h2>
<p>This laptop packs the high-performance, 8-core AMD Ryzen 7 7730U CPU with Radeon Graphics. Together, these deliver impressive work performance and powerful visuals, whether you’re working on boring office tasks or pushing some creative boundaries with a passion project. There’s a truly massive 32GB DDR4 RAM for faster, snappier multitasking, plus a 1TB PCIe NVMe SSD that offers sufficient space to store all your data. The memory is more than enough to support you during your busy, most productive work days that require you to juggle multiple programs at the same time.</p>



<p>Display-wise, you’ve got a 15.6-inch full HD touchscreen that pushes a 1920×1080 resolution for sharp, clear visuals. The anti-glare coating makes it easier on your eyes in both dim and bright settings; great for both early risers and night owls. Touch support translates into easier navigation. You won’t have to limit yourself to the trackpad or the mouse. Just use your fingers directly on the screen to scroll, swipe, pinch, sketch, and even take notes!</p>
<p>Port selection is wide, and includes USB Type-C, USB 3.2, HDMI, headphone jack, and SD card reader. As for the accessory kit, it gets you a laptop camera cover slide, a protective laptop sleeve, a 128GB USB flash drive, a magnetic stylus pen, anti-dust plugs, a cleaning cloth, and Windows 11 Pro. That’s an entire, full-fledged creative setup right out of the box.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5634/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-grab-the-15-inch-dell-inspiron-touchscreen-for-just-800-after-a-2600-drop-2000644679]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our First Look At The Filming Of Zelda Teases A Special Character]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/zelda-live-action-movie-link-bragason-ainsworth-leak-2000644816</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/our-first-look-at-the-filming-of-zelda-teases-a-special-character.1355719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We finally got a sneak peak, albeit an unofficial one, of the upcoming <i>Legend of Zelda</i> movie. Over the weekend, footage of the film’s production in New Zealand leaked on social media. It’s a short clip, and nothing can be heard over the sound of the wind, but they hint that the princess’ Sheikah bodyguard Impa will have a role to play in the live-action adaptation.</p> <h2>Impa shows Zelda a sword in leaked production footage</h2> <p>Nintendo confirmed the existence of a live-action <i>Legend of Zelda</i> film back in 2023. Directed by Wes Ball (<i>The Maze Runner</i>, <i>Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes</i>), filming started this month, November 2025. It’s expected to arrive on March 26, 2027. <a href="https://kotaku.com/zelda-movie-nintendo-lead-actors-benjamin-ainsworth-1851786373">Casting for Link and Princess Zelda</a> was revealed earlier this year, with Bo Bragason (<i>Pinocchio</i>) taking on the role of the titular princess while Benjamin Evan Ainsworth (<i>Three Girls</i>) stars as Link.</p>   <p>Footage of the production <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DRCALkNk0Nl/">hit Instagram</a> over the weekend, showing Bragason as Princess Zelda talking with another actor who <a href="https://x.com/SlLENTPRINCESS/status/1989550829758468562?s=20">fans believe to be Dichen Lachman</a> (<i>Dollhouse</i>, <i>Severance</i>). In the clip, the two actors play out a scene involving a sword while the production crew move around some horses. Not a whole lot is known about the film, including which game it may be based on, but fans are pretty sure Lachman is none other than Impa.&nbsp; Given how little we know about the film, even a few small seconds are bound to stir up speculation.</p>

 <p><a href="https://x.com/mogutweet/status/1989601169912791131?s=20">Another video appears</a> to show Ainsworth as Link wearing a green tunic and cloak:</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">another set leak from the zelda movie 👀 <a href="https://t.co/9GHbnNozfm">pic.twitter.com/9GHbnNozfm</a></p> <p>— Mogumogu (@mogutweet) <a href="https://twitter.com/mogutweet/status/1989601169912791131?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 15, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <h2>…and the official sneak peak at Bragason and Ainsworth</h2> <p>Following this weekend’s leaks, we got our first official look at the main characters in costume. An update on the Nintendo Today app showed off the film’s leads in three images. Behold, Bragason as Zelda, and Ainsworth as Link:</p> <figure id="attachment_2000644820" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000644820"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000644820">© Image: Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <figure id="attachment_2000644821" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000644821"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000644821">© Image: Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <figure id="attachment_2000644822" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000644822"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000644822">© Image: Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <p>Production of the film is expected to conclude in April, 2026, <a href="https://productionlist.com/production/the-legend-of-zelda/">according to the Film &amp; Television Industry Alliance</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/zelda-live-action-movie-link-bragason-ainsworth-leak-2000644816]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie Settles Plagiarism Lawsuit That Secretly Became About Content Vaulting]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bungie-plagiarism-lawsuit-destiny-2-content-vault-2000644793</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-settles-plagiarism-lawsuit-that-secretly-became-about-content-vaulting.1355683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Naughty Dominus Ghaul and his friends.</span> © Bungie
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>In October 2024, Bungie was sued for copyright infringement by a fantasy author called Kelsey Martineau. He alleged that&nbsp;<em>Destiny 2</em>‘s opening campaign had heavily lifted from his own work that he’d previously published on his blog, complete with a Red Legion embroiled in an “unending cycle of warfare.” The infringing storyline, however, had since been “vaulted” by Bungie, meaning it’s been entirely removed from the game. Now, as <a href="https://thegamepost.com/destiny-2-red-war-lawsuit-ends-bungie-full-settlement-author/"><em>The Game Post</em> points out today</a> (thanks <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/bungie-and-sci-fi-author-settle-lawsuit-over-alleged-plagiarism-of-his-old-wordpress-stories-for-destiny-2s-launch-campaign/"><em>PC Gamer</em></a>), Bungie and Martineau have settled the case and it will no longer go to trial.</p> <p>Martineau, who posted his stories under the name Caspar Cole, says that in 2013 and 2014 he wrote “an original work about a unique and captivating fantasy world,” as it was phrased in <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.laed.270889/gov.uscourts.laed.270889.1.0.pdf">the lawsuit</a>. This story featured a Red Legion, with a leader called Yinnerah who—he alleged—had a near-identical origin story and motivations as&nbsp;<em>Destiny 2</em>‘s Dominus Ghaul. They are both “urged, guided and assisted by outcast mentors (scholars) to overthrow their leaders to rise to power with the intentions of invading Earth,” both part of a Red Legion fought by rebels on Earth, and both seeking to focus on a hovering celestial entity “that houses strategic assets,” said the lawsuit. This last part refers to Martineau’s Tononob Station and <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s the Traveler hovering above the Last City.</p>

 <p>The lawsuit went on to list many other claims of direct similarities (some appearing more of a stretch than others), along with a claim that both narratives followed the same plot beats. Over the past year, Martineau has gone on to bring in further claims of infringement, including <em>D2</em>‘s <em>Curse of Osiris</em> expansion, and even the&nbsp;<em>Destiny Grimoire Anthology</em> books. Bungie, meanwhile, <a href="https://thegamepost.com/bungie-pushes-back-destiny-2-red-war-lawsuit/">tried to get the case dismissed</a> in December of last year with a filing that pretty much amounted to, “No we didn’t.”</p>

 <p>This ended up not working with the Judge, and was seemingly made even more spurious by Bungie’s attempt to sneer that Martineau had relied on fan-made content and YouTube videos to make his case. He had to do that, though, because Bungie had infamously <a href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-tossing-away-old-story-content-is-making-it-h-1848323271">vaulted the original storylines</a> in such a way that even Bungie was unable to go back and re-play it. It seemed that <em>Destiny 2</em>‘s code has moved on so much since its beginning was created, then destroyed, that it would be incompatible with the present version of the game even if it could be recovered.</p>

 <p>This ended up backfiring, given it also meant that <a href="https://thegamepost.com/bungie-access-destiny-2-vaulted-red-war-internally/">Bungie was unable to offer any footage of the original game</a> to counter Martineau’s claims, and eventually had to rely on the very same fan-made content and YouTube videos to demonstrate it hadn’t plagiarized the blogger. Not only was this rather humiliating given the company’s own comments, but it meant Bungie ultimately failed to get the case dismissed as it had originally requested.</p>

 <p>Now, about a year since the original filing,&nbsp;<a href="https://thegamepost.com/destiny-2-red-war-lawsuit-ends-bungie-full-settlement-author/"><em>The Game Post</em> has obtained court documents</a> that show a settlement conference took place last week, November 12, resulting in the matter being settled. “Negotiations were successful and resulted in the settlement of all claims,” said the paperwork. A further filing explained that the lawsuit was now dismissed without costs, which itself demonstrates a big climbdown from Bungie which had tried to seek legal costs from Martineau in its original attempt to dismiss.</p> <p>No details of the settlement are known, nor likely ever will be known, but it’s quite the remarkable result for a case like this. So many successful movies, books and games result in a lawsuit from someone claiming prior art, usually as a result of there being 8 billion people on the planet and so an extraordinary pool from which slightly overlapping coincidences can be found. These are usually either immediately settled just to make the complainant go away, or promptly dismissed by judges. The fact that Bungie tried to push back, but then relented, obviously doesn’t allow us to draw any solid conclusions, but it sure makes the whole ridiculous “vaulting” nonsense seem even more shortsighted.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bungie-plagiarism-lawsuit-destiny-2-content-vault-2000644793]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker’s 3-in-1 MagSafe Charging Station Falls to Almost Free, Charge All Your Apple Devices for Pennies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/snag-the-anker-maggo-3-in-1-charging-station-while-its-going-at-a-46-discount-on-amazon-2000644671</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anker%E2%80%99s-3-in-1-magsafe-charging-station-falls-to-almost-free-charge-all-your-apple-devices-for-pennies.1355680/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Having multiple devices is convenient, but juggling separate chargers for each one? Not at all.</p>
<p>If you own a smartphone to stay connected, a smartwatch to track your fitness, and earbuds for listening to your favorite tracks on the go, you need a 3-in-1 charger that can juice all these essentials up in one go, and not make a mess while it’s at it. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5632/">The Anker MagGo 3-in-1 charging station does exactly that for Apple devices, and it’s now going for less on Amazon.</a></p>
<p>This compact, but powerful charger is currently sitting at $70, after a nice 37% discount. The deal is open to both Prime and non-Prime members, but it’s only going to be around for a few more hours. If you’ve been wanting to grab a no-fuss charging solution, now is the time to make the move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5632/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Ultra-Fast Charging for All Your Essentials</h2>
<p>You’ll enjoy Qi2-certified, 15W ultra-fast wireless charging, which is twice as fast as the standard 7.5W chargers most people still use. For reference, it can juice an Apple Watch Series 9 to 48% in just 30 minutes. That means you can drop it on the stand while you’re getting ready, and by the time you’re about to head out, your watch will be charged and good to go. Powering your AirPods will be just as fast, and you can also use the anti-slip pad to charge other earbuds, regardless of the brand.</p>
<p>The stand is structured like a minimalist tech tree, meaning you don’t have to worry about overlapping or constantly repositioning devices. You can place your phone vertically or even flip it horizontally to use it as a clock or calendar while it charges.</p>



<p>As for compatibility, it works well with almost the entire Apple ecosystem. The charger supports MagSafe-equipped iPhones, including the iPhone 13, 14, and 15 series. Apple Watch Series 1 through Series 9, plus Apple Watch SE and the rugged Ultra 1 and 2 should work fine too. Audio-wise, the base charging pad is designed for AirPods Pro 1 and 2, as well as any wireless earbuds with a wireless charging case.</p>
<p>The box includes the Anker MagGo 3-in-1 Charging Station, a 40W USB-C wall charger, and a 5-foot USB-C to USB-C cable. Just note that the discount is a limited-time one, so it’s best to grab it fast.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5632/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/snag-the-anker-maggo-3-in-1-charging-station-while-its-going-at-a-46-discount-on-amazon-2000644671]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GoPro Dumps Hero 13 Black Bundle with 2 Batteries and Hand Grip, Now Goes for Pocket Change]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gopro-dumps-hero-13-black-bundle-with-2-batteries-and-hand-grip-now-goes-for-pocket-change-2000644771</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gopro-dumps-hero-13-black-bundle-with-2-batteries-and-hand-grip-now-goes-for-pocket-change.1355674/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Action cameras require accessories to actually function in the real world, so purchasing a GoPro by itself leaves you with an expensive paperweight until you grab batteries, mounts, and storage. This <strong>Hero 13 Black bundle solves that with two Enduro batteries, a floating hand grip, adhesive mounts, a 64GB microSD card, and a carrying case all in one package</strong>.</p>
<p>The good news is that<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5633/"> the complete bundle just dropped to $369 on Amazon for Black Friday (down from $479)</a>, somehow coming in below the price of buying the Hero 13 Black camera alone at its regular $429. You’re <strong>getting $500 worth of gear for $110 less</strong> than it normally costs for the standalone camera.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5633/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Best Action Cam</h2>
<p><strong>5.3K resolution provides 91% more detail than 4K</strong> and an incredible 665% more than 1080p which means your footage will maintain detail in post even if you crop in or zoom in. Additional resolution also allows for digital reframing of your shot, giving a variety of camera angles from a single recording.<strong> Capture 24.7MP photos from video via the GoPro Quik app</strong>, ensuring you don’t miss a single photo opportunity by switching between modes.</p>
<p>Burst Slo-Mo records action at 13x slower than normal speed, <strong>the slowest slow-motion GoPro has achieved in their lineup</strong>. You can capture details such as water droplets, bike tire treads gripping dirt, or facial expressions during those extreme moments that occur too fast to perceive in real time. The 4x slo-mo mode works at full 5.3K resolution and offers slow-motion footage with great clarity and detail. These are types of slow-motion shots that used to require specialized high-speed cameras that cost thousands of dollars.</p>



<p><strong>Rugged and waterproof construction to 33 feet</strong> means you can take this camera into environments that would destroy phones or traditional cameras immediately. Mud, snow, rain, and underwater environments become accessible filming locations without protective housings or concern for damage. The water-repelling lens cover also serves to actively prevent lens flare and artifacts that ruin shots in wet conditions. You can go from skiing powder to swimming in ocean waves without changing gear or stopping to protect it.</p>



<p>The <em>Handler</em> <strong>floating hand grip prevents the camera from sinking in case you drop it in water</strong> and saves many GoPros from resting forever at the bottom of lakes and oceans. Its bright orange color is visible underwater and makes it easy to spot when dropped. The ergonomic grip delivers stable handheld footage without the camera shake that makes unwatchable home videos. For overhead shots or selfie angles, the grip doubles as a buoyant extension pole.</p>
<p><strong>Two Enduro batteries</strong> extend the shooting time significantly beyond a single battery that comes with standalone cameras. Cold weather hastens the drainage of batteries, and having spares means not missing shots during winter activities. Changing batteries takes a couple of seconds, so you’re never waiting hours for charging on active days. The performance of Enduro batteries in cold conditions is better compared to standard GoPro batteries, which maintain performance in temperatures that could cripple regular lithium cells.</p>
<p>The<strong> 64GB SanDisk microSD card is sufficient for hours of 5.3K footage</strong> before needing to offload files. Curved adhesive mounts stick to helmets, surfboards, cars, or any curved surface for stable POV shots. This carrying case protects everything during transport and keeps accessories organized instead of loose in a backpack. In fact, these included items would cost $150-200 if purchased separately which makes the bundle pricing almost absurd.</p>
<p>For $369, you get a complete shooting kit featuring the latest Hero 13 Black, plus essential accessories that normally cost a total of $500, thus paying less than the camera alone costs at regular pricing. The bundle gets rid of the hidden costs that frustrate new action camera buyers because they come to realize their purchase is incomplete.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5633/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gopro-dumps-hero-13-black-bundle-with-2-batteries-and-hand-grip-now-goes-for-pocket-change-2000644771]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>