<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:30:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple’s 2025 MacBook Air (15″, M4) Drops to Its Lowest Price to Take On Windows Laptops From Microsoft, HP, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apples-2025-macbook-air-15-m4-drops-to-its-lowest-price-to-take-on-windows-laptops-from-microsoft-hp-and-more-2000654278</link>
            <guid>1387159</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="0" data-end="382">Amazon is currently offering a significant discount on <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6483/">the 2025 Apple MacBook Air with the M4 chip, bringing the price down to $949 from its usual $1,119.</a> This 21% reduction translates to a savings of $250, making it one of the best deals available for this model since its release earlier this year. For anyone seeking a powerful yet lightweight laptop, this offer is hard to beat.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6483/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="384" data-end="408"><strong data-start="384" data-end="408">Everyday Performance</strong></h2>
<p data-start="410" data-end="999">The 15.3-inch 2025 MacBook Air continues to be a top pick for users who value portability without compromising on performance. Weighing just 3.3 pounds and maintaining a sleek, slim design, this model upholds the Air’s tradition of ultra-light form while delivering performance on par with larger devices. Despite its compact size, Apple has equipped it with a 10-core CPU, an optional 10-core GPU, and support for up to 24GB of memory. With the new M4 chip, this MacBook Air offers speeds up to twice as fast as the M1-era model and up to 23 times faster than Intel-powered versions.</p>
<p data-start="1001" data-end="1291">Apple designed the M4 chip with Apple Intelligence in mind, optimizing the system for task management, efficient processing, and the ability to handle intensive workflows. Whether you’re writing reports, editing videos, or juggling numerous browser tabs, the MacBook Air keeps up with ease.</p>
<p data-start="1293" data-end="1780">For users who work on the go, the MacBook Air’s battery life is a standout feature. Apple promises up to 18 hours of use on a single charge, which is more than enough to get through a full workday and beyond. Its 12MP front-facing camera, capable of 1080p video resolution, makes it an excellent choice for virtual meetings, online classes, or video calls with loved ones. The built-in three-microphone array ensures clear audio, so you don’t need external equipment to be heard clearly.</p>


<p data-start="1782" data-end="2222">The fully backlit keyboard makes it easy to type in low-light conditions, while Touch ID offers quick and secure access to the laptop. On the sides, there are two Thunderbolt ports for fast data transfer and peripheral connectivity. The MagSafe charging port ensures your power cable remains securely attached but detaches safely if pulled. Apple has also kept the headphone jack—great for anyone who still prefers wired audio devices.</p>
<p data-start="2224" data-end="2430">For those fully integrated into the Apple ecosystem, the MacBook Air offers seamless features like AirDrop, iMessage syncing, and Handoff, allowing for smooth transitions between your iPhone, iPad, and Mac.</p>
<p data-start="2432" data-end="2790"><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6483/">The MacBook Air is available in several configurations, all of which are currently discounted. The 256GB model, priced at $949, offers a $250 savings</a>. The 512GB model is priced at $1,149, also reflecting a $250 reduction. For those needing more memory, the 24GB RAM and 512GB storage configuration has dropped by $250, bringing it down to $1,349 from $1,599.</p>
<p data-start="2792" data-end="3057" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">The MacBook Air is also available in four stylish colors: sky blue, silver, starlight, and midnight. With its impressive performance, ultra-portable design, and generous discounts, the 2025 MacBook Air is a standout option for anyone in the market for a new laptop—especially right now while its $250 off.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6483/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apples-2025-macbook-air-15-m4-drops-to-its-lowest-price-to-take-on-windows-laptops-from-microsoft-hp-and-more-2000654278]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Does Final Price Cut of Year on Xbox Controllers, Nearly 50% Off and Makes Sony’s Look Overpriced]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-does-final-price-cut-of-year-on-xbox-controllers-nearly-50-off-and-makes-sonys-look-overpriced-2000654527</link>
            <guid>1387111</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Microsoft <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/">cut the price of its 2025 Xbox wireless controller on Amazon to $38</a>, which is the lowest price ever for hardware that just came out. That’s a $26 discount off the $64 list price, and here’s the best part: it’s a lot cheaper than Sony’s DualSense (currently selling for $54, down from $74). Yes, these controllers were made for different consoles, but if you play games on your PC or on more than one device, this price makes the Xbox controller the clear choice. Just so you know, Amazon’s shipping estimates say that the package <strong>won’t arrive until after Christmas</strong>, so this is better for treating yourself than for giving as a last-minute gift.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Important for More Than Just Gaming</h2>
<p>The 2025 Xbox controller has some smart changes that make long gaming sessions feel less like finger workouts and more like natural extensions of your hands. Microsoft changed the shape of the geometry by adding sculpted surfaces that fit your grip better which may seem like a small change, but after holding the thing for three hours straight during a marathon session, you’ll see how big of a difference it makes. The hybrid D-pad gives you choices based on the game you’re playing and it has the accuracy of separate buttons and the smooth motion of a disc-style pad. The triggers, bumpers, and back case now have textured grips on them, so your controller won’t turn into a bar of soap when your hands get sweaty during intense moments.</p>
<p>With two AA batteries, the battery life can last up to 40 hours so you can play for weeks without needing to change them. That’s a lot better than controllers with built-in rechargeable batteries that wear out over time and make you play while connected to a cable. You have to carry extra batteries, but honestly, it only takes five seconds to change AAs instead of waiting hours for a charge and if you don’t like disposable batteries, you can also get rechargeable AA packs.</p>



<p>The new Share button is easy to find on the controller face and lets you take screenshots and recordings without having to search through menus or remember button combinations. This feature works directly with Xbox’s capture system, which makes making content feel less like a chore and more like something you’ll actually use. Streaming to friends or social media becomes something that everyone can do, not just people who make content for a living.</p>



<p>You can connect to almost any device you own: Xbox Wireless technology works right away with Xbox Series X, Series S, and Xbox One consoles while <strong>Bluetooth works with Windows PCs, Android phones, iOS devices, Fire TV Sticks, Smart TVs, and even VR headsets</strong>. The pairing button makes it easy to switch between devices in seconds, so you can go from playing games on your console to playing games on your phone without having to go through settings menus. The 3.5mm headset jack works with any wired headphones or gaming headset you already have, so you don’t have to deal with proprietary adapters.</p>
<p>The Xbox Accessories app lets you change the functions of buttons to fit your playstyle or meet your accessibility needs. Players of racing games can change the functions of the back buttons to work with paddle shifters, and players of fighting games can move the functions of the face buttons around to make combos faster. You can use the app on Xbox consoles and Windows PCs.</p>
<p>Here’s the truth: A brand-new 2025 controller with a 40-hour battery life, compatibility with all devices, and ergonomic improvements for $38 is a great deal. Third-party controllers that are similar often skimp on build quality or don’t have official firmware support. On the other hand, first-party controllers from competitors are usually between $50 and $70, even when they’re on sale.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6462/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-does-final-price-cut-of-year-on-xbox-controllers-nearly-50-off-and-makes-sonys-look-overpriced-2000654527]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forget Mac Mini, Amazon’s 4.5-Star Gaming Mini PC Just Hit All-Time Low and Extra Coupon Makes It Even Cheaper]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/forget-mac-mini-amazons-4-5-star-gaming-mini-pc-just-hit-all-time-low-and-extra-coupon-makes-it-even-cheaper-2000654507</link>
            <guid>1387084</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If a workstation refresh is what you’re after, Amazon is making the upgrade easy. The retailer is offering some great discounts on multiple tech gadgets, PCs, laptops, tablets, headphones, and more. Those looking to grab a mini PC should consider the Kamrui Hyper H2, which is currently sitting at $510.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5960/">That’s after a nice 38% discount, but that’s not the only offer here</a>. Using the code <em><strong>JEG1HLJI7VJK</strong></em> at checkout can save you an additional 10%, which brings the total down even further. Moreover, shipping is free, so there are no extra charges to worry about. Just note the discount is listed as a limited-time one at Amazon, which means it’s likely going to wrap up soon. We suggest acting fast to grab it before that happens.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Small But Mighty</h2>
<p>This mini PC is compact; so much so that it fits in the palm of your hand. At just 5.04 x 5.04 x 1.63 inches, it’s a fraction of the size of a traditional desktop, which makes it easy to fit into a tighter space. In fact, it can even be mounted behind your PC or under the desk for a cleaner, minimal look.</p>
<p>Don’t let the size fool you, though. The PC packs a muscular, 10-core 13th Gen Intel Core i7-13620H processor, capable of hitting speeds up to 4.9GHz. It’s made for heavy-duty, resource-intensive tasks, and offers 25–40% higher performance than the R7-8745HS (8C/16T) and i7-1280P processors. The 13th Gen hybrid architecture here distributes workloads efficiently, which results in better response times and a smoother operation, regardless of the job at hand. Pair all this with the massive 32GB RAM, and you’ve got yourself a machine that can support all your multitasking needs. You will be able to use a bunch of programs at the same time, jump through a ton of tabs across multiple browsers, take conference calls, stream while gaming, and more; all without a hint of lag.</p>



<p>There’s a built-in 1TB SSD to help you store all your important data, from work documents, to media content, research papers, and even a few games, in a single place. SSDs are also much faster than their traditional counterparts, so you’ll enjoy better boot and transfer times just as well. Note that the memory and the storage capacities are expandable up to 64GB and 4TB, respectively. You can easily upgrade the system as your needs grow. Those who prefer working with a multi monitor setup will appreciate how the mini PC supports three-screen 4k displays with its HDMI, DP 1.4, and USB4 ports. The USB4 port delivers up to 40Gbps transfer speed, as well, plus provides 15W of power delivery to charge smaller devices or accessories. Other connectivity options include Wi-Fi 6, 2.5GbE LAN, and a range of additional ports to create a full-fledged productive setup.</p>
<p>But despite all the power, the PC keeps things quite calm and cool as it works. That’s thanks to an upgraded silent centrifugal fan, dual copper heat pipes, and a dual-fin module. The all-copper structure improves the overall thermal conductivity and increases airflow by 35%. Translation? Exceptional performance even when you’re juggling heavy creative workloads on a busy day.</p>
<p>In short, if you’ve been wanting to grab a power mini PC that offers strong performance but doesn’t break the bank, the Kamrui Hyper H2 mini gaming PC is an excellent option to consider, especially at its current price. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5960/">Don’t forget to use the discounted code <strong><em>JEG1HLJI7VJK</em></strong> at checkout to maximize your savings!</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5960/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/forget-mac-mini-amazons-4-5-star-gaming-mini-pc-just-hit-all-time-low-and-extra-coupon-makes-it-even-cheaper-2000654507]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Big Mystery Surrounding Netflix’s New FIFA Game Is Who’s Actually Making It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fifa-new-game-netflix-2026-world-cup-delphi-interactive-2000654568</link>
            <guid>1387081</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>FIFA </em>is coming back as a Netflix exclusive. I mean, not really <em>FIFA</em> per se. That franchise is now called <em>EA Sports FC</em> after soccer’s international governing body failed to get EA to keep paying for the licensing rights. This new<em> FIFA</em>, which will only be playable on the Netflix app, will likely be something very different. FIFA and Netflix promise it’s coming next year in time for the 2026 World Cup, but as of right now it’s not even really clear who’s actually going to develop this new soccer game.</p> <p><a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/fifa-mens-world-cup-2026-game-on-netflix">Yesterday’s press release</a> points to Delphi Interactive as the publisher and developer. It’s only real credit up to this point is getting the licensing rights to James Bond for IO Interactive’s upcoming <em>007 First Light</em> game. The Beverly Hills-based outfit bills itself as building “AAA games based on the most desirable IP franchises in the world,” but only has 14 people associated with the company on LinkedIn.</p>

 <p>One of those is CEO <span><span dir="ltr"></span></span></p>

 <p>So who at Delphi actually knows about games? Well, the company did hire <a href="https://www.nordiskgames.com/">Nordisk Games</a> founder Mikkel Weider, who Daugaard previously lauded for having “essentially blitz-scaled Nordisk Games from one employee to 1,300 in just a few years.” Is that what’s going on here? An army of hundreds of developers and outsource teams, working for years in complete secrecy on what FIFA hopes will be the most popular sim soccer game in the world?</p>

 <p>From the outside at least, Delphi Interactive appears to be a financial instrument for hashing out deals. What does it mean to be an AAA publisher with no obvious development experience?&nbsp;“In the era of digital game distribution, we believe that if you have access to a beloved global intellectual property, and you have access to capital to develop and market games, and you have access to the best independent development talent, you can actually make a successful AAA game outside of what we now lovingly refer to as the ’publisher industrial complex’ that has sort of traditionally oligopolized the AAA space,” Daugaard <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/delphi-interactive-nordisk-games-mikkel-weider-strictly-business-1236192058/">told <em>Variety</em></a> last year. So there’s that, I guess?</p>

 <p>One possibility is that Netflix, FIFA, and Delphi Interactive will outsource most of the actual making of this new game to studios abroad, likely in cheaper labor markets where armies of developers can brute-force something into existence in record time. Or maybe the plan is to take a soccer sim that’s already in existence and reskin it with FIFA logos and the likenesses of international stars. “Stay tuned for more details soon,” Daugaard wrote this week.</p>

 <p>It doesn’t help instill confidence that the other two groups involved don’t have great track records. After throwing itself into gaming, including trying to make its own internal blockbuster studio with seasoned industry talent, Netflix has retreated into simple party games and branded cash-ins of its popular streaming franchises. FIFA, meanwhile, remains one of the grimiest international operators out there. It recently invented a fake peace prize to appease President Donald Trump ahead of the World Cup. It’ll be much harder to fake an alternative to <em>EA Sports FC</em>.</p> <p>Delphi Interactive and FIFA did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fifa-new-game-netflix-2026-world-cup-delphi-interactive-2000654568]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lenovo Goes Rogue on Amazon, This Laptop (i5, 512GB, DDR5, WiFi 6) Drops Nearly 80% Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-goes-rogue-on-amazon-this-laptop-i5-512gb-ddr5-wifi-6-drops-nearly-80-off-2000654514</link>
            <guid>1387036</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Shopping for a laptop usually means choosing between your budget and your wish list, but sometimes the universe throws you a bone: This Lenovo <em>IdeaPad Slim 3</em> laptop (512GB, Intel i5, (8GB DDR5 RAM) just <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/">dropped to $439 on Amazon, slashing over three-quarters off its $1,999 list price</a> in what’s an all-time low. Lenovo’s own website isn’t even close to matching this deal, which tells you everything about Amazon’s year-end clearance desperation.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>This Year-End Surprise Brings Together Power and Portability</h2>
<p>The IdeaPad Slim 3 laptop has an Intel 13th Gen Core i5-13420H processor inside and this octa-core chip lets you do a lot of things at once. This processor has a hybrid architecture with four performance cores that can run at speeds of up to 4.6GHz and four efficiency cores that can run at speeds of up to 3.4GHz which means it can do anything from streaming video to working on spreadsheets without any problems. The 12MB cache lets the system handle multiple browser tabs, documents, and applications at the same time which makes it great for students who have to write research papers or professionals who have to manage several projects at once.</p>



<p>The 15.3-inch screen has a WUXGA resolution of 1920×1200 pixels, which gives you a little more vertical space than regular Full HD screens which is useful when you’re scrolling through long documents or web pages. With 300 nits of brightness and an anti-glare coating, the IPS panel lets you work comfortably in a wide range of lighting conditions, from dark rooms to bright coffee shops. The 60Hz refresh rate works fine for everyday computing tasks, and the narrow bezels make the laptop feel more modern than its price would suggest.</p>



<p>The 512GB PCIe NVMe SSD provides a lot of space for documents, photos, and apps, and it also boots up quickly and lets you access files quickly. With this solid-state drive, you won’t have to wait for programs to start or files to save like you would with older laptops that had regular hard drives. If you ever need more storage space, the M.2 form factor makes it easy to upgrade in the future. This laptop has also <strong>two USB-A ports, one USB-C port with Power Delivery 3.0 and DisplayPort 1.2 support, an HDMI 1.4 output, a headphone jack, and an SD card reader</strong>: This means it can connect to just about any device you might need it to.</p>
<p>This laptop is a great deal at $439, especially since you’re getting hardware that costs less than a quarter of what it was originally asking for. That $1,560 discount turns what would be a mid-range purchase into an amazing deal, especially for people who need a good Windows computer but don’t want to spend a lot of money.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6482/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lenovo-goes-rogue-on-amazon-this-laptop-i5-512gb-ddr5-wifi-6-drops-nearly-80-off-2000654514]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>