<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:30:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How A Headline Gets Written At Kotaku: Battlefield 6 Edition]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/how-a-headline-gets-written-at-kotaku-battlefield-6-edition-2000661912</link>
            <guid>1412422</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Consider this the first in a new series of sporadic posts attempting to demystify what goes on at <em>Kotaku</em>, a website about games but also lots of other stuff. We publish many stories here. Sometimes well over a dozen throughout the course of a day. Maybe even a hundred by the end of any given week. Likely the first thing you see on any one of those stories is the headline. How do we come up with those?</p> <p>Well, in the case of a recent news post about <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-announce-classic-big-map-returning-season-two-details-2000661857">new content coming to <em>Battlefield 6</em></a>, it went something like this. Staff writer Zack Zwiezen, our resident anti-Pax Armata expert, filed an article summarizing new details on what’s coming to the shooter in season 2 and beyond. It had the working headline “<i data-stringify-type="italic">Battlefield 6</i> Devs Announce A Classic, Big Map Is Returning And Share Season Two Details.” Accurate, informative, helpful.</p>

 <p>But I spilled my soup during lunch and was feeling a bit cranky. The gaming press, myself included, has a tendency to overuse boring phrases like “announces,” reveals,” and “shows off” to convey that a new thing has happened. I pushed for something that sounded different and offered a couple of alternatives. Here’s the conversation in our work Slack that followed:</p> <blockquote><p><strong>Ethan Gach:</strong><em> Battlefield 6</em> Is Giving Fans A Classic Big Map And More In Season 2<br> <em>Battlefield 6</em> Hears You And Reveals A Classic, Big Map For Season 2.<br> wondering if there’s something more interesting than announces<br> just say what you want to say about what you think about this</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: <em>Battlefield 6</em> Bringing Back Another Classic Map And Its A Big One</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: <em>Battlefield 6</em> Season 2 Brings Back A Classic Map But Will It Be Big Enough?</p> <p><strong> Zack Zwiezen</strong>: Well that’s the catch. It won’t be in season 2<br> they have other maps for season 2<br> this is likely 3</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: lol why aren’t they revealing season 2 maps?<br> that seems like a bad sign for big maps in season 2</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: They revealed a season 2 map and teased this OTHER one</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: is it big?</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: Bigish<br> lol<br> hence why I think they are teasing this OTHER map</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: that seems more the story</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: It’s something I talk about in the post, yeah<br> can try to build a hed around it</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: wait so the map is confirmed not for season 2?<br> or they just won’t say</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: It will be in a future season</p> <p><strong>Carolyn Petit</strong>: yeah they want to appease the people pounding the tables and chanting BIG MAP! BIG MAP! by saying “we’ve got a big map coming soon, we promise!”</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: <em>Battlefield 6</em> Will Bring Back A Classic Big Map But Not For Season 2</p> <p><strong> Zack Zwiezen</strong>: That works<br> <em>Battlefield 6</em> Really Wants You All To Know Big Maps Are Coming, Okay? lol</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: As long as it’s still accurate that seems like the story to me</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: Yeah your hed is accurate</p> <p><strong>Ethan Gach</strong>: <em>Battlefield 6</em> To Concerned Nation: Big Maps Are Coming…Eventually</p> <p><strong>Zack Zwiezen</strong>: <em>Battlefield 6</em> Dev Spreads Out Arms Real Wide On Stage And Receives 20 Minutes Of Standing Applause<br> anyway, posting with your hed</p></blockquote> <p>So there you have it. A perfect headline? No. Better than “<i data-stringify-type="italic">Battlefield 6</i> Devs Announce A Classic, Big Map Is Returning And Share Season Two Details?” Maybe! On the site currently? Yes. And that’s how it got there.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/how-a-headline-gets-written-at-kotaku-battlefield-6-edition-2000661912]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Will Bring Back A Classic Big Map But Not For Season 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-announce-classic-big-map-returning-season-two-details-2000661857</link>
            <guid>1412398</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/every-battlefield-6-map-ranked-from-worst-to-best-2000647370"><em>Battlefield 6′</em></a>s delayed season two arrives in February, and we finally know more about what to expect in the upcoming season. But EA also teased more of what’s to come beyond season two in a new update on <em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s future.</p> <p>On January 21, <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/2014005415114310024">EA and Battlefield Studios shared a new and lengthy update</a> confirming some key details about season two. The biggest news is that EA confirmed season two will include at least two new maps, and it shared a few more details about one of those battlegrounds. Contaminated is one of the new maps arriving sometime in season two, and EA will soon be letting some players hop into the map early via a new round of Battlefield Labs playtesting. Interestingly, EA says it wants to test how the map’s “unique gameplay mechanics function” in a live match. As for how big Contaminated is, EA says its total size lands somewhere between <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-new-map-review-good-eastwood-big-large-ps5-pc-2000645547">Eastwood and Mirak Valley</a>&nbsp;and says it is comparable in size to classic maps such as Arras from <em>Battlefield V.</em></p>

 <p>While that sounds like a decent-sized map, I suspect EA knew some fans wouldn’t be satisfied with that announcement, which probably explains the publisher teasing the return of a massive classic map in Wednesday’s post. Golmud Railway, a map first seen in <em>Battlefield 4,</em> will be added to <em>BF6</em> in a “future season.”</p> <p>“Golmud Railway is being rebuilt for today’s <em>Battlefield</em>, not simply ported forward,” explained the devs. “Our goal is to preserve what made the map so memorable in <em>Battlefield 4</em>, particularly its combined arms gameplay, while improving how it plays and supports<em> Battlefield 6</em> systems. Golmud Railway is planned to be the largest <em>Battlefield 6</em> map to date, giving us the opportunity to expand gameplay on a larger scale.”</p>

 <p>Since before <em>Battlefield 6</em> launched, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-data-confirms-smallest-maps-franchise-ea-fps-bf1-2000640803">fans have been asking for bigger maps</a> or <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-big-large-conquest-map-battle-royale-redsec-golf-course-2000641083">even creating their own using <em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s battle royale map and in-game creation tools</a>. So it’s great to hear that EA and Battlefield Studios are working on a map that will be bigger than any of the current battlegrounds. Hopefully, fans won’t have to wait too long to get to play it. Maybe season three? We’ll have to wait and find out.</p>

 <h2><em>Redsec</em> solo mode update</h2> <p>Meanwhile, <em>Battlefield 6</em> devs confirmed that the Little Bird heli, which was featured in past <em>BF</em> games, will be added in season two. The devs also confirmed they are continuing to work on a solo queue for <em>Redsec</em>, <em>BF6</em>‘s battle royale mode. No release date was shared, and it seems like it could end up never happening if testing doesn’t work out. But for now, it seems like the studios involved in making <em>BF6</em> and <em>Redsec</em> are still working on the fan-requested feature.</p> <p>Here’s the dev’s full update:</p> <blockquote><p>We’re also continuing internal and exploratory testing around Battle Royale Solo play, as we evaluate how different player configurations impact pacing, balance, and the overall Battle Royale experience.</p> <p>This work is focused on understanding where Solo play can best fit within the broader Battle Royale roster, including how it affects match flow, survivability, and long-term engagement when featured alongside other Battle Royale experiences. These tests are part of our ongoing effort to make informed decisions about how Battle Royale is structured and presented over time, rather than committing to a single permanent configuration.</p></blockquote> <p><em>Battlefield 6′</em>s second free season arrives on all platforms on February 17, bringing new maps and, like season one, likely adding more content like new weapons, modes, cosmetics, and more.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-announce-classic-big-map-returning-season-two-details-2000661857]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League Of Legends Fighting Game Finally Hits Consoles But PS5 Players Say It Needs More Work]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/2xko-ps5-league-legends-fighting-game-issues-2000661845</link>
            <guid>1412290</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>2XKO</span></i><span>, Riot Games’ free-to-play </span><i><span>League of Legends</span></i><span> fighting game, released on PC, PS5 and Xbox Series consoles yesterday after roughly 18 months of closed beta tests. While it’s too early to comment on the overall quality of </span><i><span>2XKO’s</span></i><span> gameplay, PlayStation 5 players aren’t too impressed with its performance.</span></p> <p><span>After roughly 18 months of closed betas and “Alpha Lab” playtests, Riot Games has finally released its beginner-friendly, free-to-play (but microtransaction-heavy) fighting game </span><i><span>2XKO </span></i><span>in full. There’s no critical consensus regarding </span><i><span>2XKO</span></i><span> yet. At launch there aren’t even <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/2xko/">any reviews of the console version</a>.&nbsp; B</span><span>ut I sunk a couple of hours into it this morning and can confirm that it’s still just as good as it was during the last closed beta.</span></p>

 <p><span>Little caveat there: I played on PC. </span><i><span>2XKO </span></i><span>has technically been available on PC in early access since October 7, 2025, but only officially launched on Xbox Series S/X and PS5 on January 20. This is relevant because, according to the numerous posts that have popped up on the r/2XKO subreddit over the past 24 hours, the PS5 version of the game has a few performance-related issues.</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">2XKO on PS5 might be the roughest I’ve ever seen a fighting game launch. Extreme screen tearing in fights, lags in matches and in lobbies, horrible monetization.</p> <p>There’s a great fighting game here but it’s dying by 1000 cuts. <a href="https://t.co/w4jT0pyN5m">pic.twitter.com/w4jT0pyN5m</a></p> <p>— reyna cervantes (@Jfcdoomblade) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jfcdoomblade/status/2013843486512947644?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 21, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>As detailed in the most active PS5-related </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2XKO/comments/1qinnhu/game_runs_like_total_ass_on_the_ps5/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>thread</span></a><span> on the subreddit, titled “Game runs like total ass on the ps5,” PlayStation players have reported that they’re experiencing crashes, frequent FPS drops and, most commonly, heavy screen tearing.</span></p>

 <p><span>“I’m not having FPS drops (though I’m on PS5 Pro), but the screen tearing is horrendous,” writes user </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2XKO/comments/1qinnhu/comment/o0t6r6l/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>trugay</span></a><span>. “It’s the worst I’ve ever seen on a console title. It makes this a fairly disappointing release. I’m enjoying the game and its mechanics, but this is really dampening the experience.”</span></p>

 <p><span>Over on Twitter, user </span><a href="https://x.com/Jfcdoomblade/status/2013843486512947644"><span>Jfcdoomblade</span></a><span> uploaded a clip of the FPS drops in action and stated that “2XKO on PS5 might be the roughest I’ve ever seen a fighting game launch.”</span></p> <p><span>Oddly enough, I was unable to find any similar complaints from Xbox Series users. In fact, the only Xbox-related </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2XKO/comments/1qir40k/having_a_blast_on_xbox_so_fun/"><span>thread</span></a><span> I could find was from one user gushing about how much fun they’re having.</span></p> <p><span>It’s important to note here that the screen tearing issue can’t be properly replicated through recorded footage, as screen tearing occurs through the monitor used to display the image. PS5 owners have theorized that the screen tearing issue in </span><i><span>2XKO </span></i><span>may only occur when the game is played on a 120hz screen.</span></p>

 <p><span>If you’re confused as to why the same issue isn’t popping up for PC players who are using 120hz monitors, PS5 users have </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2XKO/comments/1qinnhu/comment/o0tfyys/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>further theorized</span></a><span> that this may be due to an issue with how v-sync has been implemented on the PlayStation 5 version of </span><i><span>2XKO</span></i><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/2xko-ps5-league-legends-fighting-game-issues-2000661845]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fat Pikachu Is Back]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fat-pikachu-chunkachu-pokemon-30th-plush-2000661861</link>
            <guid>1412242</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A plush Pikachu and the original Pikachu card.</span> © The Pokémon Company / Tomy / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The very first design for Pokémon mascot Pikachu was a delightfully chubby little fellow. Chunkachu, as it’s lovingly known, was Mitsuhiro Arita’s original drawing for the 1996 Japanese Pokémon card, and it gave the yellow mouse a lot more to love than he has in most modern renditions. To celebrate the 30th anniversary of <em>Pokémon</em> this year, Takara Tomy is releasing a proper chungus of a plushie in that original design.</p> <p>It’s going to be a very busy year for&nbsp;<em>Pokémon</em>. 2026 is the 30th anniversary of not only the release of the very first&nbsp;<em>Pokémon</em> games, Japan’s <em>Pocket Monsters </em><em>Red</em> and&nbsp;<em>Green</em> on February 27 of 1996, but also the very first Japanese <em>Pokémon TCG</em> cards with October 20, 1996’s 1st Starter &amp; Expansion Pack, meaning the celebrations are going to last the whole year. And that’s a very good excuse to remember how Pikachu used to look, both in the game and on the cards, before he got the Mounjaro.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000661887" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661887"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661887">© Tomy / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The new plush comes not from The Pokémon Company and isn’t available on its various Pokémon Center stores, but rather is being sold by toy giant <a href="https://takaratomymall.jp/shop/g/g8202602097181/">Takara Tomy</a>, and currently only in Japan. The extremely cuddle-able stuffed toy is 7,480 yen, or about $47, which isn’t too bad for a 40 cm tall cuddly. At the time of writing it’s sold out on Tomy’s site, though more expensive options for purchase still seem to pop up on <a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0GG8Y6125?th=1">Amazon’s Japanese site</a>.</p> <p>Chunkachu has been celebrated across the decades in <em>Pokémon</em>, not least with the design of the monster’s <a href="https://www.serebii.net/card/vmaxclimax/46.jpg">VMAX incarnation</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.serebii.net/card/25thanniversarycollection/1.jpg">updated versions of the original artwork</a> appearing during the 25th anniversary celebrations. But for the most part, the far more slimmed-down rendition of Pikachu is the recognizable emblem of the entire franchise. And fair enough—name a beloved cartoon character that didn’t look all kinds of weirdly different in their first form than the version we got used to. Oh my dear god, original Garfield.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000661873" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661873"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661873">© Jim Davis</figcaption></figure>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fat-pikachu-chunkachu-pokemon-30th-plush-2000661861]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>