<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:31:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Adds the ULT WEAR Headphones to Its Clearance Lineup, Almost 2x Cheaper Than WH-1000XM5 Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-adds-the-ult-wear-headphones-to-its-clearance-lineup-almost-2x-cheaper-than-wh-1000xm5-model-2000654713</link>
            <guid>1388386</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A great pair of headphones can change the way you enjoy your favorite media. You can drop a lot of cash on one, but you need to make sure you get a brand that can actually deliver. And you’ll also want to find some that you won’t have to spend an arm and a leg on. We found some great Sony headphones that are not only discounted, but they’re lightweight, cushioned, and built to fit well for long listening sessions. And best of all, you can get them on sale right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6523/">The Sony ULT WEAR Over-Ear Noise Canceling Bluetooth Headphones are up over at Amazon for just $148, down from their usual price of $250.</a> That’s a discount of $102 and 41% off. Not too shabby for a pair of great headphones from a reputable brand.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6523/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Comfortable headphones perfect for just about any use case</h2>
<p>These headphones are prided on how comfortable they feel. The ear cups offer extremely soft padding so you can wear them for hours without discomfort. If you’re used to earbuds that can sometimes pinch the insides of your ears, that could be a major game-changer. The headband is adjustable too, so you can find a fit that feels right for you. They won’t squeeze your head or ears too tightly either, something that ends up happening with far too many models.</p>
<p>The active noise canceling feature really stands out. It helps reduce background noise from things like traffic, conversations, or airplane engines so you can enjoy cleaner sound. Whether you want to concentrate on a podcast or just enjoy silence during a busy commute, the noise canceling makes a noticeable difference. You also have the option to let in some ambient sound without removing your headphones if you need to be aware of your surroundings.</p>



<p>Battery life is strong too and you can expect many hours of playback on a single charge. That means you can get through a long flight, a work day, or a weekend trip without needing to plug in. This pair also recharges quickly, so you don’t have to sit around waiting for long to get them back up to a level that you can listen at.</p>
<p>Overall, the Sony ULT WEAR Over-Ear Noise Canceling Bluetooth Headphones deliver comfort, quality, and quiet listening in a package that works for many situations. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6523/">And at the current price of $148 on Amazon, down from $250, these headphones are a solid value.</a> They’re a great pick for anyone who needs great sound, a lengthy battery life, and plenty of features that make them a fantastic-sounding pair of headphones. Don’t miss out and snag the deal while you still can.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6523/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-adds-the-ult-wear-headphones-to-its-clearance-lineup-almost-2x-cheaper-than-wh-1000xm5-model-2000654713]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP Drops a 5-Star Laptop by 70% and Throws in $199 Worth of Accessories, Only on Amazon Not the Official Site]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hp-drops-a-5-star-laptop-by-70-and-throws-in-199-worth-of-accessories-only-on-amazon-not-the-official-site-2000654786</link>
            <guid>1388260</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon is making it easier than ever to grab a new laptop without breaking the bank. We’re spotting plenty of amazing deals on a wide range of machines from popular brands like HP, Dell, Asus, Lenovo, and even Apple – basically, there’s something for everyone.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6521/">One of our favorite discounts, however, is this 70% drop on the 15.6-inch HP touchscreen laptop, which brings the overall price down to just $650, but that’s not all.</a> You’re also getting a 6-in-1 accessory bundle worth almost $200 with your purchase for free, which adds even more value to the offer. This deal applies to the stunning moonlight blue version, which gives off a premium, sleek look. Just note that the discount wraps up soon, so it’s best to grab it before the price shoots back up to $2,200.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6521/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Impressive Power</h2>
<p>You’re greeted with a stunning 15.6-inch Full HD display upon opening the laptop. The screen features an ultra-thin 6.5 mm micro-edge bezel for a bigger viewing area, while the anti-glare coating keeps the visuals easy on your eyes. Touch support takes this a bit further by making navigation a breeze. You won’t have to rely on the trackpad or the mouse solely to get things done. Need to scroll a long document? Just use your fingers directly on the screen. The included touchscreen pen also makes it quite easy to swipe, draw, sketch, and even type!</p>
<p>The screen is paired with a full-sized keyboard, alongside a dedicated numeric keypad, which is quite comfortable to use. It provides your wrist with the support it needs for jotting down long documents, plus includes a dedicated Copilot key that launches the helpful AI assistant instantly. There’s also a built-in webcam, with integrated microphones for convenient video calls.</p>



<p>Power comes from the combination of an Intel Core i3-N305 processor and a modest 16GB RAM. Together, these let you push through busy, productive days with ease, regardless of the task at hand. The 1TB SSD, on the other hand, offers ample space to store all your important documents and files in a single place, without feeling limited.</p>
<p>Battery life is another strong selling point. A single charge offers over 9 hours of use, which means you can go an entire workday without worrying about running out of power. Recharging is fast too, so you won’t have to stay tethered to an outlet for long when running low. And finally, the free accessory bundle includes a touchscreen pen, a 128GB thumb drive, a laptop bag, a cleaning cloth, a camera protector, dust plugs, and Windows 11 Pro pre-installed. That’s everything you need to get started with work and entertainment, right away, and you’re basically getting far more than just a direct discount with this deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6521/">This laptop is currently down to just $650 at Amazon, which is practically nothing for a device this packed.</a> This is the lowest we have seen it drop to in a long while, but the offer won’t be around for long. Grab it while there’s still time, as it could wrap up any moment now. Once it’s gone, we don’t expect it to be back at this price anytime soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6521/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hp-drops-a-5-star-laptop-by-70-and-throws-in-199-worth-of-accessories-only-on-amazon-not-the-official-site-2000654786]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>