<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:46:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign‘s DLC Will Be Harder And Change More Than You Think]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-map-swamp-field-bosses-2000649718</link>
            <guid>1371088</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I’m one of the many <a href="https://kotaku.com/nightreigns-bell-bearing-carion-draconic-tree-sentinel-2000649218"><em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em> players</a> who’s been begging for DLC for months.<a href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-forsaken-hollows-artorias-dark-souls-2000643101"> Once it was finally revealed</a>, I was a bit disappointed at how small it seemed. Fortunately, three new pieces of information have convinced me that I have been underestimating FromSoftware’s upcoming <em>The Forsaken Hollows</em> DLC. According to a new interview, it’ll be harder than the main game, feature a bigger reworking of the map than previously thought, and include the introduction of the <em>Dark Souls</em> studio’s signature poison swamps.</p> <p>Since the summer, it’s felt like the only way to really revitalize <em>Nightreign</em> was by <a href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-endless-mode-datamine-depths-relics-2000616334">giving players a new map</a>. When <em>The Forsaken Hollows</em> was finally announced, publisher Bandai Namco’s description suggested the Limveld sandbox everyone had become accustomed to would be tweaked but left pretty much intact by the new content. According to a new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-has-reignited-my-interest/1100-6536543/">preview at <em>GameSpot</em></a>, Bandai Namco actually undersold their new content. The new Scholar and Undertaker classes aren’t the only big additions. There’s also the Great Hollows, which is technically still a Shifting Earth event, but is also a much more expansive one than players have previously encountered.</p>

 <p>Players will glide into a separate section of the map with its own fields, city ruins, and sprawling mines. There will even be side-quests where players have to visit side-objectives to alleviate a special new curse. The Great Hollows will apparently be much more vertically focused as well, with caves and tunnels and also points higher up that require light platforming. It definitely sounds like a bigger deal than any of the existing Shifting Earth events players usually just spend the last five minutes of a run zooming through.</p>

 <h2>No new map, but the next best thing</h2> <p>Also, there are swamps now. Not just in the Great Hollows, but the whole of Limveld. These new areas will slow movement and build up poison, scarlet rot, frenzy, and other ailments if you stay in them too long. It sounds simple, but <em>Nightreign</em> is all about navigation, time management, and risk assessment. I can already see many runs succeeding or failing based on players getting too greedy or overly cautious when it comes to traversing these new hazards.</p>

 <p>Director Junya Ishizaki told <em>GameSpot</em> he’s aware of the poison swamp meme, and while there’s no strict rule about every FromSoftware game needing a swamp, it just “always seems to be [that before you realize] someone’s come up with the idea, it’s already sort of in there, and it’s just sort of taken a life of its own.”</p>

 <p>All of these new elements, including new field bosses and some re-worked points of interest, seem aimed at giving seasoned Nightfarers the feeling of playing the game for the first time again, back when they were utterly confused by its mechanics and constantly getting punished for it. This is exactly what fans have been waiting for.</p>

 <h2>Hard enough to feel like you’re playing <em>Nightreign</em> for the first time again</h2> <p>“Obviously, we don’t want it to be so hard that new players can’t get into it, but I think the original idea is that when the game initially had come out, there were even players who are veterans of some of the other games trying to figure out the new systems, trying to figure out how the game works,” Ishizaki said. “I think [we want our] ideas when we’re working on the DLC content to be a reflection of that.”</p>

 <p>He continued, “So whenever people who have played the main game extensively go into the DLC content, they’ll be able to have a bit of that feeling like they had when they first played <em>Nightreign</em>, where there’s still a bit that they’re trying to figure out. [The Forsaken Hollows is] definitely a little bit harder, but it’s not ridiculous or anything like that, but that’s still within what we would consider to be a fair challenge.”</p> <p>I hope he’s lying and players get absolutely wrecked. Like <a href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-libra-summons-everdark-tips-2000617780">Everdark Sovereign Equilibrious Beast</a> except fun.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-map-swamp-field-bosses-2000649718]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Players Upset About New Update That Makes Everyone Look Like A Stoner]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/skate-season-2-update-skin-tone-changes-tired-stoners-character-changes-2000649710</link>
            <guid>1371043</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/skate-4-reboot-ea-no-offline-mode-always-online-2025-1851777885">EA’s live-service reboot of <em>Skate</em>,</a> which launched back in September, is continuing to expand and improve. The skateboarding game’s second season is out now, and fans mostly appreciate the new content and changes. But a lot of players aren’t happy about their in-game characters suddenly looking sick and tired after season two went live, with some jokingly referring to them as drug addicts or stoners.</p> <p>On December 2, <a href="https://kotaku.com/skate-4-reboot-ea-launch-date-september-xbox-ps5-pc-trailer-2000620375"><em>Skate</em> season two went live on all platforms.</a> The update adds cosmetic items, fresh areas to skate, a new trick (the Impossible), and a host of quality-of-life tweaks and visual changes. That’s all good and nice, and overall, fans are happy about the update, even if there are some odd lag issues at the moment. But many players were surprised to find their characters looking different, a bit more tired perhaps, when logging on Tuesday to play <em>Skate</em>. As part of EA and developer Full Circle’s commitment to improving <em>Skate’s</em> visuals, a lot of characters now have dark bags under their eyes and darker complexions.</p>

 <p>“Why the faces look so tired and weird?” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcibc1/why_the_faces_looks_so_tired_and_weird/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">asked one Redditor</a> on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pciob3/season_2_comparison/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><em>Skate</em> subreddit.</a> Someone else joked that the new update had <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pchvpk/update_ghould_my_character/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">“Ghoul’d” their character.</a> On Twitter, some replies to EA’s tweet announcing the new <em>Skate</em> update included more screenshots of characters that now look a lot more tired than before. One user shouted at EA: “Look what you did to MY FACE! Look at my face! Look at it!” <a href="https://x.com/Koreyzzz/status/1995931933600350654">Another player shared an image of their character </a>with darker eyes and mentioned that the <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/skate/skate/news/the-grind-vol-six#:~:text=%E2%80%9CIt%E2%80%99s%20important%20to,our%20future%20updates.%E2%80%9D">devs had previously promised to make characters look better</a> and didn’t think that this update accomplished that.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">You guys are not making any sense. <a href="https://t.co/Rw5vhBi8fW">pic.twitter.com/Rw5vhBi8fW</a></p> <p>— Роман Платонов (@Roman__Platonov) <a href="https://twitter.com/Roman__Platonov/status/1995928606980407603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Some players even claimed that they loaded up the game and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcfk94/they_changed_my_skin_color/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">found their character</a> had <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pchja2/what_did_they_do_to_him/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">a totally new skin tone</a>. Looking across social media and Reddit and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcg51e/this_update_gave_me_cancer/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">seeing all the images</a> of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcgsg7/okay_we_went_from_looking_like_fortnite/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">characters looking different</a>, it’s clear that something has changed, and a lot of people (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcicph/were_the_visual_pass_good_guys/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">not everyone, though</a>…) <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SkateEA/comments/1pcgc0m/characters_look_really_bad_now/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">aren’t happy about it</a>. Some are even asking EA to revert the change to characters or add a toggle to let people go back to the more cartoony look seen when <em>Skate</em> launched earlier this year.</p> <p><em>Kotaku</em> contacted EA for more information.</p> <p>I doubt EA will let people toggle between the old and new look, but with how often Skate has been updated and the devs’ commitment to listening to player feedback during the game’s early access development, I expect this won’t be the last time players boot up Skate and discover their characters look a bit different. Hopefully, next time everyone won’t look so tired.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/skate-season-2-update-skin-tone-changes-tired-stoners-character-changes-2000649710]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Days Of Ridicule, Amazon Takes Down Its Awful AI-Generated Anime Dub]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-ai-generated-english-dub-banana-fish-reaction-2000649707</link>
            <guid>1370989</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>After a week of viral clips and outrage from anime fans and AI-haters alike, Amazon has taken down the AI-generated English dub for </span><i><span>Banana Fish</span></i><span>.</span></p> <p><span>The embarrassingly bad dub of the action-packed yaoi was a first for Amazon and was labeled as an “AI Beta” in the series’ language options. Instead of hiring voice actors with all of Jeff Bezos’ fuck you money, Amazon uploaded an AI voice track that is monotone, weirdly mixed, and makes even the most exciting scenes sound like a boring text-to-speech demonstration. Anime is known for its dynamic voice performances, and this shit sounds like it barely gets above a whisper. Here’s a clip, and sorry for putting it somewhere you can hear it:</span></p> <div><blockquote cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@animedomainx/video/7577995965458648328" data-video-id="7577995965458648328" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@animedomainx" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@animedomainx?refer=embed">@animedomainx</a>  <p>This is Back ngl 🥀 Amazon has started using Al to dub shows, and the first anime to receive an English Al dub is Banana Fish. Many voice actors are speaking out against Amazon’s decision, criticizing the use of Al and the fact that human voice actors were not compensated. Banana Fish is an action-packed crime thriller that follows a young, intelligent gang leader named Ash Lynx as he investigates a mysterious d_rug called “Banana Fish” while trying to protect a pure-hearted Japanese boy, Eiji Okumura, in the dangerous underworld of 1980s New York City Follow For Daily Anime News <a title="bananafish" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/bananafish?refer=embed">#BananaFish</a></p> <p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Anime DomainX | Anime News" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7577996058077301511?refer=embed">♬ original sound – Anime DomainX | Anime News</a> </p></section> </blockquote></div>  <p><span>After days of ridicule, Amazon has </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/anime-shows/after-widespread-criticism-for-the-use-of-ai-voice-actors-amazon-removes-ai-dub-from-anime-series-banana-fish/"><span>removed the fake English dub</span></a><span> from its streaming services. Bullying works. Hire actors. Bezos has </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/real-time-billionaires/"><span>billions of dollars</span></a><span>, and you’re telling me that man can’t afford to put someone in a booth?&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>As of this writing, the Spanish AI-generated dub is still available, but we’ll see if that lasts. The next question is, will Amazon continue to roll back this decision by releasing a proper English dub with real actors? God knows the company has the money to do it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Anime isn’t the only industry that has started relying on generative AI to add voices to creative works. Video games like </span><i><span>Arc Raiders </span></i><span>have AI-generated voices, and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-gen-ai-arc-raiders-brendan-green-2000644914"><span>rich people are lining up to tell you</span></a><span> that replacing real voice actors with soulless droning machines is good, actually. A lot of AI apologia relies on the false notion that AI-generated content is good enough to replace human-made work, and if this is the best it has to offer, everyone will continue to rally against it.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-ai-generated-english-dub-banana-fish-reaction-2000649707]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>