<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:57:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Has Done Something Wonderful That Every Major Publisher Needs To Copy]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/command-conquer-ea-source-code-red-alert-generals-1851767009</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-has-done-something-wonderful-that-every-major-publisher-needs-to-copy.1122006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/command-conquer-ea-source-code-red-alert-generals-1851767009<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The world is built on sharing. Sure, it might seem like the most counter-cultural act imaginable amidst these late-stage capitalism end-of-days horrors, but the very internet on which you’re reading these words wouldn’t exist without it. The games you play depend on it. It’s the very core of art itself. So, it’s generally a pretty good thing when games industry people remember this. Speaking of which, EA just made the code for the first four <em>Command &amp; Conquer</em> games officially open source.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,196663,194143" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>You may, as someone possibly young enough to have been untroubled by the <em>Command &amp; Conquer</em> games in their heyday, see this as a relatively minor act. It’s really, <em>really</em> not. And if we’re going to be fiercely critical of EA when it does horrible things, it’s also crucial that we celebrate when the publisher does something this important.</p><p>Two primers. <strong>Firstly, <em>Command &amp; Conquer</em></strong>, or <em>C&amp;C</em> as it’s mostly known to its adoring fanbase. These were a series of utterly superb real-time strategy games, sometimes the best in the medium,  gloriously loved in part for their kitschy full-motion video cutscenes. The first game, in 1995, sold <em>three million copies </em>in a time before games really did that, and that was despite its FMV sequences starring members of the development team in the lowest-budget way imaginable.</p><p>As the series went on, these cutscenes began to star some really big names, the likes of James Earl Jones, J.K. Simmons, George Takei, Tim Curry, Jonathan Pryce, and—uh-oh—Gina Carano. The release of a new entry was always a big deal, with gaming magazines inevitably plastering them over front pages and  reviews so frequently glowing. So while the name “<em>Command &amp; Conquer</em>” may not mean so much in 2025, 17 years after the last decent game in the series—<em>Red Alert 3</em>—it remains one of the most significant franchises in gaming history.</p><p><strong>Secondly, source codes.</strong> Any game being made publicly available for free (as in: yours to keep, copy, share forever) is to be celebrated, in an industry that usually so spitefully clings on to long-dead IPs that it refuses to sell, but still employs lawyers to prevent being accessible. But releasing a game’s source code is next level. This is not the game itself, as in a thing to boot up and play, but rather the flesh and bones that makes the game exist. It’s <em>all the secrets</em>. It offers developers the ability to see exactly how a game was put together, read all the hilariously botched bits of code the devs strung together in desperation to get a game out the door, and learn how the best in the business constructed their games.</p><p>Very few games publishers ever allow access to a game’s source code, even if they’re willing to let a game be freely shared. It’s not always possible—code is lost or difficult to put all in one place, and licenses can be nightmarish. But even when it is easily doable, it’s still a rarity. Often this is simply because developers are desperately embarrassed, horrified at the idea of their peers learning just how precariously held together their code proves to be, even though that’s the case for absolutely everyone else’s work too! Also, people are shitty, and there’s always grim hostility as code is judged by people who couldn’t do better. Sometimes it’s because sharing source code can give people the impression that you’re also now available for tech support, there to answer every question about every detail, and no one wants or needs that. But too often it’s because of a belief that these are industry secrets, precious treasures that must be sat upon for all of time lest a rival do something so inhumanly awful as <em>copy</em>.</p><p>So, given all this context, this move by EA is really significant, and incredibly welcome. Because going “open source” is even bigger than has already been suggested. Publishing the code under <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the GPL license</a></span> means that absolutely anybody is now allowed to take that code, make even minor changes to it, and then sell it for profit! Clearly, not many would pay for such low-effort output, but that’s the core of the principle here. It’s the same basis on which Linux distributions are published, along with all the free software that runs on it. It’s free, open code, there for the wider public to learn from, adapt, and reinterpret.</p><p>The four games now having their code published under the GPL are <em>Command &amp; Conquer</em>, <em>C&amp;C: Red Alert</em>, <em>C&amp;C: Renegade</em> (a first-person shooter!), and <em>C&amp;C: Generals</em>.</p><p>EA isn’t alone here, of course. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://github.com/id-software&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://github.com/id-software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">id Software was known for many years</a></span> for publishing the source code for its games a few years after release. (Unfortunately  id, now owned by Microsoft, doesn’t seem to have any interest in continuing the trend.) Epic, another company built in the ‘90s on principles of shareware and shared code, also releases <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://github.com/RedPandaProjects/UnrealEngine&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://github.com/RedPandaProjects/UnrealEngine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">older versions of the Unreal Engine</a></span>, as well as games like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/unreal-engine-epic-free-internet-archive-fortnite-1851698320&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/unreal-engine-epic-free-internet-archive-fortnite-1851698320"><em>Unreal </em>and <em>Unreal Tournament</em></a></span>.</p><p>What makes this <em>Command &amp; Conquer </em>move quite so striking is that it’s EA doing it. They’re not exactly a company known for, let’s say, loving acts of kindness. In more recent years, the publisher has become synonymous with the lowest aspects of video gaming, from forcing its games to be played with an internet connection before the era of widely-available broadband, to gacha awfulness with its gambling-adjacent loot boxes. In fact, the <em>C&amp;C</em> name itself was run into the ground until it was all but worthless after EA forced in always-on DRM to hastily made sequels and released terrible free-to-play mobile versions. </p><figure id="" data-id="153d4b128504c7b43e0f0a231c9a3b46" data-recommend-id="image://153d4b128504c7b43e0f0a231c9a3b46" data-format="jpg" data-width="1022" data-height="575" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The battle map, covered in fire, from C&amp;C Generals." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The battle map, covered in fire, from C&amp;C Generals." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->EA / Mobygames / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="153d4b128504c7b43e0f0a231c9a3b46" data-recommend-id="image://153d4b128504c7b43e0f0a231c9a3b46" data-format="jpg" data-width="1022" data-height="575" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The battle map, covered in fire, from C&amp;C Generals." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But, soft! What light through yonder window breaks? Is this a crack in their tough, outer veneer? A sign of a future EA that is interested in games preservation, and the open and free sharing of intellectual property from which it no longer has a means to meaningfully profit? Because dear God, I hope so.</p><p>And I hope other publishers sit up and take notice about how we’re all now making cooing noises and scratching EA under its chin, rather than simply scowling at it. This should be normal! It’s essentially free to a publisher—you just stick the source code on Github and eat your lumps. Somehow one of the most controversial things I ever wrote was suggesting that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/editorial-why-games-should-enter-the-public-domain&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/editorial-why-games-should-enter-the-public-domain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">games should go into the public domain a full 20 years after their first release</a></span>, despite this seeming like the most sensible, industry-boosting action possible, at a point when publishers are no longer making real money from the original versions. OK, so in the case of most the games being made available here, we’re talking closer to 30 years. But I’ll take it!</p><p>So come on, everyone! A revolution! EA, give us the source code for <em>Sim City 2000</em>! LucasFilm, hand over <em>Day of the Tentacle</em>! Activision, share <em>MechWarrior 2</em> with everyone! Just imagine the learning resources that could be out there, the archive of code for the most important games of past generations, and the absolute assurance of their preservation for the future.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Fans Have A Conspiracy Theory That Cyndaquil Isn't In Legends: Z-A Because Of Smutty Folklore]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-cyndaquil-typhlosion-starters-1851767008</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-fans-have-a-conspiracy-theory-that-cyndaquil-isnt-in-legends-z-a-because-of-smutty-folklore.1121970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-cyndaquil-typhlosion-starters-1851767008<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d418997a9e81c294a6238bc918f99cb3" data-recommend-id="image://d418997a9e81c294a6238bc918f99cb3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1185" data-height="666" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Hisuian Typhlosion surrounded by ghost-like fireballs." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Hisuian Typhlosion surrounded by ghost-like fireballs." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokémon Company</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d418997a9e81c294a6238bc918f99cb3" data-recommend-id="image://d418997a9e81c294a6238bc918f99cb3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1185" data-height="666" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Hisuian Typhlosion surrounded by ghost-like fireballs." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>During yesterday’s annual <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-day-presents-legends-z-a-tcg-pocket-switch-1851766680&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-day-presents-legends-z-a-tcg-pocket-switch-1851766680">Pokémon Day Presents showcase</a></span>, Game Freak finally unveiled <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-switch-trailer-mega-evolution-az-1851766880&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-switch-trailer-mega-evolution-az-1851766880">gameplay footage of <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></a></span>, revealing real-time combat, the return of some old friends, and teases about new mysteries in Lumiose City. It also revealed the three starters for the game will be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/plza-starters-pokemon-legends-tepig-chikorita-totodile-1851766763&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/plza-starters-pokemon-legends-tepig-chikorita-totodile-1851766763">Chikorita, Tepig, and Totodile</a></span>. At a glance, those picks aren’t that odd. <em>Pokémon Legends: Arceus </em>had starters that originated in regions different from the Sinnoh one it was set in. However, given two of them are from Gen II’s Johto region, fans are wondering why Cyndaquil, the fire-type porcupine-ish little guy who also debuted in <em>Gold </em>and <em>Silver</em>, wasn’t part of the starting roster alongside Chikorita and Totodile. The most plausible reasons for the omission aren’t that interesting, but the more outlandish conspiracy theories forming around it are very funny.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,195519,195905" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>If you somehow missed it last year, <em>Pokémon </em>developer Game Freak was subject to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-hack-teraleak-gen-10-switch-2-game-freak-beta-1851671688&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-hack-teraleak-gen-10-switch-2-game-freak-beta-1851671688">a massive leak in October</a></span>. As information trickled out of the company, we learned things about upcoming projects and scrapped Pokémon, and also got a few folklore-style stories about the universe that may or may not be canon. One of these stories <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-game-freak-leak-typhlosion-octillery-story-lore-1851672828?_gl=1*zqnogo*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc1NzQ2Mi4xNzYuMS4xNzQwNzU3NjEwLjQ1LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-game-freak-leak-typhlosion-octillery-story-lore-1851672828?_gl=1*zqnogo*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc1NzQ2Mi4xNzYuMS4xNzQwNzU3NjEwLjQ1LjAuMA..">focused on a Typhlosion</a></span>, the final form of Cyndaquil, who transformed into a human and impregnated a woman. The internet had a field day with it and the fire starter’s reputation hasn’t recovered from the scandal. Now, fans are spinning tales that the reason Cyndaquil isn’t joining its Johto starters in <em>Legends: Z-A </em>is that Game Freak may have thought it was too soon to put it back in the spotlight. The more likely explanation is that Cyndaquil was a starter in <em>Legends: Arceus</em>, and Game Freak probably didn’t want to double-dip in the same subseries. But nevertheless, fans are running with the theory, and while some think the Typhlosion jokes are dead, I am still laughing.</p><p>Typhlosion has gotten some recent love, so it’s not like Cyndaquil fans are starving. The Pokémon got a brand new Hisuian form in <em>Legends: Arceus</em> that is arguably even cooler than its Johto region variant. But even if he’s not a starter this time, hopefully the little guy still shows up in <em>Legends: Z-A</em> as an obtainable Pokémon when the game launches later this year.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed's Best Bow Is Bought From A Posh Shop Right At The Start]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avoweds-best-bow-is-bought-from-a-posh-shop-right-at-the-start.1121928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b17874fc1283fbfebb3ef26f164587e4" data-recommend-id="image://b17874fc1283fbfebb3ef26f164587e4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1075" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a character in Avowed holding The Long Touch bow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image of a character in Avowed holding The Long Touch bow." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b17874fc1283fbfebb3ef26f164587e4" data-recommend-id="image://b17874fc1283fbfebb3ef26f164587e4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1075" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a character in Avowed holding The Long Touch bow." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Avowed</em>’s selection of unique bows is well-rounded, but one known as The Long Touch is perhaps the best choice for most Rangers. While you could argue that the Ancient Alacrity is truly the best, it can’t be obtained until the final stretch of the game’s main story, making it a difficult recommendation. Meanwhile, The Long Touch can be found early and should make for an excellent weapon throughout the majority of your adventure. Here’s what you need to know about it and where to find it.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h58"><a id=""></a><strong>The Long Touch passive bonus and enchantments</strong></h2><p>The Long Touch comes with the Lesser Opening Strike passive bonus, which grants +5 percent damage when hitting foes with full health. This mediocre bonus isn’t the bread and butter of this bow, so it’s not something to think too much about.</p><p>The Long Touch comes with the Grim Focus enchantment, which gives you +10 percent critical hit chance when fine aiming. You can choose one of two permanent upgrades to this enchantment:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Lethal Focus - Increases the critical chance to +20 percent when fine aiming.</li><li>Thrill of the Hunt - Gives you 10 percent extra attack damage and 20 percent extra attack speed for 6 seconds after killing an enemy.</li></ul><h2 id="h59"><a id=""></a><strong>Where to find The Long Touch</strong></h2><figure id="" data-id="7b02bbd5a148559730cd1f81a5e666f3" data-recommend-id="image://7b02bbd5a148559730cd1f81a5e666f3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1086" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Long Touch bow in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Long Touch bow in Avowed." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7b02bbd5a148559730cd1f81a5e666f3" data-recommend-id="image://7b02bbd5a148559730cd1f81a5e666f3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1086" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Long Touch bow in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The Long Touch is available very early in the game, after you gain access to Paradis within the first region of Dawnshore. Unlike many unique weapons, this one is purchased from a nameless militia merchant in Northern Paradis (also known as Hightown). She can be found within the Militia Headquarters, which is located in the northeastern segment of this upper-class area.</p><p>The militia merchant sells The Long Touch for 4,320 coins, which is quite a lot of dough early in the game. Sell anything you don’t need from your adventures and try to save up for it if necessary. You should find plenty of gems and weapons even during this opening part of your journey, so you’ll be able to snag it in no time. I believe in you.</p><p>With The Long Touch now in your possession, head on back into the great big world of <em>Avowed</em> and start sniping bonces. And don’t forget to use those Power Shots for faster speed and fine aiming for more crit chance!</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Explodes On Steam Despite Terrible User Reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-steam-framerate-1851766992</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-explodes-on-steam-despite-terrible-user-reviews.1121883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-steam-framerate-1851766992<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113"><em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>is out</a></span> and off to a roaring start on Steam, already shattering previous records to become the series’ most-played PC launch to date. And that’s all despite one of the lowest Steam review scores of any recent blockbuster, due to optimization, performance issues, and other complaints. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195805" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: September 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="338" data-playlist="195805,196013,196358" data-current="195805"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: September 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195805/195805_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21320.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Officially the first massive release of 2025, <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> garnered over 700,000 concurrent players on Steam alone last night, peaking at 1.3 million and continuing to grow. It could seemingly double that by the time the weekend hits, putting it number one over the ubiquitous <em>Counter-Strike 2</em> and potentially even beating out both<em> Black Myth: Wukong </em>and <em>Palworld</em> for the all-time number 2 spot on the Valve-owned storefront. This is walloping the performance of previous games in the series: <em>Monster Hunter World </em>peaked at around 330,000 concurrent players, and <em>Monster Hunter Rise</em>’s all-time peak was 230,000.</p><figure id="" data-id="9ec3965b4c646bfd6c53957afe54e738" data-recommend-id="image://9ec3965b4c646bfd6c53957afe54e738" data-format="png" data-width="1217" data-height="755" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows concurrent players on Steam. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows concurrent players on Steam. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Steam / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9ec3965b4c646bfd6c53957afe54e738" data-recommend-id="image://9ec3965b4c646bfd6c53957afe54e738" data-format="png" data-width="1217" data-height="755" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows concurrent players on Steam. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>It’s certainly shaping up to be a breakout moment for Capcom’s dense and fiddley action-RPG then, which is even more surprising given how dismal its initial Steam reviews have been. It currently has a rating of just 47 percent, with the majority of reviews giving<em> Monster Hunter Wilds</em> a thumbs down over PC problems. We’ve seen negative backlash on the platform over rough PC launches before, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2023-star-wars-jedi-survivor-on-pc-is-still-the-worst-triple-a-pc-port-of-2023&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2023-star-wars-jedi-survivor-on-pc-is-still-the-worst-triple-a-pc-port-of-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">most notably 2023's <em>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</em></a></span> which struggled throughout the year despite several big patches. But rarely do those same games then go on to break franchise and Steam records.</p><p>It might be because many of the reviews read like this: “This game is absolutely amazing - but has the worst optimization I’ve ever seen.” A common thread is that players who had no real problems with the game’s pre-launch open betas are now struggling to get decent framerates at higher resolutions. “If I can run <em>KCD2</em> and <em>Cyberpunk</em> on maxed out settings comfortably, then there is no reason this game should be running like this,” another review reads. Others were more glib. “I paid 70 dollars to boot a crash report,” wrote one person. “My grandma runs better than this game,” wrote another.</p><figure id="" data-id="c1d54fce6eba02cd177c172138414193" data-recommend-id="image://c1d54fce6eba02cd177c172138414193" data-format="png" data-width="914" data-height="867" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows negative Steam reviews. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows negative Steam reviews. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Steam / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c1d54fce6eba02cd177c172138414193" data-recommend-id="image://c1d54fce6eba02cd177c172138414193" data-format="png" data-width="914" data-height="867" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot shows negative Steam reviews. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>It sounds like the experience can be quite rough for many players, from lots of pop-in to frequent framerate stuttering when moving the camera around the big world (although there are certainly some on older graphics cards saying they’re getting along just fine). As with everything on PC, it’s hard to know how much of this needs to be sorted out on Capcom’s end vs. players fiddling with their own drivers and settings to get better results out of their hardware.<em> Digital Foundry</em>’s assessment didn’t mince words though with a video titled “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0yhacyXcizA&amp;t=176s&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0yhacyXcizA&amp;t=176s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profound perf problems must be addressed</a></span>.” Capcom has so far responded with the usual troubleshooting guide. </p><p>That said, <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> certainly doesn’t look perfect on PlayStation 5 either. A <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4HloDRmvJs&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4HloDRmvJs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry analysis</a></span> there showed how the game can look very muddy at higher framerates. I spent most of my time with the game during my review playing at a less fluid, more cinematic 30fps for exactly that reason. On the whole though, I’ve experienced no bugs or crashes in my 40 hours with the game on console so far. </p><p>We’ll see how much of this can be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-difficulty-social-hub-free-update-1851766839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-difficulty-social-hub-free-update-1851766839">addressed in post-launch updates</a></span> and how much of it is baked into the game at a more fundamental level. <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> is Capcom’s first entry in the franchise on the RE engine it uses for <em>Resident Evil</em> (and most other games at this point). It could also be a reflection of just how dense bespoke monster animations and interactions are in the game. It’s nowhere near as immediately dazzling as, say, <em>Horizon Forbidden West</em>, but there’s a liveliness and vibrancy on display few other games have shown us. Either way, it seems like <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> could be this year’s <em>Helldivers 2</em> when it comes to being an online multiplayer phenomenon. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>