<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:12:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Losers Keep Throwing Sex Toys At WNBA Players During Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wnba-dildo-sex-toy-tossed-on-court-explained-arrest-bag-ban-2000616321</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/losers-keep-throwing-sex-toys-at-wnba-players-during-games.1264914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>On Tuesday, an Indiana Fever and Los Angeles Sparks WNBA game was <a href="https://www.espn.com/wnba/story/_/id/45911373/sex-toy-tossed-sparks-court-third-incident-7-days">temporarily disrupted after someone tossed a large green dildo</a> at the players on the court. This is the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=1760105008213278">third such incident</a> of a sex toy being tossed onto a WNBA court during an active game in the last two weeks. And with some betting markets now taking bets on whether or not a dildo will be tossed at WNBA players at future games, it’s very likely this terrible trend will continue, even as the WNBA reportedly looks to ban fans from bringing bags into venues in an effort to prevent this from happening.</p> <p>The first incident of a dildo being thrown onto a <a href="https://kotaku.com/nba-2k-announces-wnba-players-a-river-of-sexism-follow-1837111136">WNBA</a> court happened on July 29 during a match between the Golden State Valkyries and the Atlanta Dream. Like what happened on Tuesday, a neon green dildo was reportedly thrown onto the court. On August 1, a similar incident involving a sex toy happened during a match between the Valkyries and the Chicago Sky. There are also at least two reports via social media of people attempting to toss dildos onto the court at other WNBA games, but these didn’t make it out of the crowd.&nbsp; However, one of these sex toys, also neon green, reportedly thrown during an <a href="https://x.com/osnapitsari/status/1952914027618943453">August 5 WNBA game in New York City</a>, came close to hitting a child. It’s clear this is becoming a “thing” and players and coaches are understandably frustrated and upset about the situation.</p> <p>“I think it’s ridiculous, it’s dumb, it’s stupid,” Sparks coach Lynne Roberts said after the game on Tuesday. “It’s also dangerous, and players’ safety is number one. Respecting the game. All those things. I think it’s really stupid.”</p> <p>On August 1, <a href="https://x.com/OMG_itsizzyb/status/1951462340890861689">New York Liberty&nbsp;forward&nbsp;Isabelle Harrison posted on social media</a>: “ARENA SECURITY?! Hello??! Please do better. It’s not funny. never was funny. Throwing ANYTHING on the court is so dangerous.”</p> <p><a href="https://www.talkbasket.net/201156-wnba-enforces-no-bag-policy-to-stop-dildo-throwers">Polymarket Sports is reporting</a> that the WNBA is enacting a ban on bags at some upcoming games. However, I was <a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/article/no-bag-policy-wnba-games-234957914.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAIkDZKqrCCX828IDt1RKFGShi0R616NjV0DwR8coONtETZz7gAejcUjpqB0mtSlMwCAmHfs7CXFv-TFrRNg-FV226KCC0yhNs9GP1TqjuqoyMicJ-eEuRHINLQHy0fdcLAMbrXBKCut1eoQ3s4WfGaZqDJw2rFQdZM_pprHaYDp1">unable to corroborate this claim</a>, and Polymarket itself might have a vested interest in the dildo tossing as the gambling site is <a href="https://polymarket.com/event/dildo-thrown-at-wnba-game-on-august-6-13/will-a-dildo-be-thrown-onto-the-court-at-a-wnba-game-on-wednesday?tid=1754503557149">now taking bets on whether sex toys will be tossed at WNBA games</a>. Yes, we are living in a timeline where people are betting on whether someone will toss a sex toy at professional female athletes just trying to play basketball. Shit sucks.</p> <p>On August 2, police in College Park, Georgia, arrested 23-year-old Delbert Carver, the man who allegedly tossed the first dildo during the Valkyries/Dream game.&nbsp; According to law enforcement, he <a href="https://www.espn.com/wnba/story/_/id/45901403/wnba-fan-accused-throwing-sex-toy-faces-multiple-charges" target="_blank" rel="noopener">faces counts of disorderly conduct, public indecency, and criminal trespass</a>. In an affidavit, as reported by ESPN, Carver admitted that tossing the dildo onto the court was “supposed to be a joke” and that it was “supposed to go viral.” Sadly, it seems like it has, and copycats are now tossing more green dildos onto WNBA courts.</p> <p>Not only is this dangerous and annoying for players, but throwing sex toys onto the court of a WNBA game is <a href="https://www.cosmopolitan.com/entertainment/celebs/a65614990/why-throwing-dildos-wnba-games/">clearly a misogynistic act against these women</a> who dare to be professional athletes. In an era when professional women’s sports are thriving, <a href="https://www.nielsen.com/insights/2023/womens-sports-viewership-on-the-rise/">with high ratings and stars being created</a>, it’s clear some young men, likely fueled by anti-women politics and the horrible online manosphere, feel empowered and even forced to “fight back.” Tossing dildos at women is done to embarrass them and remind them that, according to these shitbags, they are only sex objects who shouldn’t be playing basketball in front of adoring crowds of fans. Hopefully, WNBA security steps things up and we can stop this shit from happening in future games.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wnba-dildo-sex-toy-tossed-on-court-explained-arrest-bag-ban-2000616321]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked Elden Ring Nightreign Mode Made Me The Most Excited I’ve Been Since Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-endless-mode-datamine-depths-relics-2000616334</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leaked-elden-ring-nightreign-mode-made-me-the-most-excited-i%E2%80%99ve-been-since-launch.1264803/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p>I’m desperate for <a href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-duos-mode-option-patch-1-02-ps5-1851786981"><em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em></a> to enter its next phase, and dataminers may have finally revealed what that is, thanks to references hidden in the multiplayer roguelite’s latest update. It sounds like an endless mode could be on the way, complete with ranked matchmaking. I wouldn’t care about any of that in most games, but <em>Nightreign</em> isn’t most games, and this new mode could be exactly what it needs to get me hooked again.</p> <p>Players have spent the summer circulating through a new rotation of tougher Everdark Sovereign variants of the game’s existing Nightlord boss fights. They’ve mostly been pretty fun, even last week’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-augur-evergaol-everdark-time-1851787245">divisive overhaul of Maris Fathom of Night, AKA Augur,</a> which forced players to use a magic sword that drops during the fight. Otherwise, most players have burned through the main campaign and each character’s remembrance side quests. We know the randomized Limveld map like the palm of our hands. Most runs have become a walk in the park. We need something different. We need something harder.</p> <p>That could be precisely what a new endless mode is bringing. References to it were discovered in <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Adminisitrator/comments/1mh908l/elden_ring_nightreign_new_mode_deep_of_night/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=post_body&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-nightreign-dataminers-have-uncovered-plans-for-a-new-endless-mode-with-armored-core-6s-rank-system-and-skill-based-matchmaking/">a recent datamine</a> posted on Reddit (via <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-nightreign-dataminers-have-uncovered-plans-for-a-new-endless-mode-with-armored-core-6s-rank-system-and-skill-based-matchmaking/"><em>PC Gamer</em></a>). The images reveal a new matchmaking option called The Deep of Night with the following description: “The Deep of Night is a battlefield of endless Night. Victory will increase your rating, burnishing your Depth. The Darkness extends unto infinity.” Screenshots shared in the post suggest five levels each with ranked ratings of 0 to 9,999. Bosses in the Deep of Night look slightly different, and the weapons you earn down there each come with unique de-buffs to make things harder. Players will also seemingly unlock additional slots on vessels where new “Depth” relics can be equipped.</p>

 <p>It’s unclear how much the map itself will change in this mode, but it sounds like players will keep going until they die rather than ending after night three with a final boss fight. At the very least, the increasing difficulty, new gear, and extra relic slots are enough to establish a completely new endgame, while the ranking system gives the sweatiest Nightfarers among us a new goal to reach for.</p> <p>It’s not clear when FromSoftware is planning to add this mode, but sometime in September seems like a good bet, as players wrap up the last run of Everdark Sovereigns this month. I’m excited for a Bell Bearing Hunter at the bottom of the castle on night one to become the least of players’ worries if this new endless mode ends up delivering on the level of difficulty teased in these datamining leaks.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-endless-mode-datamine-depths-relics-2000616334]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>