<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:17:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fantastic Four: First Steps: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-review-movie-marvel-mcu-1851786852</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-the-kotaku-review.1252035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>The Fantastic Four: First Steps</em> is obsessed with time. From the opening moments, which drops the audience <em>in media res</em>, brilliant scientist Reed Richards (Pedro Pascal) is scouring the cabinets of his 1960s-retro-future-inspired bathroom for iodine. The man known as Mister Fantastic calls out to his wife, Sue Storm (Vanessa Kirby), to ask where it is. The Invisible Woman quickly responds that she needs twelve seconds. Reed retorts that’s incredibly specific, and it’s the first of many mentions of definitive lengths of time throughout the movie.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197589" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="659" data-playlist="197589,197586,197585" data-current="197589"><div><p>Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>It turns out, after two years of trying to have children, one-half of the Fantastic Four is expecting a child. This means Reed’s best friend Ben Grimm, aka The Thing (Ebon Moss-Bachrach), and Sue’s brother Johnny, or the Human Torch (Joseph Quinn), are going to be uncles. It’s an exciting, well, <em>time</em> for the family.</p><p><em>First Steps</em> takes place at a critical inflection point for Sue and Reed, sure, but also for the Marvel Cinematic Universe as it goes through <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-dr-doom-doomsday-avengers-1851786672&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-dr-doom-doomsday-avengers-1851786672">a creative readjustment</a></span>. Post <em>Avengers: Endgame</em>, Marvel films have arrived with a considerable amount of hand-wringing, but the burden of proof feels even heavier for the <em>Fantastic Four</em>, laden with rescuing the MCU from its multiverse doldrums. Doubly so, when the disguised competition <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/superman-post-credits-james-gunn-dcu-marvel-supergirl-1851786204&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/superman-post-credits-james-gunn-dcu-marvel-supergirl-1851786204">just hit a grand slam with the launch of their new cinematic universe</a></span>.</p><p>You’d be hard-pressed to know all this watching a movie that’s this light on its feet. The fourth reboot of Marvel’s first family (but the first from Marvel Studios) is helmed by <em>WandaVision</em> director Matt Shakman, with a script from a quartet of writers: Josh Friedman, Eric Pearson, Jeff Kaplan, and Ian Springer. The result is an entertaining return to form for the MCU, bolstered by stellar visuals and even better performances.</p><figure id="" data-id="3d380d915e3c80ad1a6f8754163d4636" data-recommend-id="image://3d380d915e3c80ad1a6f8754163d4636" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Johnny and Sue chat at the table." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Johnny and Sue chat at the table." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3d380d915e3c80ad1a6f8754163d4636" data-recommend-id="image://3d380d915e3c80ad1a6f8754163d4636" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Johnny and Sue chat at the table." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After the reveal that Sue and Reed are pregnant, <em>First Steps</em> kicks into a savvy and breezy bit of exposition, detailing the origins of the team through an Ed Sullivan-esque magazine program. Here we see the team’s past as astronauts, and how they were affected by cosmic radiation that gave them superpowers; a speedy prologue before throwing the four into the movie’s central conflict. Alien harbinger The Silver Surfer (Julia Garner) appears in Times Square to declare the planet marked for destruction by the world-eater Galactus (Ralph Ineson). In an attempt to save their world, the Fantastic Four rocket deep into space to persuade Galactus otherwise, only to learn the celestial creature wants Sue and Reed’s unborn child. Should they refuse, he’ll devour the Earth. Time’s tick, tick, ticking away.</p><p>So begins the central tension of <em>First Steps</em>. The denizens of Earth-828 (fittingly named in honor of <em>Fantastic Four</em> creator Jack Kirby’s birthdate of August 28, and distinct from Earth-616 where most MCU movies are set) aren’t particularly keen on the notion that they’ll die if Galactus isn’t appeased. What was once nervous excitement on behalf of the soon-to-be parents becomes outright fear at the possibility of having to give up something once thought impossible. Thus, the movie becomes a race against time to find a solution that spares Earth but without having to lose their child.</p><p>This worst possible situation brings out the best in <em>First Steps</em>, allowing each of its leads the depth and breadth they need. As the second act unfolds, the thrill is in seeing how each of the main characters reacts to the crisis. For Sue, that’s to find strength in the familial love she’s cultivated, while for Reed it’s about trying to solve everything, even if that means considering the worst possible options. Pascal and Kirby navigate these difficult situations with a welcome sense of maturity—especially by MCU standards—and shine all the brighter because of it. Sue and Reed are a perfect pair—even in the thorniest of arguments, there’s never any doubt about the strength of their relationship. Their big, emotional moments play exceedingly well.</p><p>Johnny and Ben take on more secondary roles, but not in a way that shortchanges their development. Moss-Bachrach’s version of The Thing has melancholy moments of self-reflection, but not at the expense of being the sturdy foundation of this family. He might come across as the brawn, but Ben’s all heart. Johnny, on the other hand, is eager to prove he’s more than a flirty ladies man, and seeing his passions come ablaze is a delight—he shows he’s just as capable as the rest of his superlative super family.</p><figure id="" data-id="aaba06a124aa157df0bcf1e98831c924" data-recommend-id="image://aaba06a124aa157df0bcf1e98831c924" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="784" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Thing raises a car above his head." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Thing raises a car above his head." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="aaba06a124aa157df0bcf1e98831c924" data-recommend-id="image://aaba06a124aa157df0bcf1e98831c924" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="784" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Thing raises a car above his head." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>First Steps</em>’ <em>Jetsons</em>-like, ‘60s retro-future aesthetics make this feel unlike any other Marvel film. Full of color—a blue hue saturates the world—it’s a far cry from the washed-out sheen of most MCU projects. Director Shakman’s framing also results in some awe-inspiring moments: when the family first gazes upward at Galactus, it’s worthy of inclusion alongside Marvel’s most memorable moments. This is a movie full of cosmic scale and spectacle, very much befitting the world Jack Kirby and Stan Lee rendered across dozens of comics back in 1961 when they introduced the team. That grandness is also helped by Michael Giacchino’s score, one of Marvel’s very best.</p><p>Perhaps <em>First Steps</em> stumbles a little in the third act, with the predictability of the plot, the rushed nature of its conclusion, and underutilization of its villains. Galactus is fine—he doesn’t need much more motivation outside of needing to devour. But the Silver Surfer Julia Garner portrays is thinly-drawn, especially when contrasted alongside the Fantastic Four. The sub-two-hour runtime means that once things everything’s in motion, the film moves through big events in quick fashion, brushing past moments that could have used a few more minutes to breathe. Ironically, the film doesn’t have enough time.</p><p>Whether it’s the seconds Reed needs to try to save the world, or the years that could quickly fly by as their newborn child grows up, there’s never going to be enough time to go around. Yet, for the first time in a while, I’ve walked out of a Marvel movie thrilled and entertained by what’s transpired on the screen in front of me.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-review-movie-marvel-mcu-1851786852]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 12 Best Games On The Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-best-games-mario-kart-donkey-kong-1851786840</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-12-best-games-on-the-nintendo-switch-2.1251984/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="4c6b296cc8476a917e0a6dd5636bfc62" data-recommend-id="image://4c6b296cc8476a917e0a6dd5636bfc62" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Best of Nintendo Switch 2" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Best of Nintendo Switch 2" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4c6b296cc8476a917e0a6dd5636bfc62" data-recommend-id="image://4c6b296cc8476a917e0a6dd5636bfc62" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Best of Nintendo Switch 2" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The Switch 2 is in that awkward early phase where most of its best games are old. Nintendo has put out a couple of big exclusives, sure, but by and large, the draw of the system largely lies in the ability to play games on the go that used to demand you be tethered to a TV. So if you’re thinking of buying the thing in these early post-launch months, you might be wondering what the must-have games it has to offer are. The pickings are slim, but we put together a list of the best games currently available on the Switch 2.</p></div><div><p>CD Projekt Red’s open-world RPG is one of the most impressive technical showcases for the Switch 2 thus far. <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> once broke PlayStation 4s and Xbox Ones across the globe, but it runs well on Nintendo’s system. Driving around Night City is still a dream, and the Switch 2’s optional mouse controls are pretty intuitive in the game’s shooting segments. There are certainly better ways to play <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, but seeing it running on a Switch 2 is a reminder that while the system might seem like a pretty lowkey upgrade from the original, playing console-quality games on the go is still a novel experience eight years later. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>Story-driven RPG fans<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>People with a weak stomach for some tough subject matter</p></div><div><p>A divine maiden must be escorted across a corrupted mountain so she can purge its towns, caves, and forests of gruesome demonic spirits. There are lots of ways a game could ask you to do this, but <em>Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</em> settles on a unique hybrid of tower defense and excellent third-person arcade action. Japanese folklore permeates the meticulous, hand-crafted art direction, and Capcom’s in-house expertise when it comes to tight combat and beautiful animations is on full display. The Switch 2 version doesn’t look quite as polished and pristine as <em>Kunitsu-Gami</em> does on other platforms, but it’s still one of the most underrated real-time strategy adventures around, made better by the recent addition of new game plus and endless roguelike modes. —Ethan</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>People who love collecting orbs</p><p><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>Anyone afraid of big, long demon tongues </p></div><div><p><em>World of Assassination</em> is a treasure trove of stealth challenges, each one ending in a satisfying execution of a person you won’t feel too bad about removing from a shadowy world of conspiracy and dark secrets. With three full campaigns, side missions, countless arcade challenges, regular updates featuring celebrity targets such as the recently added Le Chiffre from <em>Casino Royale</em> (played by Mads Mikkelsen), and the endless roguelike Freelancer mode, <em>Hitman</em> <em>WoA</em> is a perfect forever game for those of us who like to sneak around places we’re not supposed to be. True, performance on the Switch 2 isn’t as great as it can be on more powerful hardware, and you do need to be online to access Freelancer mode and many other challenges. But <em>Hitman</em> presents such a rich buffet of unique and memorable stealth sequences, each full of opportunities to come up with an endless variety of clever solutions, that you could easily spend an entire console generation playing it before you feel like you’ve mastered everything the game can throw at you. — Claire Jackson</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>People who love sneaking around</p><p><strong>Not a good match for:</strong> People who <em>don’t</em></p></div><div><p>It’s no surprise that the two best games on the original Switch are vastly improved in their Switch 2 incarnations. <em>Breath of the Wild </em>and <em>Tears of the Kingdom </em>run at a smooth 60fps on the Switch 2, and if seeing these games running on a device that doesn’t feel like it’s struggling to keep them afloat isn’t enough, the Switch 2 editions come with new content thanks to the Zelda Notes app that adds new challenges and lore to two already dense games. If you played them before, they’re worth revisiting. If you never touched Link’s open-world adventures, they’re even more essential on the Switch 2. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>People who want peak<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>People who get overwhelmed with dense systems</p></div><div><p>Nintendo’s biggest launch title for the Switch 2 is still arguably the best game the system has to offer. <em>Mario Kart World </em>is a sublime addition to the kart racer series’ long line of quality party game staples. Though it’s not without its frustrations, <em>World </em>is the chaotic, rollicking fun of throwing a blue shell down a track or barreling through your enemies as a Bullet Bill at its best. The open world is kind of empty, but it’s a fun playground to practice all the cool stunts you can do now, like riding on the wall and grinding on rails. <em>Mario Kart World </em>is all about giving you the freedom to race how you want, and that means giving you more tools, more players on the track at once, and more bothersome items to chuck at your foes. This is only the beginning, and Nintendo will likely be updating the game for years to come. <em>Mario Kart World </em>will undoubtedly be a staple of the Switch 2’s lifetime. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>Everyone, really<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>Anyone looking for something chill</p></div><div><p>Y’all, it’s a damn galaxy in your pocket. Do I even need to say anything else? Over the years, <em>No Man’s Sky</em> has continued to improve, expanding the potential of what you can do in its virtually endless playground of procedurally generated planets and ecosystems. Being able to jump into your ship and fly directly to a planet you can see off in the distance hasn’t gotten old since 2016. Though there are many quests and neat challenges you can take on, you don’t have to; <em>NMS</em> is the game you want to make out of it. Want a hardcore survival experience across the vastness of a simulated galaxy? It’s here. Want to set up an oxygen farm on a remote moon somewhere? Time to get digging. Want to catalog all of the lifeforms on a planet that’ll take you hours upon hours to walk across? Lace up your boots. Hello Games’ massive space sim works really well in portable format, whether you’re playing online or off. Dogfights in space. Finding planets no one’s seen before. Seeing a gorgeous vista where you can seamlessly travel to virtually anything you can see. When you’ve an appetite for galactic expeditions, <em>No Man’s Sky</em> is here to deliver multiple courses. — Claire Jackson</p><p><strong>A good match for:</strong> Digital space explorers who aren’t afraid to find their own fun</p><p><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>Folks who find survival mechanics overbearing or want a more traditional, guided gaming experience</p></div><div><p>Hazelight’s co-op platformer <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/split-fiction-review-hazelight-coop-game-it-takes-two-1851767470&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/split-fiction-review-hazelight-coop-game-it-takes-two-1851767470"><em>Split Fiction</em></a></span> doesn’t feel built for the Switch 2. Its split-screen format makes it a pain to play in tabletop mode, so it’s really best played on a TV like you would on your PS5 or Xbox. But once you’ve got it running on a big screen, the game is still a hoot. Though its cheesy writing leaves much to be desired, as a cooperative platformer with a ton of mechanical and environmental variety, it’s easily the best in Hazelight’s long history of co-op games. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/split-fiction-final-level-mio-zoe-rader-ending-1851768868&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/split-fiction-final-level-mio-zoe-rader-ending-1851768868">That final level still whips ass, too</a></span>. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>Someone with a friend to play with<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>Someone who doesn’t have a friend to play with</p></div><div><p>Fighting games were always going to be one of the biggest tests of the Switch 2's technical capabilities, and Capcom thankfully managed to bring one of the best genre entries in recent years to the system without much compromise in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-review-world-tour-story-mode-roster-1850481281&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-review-world-tour-story-mode-roster-1850481281"><em>Street Fighter 6</em></a></span>. Some of its Switch 2 features, like amiibo support and motion controls with the Joy-Cons, feel like cute nods to the system’s original features rather than something that fundamentally changes the game, so you’ll most likely go right back to standard play before long. Once you do, though, you’ll find a really great version of an already stellar game running at a smooth 60fps. Sure, it’s probably not going to be the version people are playing at EVO, but it’s more than good enough to break out at the function and play with friends. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>The fighting game sickos<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>People who don’t like to memorize combos</p></div><div><p>Donkey Kong and Pauline’s latest adventure is one of the Switch 2’s most impressive technical achievements. Its breakable environments are so malleable that they’re a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/donkey-kong-bananza-destructible-environments-ocd-1851786630&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/donkey-kong-bananza-destructible-environments-ocd-1851786630">bit of a distraction</a></span>, but its tight platforming, creative problem-solving, and booming personality make it one of the most joyful games on the Switch 2 right now. Is it the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-launch-lineup-single-player-mario-3d-mkw-1851784352&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-launch-lineup-single-player-mario-3d-mkw-1851784352">cultural moment the system needs to bring people in out of the gate</a></span>? Maybe not. But it’s still an absolute delight worth booting up if you’ve got the system in its first few months. — Kenneth Shepard</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>People who wanted <em>King Kong </em>to have a happier ending<br><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>People who can’t move on without finding every collectable in a level</p></div><div><p>Shin’en Multimedia is back, filling another <em>F-Zero</em>-sized hole in another Nintendo console launch. <em>Fast Fusion </em>is a simple but slick racer in which you zip through crisp, hyper-realistic sci-fi courses snagging speed boosts and avoiding crashes. There’s a jump button because it’s fun to jump when it feels like you’re about to break the sound barrier, and a new mechanic that lets you combine two vehicles together to take advantage of their combined stats. It’s better than it has any right to be and a fun, flashy exclusive to show off Nintendo’s new console. — Ethan</p><p><strong>A good match for:</strong> Unreal Engine sickos who love <em>WipeOut</em></p><p><strong>Not a good match for: </strong>Those who get easily carsick</p></div><div><p>The life sim RPGs that helped define the modern Nintendo handheld landscape are alive and well on Switch 2, and <em>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time</em> is the best of them when it comes to rewarding grinding loops that give you a fair bit of freedom. It’s a city builder, survival crafting sim, and simple action-RPG all rolled up into one, with a pleasant art style and music by longtime<em> Final Fantasy </em>composer Nobuo Uematsu. There are so, so many parts, and the sum of each of them offers a progression loop that’s rewarding and compelling enough to make up for its flaws. —Ethan</p><p><strong>A good match for: </strong>Those who wish <em>Final Fantasy V</em> was more like<em> Animal Crossing</em></p><p><strong>Not a good match for:</strong> People who hate experiencing life through menus </p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-best-games-mario-kart-donkey-kong-1851786840]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>