<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:42:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This 25,000mAh 100W Laptop Power Bank Is Selling for Peanuts, Amazon Is Rushing to Clear Its Inventory]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-25000mah-100w-laptop-power-bank-is-selling-for-peanuts-amazon-is-rushing-to-clear-its-inventory-2000632554</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-25-000mah-100w-laptop-power-bank-is-selling-for-peanuts-amazon-is-rushing-to-clear-its-inventory.1318726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Small power banks that charge your phone are handy, but did you know power banks exist for laptops too? They’re less common but incredibly practical, especially since they can charge your phone and other devices at the same time. Running out of battery during a flight or during a long day away from outlets becomes a non-issue when you have serious charging capacity in your bag. For Prime Big Deal Day, Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3789/">has dropped the price on the most popular Anker (25,000mAh, 100W) laptop power bank to $89, down from $134</a>. That’s a $45 discount and an all-time low for this Anker model, <strong>available exclusively to Prime members</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3789/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The Anker power bank <strong>boasts an enormous capacity of 25,000mAh</strong> which equates to usable real-world powering of your devices. For context, it’s enough to give a full charge to a MacBook Air, enough to supply your iPhone several full charges or keep your tablet going for hours of continuous use. With a 90Wh rating, it also falls within airline requirements for personal protective devices for your carry-ons, so it’s permissible to bring it onboard your flights.</p>
<h2>Triple 100W USB-C Ports Upgrade Your Charging Experience</h2>
<p>The <strong>crown jewel here is the three USB-C ports</strong>, each of which is capable of dispensing a <strong>whopping 100W of power</strong>. That’s important because newer laptops require serious power to charge at a full speed. A MacBook Pro 16-inch, say, requires about 96W for best-in-class charging. With 100W per port, you’ll be able to charge your laptop at full speed, <strong>all while powering other devices simultaneously.</strong></p>



<p>The built-in cables rectify one of the greatest nuisances of power banks: forgetting or misplacing charging cables. <strong>Anker ships two USB-C cables embedded on the power bank itself</strong>. One of them reaches a distance of up to 2.3 feet and gives you a degree of mobility when outlets are centralized or when you want to access your device as it charges. This retractable cable is rated for more than 20,000 times of retraction so it should not readily fail due to wear and tear. The other cable is 0.98 feet long and also serves as a strap for carrying, designed to withstand over 20,000 bends. Such a dual purpose creates durability and portability.</p>
<p>Along with the built-in cabling, there are also other sources of charging <strong>available in the form of a USB-A port and a second USB-C port</strong>, for a<strong> total of four devices being charged simultaneously</strong>. This setup is best for traveling families or professionals who carry multiple devices along. You may charge your laptop off one built-in cabling, your cell phone off the other, your wireless headsets off the USB-A port and a smartwatch off the additional USB-C port.</p>



<p>Recharging of the power bank itself is incredibly quick due to a 100W ultra-fast recharging feature. It achieves a capacity of being at a 30% state by being plugged into a charger of 100W within a total of 22 minutes. <strong>Recharging takes a total of about 90 minutes</strong>&nbsp;so keep it topped off during your morning getting-ready process or lunchtime.</p>
<p>As a Prime member for $89 during this Prime Big Deal Day sale, you’re getting laptop-level powering capability at a budget-friendly cost.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3789/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-25000mah-100w-laptop-power-bank-is-selling-for-peanuts-amazon-is-rushing-to-clear-its-inventory-2000632554]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Saudi Arabia Assassin’s Creed Mirage Expansion Makes A Big Change]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-mirage-dlc-jump-button-battlefield-6-disc-2000632532</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-saudi-arabia-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-mirage-expansion-makes-a-big-change.1318723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Will the jump button come back in the next <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>? Will<em> Battlefield 6</em> really work right out of the box? Can <em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em> prevent the further atomization of modern society? It’s the latest edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture. I am still thinking about Xbox and how much Microsoft keeps fumbling the bag. And I’m <a href="https://x.com/JamiesAct/status/1975227593763999973">apparently not</a> <a href="https://x.com/JamiesAct/status/1975244040896716915">the only</a> <a href="https://x.com/DestinLegarie/status/1975556977536475617">one</a>. But for real: what’s going on <a href="https://x.com/Omnipotentgam0r/status/1974904157829321171">with those Walmart displays</a>?</p> <h2>The Saudi Arabia <em>Assassin’s Creed Mirage</em> DLC will let you manually jump</h2>  <p><a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/ubisoft-assassins-creed-mirage-saudi-arabia">Reportedly funded by</a> Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman Al Saud, the <em>Valley of Memory</em> DLC is a free major update for the 2023 game that takes Basim to the AlUla region in search of his long-lost father. It includes a new skill, tool customization, difficulty levels, and replaybale missions and challenges. The most important change to me, however, is the addition of a manual jump to add more depth to the parkour. The stealth action series hasn’t had a dedicated jump button since <em>Unity</em> as movement became more streamlined and automated. Hopefully, the experiment pays dividends in <em>Valley of Memory</em> and paves the way for more complex parkour in the next big <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> sequel.</p>

 <h2><em>Silent Hill 2</em> remake is reportedly coming to PS Plus this month</h2> <p>That’s according <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/ce-remake-sorti-en-excluvisite-console-sur-ps5-va-debarquer-sur-le-ps-plus-extra-60622">to billbil-kun at Dealabs</a>, who says last year’s PS5 exclusive will be arriving as part of the Extra and Premium tiers later this month. It arrives alongside <em>Alan Wake 2</em> on PS Plus Essential and <em>The </em><em>Last of Us Part 2</em> on Extra and Premium. Not a bad haul for this year’s Halloween.</p>

 <h2>Physical copies of <em>Battlefield 6</em> are out early and include at least part of the game on the actual disc</h2>   <p>Bucking recent trends, <em>Battlefield 6</em> apparently comes with the actual game on the disc, at least on PS5. A fan on Reddit claims the servers are live and the campaign and multiplayer both work. You can preview the game’s full day-one update and all of the over 200 changes it makes <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1975214752314937744">here</a>.</p>

 <h2>Funcom layoffs hit <em>Metal Hellsinger</em> studio</h2> <p>The Outsiders, a Funcom studio based in Stockholm, Sweden, is shutting down, founder and creative director David Goldfarb <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/locust9.bsky.social/post/3m2jumlqlmc2m">announced yesterday</a>. The team had previously produced the rhythm-based demonic FPS <em>Hellsinger</em> which sold one million copies. ” It will always be a high point for me personally and I will be forever grateful we got to make it and for the wonderful team and partnerships that made it happen,” he wrote. The veteran developer said the plan is to “continue on in some new form.”</p> <h2><em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em> is out October 23</h2>  <p>The sequel to the hit <a href="https://kotaku.com/powerwash-sim-2-trailer-release-campaign-splitscreen-1851769691">OCD management game</a> arrives with some upgraded visuals, split-screen co-op, and an increased focus on story beats which the original game kept mostly in the background. Who’s ready to spray and pray and search frantically for that remaining one percent of dirt you just can’t find?</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-concert-cancelled-dates-delay-us-tour-2000632085">Sony bails on an expensive PlayStation concert series that fans aren’t showing up for&nbsp;</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-next-gen-console-leak-rumor-costco-sams-club-2000632026">Microsoft isn’t getting out of the console business, yet</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-magic-the-gathering-scalpers-cards-2000632017"><em>Pokémon</em> and <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> risk ruining TCGs for a whole generation of new players</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-mirage-dlc-jump-button-battlefield-6-disc-2000632532]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie’s Marathon Resurfaces To Test One Of Players’ Most-Requested Gameplay Features]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-playtest-plagiarism-ttk-prox-chat-2000632553</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie%E2%80%99s-marathon-resurfaces-to-test-one-of-players%E2%80%99-most-requested-gameplay-features.1318717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i>Marathon</i>, Bungie’s upcoming hero extraction shooter, is getting another invite-only test soon. The test will run from October 22 to 27, and <a href="http://www.bungie.net/7/cen/News/Article/techtestapply">folks can sign up right here</a>. Things haven’t gone great for <i>Marathon</i> thus far, but following the <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-alpha-review-impressions-bungie-extraction-fps-1851777775">disappointing reception</a> of the first alpha test, and the <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-art-alpha-gameplay-posters-antireal-1851780911">embarrassing accusations of plagiarism</a>, it’ll be interesting to see what tweaks Bungie has made and just what the game is shaping up to be.</p> <p>Revealed back in 2023 with a very impressive cinematic trailer, <i>Marathon</i> is a reboot of <a href="https://kotaku.com/bungie-marathon-halo-destiny-extraction-shooter-1850480259">Bungie’s classic <i>Doom</i>-like shooter</a> from the ‘90s. It’s also Bungie’s first new shooter since it made the pivot to <i>Destiny</i> in the early 2010s, following its departure from Microsoft and the <i>Halo</i> series.</p>

 <h2>There’s still no release date for <i>Marathon</i>, and the game has a lot to prove to fans</h2> <p><i>Marathon</i> was originally slated to release for current-gen consoles and PC on September 23, 2025. That date has come and gone. Unfortunately for Bungie, folks didn’t find the game terribly fun during the alpha earlier this year, and so the studio made the decision to indefinitely delay its release. The drab environments didn’t really speak to Bungie’s artistic strengths, and the hero shooter element (which I, a huge extraction shooter fan, <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-runner-extraction-hardcore-1851775956">tried to be open-minded</a> about) still seems like an odd fit.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/sony-ps5-destiny-2-bungie-playstation-microsoft-xbox-ex-1848453326">Sony Buys Bungie, Makers Of Destiny 2 For $3.6B</a></p> <p>While <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-pvpve-extraction-division-dmz-2000631540">extraction shooters</a>, especially of the PvPvE variety, have yet to really appeal to all but a dedicated niche audience, <i>Marathon</i> just felt rather boring. Matches mostly consisted of fights with the same repetitive robots instead of incorporating the more alluring palette of creature designs the <i>Marathon</i> franchise has.</p>

 <p>We do know that the upcoming closed test will let players try out a new feature: Proximity chat, which allows you to hear other players’ voice chatter only when you’re near them. Bungie initially wanted to avoid using this, as the studio felt it was ripe for toxicity and abuse. While proximity chat can result in, well, <a href="https://kotaku.com/warzone-2-features-proximity-chat-gulag-contracts-mw2-1849793098">rather silly situations in a shooter</a>, it’s a pretty important feature in a PvPvE game; overhearing nearby players not only adds a bit of voyeuristic drama, but it can also help you avoid getting jumped sometimes.</p>

 <p>The closed test will also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-marathon-details-leak-from-latest-closed-test/">feature some tweaks to TTK (time-to-kill) as well</a>. We’ll see if this is enough to start rehabilitating <i>Marathon</i>’s image for folks.</p> <h2>It’s been a real cluster-f over at Bungie from the sounds of things</h2> <p>Conversations about the nuances of what does and doesn’t work in <i>Marathon</i> were all pushed to the side when it was revealed that Bungie had lifted designs from artist antire.al without permission or acknowledgement.</p>

 <p>Bungie had its explanations for how the artist’s work made it into its game, essentially saying that it was material used for inspiration and research that found its way into production pipelines, and thus made it into the game. The studio blamed this oversight on a former employee and promised a full review of all its assets to be sure this wouldn’t happen again.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-art-alpha-gameplay-posters-antireal-1851780911">Artist Shocked To Find Her Poster Designs From 2017 In Bungie’s <i>Marathon</i></a></p> <p>Still, in an age where everyone with a functioning ethical compass is on edge about plagiarism and the <a href="https://kotaku.com/robin-williams-zelda-ai-slop-human-centipede-sora-2000632483">unethical sharing</a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/sora-2-update-pokemon-nintendo-openai-sam-altman-ai-2000632089">use of people’s work via AI</a>, the timing couldn’t have been worse for a studio to reveal that it had aped someone else’s designs, however unintentionally.</p> <p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://kotaku.com/robin-williams-zelda-ai-slop-human-centipede-sora-2000632483">Bungie CEO Seemingly Spent Over $2.3 Million On Classic Cars After Sony Acquisition</a></p> <p>With the departure of CEO Pete Parsons this past August as well, and <i>Destiny 2 </i>seeing players <a href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-renegades-star-wars-power-reset-2000632488">leave the game in droves</a>, it’s been a time of upheaval for the legendary studio, and there’s a lot riding on getting <i>Marathon </i>into shape so it attracts and resonates with players. Here’s hoping the test later this month shows that it’s moving in the right direction.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marathon-bungie-playtest-plagiarism-ttk-prox-chat-2000632553]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Crucial P310 SSD Now Costs Only Cents per GB, A Steal for Steam Deck or ROG Ally Storage Upgrade]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-crucial-p310-ssd-costing-only-cents-per-gb-with-up-to-almost-50-off-for-prime-day-2000632109</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-crucial-p310-ssd-now-costs-only-cents-per-gb-a-steal-for-steam-deck-or-rog-ally-storage-upgrade.1318660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>We’re here in the thick of Prime Big Deals Day and there are some great opportunities to save on pretty much anything. Kitchen appliances, bedding, automotive tools, and, yes, even gaming hardware are on sale with huge discounts. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4568/">Right now, Amazon has the Crucial P310 internal SSD discounted by up to 49%</a>. The 1TB version — normally $135 — is now down to $80 while the 2TB version — normally $240 — is now down to just $122. That’s a savings of up to $188.</p>
<p>File sizes for AAA video games have been surpassing behemoth levels for some time now. Look at something like <em>Red Dead Redemption 2</em>. It requires a whopping 150GB of your storage to install. And that’s a game from 2018. I can’t even begin to imagine what absurd size requirement Rockstar’s upcoming&nbsp;<em>Grand Theft Auto VI</em> will have.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4568/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>This PCIe Gen4 2230 NVMe M.2 SSD is smaller than your standard internal SSDs and that’s because it is designed with PC gaming handhelds in mind to help you bring your whole game library with you when you hit the road.</p>
<p>The Steam Deck has three models, each with a different internal capacity. The LCD version of the Steam Deck only comes with 256GB while with the OLED, you have a choice of 512GB or 1TB. The ROG Ally and all new ROG Xbox Ally each come with 512GB. If those numbers aren’t enough for the gaming you want to do on the go, then you can upgrade with the Crucial P310 SSD.&nbsp;Installation is easy and should only take you about five minutes of your time to get you started gaming with way more storage.</p>
<p>While the Crucial P310 SSD is made with the Steam Deck and Asus ROG Ally in mind, it is additionally compatible with certain laptops such as the Microsoft Surface or select Dell models.</p>



<h2>Extreme Performance</h2>
<p>The Crucial gaming SSD is capable of read and write speeds of up to 7,100 MB/s. You can expect fast load times. Power efficiency is always good to have with PC hardware both for environmental reasons and to keep the electric bill down. Here, though, there is an added benefit. Game longer. Better power efficiency means easier on the battery means you can play for longer before it dies.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4568/">For a limited time, you can expand the storage on your PC gaming handheld to a large capacity of either 1TB or 2TB with the Crucial P310 internal SSD.</a> The 1TB is down 41% to $80 while the 2TB is down 49% to $122.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4568/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-clears-out-crucial-p310-ssd-costing-only-cents-per-gb-with-up-to-almost-50-off-for-prime-day-2000632109]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Thing The KPop Demon Hunters X Fortnite Collab Gave Us Wasn’t In The Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-fortnite-rei-ami-stream-zoey-rumi-2000632536</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-thing-the-kpop-demon-hunters-x-fortnite-collab-gave-us-wasn%E2%80%99t-in-the-game.1318657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>I finally broke the seal on </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>this past week because I am a mark for </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-fortnite-skins-rumi-mira-zoey-event-2000630221"><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i></a> <span>and its trio of monster-slaying idols. Epic fast-tracked skins, cosmetics, and a reskinned mode themed around Netflix’s animated musical, and I paid for my first V-Bucks to play as Rumi and fight hordes of demons with shotguns and SMGs. Friends, it gave me the ick. I loathe </span><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span>’s brand of artless, cross-promotional excess, and even a solid social hub and battle royale can’t wash that away for me. You know what can, though? Watching the singing voices of Huntr/x get into </span><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span> now that their characters are in the game.</span></p> <p><span>Rei Ami, the singing voice of Huntr/x’s rapper Zoey, has been campaigning for a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-best-worst-songs-soundtrack-ranking-2000616633"><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters</span></i></a> <span>X </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>collaboration for months, and even </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@rei.ami/video/7555327877944839455"><span>got to reveal her character’s skin ahead of the crossover’s launch</span></a><span>. Now that she’s finally got it, she’s been playing </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>on streams and TikTok Lives as Zoey, and I haven’t seen a pop-off as hype as the first time she got a Victory Royale in the skin in a minute. My girl is out here emoting in real life.</span></p>

   <p><span>Ejae and Audrey Nuna, the singing voices for Rumi and Mira, aren’t </span><i><span>Fortnite </span></i><span>players, but they did shoot a promo video reacting to the skins in which the group jokes about taking a class on how to play Epic’s game.</span></p>

   <p><span>Well, it looks like those lessons are happening. Rei Ami posted a video during their ongoing promotional tour for </span><i><span>KPop Demon Hunters,</span></i><span> showing them spending some of their spare time playing </span><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span>. Ejae managed to get 36th place in her first battle royale match as Rumi, though she was killed by another player called WetPickle4996. I want to talk to that player. Do they know they just destroyed the Honmoon?</span></p>    <p><span>I’m obsessed with this, and I’m waiting for some talented animators and artists to draw Zoey teaching Rumi and Mira how to play </span><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span> like a new fandom in-joke. Huntr/x probably doesn’t have that much time to game these days, though, as the group is about to make their live debut on </span><i><span>The Tonight Show with Jimmy Fallon</span></i><span> as the musical guest. The trio is </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bzuUNSf0bCg"><span>performing “Golden” on tonight’s episode</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/kpop-demon-hunters-fortnite-rei-ami-stream-zoey-rumi-2000632536]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Just Shared A 4-Minute Pixar-Like Animated Short With No Explanation]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-shared-a-4-minute-pixar-like-animated-short-with-no-explanation-2000632524</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-just-shared-a-4-minute-pixar-like-animated-short-with-no-explanation.1318621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A baby shakes a rattle as a pacifier falls out its mouth.</span> © Nintendo / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>We’re fairly used to Nintendo making strange or iconoclastic decisions, whether it’s releasing folding two-screen portable gaming devices or announcing a <a href="https://kotaku.com/virtual-boy-nintendo-switch-classics-2000625301">Virtual Boy peripheral for the Switch 2</a>, but even now the Japanese games company is capable of surprises. It has just uploaded to its various worldwide YouTube channels a stunning four-minute animated short called <em>Close to You</em>, about a baby learning to take their first steps, and there’s no explanation for why. Is it a Princess Peach origin story? Something to do with Rosalina? Is it something to do with <em>Pikmin</em> of all things?</p> <p>It is a truly wonderful cartoon. Evoking Pixar in almost every possible way (complete with&nbsp;<em>Incredibles</em>-like faces), the short shows the mother of a baby just popping out of the room, after which the baby’s toys begin to become animated. Wooden blocks hop about and a rattle rolls itself to the baby’s foot. While enjoying the rattle, the kid’s pacifier falls out of their mouth, and that too comes to life, playfully moving around and evading the baby’s attempts to grab it back. In the end, it gets wedged in a mobile dangling above the baby’s crib, giving the tyke the motivation to reach higher and attempt their first steps.</p>

  <p>There’s obviously no way to know if this baby is a boy or a girl, let alone the child form of a particular character. Given the kid’s white with blonde hair, it could be either Zelda or Link, or Samus, or pretty much any gaming character bar Mario or Toad. Hell, my hair was that blonde as a baby, maybe it&nbsp;<em>is</em> Mario. (It isn’t.)</p>

 <p>Someone has claimed that there’s a Red Pikmin appearing in the video at 1:40. Um, I paused it there, and here it is! But there are musical nods to the&nbsp;<em>Pikmin</em> series in here, and they’re certainly the sorts of mischievous creatures who would move toys around a room.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000632540" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000632540"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000632540">© Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The only credit at any point is “<b><span>© </span></b>Nintendo” at the bottom right at the end of the video, with no mention of Illumination, the animation house behind&nbsp;<em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em> and its forthcoming <em>Mario Galaxy </em>sequel. It’d make some sense if it were related to that, perhaps depicting a moment from Princess Peach’s childhood? She’s fairly magical, and the pink of the pacifier points in that direction. Then again, the blue of the onesie implies Rosalina. Actually, that’d make sense, given the next movie is set in the <em>Super Mario Galaxy</em> universe, and that’s the game in which she first appeared. Let’s go with that! Starting over…</p> <hr> <h2>Nintendo Reveals Rosalina’s Origin Story In Animated Short</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000632541" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000632541"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000632541">© Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Nintendo today has posted a four-minute animated short to its YouTube channels, revealing the beginnings of fan-favorite&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Galaxy</em> character Rosalina, to coincide with the upcoming <em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em> sequel,&nbsp;<em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em>. Rosalina, the resident of the Comet Observatory and mother figure to the game’s star-shaped Lumas, will obviously play a central role in the forthcoming film, so it only makes sense to see her being highlighted here…</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-shared-a-4-minute-pixar-like-animated-short-with-no-explanation-2000632524]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Has Surprised Everyone, The Kindle Is Practically a Gift If You’re a Prime Member]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-has-surprised-everyone-the-kindle-is-practically-a-gift-if-youre-a-prime-member-2000632519</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-has-surprised-everyone-the-kindle-is-practically-a-gift-if-you%E2%80%99re-a-prime-member.1318615/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>If you’ve been waiting for the right moment to finally grab a Kindle, that moment just arrived. Amazon rarely discounts its e-readers, especially the base model that consistently tops the bestseller lists. Summer is peak reading season so the retailer typically holds prices steady through the July Prime Day when demand is already high.</p>
<p>But this Prime Big Deal Days event has brought an unexpected surprise for Prime members: <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4586/">the newest Kindle model is down to $84, reduced from $109</a>. That’s an <strong>all-time low on the lightest and most compact Kindle</strong> Amazon has ever made, and it solves one of the biggest frustrations readers face: lugging around heavy books or scrolling through distracting phone screens when you’re trying to lose yourself in a story.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4586/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why You Have to Choose This Kindle</h2>
<p>This latest generation Kindle (2024) eliminates the little irritations that previously made e-readers <strong>slow to react or more difficult to read</strong> under certain circumstances. The <strong>front light is also increased by 25%</strong> at its highest setting over its predecessor so you are free to read comfortably even in direct sunlight without eye strain or having to shift position to prevent glare. The <strong>6-inch display is also purely glare-proof</strong>&nbsp;so being outdoors by the pool or on a park bench becomes just as comfortable a place to read as being indoors. There is <strong>also a dark mode setting</strong> whereby the text and background are reversed and gives white text on a black display for midnight reading sessions.</p>



<p><strong>Page turns are significantly quicker now</strong> which may sound like a trivial thing but becomes a real distinction when you’re engrossed in a thriller and whizzing through pages rapidly. The increased contrast ratio causes text to seem sharper and darker against the background and better replicates the sensation of reading ink on paper than before.</p>
<p><strong>Battery life is six weeks between charges</strong> if we assume a reading of about 30 minutes per day by shutting off wireless and setting the light to a luminous 13. If you read longer hours or leave wireless on so your reading stays current among multiple devices, a few weeks of life remain until it’s necessary to charge it.</p>



<p>The <strong>16GB of capacity stores thousands of books</strong>, a number far greater than most individuals will want to keep current at a single moment. Even if your downloads are a delicate balancing act between text-heavy novels and graphics-intensive comics or magazines, you’ll have quite a bit of capacity left for other titles. The reader itself <strong>is Amazon’s thinnest and lightest Kindle</strong>, weighing a mere 5.56 ounces.</p>
<p>One of the greatest benefits of reading a book on a Kindle rather than a phone or a tablet is total lack of distraction: There are <strong>no text messages flashing, no urge to see what’s new by email, no social media scrolling</strong> and no other programs demanding your focus. You turn on the thing, resume where you left off, and read. That’s it.</p>
<p>This is a members-only deal for Prime members during the Prime Big Deal Days, and it’s also a record-low price for this model, at $84. If it’s been on your mind to pick up an e-reader, or it’s been a couple of years since you’ve picked up a Kindle, it’s your turn yet.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4586/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-has-surprised-everyone-the-kindle-is-practically-a-gift-if-youre-a-prime-member-2000632519]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>