<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 12:15:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Superman's Opening Weekend Is The Best The Man Of Steel Has Ever Seen]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/superman-james-gunn-opening-weekend-box-office-1851786190</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/supermans-opening-weekend-is-the-best-the-man-of-steel-has-ever-seen.1242900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>James Gunn’s reboot of the DC Cinematic Universe is off to an appropriately flying start. <em>Superman</em> has had a stellar opening weekend, hitting $122 million in the U.S. alone, making it the third-biggest box office launch of the year.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197586" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Disney+ Pulls The Abyss Over Controversial Rat Scene — Again" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="128" data-playlist="197586,196406,197589" data-current="197586"><div><p>Disney+ Pulls The Abyss Over Controversial Rat Scene — Again</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197586/197586_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23107.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>International audiences have been slightly slower to show up, with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.empireonline.com/movies/news/superman-gives-dcu-a-flying-start-with-217-million-opening-weekend-at-the-box-office/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.empireonline.com/movies/news/superman-gives-dcu-a-flying-start-with-217-million-opening-weekend-at-the-box-office/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Empire </em>reporting</a></span> that only another $95 million has come in from 78 nations, but it still gives Supes a fantastic total of $217 million in just a couple of days. It’s already safe to say that Gunn’s initiative is proving to be a success.</p><p>DCU movies have been in steep decline over recent years, as the muddle of tonally confusing films saw decreasing interest. Putting aside the various distinct <em>Batman</em> films <em>not</em> set in the shared universe, the last time a DC movie opened domestically to over $100m was <em>Wonder Woman</em>, nine years ago in 2017. Soon after, the Snyder-infused films dropped sharply, with <em>Justice League</em> falling to under $94m, and 2018's <em>Aquaman</em> reaching just shy of $68m, before things got a lot worse.</p><p>In fact, the only two films in the franchise to open to over $50 million since are 2019's <em>Shazam!</em> ($53.5m) and 2023's <em>The Flash </em>($55m)—the latter a deservedly considerable flop, its lifetime U.S. gross scraping to just $108.1 million. The final two movies in the contained franchise, <em>Blue Beetle</em> and <em>Aquaman 2</em>, both barely topped $25m in their opening weekend.</p><figure id="" data-id="21e7be7406234dda108cd28cc0b70a94" data-recommend-id="image://21e7be7406234dda108cd28cc0b70a94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="665" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Superman and Lois kiss while floating in the middle of a mall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Superman and Lois kiss while floating in the middle of a mall." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->DC</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="21e7be7406234dda108cd28cc0b70a94" data-recommend-id="image://21e7be7406234dda108cd28cc0b70a94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="665" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Superman and Lois kiss while floating in the middle of a mall." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>So, two years have gone by, the previous version of the DCU now (mostly) retconned, and <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>’s James Gunn has reinvented everything. With a ludicrously long list of superhero movies planned, including <em>Supergirl</em>, <em>Clayface</em>, <em>The Authority</em>, <em>Swamp Thing</em> and <em>Sgt. Rock</em>, among many others, <em>Superman</em> absolutely had to be a success, or the entire project would look extremely unlikely. So Big Blue’s initial success must be a huge relief to an awful lot of people.</p><p>This is certainly helped by the movie being quite good. While padded and oddly paced, Gunn managed to deliver a much more interesting opening take on the classic superhero, with a fun ensemble cast and an overt commentary on America’s current attitudes toward immigration. This was all helped by scattering Supes’ origin story throughout rather than <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/james-gunn-spider-man-batman-superman-dcu-1851785756&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/james-gunn-spider-man-batman-superman-dcu-1851785756">making us sit through it all yet again</a></span>, and sparing us yet another depiction of Lois’s figuring out who he is. Given this, word of mouth seems likely to boost the film’s continuing box office, rather than see it sharply drop off as people warn others to stay away, as with the truly awful <em>The Flash</em>.</p><p>The ticket sales also make this the most successful solo <em>Superman</em> movie opening of all time, too. It beat <em>Man of Steel</em>’s previous record of $116.7 million, although if you count Snyder’s po-faced 2016 <em>Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice</em>, that steaming turd of a film somehow brought in $166m in its first two days.</p><p>It’s a promising start to the Gunniverse, although names as obscure to non-comics readers as <em>Clayface</em> and <em>Sgt. Rock</em> are going to be a tough sell on reputation alone. <em>Supergirl</em> is going to have to do a lot of heavy lifting next year if people are going to show up for those.</p><p>It only remains to be seen how Warner CEO David Zaslav can step in to sabotage everything.</p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/superman-james-gunn-opening-weekend-box-office-1851786190]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>