<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:35:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple M4 MacBook Air Joins the Holiday Price War at an All-Time Low to Compete With Windows PC Deals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-m4-macbook-air-joins-the-holiday-price-war-at-an-all-time-low-to-compete-with-windows-pc-deals-2000653263</link>
            <guid>1383286</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple’s willingness to cut huge deals on their newest tech gear has been one of the biggest and most pleasant surprises of the 2025 holiday shopping season. It’s still not too late to cash in on this surprising new trend, if this latest Amazon deal is any indication. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6030/">The 2025 M4 MacBook Air is still just $749 at Amazon, its lowest price ever and a big $250 step down from its usual $999.</a></p>
<p>The M4 MacBooks are one of the best places to look for amazing deals since being supplanted at the top of the Apple ecosystem by the M5 chip last October. But the price drops on the M4 models go way beyond the step down from the M5 to the M4, because the M4 machines are still absolutely elite-level computers, loaded with Apple Intelligence, Apple’s industry-best Liquid Retina display, outstanding cameras and speakers, and enough memory and power for heavy-duty creative work.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6030/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A Small Step Down</h2>
<p>The talk in techworld has been all about the M5 MacBooks since they debuted in October, and rightfully so. The M5 machines are industry-best laptops, so when we see a huge deal on an M4 model like this one, the question becomes, just how big is the difference? The M5 chip is a faster CPU by up to 20% and faster in terms of AI thanks to new integrated Neural Accelerators. Big numbers to be sure, but how noticeable to the everyday user? Answer: Not very, unless you’re completely immersed in exceptionally heavy AI work, and even then it’s an incremental difference.</p>
<p>So while there may be an M5 MacBook Air coming in the early months of 2026, it’s a fairly safe bet that the resulting price drop on this M4 model won’t go any lower than this Amazon deal for $749, and the performance difference won’t come near meeting the price difference. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6030/">The time to grab the M4 MacBook Air is now, during this last-minute holiday sale at Amazon.</a></p>



<h2>All the Bells, All the Whistles</h2>
<p>It’s been less than a year since the M4 MacBook Air dropped, so it has all of the perks and tech that make the MacBooks so coveted. The M4 chip itself has a 10-core CPU and up to 10 cores of GPU, with 16GB of unified memory and a 256GB SSD. It’s the ideal machine for photo and video editing and other content creation-related tasks. The 12MP Center Stage camera, four built-in speakers with Spatial Audio, and studio-quality mics make the MacBook Air the perfect video conferencing or video call laptop, along with its slim, lightweight design.</p>
<p>We’ve all been so used to a $749 MacBook either being 2 or 3 generations old or having the words “refurbished” or “scratch and dent” attached to the deal that the idea of that price being on a brand-new 2025 model is a little surreal. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6030/">But this Amazon deal taking $250 off of this 13-inch M4 MacBook Air is the real deal, and it’s real close to being real gone.&nbsp;</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6030/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-m4-macbook-air-joins-the-holiday-price-war-at-an-all-time-low-to-compete-with-windows-pc-deals-2000653263]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>