<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:20:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Is Practically Giving Away the New Fire TV Stick HD in a Pre–Black Friday Price Meltdown]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ahead-of-black-friday-amazon-has-its-fire-tv-stick-hd-on-sale-for-half-price-2000644443</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-is-practically-giving-away-the-new-fire-tv-stick-hd-in-a-pre%E2%80%93black-friday-price-meltdown.1355515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Back when the Amazon Fire TV Stick first showed up, the whole pitch was basically, “Hey, plug this in and boom—your old TV is suddenly smart.” Fast-forward to now, and most TVs fresh off the shelf already have some kind of smart interface built in. The thing is, a lot of those built-in interfaces… kind of suck. Some companies still haven’t cracked the code on making a simple, smooth UI. (Looking at you, LG, with your strange Wiimote-wannabe remotes). So at this point, the real draw of the Fire TV Stick isn’t that it makes your TV “smart”—it’s that it gives you a <em data-start="722" data-end="730">better</em> smart experience. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/">And right now, the newest Fire TV Stick HD is down to just $18.</a> Normally it runs $35, but this deal chops nearly half off the price, which is pretty hard to complain about.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Once you plug it in, you can basically stream anything you’d expect: Netflix, Hulu, HBO Max (or whatever they’re deciding to call it this month), Disney+, Prime Video—the usual cast.. As long as you’ve got the subscriptions, the content is there. But even if you don’t want to spend any more on streaming subs, the Fire TV Stick actually has quite a bit of free stuff built in. Apps like Freevee, Tubi, Pluto TV, and a ton of Fire TV’s own free channels give you a surprising amount of movies and TV show episodes to just kick back and watch. Sure, they’re ad-supported, but free is free.</p>
<p data-start="1513" data-end="1986">One of the nicest quality-of-life things is the Alexa remote. No one enjoys hunting and pecking their way through an on-screen keyboard with a clunky d-pad. With the Alexa button, you literally just say what you want—“play <em data-start="1736" data-end="1742">Dune</em>” or “find <em data-start="1753" data-end="1770">The Mandalorian</em>”—and it pulls it up for you. It even scans across multiple apps to tell you which service actually has the thing you’re searching for, which saves you from the endless “which app did I watch that on?” guessing game.</p>


<h2 data-start="1513" data-end="1986">Cloud-based Gaming</h2>
<p data-start="1988" data-end="2503">Another neat perk that’s becoming more and more practical: you can actually play cloud-streamed Xbox games through it. If you’ve got Game Pass Ultimate, you don’t need an Xbox console at all—the cloud streaming service lets you play straight on your Fire Stick as long as your internet isn’t terrible. It’s kind of wild being able to fire up games like <em data-start="2321" data-end="2334">Animal Well</em> or <em data-start="2338" data-end="2374">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> on something only marginally larger than pack of gum. As long as your Wi-Fi is steady, the whole experience is way smoother than you’d expect. And now with&nbsp;<em>Red Dead Redemption 2&nbsp;</em>coming to a number of services including Netflix, now’s a great time to experiment with cloud gaming.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4359/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ahead-of-black-friday-amazon-has-its-fire-tv-stick-hd-on-sale-for-half-price-2000644443]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Dumps the 1000XM5 at 40% Off, Now 2.5x Cheaper Than Apple’s Rival Headphones]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-dumps-the-1000xm5-at-40-off-now-2-5x-cheaper-than-apples-rival-headphones-2000644742</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-dumps-the-1000xm5-at-40-off-now-2-5x-cheaper-than-apple%E2%80%99s-rival-headphones.1355491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Premium noise-canceling headphones tend to be a choice between Sony’s 1000XM5 and Apple’s AirPods Max and the price difference is just ridiculous. Apple wants $549 for their headphones, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5629/">while Sony’s flagship just dropped to $248 on Amazon, down from $399 in a Black Friday deal</a> that hits nearly all color options. Some colors are selling out fast as people realize they can get comparable performance for 2.5 times less money. If you’re willing to step outside the Apple bubble and give up the brand premium, you’re getting essentially the same listening experience for half the cost.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5629/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Why Sony’s Noise Cancellation Beats All Competitors</h2>
<p>The<strong> noise cancellation is powered by a pair of processors and eight microphones</strong> and it is as good as it gets: yes, even better than Apple’s implementation. It works in real-time and adjusts to your surroundings to block out the din of airplane engines, coffee shop chit-chat, and street noise with scary effectiveness. An Auto NC Optimizer adjusts for atmospheric pressure, so the noise cancellation doesn’t change whether you’re at sea level or cruising at 35,000 feet. You can genuinely work or relax in near-silence even in the noisiest environments.</p>
<p>The <strong>battery life hits 30 hours on a single charge</strong> to cover multiple cross-country flights or weeks of daily commutes without hunting for an outlet. With quick charging, you’ll get three hours of playback from just three minutes plugged in, so forgetting to charge overnight doesn’t ruin your day. A USB-C cable comes included, and the headphones work while charging if you absolutely need them immediately.</p>



<p>Hands-free calling uses four beamforming microphones in concert with <strong>advanced audio signal processing to isolate your voice from ambient noise</strong>. These microphones focus on your voice while filtering out wind, traffic, and the general hum of people chatting in the background that usually ruins phone calls. Video conferences sound professional, even when you’re calling in from a busy street or noisy office.</p>



<p>Touch controls on the ear cups let you pause, play, skip tracks, adjust volume and answer calls without having to pull out your phone. After one day of usage, gestures become second nature, and responsiveness is immediate without lag or missed inputs. You can swipe up and down for volume, tap to pause, or hold to activate your voice assistant. It’s large enough to register gestures but not so sensitive that an accidental touch constantly stops playback.</p>
<p><strong>Comfort comes from the lightweight design and soft-fit leather that distributes pressure equally</strong> across your head. The headband has just enough padding to prevent hotspots during long listening sessions without adding bulk. The ear cups create a seal that enables noise cancellation while staying breathable enough to wear for hours without sweating. These headphones disappear on your head in a way that heavier models never do.</p>
<p>Sound quality provides the well-balanced and detailed profile Sony is known for without the bass-heavy tuning some brands use to impress in quick demos. Mids and highs remain clear and separated, which means vocals and instruments don’t muddy together during complex tracks. The soundstage feels wide and natural rather than artificially processed. Audiophiles will appreciate the fidelity and casual listeners will enjoy how everything just sounds right without needing EQ adjustments.</p>
<p>At $248 for headphones that go head-to-head with $549 AirPods Max, you save $301 and get equal noise cancellation, better battery life, and similar audio quality.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5629/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-dumps-the-1000xm5-at-40-off-now-2-5x-cheaper-than-apples-rival-headphones-2000644742]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Is Getting A Brutal Kicking From Players Over Its Use Of AI]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-is-getting-a-brutal-kicking-from-players-over-its-use-of-ai-2000644734</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-is-getting-a-brutal-kicking-from-players-over-its-use-of-ai.1355428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Two robots in Black Ops 7.</span> © Activision
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em> is proving pretty popular with critics. The latest entry in the infinitely-running series is sitting on a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/critic-reviews/?platform=pc">Metascore of 83</a>, with no reviews so far marked as “negative.” The same, however, can not be said of user reviews. At a desultory <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/user-reviews/?platform=pc">Metascore of 1.9</a>, it’s the worst-rated&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty</em> ever.</p> <p>A lot of the ire in the Metascore reviews is focused on the game’s “lackluster” multiplayer-only campaign, faulty matchmaking, litany of bugs, and very unfavorable comparisons with <em>Arc Raiders</em>, but the use of AI also comes up a great deal as people vent their frustrations. It was noticed immediately after launch that the latest entry in one of the biggest franchises in the world had used AI-plagiarized art for player banners, calling cards and even artwork within the campaign. <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ai-art-activision-statement-blops7-steam-ps5-2000644397">When&nbsp;<em>Kotaku</em> approached Activision for comment on this</a>, the company seemed entirely nonplussed by the situation, simply stating “Like so many around the world, we use a variety of digital tools, including AI tools, to empower and support our teams…”</p>

 <p>“Just pure trash full of ai slop,” says one Metacritic user. “What AI bot did they use to puke up this garbage?” asks another. A third comments, “It’s just another hurriedly rushed AI slop-fest.” One comment that appears to capture the mood of most poetically phrases it, “Unbelievable, abysmal dogshit. Save your money please! The use of AI is just the cherry on top.”</p>

 <p>Of course, user scores do tend to be marked on a binary scale, rather than adopting the full spread of numbers. People tend to leave reviews not out of a sense of civic duty, but rather because they’re either delighted or furious, hence the majority of these scores being a possibly somewhat exaggerated 0. Scattered throughout (albeit very much in the minority), bringing the overall average to 1.9, are 9s and 10s from enthusiasts. It’s obviously not a useful metric of a game’s quality, but it’s certainly a very useful way to see which way a game is being received by the wider public.</p>

 <p>Meanwhile, over on Steam, the game is currently sitting on the very low end of “Mixed” reviews, with just 42 percent of reader reviews finding&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 7</em> to be positive. (However, that rating drops to “Mostly Negative” when reviews are filtered for English language only. Chinese players seem to be having a better response.) “chatgpt generate me a lackluster campaign with reused assets and cringe worthy dialogue,” reads one popular review. “Activision just pay for art you clearly have money and it won’t look like shit,” says another.</p> <p>It’s something of a relief that the brazen use of AI in games still generates fury like this, players yet to be inoculated to it by its widespread use. Companies are keen to trot out the “But everyone else is doing it!” excuse, like a child caught cheating in a test, but right now this isn’t cutting it with audiences. It seems pretty likely that any major company pledging&nbsp;<em>not</em> to use AI could win enormous favor with players in this climate. It’s probably worth a try!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-is-getting-a-brutal-kicking-from-players-over-its-use-of-ai-2000644734]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>