<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:09:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iRobot Roomba at 50% Off, Now Cheaper Than Basic Stick Vacuums but Only on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/irobot-roomba-at-50-off-now-cheaper-than-basic-stick-vacuums-but-only-on-amazon-2000650099</link>
            <guid>1372309</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon keeps some Black Friday deals going until early December and the <strong>iRobot Roomba 105</strong> is still at its lowest price ever which makes robot vacuums affordable: This <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/">model is now on sale for $149 on Amazon instead of the usual $299</a> which is the same price as a basic stick vacuum without any smart features. Robot vacuums do the work for you, so you don’t have to push a vacuum around your house several times a week and you can use that time for anything else while your floors stay clean.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>LiDAR Mapping</h2>
<p>The <strong>ClearView LiDAR sensor spins around the room</strong> while the Roomba moves, sending out laser beams and measuring how long it takes for each beam to bounce back from walls, furniture, and other things in the way. The robot uses this information to make an exact map of your home’s layout which it keeps and uses during every cleaning session. The<strong> mapping process goes quickly at first</strong> but the Roomba gets better at knowing your space over time as it runs into new obstacles or sees that the furniture has been moved.</p>
<p>The navigation system makes sure that the cleaning paths are efficient and cover your floors in neat, parallel rows, like how you would mow a lawn. This methodical approach makes sure that everything is covered while cutting down on unnecessary passes over areas that have already been cleaned. This extends battery life and speeds up the completion of tasks. Specialized sensors keep the Roomba from falling down stairs or off ledges by finding stairs and drops.</p>



<p>The three-stage cleaning system uses a brush that works on multiple surfaces, an edge-sweeping brush, and a suction channel to pick up dirt from different types of floors.<strong> iRobot says that this model has 70 times more power-lifting suction than their older 600 series robots</strong> and it creates enough airflow to pull dirt out of carpet fibers and cracks in hardwood floors. The edge-sweeping brush goes beyond the robot’s round body and into corners and along baseboards, where dust collects and circular vacuum paths usually miss.</p>
<p>You can control the Roomba Home app from your phone and you can start cleaning sessions from anywhere, set up automatic runs based on your daily routine, and make sure the robot stays away from pet bowls or other delicate areas. You can change the suction power and set the number of cleaning passes for each room. This lets you change the intensity based on how much dirt and traffic there is in different areas.</p>



<p>Spot cleaning mode cleans a small area over and over for up to five minutes which is helpful when you’ve spilled something or see a really dirty spot that needs extra attention. <strong>Voice control integration works with Alexa, Siri, and Google Assistant</strong> and it lets you start or stop cleaning sessions with your voice when your hands are full or you’re in another room. There are physical buttons on the robot itself that let you start cleaning quickly without having to open the app or look for your phone.</p>
<p>At $149, robot vacuums go from being a luxury item to a useful investment that costs the same as stick vacuums that you have to use your time and energy to operate. The 50% off sale makes advanced LiDAR navigation and smart mapping features available at a price that was only available with basic random-pattern cleaning in earlier models.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6023/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/irobot-roomba-at-50-off-now-cheaper-than-basic-stick-vacuums-but-only-on-amazon-2000650099]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Has Leftover Stock From Black Friday, Now Quietly Sells MacBook Air M4 at Record Low on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-has-leftover-stock-from-black-friday-now-quietly-sells-macbook-air-m4-at-record-low-on-amazon-2000650134</link>
            <guid>1372300</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Black Friday came and went with some decent Apple deals on Amazon, but the retailer didn’t move all its inventory during the rush. That means the all-time low pricing on the MacBook Air M4 256GB, which launched in March 2025, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/">is still available right now at $749 instead of the usual $999 tag.</a> This matters because Apple rarely sees discounts this deep, especially on hardware that’s less than a year old.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The M4 Chip Changes the Way This Machine Works</h2>
<p>The Apple M4 processor makes things a lot faster and you’ll notice it right away when you switch between demanding apps. Video editing software that used to stutter now works perfectly with 4K video, and you can run multiple Chrome tabs and Photoshop at the same time without hearing a fan noise because there isn’t one. The chip <strong>architecture puts the CPU, GPU, and neural engine all on one piece of silicon</strong> which makes data move faster between parts and uses less power. This means that the <strong>battery can last up to 18 hours</strong> without dying when you’re doing real work instead of just browsing Safari.</p>



<p>This<strong> hardware can run Apple Intelligence on its own</strong> and it can do things like help you write, make images, and organize your files without sending your data to other servers. The privacy architecture does everything on the device, so your personal information never goes to the cloud for processing. This is very helpful when you want to summarize long email threads, make custom emojis based on descriptions, or have the system sort notifications by how important they really are.</p>
<p>The<strong> 13.6-inch Liquid Retina display has a brightness of 500 nits</strong> and can show one billion colors: This means you can work outside without having to squint at a dim screen. The text is clear enough that you won’t strain your eyes when you write for a long time, and the colors in photos are accurate enough that designers and photographers can trust them. The bezels around the screen are thin enough to give you the most viewing area without making the whole thing too big to handle.</p>



<p><strong>Two Thunderbolt 4 ports handle charging, data transfer at 40Gbps</strong>&nbsp;and video output to external displays, so connectivity is complete. You can use two external monitors at the same time, which turns this light laptop into a real workstation when you’re at your desk. <em>MagSafe</em> charging is back and it has a magnetic connection that safely disconnects if someone trips over the cable. This keeps both your laptop and your sanity safe. If you have a router that works with Wi-Fi 6E, your wireless speeds will be faster. The<strong> four-speaker system with Spatial Audio</strong> makes the sound surprisingly immersive for a chassis this thin and the three-mic array also does a good job of isolating your voice during calls, even in noisy places.</p>
<p>This price of $749 is $250 less than what the hardware usually sells for which is a good deal because it usually holds its value all year. You’re getting a current-generation processor with twice the base RAM, which will keep the machine up to date for years to come with software updates and more demanding applications. This <strong>is the lowest price ever for anApple laptop</strong> that can handle both creative work and everyday tasks without any problems.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4498/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-has-leftover-stock-from-black-friday-now-quietly-sells-macbook-air-m4-at-record-low-on-amazon-2000650134]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Twin Stick Shooter Is The New Geometry Wars And It Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-twin-stick-shooter-is-the-new-geometry-wars-and-it-rules-2000650227</link>
            <guid>1372282</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I’m very annoyed that I have a job, that I have to go to the bathroom, that I have to write this damn blog. All I want to do is play more <em>Sektori</em>, a newly released roguelike twin stick shooter that all fans of <em>Geometry Wars</em> should play ASAP.</p> <p>Out now on <a href="https://www.gimblll.com/sektori/#:~:text=Store%20Links%20(Game,Steam">Xbox, PlayStation, and Steam, <em>Sektori</em></a> is one of those games that takes less than five minutes to understand and yet will suck up hours of your life in no time. You control a small, colorful shape that must destroy other vibrantly glowing shapes and objects that will damage you if touched. Blast and dodge these bastards with your laser canon, which, like your shield, overall speed, and dash ability, can be upgraded during each run, to defeat the boss and set a new high score. It’s very simple and very, very good.</p>

 <p>Oh, and <em>Sektori</em> looks incredibly sharp and slick, with loads of particle effects and eye-popping neon art. Seriously, look at this game in action.</p>  <p><em>Sektori</em> understands that the main appeal of games like <em>Geometry Wars</em> is watching the playfield fill up with all manner of colorful objects and shapes, and then systematically evaporating them using your blasters and power-ups. But it builds on that formula by pulling in some gameplay mechanics found in games like <a href="https://kotaku.com/castlevania-roguelike-vampire-survivors-steam-itch-io-1848402308"><em>Vampire Survivors</em> and <em>Halls of Torment.</em></a> Each little shape you blast away leaves behind some shiny glimmer. Pick up enough of this stuff, and you’ll spawn an upgrade token. Save a few of these up, and you can replenish your shield, unlock missiles, or upgrade your laser gun.</p>

 <p>Occasionally, you’ll be asked to pick a card to unlock a new perk. I’m not entirely sure how this works, and that’s because <em>Sektori</em> has one other cool ace up its neon-lined sleeve: It ain’t as simple as you might think. There’s more going on here that the game chooses not to explain in the brief tutorial, and discovering the secrets in <em>Sketori</em> and how everything works has made it extremely easy for me to just go “Well, one more run won’t hurt!” And then suddenly I’ve been playing for two hours. It helps that the game runs flawlessly, features great music, and feels incredibly snappy to play.</p> <p>I mean, I literally downloaded this game on my father-in-law’s Xbox Series X while visiting for Thanksgiving. I just wanted to play a few more rounds. And now, I’m done writing about <em>Sektori</em>, and I’m going to go back and play more of it. Leave me alone. Thanks.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-twin-stick-shooter-is-the-new-geometry-wars-and-it-rules-2000650227]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP Laptop With Solid Daily Specs at 81% Off, Amazon Skipped Black Friday and Goes Record Low Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hp-laptop-with-solid-daily-specs-at-81-off-amazon-skipped-black-friday-and-goes-record-low-now-2000650092</link>
            <guid>1372279</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When you’re looking for a good daily driver that can handle web browsing, productivity apps and streaming without breaking the bank, you don’t need to spend $2,000 on a MacBook Pro: This <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6197/">HP 15.6″ (256GB SSD, 16GB RAM, Intel Core chip) laptop is now on sale for $369 on Amazon, down from its usual price of $1,999</a>. This seems to be an inventory clearance sale that has brought this model’s price down to its lowest point ever.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6197/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Everyday Computing Performance</h2>
<p>The<strong> Intel Processor N100 has four cores that run at a base frequency that can go up to 3.4GHz</strong> when tasks need more processing power. It also has 6MB of L3 cache to help frequently accessed data load quickly. This chip is part of Intel’s lineup of chips that are made for thin and light laptops, where battery life and heat management are more important than raw benchmark scores. This processor won’t let you work on 4K video projects or play demanding games, but it can handle the everyday computing tasks that most people do without slowing down.</p>
<p>With 16GB of DDR4 RAM, you can keep dozens of browser tabs open at the same time as Microsoft Office apps and video conferencing software without having to move data to the slower SSD and this much RAM is enough to make you stop worrying about closing programs to free up memory. The 256GB PCIe NVMe SSD loads Windows and apps faster than mechanical hard drives, but you’ll need to be careful about how you use the space because modern games and big media libraries can fill it up faster than you’d like.</p>



<p>The <strong>15.6-inch Full HD screen shows content at a resolution of 1920×1080</strong> and has an anti-glare coating that cuts down on reflections from windows and overhead lights. The 250-nit brightness rating is good enough for most indoor lighting, but you might have trouble reading the screen in direct sunlight or very bright places. Intel UHD integrated graphics can play videos and do basic photo editing and they have enough power for casual older games, but not enough for modern AAA games or heavy creative work.</p>
<p>Wi-Fi 6 connections are faster and work better in crowded networks than Wi-Fi 5 connections; Bluetooth 5.3 keeps wireless mice, keyboards, and headphones connected without dropping out. Two USB-A ports let you connect older peripherals without needing dongles, and the HDMI 1.4b output lets you connect to external monitors or projectors for presentations and more workspace.</p>



<p><strong>Windows 11 Home</strong> comes with a desktop interface that most people are used to and works with a huge number of Windows programs that have been made over the years. You can use traditional desktop programs like Adobe apps, business software, and games from Steam on a Chromebook without the limitations that come with web-based workflows. The headphone/microphone combo <strong>jack works with standard 3.5mm audio devices</strong>&nbsp;and the built-in webcam is good enough for video calls for work and school from home.</p>
<p>At $369, this HP is at the same price as a Chromebook, but it has full Windows functionality and more RAM than you’d expect to find at this price point. Amazon is probably clearing out its remaining stock, which is why the price has dropped so much from the inflated $1,999.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6197/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hp-laptop-with-solid-daily-specs-at-81-off-amazon-skipped-black-friday-and-goes-record-low-now-2000650092]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 4 Is 17 Years Old But Looks Practically Next-Gen Thanks To A New Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gta-4-is-17-years-old-but-looks-practically-next-gen-thanks-to-a-new-mod-2000650202</link>
            <guid>1372171</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A new free mod for <a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-ivs-story-is-better-than-gta-vs-1690387521"><em>Grand Theft Auto IV</em></a> breathes fresh life into the early PS3-era open-world game and its aging visuals, making the dated blockbuster look almost as impressive as some modern releases.</p> <p>Rockstar’s<em> Grand Theft Auto IV</em> launched on Xbox 360, PS3, and (eventually) PC all the way back in 2008. While the console versions were great and are fondly remembered to this day by fans, the PC release was a mess that was often cited as one of the worst AAA ports of that era. <a href="https://kotaku.com/years-later-rockstar-releases-new-pc-patch-for-gta-iv-1789523135">But thanks to some official updates</a> and the hard work of fan modders,<em> GTA IV</em> is very playable on PC in 2025. It even runs well on Steam Deck. And a newly released path tracing mod makes the nearly two-decade-old crime simulator look incredible on a sufficiently powerful computer.</p> <p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/xoxor4d">Created by modder Xoxor4d</a>, GTA4 RTX Remix is a mod that adds gorgeous path-traced lighting to the game via Nvidia’s RTX Remix tech. This mod doesn’t change any textures or swap in any higher-res assets. This is still mostly <em>Grand Theft Auto IV</em> from 2008. But now every light source, like headlights and the sun, reacts more naturally with the objects and environments around them.</p>

 <p>What this mod pulls off without changing any geometry or textures is impressive and, at times, near-photorealistic, <a href="https://youtu.be/vGxPdcMQfwg">as seen in this video</a> that was released when the mod was still locked behind a paywall. And it’s especially impressive when compared side-by-side to the OG game.</p>

  <p>GTA4 RTX Remix is a great example of how realistic, advanced lighting can make even older games look far more impressive. To me, this is the tech I want to see game developers and console makers focusing on as the next big thing. I don’t need 8K resolution or 240 FPS. I want accurate shadows and light bouncing off surfaces naturally. <a href="https://kotaku.com/half-life-hl-ray-tracing-rt-mod-valve-pc-mod-download-1850150600">As seen in <em>Half-Life</em></a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/nvidia-rtx-remix-mods-modder-max-payne-swat-portal-pc-1849884871">other older games</a>, this kind of tech can make games look truly next-gen.</p>

 <p>Technically, GTA4 RTX Remix has been floating around online for a few months now, but it was only available to folks who subscribed to the mod creator’s Patreon page. However, last week, after it had been thoroughly tested, the mod was made public for all to download and enjoy for free. You can grab it from <a href="https://github.com/xoxor4d/gta4-rtx">Xoxor4d’s GitHub page</a>, where the modder has instructions on how to install the mod and how to make it work with the popular <em>GTA IV</em> mod Fusion Fix.</p> <p>While it ain’t perfect, Nico’s head is far too shiny, for example, I still think anyone wanting to replay <em>Grand Theft Auto IV</em> in 2025 should get this mod and Fusion Fix working together to experience the best version of the game. Who needs Rockstar to remaster <em>GTA IV</em> when fans are doing it already and for free? Just be prepared for some FPS drops if you are playing on an older PC or don’t use DLSS.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gta-4-is-17-years-old-but-looks-practically-next-gen-thanks-to-a-new-mod-2000650202]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finance Bro Thinks It Would Be Cool To Turn Your Entire Life Into The Stock Market]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/finance-bro-thinks-it-would-be-cool-to-turn-your-entire-life-into-the-stock-market-2000650201</link>
            <guid>1372138</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Kalshi’s CEO is bullish on the future of prediction market betting to solve disagreements for people, or at least make him very, very rich. What if every outcome in your life could be turned into a way to win or lose money? Imagine your very existence has been gamified into a gambling roguelike. “The long-term vision is to financialize everything and create a tradable asset out of any difference in opinion,” Tarek Mansour said at last month’s <a href="https://www.citadelsecurities.com/news-and-insights/kalshi-founders-tarek-mansour-luana-lopes-lara-on-turning-events-into-assets/?series=future-of-global-markets-2025-conference">Citadel Securities conference</a>.</p> <p>What sounds like a loading screen <a href="https://kotaku.com/gen-ai-fps-tom-clancy-shooter-hyperwrite-2000638861">from<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em></a> was enough to make investors jump at the opportunity to turn angry Reddit threads into stock tickers you can gamble on. Kalshi recently raised $1 billion in its latest funding round this week, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/prediction-market-kalshi-hits-11-billion-valuation-in-new-funding-round-c4b1ddfe?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqdK-C0DhBc1ROkTdmdjauO7NE1xfoRnplk7FG1xKlaVPgwq1j6G1W_GWZ8c32U%3D&amp;gaa_ts=69309f9c&amp;gaa_sig=hKp-ZWblR1czvzvZi6BU2jUgxKi7W5LCwBBoCgom6lbVg_ldgoo9zy88xGYY8empWbRhMBInY0rli8I8qQBvIQ%3D%3D">leading to an $11 billion valuation</a>. What are investors so pumped about? Here’s the pitch Mansour <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/moreperfectunion.bsky.social/post/3m747g22dcc2o">gave in November</a> on stage with co-founder Luana Lopes Lara:</p>

 <blockquote><p>[Prediction markets are] pretty much already close to a $100 billion a year asset class. It’s pretty easy to imagine it 10x from here. We haven’t even started. It’s been a year. I think a very large number of people care, much larger than traditional markets, and I think retail as a pie has just been growing in the U.S. and I think it’s going to keep growing–it’s growing in the stock market, it’s growing outside the stock market.</p> <p>The long term vision is to financialize everything and create a tradable asset out of any difference of opinion. And I think if you do build a general purpose exchange that can resolve differences of opinions on anything the [total addressable market] is quite massive, quite a bit bigger than the current TAM of the stock market.</p> <p>Putting aside the retail trading and the institutional trading product there’s sort of this separate product which is we are living in a world where we have an abundance of information but there’s a lot of noise and we don’t really understand what’s real from what’s not and prediction markets are an antidote to that, they do a very good job of surfacing information and distilling truth to people.</p></blockquote>   <p>Mansour’s prediction market, i.e. opinion polls turned into casinos, was established back in 2018. <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2025-goty-race-polymarket-clair-obscur-2000640468">Like rivals such as Polymarket</a>, It’s pitched as a sophisticated tool for hedging risk. Picture some big world event like a war or an election. No one knows the outcome or what it might mean for their business so they trade bets to reduce the chance of losing a ton of money.</p>

 <p>I’m not going to weigh in on whether that makes any sense because that’s not what Mansour is saying is going to make Kalshi go 10X. The real moonshot is being able to take the popularity of betting on stocks with apps like Robinhood or sports with Draft Kings, and apply it to the totality of life. Every outcome, not just one in the market or a football game, will be an opportunity for people to gamble, ahem, I mean hedge risk.</p>

 <p>It all feels very Sam Bankman-Fried-coded. Remember <a href="https://kotaku.com/riot-games-ftx-cryptocurrency-exchange-sponsorship-sue-1849909204">that big FTX crypto debacle</a> from the wunderkind that was also making grand pronouncements on stage at conferences just before it all went belly up? Headlines <a href="https://frontofficesports.com/polymarket-and-kalshi-ceos-say-theyre-changing-the-world/">like this</a> about Kalshi and Polymarket don’t drive confidence. Where’s the prediction market for betting against prediction markets?</p>

 <p>If the post-covid era has taught us anything about the current state of the distraction economy, it’s that we love finding new ways to waste time and money on our phones. I don’t actually think most people want to treat break room debates or dinner table arguments like betting on horse racing. Maybe if it was more like <em>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</em>.</p> <p>But I think Mansour does and the people prepared to give his company billions do and that’s all it takes for bad things to happen.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/finance-bro-thinks-it-would-be-cool-to-turn-your-entire-life-into-the-stock-market-2000650201]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>