<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 23:06:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stardew Valley Fans Aren’t Holding Back About How Much They Hate This Guy]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-clint-marriage-1-7-update-2000674574</link>
            <guid>1449178</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>In honor of </span><i><span>Stardew Valley</span></i><span> turning 10 on Thursday, ConcernedApe </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-marriage-candidates-new-update-1-7-qi-2000674093"><span>unveiled two new marriage candidates</span></a><span> for the upcoming 1.7 update: Sandy and Clint.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Sandy is a beautiful, mysterious lady who runs the Oasis in the Calico Desert, a relatively late-game location which only adds to her intrigue and allure. While it requires a lot of hours logged to meet and romance her, she’s a relatively uncontroversial addition to the marriage roster. Clint, however…</span></p> <p><span>Clint is Pelican Town’s blacksmith, which means players (unfortunately) interact with him quite a bit. He has become quite a hated figure in the </span><i><span>Stardew</span></i><span> community over the years due to his creepy obsession with Emily, a different marriage candidate.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">not a single person opens stardew and goes yeah I wanna marry clint <a href="https://t.co/G0F220YeEy">https://t.co/G0F220YeEy</a></p> <p>— xo, my Rolliepollie ♡ (@FataIYuri) <a href="https://twitter.com/FataIYuri/status/2027103849979244651?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Clint after i divorce him and marry emily immediately after so he ends up drowning himself in the river (I collect his corpse and use it as fertilizer) <a href="https://t.co/J07zYAQwkc">pic.twitter.com/J07zYAQwkc</a></p> <p>— 🌼 Miquella D. kind 🌼 (@ZaVileBob) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZaVileBob/status/2027110662917292192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">They cancelled smiling friends and made clint a marriage candidate in the same 24 hours bruh these are dark times</p> <p>— King Pinna (@king_pinna) <a href="https://twitter.com/king_pinna/status/2027186967876923455?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Separated by language, united in hate for that fucking blacksmith <a href="https://t.co/X8MvUKEIQB">https://t.co/X8MvUKEIQB</a></p> <p>— Koda (@Clark_KentButch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Clark_KentButch/status/2027201265478828543?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">imagine getting off of the worst shift of ur life and finding out clint is now a marriable character in stardew valley <a href="https://t.co/L5HjmT8aun">https://t.co/L5HjmT8aun</a></p> <p>— will (@rdiohdfntsy) <a href="https://twitter.com/rdiohdfntsy/status/2027105422822219794?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">just check up on your friends today man. they added clint as a bachelor in stardew valley and it’s a really dark time for some of us right now 🥀</p> <p>— Lucy Pyre😈🍟 (@LucyPyre_) <a href="https://twitter.com/LucyPyre_/status/2027126036316721236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:k5vv2loluc7klepjq3ccd7ad/app.bsky.feed.post/3mfs3qb4tks2a" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreihpu2iizjcpswgl3w3442jsyiwdwvhzzt4izounczpd6q7e2ewfzq"> <p lang="en">The announcement that Clint can be romanced now in Stardew has destroyed me</p> <p>The wizard, the actual cool sexy fat option, WAS RIGHT THERE. Could have opened up some new fun storylines too.</p> <p>At least we have Sandy but grubs….I'm gonna need a moment to pour one out for the wizard</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:k5vv2loluc7klepjq3ccd7ad?ref_src=embed">BigNoseBug 👃🎡 (@bignosebug.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:k5vv2loluc7klepjq3ccd7ad/post/3mfs3qb4tks2a?ref_src=embed">2026-02-26T21:01:24.860Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p><span>In the game, Clint can be spotted in Emily’s bushes, writing incel-coded notes to her that he never sends, and asking the player to deliver gifts to her because he’s too much of a </span><a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Pick+me+boy"><span>pick me boy</span></a><span> to do it himself. He’s the kind of guy whose self-pitying desire nobody wants to be the object of. So, understandably, the internet is up in arms over the announcement that he can now be married.</span></p> <p><span>Of course, some players out there want to fix him, and to them I say good luck.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-clint-marriage-1-7-update-2000674574]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Sapphire And Ruby ROM Support Found In FireRed/LeafGreen Switch Files, Dataminer Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-saphire-ruby-emerald-switch-2-datamine-2000674544</link>
            <guid>1449139</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The Nintendo Switch ports of </span><i><span>Pokémon FireRed</span></i><span> and <em>LeafGreen</em></span><span> have officially been out for just a few hours, which may as well be a few months as far as dataminers are concerned. In the past two hours alone, the internet has been doing its best to speedrun all of the secrets hidden within the ROMs for </span><i><span>FireRed </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>LeafGreen</span></i><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p>That includes t<span>he saddening news that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-firered-leafgreen-nickname-rival-censorship-2000674512"><span>profanity is now banned</span></a><span> when naming your in-game character/rival and, according </span><a href="https://x.com/_Gon_z/status/2027423326285750594"><span>to one player</span></a><span> who has somehow already made it to the end of the game, the inclusion of the Aurora Ticket and Mystic Ticket limited-time distribution items. You can shiny-hunt Deoxys, but you can no longer call your arch-nemesis ASSCLOWN. Nintendo giveth, and Nintendo taketh away.</span></p>

 <p><span>However, the most interesting revelation, according to a dataminer by the name of <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/2027442636810838416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E2027442636810838416%7Ctwgr%5Ee6838a986b66fc7a54c129f59ae6b3f7529b29fd%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fkotaku.com%2Fwp%2Fwp-admin%2Fpost.php%3Fpost%3D2000674544action%3Dedit">Yakumono/LuigiBlood</a>, is that the emulator used to boot </span><i><span>Pokémon FireRed</span></i><span> and <em>LeafGreen</em></span><span> reportedly </span><span>supports ROMs</span><span> for </span><i><span>Pokémon Sapphire</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Ruby</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Emerald </span></i><span>as well</span><span>. That would hint at possible plans for Nintendo to bring more classic Pokémon games from the series’ GBA days to the Switch and Switch 2 libraries.&nbsp;</span></p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">According to a dataminer, the Pokémon FireRed and LeafGreen releases from today internally also have compatibility for Ruby, Sapphire and Emerald, meaning those could be coming in the future. <a href="https://t.co/MvdB0sJS7N">pic.twitter.com/MvdB0sJS7N</a></p> <p>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/2027442636810838416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 27, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/luigiblood.bsky.social/post/3mfu5wabxac2t">In a post on Bluesky</a>, LuigiBlood stated that they’d uncovered a few interesting tidbits about the new GBA Switch ports, including that the emulator in question is Sloop, <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-online-game-boy-advance-emulator-leak-p-1848809116">the same emulator Nintendo uses for the Game Boy Advance games</a> featured in the Nintendo Classics library, and that the ROMs have been “heavily modified and rebuilt.”</span></p>

 <p><span>Of course, that’s small potatoes compared to their biggest reported discovery. “The only other information I will put out is that the emulator explicitly recognizes ROMs of<em> Ruby</em>,<em> Sapphire</em> and <em>Emerald</em> alongside <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-firered-leafgreen-version-exclusives-switch-2-2000674027"><em>FireRed</em> and <em>LeafGreen</em></a>. I found this alongside the initialization code that is related to enabling emulator hacks for specific games.”</span></p>

 <p><span>If this is indeed correct, does this mean that ports of the third-gen </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span> games might be coming to the Nintendo Switch eShop in the near future? In a follow-up reply, LuigiBlood was quick to state that we shouldn’t be getting ahead of ourselves on that front. “What we see is a snapshot of current code at the moment it was built. It’s not an oracle. Maybe it means RSE is next, maybe it’s never actually happening. It just means they had intentions at one point and nothing else.”</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-saphire-ruby-emerald-switch-2-datamine-2000674544]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne Remake Reportedly Shot Down By FromSoftware As Bluepoint Games Scrambled For Ideas]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bloodbrone-remake-bluepoint-fromsoftware-ps5-2000674548</link>
            <guid>1449076</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>For years, PlayStation fans have begged for a remake of<em> Bloodborne</em>. <a href="https://kotaku.com/bluepoint-sony-playstation-ps5-god-war-2000671390">Bluepoint Games</a>, the PlayStation studio behind the excellently received <em>Demon’s Souls</em> remake, seemed like the obvious candidate. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2026-02-27/sony-s-bluepoint-pitched-bloodborne-remake-before-closure?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc3MjIyMjY3OSwiZXhwIjoxNzcyODI3NDc5LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUQjRWUTJLR0NURlowMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.s6maZIveh-F152mZBWUNjPFeE0Lm7AFRegwaizQvVlA">According to <em>Bloomberg</em></a>, the first-party team actually did pitch a <em>Bloodborne</em> remake not too long ago, but FromSoftware rejected the idea.</p> <p>In fact, many at Bluepoint had assumed for a long time <a href="https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-remake-bluepoint-demons-souls-ps5-sony-playstation-2000671988">that a <em>Bloodborne</em> remake was inevitable</a>. Then in 2025, after its <em>God of War</em> multiplayer project was cancelled, Bloomberg reports that the idea of the studio fielding such a remake was formally pitched within Sony. Unfortunately, FromSoftware wasn’t onboard. While Bluepoint scrambled to come up with other ideas, including a potential <em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> spin-off, Sony never greenlit any of the other pitches.</p>

 <p><em>Bloomberg</em> doesn’t report exactly why FromSoftware rejected the pitch. The only real theory for why is one offered by former PlayStation Worldwide Studios executive Shuhei Yoshida <a href="https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-2-remake-remaster-miyazaki-sequel-1851741356">in an interview last year</a>. “I have only my personal theory to that situation,” he said in 2025. “I left first-party Sony so I don’t know what’s going on, but my theory is— because I remember Miyazaki really, really loved<em>&nbsp;Bloodborne</em>, what he created—and so I think he is interested, but he’s so successful and he’s so busy so he cannot do it himself, but he doesn’t want anyone else to touch it. So that’s my theory, and the PlayStation team respects his wish.”</p> <p>All of this suggests that a <em>Bloodborne</em> remake by FromSoftware itself could still happen at some point in the future, but that possibility is little consolation for fans who don’t want to see one of the last console generation’s best games locked away exclusively on PS4. It’s also of no use to the folks at Bluepoint who might have had their studio saved if their remake pitch had actually come together.</p>

 <p>According to <em>Bloomberg</em>, the ultimate reason for the studio’s closure was a loss of faith among the higher-ups at Sony that Bluepoint could still deliver a high-quality original game as it has once been tasked with. <a href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-multiplayer-bluepoint-days-gone-2-concord-1851742012">The <em>God of War</em> live-service project</a> it had previously been working on would have reportedly featured Atreus navigating the underworld, but shift to co-op gameplay that never came together. Sony has moved forward with a remake of the original single-player trilogy, just without its best remake studio at the helm.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bloodbrone-remake-bluepoint-fromsoftware-ps5-2000674548]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>