<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:15:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Watch Series 11 Hits an All-Time Low With a Sudden Price Drop, Making the Latest Model More Affordable]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-watch-series-11-hits-an-all-time-low-with-a-sudden-price-drop-making-the-latest-model-more-affordable-2000658553</link>
            <guid>1422895</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Apple Watch Series 11 can track your overall health and fitness goals and keep you connected. Because the display is rectangular and can show very bright images, time, stats, and notifications will remain viewable even as you move around in bright light throughout the day. It is also waterproof to 50 meters and has a dust-resistant rating of IP6X, making it durable and able to withstand the elements.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6995/">You can purchase the Apple Watch Series 11 today at Amazon for $299. This is $100 off the original price of $399, representing a 25% discount.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6995/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A showstopper of a smartwatch for a low price</h2>
<p>The Apple Watch Series 11’s Always-On Retina Display lets users see the time and any other chosen complication or calendar event by simply glancing down at the watch. The glass on the aluminum model has been improved to be twice as scratch-resistant as on the Series 10. Additionally, because the watch has a 50-meter swim-proof rating and is also IP6X dust-resistant, users can wear it in everyday situations and still have confidence in its ability to perform under various environmental conditions.</p>
<p>In addition to tracking your steps and providing information about your physical activity, the watch offers a comprehensive view of your body’s activity. You can use the watch to take an electrocardiogram (ECG), measure your blood oxygen level, and monitor your heart rate using both an electrical heart sensor and a third-generation optical heart sensor. The watch also provides notification alerts to inform you when your heart rate is abnormally high or low, or when it detects irregular heartbeats, potential sleep apnea, or hypertension, as well as the opportunity to review how you slept each night using the built-in Sleep app, along with the sleep score and sleep stage views. Additional apps for Medication, Mindfulness, and Noise provide tools to help you track habits, moods, and exposure to loud environments.</p>



<p>The Apple Watch Series 11 offers multiple options for fitness tracking, including walking, running, cycling, gym sessions, and more. With the watch, you can view detailed metrics for distance, heart rate, and pace for each of these activities. Heart Rate Zones and Training Load Estimates will help you determine how hard you worked out, and other features, such as Pacer and Workout Buddy, which use your nearby iPhone, will provide structure and support for runs and other workouts.</p>
<p>Additional safety and connectivity features make this watch feel like a trusted partner in addition to being a tracker and fitness device. The watch includes Fall Detection and Crash Detection technologies that will detect a severe fall or serious auto accident and help connect you to emergency services if you are unable to respond. Emergency SOS and International Emergency Calling provide you with direct access to emergency services. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6995/">If the Apple Watch Series 11 sounds like the watch for you, now’s the time to buy, as it’s available for $299, down from $399.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6995/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-watch-series-11-hits-an-all-time-low-with-a-sudden-price-drop-making-the-latest-model-more-affordable-2000658553]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS 34″ Curved Gaming Monitor Falls Back to Its Lowest Price in Weeks to Compete With Samsung Odyssey]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-34-curved-gaming-monitor-falls-back-to-its-lowest-price-in-weeks-to-compete-with-samsung-odyssey-2000660670</link>
            <guid>1422853</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When it comes to gaming monitors, you have an overwhelming amount of options to pick from and specs to consider. Not just deciding on a brands, but also size, resolution, refresh rate—all of these factors come into play when finding what’s best for you and your budget. Though there’s one detail that’s more important than the others. How <em>curved&nbsp;</em>is it? If you’ve never worked with a curved monitor, it may just sound like a cheap gimmick, but you couldn’t be more wrong. Asus happens to have one of its curved monitors on sale right now. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6994/">The 34-inch VG34VQL1B TUF curved gaming monitor has seen a price drop at Amazon, coming down from $369 to just $289</a>. That 22% discount adds up to you being able to save a whole $80 for a limited time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6994/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="0" data-end="472">Fully Immersive Gaming</h2>
<p data-start="0" data-end="472">A curved monitor is really something you need to experience firsthand to fully appreciate its advantages. The Asus 34-inch monitor features a 1,500R curvature designed to mirror the natural curve of human vision and how we perceive our surroundings. When placed at the optimal viewing distance, this curvature delivers a level of immersion that flat monitors simply can’t replicate, filling your peripheral with what’s happening on screen.</p>
<p data-start="474" data-end="1149">The Asus curved gaming monitor supports refresh rates up to 165Hz through its two DisplayPort 1.4 connections and two HDMI 2.0 ports, while also offering compatibility with AMD FreeSync and NVIDIA GeForce Adaptive-Sync to eliminate screen tearing. With a rapid 1ms response time and a QHD 1440p resolution, the display provides sharp, smooth visuals that are well suited for a 34-inch screen. Color performance is impressive for its price range, and the variety of available ports makes it an excellent choice for both PC and console gamers.</p>


<p data-start="1151" data-end="1391" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">The display is mounted on a stand that allows for both height and tilt adjustments. This enables users to fine-tune the viewing position for maximum comfort, making it easier to enjoy longer and more extended gaming sessions without strain.</p>
<p>As a little bonus, Asus has generously thrown in a 3-month license for Adobe Creative Cloud. This software suite comes with applications like Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, and After Effects. Normally, you’d be paying in the ballpark of $70 per month for an Adobe subscription, so you can see this as a $210 value included for absolutely free. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6994/">If this is something you happened to already be planning on subscribing to and now you don’t have to pay, you can think of it as this monitor only costing you $79.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6994/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-34-curved-gaming-monitor-falls-back-to-its-lowest-price-in-weeks-to-compete-with-samsung-odyssey-2000660670]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Apple Pencil Alternative Drops 43% to a New Record Low, Compatible With iPad Pro and iPad Mini]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-apple-pencil-alternative-drops-43-to-a-new-record-low-compatible-with-ipad-pro-and-ipad-mini-2000664837</link>
            <guid>1422799</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Tablets make it incredibly easy to stay productive and entertained on the go. If you mainly use yours for creative tasks or note-taking, you can take the experience even further by investing in a Stylus Pen.</p>
<p>Apple has its own Pencil, but like most products from the brand, these don’t come in cheap, with the latest options sitting over $100. If you’re not keen on spending that much, but still want to enjoy the features and precision, there are plenty of third-party options around, available for way less. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6991/">Now is a great time to pick one, as we just spotted the Jamjake Stylus Pen going at a 43% discount at Amazon, which brings its price down to just $17.</a> This offer applies to the white option. Several other colors are discounted too, but the prices may vary.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6991/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Better Accuracy and Higher Precision</h2>
<p>This stylus pen features a 1.5mm pen tip that can easily replace your finger to execute finer instructions. You’ll enjoy higher sensitivity, an accurate signal, and a more comfortable hold, along with palm rejection technology that lets you place your hand on the screen while working. The pen offers a natural writing feeling and quick interaction with the screen, so you won’t have to press/drag it against your iPad to make work; just write or draw how you would in a regular notebook!</p>
<p>Compatibility is seriously impressive. The stylus plays nicely with iPad series 2018-2025, which includes models like the 13-inch M4 iPad Pro, 12.9-inch iPad Pro (3rd/4th/5th/6th), all generations of the 11-inch iPad Pro, iPad Air (M3, M2, 5th, 4th, 3rd generation), iPad series 6th through 11th, iPad Mini 5th, and iPad Mini 6th gen. The models it doesn’t support include iPad Pro (1st and 2nd gen), the 10.5-inch iPad Pro, 9.7-inch iPad Pro, iPad series 1st through 5th, iPad Mini 1st through 4th gen, or iPhones. It’s best to double-check compatibility before you purchase the stylus to avoid issues later.</p>



<p>The pen magnetically clicks onto the side of your iPad for easy storage and quicker access. Activating the thing is quite straightforward; simply touch the cap button to get started. As for the battery life, one full charge gets you around up to 10 hours of usage, which is more than enough to go a full day without worrying about topping it up. Even better, recharging doesn’t take forever. A quick 5-20 minute charge prepares it for the day.</p>
<p>Just note that the stylus pen does not come with a pen cap or a charging port cover. The manufacturer also suggests using a 5V2A power adapter to charge the product to maintain its efficiency.</p>
<p>All in all, if you’ve been looking for an easy way to take notes or sketch on your iPad, this stylus pen is a must-have. You can use it to write documents, doodle on the screen, paint, draw, navigate, and a lot more. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6991/">It typically sits at $30, which is already quite affordable considering all that the stylus offers, but Amazon is letting you pick it up for just $17 today.</a> It’s best to grab it as soon as you can, as we’re not expecting the offer to last long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6991/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-apple-pencil-alternative-drops-43-to-a-new-record-low-compatible-with-ipad-pro-and-ipad-mini-2000664837]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devs Behind Steam Game With Over 300,000 Reviews Hit The Panic Button After A Malicious Mod Starts Deleting Fans’ Data]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/people-playground-steam-mod-workshop-virus-2000665028</link>
            <guid>1422793</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The<span> creators of </span><i><span>People Playground</span></i><span>, a lo-fi, cartoonishly gory sandbox with over 300,000 Steam reviews, have warned players to update the game immediately and delete all of their mods after a “malicious add-on” began infecting other mods in the game’s Steam Workshop.</span></p> <p><span>The “</span><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1118200/view/534373847137256681"><span>Urgent PSA</span></a><span>” was posted to </span><i><span>People Playground’</span></i><span>s </span><span>official Steam News Hub on February 1, with a patch for the game following hours later. All Workshop functions, mods, and access to the Workshop page for the game were immediately disabled, but not before the malware claimed its first victims.</span></p>

 <p><span>Several users in the comments of the Steam post report that all of their</span><i><span> People Playground’s</span></i><span> achievements, save files, and Contraptions folders (a separate save file for custom creations) have been wiped. According to the devs, the virus in question “does not destroy your computer,” but instead aims to disable or otherwise destroy certain aspects of </span><i><span>People Playground’s </span></i><span>functionality.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Users who have downloaded any mods from the game’s Workshop are being urged to wipe their entire mod lists, even if they didn’t download the malicious mod in question. This is because the add-on “replaces [mods] with itself,” and has reportedly supplanted several other mods in </span><i><span>People Playground</span></i><span>’s </span><span>workshop.</span></p>

 <p><span>The malicious mod also somehow made its way into </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pcmasterrace/comments/1qtdmac/comment/o326x09/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><span>the top-rated section</span></a><span> on </span><i><span>People Playground</span></i><span>’s</span><span> workshop, which may explain how it spread to so many users in such a short space of time, considering the mod was uploaded to the Steam Workshop on January 30.</span></p>

 <p><span>This, unfortunately, isn’t the first time that a Steam Workshop mod has infected users’ games. In February 2022, several mods for </span><i><span>Cities: Skylines</span></i><span> were removed from the Steam Workshop following reports that they contained </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/cities-skylines-mods-mod-bitcoin-virus-steam-pc-trojan-1848536798"><span>keyloggers and bitcoin mining software</span></a><span>. In December 2023, the popular Workshop mod </span><i><span>Downfall </span></i><span>for </span><i><span>Slay the Spire</span></i><span> was subject to a “security breach” that infected users’ </span><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/popular-slay-the-spire-mod-downfall-was-hijacked-to-spread-malware-through-steam"><span>machines with malware</span></a><span> that attempted to steal their passwords via their web browsers.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/people-playground-steam-mod-workshop-virus-2000665028]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>