<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:29:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nothing About The Big Xbox Shakeup Makes Sense]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nothing-about-the-big-xbox-shakeup-makes-sense-2000672914</link>
            <guid>1444315</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When big news happens there’s an inevitable rush to put it in context and explain it. One approach is to take the news at face value and begin rationalizing it. Another approach is to assume there’s some hidden logic at work and unearth whatever that is. We’ve seen both of these when it comes to <a href="https://kotaku.com/phil-spencer-xbox-leaving-retirement-microsoft-2000672059">Xbox’s big leadership shakeup</a> and neither offers a completely satisfying answer to the basic question everyone’s been asking themselves a version of since Friday afternoon: what the hell?</p> <p>Phil Spencer is retiring. Sure. Makes sense. He’s been at Microsoft for 38 years. God bless him. But for it to be announced on a Friday afternoon via a series of memos and weird media “exclusives?” Odd way to put a pin in the career of one of gaming’s longest-serving and most visible executives. Not even an Official Xbox Podcast episode to break the news and offer Spencer the chance to share it in a more personal way with the millions of fans who have been following his vision for Xbox and gaming for over a decade now.</p>

 <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/883015/microsoft-xbox-new-ceo-shakeup-notepad">A report from <em>The Verge</em></a> explains some of this weirdness. The announcement was originally supposed to happen on Monday February 23 instead, but reporting from<em> IGN</em> forced Microsoft to move up its timeline. Most employees learned about the move from social media first as a result. Spencer has reportedly been planning to retire for almost a year now. Microsoft just happened to choose the end of February to pull the rip cord. Microsoft head of comms Frank Shaw <a href="https://twitter.com/fxshaw/status/1940481184649433246?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1940481184649433246%7Ctwgr%5E4a5e94428821a7740f8fb58a86617febd86490cc%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fkotaku.com%2Fphil-spencer-retire-xbox-layoffs-microsoft-sarah-bond-1851785564">shut down rumors</a> last July that Spencer was retiring “anytime soon,” calling them made-up. Was he lying then, or now?</p> <h2>A celebration cut short</h2> <p>All the stranger considering Spencer will technically still be hanging around in an advisory role through the summer to help with the transition as new Microsoft Gaming CEO Asha Sharma takes the reigns. Will he be teaching her how to get all the achievements in <em>Brotato</em>? Spencer’s public-facing role at Xbox has felt ceremonial for a while now, yet he’s bailing out before the console’s 25 year anniversary celebrations get underway?</p>

 <p>For all its stumbles and challenges in recent years, 2026 is supposed to be a victory lap for Xbox. Game Pass’ price hike was wildly unpopular but its been on a tear of great releases. Xbox console sales are tanking but people are intrigued by the PC gaming future that devices like the Xbox Ally X are pointing to. And the games, a perennial Achilles’ heel for the tech giant, are here. <em>Forza Horizon 6</em>, <em>Gears of War: E-Day</em>, the <em>Halo: Combat Evolved</em> remake, and <em>Fable</em> are making good on the company’s promise of quarterly tentpoles. They’re not exclusive, but they’re each a celebration of franchises that have defined Xbox across four console generations.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Phil Spencer tries to explain Indiana Jones coming to PS5 so soon after Xbox. </p> <p>"We run a business, it's definitely true inside of Microsoft the bar is high for us in terms of the delivery we have to give back to the company" <a href="https://t.co/U9z5MWxxAe">pic.twitter.com/U9z5MWxxAe</a></p> <p>— AmericanTruckSongs9 (@ethangach) <a href="https://twitter.com/ethangach/status/1826253543491453381?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 21, 2024</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Then there’s the curious case of why Xbox president Sarah Bond resigned on Friday. Spencer’s goodbye email was the only one to mention her. Even Xbox’s long-time third musketeer Matt Booty declined to thank her for her service to the company and the platform. Hours after the news was out, Bond shared her statement on LinkedIn. She didn’t mention Booty either.</p> <p>“This moment also presents a unique opportunity for fresh eyes and new leadership to guide the team into its next chapter,” she <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7430753683912531968/">wrote</a>. “I’ve had the privilege of spending time with Asha over the last few weeks as we’ve planned for this transition, and I’ve seen firsthand her deep commitment to our players, developers, and brand.”</p>

 <h2>A convenient scapegoat</h2> <p><em>The Verge</em> reports that Bond was seen as “tough to work with” and that some employees were “relieved that Bond is leaving Microsoft.” Curiously, it lays much of the blame for Xbox’s recent strategic blunders at the feet of Xbox’s most junior leader. “Bond had tried to push mobile and cloud over console, to reach potentially millions more Xbox customers, but the result has been a classic case of chasing tomorrow’s customers by neglecting today’s,” writes Tom Warren, though he later notes that Bond’s actions were “under Spencer’s direction.”</p> <p>I think you’d be hard pressed to find an Xbox fan anywhere who believes even for a minute that Microsoft’s multiplatform “play anywhere” pivot to cloud, PC, and mobile was a bottom-up movement spearheaded by Bond rather than a mandate incentivized from the top down as CEO Satya Nadella and CFO Amy Hood demanded <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-price-hike-game-pass-layoffs-new-console-2000638546">aggressive growth targets and strict profit margin discipline</a> following the $70 billion acquisition of Activision Blizzard. <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/papapishu.bsky.social/post/3mfkdfhaals2i">Many have noticed</a> how convenient it would be for Microsoft to pin the erosion of Xbox as a meaningful concept on someone who’s no longer at the company and her retiring boss.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Xbox president Sarah Bond responds to a question from Bloomberg's <a href="https://twitter.com/dinabass?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dinabass</a> about why Hi-Fi Rush developer Tango Gameworks was shut down. Full interview here: <a href="https://t.co/te5Trhut0Q">https://t.co/te5Trhut0Q</a> <a href="https://t.co/LGs0n9iV0t">pic.twitter.com/LGs0n9iV0t</a></p> <p>— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) <a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1788728698184540355?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 10, 2024</a></p></blockquote>  <p>It might be easier to square any of this if Microsoft’s own messaging on this moment and what it signals sounded any more coherent than the rest of the Xbox Series X/S generation. “We will recommit to our core Xbox fans and players, those who have invested with us for the past 25 years, and to the developers who build the expansive universes and experiences that are embraced by players across the world,” Sharma wrote in her introductory memo to staff and fans. She promised “a renewed commitment to Xbox starting with console which has shaped who we are.”</p>

 <p>Then just a sentence later she continued beating the “play anywhere” drum. “Gaming now lives across devices, not within the limits of any single piece of hardware,” she wrote. “As we expand across PC, mobile, and cloud, Xbox should feel seamless, instant, and worthy of the communities we serve. We will break down barriers so developers can build once and reach players everywhere without compromise.”</p> <h2>A renegade spirit for the AI age</h2> <p>No mention of other consoles like PS5 and Switch 2. Is Microsoft ending its experiment with exclusivity? “<a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-exclusives-halo-asha-sharma-microsoft-2000672587">Hear you</a>,” Sharma told an Xbox fan over the weekend when he told her to bring back console exclusivity. The new Microsoft Gaming CEO has been saying all the right things to build trust with Xbox’s core audience, but the platform has zigged and zagged so much over the last five years that no one’s going to believe words until they’re backed up by actions, and even then what will stop Microsoft from pivoting again while gaming remains a rounding error relative to its other businesses and the emerging AI market?</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-series-prices-dram-amd-ai-shortage-2000646851">Affordable hardware</a>. <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-perfect-dark-halo-gears-war-fable-ps5-1851785732">Killer games</a>. Those are the ingredients a console platform needs to thrive and flourish. Microsoft has shown time and again it’s either not committed to those two things or is unable to execute on them. Bond may have been a <a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1788728698184540355?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1788728698184540355%7Ctwgr%5E76c1407b0e4a4366c0ea5b5dff746c7d0cf8191c%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fkotaku.com%2Fxbox-game-studios-arkane-tango-gameworks-hi-fi-rush-1851470253">poor messenger</a> for the future of Xbox, but it will take more than messaging <a href="https://kotaku.com/thats-it-im-calling-it-xbox-is-dead-time-of-death-february-20-2000672114">to save Xbox</a>. And the way this entire Xbox reorg has been rolled out suggests that even the messaging will continue to be a mess.</p> <p>“I want to return to the renegade spirit that built Xbox in the first place,” Sharma wrote in her memo. One person who doesn’t believe that is an actual renegade who built the first Xbox, Seamus Blackley. “I expect that the new CEO, Asha Sharma, her job is going to be as a palliative care doctor who slides Xbox gently into the night,” he <a href="https://gamesbeat.com/what-an-xbox-founder-thinks-of-the-new-xbox-ceo-seamus-blackley-interview/">told <em>Games Beat</em></a> today. “The job of all these people is to just gently usher all of these business units into the new world of AI. That’s what you’re seeing here.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nothing-about-the-big-xbox-shakeup-makes-sense-2000672914]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Is Already Improving On Arc Raiders In One Key Area]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marathon-is-already-improving-on-arc-raiders-in-one-key-area-2000672901</link>
            <guid>1444273</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Marathon</em> has been <a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-fans-mad-marathon-bluepoint-boycott-ps5-bungie-2000672040">playing catch-up</a> to <em>Arc Raiders</em> ever since both games debuted their first player tests last year. But Bungie’s extraction shooter finally seems to have moved ahead when it comes to fair play and exploits. The development team revealed that <em>Marathon</em> will have a strict one-strike ban policy when it comes to cheating, which is more than can be said for <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-review-extraction-loot-shooter-embark-2000642198"><em>Arc Raiders</em></a>.</p> <p>“Anyone found to be cheating will be permabanned from playing <em>Marathon</em> forever, no second chances,” Bungie wrote <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/marathonsecurity">in a new blog post</a> previewing the multiplayer shooter’s upcoming server slam on February 26. The rest of the post lays out the different features and systems <em>Marathon</em> uses to maintain network security and limit the kinds of exploits that could be deployed during matches.</p>

 <p>Bungie boasts a “new server authority model” that automatically rejects “invalid client actions” before they can impact other players’ experiences. “This protects the gameplay experience against exploits such as teleporting, unlimited ammo, or damage manipulation,” Bungie writes. There’s also a “fog of war” that limits what map information each player has access to so that player and item locations remain safe from “wall hacks” or “ESP cheats.”</p> <p>While “client-side security upgrades,” a telemetry “backend analysis system,” and getting your loot back if your game accidentally crashes or disconnects all sound great, the proof will be in how <em>Marathon</em> performs out in the wild. <a href="https://kotaku.com/bungie-cheat-lawsuit-destiny-2-aimjunkies-aimbot-1850140970"><em>Destiny 2</em></a> players have dealt with a range of cheating epidemics over the years, and even the most determined teams and processes don’t always get the job done.</p>

 <h2><em>Arc Raiders</em> is still dogged by complaints about rampant cheating</h2> <p>But one strike and you’re out for cheaters should be reassuring to people familiar with <em>Arc Raiders</em>‘ <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-patch-cheating-out-of-bounds-embark-2000661267">current cheating issues</a>. The current extraction shooter king implemented strict permabans back in January, but only for repeat offenders. “A three strikes progressive ban system is in the process of being implemented,” read the <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/patch-notes-1-13-0">patch notes</a> at the time. “Bans will progress from 30 days, to 60 and finally a permaban for repeat offenders.”</p>

 <p>The latest exploit du jour involves players spawning their own hatches <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/arc-raiders-cheaters-are-now-spawning-their-own-hatches-to-escape-death-and-players-are-once-again-begging-embark-to-punish-cheating-more-the-fact-people-can-do-this-is-insane/">to escape death</a>. “I’ve seen mod menus and all sorts of hacks in games before but for some reason this is the most ridiculous shit to me,” says&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1ravr41/how_are_the_people_not_getting_perma_bans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-id="inline-link" data-url="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1ravr41/how_are_the_people_not_getting_perma_bans/" data-hl-processed="none" data-mrf-recirculation="inline-link" data-hawk-tracked="hawklinks" data-mrf-link="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1ravr41/how_are_the_people_not_getting_perma_bans/">one commenter</a> on Reddit. Fans have been begging for better exploit detection and harsher penalties for perpetrators, but so far<em> Arc Raiders</em> has been taking a concerted but more cautious approach to weeding out cheaters.</p> <p>The game’s also suffered from a range of <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-dup-glitch-hotfix-patch-1-15-2000667320">duplication glitches</a>, which is bad when a scarcity of resources is a key mechanic in your game. <em>Marathon</em> is preparing for that potential challenge as well. “We take your investment of time seriously,” Bungie wrote. “We will strive to keep your progress safe and protected from item duplication or other economic cheats.” While that may be true,<em> Marathon</em>‘s first duplication glitch feels less like a matter of if than when.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marathon-is-already-improving-on-arc-raiders-in-one-key-area-2000672901]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yet Another Live-Service Game Is Shutting Down And Refunding Players]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/yet-another-live-service-game-is-shutting-down-and-refunding-players-2000672900</link>
            <guid>1444246</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Online-only live-service co-op game <em>King of Meat</em> launched last fall. About four months later, the game announced that its servers would be shutting off in April. This has become a very familiar story in the game industry.</p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/king-meat-glowmade-layoffs-keighley-mrbeast-trailer-2000651722"><em>King of Meat</em></a> launched on October 31, 2025, and cost $30. In the lead-up to the launch of the Amazon-published game, it got a flashy (and likely very expensive) <a href="https://youtu.be/iT5ilwECdrA?t=3000">animated trailer</a> at Gamescom Opening Night Live in August 2024. There was even a (also likely expensive) promotional video from MrBeast featuring content creators playing <em>King of Meat</em> in a big tournament. Reportedly, leadership at Glowmade, the studio behind the game, was aiming for around 100,000 concurrent players on Steam at launch. It never exceeded more than <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1926980/charts/">400</a> according to SteamDB and never cracked 1,000 across consoles and PC. Shocking nobody, layoffs were planned in late December. Now, the game is shutting down.</p>  <p><a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/1926980/announcements/detail/527620350145462992/">On February 23,&nbsp; Amazon announced</a> that <em>King of Meat</em>‘s servers will shut off for good on April 9, 2026 in a post titled “The Future of <em>King of Meat.”</em></p>

 <p><wbr>“Despite the creativity and innovation Glowmade brought to <em>King of Meat,</em> the game has unfortunately not found the audience we hoped for,” said the post. “As a result, we have made the difficult decision to conclude our investment in the game, and <em>King of Mea</em>t’s servers will close on April 9, 2026. Players will be able to access and play all existing content until then, so we encourage you to enjoy your remaining time in the game with your fellow Contenders.”</p> <p>All players who purchased <em>King of Meat</em> will receive a full refund “in the coming weeks,” according to the post announcing the game’s demise.</p> <p><wbr>“We want to sincerely thank every player who supported <em>King of Meat</em> and the wonderful community that formed around it,” said Amazon. “Your enthusiasm, imagination, and feedback have meant the world to us and to the team at Glowmade. We’re grateful for Glowmade’s partnership and passion throughout this journey and wish them continued success in the future.”</p> <h2>Stop trying to force people to play more live-service games</h2> <p>This is far from the first live-service game that’s announced a shutdown over the last few years. In fact, the odds are high that if a studio launches an online-only live-service game, it will be dead in about a year or less nowadays. We <a href="https://kotaku.com/concord-shutting-down-closing-servers-refunds-ps5-1851638566">famously saw that with <em>Concord</em> in 2024,</a> which was such a disastrous launch that it died in less than two weeks and torpedoed Sony’s ongoing live-service game efforts, likely leading to canceled projects and studio closures as PlayStation reevaluated its strategy. <a href="https://kotaku.com/sonys-new-live-service-game-is-coming-at-just-the-worst-possible-time-2000666078">It hasn’t given up entirely, though.</a></p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/sonys-ps5-era-studio-acquisition-spree-has-been-a-disaster-2000671404">But Sony isn’t alone in its desperate, messy push for forever games that can print money</a>. Amazon is shutting down its once-popular MMO <em>New World</em>, and before that, killed online shooter <em>Crucible</em>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/troubled-amazon-shooter-crucible-is-shutting-down-1845330651">a game that I can almost bet nobody remembers in 2026</a>. You could make a pretty long list of all the live-service and other online games that have died in recent years. <a href="https://kotaku.com/dead-games-2023-delisted-servers-offline-1850083031">Actually, we have done that.</a> It just keeps happening. And yet, publishers keep investing a lot of money and resources into chasing <em>Fortnite</em> and other live-service hits, despite being surrounded by a graveyard of past attempts. <a href="https://kotaku.com/most-playstation-5-owners-have-been-playing-the-same-games-since-2022-2000672009">And the few big winners there are these days came out years ago, and everyone is still playing them.</a></p>

 <p>Hopefully, the folks at Glowmade can bounce back, along with all other affected devs, and the industry stops trying to make 500 more live-service games nobody clearly wants. Yes, <em>Helldivers 2</em> succeeded. There are rare exceptions, sure. But odds are your in-development live-service project won’t be so lucky.<wbr><wbr></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/yet-another-live-service-game-is-shutting-down-and-refunding-players-2000672900]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>