<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:16:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ Hits Clearance-Level Pricing Ahead of New S11 Tablet Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-hits-clearance-level-pricing-ahead-of-new-s11-tablet-launch-2000622426</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-hits-clearance-level-pricing-ahead-of-new-s11-tablet-launch.1287495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>September is here and even though we still technically have a few more weeks of summer, culturally, it’s over. That’s because all the kiddos are headed back to the classroom to kick of the new school year. And with that comes tons of back-to-school sales.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/"> The Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ tablet which usually goes for $220 dropped by 30%.</a> That saves you $65, bringing the price down to just $155 for a limited time. You’re getting an 11-inch touch display for under $200.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Great Look and Sound</h2>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ is packing an LCD screen that has a resolution of 1200p with a refresh rate of 90 Hz. The built-in speakers supply a powerful and rich sound you can hear clearly with the help of Dolby Atmos. You’re getting cinema-like sound in the palm of your hands. Alright, you and I both know a tablet isn’t producing “cinema-quality” audio. Those are Samsung’s words and even though that “like” is doing a lot of heavy lifting, it’s still quite relatively speaking when talking about tablets.</p>
<h2>Portability</h2>
<p>At 11 inches across, the tablet is light and slim in design, yet remains durable. That makes it wonderfully portable so you can take it with you when traveling on long weekend trips, or just with you to your local coffee shop to get some work done or enjoy some reading with a change of scenery.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/">You have two choices or storage capacities.</a> To no one’s surprised, the less expensive model of the two is the lower capacity 64GB model. You have an option for twice that with 128GB. Storage is good for if you find yourself downloading a bunch of movies and shows, though if you’re just streaming everything anyway, the 64GB model will be perfectly suffice.</p>



<p>The Samsung Galaxy Tab A9+ is running Android OS which can actually have multiple apps open side-by-side at once. You can switch back and forth between different tasks or have two more tabs open next to each other for easy viewing.</p>
<p>Moving files to and from the Tab A9+ is pretty simple. Quick Share allows you to just select a file and transfer it immediately to a nearby device. That even works for phones and tablets running something other than Android OS.</p>
<p>The Samsung Kids app makes this tablet a great choice for parents who might be sharing the tablet with their children. Not every kid needs their own dedicated smart device and the Kids app is filled with a bunch of playful content appropriate for kids.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3880/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-galaxy-tab-a9-hits-clearance-level-pricing-ahead-of-new-s11-tablet-launch-2000622426]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0 Hands-On: Way More Than Just A Mobile Game Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-0-demo-hands-on-impressions-jrpg-2000622687</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/octopath-traveler-0-hands-on-way-more-than-just-a-mobile-game-remake.1287462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I can’t say I expected <a href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-0-trailer-release-date-switch-2-1851787423">much from <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em></a>. I’ve long admired the HD-2D role-playing game series but each new entry eventually leaves me cold. All of the pieces are there but they don’t solidify into an experience that’s more than the sum of its grindy, retro-infused parts. So I was surprised by just how much I immediately clicked with Square Enix’s latest tribute to the genre’s pixel art golden age.</p> <p>It probably helped that the demo I played last weekend at PAX West pushed me right to the brink of failure in a tough boss fight I ultimately only survived after all of my healing items were depleted and only one party member was still barely left standing. Some fans have worried about <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> being based on a mobile game that came out several years ago called <em>Champions of the Continent</em>. While Square Enix <a href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-0-gacha-champions-continent-remake-1851787459">already confirmed the gacha gameplay elements</a> have been stripped out from this remake (the story has also been reworked), I can confirm, based on what I played at least, that <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> doesn’t feel like an obviously <em>lesser</em> entry in the series.</p> <p>My roughly 30 minutes with <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> was what anyone familiar with the old-school, turn-based RPG series would expect: I ran around town, fought enemies in a desert, and eventually made my way through a brief, cavernous dungeon peppered with treasure chests and dead ends to the boss fight within. The HD pixel art with soft focus backgrounds is still pretty and effective nostalgia bait, and the music in the section of the game I got to play was exceptional.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000622694" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000622694"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000622694">Square Enix</figcaption></figure> <p>But my demo did highlight two of the main features that set <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em><em>&nbsp;</em>apart from its predecessors. The first is a settlement sim mini-game in which you get to rebuild a town burned down at the start of the game from scratch. This includes both structures that impact aspects of your recovery efforts and the village’s development, like how many villagers come to live with you and the kinds of resources they harvest, as well as purely cosmetic features like cobblestone roads, trees, and benches.</p> <p>You gather materials out in the world and build stuff by placing objects on a square grid. While I didn’t get much time to play around with how these systems interact with one another over time, it’s easy to see how the settlement sim elements offer another avenue of satisfying progression that will directly benefit the rest of your party on your travels. Combined with all of the characters you’re meeting and collecting on your adventure, it all feels <a href="https://kotaku.com/suikoden-1-2-hd-collection-review-rpg-features-ps1-1851767870">a bit <em>Suikoden</em>-coded</a> in the best way.</p>

 <p>Speaking of parties, <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> lets you wander the world with eight instead of just four. During combat, half are relegated to a back row while the rest take turns attacking on the frontlines. Whenever it’s someone’s turn you can swap them with their buddy in the back if you need to take advantage of a different skill to exploit an enemy’s weakness or increase survivability for an upcoming onslaught. Even though they don’t get to act from the back row, these members of your party still boost the squad with free health restoration, skill points, and Boost Points at regular intervals.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000622695" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000622695"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000622695">Square Enix / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The result is combat that feels a lot busier but also more dynamic. Maybe someone in the back row has full BP so you swap them in to unleash a super attack and stun an opponent. Or you need the dancer to come out and buff the team before swapping her out with the spear guy who can target the enemy’s weakness. It speeds combat up and also creates a satisfying second layer of party management. For me it hit a sweet spot that the level of in-combat decision making in other <em>Octopath Traveler</em> games hasn’t always managed to.</p> <p>Out December 4 on PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, and PC, <em>Octopath Traveler 0</em> seemed like a stop-gap release aimed squarely at existing hardcore fans while they wait for Square Enix’s Team Asano to eventually deliver <em>Octopath Traveler 3</em>. But as an <em>Octopath Traveler </em>sympathizer who’s long been <a href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-ii-impressions-rpg-partitio-osvald-1850179725">on the fence about the series</a>, my hands-on time convinced me this might finally be the one to break my skepticism.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-0-demo-hands-on-impressions-jrpg-2000622687]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Might Be Making One Of Its PlayStation 5s Worse]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-playstation-5-digital-slim-storage-price-2000622679</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-might-be-making-one-of-its-playstation-5s-worse.1287459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A pair of scissors cutting a PS5.</span> © Sony / Kotaku / Gabriel Mihalcea / Unsplash
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>This console generation has been notable for many reasons, from the scarcity during a covid-era launch through to the unprecedented scale of failures and studio closures, but one aspect that’s more bizarre to see than any other is the continual <em>increase</em> in prices. Historically midway through a generation we would see prices start to drop—this time, however, we’ve only seen the cost go up. And now in an astonishing move, it’s looking like Sony might be downgrading the PlayStation 5 Digital Edition.</p> <p>While currently only affecting customers in Europe, the situation appears to be that the narrower PlayStation 5 Digital’s storage will be reduced from 1TB to 825GB, with the price remaining the same. That’s a price which, notably, has already been increased twice since launch. This is what’s being reported by billbil-kun on the French site <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/ps5-slim-numerique-chassis-e-vers-une-reduction-du-stockage-ssd-60471"><em>Dealabs</em></a>, based on information from <a href="https://kunkoku.jp/playstation5-cfi-2100-3.html">certification documents</a>&nbsp;that show the next version of the discless PS5 in Europe, the <span dir="auto">CFI-2116 model, will maintain the current €499 ($580) price, but lose 20 percent of its storage capacity. This is currently only affecting the digital PS5; the version with a disc drive is as yet unchanged.</span></p> <p>That €499 price, it should be noted, is €100 ($116) more expensive than the PS5 was at launch, after two €50 increases since 2020. In the U.S., the console has also increased in price. <a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-price-tariff-sony-pro-xbox-unit-sales-earnings-1851780593">Sony warned in May</a> that Trump’s implementation of tariffs would likely cause costs to increase, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-console-price-increase-sony-america-august-21-2000618873">last month that happened</a>. The PS5 Digital, which launched at $400, is now only available as the PS5 Slim at $500 (originally $450), though at least it still comes with a full terabyte of storage.</p>

 <p>Of course, any of this could change at any time. In previous generations, at around the four-to-five year mark in a console’s lifespan, we’d usually be seeing prices dropping on original builds, perhaps alongside a tweaked version at the original launch price. As such, it’s been weird enough to see this reversed, let alone then learning that new versions of the machines might become <em>worse</em> instead of better.</p> <p>825GB is far too little space in 2025. The PS5 Digital originally launched with that as its standard storage, before the “Slim” version replaced it in 2023 and upgraded things to 1TB. But given Sony’s software already takes up a huge chunk of the drive, that only leaves 667GB on an 825GB disc for your use. Given AAA games are routinely coming in around 150GB these days, you’re left with room for maybe four or five big titles? That’s&nbsp;<em>terrible</em>.</p> <p>But console manufacturers are clearly hurting when it comes to hardware revenue, given most are notoriously sold at cost or at a loss, and with tariff confusion and reality deeply hurting markets, there’s obviously a desire to shave costs wherever it’s possible. Putting the price of the console up a third time in five years in Europe is probably too big of an ask, so cutting corners could well be the next option. Which sucks. Big time.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sony-playstation-5-digital-slim-storage-price-2000622679]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UGREEN M4 Mac Mini Dock Drops to Peanuts, Loaded With 8TB Storage and 11 Expansion Ports]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-m4-mac-mini-dock-drops-to-peanuts-loaded-with-8tb-storage-and-11-expansion-ports-2000622408</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ugreen-m4-mac-mini-dock-drops-to-peanuts-loaded-with-8tb-storage-and-11-expansion-ports.1287399/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A Mac Mini is a wonderful choice for anyone who considers the available space atop their desk to be a valuable commodity. You can get the full experience Mac has to offer, without sacrifice what limited area you have to work with. That being said, you connectivity and compatibility options on the Mac Mini itself leave a bit to be desired. It can only support a small handful of accessories at once through its limited ports. <strong>The good news is you can expand what’s possible by attaching you Mac Mini to this dedicated Mac Mini M4 dock from UGREEN</strong>. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3879/">Plus, right now, it’s discounted by 28%. Normally going for $90, you can now get it for just $65. You’ll save $25.</a></p>
<p>This compact Apple docking station just slips right under your Mac Mini which means the footprint stays exactly the same. You won’t be giving up any extra desk room for the additional compatibility the dock will bring you. It’s been designed to fit the curvature and form of your Mac Mini exactly as to appear as one cohesive unit. Underneath are several anti-slip silicone pads which both protect the dock and keep it from getting pushed around on your desk.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3879/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Added Connectivity</h2>
<p>The M4 Mac Mini dock adds five extra USB-A ports, two of which support data speeds of 5GBps while the other three supports twice that with 10GBps. You also get three USB-C ports supporting 10GBps. They are high speed, able to hand moving large files across to a flash drive or external storage like it’s nothing. You can edit 4K video or back up your data quickly and easily.</p>
<p>The dock is powered by your Mac Mini itself which means no extra cables running back behind your desk and tacking up another outlet. By connecting the dock to the Mac Mini, you are sacrificing one USB-C port, but with three new ones you’re still netting two ports.</p>
<p>You’re not just getting more USB ports though. With the dock, you’ll now have SD and TF card compatibility through it’s two card slots. These are handy to have right there at the Mac Mini, especially for photographers and video editors.</p>



<h2>Expandable Storage</h2>
<p><strong>If your Mac Mini doesn’t have enough internal storage for your needs, the dock allows you to expand by up to 8TB</strong>. The dock has a slot underneath to add on an SSD drive with support for PCI Express, NVM Express, and M.2 NVMe (drive not included).</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3879/">For a limed time, grab yourself this UGREEN Mac Mini M4 dock for its lowest price ever of $65.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3879/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-m4-mac-mini-dock-drops-to-peanuts-loaded-with-8tb-storage-and-11-expansion-ports-2000622408]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NordVPN Is Almost Free: Here’s the Trick to Slash the Price by Nearly 80%]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nordvpn-is-almost-free-heres-the-trick-to-slash-the-price-by-nearly-80-2000622672</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nordvpn-is-almost-free-here%E2%80%99s-the-trick-to-slash-the-price-by-nearly-80.1287396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>In a world where (almost) everything exists online, it’s more important than ever to keep your privacy secure: That’s where a VPN (or <em>Virtual Private Network</em>) comes in. <strong>It’s your own personal internet bodyguard</strong>: It keeps your data under lock and key and your online behavior hidden from hackers, trackers and even your internet company. Of all the VPNs available, NordVPN is the world’s top service.</p> <p>NordVPN has a few very cheap plans that are really good: The <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3712/"><em>Basic</em> plan only costs around $3.09 per month (down from $11,59 per month) if you subscribe for two years</a>. f you want something with a bit more bells and whistles, the Plus package is the most popular choice: It’s <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3712/">about $3.99 monthly (down from $14.99) with the same two-year subscription</a> and comes with some handy add-ons that are nice to have if you want to get the most out of your VPN experience. Both of them are <strong>73% off the original price</strong> right now.</p> <p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3712/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See NordVPN</a></p> <h2>Safe and Secure Connection</h2> <p>NordVPN <strong>makes your connection very safe with military-grade encryption</strong>&nbsp;so your data is encrypted and no one can view it. And <strong>they don’t keep logs</strong> so your browsing history stays just that – yours, and not on their servers or tracked. If you require an extra level of protection, NordVPN offers a Double VPN feature that routes your connection through two servers for double encryption.</p>

 <p>The Plus plan adds even more protection in its Threat Protection Pro (similar to an antivirus software) which prevents annoying ads, trackers and malware that slow you down or invade your privacy. It also has NordPass which is a decent password manager (<a href="https://gizmodo.com/best-password-managers" target="_blank" rel="false noopener">check out Gizmodo’s list here</a>) that helps you store and keep your passwords safe so you don’t have to remember them. And if you worry about how many devices you can protect, <strong>NordVPN’s got you set with up to 10 simultaneous connections</strong>.</p> <p>Speed also matters when you go for a VPN, isn’t it? With <strong>over 7,000 servers spread across more than 120 sites worldwide</strong>, NordVPN gives you fast and reliable connectivity wherever you go. This makes streaming and gaming smooth and uninterrupted. You will not need to suffer from lags or buffering.</p>

 <p>If you’re still not convinced, no problem: <span><strong>NordVPN has a 30-day money-back guarantee</strong></span>. Try it, test it out with no obligation. If you don’t enjoy it, simply get your money back.</p> <p>And if you want to save even more or be able to customize your protection, NordVPN has other options too—from Basic to Complete and Prime—that give you options with additional features like encrypted cloud storage and identity theft protection. But in the end, for great privacy and security at a cost that won’t hurt the budget, NordVPN’s Basic (and Plus) plan is where it’s at.</p> <p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3712/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See NordVPN</a></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nordvpn-is-almost-free-heres-the-trick-to-slash-the-price-by-nearly-80-2000622672]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HP Clears Out Its 14″ Laptop Bundle at Over 80% Off, Even Cheaper Than an Entry-Level Apple iPad]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hp-clears-out-its-14%e2%80%b3-laptop-bundle-at-over-80-off-even-cheaper-than-an-entry-level-apple-ipad-2000622471</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hp-clears-out-its-14%E2%80%B3-laptop-bundle-at-over-80-off-even-cheaper-than-an-entry-level-apple-ipad.1287372/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Summer is over. Sorry, folks. September is here, and even though the season doesn’t technically end until September 22, you and I both know that date is meaningless. Once August ends, I’m swapping my tank tops for flannels, drinking pumpkin spice lattes, and rewatching <em>Over the Garden Wall</em> again. And with summer ending, school is starting—a great time to save on a bunch of tech stuff with all the back-to-school sales. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3877/">Take this student laptop for instance. Normally priced at $1,400, this has dropped by 81%. That brings it under $300 to just $260 for a limited time.</a></p>
<p><strong>This student-ready laptop is working with a powerful Intel N150 processor with an integrated graphics card</strong>. This thing won’t be playing <em>Elden Ring: Nightreign</em> with ultra-high settings or anything, but it’s perfectly capable of taking care of basic everyday task a student might need. Things like browsing the web, sending emails, drafting up essays, or building slideshows will be easy-peasy. It comes pre-installed with Window 11 Home.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3877/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
<p>The laptop’s got 4GB of RAM with 128GB of internal storage. However, it does come with <strong>an extra 128GB in the form of a microSDXC card</strong> generously included. That’s 256GB of workable space.</p>

<h2>Microsoft Office 365 Included</h2>
<p>You also get a full year subscription to <a href="https://gizmodo.com/download/microsoft-365">Microsoft 365</a>. That includes access to Word, PowerPoint, Excel, and more. Plus with OneDrive, you can get even more storage on the cloud which you’ll be able to access anywhere from your other devices. Forgot to submit your paper, but you’re sitting in class with your laptop back in the dorm? Not a problem. Just pull it up on your phone and send it away.</p>
<p>The anti-glare display stretches across at 14 inches and is capable of a resolution of 1366 x 768 pixels. You can expand onto a second monitor over either USB-C or HDMI which can support resolutions of up to 4K at 60Hz. In addition to those ports, you get two USB-A ports and an audio jack.</p>



<p>Collaboration is easy with the built-in mic and HD 720p web camera which can record crisp and clear videos.</p>
<p>With a long battery life of up to 11 hours on a single charge, you can keep it running all day. You won’t need to bring your charger with your when taking your laptop out to all your classes for the day.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3877/">For a limited time, you can save 81% on the HP 14 student laptop</a>. The price is down to just $260 for back-to-school season and it even comes with a year of Microsoft Office 365.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3877/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hp-clears-out-its-14%e2%80%b3-laptop-bundle-at-over-80-off-even-cheaper-than-an-entry-level-apple-ipad-2000622471]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>