<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:27:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Only One Pokémon Is Catchable In Every Game Now, And It’s Not Pikachu]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-magikarp-catchable-every-game-pikachu-2000638877</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/only-one-pok%C3%A9mon-is-catchable-in-every-game-now-and-it%E2%80%99s-not-pikachu.1334272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Ever since </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>stopped including every monster in every game with </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-fans-i-need-yall-to-shut-up-about-dexit-1839949110"><i><span>Sword </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Shield</span></i></a><span>, someone’s favorite probably gets left behind in each new release. Sure, they might show up in the next game or two, but there are over 1000 of these guys now, and everyone’s bound to get benched now and then. Up until last week, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/only-three-pokemon-are-catchable-in-every-game-but-not-1850461272"><span>only three Pokémon could claim to be catchable in every single RPG</span></a><span>. Now that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</span></i></a> <span>is out, two of those are off the list, leaving only one left in every game. And no, it’s not Pikachu, the electric mouse and mascot of the whole franchise.</span></p> <p><span>Magikarp is, as of this writing, the only Pokémon you can obtain normally in every </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>RPG. This means without trades, hacks, or anything outside the scope of the game. The floundering fish that evolves into one of the most fearsome monsters in the franchise has kept this streak for almost 30 years, thanks to a salesman in </span><i><span>Pokémon Black </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>White</span></i><span> who would give you the water Pokémon. </span><i><span>Black </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>White </span></i><span>was the combo breaker for almost every other Pokémon because its dex was made up almost entirely of brand new Pokémon from the Unova region, meaning Pikachu, Charizard, and many other mainstays were only available in the post-game. Psyduck and Magnemite were also catchable in </span><i><span>Black </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>White </span></i><span>through some extremely roundabout means, but they were there, too.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000638880" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000638880"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000638880">© The Pokémon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Now, however, Psyduck and Magnemite are nowhere to be found in </span><i><span>Z-A</span></i><span>. This might change with the </span><i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>DLC, as they were both reinstated to the ranks of Magikarp through </span><i><span>Sword </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Shield</span></i><span>’s DLC, but for now, there’s no sign of the headache-ridden duck or the sentient magnets, making Magikarp the reigning champ. For now, at least. Things might change in the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-leak-generation-10-wind-wave-galar-legends-mmo-2000635337"><span>Gen X games that are reportedly coming next year</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-magikarp-catchable-every-game-pikachu-2000638877]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six Soapy Hours With PowerWash Simulator 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/powerwash-simulator-2-review-futurlab-impressions-2000638850</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/six-soapy-hours-with-powerwash-simulator-2.1334221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Washing a giant teapot house.</span> © FuturLab / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>What do you expect from a sequel? That’s a question I’ve been asking myself ever since <a href="https://kotaku.com/powerwash-sim-2-trailer-release-campaign-splitscreen-1851769691">the first trailer</a> for the follow-up to 2022’s glorious&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>, which showed off a lot more of what has come before, but with slightly prettier graphics. Now that I’ve spent a good six hours playing the released version of <em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>, and having a thoroughly good time doing so, I’m still pondering the same question. Because while I’m delighted to have a whole load of new dirty buildings and vehicles to spray, I really don’t feel like I’m playing a whole new game.</p> <p>To describe 2022’s original is to describe 2025’s&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em>. It’s a game about jet-washing enormous structures that are covered in dirt and mud, with a growing variety of jets, nozzles and sprays. Your job is to remove every last speck of dirt, at which point you get paid, can buy more gear, and then move on to the next project. It should be the dumbest thing, and yet it proves outstandingly soothing, even cathartic, as you methodically make a gross thing get shiny and clean. And while I’m delighted to report <em>PW2</em> improves on the original in a bunch of different ways, what this amounts to is tweaks, streamlining the more fussy and less enjoyable aspects, and fixing the weirdness of how the first game handled soap. All very welcome, but none of it revolutionary. This is a refinement, not a step forward, and that leaves me in the peculiar position of being very happy playing the game, while still fundamentally disappointed to not have something <em>new</em>.</p>

  <p>Given that I don’t have any big new concepts to introduce, let’s get right on to talking about those improvements. First up, while the menus are still ludicrously convoluted, the very worst aspect of the first game’s store is gone: soap. In <em>PowerWash Simulator</em>, you needed to buy refills for all manner of different types of detergent for different dirty surfaces—costly refills that lasted literally seconds, and I still suspect made little to no difference at all. You could sort of convince yourself it made a brick wall clean a bit faster, but it could just as easily have been a placebo effect. Now that’s all gone, and soap is just a thing you always have. In fact, it’s a single button press to swap between your washer and your soap-sprayer, with suds collecting on dirty surfaces in a very satisfying way. It’s something that the first game should have done.</p>

 <p>Oh, and it now makes a difference. You’ll occasionally find bits of stubborn dirt, especially on glass, that won’t just spray off with water. So click, soap, click, spray, and now it’ll go. It adds a tiny extra element, and its unfussy and rewarding to do. It’s something the first game should have done.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000638868" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000638868"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000638868">© FuturLab / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Next up is a more rational use of your home base. In the first game you’d occasionally wash people’s vehicles in your own garage, and the game made play of the fact that you owned this business and building, but in the end it was only scenery. While it honestly doesn’t add anything significant, your business’s offices are really nicely used in <em>PW2</em>. They’re explorable, and you can spend your money on furniture and trinkets to decorate the space—completely pointless, but with the lovely bonus of everything you buy being utterly filthy (where are you shopping?!), and needing you to powerwash them clean first. Upstairs are your offices, including shelves covered in trinkets based on each completed job that let you return to play them again outside of story mode, and then a large map of the area from which you can choose story and bonus missions. Or you can eschew this entirely and just access the jobs from the menu as before. (But if you did, you’d miss out on playing with your three pet cats.) It’s something the first game should have done.</p>

 <p>Beyond this…um. Come on, there has to be something else…Oh! You can move the ladders and frames around more easily, and while it still seems to be using the same broken tech that has them refuse to be put down in completely legitimate places but happy to be placed so they’re clipped through walls, it’s all better to use. Those huge frames with all the steps now have ladders on the outside so you can rapidly reach the top, and there are also mechanical cherry pickers for reaching far higher. It’s all stuff the first game should have done.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000638865" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000638865"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000638865">© FuturLab / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Of course, it’s also a prettier game. Not only is everything more detailed and better lit, but there are nice effects such as little animations of splattered dirt as you clean, and both water and soap effects that make them look as though they’re flowing. They’re not though, and that’s such a damned shame, because some actual physics was my number one wish for this sequel. It’s aesthetically pleasing, but you still have nothing like water trickling down surfaces, or mud puddling at the bottom to be washed away, or any of the seemingly obvious features to add to a sequel.</p>

 <p>That was, in fact, <a href="https://kotaku.com/powerwash-simulator-2-dlc-clean-dirt-futurlab-1851773438">one of two elements I suggested a <em>PowerWash</em> sequel would definitely have to add</a>. The other, and it’s far more damning that this hasn’t improved, is the way the game either has a still very dirty surface suddenly PING! clean before you’re done washing it, or has you hunting down the single pixel of dirt on a railing before it’ll let you move on. My theory on this in the first game was that it must be based on the percentage of dirt remaining on any section—perhaps deciding a surface is clean if you’ve cleared maybe 98 percent of the dirt. So if you have a huge flat area of wall, that remaining two percent is incredibly visible and annoying when you’re not allowed to clear it, while on a tiny feature it’s a microscopic speck that’s infuriating to find. And, maddeningly, it’s exactly the same here. I don’t know how to make video games, but I still believe that changing the math from “percentage of total surface” to “percentage of total surface relative to size” cannot be an insurmountable problem.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000638866" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000638866"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000638866">© FuturLab / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>I’m incredibly aware of just how ridiculous I sound, picking apart these elements in a lighthearted game about washing playgrounds, with a storyline about some gems being stolen from a giant merman statue whose magic beam had been preventing a volcano from erupting. Not least considering that I’m thoroughly enjoying the game! But then, I’m still mostly at a loss as to how this isn’t just a giant DLC pack for the first game with some necessary UI improvements. Or as we used to say in the olden days, an expansion pack.</p> <p>So yes, please, if you were for some reason waiting for my blessing to spend your $25 on&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2</em> (or to download it from Game Pass I guess), then yes, go right ahead! Heck, $25 would be a great price for an expansion pack of this enormous size! This is very much <em>PowerWash Simulator But Slightly Better</em>, and that’s a good thing to have. It’s not a sequel though, really, is it? Is it? I don’t bloody know.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/powerwash-simulator-2-review-futurlab-impressions-2000638850]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Is Making Its In-Game Challenges A Lot Less Annoying]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-challenges-grind-injector-30-kills-change-season-one-update-ea-2000638854</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-is-making-its-in-game-challenges-a-lot-less-annoying.1334194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>EA and Battlefield Studios have some good news. Soon, you won’t have to inject yourself over and over with magic soldier juice and kill over two dozen people to unlock a spawn beacon in the recently released online FPS <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/new-battlefield-6-skin-is-causing-community-meltdown-grounded-ea-2000638294">Battlefield 6</a>.&nbsp;</em></p> <p>In <em>Battlefield 6,</em> there are numerous <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Battlefield_6_Assignments">in-game challenges</a> to complete that provide various rewards. Some of these aren’t much to write home about, like a camo skin or some extra XP. However, other rewards are extremely useful and offer powerful gadgets or gear. For example, to unlock the Assault’s spawn beacon, a device that lets others spawn in at that spot, you have to complete one of these in-game challenges. And some of these, like the aforementioned spawn beacon challenge, are a real pain in the ass. Thankfully, EA has confirmed that big changes are coming soon to alleviate some of these annoying grinds.</p>

 <p>On October 24, <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1981707319550341305">the <em>Battlefield</em> devs published a blog post</a> announcing some minor changes that have been recently made to the game and teased some bigger tweaks coming over the course of the online shooter’s first season. Among the updates is the news that many challenges will be made easier to complete starting in season one. Here are the challenges EA specifically revealed will be tweaked in the post:</p>

 <ul data-offset-key="7itjf-0-0"> <li data-block="true" data-editor="ck3kq" data-offset-key="a1edv-0-0"> <p><span data-offset-key="a1edv-0-0">Class Assignment – Assault 1 – Get 30 kills while using the Adrenaline Injector – Changing to 3 kills</span></p> </li> <li data-block="true" data-editor="ck3kq" data-offset-key="98fhh-0-0"> <p><span data-offset-key="98fhh-0-0">Class Assignment – Engineer Expert 3 – Repair Vehicles for 6,000 health in a match – Changing to 1,000 health</span></p> </li> <li data-block="true" data-editor="ck3kq" data-offset-key="92rjp-0-0"> <p><span data-offset-key="92rjp-0-0">Weapon Assignment – Deadeye 2 – Get 150 headshot kills over 200m with Sniper Rifles – Changing to 5 kills and distance requirement will be reduced, too</span></p> </li> </ul> <p>These are just the ones EA revealed. Others are being tweaked, too. And that’s great, as some of these challenges were incredibly annoying. I recently completed the Assault challenge involving the injector, and it was like pulling teeth. The injector currently sucks in <em>Battlefield 6,</em> as it doesn’t last long and takes forever to use. But the spawn beacon is a very valuable tool, so I spent time grinding for it and hated the experience. Talking to friends who play <em>BF6</em>, they have had similar issues with the challenges sucking the fun out of the game, so I think these tweaks are smart. Also, maybe EA could make the injector actually good one day in a future update? Just a thought.</p>

 <p>Beyond the challenge tweaks, the devs are also planning some changes for player movement in an effort to make the game feel more consistent, but without changing the “pace” and “core feel” of how <em>BF6</em> plays now. “These adjustments aim to deliver a smoother and more precise aiming experience, all while preserving an immersive first-person feel,” explained the devs in the update post.</p> <p>You can also expect some more fixes for weapon bloom issues, an ongoing problem in the game, and changes to lighting and brightness, which will hopefully help players who keep being blinded by the sun when stepping outside. There are also some notes in here about <em>BF6</em>‘s battle royale mode, which doesn’t officially have a release date, but <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-datamine/">rumors are swirling</a> that it will <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-first-new-map-review-season-1-blackwell-fields-eastwood-update-2000638228">drop on October 28, alongside season one.</a> We’ll see if that happens. For now, I’m just happy people won’t have to grind for that damn spawn beacon when these <em>BF6</em> season one changes start rolling out across consoles and PC later this month.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-challenges-grind-injector-30-kills-change-season-one-update-ea-2000638854]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>