<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - kotaku_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/kotaku_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for kotaku_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:34:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Pokopia: Everything We Know About The Animal Crossing-Style Life Sim]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-switch-2-multiplayer-ditto-2000660646</link>
            <guid>1408624</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>It’s the 30th anniversary of </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span> this year, and while there are probably big RPG announcements on the way, the first major game we know is coming this year is something a little bit different. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-animal-crossing-switch-2-nintendo-direct-2000625331"><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></i></a> <span>is an </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-3-0-tips-guide-2000660180"><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span>-style life sim</span></a><span> in which you help rehabilitate a desolate town into a habitat livable for Pokémon. It seems to be </span><i><span>Pokémon</span></i><span>’s play at the “cozy” genre, but it may have some dark undertones based on what we’ve seen. Here’s everything we know so far.</span></p> <h2><b>The premise</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>stars a Ditto who transforms into a human, whose form you will be able to customize. It is heavily implied that this human form is meant to embody Ditto’s trainer, who is missing as of the beginning of the game.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>They meet a graying Tangrowth called Professor Tangrowth, with whom they decide to help rebuild a desecrated town into a livable space, complete with specialized habitats to attract new Pokémon residents. Along the way, Ditto will learn new abilities that will help it cultivate its growing town, using water attacks to water plants and fire ones to cook and burn objects. Ditto can also transform into other Pokémon for traversal’s sake, turning into a Lapras to swim between areas, for instance, or a Dragonite to fly across great distances.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>As you build your plot of land back up, Pokémon will flock to it and soon you’ll have a little community of critters. They’ll come to you with requests for how to make the town better, and that will attract more Pokémon to your space. The more people that show up, the more you’ll need to build homes and other buildings to fill up the town, such as houses, Pokémon Centers, and other utilities.</span></p>

  <h2><b>New Pokémon</b></h2> <p><span>While there haven’t been any new Pokémon species announced for </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>, a few returning monsters have named variants. Peakychu is a pale-white Pikachu that has an almost ghostly aura about her. Professor Tangrowth has white vines on the top of its head as if it’s an older grass-type Pokémon, and it also wears glasses and a broken Technical Machine on its head to look like a human doctor. Mosslax is a Snorlax that has been asleep for so long it’s been wrapped in vegetation. And lastly, Smearguru is a Smeargle covered in plant splotches. As best as we can tell, these are just named characters and are still considered members of the same existing species. I would be surprised if any of them showed up in the RPGs as usable party members, though.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <h2><b>Is it post-apocalyptic?&nbsp;</b></h2> <p><span>There’s a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalypse-snorlax-pikachu-fuschia-2000644400"><span>running theory</span></a><span> that </span><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>might be set in some kind of dark, post-apocalyptic future version of the Kanto region from </span><i><span>Pokémon Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>. Professor Tangrowth says he hasn’t seen humans in a while, and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-map-kanto-region-post-apocalypse-leak-2000650529"><span>some of the areas</span></a><span> we’ve seen do seem to resemble areas from the original games. Also, each of the “new” Pokémon has some element to them that is giving post-apocalypse. Mosslax has been sleeping so long that nature is reclaiming it, Peakychu is either dead or dying, and Smearguru has seemingly been painting so much that it hasn’t had a proper shower in a while. Will the game actually explore this, or will it just be a haunting truth in the background of an otherwise cozy game? We’re not sure yet.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Multiplayer</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokopia </span></i><span>will include a cooperative multiplayer mode for up to four players, either by connecting online with multiple game owners, or using GameShare to play with a second player who doesn’t own the game. When using GameShare, the second player can play on the original Switch system, but the game will only be natively playable on Switch 2.</span></p>

 <h2><b>It’s a game-key card</b></h2> <p><span>Unfortunately, </span><i><span>Pokopia</span></i><span>’s physical copies will include </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-pokemon-pokopia-game-key-card-2000642940"><span>a game-key card</span></a><span>, which means the cartridge you put in your system won’t actually contain the game data. Instead, it will just act as a key to tell your Switch 2 to download the game onto your system through the eShop.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>But when is it coming out?</b></h2> <p><i><span>Pokémon Pokopia </span></i><span>is coming to Switch 2 on March 5.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-switch-2-multiplayer-ditto-2000660646]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Starts Handing Out Brutal Permanent Bans To Its Worst Cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-permanent-bans-cheaters-stream-sniping-2000660615</link>
            <guid>1408582</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>The word 'BANNED' across an Arc Raiders screenshot.</span> © Embark Studios / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Since the New Year, discussions about <em>Arc Raiders</em> have shifted from near-unadulterated praise (for everything but its use of AI voices) to growing concerns over the game’s cheating problem. Developer Embark has already started making moves to improve this, first removing access to the console in the PC version, and now issuing some quite surprisingly dramatic bans to those it’s catching stream-sniping.</p> <p>Things started getting heated around January 6 <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-cheaters-ninja-shroud-embark-patch-2000657708">when streamer Shroud expressed his frustration</a> during a live broadcast, uttering “What’s the point of fuckin’ playing?” as he encountered so many issues. He was joined by other big names like Ninja and Nadeshot in making it clear that if something didn’t change soon, the high-profile players were likely to move on to other games.</p>

 <p>At the same time, others were complaining that PC players were able to access the Unreal Engine console within the game and switch off various visual settings such that they could see other players with effectively supernatural vision. By January 13, Embark released a new patch that nerfed a couple of elements that were spoiling PvP, while also preventing key card spoof cheats. This followed a hotfix that removed the console from the PC build, with the explanation that it was never supposed to have been available. And this all followed an announcement on the game’s Discord that <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-devs-say-they-have-big-plans-to-stop-the-current-wave-of-cheaters-2000658425">there were longer-term plans in place</a> for addressing the wider cheating concerns.</p>

 <p>Today, it seems, Embark has begun better wielding the banhammer. According to various posts on Reddit and X, streamers have reported that those players engaging in stream sniping are finally receiving retribution, while others have been posting images of ban messages to social media.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">not even 30 minutes later and theyre banned😭 <a href="https://t.co/QxBqjMaGo5">https://t.co/QxBqjMaGo5</a> <a href="https://t.co/aY2AtwALEC">pic.twitter.com/aY2AtwALEC</a></p> <p>— aimkey (@aimkeyx) <a href="https://twitter.com/aimkeyx/status/2012139292001448355?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 16, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>And these aren’t 24-hour slaps on the wrist, either. One image of a ban posted to X by user @aimkeyx begins, “Permanently suspended,” with accompanying text reading:</p>

 <blockquote><p>“Your account has been permanently suspended for behavior that violates our code of conduct. Due to the severity of your violation, access to your account will not be restored.”</p></blockquote> <p>This is a big step up from the 30-day bans that were being issued previously.</p> <p>The few examples we’ve been able to find so far seem to focus on stream snipers. These are people who either deliberately try their luck to get into the same lobby as a streamer, or use external software to ensure they do should the streamer make the mistake of leaving the UUID for their game session visible at the bottom of the screen. While the former might seem unlikely to work often enough for a person to ensure to match up, you have to factor in that should a streamer have tens of thousands of viewers, there could be a couple of hundred people attempting to cheat this way, making the chances of <em>someone</em> managing it a lot higher. And of course once in the same lobby, they can use the livestream footage to gain an advantage over the streamer. But it does seem to suggest that Embark is taking the issue seriously.</p>

 <p>One streamer who claims to have been caught in the crossfire of all this is Tfue, who found he had a 30-day suspension from <em>Arc Raiders</em> a few days ago. Many suggested it could be because Tfue brought up the console on his stream to show how it could be exploited, although he claims he didn’t actually use it. Others made unsupported accusations about the use of various macros, which Tfue strongly denied. Eventually the Twitch streamer with 11.4 million followers had his account restored, seeming to suggest it was an error.</p>

  <p>Who knows! Tfue’s ban was clearly one of the more regular 30-day sin-binnings, rather than these new permanent exclusions. It’ll be interesting to see if things improve for streamers, and then hopefully for the wider PvP audience for the game.</p> <p>Meanwhile, can I suggest a far better way to play? This is my favorite&nbsp;<em>Arc Raiders&nbsp;</em>clip of all time:</p>  
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-permanent-bans-cheaters-stream-sniping-2000660615]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Could Learn Something From This Incredible 3D Platformer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-could-learn-something-from-this-incredible-3d-platformer-2000660289</link>
            <guid>1408543</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>One of the most important aspects for a 3D platformer to nail is making sure it feels amazing. Running around, jumping, climbing, diving, all of it should be a joy. You should be able to run and jump in a mostly empty room with no textures or music and still have a good time. And </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span>, out now on PS5, PC, and Switch, is a new 3D indie platformer that succeeds perfectly at providing a platformer that’s incredible to play while also offering up plenty of ways to experiment and explore.</span></p> <p><span>In </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span>, you play as the young, precious, and very agile Hop, a talking frog with dreams of leaving his forest to see more of the world. While out with his younger sister on a hike through the woods, which serves as the game’s short and not-annoying tutorial, Hop is summoned by a mysterious voice into a strange dimension. From there, he goes on an epic journey across three different worlds to find the pieces needed to get back home. The eight hours that followed were some of the best 3D platforming I’ve played in a long, long time.</span></p>

 <h2><b>Tongue Tied</b></h2> <p><span>Like most main characters from platforming games, Hop can, well…hop, roll, dive, climb, and eventually swim. But Hop has something special that Mario, Ratchet, and beloved icon Bubsy lack: A handy, dandy, and very long tongue. And it’s Hop’s tongue that elevates </span><i><span>Big Hops </span></i><span>from a great platformer to an all-time classic.</span></p>

 <p><span>With his trusty tongue, Hop can grapple and swing to new locations like Spider-Man. He can also use his tongue to open chests, flip levers, collect items, and even unlock doors via one of the strangest lock-picking mini-games I’ve ever seen. The tongue in </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> is implemented so well that using it just became second nature to me, as natural as jumping or running in any other game.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>That’s not to say the tongue in</span><i><span> Big Hops </span></i><span>isn’t very cool and awesome, because it is, and the developers designed a lot of clever puzzles and platforming segments that take advantage of it. But it never feels</span> <span>like a silly slapped-on gimmick or a worthless ability that you have to be reminded of via constant screen prompts.</span></p>

 <p><span>And yet, as cool a feature as it is, the devs don’t rely solely on Hop’s tongue to add variety to each of the massive semi-open worlds you explore over the course of </span><i><span>Big Hops’</span></i><span> runtime.</span></p>  <h2><b>Experimenting With Freaky Fruits</b></h2> <p><span>As you meet the locals in these places, which include pirate otters and punk rock bats, you’ll find various fruits that have all sorts of effects. One fruit, for example, when thrown against a wall, generates a rope bridge. Another fruit sets things on fire.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>My favorite special fruit is a green apple that sticks to nearly any surface and can be used to create permanent grapple points. All of these fruits offer a lot of creativity and let me pull off maneuvers that felt like cheating. Wildly,</span><i><span> Big Hops</span></i><span> lets you hold a few of these fruits in your expandable backpack, meaning you can take them to areas where maybe the developer didn’t plan on you having a fire fruit or trampoline fruit. It feels risky as heck to offer the player so much freedom, yet I’m not complaining.</span></p>

 <p><span>Combined, the fruits and tongue let me pull off some wild shit in this colorful 3D platformer. I was able to skip some sections of a level here or avoid a puzzle there using a combination of </span><i><span>Big Hops’</span></i><span> tongue swinging and fruit storing. And it’s this focus on rewarding and encouraging experimentation and exploration that really stood out to me. There were countless times in my journey to get Hop back home when I used my tongue and a fruit to get somewhere that I thought was out of bounds, but hiding up in a corner were a few coins or other small collectibles, a little hat tip from the makers of the game for trying something weird and pulling it off.</span></p> <div>           <ul>                           <li>                 <p>Back-of-the-box quote:</p>                 <p>“Hop does what Mario won’t: Licking everything useful he sees.”</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Developer</p>                 <p>Luckshot Games</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Type of game:</p>                 <p>Third-person 3D platformer</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Liked:</p>                 <p>Wonderful visuals,  awesome controls, unique tongue features, music</p>               </li>                               </ul><ul>                                         <li>                 <p>Disliked:</p>                 <p>Some performance issues, a few glitches</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Platforms:</p>                 <p>Switch, Switch 2, PC, PS5 (Played on PS5 Pro) </p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Played:</p>                 <p>Completed the main story and some side content in about 8 hours</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Release Date</p>                 <p>January 12, 2026</p>               </li>                                     </ul>         </div>  <p><span>Exploring and poking around levels is a joy in </span><i><span>Big Hops,</span></i><span> not only because the devs clearly want you to do that, but because each area and level is gorgeous, featuring cel-shaded-like visuals and crisp colors. On PS5, the game looks stunning and runs at a mostly locked 60FPS that helps the platforming feel snappy, fast, and fluid.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>The creepy, purple-tinted Void sections of the game are a standout, featuring stylish environments that twist and fold around in impossible ways. Oh, and the music is wonderful, too, evoking the same vibes as you’d expect from a classic platformer from the PS1 or N64 era.</span></p>

 <h2><b>No Fighting, Just Jumping</b></h2> <p><span>If you’re wondering what combat feels like or what kind of enemies Hop has to deal with, well, there’s none of that in </span><i><span>Big Hops.</span></i><span> Technically, there are a few bugs that will chase Hop (and many more that he can eat for a stamina boost) as well as a handful of fairly easy boss fights. But outside of that, 90 percent of </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> is combat-free and focused entirely on platforming, exploring, and puzzle-solving.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Don’t expect a relaxing or completely cozy adventure, though, as </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> has some tense and fast-paced platforming challenges, especially in the second half of the game. You just won’t have to squash 300 random enemies along the way.</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> is exactly what I want out of a modern 3D platformer. It takes advantage of what modern games can do, with massive levels, detailed graphics, and lots of well-performed voice acting, while also remembering that the main reason people play these kinds of games is to have fun hopping between platforms and obstacles, to feel the satisfaction of getting better with each level and conquering new, trickier jumping challenges.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> delivers that experience and more via a visually varied journey that rewards you for poking at the edges of each level while using the game’s brilliant tongue mechanic to find different ways to succeed. Nintendo designers should play </span><i><span>Big Hops</span></i><span> and learn some valuable lessons from this very special game.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-could-learn-something-from-this-incredible-3d-platformer-2000660289]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fans Try To Sell 2008 DS Game For Absurd Prices Thanks To Meme-Fueled Metacritic War On Clair Obscur]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/cory-house-metacritic-clair-obscur-ebay-2000660631</link>
            <guid>1408498</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The ongoing battle between </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/how-cory-in-the-house-ds-went-from-bad-forgotten-game-1842525482"><i><span>Cory in the House</span></i></a><span> and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402"><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i></a><span> to decide which will ultimately be crowned the top user-rated game on Metacritic rages on, but an unforeseen consequence of the conflict is that secondhand copies of the Nintendo DS Disney game are skyrocketing in price in online marketplaces.</span></p> <p><span>As </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-metacritic-cory-in-the-house-ds-game-2000659380"><i><span>Kotaku</span></i><span> first reported on Tuesday</span></a><span>, something strange was brewing over on Reddit: a seemingly organic campaign to get the long-memed 2008 Nintendo DS game </span><i><span>Cory in the House</span></i><span> to the top of Metacritic’s user-rated rankings, unseating 2025’s Game of the Year. </span><span>When I originally reported on the story, </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span>, the current top-ranked user-rated game on the platform, had just dipped from a 9.6 to a 9.5. </span><i><span>Cory in the House </span></i><span>had just risen from 9.3 to 9.4. The meme was about to become a reality.</span></p>

 <p><span>Since then, things have simultaneously changed drastically and also somehow stayed exactly the same. </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span> is still clinging on to a 9.5 rating, but </span><i><span>Cory in the House</span></i><span> is back down to a 9.3. </span><span>The big change is in the number of ratings on Metacritic. I made a note on the 13th that the PS5 version of</span><i><span> Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span> had roughly 23,351 ratings. Now it has 23,654 user ratings. On the other hand, </span><i><span>Cory in the House</span></i><span> had roughly 2,400 ratings on the same date. Now that’s climbed up to whopping </span><a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/disney-cory-in-the-house/"><span>4,666 user ratings</span></a><span>. Actually, never mind, I typed that and then immediately refreshed the page. Now it’s up to 4,684.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">As a result of users flooding metacritic &amp; pushing the game to the #2 spot of all time, sealed copies of Cory In The House have skyrocketed by more than 3000% in the past 2 weeks. <a href="https://t.co/nlVkLGWP0V">pic.twitter.com/nlVkLGWP0V</a></p> <p>— Resell News 💸 (@resellnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/resellnews/status/2011945080198930695?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>The point is, the focus is less on review-bombing </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span>, as some had assumed, and more on reverse review-bombing </span><i><span>Cory in the House. </span></i><span>That also probably goes some way toward explaining the recent meme-fueled price increases for physical copies of the Nintendo DS game on eBay. </span><span>The first writer to spot this story seems to have been </span><a href="https://www.cllct.com/sports-collectibles/auctions/cory-in-the-house-meme-makes-video-game-flop-a-collectible-hit"><span><em>Cllct</em>’s Will Stern</span></a><span>. They noted that a copy of the game had sold for $199 on eBay on January 14. Since then, </span><em><a href="https://x.com/resellnews/status/2011945080198930695"><span>Resell News</span></a></em><span> noticed that prices had shot up by “more than 3000% in the past 2 weeks,” with some ongoing auctions reaching bids of up to $721.00.</span></p>

 <p><span>That was yesterday. Since then, one copy has been successfully sold </span><a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/267546127693?_skw=CORY+IN+THE+HOUSE&amp;epid=64390888&amp;itmmeta=01KF3RD56M81T6JS1XE9XB80PZ&amp;hash=item3e4afded4d:g:CvsAAeSwRC1paViU&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQALAAAA8O7PUuNWmJ%2B%2BUShgI9tQz%2FquEO55lxhvWCg3RydlgHCEjp8CAiKjb84k%2Bhpis7IXfDNjpSsJ1li8nbcdWZfxEtPpMOpIG4hkef2iVA8tD08U0GU4l4bz38VxaxmAictMDfvHUoCzvEnVI8%2B1XcKPP511WDp7HWSW29hi2Fup7ym441EkvenWnUnU2yezhaayx%2BjxBJ0zK4iiiN%2BNN9n1owWWYj8qqFApNLKqgrfJQPu0Ld8qUemwhUdTED6CTrvOjZvTN6pVXavwiMRd%2B%2FtfJMwJzto%2F9t%2F%2BczNvF%2B5JA%2B6StVcgGXvL1eKwyEpCyxoxeg%3D%3D%7Ctkp%3ABk9SR87TtPj4Zg"><span>for $299.00</span></a><span>, and another has sold </span><a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/236583898515?_skw=CORY+IN+THE+HOUSE&amp;epid=64390888&amp;itmmeta=01KF3RD56KEWCW6YESX5Q57C5G&amp;hash=item37157fcd93:g:9TkAAeSw~elpaVPj&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQALAAAA8O7PUuNWmJ%2B%2BUShgI9tQz%2FqNOasvXNq3gCk8APei9x3fS8yhajrjwK3si8gT1GrJOOQXDizb1ezGucBKOMjSUpU6zsOdclyZPVSfe3neokFM0hYow6iuY9%2FzOojfGBTzdWI9YxTZSf9FRQH92RyQQcZ7mxj62QSigxwpPLC91hDAJnGkh0UDEiFnvhUcq%2F8y9MWQ1iSDqIAD6psJab16rp5s7QVOjmSepEExyTysEXnRxkDHAnLxJ4ePSQiOzoBmBswnGoT%2FkbLbXCqvj7tSLMU%2Ba2McGxQAZ5u0rhb8S0BY8fp58flcAaQtRqan9%2BYs0w%3D%3D%7Ctkp%3ABk9SR8zTtPj4Zg"><span>for $399.97</span></a><span>. One dreamer has also put a copy up for a Buy It Now price </span><a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/336392742143?_skw=CORY+IN+THE+HOUSE&amp;epid=64390888&amp;itmmeta=01KF3WK3QX15XYHPWCDK20A23M&amp;hash=item4e5291e4ff:g:OMYAAeSwhZ9pam-4&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQALAAAA8O7PUuNWmJ%2B%2BUShgI9tQz%2FrFM3fI5kOCHKqnzFCQT7P0BIRa5S7ieVZfdEI8jszgQOfgo2xl71peGJQt3dZfvsJNfG%2FsI%2FpwJSgR8hHLPdQLoBHJgyAaDRa2YfMmYEubKReFnCNmKU5LQXbXLVj8zQPBwjJQ41C7aFyQ3%2BmTc4SdlQy3oFQWVLbDB6a7tClX%2BcKzlcikn5MyMtRh5cMHmUxSgGkoJYOcstgwvwq0lLrLJEuLKuh4ryDiV4kNBeU4scb8Dpr%2FXrawmnbjqo%2BYmthgwvajGE5ziuJgooepkXHLkqhyuL2ah3BcPDqZ5QL%2F8A%3D%3D%7Ctkp%3ABk9SR5q8zPz4Zg"><span>of $1,704.83</span></a><span>, but thankfully, nobody has been stupid enough to take them up on that deal. </span><span>That $721.00 auction still hasn’t moved, but the bidding doesn’t close until January 22. It’ll be interesting to see if these prices continue to increase if and when </span><i><span>Cory in the House</span></i><span> manages to finally dethrone </span><i><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></i><span> on Metacritic. Oh, and in case you were curious, it’s up to 4,697 user reviews now.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/cory-house-metacritic-clair-obscur-ebay-2000660631]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inverse ‘Divests From Gaming’ As Owner Pivots To ‘Next Generation Influence Company’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/inverse-layoffs-gaming-bustle-digital-group-bryan-goldberg-2000660620</link>
            <guid>1408492</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The<em> Inverse</em> gaming section is dead. Three staff, including Deputy Editor Shannon Liao, were laid off from the website on Friday as it reportedly “divests from gaming.” It’s a shift that comes as owner Bustle Digital Group pivots to being an “influencer company,” whatever that is.</p> <p>Launched in 2015 by Dave Nemetz, who previously co-founded <em>Bleacher Report</em>,<em> Inverse</em> began life primarily as a tech and science website before later pivoting to entertainment and gaming. It will seemingly now only cover movies and TV as the gaming side of its masthead has been wiped out. Several staff, including Liao, shared the news on Bluesky.</p>

 <p>“After flying back from Vegas last week, I was just laid off from <em>Inverse</em> today,” she <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/shannonliao.bsky.social/post/3mcki3gpiy22o">wrote</a>. “<em>Inverse</em>‘s gaming section is being shut down as the company ‘divests’ from gaming content. I’m out of a job along with my wonderful co-writers,” <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/solfleet.bsky.social/post/3mckhymb5tk2d">wrote</a> staffer ‪Hayes Madsen. “I’ve put my heart and soul into this job for four years. Gonna need to take time to process…”</p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ck4fr6ws6nsebldvf5m72w5w/app.bsky.feed.post/3mckhymb5tk2d" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreibzdyohqg3cg4vcyg56wi3d6zg3kdubvbps2quezjittrywbbnrk4"> <p lang="en">Inverse's Gaming section is being shut down as the company "divests" from gaming content. I'm out of a job along with my wonderful co-writers. I've put my heart and soul into this job for four years. Gonna need to take time to process, but I'm now completely open for work – and boy do I need it.</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ck4fr6ws6nsebldvf5m72w5w?ref_src=embed">Hayes Madsen (@solfleet.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ck4fr6ws6nsebldvf5m72w5w/post/3mckhymb5tk2d?ref_src=embed">2026-01-16T16:03:57.663Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p><em>Kotaku</em> understands that game section staffer Trone Dowd is being kept on, but it’s unclear in what role moving forward or if it will be at all involved in covering games.</p>

 <p>Bustle Digital Group, which purchased<em> Inverse</em> in 2019, has been on a rollercoaster ride over the last 12 months. Last February, it was being <a href="https://www.curbed.com/article/bryan-goldberg-bustle-digital-media-back-rent-lawsuit.html">sued for $3 million</a> it allegedly owed in back rent.&nbsp;CEO Bryan Goldberg, who also co-founded <em>Bleacher Report</em>, <a href="https://www.adweek.com/media/bdg-targeting-record-profits/">then announced in May</a> that profits were soaring and the company’s cost-cutting era was behind it.</p>

 <p>By the fall, however, he was pitching the investor world on a new pivot. “We are the next generation influence company,” Goldberg <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/10/14/bdg-media-bustle-scary-mommy-nylon">told<em> Axios</em></a> last October. The idea was to turn style and clothing audience members into cash-generating influencers by giving them special access to brands. The whole thing still sounds really weird, but apparently 12,000 people applied. It’s basically the unpaid blogger network that <em>Bleacher Report</em> pioneered, but for Instagram.</p>

 <p><em>Update: 1/16/2026 1:09 p.m. ET: Clarified that one of Inverse Gaming’s staff members remains at the company.&nbsp;</em></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/inverse-layoffs-gaming-bustle-digital-group-bryan-goldberg-2000660620]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>