<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 05:43:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yakuza Kiwami 3 & Dark Ties Announced For Switch 2, Launching In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/yakuza-kiwami-3-and-dark-ties-announced-for-switch-2-launching-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties-announced-for-switch-2-launching-in-2026.1306182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Experience a brand-new tale in Dark Ties</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Sega isn't slowing down any time soon when it comes to the Yakuza series, and with this in mind, Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio has today announced it's bringing <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yakuza-kiwami-3-and-dark-ties">Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties</a></strong> to the Switch 2 and multiple other platforms next year.</p>
<p>During this year's RGG Summit livestream, the studio confirmed this particular entry would be arriving on <strong>12th February 2026</strong>, with pre-orders now available.</p>
<p>As mentioned in the official game description, this entry originally made its debut on the PlayStation 3 in 2009, and it's now been "reimagined with cutting-edge visuals and modern technology". It also comes with the brand-new tale, Dark Ties. Here are some more details about what you can expect:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Originally debuting on PlayStation 3 in 2009, Yakuza 3 has been reimagined with cutting-edge visuals and modern technology. This evolved edition brings Okinawa to life, featuring more intense battles, added cutscenes that bring depth to the story, and minigames chock-full of replay value. Kiryu's back in the brawl, continuing the fight to protect those he holds dear.</p>
<p>This title also includes Dark Ties, which stars Yoshitaka Mine, Kiryu's adversary. Follow Mine on his journey from working as a venture company's founder to becoming a full-fledged yakuza member. After losing everything, Mine sets off in an attempt to form a connection that would fill the void in his heart. Kazuma Kiryu and Yoshitaka Mine live in different ways.</p>
<p>Walk alongside them as their paths intersect, throwing both of their fates in the balance.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This latest <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/yakuza_kiwami">Yakuza Kiwami</a> game announcement follows the release of Yakuza Kiwami on the Switch eShop last October.</p>
<p>Since then, the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yakuza-0-directors-cut">Yakuza 0: Director's Cut</a> was released on Switch 2, and this will be followed by Yakuza Kiwami and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/yakuza-kiwami-2">Yakuza Kiwami 2</a> for the Switch 2 this November. It's also been confirmed Yakuza Kiwami 1 &amp; 2 for the Switch 2 <a href="https://x.com/gematsu/status/1970714949006827656">are getting separate physical releases</a>, but they're both Game-Key Cards.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185895,182900,173073 @ 1758689387 -->
<p>Excited for this one? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/yakuza-kiwami-3-and-dark-ties-announced-for-switch-2-launching-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Videos: Square Enix Releases New Trailers For 'Octopath Traveler 0' And 'The Adventures Of Elliot']]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/videos-square-enix-releases-new-trailers-for-octopath-traveler-0-and-the-adventures-of-elliot</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/videos-square-enix-releases-new-trailers-for-octopath-traveler-0-and-the-adventures-of-elliot.1306143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>More HD-2D RPG action is on the way</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="The Adventures of Elliot" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a2adb42427c59/the-adventures-of-elliot.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Square Enix has already released a new trailer for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</a> this week highlighting the fresh features, and now there are a few more to go with it.</p>
<p>Timed in with this year's Tokyo Game Show, Square Enix has shared another trailer for the upcoming HD-2D action RPG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/adventures-of-elliot-the-millennium-tales">The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales</a>. This game is on its way to the Switch 2, and you can try out an eShop demo now.</p>
<h3>The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales | TGS Trailer</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>"A brand-new action RPG from the creators of OCTOPATH TRAVELER and BRAVELY DEFAULT - The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales combines stunning HD-2D visuals and exciting action-adventure gameplay for the first time!"</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185951 @ 1758691165 -->
<p>Next up is an introduction to the gameplay of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0</a>. This particular outing in the HD-2D RPG series will make you the protagonist. This game will be available for the Switch and Switch 2 and is launching this December.</p>
<h3>Octopath Traveler 0 | TGS Trailer (Gameplay Introduction)</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>"Start from zero and discover the newest entry in the OCTOPATH TRAVELER series. Experience a story of restoration and retribution over the divine rings—an epic saga that unfolds across the realm of Orsterra."</p>
</blockquote>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185893 @ 1758692126 -->
<p>A <a href="https://youtu.be/1ybRc-8sywk">new battle trailer</a> for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</a> has also been released in Japan, so if we get an English trailer update, or something similar, we'll provide an update.</p>
<p>And again, Square Enix has also shared a new trailer for Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake, which is due out for the Switch and Switch 2 on 30th October 2025. You can check out the latest trailer in our previous story here on Nintendo Life:</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188278 @ 1758692126 -->
<p>Will you be playing any of these upcoming HD-2D releases on Nintendo's systems? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/videos-square-enix-releases-new-trailers-for-octopath-traveler-0-and-the-adventures-of-elliot]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza Version 2.0.1 Is Now Live On Switch 2, Here's What's Included]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/donkey-kong-bananza-version-2-0-1-is-now-live-on-switch-2-heres-whats-included</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananza-version-2-0-1-is-now-live-on-switch-2-heres-whats-included.1306086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Following the release DK Island &amp; Emerald Rush</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Donkey Kong Bananza" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/2b0310e7b40d8/donkey-kong-bananza.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Following the recent arrival of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">DK Island &amp; Emerald Rush</a>, Nintendo has now updated <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> to Version 2.0.1.</p>
<p>This follows the major 2.0.0 update earlier this month which added this paid DLC to the game and also included multiple other adjustments. This latest update fixes multiple issues tied to the previous update and also makes several other changes to improve the overall gameplay experience.</p>
<p>Once again, here's the full rundown from Nintendo's official support page:</p>
<h2>Donkey Kong Bananza: Ver. 2.0.1 (Released September 23, 2025)</h2>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p><div><figure data-videoid="fMx2XNyAq4E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d98e4isymhg&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fMx2XNyAq4E" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>834k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<ul>
<li>Fixed issue where the player could not get a disc as a reward for collecting all the balloons in Bananza Rehearsal.
<ul>
<li>If the above issue is occurring in the game in Ver. 2.0.0 or earlier, the player will be able to get the disc right after the stage starts by entering Bananza Rehearsal after downloading this update data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Fixed issue where some of Pauline’s shout voices would not play when language setting of the Nintendo Switch 2 system is “English (UK/Australia)” and travel buddy’s voice (Pauline’s voice) in “Options” has its “voice language” set to “Same as system.”</li>
<li>Several other changes have been made and issues addressed to improve the gameplay experience.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>This latest update for Donkey Kong Bananza follows an update for Mario Kart World today, which bumped the launch title up to Version 1.3.0.</p>
<p>If we hear anything else about the latest update for DK, we'll let you know. You can see the patch notes for the previous update in our story from earlier this month.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187832,187829 @ 1758692334 -->
<p>Have you tried out DK's new DLC yet? How about this new update? <em>Tell us in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68614/~/how-to-update-donkey-kong-bananza" rel="noopener" href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68614/~/how-to-update-donkey-kong-bananza">en-americas-support.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d8f93bfd137dfab7fbc2dbab3f83fef7 @ 1758691341 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/donkey-kong-bananza-version-2-0-1-is-now-live-on-switch-2-heres-whats-included]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Has Been Updated To Version 1.3.0, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-3-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-3-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes.1306083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Download this update for Switch 2</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Mario Kart World" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/196bc997ebaa5/mario-kart-world.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> has received multiple updates since it arrived in June, and now the latest one for September has been released.</p>
<p>This bumps the game up to Version 1.3.0 and makes some welcome adjustments in "Free Roam" mode, along with various other changes. This latest update also addresses some issues you may or may not have encountered.</p>
<p>Here's the full rundown, courtesy of Nintendo's official support page:</p>
<h2>Mario Kart World: Ver. 1.3.0 (Released September 23, 2025)</h2>
<p><strong>General</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>You can now join friends playing "Knockout Tour" by selecting "Friends" from "Online Play" "1p."</li>
<li>Up to 2 players can now play "Free Roam" while waiting if the game was full when trying to join friends playing "Race," "Knockout Tour" or "Battle" in "Online Play."</li>
<li>The "Free Roam" map now displays the locations of P Switches you've run over and Peach Medallions you've obtained.
<ul>
<li>You can now select a P Switch from the map and move to a location near the P Switch.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In "Free Roam", you can now transform into the character pulled into the UFO.
<ul>
<li>If "Dash Food" in "Settings/Controller" is set to "Doesn’t transform" then you will not transform.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>It is now easier to encounter UFOs in "Free Roam."</li>
<li>The conditions for the appearance of some Peach Medallions in "Free Roam" have been adjusted.</li>
<li>When spectating in "Knockout Tour" or "Balloon Battle" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play", you can now choose who to watch, even if you are holding the Joy-Con 2 or Joy-Con horizontally.</li>
<li>Decreased the time between when an item box is taken by someone and the next time it is revived.</li>
<li>Increased the invincible time after spinning or crashing during a race.</li>
<li>Reduced the force of jumps when landing on a rival from above.</li>
<li>Decreased the amount of time between when you finish and when spectating begins in "Knockout Tour" or "Balloon Battle" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play."</li>
<li>Decreased the amount of time between passing through the checkpoint and when the ranking is displayed in "Knockout Tour" in "Wireless Play" and "LAN Play."</li>
<li>Further increased the frequency of lap-type courses appearing in the selection when choosing the next course in "VS Race" and wireless races.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Online Play" and "Wireless Play" where the ranking would sometimes become incorrect if a player went off course at the same time as reaching the finish line.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Grand Prix", "Knockout Tour", and "VS Race", where the CPU's ranking would sometimes drop after reaching the finish line.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Knockout Tour" in "Online Play" where other players' ratings would sometimes appear as "0" on the results screen.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Spiny Shell would sometimes pass the first place player in "Wireless Play" or "Online Play."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where players would sometimes be sent flying backwards a great distance when hit by a Spiny Shell.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the second item in an item slot would sometimes not disappear when hit by Lightning.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where hitting the base of a pillar in mid-air would sometimes cause a large jump.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that sometimes caused movement to become unstable when doing a wall ride on water.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where players would sometimes be swept away strongly after landing when doing a mini jump while going up a river.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where players would sometimes pass through the ground when hit by a car driving on the road.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Free Roam" where players would sometimes be unable to enter pipes correctly after exiting a trailer.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the results screen would sometimes become distorted after spectating "Balloon Battle" in "Online Play."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the game would sometimes not proceed to the course selection screen after exiting a pipe during "Free Roam" in "Online Play."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Bullet Bill would sometimes slip through walls when used in "Sky-High Sundae."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where players would sometimes get stuck on a wall at the start of the race heading from "Airship Fortress" to "Shy Guy Bazaar."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where players would sometimes get stuck in walls when using a Bullet Bill in "Bowser’s Castle."</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Cheep Cheep Falls" where item boxes were sometimes difficult to pick up when Smart Steering was turned on.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in "Knockout Tour" "Spiny Rally" where sometimes there was an item box buried in the ground.</li>
<li>Several other issues have been addressed to improve the gameplay experience.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>If there is anything else discovered about this latest update, we'll let you know. The previous update was released in August and fixed some small issues. You can find out more about it in our previous patch notes story here on Nintendo Life.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186706,182523 @ 1758691129 -->
<p>Have you updated your copy of Mario Kart World to this latest version? Notice anything else? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world" rel="noopener" href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world">en-americas-support.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/3e5b133501685c0a2330646cb7ca4830 @ 1758691753 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/mario-kart-world-has-been-updated-to-version-1-3-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Has Been Delayed For Switch 2, Digital Pre-Orders Cancelled]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/borderlands-4-has-been-delayed-for-switch-2-digital-pre-orders-cancelled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-has-been-delayed-for-switch-2-digital-pre-orders-cancelled.1306050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"We do not take this decision lightly"</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Borderlands 4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/33679294a9ba7/borderlands-4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games, Gearbox Software</em></figcaption></figure><p>If you've been looking forward to diving into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> next month on the Switch 2, we're sorry to say, but it's been delayed.</p>
<p>2K Games and Gearbox Software confirmed this <a href="https://x.com/Borderlands/status/1970609156936868102">on social media today</a>, mentioning how the team does not take this decision lightly. The aim is to deliver the "best possible experience", so this version needs more development time.</p>
<p>While a new launch date for Switch 2 hasn't been revealed just yet, the aim is to line it up with the addition of cross saves, which are currently in the works. In accordance with Nintendo's policy, digital pre-orders have also been cancelled.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Greetings, Vault Hunters - We need to share that the release of Borderlands 4 on Nintendo Switch 2 is being delayed. We do not take this decision lightly, but are committed to ensuring we deliver the best possible experience to our fans, and the game needs additional development and polish time to do that. Our hope is to also better align this release with the addition of cross saves, which we are working on and recognize is very important. We will update you all on the new release timing once we’ve fully adjusted our plans.</p>
<p>In accordance with Nintendo’s policy, all digital pre-orders to date will be cancelled. Customers can initiate that process themselves now, or it will happen automatically starting on Friday, Sept. 26. For questions about the Nintendo eShop, contact <a href="https://t.co/p0U8UeGs49" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://bit.ly/4niZo7h</a>. For physical pre-orders, please reach out to the corresponding retailer.</p>
<p>We greatly appreciate the feedback, support and patience of our fans and community. It’s truly what keeps us going.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Borderlands 4 was originally released for PC, Xbox X|S and PlayStation 5 earlier this month on 12th September 2025. Our colleagues at Push Square thought the shift to an open world was the "right move", but couldn't ignore the console version's "problematic performance".</p>
<p>Before this latest development update, the Nintendo Switch 2 version was originally scheduled for 3rd October 2025.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188024,185551 @ 1758689875 -->
<p>What are your thoughts about this delay? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/borderlands-4-has-been-delayed-for-switch-2-digital-pre-orders-cancelled]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>