<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:28:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Check Out Pokémon Legends: Z-A's Switch 2 Evolution In This Side-By-Side Comparison]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/video-check-out-pokemon-legends-z-as-switch-2-evolution-in-this-side-by-side-comparison</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-check-out-pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-as-switch-2-evolution-in-this-side-by-side-comparison.1327732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Switch 2 used String Shot!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> has finally arrived on Switch and Switch 2, but with all the marketing focused on the latter edition, you may well be wondering how TPC's latest fares on Nintendo's old hardware.</p>
<p>Well, the wonderful Felix Sanchez is here to demonstrate. In the above side-by-side comparison video, you can get a glimpse at how Legends: Z-A runs on both Switch 1 and Switch 2, showcasing standard gameplay, cutscenes and load times.</p>
<p>As you'll see, the Switch 2 implements many of the improvements that we'd expect. The 60fps boost is a welcome sight compared to the last gen's 30, resolution and texturing are vastly improved, and a lot of the load times have moved in the right direction — though not <em>all</em> of them, as the video shows.</p>
<p>That said, the Switch 1 side of things looks... surprisingly <em>fine</em>. It's certainly a lot choppier and slower than the Switch 2 edition (as you'd expect), but at least it looks reasonably stable. It's no <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_tears_of_the_kingdom">TOTK</a>, of course, but nobody was really anticipating that, were they?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192371 @ 1760714198 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this video comparison? Have you picked up the Switch 1 version yet? Let us know your thoughts in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/video-check-out-pokemon-legends-z-as-switch-2-evolution-in-this-side-by-side-comparison]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>