<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 01:44:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Random: The Latest Mario Stop-Motion Short Might Be The Most Adorable Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/random-the-latest-mario-stop-motion-short-might-be-the-most-adorable-yet</link>
            <guid>1386460</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Let's play hide-and-seek!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>If you're looking for a little bit of lightness this holiday season for you and the kids, then hopefully you've been saving up a bunch of those <strong>It's Me, Mario!</strong> shorts. Nintendo has been sharing these on its family-friendly <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@playnintendo">Play Nintendo YouTube Channel</a> since August 2025.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rkVH3EaHbL4">Episode 5</a> dropped overnight and features Mario with Yoshi and Toad, who are playing a simple game of hide-and-seek. Mario must find both of his friends, who have found devious places to keep themselves out of the plumber's eyesight.</p>
<p>And look, we're extremely partial to stop-motion animation, but Yoshi and Toad look particularly adorable; we love the little Super Mario World nod with the trees and the fruit, and Toad is... well, Toad! He can hide in some pretty easy places in the Mushroom Kingdom.</p>
<p>All five shorts have some lovely little callbacks to the Mario series as a whole, so while the kids might delight in the lovely colours and animations, parents (or grandparents, or uncles, aunts — whoever!) can get all nostalgic. You can see all five currently released episodes in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLngvvr1C2bLGRo0H8Lwl33utYqofaMDT3">this playlist</a>.</p>
<p>The It's Me, Mario! shorts are actually designed to promote the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/gallery-nintendo-updates-its-my-mario-product-line-with-multiple-new-yoshi-items-heres-a-look"><strong>My Mario</strong> range of toys for young children</a>, which were <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/gallery-nintendo-shows-off-its-new-my-mario-product-line">released in Japan back in August this year</a>. A selection of these are coming to the US in 2026.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you a fan of these stop-motion shorts? Will you be grabbing some My Mario products next year? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario/related-articles:193560,186242 @ 1766018926 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/random-the-latest-mario-stop-motion-short-might-be-the-most-adorable-yet]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>