<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:10:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What Do You Make Of The Mario Galaxy Movie's Leaked Yoshi Design?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/poll-what-do-you-make-of-the-mario-galaxy-movies-leaked-yoshi-design</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-what-do-you-make-of-the-mario-galaxy-movies-leaked-yoshi-design.1348528/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Eyes on the prize</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="38971ea3a75fd"><a title="Yoshi Mario Galaxy" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/38971ea3a75fd/yoshi-mario-galaxy.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>We are still a good five months away from the release of <strong>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</strong>, but the rumour mill is already kicking into gear about Mario's next big adventure.</p>
<p>First, there was the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/a-trailer-for-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-will-debut-this-month-its-claimed">rumour</a> that an official trailer would be heading our way at some point this month, theoretically before <strong>Wicked: For Good</strong> arrives in theatres on 21st November. That was enough to get us excited, but its follow-up had us feeling a little more... mixed. Yes, we're talking about that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/images-of-yoshi-from-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-have-leaked-online">leaked Yoshi design</a>.</p>
<p>For those who haven't seen it yet, this weekend, US baking company <a href="https://shop.topsmarkets.com/store/tops-markets/products/83425108-pillsbury-ready-to-bake-yoshi-egg-sugar-cookie-dough-9-1-oz">Pillsbury</a> revealed its upcoming 'The Super Mario Galaxy Shape Sugar Cookie Dough'. A harmless enough endeavour, if a little premature, but the big talking point is the presence of the big green dino on the front and back of the box.</p>
<p>Sporting a similar Illumination sheen to the character design spotted on a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/its-official-the-mario-movie-sequel-is-based-on-mario-galaxy">tie-in Old Spice bottle</a> back in September, it's becoming increasingly likely that this is the Yoshi we'll all see in The Super Mario Galaxy Movie next year. Nothing is confirmed yet, of course, but we can only see so many pre-release promo products before we start to think that this is the real deal.</p>

<p>The big question now is, how do we all feel about this Yoshi design? The entire thing looks just about safe enough that we can absolutely believe it's true. It looks... like Yoshi, but the little scales all over his body are a nice little bit of detail, we suppose.</p>
<p>The stumbling point, and we're sure many of you will be in the same boat here, is those eyes. They are just so big. So white. So shiny. No matter which way we move our heads, it feels like those baby blues follow us around the room. How are we supposed to go about our daily lives with the knowledge that out there somewhere, Yoshi is staring at us?</p>
<p>But what do you think? Is this leaked Yoshi design everything that you would have hoped for in the Mario Galaxy Movie, or is it freaking you out a little? You can let us know your thoughts in the following poll, then head to the comments to share your full dino discussions.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario/related-articles:164056,193620,193336 @ 1762777802 --></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/poll-what-do-you-make-of-the-mario-galaxy-movies-leaked-yoshi-design]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Update Announced, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/hollow-knight-silksong-update-announced-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-update-announced-here-are-the-patch-notes.1348504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Including the implementation of a fan mod</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="49ebebe40e473"><a title="Silksong" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/49ebebe40e473/silksong.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Team Cherry</em></figcaption></figure><p>Team Cherry <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-4">has announced</a> a new update for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, and while it's already available for Steam users, it's been submitted for approval on console and will be available very soon.</p>
<p>Primarily, the update addresses the Chinese translation issues present in the game by implementing a fan mod from Team Cart Fix. Team Cherry praises the team's work, stating that the individuals involved "are well-versed in the (quite dense) narrative and lore of both Hollow Knight games, and understand the subtle links and connections that should be retained in the text"</p><div><figure data-videoid="8PPa7JzGiQE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8PPa7JzGiQE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt8PPa7JzGiQE" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8PPa7JzGiQE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8PPa7JzGiQE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed61a957otyjsr&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Other highlights include a film grain effect, more dithering options, and a plethora of general fixes.</p>
<p>Here's a look at the patch notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Updated Simplified Chinese translation to use fan translation provided by Team Cart Fix.</li>
<li>Switched to Unity's Input System to improve overall controller support. This includes rumble features now working for various controllers, and additional controllers being recognised. Some issues may remain. For a full list of supported controllers and features, please visit: <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/linkfilter/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.unity3d.com%2FPackages%2Fcom.unity.inputsystem%401.14%2Fmanual%2FSupportedDevices.html">https://docs.unity3d.com/Packages/<span data-cfemail="d6b5b9bbf8a3b8bfa2aff8bfb8a6a3a2a5afa5a2b3bb96e7f8e7e2">[email&nbsp;protected]</span>/manual/SupportedDevices.html</a></li>
<li>Added additional dithering levels. Now defaults to 'low'.</li>
<li>Added film grain effect to advanced options. Defaults to ‘off’</li>
<li>Various localisation fixes implemented across all languages.</li>
<li>Fixed Styx not giving rosaries when delivering the Queen's Egg.</li>
<li>Fixed Druid's Eyes sometimes not equipping correctly when first acquired.</li>
<li>Fixed some down attack colliders getting stuck on in rare instances.</li>
<li>Fixed several instances of Hornet's plasmified state clearing when not intended (eg Bellway travel).</li>
<li>Fixed issues entering the plasmified state when killing a Winged Lifeseed, rather than using the Plasmium Phial.</li>
<li>Reduced unintentionally long bind time when using Multibinder with the Shaman crest.</li>
<li>Updated Multibinder's initial bind to clear maggots, per community comments.</li>
<li>Wreath of Purity durability increased.</li>
<li>Fixed void incorrectly conducting electricity.</li>
<li>Gurr the Outcast trap-throw attack updated from single lob to spin-style, to reduce time spent static. Other slight refinements.</li>
<li>Fixed Beast Crest fury slashes not piercing as intended.</li>
<li>Fixed Rune Rage damage scaling incorrectly.</li>
<li>Fixed Thread Storm damage tapering (additional hits don't taper down as sharply).</li>
<li>Fixed rare instances of regaining control when grabbed by a Wraith.</li>
<li>Fixed couriers incorrectly offering the same delivery immediately after completing it.</li>
<li>Fixed additional instances of Hornet being able to push some enemy types through the floor.</li>
<li>Fixed issues when using Harpoon to stun or kill certain bosses.</li>
<li>Fixed Fractured Mask not protecting against volt hazards.</li>
<li>Various smaller tweaks and fixes.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192513,188204 @ 1762778725 -->
<p><em>Are you still plugging away at Silksong? Does this latest update address any of your own concerns? Let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-4" rel="noopener" href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-4">teamcherry.com.au</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/67ba08d9110fa0ae0657e3350f0bc172 @ 1762776427 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/hollow-knight-silksong-update-announced-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Just Hope To Stay Healthy" - Shigeru Miyamoto On Taking Further Steps Away From Development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/i-just-hope-to-stay-healthy-shigeru-miyamoto-on-taking-further-steps-away-from-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-just-hope-to-stay-healthy-shigeru-miyamoto-on-taking-further-steps-away-from-development.1348450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"I won't look anymore!"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="142703ed0cc7e"><a title="Miyamoto" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/142703ed0cc7e/miyamoto.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JApUMBscKOc">Nintendo</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>It's no secret that Shigeru Miyamoto has taken a bit of a backseat when it comes to game development. The last Mario game he personally oversaw as director was <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/super_mario_run">Super Mario Run</a>, and after his most recent experience as general producer on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pikmin_4">Pikmin 4</a>, the creator has largely shifted over to the world of movies.</p>
<p>In a new interview with <a href="https://casabrutus.com/magazines/issue/no308">Casa Brutus</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/its-going-to-be-fun-miyamoto-discusses-mario-galaxy-movie-and-the-future-of-mario-games/">VGC</a>), Miyamoto hints toward taking even further steps away from game development. He states that while Nintendo currently has other developers leading the charge on new Mario titles, he nevertheless endeavours to play them and deliver feedback on the overall interface.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Nowadays, I have teammates who help maintain the world of Mario, so I entrust much of it to them. Even so, I always personally play through about the first 30 minutes of the game and check the interface thoroughly — to make sure it really feels like Mario.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He then – perhaps jokingly – hints that he may not even do this in the future and simply leave everything to his colleagues, before expressing his wish to remain healthy until Mario's inevitable 50th anniversary in ten years' time:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Up through <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a>, I feel we’ve done just about everything we could on the Switch. In the past, whenever a new console came out, we always released a new Mario game, so I do wonder how the current team will take on that challenge.</p>
<p>“But maybe I’ll say, ‘I won’t look anymore!’ (laughs) I just hope to stay healthy until Mario’s 50th anniversary!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Discussion also turns to the upcoming <strong>Super Mario Galaxy Movie</strong>, which Miyamoto states is in the "final stages of production" while expressing the opinion that "it’s going to be fun". Only time will tell, but the movie's introduction of Yoshi was recently revealed prematurely thanks to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/images-of-yoshi-from-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-have-leaked-online">a product listing from none other than US baking firm Pillsbury</a>.</p>
<p>The movie officially launches on <strong>3rd April 2026</strong>, and it's said that a trailer will debut later this month and play before screenings for <strong>Wicked: For Good</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-articles:193620,193099 @ 1762778645 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Miyamoto's comments here? Is it possible he will eventually retire completely? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://casabrutus.com/magazines/issue/no308" rel="noopener" href="https://casabrutus.com/magazines/issue/no308">casabrutus.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/its-going-to-be-fun-miyamoto-discusses-mario-galaxy-movie-and-the-future-of-mario-games/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/its-going-to-be-fun-miyamoto-discusses-mario-galaxy-movie-and-the-future-of-mario-games/">videogameschronicle.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-info/588d7133030efc3615bcd81bdb6c75bf @ 1762779614 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/i-just-hope-to-stay-healthy-shigeru-miyamoto-on-taking-further-steps-away-from-development]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Launches Switch 2 Backwards Compatibility Search Page]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page.1348408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Find out if the Switch game you want to play is compatible</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="05bd7684ae54f"><a title="Super Smash Bros. Ultimate" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/05bd7684ae54f/super-smash-bros-ultimate.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Since the launch of the Switch 2 in June, Nintendo has released game upgrades, updates, and system firmware patches to make more games compatible with its new hybrid system.</p>
<p>It's not always been the easiest to keep track of every update, and to help make this process a little easier, a new website has now gone live.</p>
<p>It allows you to check the compatibility of Switch software on the Nintendo Switch 2. It's as simple as <a href="https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US">typing a Switch game into the search bar</a>, and it will reveal if it's "supported" or not. Nintendo also notes how search results include both physical and digital versions of software.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067vspxgn&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<figure data-uuid="ff24e60ddee85"><a title="Game" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ff24e60ddee85/game.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This search functionality extends to apps, and each search may or may not include additional information such as recent patches. Other searches will result in "incompatible" or "unsupported" as you can see in the screenshots below - with Nintendo even acknowledging specific issues.</p>
<p>So, instead of having to refer to the official PDFs or other search methods on Nintendo's website, you can now simply enter the game title in the search bar and find out if the software you want to play is compatible on the Switch 2.</p>

<p>When Nintendo initially revealed Switch game compatibility for the Switch 2, it mentioned at the time how not every game would be supported at launch, but explained how the work to make more games compatible was ongoing.</p>
<p>This new search page means you can now regularly check the status of games that may not yet be compatible with the Switch 2 and see if there are any updates.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:164338,192705,176994 @ 1762779317 -->
<p>Are there any particular Switch games or apps you would like to see made compatible with the Switch 2? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US" rel="noopener" href="https://switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com/en-US">switch-software-compatibility.nintendo.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1987690692462747969" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/OatmealDome/status/1987690692462747969">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/0cafcdd7980df7d2201dfb7a9cfa2992 @ 1762777544 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-launches-switch-2-backwards-compatibility-search-page]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>