<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - nintendolife_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/nintendolife_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for nintendolife_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:12:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Need A Bit More Flirting With Your Mega Man Gameplay? You're In Luck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/need-a-bit-more-flirting-with-your-mega-man-gameplay-youre-in-luck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/need-a-bit-more-flirting-with-your-mega-man-gameplay-youre-in-luck.1287933/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>'Radiant Starlets' is targeting Switch 2</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>If you've ever played <strong>Mega Man</strong> and thought <em>"hmm, this is great, but what if I could hook up with the Robot Masters?"</em>, then you're in luck. <strong>Radiant Starlets</strong> is a new title from developer Buster X Buster, and it's looking to combine that classic side-scrolling action gameplay with some intriguing dating sim elements.</p>
<p>The game is targeting a release on the Switch 2, with a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/busterxbuster/radiant-starlets">Kickstarter campaign</a> now live with 28 days remaining at the time of writing. The developers are looking for a total of CA$ 100,000, which roughly converts to just under £50,000, but a whole bunch of stretch goals have also been detailed should funding surpass expectations. These include a Boss Rush Mode, hard difficulty setting, a secret extra date, and more.</p>
<p>So essentially, you'll be able to choose which 'Starlet' you want to pursue from eight main stages. When you eventually encounter a Starlet, you'll have the choice to either fight them or date them. If you choose the latter, you'll need to complete a minigame unique to each character. Successfully doing so will then essentially recruit the Starlet to accompany you on further playthroughs, introducing fresh power ups and unique endings.</p>
<p>With some beautiful HD2D-inspired visuals, this one is looking really cool. We'll definitely keep a close eye on the Kickstarter campaign over the coming days and weeks.</p>
<p>Let's check out the key features:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>- Traverse Challenging Environments:</strong> Play 8 main stages and face against <strong>Starlet Overdrive,</strong> a world-famous S-Pop group bent on obtaining Dream for themselves.<br>
- <strong>Per-Relationship Speed-runs:</strong> Each partner provides a separate speed run and endings. With Radiant Starlets, you're encouraged to try every boss order. Replay to experience each partner’s armor set, minigame, and story.<br>
- <strong>Partner Specific Mini Games:</strong> Each partner has a custom mini game, designed to unlock partner-specific power-ups and narrative.<br>
- <strong>Armor Designed by your Partner:</strong> Each partner playthrough will have a custom armor set with unique properties, creating variances in gameplay between runs.<br>
- <strong>Custom Partner Charge Shot:</strong> Each partner provides you with a <strong>custom charge shot that you blast!<br>
-</strong> <strong>Get power ups from each boss:</strong> The Starlets have all modified Dream's power source to power their equipment. When he retrieves them he will get a part of their powers.<br>
- <strong>Endings for Each Romantic Partner:</strong> Each Romantic partner provides narrative changes and their own distinct ending.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184918,179892 @ 1756920604 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this one so far? Are you planning on backing it via Kickstarter? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/busterxbuster/radiant-starlets" rel="noopener" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/busterxbuster/radiant-starlets">kickstarter.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1756921981 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/need-a-bit-more-flirting-with-your-mega-man-gameplay-youre-in-luck]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everybody's Golf Spiritual Successor 'Easy Come Easy Golf' Gets Surprise 60fps Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/everybodys-golf-spiritual-successor-easy-come-easy-golf-gets-surprise-60fps-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everybodys-golf-spiritual-successor-easy-come-easy-golf-gets-surprise-60fps-update.1287870/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Now that's a Hot Shot</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Easy Come Easy Golf" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/73ac62ea87ef0/easy-come-easy-golf.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Clap Hanz</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/easy_come_easy_golf">Easy Come Easy Golf</a>, the game from the former <strong>Everybody's Golf</strong> developers ClapHanz, has just received a surprise free update on Switch, which includes Switch 2 support and a 60fps mode. <em>[Thanks to reader James McWhirter for the tip!]</em></p>
<p>Version 1.9.8 <a href="https://claphanz.com/en/news/nintendo_switch_easy_come_easy_golf_ver198_update.html">arrived earlier today</a> and includes a caddy's worth of improvements for load times, grid display, and 1080p support for the larger Switch 2 screen.</p>
<p>Plus the game, which ran at 30fps on the original Switch back when we reviewed it in 2022, will now let you choos between a 30 and 60fps mode.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067vonwkl&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>833k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>The timing of this update is a little curious, as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/everybodys_golf_hot_shots">Everybody's Golf Hot Shots</a>, a brand new game in the Everybody's Golf series, comes out on Switch on 5th September (4th in Japan). We've even got <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/everybodys-golf-hot-shots">a review up for that today</a>. Is Clap Hanz taking a Hot Shot at Hot Shots...? (Please don't give us a Double Bogie).</p>
<p>Anyway, here are the patch notes straight from Clap Hanz's website:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Ver. 1.9.8 of "Easy Come Easy Golf" was released.<br>
The content of the latest update is listed below.<br>
- Improved load times<br>
- Improved grid display<br>
- Reorganized home screen menu into a single page<br>
- Adjusted Triple Tap spin input<br>
- Improved Triple Tap gauge UI<br>
- Frame rate selection (30fps/60fps)<br>
You can also play at 60fps on Switch 2</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you fancy a shot at Easy Come Easy Golf, then we rather enjoyed it back when it released on Switch, scoring it an 8/10. Now with smoother performance and an updated resolution for Switch 2, there's no better time to try it.</p>
<p><em>Let us know whether you're an Easy Come Easy Golf fan by teeing off in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:137852,187170 @ 1756922445 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://claphanz.com/en/news/nintendo_switch_easy_come_easy_golf_ver198_update.html" rel="noopener" href="https://claphanz.com/en/news/nintendo_switch_easy_come_easy_golf_ver198_update.html">claphanz.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/5186ad38207c8ce99568eaaaf34370cf @ 1756922355 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/everybodys-golf-spiritual-successor-easy-come-easy-golf-gets-surprise-60fps-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yuzo Koshiro's Shmup 'Earthion' Finally Has A Switch Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/yuzo-koshiros-shmup-earthion-finally-has-a-switch-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yuzo-koshiros-shmup-earthion-finally-has-a-switch-release-date.1287789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>According to the eShop</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Did you know that Yuzo Koshiro, legendary video game composer, has made a Sega Mega Drive / Genesis shmup? It was released on Steam back in July, with our friends over at <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/reviews/steamdeck/earthion">Time Extension giving it a glowing review</a>. It was due to launch on consoles, including Switch, at the same time, but <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/07/the-console-versions-of-yuzo-koshiros-earthion-have-been-delayed">was pushed back to "mid-September"</a>.</p>
<p>Fortunately, it looks like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/earthion">Earthion</a> will be landing that mid-September date, as the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/earthion-switch/">eShop page</a> says the game is coming out on 18th September 2025. That's just over two weeks away!</p>
<p>Published by Limited Run Games and developed by Koshiro's company Ancient, Earthion is a gorgeous-looking shoot 'em up developed <em>for</em> the classic Sega console. That version is coming in 2026, but for anyone wanting it on modern consoles, you won't have long to wait.</p>
<p>Like many of the best shmups, the Earthion keeps things simple, giving your ship a main weapon and two sub-weapons and eight diverse stages to blast your way through.</p>

<p>We'll point you towards Time Extension's review for the low-down, but if you're not sold on Makoto "Karu_gamo" Wada (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/gotta_protectors_cart_of_darkness">Gotta Protectors: Cart Of Darkness</a>) and Koshiro's yet, here's a little snippet from that review:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>"Earthion is everything I'd hoped it would be when Yuzo Koshiro first announced it; a challenging shmup which pushes Sega's 16-bit hardware to its limits in terms of visuals and audio whilst combining a high level of polish with tight gameplay and plenty of longevity."</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well now, that sounds pretty good, doesn't it? Let's hope that the 18th September date sticks — we've had no word from the publisher or developer on it yet, so keep your eyes peeled.</p>
<p><em>Let us know if you're looking forward to Earthion in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:186316,185776 @ 1756919787 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/earthion-switch/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/earthion-switch/">nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-info/eb9da09e70a4e128d475dba34c56020f @ 1756919701 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/yuzo-koshiros-shmup-earthion-finally-has-a-switch-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>